<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes by Kerosene and Gasoline Lamps</title>
               <date value="1928-06">1928-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 225 June, 1928 The Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes by Kerosene and Gasoline Lamps GRETA GRAY Department of Home Economics THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY The lamps owned per household number 3.8. Of these 2.6 are ordinary kerosene, 0.3 are round wick kerosene, 0.08 are kerosene mantle, and 0.8 are gasoline lamps. The average cost for upkeep per year per household, not including fuel, is $2.0-1. In households using ordinary kerosene lamps only, the average cost is $1.27, aTid m households with ordinary kerosene lamps and other lamps the average cost is $2.17. Forty-five minutes per week per household are spent m the care of lamps, and 50 minutes per week per household m those households having ordinary kerosene lamps only. Approximately 82 per cent of the kitchens and sitting rooms are lighted by one lamp each, 17 per cent by 2 lamps each, and 0.7 per cent by 3 lamps each. Less than 30 per cent of the lamps are above eye level. Twenty-eight per cent of the lamps are shaded. The light most frequently found m the kitchen is that furnished by one unshaded kerosene lamp placed below eye level. The light most frequently found m the sitting room is that furnished by a shaded gasoline reading lump placed on a table. In a kitchen 12 feet by 14 feet with light ceiling and walls the illumination from the unshaded ordinary kerosene lamp on the work table when this is at the average distance from the lamp is 0.25 foot - candles. Under similar circumstances the illumination on the stove is 0.18 foot-candles, and the illumination on the sink or water bucket is 0.12 candles. In a sitting room 12 feet by 14 feet with light ceiling and walls the illumination from the shaded gasoline reading lamp at the edge of a table 42 inches m diameter with the lamp at the center is 8.0 foot-candles. Under the same conditions, the illumination at the edge of a table 52 inches m diameter is 5.25 foot-candles. The intensity of illumination m Nebraska homes lighted by kero - sene and gasoline lamps is far below the standards set by illuminating engineers. There is &gt;i great deal of glare m these houses, the dis - tribution of light is very poor, and there are harsh, objectionable shadows. The lighting might be improved by 4 methods: first, by using more of the higher-candle-power lamps; second, by using two or more lamps per room; third, by putting the lamps m the kitchen above eye level; and fourth, by shading all lamps. The first two methods would increase the intensity of illumination. The second, third, and fourth methods would improve the distribution of light and eliminate some objec ionable shadows. The third and fourth methods would prevent gla - c. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes by Kerosene and Gasoline Lamps f■ : ■ The purpose Of this investigation has been to determine, first, how much! of the housewife's time is occupied m the care of kerosene and gasoline lamps, second, the cost of the upkeep of these; lamps, and third, what the lighting condi - tions are m Nebraska rural homes without electricity or gas light. The reported expenditures of time and money for the care and upkeep of the lamps pertain to the care and cost , of all the lamps and lanterns used. However, only the lighting of the i kitchens and of the rooms used as sitting rooms has been considered and compared with accepted illumination standards. Data were collected from 184 homes by 10 persons resident m the communities represented m this study. All but 6 of the homes are m the eastern part of the state. All the data asked for on the study sheets used were not obtained m every noop . -1 Table 1 shows the tenancy, the average value of the farm and buildings, and the average number of persons per house - hold. Table 1. Tenancy, value of farm and buildings, and size of household i Value Size "3-3 "3-Su „ "S-ou- »2 Tenancy . || g 2%*2 S o |||S §•§ I 1 1-sA gill %% zltf II A ll |. 184 46 $12,574 180 4;16 : 1 — r | Owners 70 16 14,353 68 1 3.48 Tenants J I 108 29 11,651 107 4.56 ! I T Ownership not stated 6 1 11,000 5 4.8 . | I Table 2 gives' the types and numbers of lamps owned and used daily. Fig. 1 shows the percentage distribution of the types of lamps used. There are more than 3 times as many </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 Table 2. — Lamps and types per household mimed and used daily ,o I _1 Type of lamp _1S$ ~1 f — | "J || 1 1| All ] O.K.* I R.W.K.' | K.M.' gas • i__j_ £5 i "! ■ i r 7 j - r ~ ' i Owned 177 3.8 2.6 .3 | .08 j .8 " Used daily 120 2.9 ( Used daily in households with O.K. only 29 2.9 2.9 i \ . I . I I .... I • o.K. — Ordinary kerosene lamp ; R.W.K. — Round wick kerosene lamp ; K.M. — Kerosene mantle lamp *. Ras — Gasoline lamp. ordinary kerosene lamps as gasoline lamps. The ordinary kerosene lamp is the No. 2 burner flat- wick lamp; the gaso - line lamp is in almost every case one with 2 mantles about one and one-half inches long. » Table 3 presents data as to the cost in 5 60 r~l money for the upkeep, excluding the cost of ; 4o fuel, and in time for the care of lamps. The °_, 0 amounts of money and of time reported are j „, estimates in most cases. The average sum t &lt;0 &gt; of money spent in households having only t io o &lt;* *■(«. e ordinary kerosene lamps is less than £ 0 —\* % that spent in those households which have other lamps as well as ordinary kerosene fig. i. Percentage di*. i amps . Most of the ordinary kerosene lamps tnbution of tamps ... , . , ... , . owned by i.4 house- found in this study are without shades, as __' ry ke.osenJ' ilt may be seen in Tables 8 and 9 and in Fig. 3. R.w.K. is round- so in the majoritv of cases the only expense wick kerosene lamp, .._ _i_ _■*_-.-_. 1 • l k.m. is kerosene aside from that for fuel is for chimneys and mantle ump^and w i c k s . From Tables 8 and 9 and Fig. 3 it lamp. may be seen also that the greater part of the lamps other than the ordinary kerosene are gasoline lamps, and over half of these gasoline lamps have shades. Shades are frequently broken when the mantle breaks, and it seems rea - sonable that the money spent for shades and mantles for these lamps should be more than that spent for the upkeep of the kerosene lamps. The reports summarized in Table 3 as to the relative amounts of time spent in the care of ordinary kerosene lamps only and in the care of all lamps are what might be expected, because the chimney and the wick of the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Lighting op Nebraska Rural Homes Table 3. — Expenditure per household in money for wicks, mantles, generators, chimneys, and shades; arid in time for the care of lamps = = = K^_g_T Expenditures in time '•-•■'-:- - S I Households 0, 3»- 3 t) 0, ott- . sill Tiji lis! |tq{« m - * 'Z O ».£ S « _L eft 1 T_ _.___» 5 S.TJ . «_&gt; Si Hh Isla l|H illill 111 All 165 $2.04 123 4.5 45 : _^ 1 With O.K. lamps only 33 1.27 30 4.5 50 ' i ; [__ With O.K. lamps and others 126 2.17 . j ' j kerosene lamp need frequent attention, while the gasoline lamp requires little care. Nine persons are known to have kept accurate account of the time spent in caring for lamps. These 9 averaged 43 minutes a week, which agrees very closely with the average of the estimated intervals of time. With kerosene averaging a little over 15 cents a gallon and electricity at 11.7 cents per kilowatt hour, Kunerth (10) * found the cost jof kerosene and of electricity the same for equal amounts of illumination from No. 2 burner flat-Wick kerosene lamps and from tungsten lamps. For 1,000 mean spherical candle-power hours from either source, the cost at the above rates was 19 cents. A quart of gasoline burns from 10 to 13 hours! in the gasoline reading lamp with a mean spherical candle; power of over 100 ; therefore, less than one quart of gasoline is required to furnish 1,000 mean spherical candle-power hoiirs. In order to determine the lighting conditions in the homes studied, data were secured as to the following items: the sizes of the kitchens and sitting rooms, presented in Table 4 ; the uses of these rooms, presented in Table 5 and Fig. 2; the' distances from the lamp to the different work places, shown in Tables 6 and 7 ; and the number, type, position, and shading of the lamps used, given in Tables 8 and 9. Complete data were secured as to the lamps in 298 rooms. Two hundred and forty-four rooms are lighted by one lamp each. The facts as to the kind, position, and shading of these lamps are .shown in Table 8. Fig. 4 shows how the rooms lighted by ' j * All figures in parentheses are references to literature cited on the last page. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 these lamps are distributed according to the type, position, and shading of the lamp. Fifty-two of the rooms are lighted by 2 lamps each. Twenty-two of these rooms are in 11 homes. Two rooms in the same house are lighted by 3 lamps each, all of them ordinary kerosene lamps. The distribution of the rooms with more than one lamp as to number, position, type, and shading of lamps is given in Table 9. Fig. 5 shows how the rooms lighted by one lamp compare in number with the rooms lighted by 2 or more lamps. Fig. 6 gives a com - parison of the percentages of lamps above eye level and of shaded lamps in rooms lighted by one lamp and in rooms lighted by more than one lamp. Table 4. — Floor areas of rooms Floor area in square feet Quartiles Rooms l Z || = - * Mean Median Mode ' Kanco Q, Q_ ■;. ..5 i I i All kitchen. 17'.' 11)8 168 168 6..-..20 121 225 All sitting moms 178 202 1!).. 168 72-620 168 225 Kitchens nut sitting rooms 148 15. 14. 168 63-320 120 192 Sitting rooms not kitchens 147 200 102 168 72-620 168 224 Kitchens used as sitting rooms 31 208 111.. 168 120-320 168 253 From Tables 8 and 9 the following facts may be noted : In all kitchens and sitting rooms there are as many ordinary kerosene lamps as higher-candle-power lamps. In rooms with one lamp only there are 50 per cent more higher-candle - power lamps than ordinary kerosene lamps; that is, in 3 out of 5 rooms lighted by one lamp the lamp is a round-wick kerosene lamp, a kerosene mantle lamp, or a gasoline lamp. Thirty-two of the 54 rooms with more than one lamp have ordinary kerosene lamps only, and in 13 of the rooms with 2 lamps one of them is an ordinary kerosene lamp. In kitchens not used as sitting rooms there are more than twice as many ordinary kerosene lamps as other lamps, while in sitting rooms not also kitchens there are fewer than half as many. There are nearly twice as many kitchens lighted </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Table 5 Artificial light sources and the use of all sitting rooms, with respect to the work done 55 — t in which dose- discrimination- of-detail-is-necessary, and .to-.the-numb.er-.of- occupants _gj ■ " — ' - ' Use, of sitting roomfl - ■ ; *2u Percentage of rooms in which indicated operations are conducted Number of persons per household 'tt No. of : : O rooms tj ►_ Number and kind of lamps in •- X e ►-_/ ■ group H • e . g =_ o _ „ _ Z £ « _ w _^ • i* 3 J* J. _S 53 _&gt; _H to &lt; B in _■_ i- _! 1 "■ E S £ __ , ■— — 1 — : — r I &gt; OneO.K ....31 61 42 97 -45 16 45 84 ,L 4.3 4- 3&amp;4 1-10 . g Two o.K I 15 [87 33 100 60 7 80 100 j 5.0 4 4 2-10 g One gas or better I 95 87 53 99 54 22 69 99 4.3 1 4 4 j 1-12 f ; O M </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 las by o n e ordi - aa I I nary kerosene t sa r~l 1 a m p as are o zs lighted by one Z ~r~] —i better lamp. _ **- • _- - "I. There are I- 2 0 ~R . „ g ,, |l nearly 4 times :*s!?).2 |~5&gt;-S | _ . &gt; * as many sit - $ *•* I £ I 8 * &gt;-_*§£ S C 5 ? a ting rooms ° "*- 3 * 5 Si ." 5 * S S ■&gt; SilSJ.; lighted by one 0 1 — I — I — 1 — I — I 1 I I 1 1 I '11111 lamp better 000«» with doom, with Qoon* With QM. tVinn tViP nrrl* o„, O .» TWO O.K fc*. l,.p tllan *™ ° rfll - lai.0 lams. os el-nut nary kerosene Fig. 2. Percentages of rooms in which indicated occupations arc ..i, 1+1 T conducted and the number of persona per household in sitting ull&amp; 131161'. In room, lighted hy one ordinary kerosene lamp, bv two ordinary t Vi p \citrhpr\a kerosene lamps, and by one gasoline lamp or better Xr. IMtWlCllO 60 per cent of the ordinary kerosene lamps and 61 per cent of the other lamps are below eye level. In the sitting rooms 90 per cent of the ordinary kerosene lamps and 75 per cent of the other lamps are below eye level. Ninety-six per cent of all ordinary kerosene lamps and 97 per cent of those below eye level are unshaded. Fifty-two per cent of all higher-candle-power lamps and 43 per cent of those below eve level are unshaded. The light in the kitchens is most frequently furnished bv one ordinary unshaded kerosene lamp placed below eye level and that in the sitting room by one higher-candle-power lamp shaded and placed on a table. An attempt has been made to ascertain approximately and to compare with recognized lighting standards the following factors of illumination as found in these Nebraska sitting rooms and kitchens: first, the intensity of the illumination at the various work centers; second, the extent to which glare exists; and third, the diffusion and the distribution of the light. These factors of illumination depend upon the number and the candle power of the lamps used, their posi - tions, their shading, and the reflecting surfaces the light meets. The lumens from a kerosene lamp are constantly changing and vary with the quality of the oil, the clogging of the wick the height of the flame, the fogging of the chimney, and atmospheric conditions. The lumens emitted by the gasoline lamp depend upon the pressure and other operating condi - tions. Kunerth in " Illuminating Power of Kerosene" (10) states that he found the mean spherical candle power of different oils burned in the No. 2 flat-wick burner at the optimum ad- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes i . ■ ■ .: 1 -22 ' ' ' 116O £___ *=^ p Sag I 2 &gt;. „_, S * „ i . °is i | . ■ r I fin. I -J H . is? I (10 % «s J I us ■■".'. i tfO li - te? IS _*! I ■-I' - "fl% LAMP. IN LAMPS IN LAMPS iW'Z KlTCHfN. HOT KITCHENS IN OTHIR . /^ LAMPS tn US. O AS SIT- U3(D A3 sittino w all Qoont ! Ti(M noon _iT.m_ «oon Sooms Fig. 3. Location, number, type, and Bhading of 354 lamps in 208 kitchens and sitting rooms. The crosshatched areas indicate shaded lamps. justment to be 9.3. The Bureau of Standards of the United States Department of Commerce is authority for the follow - ing statements-.j The horizontal power of the No. 2 flat-wick kerosene lamp ranges from 5 to 9 or 10 ; 7 is a good average for a well-adjusted lamp, and the mean spherical candle power is only slightly less than this. The candle power of the round-wick 'kerosene lamp ranges from 20 to 25 candles and under very! careful adjustment to 30 candles. Kerosene </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 z"&amp;a mantle lamps give about 60 «..** va candles. The horizontal 1 5- % candle power of the gasoline • s - II reading lamp is approximate- S ; J * z ly 175 candles under condi - 5 •&gt;-—#}—-£ r*)v'|_a^" tlons of maximum efficiency. \is °m -% _\ *■ ° The Bureau of Standards has |?i» p &amp; p no measurements on the mean | i tt % spherical candle power of this \— vk lamp, but estimates it at from S „ | 125 to 140 candles. This read - jj /A ing lamp has 2 mantles placed „ \_j y side by side so that the dis - „ tribution is quite uneven as kitchms MTTI/.C, qhs may be seen in Fig. 7, which f,_. 4. rereenu^ of Kitchens „,., use,, as jf reproduced from Fig. 4 in sittine rimms anil nt sittin. n...ms not Lighting for Country sene h ?^p n trone%;rd.^r r ker„ k ;eTe Homes and Village commun - lamp, by one kerosene mantle lump, nnd itleS " (11). The Candle hy one casoline lamp, ahnv,- and below _* _i - i • ,, eye level, shaded and unshaded The pOWei' Ot tlllS lamp In the »." s .:. r r:;lr';.nh in :'naded tml"' horizontal direction, in which , it is . least, is about half of that in which it is greatest. The brightness of the flame of the kerosene lamp depends upon several things, as does its illuminating power. Kunerth (10) gives 6 candle power per square inch as the brightness when the flame of a No. 2 flat-wick burner is at its optimum adjustment. When the flame was lower than this he found it brighter and when the flame was higher he found the brightness less. He found that the brightness varied with the oil used, depending upon the density of the oil. Ferry (6) gives 5 lamberts, or a little over 10 candle power per square inch, as the brightness of the ordinary kerosene flame. The bright - ness of the kerosene and gasoline mantle burners greatlv ex - ceeds that of the kerosene flame. kitchi«s i u __. mi&gt;s As is shown in lable 4, a room of 168 square feet is kit.hins l \ z lamps the one most fre- us " A _ Hi i lamp ., _ , . SlTTmq Boom ' i«nw quently f o u n d in this study, altho oth. o i u LAn(&gt;4 the room of average jj™ . lamp 1 size is somewhat 0 l0 M M «, „ w „ - 5 ,_ ,'_. larger and sitting _u W &gt;iq or ..... rooms tend to be larger than kitch- ' ' "'' N " m, "' r " c "* ,n,s »™''*i one lamp nnd with two or more lamps. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes „ A ens. The variations in illumination in 2 e.| £ * different parts of a room of 168 square £ 55 t 5 mj feet floor area lighted by one lamp are 5l0 (4i« _f _3 great. The direct illumination at any S zs ~ -51 x 3 point may be calculated but besides this in | M t . 5 9 a small room there is a varying amount of 5' 3 * * •! reflected light (2, 12, 13, 18). In order *'° £ « ■£ « *° determine the illumination on the work a 5 j t z\ plane at different distances from the oL_L___ L±_J various lamps found in this study, meas- A&amp;ovt iHAOir. urements were made with a foot-candle ««•"*» meter. Professor F. W. Norris of the F 'Lw in P ram» ta with on_ Department of Electrical Engineering of lamp and in rooms with the University of Nebraska made these two lamps which are , - above eye level, and measurements. Eed taKes which i Bre The test room was a kitchen 15 by 11.5 feet with a ceiling height of 8.75 feet. Two built-in cupboards extending to the ceiling measured 44 by 22 inches and 17 by 43 inches, leaving a floor area of 161 square feet. The ceiling, walls, woodwork, floor, and fur - nishings were rated by Professor Norris as medium light in color. | Measurements were made of the light from the unshaded ordinary kerosene lamp, the unshaded round-wick kerosene Table 6. — Measures of distances from lamp to kitchen work places Measure in feet 1 '*- « 1 I 0 "-i tt_ „. . &gt;■•!-_ \ Quartiles Distance £,c:5 « ill-B I Zj -I-. I Mean Median Mode I Range Q, I Q. , ~' : r ~^ i i From lamp to kitchen dining table*....! 100 2.0 0 0 0-16 0 3 , _ _ From lamp to work table* i 159 3.3 3 0 0-18 0 6 : i_ 1 • I ! From lamp to stove* .... 174 5.7 6 6 0-15 4 \ 7 ___ 1 1_ 1 I I | ! ~ II From lamp to sink or | . - III water bucket *....! ! 1C4 7.3 . 7 6 0-18 5 8 1 i I i * Lamps which are over the work surface are not included. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 Table 7. — Measures of distance from lamp to table or desk in room used as sitting room Measure in feet Room | ill j ) I Quartiles i||i i i i i Zx.5 Mean IMedianl Mode 1 Range 1 Q, I Qa i '■ ■ i I " r Kitchen * 31 1.6 ; 0 0 I 0-10 \ 0 j 0 i III 1 , 1 , i &gt; !■ Other room used as sitting room * 137 0.8 0 0 • 0-10 , 0 0 i I I • Lamps which are over the tahle or desk are not included. lamp, and the gasoline reading lamp with an opal shade. Each of these lamps in turn was placed on a table toward the center of the room, 3.3 feet from the work table, which is the average distance from the lamp to the work table found in this study. The average illumination from each lamp on the surface of the work table was determined. In the same way the average illumination from each lamp was measured on the surface of the stove, 5.7 feet from the lamp, and on the surface of the sink, 7.3 feet from the lamp, these being the average distances from the lamp to the stove and to the sink or water bucket found in this study. The illum - ination from each of the lamps was measured at the edge of two tables, one 42 inches in diameter and the other 52 inches in diameter, with the lamp placed at the center of the table. In Table 10 these measurements are presented. There are 2 measurements for the illumination from the ordinary kero - sene lamp and 2 for the illumination from the gasoline read - ing lamp. These measurements are for the illumination in 2 directions from each of these lamps, the one in the direction in which the luminous flux is a minimum, the other in the direction in which it is a maximum. In Table 11 are given standards for the intensity of illum - ination for different areas and for certain kinds of work done in every home, which have been taken from " Code of Lighting Factories, Mills, and Other Work Places" (8), or from "Code of Lighting School Buildings" (9). In some states these codes have been made the basis for legal require - ments for lighting. They provide also for the avoidance of glare and of " objectionable shadows " and for a distribution of light which will " avoid excessive variations in illumina - tion upon work places." The formulae relating to glare and distribution of light given by these codes are not applicable </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Table 8. — Distribution of 244 lamps in rooms lighted by one lamp; according to location, type, £_ and shading of lamps ____*__ uw -Location of lamps Type and shading of lamps j 2. Position All lamps | O.K. R.W.K. K.M. gas O Boom as to All I Shaded | All I Shaded All I Shaded All | Shaded AH | Shaded q eye level No | No | Per cent l No . | No . | p er cent No. I No. | Per cent No. | No. | Per cent No. |___&gt;__l_____e.__ t •_ All All I 244 I 86 I 35 I 98 6 | 6 | 31 | 11 | 35 | 3 | 2 | 67 112 | 67 | 60 g Above | 75 | 19 | - 25 | 34 3 | 9 ' ] ' » * " I 0 1 0 I 0 40 | 16J _40_. gj Below | 169 | 67 | 40 | 64 3 | 5 j 30 | 11. | 37 | 3 | 2 | 67 72 j, 51 | 71 g Kitchens not All ' | 109 | 22 |_20_ | 68 3 | 4 | 9 | 4 | 44 | 0 | 0 [ 0 31 | 15 | 48 to used as Above | 43 ] 7 | 16 I "28 [ 2 j 7 | 1 I 0 [ 0 0 | 0 I 0 14 I 5 | 36 £ sitting rooms B^^J_^65Tu [~23~r~l0 TT~3 | 8 | 4 | 50 [ 0 | 0 I 0 17 | 10 | 59 Kitchens All 17 | 5J 29 j 5 0 j 0 4-j 0 | ' 0 j 0J 0 I 0 8 ] 5 | 63 c used as Above f~ 4 0 1 0 | 3 | 0 0 | 0 | 0| 0 0 | 0 I 0 1 I 0.1 Slttl "g rooms Below __T__T_ 5'T 38 ~| _Tj_J 6~| 4T~"0~I ° I "I 01 0 7 | 5 | 71 t&lt; Other All l___LL____L J. __ 5 _. 3 | 12 | 18 [ 7 | 39 | 3 ] 2 | 67 73 | 47 | 64 |ij sitting Above | 28 | 12 [ 43 | 3 1_|__33__J___0 J__0_j__ _0___ _JLLJLL_iL-_^LLiLi_ii- i rooms Betow j" 91 | 47 |" 52_ [ 22 2 | 9 | 18 | 7 I 39 | 3 | 2 | 67 | 48 | 36 | 75 m </seg>
            <seg id="p014">TABLE 9 —Distribution of 54 rooms lighted by tico or more lamps according to location, number per room, type, and shading. Figures in parentheses are rooms with one or both lamps shaded Location of tamps ** Z* I 5 _ 5. _. a _j . f-g § One above H_ 1 + (2) I ■ j _.. g O.K. above ' I i -H w I _J_. _.. g Gas above I _ i — ►_ Kitchens A1 &gt; ab(&gt;ve . jj ' ( " , I I "~ S not used All below 15 ' /,_ " &gt; as One above | I 5 | i ( 1 ) - H sitting aK above ! 1 . . - o rooms _ , . i ' I i i 1 ! ' - Gas above I ■ - . — , Kitchens AH above 2 ■ .-. W usedas All below I I 3+ (1) U' — p sitting one above 2 1 _ '&lt; . ■ -I ! __ rooms O.K. above I I ; - 1 3 Gas above I J. — - , — 7.T - ~c — 7T. Other All below I 1 8 1 (D 2+&lt;2&gt; I »&gt; (1) g SSSt One above 1 I I .1 + 0) j — _ |- 8 rooms O.K. above 1 — - . , ------ R.W.K. above I.I I I - — I -' Gas above III I I ! - ""• Seventeen shades in 1. rooms with one or two lamps shaded. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes Table 10. — Illumination in foot-candles on horizontal plane at indicated distances from different lamps as measured in test room j Illumination in foot-candies At 3.3 feet At 5.7 feet At 7.3 feet At edge of At edce of _ from lamp from lamp from lamp table 42 table 52 LBm '~ inches in inches in diameter diameter with lamp with lamp at center at center O.K. (unshaded) Less minimum ;. 0.22 0.17 than 0.1 1.2 0.9 maximum 0.28 0.18 0.12 1.8 | 1.1 R.W.K. (unshaded) ■■■■ 0.6 0.45 0.25 3.5 2.0 Gas (shaded) ! minimum ' ....[• 0.7 0.45 0.22 8.0 5.0 i maximum l....| 0.9 ■ 0.5 0.25 8.0 5.5 Table 11, — Illumination in foot-candles required and recom - mended in different places and for different kinds of work. Extracted from "Code of Lighting Factories, Mills, and. Other Work Places" or from "Code of Lighting School . Buildings" Minimum foot-candles on the - ■, space or at the work Space or type of work Required ] Recommended | Where discrimination of detail is not | essential — hallways, stairways, etc | 0.5 1.0 to 2.0 I ' I • Where close discrimination of detail is es- I sential — office work, accounting, typing, meat packing (cleaning, cutting, cook - ing) , baking, roasting i 3.0 5.0 to 10.0 Where discrimination of minute detail is essential — sewing | on dark material ) 5^ 10.0 to 20.0 Class study rooms I I 5_) 10.0 ■ • I Sewing ■ 8.0 15.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">i Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 in this study, but we """"--^ have other authorities' w^ \ ; figures as to allowable y\ \ , &gt;^ brightness of light / I ' \ sources, which do apply. / \ Walsh (19) says that it L \ \ \ is generally agreed that ( - \ . , „^ ) a brightness of 3 to 5 \ ' \ I / candles per square inch V--. x\\; /- --"'/ should not be exceeded 2s_ ''ZiZZ-'-" / in any source, shade, or Z ~r^-^i=' reflector which the eye /_.. : \ is. likely to see by direct . t .' . v 'j vision. Bell (2) says it \y J is well to avoid any bril - 7^ Z liancy over 2 or 3 candles \ / per square inch. \ , / A comparison of the \ / conditions of illumina - \ , / tion found in Nebraska \^ i Z rural homes without gas F.o. -,. Distribution of li_ht from the easoline Or electric light With the readinir lamp in horizontal plane passim: thru standards given abOVe the liirht source. Reproduced by permission . .^ _i._ _.-...-_ U or l li.-t.f from Bui. 55. Iowa EnKineerin. Experiment maniieSIS Veiy DaQ Ugni- Station. " LilshtinK for Country Homes and \r\cr Dl'actice Village Communities," by Wm. Kunerth. Y -.. r\ i In Fig. 8 are shown the foot-candles required and recommended for work of the kind that is done in the kitchen and the foot-candles, as measured in the test room, which are received from the different lamps at the kitchen work centers when these are at the mean distances from the lamp, as found in this study. It should be remembered that the ratio of kitchens lighted by one ordinary kerosene lamp to those lighted by one better lamp is nearly 2 to 1, as shown in Fig. 3. Fig. 9 shows the foot-candles required and recommended for the work done in sitting rooms. It gives also the foot - candles received from different lamps, as measured in the test room, at the edge of a table 42 inches in diameter and at the edge of a table 52 inches in diameter with the lamp placed in the center of the table. As stated before there are nearly 4 times as many sitting rooms lighted by a lamp better than the ordinary kerosene lamp as are lighted by the latter. In the majority of cases, this lamp is on a table, and if it is an ordinary kerosene lamp or a round-wick kerosene lamp it is unshaded, but if it is a gasoline lamp it is shaded, as is shown in Fig. 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Lighting of Nebraska Rural Homes Only 61 per cent of the gasoline lamps and only 28 per cent of all lamps |are shaded; therefore, there is a great deal of glare in these kitchens and sitting rooms. All the un - shaded lamps within the range of vision are glaring. Many of the lamps above eye level are still within the ordinary range of vision, j Assuming that none of the shaded lamps produces glare and that there is no glare from lamps above the eye level, 63 per cent of all the lamps are glaring; assum - ing that half of |the lamps above eye level are within the range of vision, 77 per cent of all the lamps are glaring. The diffusion and distribution of light depend largely upon the shading and upon the number of the light sources. With the inadequate shading disclosed by this study and with the * large proportion 'of rooms lighted by one lamp only, it is evident that the diffusion and distribution are poor. Better illumination, including more light on the work areas, a subdued general illumination, and a reduction of the T • J. _ » — » t ° t I s-J mn i. ii is it ■; 'Si IjMl |||.;l Hi.*. __J_J mill Mil I _cm coat &lt;v.woij. tabic on btovb oaj sink. Fio. 8. Contrast between the foot-candles required and recommended by light - ing code and those received in kitchens lighted by kerosene and gasoline lamps. The first Bection ol the chart shows the foot-candles required and recommended by j" Code of Lighting Factories, Mills, and Other Work Places" for the type of work done in the kitchen. The other sections show the foot-candles received at the worktable, stove, and sink when these are distant from the lamp 3.3 feet, 6.7 feet, and 7.3 feet respectively and the lamp is on a table. The distances from the iamp are the mean distances found in this study. Minima and maxima of illumination are given because the- distribution on a horizontal plane of light from the ordinary kerosene] and from the gasoline lamp is not the same in all directions from the lamp. The foot-candies charted in the second, third, and fourth sections were those measured in the test room described in the text . ■ . </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 glare, may be secured in these rural Nebraska kitchens by placing an ordinary kerosene lamp, which is the one most frequently used, above the head and using a suitable shade. A table lamp may be set upon a high shelf but there are bracket and hanging kerosene lamps which may be used. One of the higher-candle-power lamps above the eye level and so shaded that the flame or mantle is out of the range of vision w o u 1 d im- prove the kitchen M lighting still fur- __ ther. There are fl gaso line bracket and banging lamps 7 so designed that the fount is against the _ wall or ceiling and, therefore, its shad- _ ow is out of the F| way. These are „ 4 some what better j _ than the gasoline z _ e = fl - « 5 table lamp for use y s _ : ! E f * e f above the head. In | x a » £ _ | * _ | _ f general, no one 2 £ c e _ *. &lt; _ $ lamp, even if of suf- 5 0 * ZL z £ f i c i e n t candle s g . [7*. 55 power, can 1 i g h t 0 | | | |o|o| 0 | j| a | HoM^rl satisfactorily all coot &lt;m«. 1/1 table oh « m table the WOl'k places in Flo. 1&gt;. Contrast between the font-candles required and ,_,... Af _,„_, recommended by lighting rode and those received in the KltCnen. At Olie, houses lighted by kern.enc and gasoline lumps. The r». at mm- o nf tVlpm first section of the chart shows the foot -candles re - or at moie 01 ine..., tecommrriAr , A by -c.»de of Lighting f.c no matter Where lories, Mills, and Other Work Places.'' for work in tha lirrVlt io nlafprl which discrimination of minute detail is necessary, tne llgnt IS pidCetl, .. jn „, win( , „„,, real) j ni ,. The second and third the WOrk Surface sections of the chart show the foot-candles received .... 1 , 11 at the edge of a table .2 inches in diameter and of Will De SnaOOWeCl D,\ „ n( . 59 inches in diameter from different lnmps placed the Worker Stand- at '^ center of each table. Minima and maxima of • _• •_ i.1- illumination are given because the distribution on a ing before it", there- horizontal plane, of light from the ordinary kerosene fn,.rs o o_.r./.nr) lomn and from the gasoline lamp is not the same in all IOie, J SeCOIlU Idllip directions from the lamp. The foot-candles charted iS needed. PrOPel'IV in the second and third sections were those measured , , , , ' u !_._' in the test room described in the text. shaded lamps below the eye level may be used with satisfactory results, but in most kitchens more than 2 lamps below eye level would be necessary to meet good lighting standards. A shade on a lamp increases the amount of light below the horizontal plane passing thru the light source and when the lamp is above the eye level in a room of ordinary size it provides a better distribution of light, concentrating it in </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Lighting op Nebraska Rural Homes that part of the room which is occupied. In many cases an unbreakable metal shade may be used upon a lamp placed above the head, for when in this position it is not often neces - sary that any light pass thru the shade. The inner surface of any shade useid on a lamp in this position should have a high reflection factor in order to direct as much light as pos - sible into the lower part of the room. The light source in - a shaded lamp above eye level, or even below it, may still be within the range \ of vision and therefore glaring. One large company manufacturing gasoline lamps has done some ex - perimenting with diffusing bowls in an effort to hide com - pletely the light source of the lamp when it is above the head. At the present time, however, they have not been able to make this practical. A shade on a lamp below the eye level, while increasing j the illumination in the space immediately around and below it, lessens it at other points in the lower occupied part of; the room. Almost all the shaded gasoline lamps found in this study have an opal shade, the brightness - of which is within the permissible limit. Altho this shade concentrates the greater part of the light into the space below it, enough passes thru to give a ground work of light in which to see ione's way about. Such a shade as this is desirable when there is only one lamp and it is placed on a table. To improve the illumination of the sitting rooms, the lamp in every case should be shaded and if one properly shaded lamp does not give a background of illumination high enough to secure convenience or if one reading center is not enough, there should be an additional lamp or two. With the low beilings found in many houses, it is impos - sible to put kerosene or gasoline lamps above the head be - cause of the heatj they radiate. This is unfortunate, for more lamps are required to light properly a room when the light sources are below eye level than when there is overhead lighting to give, • if not all the light, the general background of illumination which is desirable. City dwellers and presumably rural people who use electric light suffer also ifrom poor illumination, sometimes from in - sufficient light, and frequently from glare due to improperly shaded lamps (14, 16). If those who use kerosene and gaso - line lamps learn! to use them correctly, thfey will benefit by better lighting from these sources, and consequently by better eyesight (3, 4, 5, 7, 15) and by better health (1, 17, 20). Besides this, when electric light is made available for them they will be more likely to make proper use of it, for the principles of good lighting are the same no matter what is the source of illumination. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 225 literature cited 1. Abbott, Gladys: A Study of Posture in School as Affected by School Room Lighting. Amer. Phys. Ed. Rev., Vol. 10, p. 36. 1905. 2. Bell, Louis-. The Art of Illumination. 2nd Ed. 11*12. 3. Cobb, Percv W.: Some Experiments on the Speed of Vision. Ilium. Engin. Soc. Trans., Vol. 19, p. 150. 1924. 4. Cobb, Percy W., and Moss, Frank K.: The Effects of Brightness on the Precision of Visually Controlled Operations. Jour. Franklin Institute, Vol. 199, p. 507. Apr., 1925. 5. Cobb, Percy W., and Moss, Frank K.: Eye Fatigue and Its Relation to Light and Work. Jour. Franklin Institute, Vol. 200, p. 239. Aug., 1925. 6. Ferry, Ervin S.: General Physics. 1921. 7. Ives, James K., and Sydenstricker. Edgar: Studies in Regard to thi- Lighting of Postoffices, Made bv the U. S. Public Health Service. Jour. Indus. Hyg., Vol. 8, p. 232. May, 1926. 8. Illuminating Engineering Society: Code of Lighting Factories, Mills, and Other Work Places. U. S. Bur. of Labor Statis., Bui. N'o. 331. 1923. 9. Illuminating Engineering Society: Code of Lighting School Build - ings. U. S. Bur. of Labor Statis., Bui. No. 382. 1925. 10. Kunerth, Wm.: Illuminating Power of Kerosenes. Iowa Engineer - ing Expt. Sta., Bui. N'o. 37. 1914. 11. Kunerth, Wm. : Lighting for Country Homes and Village Com - munities. Iowa Engineering Expt. Sta., Bui. 55. 1919. *" 12. Lansingh, V. R..- Walls and Floor, Their Effect on Lighting. Ilium. Engin. Soc. Trans., Vol. 15. p. 124. 1920. 13. Lansingh, V. R.. and Rolph, T. W.: Some Experiments on Reflec - tions from Ceiling, Walls, and Floor. IUum. Engin. Soc. Trar.s.. Vol. 3, p. 584. 1908. 14. Luckiesh. M.: A Survev of Residence Lighting. IUum. Engin. Soc. Trans., Vol. 17. p. 510. 1922. 15. Luckiesh, M., and Moss. Frank: The Rate of Visual Work on Alternating Fields of Different Brightnesses. Jour. Franklin In - stitute. Vol. 200, p. 731. Dec. 1925. 16. MacDonald, Norman D.: Lighting Statistics of Representative Urban and Suburban Homes. IUum. Engin. Soc. Trans., Vol. 17, p. 488. 1922. 17. Ohm, J.: Kurze Darstellung der Ergebnisse meiner Augenzettern - forschung. Med. Klin., Vol. 21, p. 839. June, 1925. 18. Sharp, Clayton, and Millar, H. Preston: Illumination Tests. IUum. Engin. Soc. Trans., Vol. 5, p. 391. 1910. 19. Walsh, J. W. T. : Photometry and Illumination in Glazebrook. Dictionary of Applied Physics, Vol. 4, p. 410. 1923. 20. Westcott, Cassius D.: Eyestrain, Its Cause and How to Avoid It. Hygeia, Vol. 4, p. 44. Jan., 1926. (5M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>