<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eleventh Biennial Report OF THE COMMANDANT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Eleventh Biennial Report OF THE COMMANDANT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENMUM ENDING NOVEMBER 80. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">190 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions,' Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I have the honor to submit the Eleventh Biennial re - port of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home of Milford, Ne - braska. In beginning this report I wish to express my grati tude to the all-wise Frovidence, for His goodness in preserv ing the members of this home. PHYSICAL CONDITION The conditions existing in the home and among the members are the best I have ever known. When the new well is finished we will have an abundant supply of the very best water. The food is of the best and very well cooked. I have bought 30 new beds and 39 new springs and have had 48 mattresses renovated and pur - chased 30 new ones, so the beds are in the best of condition. The plumbing has all been overhauled and is now in first class condition and I have installed another boiler in the heating plant which will give us plenty of heat. The new hospital building is now under way and when finished will give room for about 60 inmates and will be a mod - ern and fire proof building. The main building is in need of repairs such as new floors, painting and minor improve - ments. The hospital is under the management of Dr. J. C. Muir, who is very successful in treating the ailments of men. DISCIPLINE The proper administration of discipline in the insti - tution is always more or less difficult. The inordinate use of intoxicants is the most serious disturbance we find in the home. I think the stand I took in regard to the drinking </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 191 has had a good deal to do with the peace and good will of the home. There are many men and women in the home who appreciate all that the State and nation is doing for them and do all they can to make the home a haven of rest. This institution does not attempt to do much farming outside of gardening truck, such as green corn, field corn, potatoes, cabbages, cucumbers, lettuce, beets, onions, rad - tlishes, etc. In favorable seasons we have fruit such as apples, grapes, pears, and plums. The pigs eat refuse of the tables which is almost enough to keep them and I have raised about 150 bushels of corn this biennium which will be plenty for the hogs and horses. When hogs are sold the money goes to the cash fund of the institution. The garden truck, fruit, etc., is used for the home. I wish to acknowledge in this connection the receipts of gifts to the men in the hospital, and in the home, of the good things from the W. R. C. of the State ; these things are always thankfully received and appreciated. NEEDS OF THE HOME I recommend that the following amounts be appro- priated to meet the necessary expenses of the institution for the next biennium. Maintenance (including board, clothing, bed and bedding, farm and stock, fuel, lights, elec - trical supplies, drugs, medicine, telephone and telegraph, express, freight, postage, printing stationery, improvements of grounds and transportation) $50,000.00 Officers' salaries 5,800.00 Employees' wages 9,612.00 Nurses &amp; Chaplain 2,040.00 General repairs 11,000.00 New building 10,000.00 Total : $88,452.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 192 I have asked for $10,000.00 for a new building for laun- dry. The old building is not large enough for the present population of the home and is in very bad shape and we should have an up-to-date laundry so as to take care of the increase of the population of this institution. The main building is in need of repairs badly such as new floors, painting inside and outside, also the standpipe and fire escape, and there are lots of minor improvements. POPULATION M. F. T. Number of members Dec. 1, 1912 135 11 146 Number received since 73 8 81 Number discharged or died 82 2 84 Number on roll Nov. 30, 1914 126 17 143 GARDEN PRODUCE AND LIVE STOCK List of garden truck and other product raised by the home: Corn 214 bu. at $ .55 per bu $128.20 Potatoes 550 bu. at .70 per bu 385.00 Beets 50 bu. at .45 per bu 22.50 Turnips 40 bu. at .45 per bu 18.00 Tomatoes 20 bu. at .50 per bu 10.00 Onions 15 bu. at 1.00 per bu 15.00 Cabbage 450 hd. at .05 per hd 22.50 Cucumbers 25 bu. at .60 per bu 15.00 Total $616.20 Lettuce enough for the use of the home during the season. Six large hogs value $240.00 Seven pigs at $5.00 each 35.00 $275.00 Sold one hot water heater to Asylum for the Insane of Nebraska at Ingleside for $200, money to go in cash fund. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 198 SURGEON'S REPORT Col. D. C. Rowden, Commandant, Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, MUford, Nebraska, Dear Sir: I have the honor to make the following report as sur - geon of this home for the biennium ending November 30, 1914. There has been an average of twenty patients in the hospital for this time, with chronic trouble mostly and some with acute diseases. The hospital is in a good sanitary condition at this time, being in charge of a nurse and assistant nurse, who are very kind and considerate of the old men and women in their charge. I wish to thank the officers and employees and patients for the courtesy shown me during this time. Respectfully yours, James C. Muir, Surgeon. MUford, Nebraska, November SO, 191k- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">194 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total to to Nov. 30 for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium M F T M FT MFT MFT Present at begin- ning of period 108 11 119 77 14 91 67 16 83 108 11 119 Admitted: Readmitted* 1 1 6 6 7 7 For first time 22 5 27 21 21 23 2 25 66 7 73 Transferred from other institutions Returned from furlough granted before commence- ment of period 325 55 10 213 10 8 18 Totals 134 18 152 103 19 122 98 19 117 191 26 217 Discharged : Honorably 19 19' 13 13 22 1 23 54 1 55 Summarily ...; Transferred to other institutions Died 12 12 2 2 14 14 28 28 On furlough Nov. 30, 1914 26 4 30 21 3 24 17 5 22 64 12 76 Totals 57 4 61 36 3 39 53 6 59 146 13 159 Remaining at end of period 77 14 91 67 16 83 45 13 58 45 13 58 Average number in Home_ 131 14 145 13 313 146 127 13 140 391 40 431 'Includes all who have been previously admitted to this or a similar in- stitution. TABLE II. AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year AGE AT ADMIS- Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total SION Nov. 30 for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Under 30 years 30 and under 40 40 and under 50 50 and under 60 2 2 2 2 ..._ 4 4 60 and under 70 43 7 50 30 7 37 35 6 41 108 20 128 70 and under 80 60 2 62 70 2 72 80 10 90 210 14 224 80 and under 90 ... 5 5 2 2 7 Over 90 Totals. 108 11 119 102 11 118 116 16 131 325 38 363 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 195 TABLE III. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 CIVIL STATUS Dec. 1, 12 to June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 ending Nov. 30 1914 ToUl for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T Single Married . Widowed Divorced Separated Unknown 76 76 53 30 83 24 8 32 Totals . 153 38 191 For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 NATIVITY Dec. 1, 12 to June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,'13 ending Nov. 30 1914 Total for Biennium M F M F T M F T M F T Nebraska United States, other than Nebraska Total native born Canada England Germany Ireland Norway Switzerland Total foreign born Unknown 1 ..._. 1 _ ' 132 37 169 133 37 170 2 2 _ 1 ..._. 1 8 8 _ 4 4 _ 2 13 I 2 2 19 1 20 1 ...... 1 Totals 153 38 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">196 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE V. PREVIOUS OCCUPATIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED Totals for Biennium Nov. 30, '14 M F T OCCUPATION Brick layers 3 3 Butchers 2 2 2 2 Bookkeepers Blacksmiths 2 2 8 8 Carpenters Cooks 1 1 Conductors - 1 1 Engineers 8 8 Farmers _ 65 66 Gardeners 3 3 Insurance agents 1 1 Laborers _ 16 16 Linemen 1 1 Masons _ _ 1 1 Musicians _ 1 1 No occupation 13 13 Painters 6 6 Physicians _ 1 1 Plasterers 1 1 Publishers 1 1 Salesmen 1 1 Shoemakers 1 1 Teamsters 1 1 Teachers - - - 1 1 Telesrraph operators 1 1 Tailors 1 1 Housewives 17 17 Totals 126 17 143 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 197 TABLE VI. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM All COUNTY Remaining Nov. 30, '14 M F T Adams 2 2 Butler 3 3 Boyd Burt ...- 1 1 8 3 Buffalo _ ZZ'Z ~ 1 Cuming cuming _ . 1 1 Custer 1 J T - - 1 f 1 Clay &gt; ! 1 Dixon uixon t ■ DoutfM ZIZZZZZZL__ 28 " "i 24 Dodge 3 m «S Franklin franklin Gage ".." 2 2 Garfield 1 1 Hall _ Holt _ 5 16 HOlt _ _ _ __ 1 Hamilton i i 1 1 Kearney Kearney _. Lancaster Z_ "™ 41 ""£ ah if nca « ter - 41 5 46 Nemaha a c Memaha _ g g Otoe ". ! J~i o Otoe 1(11 Platte _ 9 9 , - — - 2 2 Richardson _ _ ZZ Seward _ ic 7 99 g e * art » , - - 16 7 23 Saline _ 1 1 - _ __. 1 1 Saunders _ "Zll-Z.."" Thurston 1 ""V 9 ihurston 119 York Z_ " ~~ 11 1 1 Johnson o " "V q TotaU 126 17 143 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">198 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII. NATURE OF SERVICE ON WHICH ADMISSION IS BASED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total SERVICE tu to Nov. 30 for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT I. War in which enlisted : Civil war _ - - 122 17 139 Spanish-American. war _ ... 3 8 Philippine Insur- rection — 1 1 Totals - _..- 126 17 143 II. Division of Service: Regulars _ 12 12 Volunteers 114 114 Totals _ - 126 126 Artillery ..._ i 4 4 Cavalry - 27 27 Engineers Hospital service Infantry _. 96 . — 96 Navy &amp; Marine. Totals _ 126 126 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 199 TABLE VIII. STATES OF ENLISTMENT OF MEN ADMITTED OR OF HUSBAND OR SON OF WOMEN ADMITTED Totals for STATES OF ENLISTMENT Biennium Connecticut 1 California 1 Illinois ' 32 Indiana I 15 Iowa „ 20 Massachusetts 1 Maine I 2 Michigan I 1 Minnesota 4 Maryland 1 Missouri 8 New Hampshire. 2 New York 8 New Mexico 1 New Jersey 1 Nebraska 5 Ohio ! 6 Pennsylvania ' 7 Vermont 1 Wisconsin _ ; 126 TABLE IX. AGES AT DEATH For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total AGE to Nov. 30 for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Under 40 years. 40 and under 50. 50 and under 60 60 and under 70 _ - — 2 2 70 and under 80 - -. ..... 14 14 80 and under 90 4 4 Over 90 years _ - 8 8 4 . 4 Over 90 years Totals - '.._ 23 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">200 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X. PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOME OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING B1ENN1UM For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year PERIOD OF Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending ToUl RESIDENCE to to Nov. 30 for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFTMFT Less than six mos. From 5 to 12 mos. , S ...Z. " t From 1 to 2 years _ _. I 8 8 From 2 to 5 years _ I 5 5 From 6 to 10 year* , _ I 6 6 From 10 to 15 yrs _ _ | 1 1 6 6 TABLE XI. CAUSE OF DEATH NAME AGE CAUSE Armel, James L I 76 Drowning Btck, En.anuel .._...' 91 |Old Age Carpenter, Henry _J 78 Paralysis Old Age Gangrene Churchill, John N 77 _.. Culp, Benjamin 79 Faurot, Jacob P ' 74 Bladder Trouble Paralysis Hart, John _ 1 82 _.. Hendryx, Thomas 70 Bladder Trouble Old Age Jackson, James J I 87 Jones, Sylvester | 92 Old Age Knight, Evan T 71 _.. Cancer, Liver McVey, Reuben 72 Cancer, Stomach Syphilis Mein, Richard _ 70 Mitchell, Aaron 73 Bladder Trouble Apoplexy Moore, Henry 74 Paine, Charles H 75 Paralysis Drowning Gangrene Old Age Patterson, John _ 83 _ Pratt, George 72 Soper, Lyman _ 83 Bladder Trouble Gangrene Studebaker, William 67 Thatcher, Isaac 79 Ulch. Simon P _ 69 Van Ness. Ralph _... 93 Old Age Old Age Van Ness. Ralph </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 201 In closing this report I wish to thank the governor of the State, Hon. John H. Morehead, for the courtesy he has at all times shown me as commandant of this home and the interest he has taken in the general superintendency of the institution, also to the members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions in looking after the supplies that have been furnished and in granting every request that I have asked at their hands. I am also under obligations to the subordinate officers and employees for the faithfulness that they have shown in the discharge of their duties. I also wish to thank the members of this home for their good behavior. I have the honor to be, Very truly yours, D. C. Rowden, Commandant. Milford, Nebraska, November 30, 191 U • </seg>
            <seg id="p014">• </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>