<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  COOPERATIVE COUNTY FARM DEMONSTRATORS</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Distributed March 13, 1913. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. COOPERATIVE By C. W. Pugsley and A. E. Anderson I "he Farm Demonstration Work in Nebraska is conducted the University of Nebraska, the local County Farm Manage tit Association and the Bureau of Plant Industry. United tes Department of Agriculture, cooperating. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. PUGSLEY, Superintendent. COUNTY I ARM l)KM&lt; &gt;XSTRATORS </seg>
            <seg id="p002">1. Alfalfa Management. I Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska. Testing Seed Corn. I Cooking and Sewing (Boys' and Girls' Clubs). Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle (Boys' and Clubs). Part II.— Corn. I Part III.— The Home Garden. Spraying Apple Trees. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. I Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn. ■ Organization of Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. 12. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. Growing Potatoes. The above bulletins will be sent free to residents of Nebraska upon request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Farm Demonstrators 3 COOPERATIVE COUNTY FARM DEMONSTRATORS BThe Cooperative County Farm Demonstrator is a man of ctical farm experience having an agricultural education, rking under the joint direction of the farmers, the Univer sity of Nebraska and the United States Department of Agri - culture, whose duty shall be to promote all interests of an agricultural nature. In cooperation with the farmers, and under actual farm conditions, he shall assist in determining the best farm practices adapted to the community. He shall make public and spread over the county the best practices of the most successful farmers in the county. He is not an "advisor" or "agricultural expert." He is a cooperator. It shall be one of his duties, however, to give or secure expert B&gt;rmation for farmers who desire it, since he is familiar or n touch with the latest work of the various State Experi - lt Stations and the United States Department of Agriculure. is in the county to study its farm problems. THE NEED OF DEMONSTRATION WORK. I Every county has agricultural problems which are distinct local in character. The solutions to some of these prob - s may be found in the work of Experiment Stations or in methods used by some individual farmer. The entire com - lity should be interested not only in finding the solutions in putting them into practical operation. I Not only do distinct problems exist in each section but it lso true that many farms are not tilled as well as they should This is doubtless partly due to a lack of knowledge of the t farm practices on the part of the farmers. Efforts are stantly being made through bulletins, agricultural papers, mers' Institutes and Short Courses to acquaint every farmer h the results of experiments which might be of benefit to him, only a comparatively small number can ever be effectively ched through these agencies. In these methods there is king in a large degree two very important considerations, nely familiarity with local conditions and continued personal tact with the farmers. One suggested method of bringing the work home to the community is by the establishment of a Demonstration Farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 This method, while it permits the man in charge to become familiar in some degree with local conditions and also to come in personal contact with some of the farmers in a community, does not furnish an ideal method of demonstration work. There always exists in the minds of the farmers a suspicion that farm equipment and .supplies may be bought cheaper, or produce sold higher than is possible with the individual farmer It is also known that the man in charge is especially qualified for the work and there is a feeling that he should succeed under such conditions. The farm belonging to the state is set apart from the general farms of the community and the people do not feel that it is operated on the same basis as their own. A dem onstration farm to be of the most influence must necessarilv be a paying proposition. This is almost impossible, since a part of its work should be to determine the proper varieties to grow in the community and to demonstrate poor practice^ as well as good ones. If the superintendent of such a farm makes a success of the farm, he will have little time t&lt;&gt; &gt;tud' - actual farming conditions as they exist in the community. It is altogether possible that some of the farm practices that have been pmven of great advantage at the central Experi - ment Station or at Sab-stations may be of greater or less ad - vantage in other sections of the state. Nebraska is four hun - dred and fifty miles long and two hundred and seven mild wide. It has a growing season nearly live weeks longer in the southeastern corner of the state than in the northwestern cor - ner. Its elevation varies from eight hundred and fifty feet t" five thousand three hundred feet. Its annual rainfall varies from sixteen inches in the western part to thirty-two inches in the eastern. It has several distinct soil regions and many soil types within these regions. While it is true that these variations exist it is also true that the general principles underlying the practices of agri - culture can best be determined at experiment stations within general large districts. Xebraska now has a central station and four sub-stations covering the principal soil regions. I' would be a very heavy and useless expense to attempt to put Experiment Stations with adequate equipment for the study of general principles of agriculture in each county, and thf same reasoning will apply to demonstration farms, provided some more effective system of demonstration work can be undertaken. Demonstration work to be effective should be undertaken on farms and carried on under actual farming conditions. To </seg>
            <seg id="p005">be educational these demonstrations' must be seen and under - stood by the farmers of the community. They must, of course, be carried on under the supervision of a demonstrator with an agricultural education and practical farm experience. A plan of demonstration work which it is believed wil' accomplish such results is comparatively simple. It was tried with splendid success in Merrick County in 1912 and so is not mere theory. The farmers and business men in the vicinity of Central City hired for seven months during last summer, a Nebraska farm boy who was a graduate of the Agriculaural College. His duty was, and the duty of all Farm Demon - strators will be to cooperate in every way possible with the farmers of the community to determine the best argicultura! practices. THE DEMONSTRATOR'S DUTIES. The Demonstrator does not come to the community as an expert knowing all things about agriculture, neither does he come as an adviser to tell the farmers exactly what must be done. He comes as a cooperator who has had the advantage of an agricultural education together with practical farm ex - perience. He can reasonably be expected to know the latest published results of the experiments at the Nebraska Station and other Stations. After he has familiarized himself with these, and with existing conditions in the county, if he feels that they are applicable to the community in which he is work - ing, he will secure cooperators from among the members of the County Farm Management Association and make tests of the recommended practices. One particular advantage of this sort of work is that the farmers do not need to change in any marked degree their prac - tices while the demonstration is in progress. For example, the Nebraska Experiment Station at Lincoln has reported that tests covering a period of five years have shown that the roll - ing of winter wheat early in the spring with a heavy land roller has given an average annual increased yield of five bush - els per acre. The Farm Demonstrator may find that a good many people in his county do not believe in rolling winter wheat. He approaches Farmer A on the subject and finds that a trial was made a few years ago, but Farmer A thought it was not successful because he did not secure as large a yield as his neighbor did in the adjoining field. He lost sight of the fact that his neighbor's erround might have been richer, that </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Farm Demonstrators L 1 1 C sCt U III 1 1 III I Id * C LJ(T t II LJ 1 till I sz vl d L cL vl 1 11 v I t II I 1 1 1 11C » Ul 1 1 1&lt;* L it might have been of a different variety. The Demonstrator calls his attention to the fact that a test to be accurate must have all conditions alike except the practice being tested: therefore he asks Farmer A to treat his entire forty acre field of winter wheat as he thinks best, with the exception of an acre or a five acre strip through the center of the field. This strip will be rolled and the rolling will be the only difference in the treatment it receives compared with the treatment given the rest of the field. When harvesting time comes, this strip is harvested separately and the yield will tell the story. I The Demonstrator then approaches Farmer C, who also a field of winter wheat and finds that Farmer C believes •oiling. He will probably find that no accurate test has ever n made, so he asks Farmer C, who has agreed to cooperate, roll all of his field but a strip down through the center, len harvest time comes the yield will also tell the story of treatment there. With quite a number of the men in the nty making this test and with records kept on the cost of ling, it can be determined beyond the question of a doubt that year at least, what the effect of rolling wheat is in t community. With results covering a period of several .rs that particular farm practice can be settled. The advantage of this sort of a demonstration is that the farmer himself is doing the work under his own farm condi - tions ; that he knows whether it is practical or not ; that he becomes intensely interested himself and that all the neighbors become interested. When the results are published by means of meetings and through the papers, everybody in the country learns what that particular style of treatment will do for the wheat crop, and has confidence in the results because the men carrying on the work are neighboring farmers. The same method of procedure can be applied to the preparation of seed beds, cultivation of crops, seeding of small grains, variety tests of grains, pruning and care of orchards, and practically every line of crop production. In all of these special lines of work in seeking for the best practices the Demonstrator will follow the directions and methods suggested by the heads of the vari - ous departments at the Experiment Station. Thus he will have the advantage of the advice of the experts on all difficult problems. This work also lends itself nicely to demonstrations with certain treatment for plant diseases, such as potato scab and smut on small grains. Treatments can be given and a portion </seg>
            <seg id="p007">- of the field planted with treated seed and a portion planted with untreated. If the treatment is not worth while, it can easily be determined by comparing the harvested crop from the different portions of the held where all conditions have been the same except the one being tested. In live stock work it becomes the duty of the Farm Demon - strator to assist in every way possible in determining the best methods for the feed and care of live stock. With his technical education he should be able to determine what rations will be the best adapted to existing conditions. He can either organize associations to bring into the county pure bred sires or locate good sires which are already in the county, thus improving in a series of years the quality of the live stock. He can aid in the marketing of live stock by inducing farmers to cooperate in their shipments so that carloads can be shipped instead of marketing in smaller quantities and thus receiving smaller prices. He can suggest to the dairymen of the community the advantage of all producing the same kind of live stock that they may have a better market for their increase, and that they may have a better chance to use the very best of sires. It has been determined by the testing associations that many cows which were regarded as good cows did not even pay for the cost of the feed they consumed. He can make tests of a few herds of cows and thus demonstrate the importance of organiz - ing cow testing associations in dairy communities. It will be the duty of the Farm Demonstrator to watch for certain diseases among the farm animals. It is not expected that he will be able to treat many of these diseases, but in the case of some of them he can be of great service to the com - munity. For example, if he sees a herd of hogs that show - cholera symptoms he should make every effort to determine whether they have cholera, even if it is necessary to take a licensed veterinarian out to see the herd. If cholera exists he should put the matter before the committee of the Associa - tion that steps may be taken to have the herd vaccinated and that all possible precaution may be taken to prevent the spread of the disease. In the case of the outbreak of a strange disease, such as the horse disease last year, the farmers of the com - munity can reasonably expect the Farm Demonstrator in co operation with competent veterinarians to secure accurate in - formation as to the best treatment of such a disease and thus prevent money being squandered on fake treatments. The Demonstrator in visiting farms in all parts of the coun - ty, learns of men having seeds or breeding animals that they </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 wirt to sell, lie also come, in contact with othets who with to buy. He can be the means of getting the buver in touch with tman who has the articles for sale. He can also be a medium getting persons looking for work in touch with farmer* &gt; want to hire help. I Another phase of his work will be arranging for meetings the county where agricultural subjects will be discussed, the results on a certain farm warrant the calling of the peo - together to view the treatments being tested, a picnic can held and the matter discussed in detail. These local meet - fi should mean much to the community and in many instances mid lead to the organization of local farmers' clubs, — hav - [ as their object social as well as material benefits. The tension office will look to the County Farm Demonstrator make the final and complete arrangements for various agri - tural meetings to be held in the county. He would be better ilified than any other one person to determine the best places • holding these meetings and the nature of the subjects which &gt;uld be discussed. DIRECTION OF THE WORK iThe work should be under the direction of interested citi - s of the county and the State Leader of demonstration rk. University of Nebraska. To make this possible a County m Management Association should be formed. A consti - on for such an association appears at the end of this bulle- The executive committee of the association composed of president, a vice president from each township and a sec - iry-treasurer, have charge of the work within the county ject to the will of the association. FINANCES I The money is to be raised by membership dues and sub - iptions from interested parties. It is expected that if the rk proves of value it will eventually be provided for by i inty Fund. To prove the merits of the plan, however, it 1 be necessary at first to raise the money by subscription, property owners in the county should be interested an-i iuld be willing to aid. What benefits agricultural condi - ns benefits all. At least one railroad in the state offers t ) • towards the work $3.00 for each mile of its road in a county. a minimum of $150 per county annually. This is on condi- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 tion that an association be formed and money provided for at least two years work. All subscriptions should be taken on a two-year basis or for a longer time. Subscription blanks will be sent by the Kxtension Department upon request. In so far as possible, the United States Department of Agri - culture through the University of Nebraska will aid such county work by paying $100 per month or less, on condition that the County Farm Management Association raise at least an equal amount. The funds raised for the work are to provide for the fol - lowing expenses: 1. Office. It will be necessary for the man to have a per - manent office in some central location. He should be in the office on one certain day of each week. There should be in this office a telephone and a small amount of equipment. For example, he should have a Babcock tester for making butterfat tests of milk and cream. He should have apparatus for deter - mining moisture contents of soils, as this will help him in in - terpreting certain results that are secured in some of the test&gt; He should also be equipped to make certain other simple, phys - ical soil tests. He should have an incubator for testing th&lt;? germination of various seeds and needs a microscope for some of his work. It will be necessary to have a certain amount of printing done and some suitable filing cases. It is quite possi - ble that an office could be found at the Court House or in some public building, so that the cost of renting an office would be saved to the association. The office should if possible be in the count v seat town or in some other accessable location. 2. Material. The Association will sometimes find it nec - essary to purchase certain seeds for making variety tests ; it may be considered wise to purchase some machines for trial and in the case of some diseases the association may consider it policy to buy certain serums or medicines in an effort to stamp out a disease before it has done serious damage. It may occasionally be necessary to bring some plant or animal expert to the county for consultation. 3. Transportation Expenses. It is necessary for the asso - ciation to furnish transportation facilities. The most satisfac - tory method of transportation and the one followed by the counties at present employing Farm Demonstrators is for the association to buy and to keep the title to a runabout or an automobile. This car need not be an expensive one, but the value of the man to the county will be more than doubled by this rapid means of transportation If the man for anv reason </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ... does not stay in the county for a term of years, the car is owned by the association and ready for the use of the next Demonstrator. In Merrick County an effort was made at the beginning to cover the county on horseback. This was found unsatisfactory and a runabout was purchased. It is better to get a car a little larger than a runabout, because it is often necessary to take somebody around the county in carrying on the work of the association. 14. Salary. It is, of course, necessary to pay a salary to Farm Demonstrator. This salary will depend upon the ilifications of the man secured. He should be familiar with ictical farm problems; preferably one who has spent most his life on a Nebraska farm. He must necessarily have had advantage of a full agricultural course in an Agricultural liege. He must have a pleasing personality and a thorough ierstanding of his work. He must meet the approval of the :cutive committee of the association before he will be placed a county to conduct the work. The salary of such a man, ;ed on salaries paid to graduates of Agricultural Colleges Experiment Station, Government and College work, would from $1,000 to $2,500 per year, depending upon the man. : would, of course, be expected to take care of his personal senses, except as mentioned above. HOW TO GET THE WORK STARTED. Any county contemplating demonstration work should be very certain that the citizens of a community have a thorough understanding of just what the work means. It is first nec - essary to familiarize the farmers of the county with the general plan by means of bulletins, articles in county papers, letters, and conversations. If there is a demand on the part of the farmers for the work, a general meeting should be called at the county seat or other convenient place to talk over the mat - ter of organization and to listen to a discussion of the methods and benefits to be derived. This meeting should be arranged for by communication with the Agricultural Extension Depart - ment of the University of Nebraska. The State Leader, his Assistant or one of the County Demonstrators already em - ployed in the state will be sent to address the meeting and assist in the organization. When the permanent organization is completed and the funds raised, the executive committee and the University will select a man for the work. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 PROGRESS OF THE WORK. The following counties have County Farm Management Associations at the date this bulletin is issued. Merrick Gage Seward Polk Thurston Dawes Custer Hall Franklin Farm Demonstrators are now at work in the first three, and men will probably be selected for work in several of the other counties very soon. The government can lend assistance to only a limited number of counties, but if it is desired to use this money it is necessary to complete the organization and make application some time in advance of the actual starting of the work. Several of the counties are expecting to start the work this year without government aid, raising the entire amount of money within the county. It must be remembered that the success of the work depends very largely upon the ability of the demonstrator. The supply of suitable demon - strators is at present very limited. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 CONSTITUTION County Farm Management Association. ARTICLE I.— Name. This organization shall be known as the Farm Management Association. ARTICLE II.— Object. t Section 1. The object of this Association shall be to en - rage among its members and among the farmers of the nty better methods of farming, stock raising, fruit culture. ie building and all lines of agricultural work and to pro - ;e the moral, intellectual and material welfare of the com- I Section 2. It shall be one of the principal duties of this iociation to hire and assist in every way possible a County m Demonstrator. Section 3. It shall be the duty of said Farm Demonstrator to cooperate with all the members of this Association and other citizens of the county to determine, under actual farm conditions, the best agricultural practices for this county. He shall use every effort to coordinate and apply the results of the work conducted by the United States Department of Agriculture, the various Experiment Stations and Colleges of Agriculture and especially of the Nebraska Experiment Station and College of Agriculture. He shall study the practices of successful farmers in this county, and publish such farm practices as may be especially applicable to conditions arising in this county. He shall aid in the re-organ - ization and re-direction of the agriculture in the county so far as may be found possible and desirable, and shall cooperate with Agricultural Clubs and Associations and other organiz- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 ations whose object is the betterment of the agricultural and rural conditions throughout the county. ARTICLE III.— Membership The members of this Association shall consist of residents of this County who shall subscribe their names to this consti - tution and pay an amount for the support of the work of this Association at least equal to the membership dues of this Association. ARTICLE IV.— Due Section 1. The membership dues of this Association shall be fwedftiite'f per year. Section 2. The executive committee of this Association has the power to accept subscriptions from individuals or organ - izations, to aid in furthering the objects of this Association. ARTICLE V.— Privilege Section 1. The members of this Association are entitled to participate in any meetings of the Association and each mem - ber of the Association is entitled to a vote on any question of business brought before the Association. Section 2. Members of this Association are to be enrolled on the mailing list of the Nebraska Experiment Station and the United States Department of Agriculture to receive all bulle - tins published by them which are sent out to farmers. Section 3. Members of this Association are entitled to any reasonable service which can be rendered by the Association, by the Farm Demonstrator of this county, or by any individual member of the Association. ARTICLE VI.— Meeting. The regular annual meeting of this Association shall be held day of each year. on the The executive committee of this Association may call special </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 P lings at any time they see fit, or a special meeting may be d by a petition of twenty-five members of this Associa - duly signed and presented to the executive committee of Association. ARTICLE VII.— Officers and Duties. B Section 1. The officers of this Association shall be a presi - it, a vice-president for each township in this county, and a retary-treasurer. Section 2. The duties of the officers of this Association shall be such as usually pertain to such offices. 1 Section 3. The officers shall constitute an executive com - tee with power to act, subject to the approval of the Asso - ion at its next business meeting. I Section 4. The executive committee of this Association the power to execute such contracts as are necessary to the therance of the purposes of this organization. » Section 5. In case a vacancy occurs among the officers of association the executive committee may fill such vacancy il the next meeting of the Association. Section 6. It shall be the duty of the secretary-treasurer of this Association to keep on file copies of all contracts executed, report same at the regular annual meeting of the Association and to send copies of such contracts to the State Leader of Farm Management and Demonstration Work, at University p arm, Lincoln, Nebraska, together with a list of the Member - ship of this Association. ARTICLE VIII.— Direction of Work. I The direction of the work of Farm Demonstrators or other iple hired by this Association shall rest with the officers this Association and with the State Leader of Farm Dem - tration Work. University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 ARTICLE IX.— Amendments. This constitution may be amended at any regular business meeting by a majority vote of the active members present at any annual meeting. Such amendment shall, however, be sub - mitted to the members of the Association in writing at least one month previous to the time the vote is taken. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">We herein- promise to pay annually for a period of two years to the Treasurer of Chnntv Farm County Farm Management Association the amounts set opposite our names </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>