<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home LOCATED AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home LOCATED AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1910. D. C. ROWDEN COMMANUANT </seg>
          
            <seg id="p002">THE MILFORD SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS HOME Tu the Governor and Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings of the State of Nebraska : Gentlemen: I have the honor to submit the Ninth Biennial Report of the Soldiers" and Sailors' Home, of Milt'ord. Nebr Hid Sailors' Home, of Milt'ord. Nebr Kin beginning this report I wish to express my gratitude tu dl wise providence, for his goodness in preserving the tii.-m - of this home. The condition* existing in the home, and lg the members are the beat I have ever known. Physical Conditions I We have an abundant supply of the very l&gt;est water, p ; and pure food. I have bought some new. and repaired the elosets. I repaired the smoking room and painted it ng room and kitchen, and many minor improvements. Hut main building needi a general over hauling. The new build - for the officers has been completed, furnished and painted cost of about $750.00 for furnishing and painting. I have the roof of the hospital and main building repaired at i B 150.00. Tlie hospital is under the management of Dr. .F. •' r. who is very successful in the treating of ailments of tht Discipline. The proper administration of discipline in an institution is always more or less difficult. The inordinate use of intoxi is the most serious disturbance we find in the home. I think th&lt;- stand I took in regard to drinking has had a good deal to do with the peace and good will in the home, there are manv worthy men and women in the home, who appreciate all that the g and the nation is doing for them, and do all they can to make the home a haven of rest. I have been compelled to disc! i men for the drink habit, and man and wife for taking </seg>
            <seg id="p003">134 lJs.SU COMMISSIONERS REPORT Needs of the Home K recommend to the Auditor that the following amounts be priated to meet the necessary expenses for the institution e next hiennium. Maintenance. I [Deluding fuel and light, furniture and bedding, drugs and icines. hospital supplies, stock feed, electrical supplies, laun - stationery. printing, postage, telegraph, telephone. Imrial ex - es and tlie purchase of ten lots in the cemetery, the im - ements of the grounds, food and clothing the sum of and clothing the sum of .Maintenance Officers Salaries Kmployes wages 9.000.00 General repairs :!.."&gt;( )0.00 Total ♦58.0? I would also recommend the improvements as follows: Kl - evator in the main building running from first to fourth floor. Better stock building and accommodations. Main building paint - ed inside and outside, also the standpipe and fire escape. A woven wire fence around the entire home grounds on the line. *4(&gt;.&lt;)00.00 5,580.00 The appropriation made by the last legislature has not been le ample to meet all demands, and there will be a deficiency in the fund for maintenanc The following amounts have been expended during the bien- .Maintenaiice +27.1.").") 06 Officers' salaries 4,649 0] Employes wsgei _ 7,097 91 Total 138,901 98 $38,901 98 General repairs 1,362 86 1,362 86 L Grand Total *40.264 84 Institution Cash Fund. On hand at the elose of last biennium I 72 08 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">135 vfil sinct Total i{4 tjy Expanded Balance on hand November 30, HMO The pay roll for the month of November, 1!&gt;1&lt;&gt;. is as folk 1 Bookkeeper $50 00 1 Hospital ('i)ok 1 Hospital Waiter :{ Waiters, $11 00 1 Fireman 1 Hospital Steward :{(&gt; (Hi 1 A distant St. •ward 24 00 1 Laundryman 30 00 1 Laundress 15 00 1 Teamster 1 Head Cook ."&gt;.") (Mi 1 Com. Sergeant ■nd Cook 20 imi Population. Males Females Total Number of members December 1. 1908 1 4-{ B l-~&gt;] s Number discharged or died !&gt;4 •{ Number on roll November 30, 191fl 136 9 135 This institution does not attempt to do any farming ou of gardening truck, such as green corn, potatoes, cabbages. &lt;-u- •umbers. lettuce, beets, onions, raddiahes In favorable seasons we have fruit such as. strawber tpples, gripes, pears and plums. We have not enough furnish milk for the use of the home, the pigs eat the refu- the tables which is almost enough to keep them, but I buy a load if eorn once in awhile When the hogs are sold the money goes into the cash fund The amount realized from this source, milk and garden in tin I wish to acknowledge in this connection the receipts of p to the men in the hospital, and in the home, of good things from the W. K. C. at Lincoln. Nebraska, and other places, ami other corps, these things an always thankfully received and apprt In closing this report. I wish to thank the Governor of the State. Hon. A. &lt; '. Shallenlierj^er for the courtesy he has at all times shown me as Commandant of this home, and the interest NiihiImt received since *&gt;(• •"&gt; biennium is $1,150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 136 he Ins taken in tin- general saperintendency of the institution. Als.i to the members of the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings in looking after the supplies that have been Furnished, and in trrantinir every request that I have asked at their hands. Iain also under obligations to the subordinate officers and uves for the faithfulness that they have shown in the dis - re of their duties. This is in a particular sense true of tho^. - have labored in the hospital, they deserve the lasting grati - &lt;&gt;f those who have been in their eare. I also wish to thank omrades of this home for their good behavior. I expect to retire on the advent of the incoming administra - tion with out a single regret, and leave to other hands the can of my eoBtrades. I have the honor to be very truly youi </seg>
            <seg id="p006">SURGEON REPORT To Col. D. D. Rowden, Commandant of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska. Sir: — I have the honor to Sir: — I have make the following report as surfiTCOQ to t h' j It &lt;"*nif for t li ■ There has been an average ital during tliis time. Three surgeon to th&lt; j 1 winning February 1, (if twenty-two patients in the in avera ital during this time. Tl entirely hel] ■ hav- ing ti&gt; have meals in their room: I visit the bom day their room least, and subject to call at OIH ay any time. The comrades who are :t;i] for treatment and medk e comrades who are able to come to the office at the ital for treatment and medicine, those who are sick in bed in quarten are viaited and if n arc removed to the hospita in quarter? are visited and if more than a temporary ail &gt; the hospital. We have hi tl minor nirgiea] ■ ! one major op&lt; lrpical cases and one major operation, amputation of leg . gangrene had developed in the foot, but gangrene airait gangrene had developed in the ranerer veloped in the stump and the pa The care of the patients in ward who are comn " men are getting older an u ling, and I wish to reeommei and the patient died. &gt;ned m "if patients in the hands of the Stewar The car re comrades, and they do very well, but wF ler an more helpless, they require better in recommend that a trained nurse b»- nursing, ar w ployed to have charge of the pa f the patient, and that the Steward retained nd to ke retained nd to keep hospital clean. The present men are worthy and have b&lt; The food is specially p nd have been of great assistance to me in the thv men are w ially prepared by a eook and abundantly pe supplied to patients who are able who are able to eat, others are fed only things as they can digest. The building is elean, and tl known. Yourself and oth shown me during digest. n. and there is no complaint as far as I The bui din irself and other officers have my thanks for have known V wn me during my connection with the home. Respectfully yours. TAMES G. MF'IR. M. D., Surgeon. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">138 Names of Members Who Have Died During the Biennium. Names Cause of Death Heart Trouble Henry If. Craig M. Farmer pa Miller Thoraaa Smith Henry Bellinger •John B. Payton Heart Trouble ( lancer Heart Trouble Blader Trouble Heart Trouble Heart Trouble Bright* Decease (lansrrene Arthurwine Shorkey Samuel Marriman 73 69 Jenry -Marshell Curtis S. Smith William Ward Charles Conner ire B. Pickett. John Dunz 7!) Throat Trouble Alcoholism t.) 65 70 Cancer of Bladder Heart Trouble 63 Apoplexy Paralysis 64 Kew R. Stormont eis Yearick... /a Heart Trouble Kb Teneyek Gresham 7(&gt; Heart Trouble and Drop &lt;&gt;lil uge ami general debilitv </seg>
            <seg id="p008">139 Counties in the State from Which Members Have Been Received Men Women Men Women Present Pr County 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 B -t 1 1 1 1 1 1 17 Douglas lit 1 1 1 ,) 1 1 Harlin Jefferson 1 i Johnson o 4&gt; 2 41 •&gt; ma Kardson iders _ 17 17 1 1 1 1 Butler .) •) Kearney Lancaster 1 •&gt; 2 1 •&gt; Platte Seward ST. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>