<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Varieties of WINTER WHEAT in NEBRASkA BULLETIN 326 MA V 1940 ; K. S. QUISENBERRY J ¦ O. J. WEBSTER, and : ; . T; A. KIESSELBACH f.~:, ¦ ¦ " . . ¦ ¦.".: - ¦¦' ¦ : ¦ ¦¦¦.¦¦ . '&#132; . . _¦¦¦" .-¦'...-' 1; '¦•'¦". " ¦'¦¦'.¦'¦'".': :; ¦'¦ ,¦¦"' ¦¦¦/' ; '¦¦'¦ V-.' ¦ ; ¦.: . ¦ *.'.'". ¦'¦ '' ', ¦.':-¦ ¦'.'¦¦¦-¦ "'•' ¦ .'• -¦ - : ; '¦"•¦ ¦¦'¦ ¦ . ¦¦¦¦¦'¦ '¦¦"'¦. ¦'¦¦¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦-. ' ¦i ' ¦ ¦-¦.¦' ¦'¦ '. ¦'." -¦'• ¦' - ¦¦¦¦¦'¦ ..; ¦.;¦' ¦¦ ¦ - -." ' ; '.¦'¦' I "he AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION of lh» [¦ UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE ¦ ¦ ¦ "I ' ¦¦¦ • ¦ ¦- - - ' ¦ ;' - r, W. W. Burr, Director LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS PAGE Spring vs. Winter Wheat 3 Wheal Improvement at the Nebraska Station 4 j Comparative Variety Tests at Lincoln, Nebraska ...... 6 I Comparative Variety Tests at North Platte, Nebraska. .. 13 Comparative Variety Tests at Alliance, Nebraska 14 Comparative Yields at the Three Stations 16 Milling and Baking Tests 17 Winterhardiness 17 Smut 19 j Descriptions of Important Varieties 21 Summary 27 I j I I \ i </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska 1 K. S. QUISENBERRY, O. J. WEBSTER, and T. A. KIESSELBACH* "^A^INTER WHEAT is one of the most important crops in Nebraska, '"being surpassed only by corn. During the last ten years an average ol; approximately three million acres has been grown annually, with an average production of about 45 million bushels. The use of varieties that are adapted, productive, and acceptable in milling and baking character - istics is essential. The results reported herein summarize the.wheat - improvement work being conducted by the Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station at Lincoln, North Platte, and Alliance. SPRING VS. WINTER WHEAT Prior to 1900 spring wheat was the predominating type grown in Nebraska. Most of the varieties of winter wheat first tried were soft - kerhcled types brought from eastern states, and since they were unadapted they winterkilled badly and were unable to compete with the spring types. T|us led to the conclusion that spring varieties should be grown. Mennon - ite immigrants are credited with introducing the so-called Turkey type of hard red winter wheat into Nebraska and Kansas from Russia in about 1873. While this and later importations of similar wheat have been the foundation of nearly all the winter wheat grown in Nebraska, a general adoption was delayed until the superiority was thoroughly demonstrated. The change came slowly as a result of the discouraging first results with winter wheat .and the opposition of millers to hard wheat. Within 20 years after the introduction of Turkey wheat it was grown on a quarter of a million acres in this state and thereafter its spread was very rapid. Acreage data, summarized by five-year periods (Table 1), show that as late as 1900 less than 20 per cent of the wheat acreage was planted to w nter wheat. After that time, a rapid change took place and since 1921 \v nter wheat has occupied between 90 and 95 per cent of the total wheat acreage of the state. During the period 1931-35 the acreage dropped nearly one-third, but for the following four-year period it has been more.nearly average. The state-wide crop statistics for the 49-year period, 1891-1939, show that the average yield of spring wheat has been 11.8 bushels per acre, compared with 15.1 bushels for winter wheat. Comparative yields on the Experiment Station Farm at Lincoln have been 14.8 and 29,0 bushels per acre, respectively, for standard spring and winter types as an average for 31 years, 1909 to 1939. It must be remembered that conditions at Lincoln usually are more favorable for winter than for spring wheat. Atj the North Platte Substation, for an average of 28 years (1912 to 1939) following both fallow and corn, spring wheat has yielded 143 bushels com - pared to 20.6 bushels for winter wheat. }¦ Cooperative with the Divisions of Cereal Crops and Diseases and Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau of riant Industry, U. S. Department of Agriculture. ; . . • . * - . j* Agronomist, Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, Field Assistant, Division of Dry , Land Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. Department of Agriculture, and Agronomist, Department of Agronomy/ Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, respectively. ' .' *' </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 Table I.—Annual acreages and grain yields of spring and winter wheat grown in Nebraska during successive five-year periods between 1891 and 1939} p .. I **-*"-* eSetg *"*"" Period 2 1 Spring I Winter All Spring Winter Spring Winter wheat I wheat wheat wheat wheat wheat wheat 000 000 000 P.ct. P.ct. Bit. Bu. 1891-95 1,8-18 352 2,200 84 16 11.0 11.0 1896-00 2,021 302 2,323 87 13 13.4 14.6 1901-05 813 1,867 2,680 30 70 13.1 19.3 1906-10 279 2,370 2,649 11 89 13.5 18.6 1911-15 256 3,236 3,492 7 93 12.7 16.6 1916-20 m 2,812 3,284 14 86 11.8 14.3 1921-25 230 3,198 3,428 7 93 11.4 14.0 1926-30 186 3,473 3,659 5 95 15.8 16.9 1931-35 278 2,436 2,714 10 90 7.4 12.6 1936-39' 287 3,421 3,708 8 92 6.7 13.2 Average U.B 15.1 1 Calculated from data reported in the U. S. Department of Agriculture yearbooks. Data from Nebraska Agricultural Statistics (1923-24) were vied in separating the ipring and winter wheat acreages and in reporting the yields per acre prior to 1900. ¦ Four-year period. During the periods 1931-35 and 1936-39 average spring-wheat yields were relatively much lower than for previous periods. This was probably due to the generally severe conditions which have existed during the last several years in the northwestern part of the state where spring wheat predominates. There seems to be little question as to the superiority of hard red winter wheat over spring wheat for the state whenever varieties with sufficient winterhardiness and general adaptation are used. Spring wheat is now largely restricted to western Nebraska, where it is relatively better adapted than elsewhere in the state. The distribution of winter wheat in Nebraska is shown in Figure 1. This map is based on the average harvested acreage for the five-year period 1933-37. The data were supplied by the Nebraska State-Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics. It will be noticed that winter wheat is grown chiefly south of the Platte river, with the greatest acreage in the south - eastern counties. There is also considerable acreage in the southwestern counties, and a small acreage in the northwest. WHEAT IMPROVEMENT AT THE NEBRASKA STATION Beginning in 1902 the Nebraska Experiment Station undertook the improvement of Turkey wheat by selection and crossing. In the earlier years the improvement work consisted largely of making numerous selec - tions and testing these for favorable vegetative habits, yields, and protein content. At various times during the past 37 years selection and breed - ing programs have been initiated, followed by careful testing and distri- </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska Pic. I. —The distribution of winter wheat in Nebraska, 1933-37. Average total acreage, 2,581,352. Each dot represents 1,000 acres harvested. (Data furnished by the Nebraska State-Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics.) buiion o£ outstanding new varieties. These efforts may be summarized as follows: (1) The 1902 selections from Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) resulted in the dis ribution of strains known as Nebraska No. 42 and No. 48. (2) The 1908 selections from the same Turkey wheat produced Ne - braska No. 60, which came to be rather widely grown in the state. (3) Following 1922, extensive selection work was done within Crimean (C 1.1435) 3 and Turkey (S. Dak. 144). From the Crimean selections came Ch:yenne,-a productive, stiff-strawed variety. The Turkey selections were made with resistance to bunt or stinking smut and stem rust as major ob - jectives. Many lines resistant to local races of bunt were obtained, the most outstanding being Nebred. More recent selections from this same Turkey haye shown some resistance to Hessian fly. During this period a fairly extensive hybridization program was also inaugurated. (4) Since 1930 numerous hybrid combinations have been made with the object of combining certain desired characters such as disease resistance, ear mess, winterhardiness, high yield, and grain quality. It will be seen that the early work emphasized selection as a method of improvement. While selection is still being used, more emphasis is being placed on hybridization followed by selection. At present much more is known about the characteristics of the various parent varieties than was the case in previous years. Certain varieties are known to make better parents than others and while a variety may carry heritable factors for a desirable character it may also carry factors for a very undesirable character. Parental material is being classified as to sources of superior germ plasm, and as many desirable characters as possible are being combined in a single parent. .¦¦ ¦ '¦'*'v. '¦¦ '•'¦ '" -' •¦ ¦'¦ ¦' ¦ ¦ ¦¦ ¦¦¦¦¦ After a. decision has been made regarding characters to be combined, the best possible parents are selected for the cross. During the segregating 3, C. I. refers to the accession number or the Division of Cereal Crops, and Diseases. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 generations the hybrid material may be selected each year and grown in pedigree rows, or it may be grown in bulk where there is no artificial selection until the fifth to seventh generation. The first method is probably quicker and if a good combination has been made is probably more sure, although it requires much land and labor. In the bulk method nature may eliminate some of the undesirable types and after the fifth or sixth genera - tion most of the plants are expected to be homozygous; in other words, selections made in the material may be expected to breed true in most cases. All selections are first grown in short plant- or head-rows. Here they are studied for winterhardiness, earliness, reaction to leaf and stem rust, stiffness of straw, and hardness and type of kernel. Selection is very rigid and only a small percentage of the selections are continued into longer rows the following year. Each year the strains are studied for reaction to any environmental conditions that may be present, and the undesirable types are eliminated. As rapidly as possible the selections are advanced to nursery yield tests, and from there the more outstanding ones are advanced to field-plot tests. During the years of yield testing, the selections are subjected to many special tests. The reaction to leaf and stem rust is determined in a special nursery, and also reaction to bunt and Hessian fly. Cold resistance may be tested under controlled conditions in special freezing chambers, or at some experiment station farther north. In addition to the information obtained in the special nurseries the selections may be grown cooperatively at various experiment stations throughout the hard winter wheat region, so that in a single year information may be obtained as to behavior under several environments. As early as possible the grain is tested for milling and baking characteristics and if a selection is found to be undesirable it is discarded. After a strain has been thoroughly studied and is found to be outstanding it is entered in cooperative tests on farms over the state. After two or three years in these tests recommendations can be made with considerable assurance. The development and testing of a new variety of wheat is a long-time job, requiring from 12 to 15 years of very careful work. One of the major objectives of the breeding work in Nebraska is the development of a winter wheat resistant to stem rust. It was found necessary to go to Hope spring wheat for the desired amount of rust resistance, which complicated the problem. Winter wheats are now avail - able from this hybridization program which apparently carry the Hope resistance to both leaf and stem rust, but are somewhat deficient in cold resistance. It will be necessary to recross the new rust-resistant winter wheat to a standard winter variety so as to increase its winterhardiness. This work is now under way. COMPARATIVE VARIETY TESTS AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 4 A complete summary of the yields of the varieties grown in plot tests at Lincoln from 1924 to 1932 was published in Nebraska Experiment «C A Sunc.on rcprcicntcd tl.r Bureau of Plant Industry in the cooperative work from 1931 to l'&lt;)f </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska T - Fig. 2.—Harvesting varietal test plots at Lincoln. Station Bulletin 283. This report will present that data up to 1939. In some! cases data previously reported will be repeated in order to give a more complete record of a variety. . •¦ Sixteen-year comparison.— Eight varieties have been grown in plot tests at Lincoln for the 16-year period 1924-39. The average yields for this period are presented in Table 2. Turkey (S. Dak. 144) had the highest average yield with 28.4 bushels per acre, while Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) had the lowest with 27.2 bushels per acre. Blackhull and Nebraska No. 60 had averages of 27.5 bushels per acre. It is rather surprising that the average yields differ so little, considering the rather wide differences in type between the varieties. . In 1939,31 varieties were grown in plot tests at Lincoln. The yield data for tiiesc varieties for the years grown from 1930 to 1939 are presented in Tabie 2;— Average yield in bushels per acre of eight varieties of winter | wheat grown in replicated plot tests at Lincoln, 1924-19. . / : ¦ Number* Averageyield Variety —; .„.,„ -;-• ¦'¦¦¦¦..: Nebr. I C.I. pcfacrc : ~~ ~~ 7 ~^ . - ;'¦¦¦ : "b«. Turkey (S. Dak. 141) &#132;.../:....:..,.:..:.....: 1011 3689 28.4 Turkey (Scward Co.) JOO5 28.3 Kanr^d •• 1006 ¦ 5H6 27.9 KharLf ...,:.........;.......:, ; ............ ,1010 H42 27.8 Turkdy selection ... ........ . 312 .... *7.7 BlackU .....,,, ...:...... .:..,.. 1004 «d! 27.5 Nebraska No. 60. •• 60-6250 27.5 Tiil^..; -....-.;:;.'..:;..v.i-''V".'-"- l '••¦ 27:z 1 Acpciiion number! of the Ncbrailca Experiment Station and Division of Cereal Crop! and Diieam, U.S. Department of Agriculture. : : , ... </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 8 I'abli 5. — Annual ami iire-rngi yields per iitrt of witilti whtut tiim/it* ami scln-lians groun in plot lists tit flit Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Uncoln, during all nr a part oj the period 1910-19} N ,.|,, | Nl , \v. \&gt;. X.1.ii.,, nrl.U" U,r Wiriely or Mle.iinn N, ' &lt; 1 |1"" 1931 l'll' l"il '''•• ''" s I'"' 1 '" r I&lt; X !''&lt;'' in ' M- . i,, . ts |rs Turkcv »cliiMfin (i; 17 I14?&gt; s .&gt;; i &lt;'^ I Mr. l-i 'I | ( ,ii 14 s 20.S 2~ 4177 NS lOH &lt;JH Turkrv (S. n.ik. 1441 Hill tfi* 1* 4:4 47 'I (is &gt; t.n 4)1 :-i n ij HI |&lt;.r. _'!,: 2&lt;&lt; s |M IU7 112 107 NVhrcil H'f'l Inn'M 44^ H: 'hi. 24 7 4(i ¦; ?Vi ll.' l.'s 17 7 11.3 -"'7 I S.S Inf. 11l 106 Turkrv srlrinoii Inf.: Innl^ 4il 41 11 :7 '» 26 4 17 (. :4 I Ins |n ¦ 1S N I'M 27 7 17 f. lit) 107 W Turkey ufecuuii lll'.'l l«ll* I.* 8 41.. 2.0 IS S « i. 2'- I 2».» H7 16 2 17.-1 3«. l 1r..« 1111 lit! 101 ''hcjfcniir IIW xss^ ¦)" 44^ I !«.'» ?'J * 41.1 24 d .ii s 14. nil; 22.7 'I 2 1M.2 112 111 112 Knnrctl 10ll(. S]4r. "I 2 4^4 M 27.fi 1H ] !'&gt; 2 UO II.S U..2 l'&gt; 7 2^2 IHII 101 110 101 Kharkof HIHI 1442 -H.'l IST II. I 2fi." C..1 2"S M &lt; If,. I If,, t 2"." 2S 'I 1H.6 104 111 104 O r( , I(H2 522" *''.! 44.') 2*l. f&gt; 2f,.l 11.2I 1'. 2 Il'.* li, 14.6 11.7 \'t H 27 f, 15. H ,)') i^, 91) Turkey ISru.ir.l r,,.) Illlli 42 4 411 14. h 24. S ill) 2TK II. 11 n.'l IS. 4 21.') 2'M 18.7 104 IN 104 Bliifkhull 1004 f.2^l 41.n 4t 2 12 0 23.1 19.') 2n.2 2'».0 M.I IS. 7 20 1 2« f, 170 101 109 103 Tcnmnm III3I) f.'llf. 47. 11 4". 2 41.(1 2i.4 17. S 2N.4 2') 1 15.1 IS. 7 20.0 toil 17.1 10» 10Q IOH Kawialt 10S2 KIHO 42.2 MM 44.1 2s (I IS.I 12 2 27. N 12.2 16.7 17. S .10.0 17.1 IO« 104 IOX Clarkan 1(1(14 S*SS 25.(1 2H.4 It.* 16.5 22« 19.7 120 110 Turkey »lc«ion 1081 I 1577 2.!.S 29.fi IS. 2 14.1 22.7 1H.5 In lOf&gt; Ka\v\ale x Tcnmarq 108f&gt; I16(.') 32.7 14.1 20.fi 22.7 21.7 H2 114 Chcvcnnc sclcciion . 10K7 llfifrfi . 31.2 14.8 17.(1 21.2 19.1 116 107 Ulackhull selection .. KW 117.17 1C.5 14.5 20.3 17.4 Illfi 108 Tcnmarq X Mimurki . ... 1094 11580 |.j.fi ic.7 21.9 19.3 118 lid Chicfkan 1100 11754 21.0 21.9 21.5 131 131 Minturki X Klackhiill 1099 11815 . . ... ... 14.9 19.0 17.0 . 104 104 Kanrcd x Ulackhull . 1098 11844 . H. 6 22.4 18.5 113 111 Turkey (SondcrcgKrr) . 15.1 19.(1 17.5 107 107 Oro x Tcnmarq . . 1101 11673 ... 18.8 21.1 20.0 122 122 Oro X Tcnmarq 1103 11672 ... 22.8 114 Kawvale. x Tcnmarq 1113 .... . . ... ... . ... . . .. . . 22.2 . . . 11l Kawvale x Tcnmarq 1102 11750 21.6 108 Kawvalc x Tcnmarq lIM ... 21.3 . 107 lobrcd 1023 6934 37.2 38.3 30.0 17.4 90 Standard error of a (Inference 3.32 2.61 2.52 1.78 1.63 1.78 1.93 1.90 1.17 2.05 0.68 1.18 1 The varieties were replicated three, four, or live times annually in plots 1/40-acrc in she. The wheat was drilled at normal rates ami il.iti-s. 2 Expressed as a percentage of Turkey (Nelir. No. 1) grown for the same years. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">1 Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska le 3. The data have been averaged for different periods, and relative yields are shown. |Ten-year comparison.— Fifteen varieties were tested during the years 1930-39. During this period Cheyenne had an average yield of .31.2 bushels per acre, compared with 27.9 bushels for Turkey (Nebr. No. 1). Kawvale and Tenmarq averaged 12 bushels per acre less than Cheyenne. For those same years Nebred averaged 29.7 bushels and Turkey (S. Dak. 144), 29.8 bushels. Only four of the 15 varieties yielded less than Turkey (Nebr. Nol 1). It is probably safe to conclude that during this period Cheyenne wal significantly higher in yield than Turkey, but probably not signifi - cantly higher than Kawvale, Tenmarq, and Nebred. (Two-year comparison.—During the twq^ years 1938-39, 26 varieties may be compared. The average yields during this period were much lower than those for 1930-39, because of drouth and leaf-rust damage. A variety that was early and resistant to leaf rust had a great advantage during this period. The highest average yield, 21.7 bushels, was made by Kawvale x Teiimarq (Nebr. No. 1086). This strain yielded 5.3 bushels higher than Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) and 3.2 bushels higher than Nebred. Chiefkan, a beardless hard wheat, ranked second; Oro x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1101); third; and Clarkan, fourth. The Oro x Tenmarq strain is an early hard wheat, while Clarkan' is a variety of soft wheat. All but one of the varieties, Oro, had yields equal to or better than the Turkey check. The ratiier poor showing made by the standard varieties: was due largely to the unusual climatic conditions prevailing,during the two years, and to the heavy leaf-rust epidemic in 1938. Other comparisons.— Several other varieties of some interest have been tested but were discarded by the end of 1938 or before. The yields for rheke varieties are presented in Table 4. None of the varieties was out - standing and only four had relative yields above 100 per cent. These were discarded for reasons other than yield or because they could not compete with varieties of very similar type.j Among the list will be found Early Blackhull, Minturki, and lowin, varieties grown commercially in neighboring states, but they failed to give superior yields at Lincoln. '¦'" Data on characters other than yield.—ln Table 5. data are presented for characters other than yield, for varieties grown in the 1939 plot tests at Lincoln. In general the averages are for a four-year period (1936 - -39)', but in some cases for shorter periods' or for a single year as indicated. [For date of heading and ripening the data show theearliness of Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1069), Kawvale x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1086), Black - hull, and Nebred. Nebraska No.' 60 is the latest variety being grown at present. : v -¦ :" - "'-;'.,;¦¦ ¦:.:.V: "¦ ; ¦:. Height of the varieties differs very little, except for Clarkan, which is at 'east five inches taller on the average than any other variety. Winter survival averages do not show any great differences since there was very little killing during the last three years; The most tender vari - eties proved to be Kawvale x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1086), Kawvale, Ten - ma -q, and Blackhull. Most of the standard varieties had average survivals </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 10 Table 4.— Annual and relative yields of winter wheat varieties and selections grown in plot tests at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Lincoln, during all or a part of the period 1930-38. Variety or .election Nebr. CM. ,„„ „„ I m 2 ]9JJ | Relive ! 1 grown ' _ ""• ""• »" *»¦ In /In On. ttn ttii Pel Turkey 1 42.6 44.8 28 9 26 6 16 7 20 6 il 4 M /¦ i? 7 inn Early Blackhull 1057 8856 34.8 41.8 10.2 22.2 1 \» 29.8 24 2 { '" '9° Minturki 1012 6155 39.4 41.5 35 9 22 9 2H 2 29 1 27 7 97 Quivira 1053 8886 38.2 43.8 22 5 22 J V. 2 21S 27 V, Ql lowin 1059 10017 40.1 29 3 144 « 4 2i I »g'i 11- o^ Nebraska No. 6 6 6249 40.9 43.7 217 &gt;28 37 2 21.f, "(It w Crimean 1002 1435 41.0 46.8 23.4 25&gt; (9^ 18 4 11 (1 is » M Crimean selection 1035 44.6 45.3 22 G 24 5 39 5 IB ' g? Turkey selection 1065 10095 44.6 45.1 29.1 262 418 " 104 Turkey selection 1068 10097 42.5 43.8 26 1 25(1 40 4 gj Turkey selection 1067 11506 41.6 44.2 28.8 24 9 40' "'" inn Beloglina selection 1054 8884 42.8 45.4 29 7 26 6 36 3 nA Turkey selection 1070 10098 43..1 44.4 .11.4 25~7 16 1 fS Kharkof (Hays No. 2) 1071 6686 45.3 310 27^5 ni Kruse 1058 11524 35.2 39.7 30 9 22 3 m Turkey selection 1082 11576 ... ... " 23 930 1 136 lift in? Oro 1 Fulhard 1083 11579 ... ... i [2 315 11 71 2g Minhardi-Minturki x Tenmarq ... 1085 11668 &#132; Ji"J &#132; v „„ Turkey (Schluckcbicr) 1090 ' ,g&lt; 5 ™ Turkey selection 1088 11667 .. 29 1 11 i «» Turkey selection 1095 11734 .. ... . , &#132; . 55 Minturki x Blackhull 1089 11671 . '.'..'. n't !?o 03 Blackhull selection 1092 . .____ ._/. \\\ ;;; ¦ '" }j| ,»| Standard error of a difference ._^ 3.32 2.61 2^2 178 1.63 Ft? U93 1.90 ft? 1 Expressed in percentage of Turkey No. 1 grown for the same years. "~ </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska 11 Table s.—Agronomic data for winter wheat varieties and selections grown at Lincoln during the years 1936-39^__ ~~ " ~ ."¦ . • Winter Culms I Test I Lodging Sim Leaf At. yield v,.-.—„ „ _w,i». Nebr. C.I. Headed Ripe Height tan - m \ -her acre I weight 1935 and roit rait per acre Vanety or election . K p. No. 1936-39 1936-39 1936-39 1936-38 1936-39 I 193&amp;9 I 1938 1935 1933 1936-39 May /«« In. P.cl. 000 '-*'• ''•«• '"¦«• '*• . fl"- Sdn^ 0":•::•:::::::::::: !SS !3T S ;¦¦S: :SSI'If fi » ,8-.. 1 llf.e.ec.ion... .087 ; ,,« g g « ¦«,; &#132;|g «;- ; | ,| lill 1 11 11- 1 g 11 i Kaw^le x Tenmarq... .1086 11669 26 24 26 79 2.501 59.1 .. ¦¦ 3 ... </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 12 Table 6.— Annual and average agronomic and yield per acre data for winter wheat vain-ties grown in replicated field plots at the Experimental Substation, North Platte, during the years I9H-J9. 1 Win, a, selection I No. ! No.' j '35. '.» l(,\ %'," jj", 30 j 19.11 1932 1933 1934 1W 1136 19.W 1939 .^ and '"^"i IJj/r Him- In. Pet. IM. 11,,. nil. Bu. Hn. 11,,. tin. tin Kii. 111,. 111, I'd. Turkey (Local) V* 7/2 U " HJ &lt;" 3 f..7 32. 1 16.1 4K.11 M .X 12.2 23.5 24.2 17.9 100.0 Icnnura 1»3" mm 1./2 7 1 37 «¦ «5 In 2 '-.(I 14.0 13.7 45.0 16.» 12.7 21.1 23.8 16.« "8.3 K™rS^ ' lIKI3 SHO «./2 7.' (7 IS Ml «. »?H 12. 7 1v(l l&lt;i .2 12.S 23.9 23.1 1K.2 95.5 Nebraska No 60 W 62W1 (&lt;&lt; J «, v «l 4J.=5 » ; «, ll 'M 41.11 H.I 11.3 27.11 24 3 21.2 100.4 Stall I'M 6251 I'l 7 1 «! I" «.:» 1(1 Mil HJI 41.7 IV4 H.l 22-H 21.(, 17.« 97.5 o ro HH2 8220 0,2 7 2 3» 3 M.2 1» 3 - -I n .7 13 1 42.0 1V« 13.5 26.5 23» 211.11 98.3 llcloclina scl (N I" II) 1054 HXH4 '"2 7,1 .17 11 5^2 i'l.4 7.11 15" 15.1, 421) 14 » 11.8 23.11 23.5 17.4 97.1 ¦hcTcnnc 1115" B»HS &#132;,1 7-2 li, ll 56.5 41.5 1..7 36.C1 I I.I) 44.4 17.7 1f,5 2».7 25.0 22.6 HIS.H Turkey selcclior. ".'".. HIM HMIG 5 30 7/1 15 H 54.3 10 7 111.4 .10. 1 I.U 48.5 10.1 13.3 24.2 24.1 18.8 99.6 Kharkof 10111 1442 0 Is 2 10.7 35.7 «.7 44.4 14.3 24.3 19.3 99.2 Ncbrcd 1063 11)094 6/1 7/2 37 U 55.2 35.0 14.1) 4fi.l. 12.8 H. 7 26.0 19.9 100.4 llcloglina X Hussar .: 11664 6/2 7/3 38 8 55.2 43.0 16.5 9.3 21.8 15.6 92.3 Cheyenne Iclcclion 1087 11666 .. 55.0 15.7 14.6 27.9 21.3 115.5 H^a«Hussar:::::::::: wm :: ::. :. : :. :: : Ydfd IV, nli Kawvalc x Tenmam 1086 11669 »•« 21.9 20.4 14.0 Oro x Tenmarq 1101 11673 15.0 24.2 9.6 09.5 Chiefkan 1100 11754 l«-« 22.1 19.5 108.9 Oro x Tcnmarq 1103 11672 23.2 98.7 KeloKliu x Hussar.. .... 11582 42.4 16.5 93.9 Belugliiu x Hussar 11583 «ni«', nf, Beloglina x Hussar 11663 42.0 16.3 ... 93.0 1 No data were obtained in 1937. -Expressed in percentage of Turkey (Local). </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska higher than the varieties mentioned above. The data are in line with what is known regarding the winterhardiness of these varieties as deter - mined in other tests. ¦ • Blackhull was the only wheat having an average test weight of 60 pounds per bushel, while a number of varieties had averages just slightly lower. The lowest averages, 57.6 and 57.3 pounds per bushel, were for Tenmarq and Kawvale, respectively. Lodging data were obtained in 1935 and 1938 and show that Clarkan, Cheyenne, and Tenmarq had the best straw of any varieties in the test. Stem-rust readings 5 were obtained in 1935 and leaf-rust notes in 1938. No variety was resistant to stem rust but some of the earlier Turkey selections showed the least infection. The most susceptible varieties were Nebraska No. 60, Cheyenne, and Clarkan. The situation is a little better with regard to leaf rust in that Kawvale x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1086), Kawvale, and Clarkan had low readings. Most of the Turkey wheats developed heavy infections of leaf rust. COMPARATIVE VARIETY TESTS AT NORTH PLATTE, ¦ ... NEBRASKA 0 Winter wheat varieties have been tested at the Experimental Substation at North Platte, Nebraska, for many years. The most recent summary was published in Bulletin 272. The data for the period 1931-39, excluding 1937{ are presented in Table 6. Each year the varieties are seeded in four replications, two on fallow and two on corn ground. Since this report compares the performance of varieties the yields and other data from the two soil preparations have been averaged. In 1932, 1933, and 1934 the crop on corn ground was a complete failure so the data for these years are from fallow only. ;; '-¦¦'.. '¦¦[' r : . : '.'•. '.': Agronomic data are averaged for a number of varieties. Average dates of heading do not show a wide spread, and the dates of ripening cover a still narrower range. Turkey (Local) and Turkey selection (Nebr. No, 1069) were the earliest varieties and Nebraska No. 60 the latest. Lodging data I obtained in 1935 show distinct differences between varieties and indicate that Tenmarq, Blackhull, and Kanred were inclined to have ¦weak straw. Average test weights were low for all varieties, with Chey - ennej Nebraska No. 60, Nebred, and Beloglinax Hussar (C. I. 11664) having the highest weights. ; \" .• :: Yields were obtained for nine varieties for the period 1931-39. When thesej yields are averaged there is a spread of only 2.5 bushels per acre between Cheyenne, the highest yielding variety, and Kanred, the lowest yielding one. Nebraska No. 60, Turkey (Local), and Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1069) all had fairly good average yields. Based on the last two years (1938-39) the highest yielding varieties have been Cheyenne, 'Rim reading! taken. on . basil of U. S. Department of Agriculture nuc chart published in U. S. D. A. Bulletin I 0«, by L. E. Meldiers and John H. Parker. ' Acknowledgment is nude to L. h. Zook, Superintendent of the Eiperimental Substation, for making these dau available. . ' </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 14 Tabu-, 7.— Annual and average agronomic and yield per utrc data jor winter wheat varieties grown in field plots at the Box Btttte Experimental Farm, Alliance, during five of the years 193 l i 9.' ___ Vane,, or *.«,*.,. JN No r' | No. ~^'«^|'«« B»S-3, fS "»' | ¦»" '-"• '938 IW» '"^ )£». Kharkof 1010 I+o 59 12 II 27 58.4 X 11.» 5.7 217 19.2 6.1 12.9 100 Turkey .eleccion 1069 IOOU. 6.1 7 &lt;&gt; M SIS « 12.1 6.3 24.5 22.2 9.7 5.0 16 Turkey .elrcl.on 1062 lonis M 10 II 24 5».5 55 12.9 7.5 21.9 19.6 ¦ 3.2 02 Cheyenne 1051) KHHS 6! In II 24 59.3 211 10.4 6.5 25.2 23.3 9.3 14.9 116 O,V 1032 K220 65 II 12 25 59.5 35 10.2 5.7 26.5 19.4 ».8 4.1 09 Nebraska No. 60 «i 625 D v, 12 n 2f. 57.5 50 12.7 9.7 21.4 22.1 7.5 M.7 14 BUekhull 1004 6251 5! 8 in 26 5H.3 20 H. 7 4.n 26.S 20.0 7.2 3.3 03 Te n^q 1030 6936 55 9 11 26 57.0 25 4.9 4.0 29.7 20.4 &lt;&gt;.fi 13.7 06 Nebred 1063 10094 58.4 55 22.1 2(1.6 J.fi 09 Kawvalc X Tenmarq IOW. 11669 57.0 5 22.9 6.9 6 Sr,-?,.-^." .IS ii£ :: :: :: :: g S ::: :: : j Kharkot (Hayi No. 2) 1071 6686 ¦ H.S 7.3 24.5 ... ... 10 Crimean lelec.ion 1035 10.3 7.3 01 Kanred 1006 5146 '-9 7.2 23.1 03 Minturki 1012 6155 . ».8 M 23.3 MM Krase 105S 11524 ••¦ J.« •¦• JJ Quivira 1053 8886 71 2.3 29.3 99 Turkey iclection 1070 10098 .. ¦-- _¦ M-S ¦__ 94 1 The varietiei were replicated three tiracl in plots 1/17-acre in size. » No data for 1932. 3 Complete failures in 1934 to 1937 due to drouth. ?Expresied in percentage of Kharkof (C. I. 1442) grown the same yean. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska I . ¦: ¦ . . Fig. 3. —Winter wheat variety test plots at the Experimental Substation, North Plane, Nebraska, 1939. :'.-.¦ Cheyenne selection, Nebraska No. 60, and Kawvale x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1086). Relative yields, expressed as a percentage of Turkey (Local), emphasize the slightly higher yields of the varieties mentioned above. For the years grown Blackhull, Kanred, and Tenmarq have yielded slightly less than Turkey (Local), while Nebred has been equal to it. Some of "the newer strains grown for only one or two years have given good yields in comparison to the check. At the bottom of Table 6 are shown the yields of four hybrid strains discarded before 1938. None of these was equal to Turkey in yielding ability. COMPARATIVE VARIETY TESTS AT ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA T A winter wheat variety test has been seeded each fall since 1930 at the Box Butte Experimental Farm, Alliance, Nebraska. Crops were har - vested in 1931, 1932, 1933, 1938, and 1939, and the data obtained are pre - sented in Table 7. Agronomic data are averaged for eight varieties grown in the test, and in general the data are in line with what is known about these varieties. Blackhull and Tenmarq showed the most winterkilling and together with Turkey selection (Nebr.* No. 1069) were the earliest in heading. The later maturing varieties such as Nebraska No. 60 and Oro were more hardy. Test weights per bushel were obtained in 1938 and 1939, and show that Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1069), Oro, Cheyenne, and Chiefkan had the highest averages for the two years. The leaf-rust reading in 1938 showed Chiefkan and Kawvale x Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1 Acknowledgment is made to George Schmid. Manager of the (tax Butte Experimental Farm, for assistance in conducting these tests. . . , : . A </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 1086) to be rather resistant, while Nebred and two Turkey selections (Nebr. Nos. 1069 and 1062) were very susceptible. Yields have been obtained for eight varieties during the five crop years. Although the averages vary only slightly more than two bushels, | Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1069), Cheyenne, and Nebraska No. 60 were ' slightly above the average, while Kharkof, Tenmarq, and Blackhull were , below. Nebred has been tested for three years only and has yielded nine per cent more than Kharkof. Several new wheats were grown in 1938 ! and 1939 and all gave average yields ranging from 10 to 19 per cent i higher than Kharkof. To complete the record those varieties that have been discontinued are also included in Table 7. Kharkof (Hays No. 2) averaged 10 per cent more than Kharkof for three years. Kanred and Minturki were also slightly above Kharkof. Kruse, tested for one year, yielded only 64 per I cent of the Kharkof check. Quivira, a very early variety, yielded about j the same as Kharkof for three years. 1 1 COMPARATIVE YIELDS AT THE THREE STATIONS In Table 8 the average yields of eight varieties grown for different periods at each of the three Nebraska stations, Lincoln, North Platte, .uid Alliance, are presented and averaged. The varieties are listed in the lable in the order of the weighted average. Cheyenne ranks first, and was highest in average yield at Lincoln and North Platte. Tenmarq averaged 1.2 bushels per acre less than Cheyenne tor all stations, but was . T\BLt B.— Average yields per acre of winter wheat varieties grown uni - formly at three Nebraska stations (luring all or a part of the period 1910-19. I ' | i Weighted : Nebr. Lincoln North Pljttc j Alliance average Variety So. 1930-3P | 1933-36 and ' 1933.1938, (19 .tation- 1938-39 ) and 1939 yean) Bit. Bit. Bit. Bit. Cheyenne 1050 31.2 26.! 19.3 27.7 TYnmarq 1030 30.0 23.9 19.9 26.5 Nebred 1063 29.7 2-U&gt; 17.1 26.1 Turkey selection 1061 2K.1 2-I. i 18.8 25.4 Blackhull I DIM 28.6 23..S 18.0 25.4 Kharkof 10KI 2R.&lt;&gt; 23.9 15.7 25.2 Oro 1032 27.6 23.S 18.2 24.9 Nebraska No. 60 60 27.1 23.S 17.0 24.5 slightly ahead of Cheyenne at Alliance. This high ranking of Tenmarq may be accounted for by the absence of severe winterkilling during the period of the test. Among the varieties listed, Nebred ranks third at Lincoln, second at North Platte, sixth at Alliance, and third for the average of the three stations. Blackhull has averaged somewhat lower than Tenmarq, and Nebraska No. (50 is at the bottom of the list. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska MILLING AND BAKING TESTS The demand of the milling trade in Nebraska is for hard red winter, or hard red spring wheat suitable for making light bread. Such wheat is usually characterized by relatively high protein : content and a strong gluten. While it is known that varieties may differ as to protein content, variations caused by differences of soil or climate may be much greater than' heritable differences. For example, the protein content of wheat has ranged from approximately 11 to 20 per cent in different seasons, while the variation between varieties grown under similar conditions seldom exceeds 2 : or 3 per cent. It is generally considered that a strong baker's flour must have at least 11 per cent protein and in commercial practice the protein percentage of flour is standardized by blending. Aside from! amount of protein, varieties may differ as to characteristics of' the protein or gluten. In some cases the gluten will not stand long mixing in highjspeed mixers, while in other cases the dough must be mixed for a longer time in order to get the best loaf of bread. ~ It is highly desirable that there should be regional uniformity with respect to the type of wheat grown in order that market demands may be met most satisfactorily. As a general rule a miller or a baker can use almost any sound wheat or flour provided he knows beforehand what he is getting. The trouble arises when he thinks he has one kind and, too late, discovers that he has something else. . In,; the process of testing new selections or strains of wheat, milling and baking studies are included. This work is done by the cereal chemists, using standardized laboratory tests, made in accordance with specifica - tions' of the American Association of Cereal Chemists. These tests may be conducted at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station or in Fedejral Laboratories located at Washington, D. G, and Manhattan, Kansas. Ttie object of these tests is to evaluate the varieties as to their suitability for bread making, and to determine the baking procedure needed by the individual flour to give the best results. If a variety proves to be poor in quality it will not be released for growing, ho matter how desirable it might be agronomically. On the other hand, a variety may' be high in yield but its quality may be a little different from that of the types being grown, yet by some slight change in baking procedure good bread can be made. In this case the variety probably would be released together with information as to how to handle the flour. The objection to this practice might be that the miller would have no way of knowing with which variety he was working. . AH of the important varieties discussed in this report have been or are being tested for quality, and no distinctly inferior one will be released by,the Experiment Station. ¦ :. WINTERHARDINESS Winterkilling occasionally causes severe loss to winter wheat in the state. Losses from this source, when they do occur, are so important that </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 this character must be considered in a breeding program, and before a new wheat is released it must be thoroughly tested for hatdiness. Winter - hardiness is not easy to study in the field due to the irregularity of killing. In some years the entire test may be wiped out, while in other years there j may be no killing. For this reason the test must either extend over several } years, or be carried at many stations some of which are farther north, or be carried on with the use of controlled equipment. Data from such tests are presented in Table 9. ;, Table 9. — Relative winter/tardiness o] some winter wheat varieties as mdi- :¦¦ cated from different experiments. i, Wintcrhardiness as percentage of Kharkof (C. I. 1442) j Variety or N'br- Controlled At 3 In ; selection freezing Nebraska regional . tests * stations tests " P.cl. P.cl. P.c/. Yogo 8033 . .. UO 119 , Minturki 1012 6155 129 110 117 .;] Nebred 1063 10094 139 101 111 Cheyenne selection 1087 11666 138 97 108 Turkey selection 1062 10015 121 108 Nebraska No. 60 60 6250 133 109 106 Turkey selection ... 1069 10016 107 106 Cheyenne 1050 8885 90 106 105 Kanred . . 1006 5146 85 101 102 Oro 1032 8220 .. 108 101 Kharkof 1010 1142 100 100 100 lowin 1059 10017 . .. 95 95 Kawvale 1052 8180 .. 93 94 Blackhull selection 1093 11737 57 102 92 Kawvale x Tcnmarq 1086 11669 58 102 91 Oro x Tcnmarq . 1101 11673 63 99 86 Quivira 1053 8886 ... 94 83 Tenmaiq 1030 6936 .. 84 83 Blackhull 1004 6251 32 84 78 Early Blackhull . 1057 8856 ... 41 71 1 From unpublished data obtained by R. O. Weibcl. - Darj obtained in cooperative leitl reported in /. Amer. Soc. Agron. 30:399-405, 1938. In al! cases the data are shown as percentage of Kharkof (C. I. 1442) check grown in comparable tests. The controlled freezing data are the averages of 24 separate freezes, made in the freezing chambers at the Experiment Station. 8 Not all of the varieties in the table were included in controlled tests \ but of those included Nebred, Cheyenne selection, and Nebraska No. 60 I were the most hardy, while Blackhull was very tender. j For the three Nebraska stations (Lincoln, North Platte, and Alliance), the data were obtained in the field in nursery rows and are based on from one to sixteen comparisons. The varieties were not all grown for the same " For .i description see C. [.. Peltier, ( ontrol equipment for the study of hardiness in crop r.b/ii&gt; I Ut R-v 41:1 —-12. Ml </seg>
         <seg id="p019">..¦¦¦'¦- -. . :&gt; Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska periods, but the data are based on a common check variety included throughout the tests. Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1062) had the high - est survival, being slightly more hardy than Yogo and Minturki. This series of tests shows Nebred about equal to Kharkof, and Nebraska No. 60 and Cheyenne more hardy. Some of the early varieties were among the least hardy. : The data'from the regional tests are the most extensive and are based on from 21 to 301 comparisons made over a 20-year period at several stations. The varieties are listed in Table 9 in order of hardiness based on these tests. Yogo and Minturki are the most hardy, followed by Nebred, Cheyenne, and Karired, all of which are above Kharkof. Such varieties as Kawvale, Quivira, Blackhull, and Tenmarq are not so hardy as Kharkof. j It is felt that the data agree fairly well although there are minor differences in ranking. In the controlled tests Nebred is relatively more hardy than in either the Nebraska or the regional tests. Cheyenne was less hardy than Kharkof in the controlled test but more hardy in the regional tests. Blackhull was shown to be lacking in hardiness in all tests, and Early Blackhull was the least hardy in both field experiments. It must be remembered that winterhardiness is a rather variable character and may be caused by several factors, so tests must be carefully controlled or else extended over a long period or at several stations. The controlled test is chiefly a measure of resistance to cold and this may account for some of the variation between the rankings in the different experiments. :•/ ;¦"¦: ¦,:' ; .¦•}:. smut ¦ ' ¦'¦ / .-. &#132;' Since bunt, or stinking smut, is a major problem in the winter wheat areas of Nebraska this disease is given consideration in the breeding pro - gram. It is true that the forms of bunt now known in Nebraska may be controlled by seed treatment, but a resistant variety would be a great hdp.| ,:¦-;:¦¦ '¦¦¦ ¦ ::. ¦ ¦¦' ¦' . ;:: ¦¦¦; -. Considerable progress! has been made on this problem in Nebraska. A large number of Turkey, selections are available that are very resistant to the races or forms of bunt known to be present in the state. All of the varieties and strains in plot and nursery tests are subjected to a bunt test in which the seed is heavily inoculated before planting. After a strain is shown to be susceptible it is taken out of the bunt test, but if no smut develops it is kept in the test for several years to be sure the variety has not merely escaped infection. The more resistant strains are then put into cooperative tests in various states throughout the hard winter wheat region. Data on smut infection as determined in regional tests and in the bunt [nursery at Lincoln are presented in Table 10. Since these tests are not all for the same number of comparisons the average bunt infections are reported as percentages of Kharkof (C. I. 1442) grown in the same experiments. The data must not be considered as average bunt infections, </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 but only as comparative figures showing the infection on the variety in relation to the infection on Kharkof in the same test. 1 sBi.E 10.— Comparative bunt reaction o) some winter wheat varieties as shown by tests at Lincoln and at stations throughout the hard winter wheat region. Smut infection as ... _ , percentage of Yamu &lt;,i selection N™r C s ] n - Kharkof (C. I. 1442) Lincoln Regional tests tests * P.ct. P.ct. Turko (S. Dak. 144) . 1011 3689 0 Turkn selection . 1065 10095 6 1 Turkey selection . . . 1081 11577 0 1 Turkey selection . . 1070 1009K 3 2 Turkey selection 1067 11506 3 2 Turkey selection 1068 10097 6 2 Turkey selection 1069 10016 7 3 Turkey selection 1082 11576 2 5 Nchveil 1063 10094 2 5 ¦ Mimurki x Blackhull 1089 11671 1 5 Vo B n 8033 6 5 \ Chocnne selection 1087 U666 0.3 5 I Turkey selection 1088 11667 2 6 Or,, v Tenmarq 1101 11673 1 7 Tenmarq x Minrurki 1094 11580 5 7 Or,, x Fulhard 1083 11579 3 8 Turkcx selection 1062 10015 8 8 1 On, 1032 8220 7 11 | Kruvc 105K 1152-f 10 13 Mimurki 1012 6155 10 14 Minturki x lilackhull 1000 11815 11 21 I Turkey (Seward G&gt;.) 1(1(15 15 lurkev 1 26 K.nvi.il, v Tenmarq . . 1086 11669 54 36 Turkey selection 1095 11734 58 48 Icihrcil ........ 1023 6934 ... 61 Kawvalc 1(152 K1 SO 70 66 Nchraska No. 61) 60 6250 42 68 Nebraska No. 6 6 . 76 ... • ¦ Crimean selection . . 1035 64 ... lowin 1059 10017 136 71 Kl.ick/iuli 100-) 6251 86 74 Tenmarq 1030 6936 111 82 K.anred 1003 5146 102 86 Minhardi-Minturki x Tenmarq 1085 11668 107 89 Belnjtlina selection 1054 8884 124 91 Ouivira 1053 8886 112 96 Cheyenne 1050 8885 101 97 Kharkof 1010 1442 100 100 Clarkan 1084 8858 120 134 Blackhull selection 1093 11737 83 137 Early Blackhull 1057 8856 107 145 Crimean 1002 1435 141 Kharkof (Hays No. 2) 1071 6686 156 Chicfkan 1100 .... 199 1 Data taken from the rcpon of cooperative tests reported in ). Amer. Soc. Agron. 30:484-92, 1938. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">"Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska For the most part the agreement between the Lincoln data and regional data is very good. The regional data are based on more comparisons than is the case for Lincoln. While Turkey (S. Dak. 144) shows no infection in (the Lincoln test, it should not be considered as an immune variety since this test was for only one year, and other tests have shown it will develop some smut. Had the variety been tested for a longer time un - doubtedly some smut would have developed. It will be seen that several of the Turkey selections are rather resistant as are also Nebred, Yogo, and Cheyenne selection. All of these wheats show more resistance than Oro and Minturki, two resistant commercial varieties/Varieties such as Nebraska No. 60, Blackhull, and Tenmarq did not develop as much smut in the regional test as did Kharkof. Cheyenne was about equal to Kharkof, while Clarkan, Early Blackhull, and Chiefkan developed more smut than the check. [Any variety with a bunt infection as low as or lower than that of Minturki could be classed as having some resistance to the forms used in the test. Varieties developing as much or more s'mii.t than Kharkof must be considered as¦; quite susceptible. Chiefkan appears to be very susceptible. j DESCRIPTIONS OF IMPORTANT VARIETIES [The following brief descriptions of the varieties that are important commercially, or are otherwise of special interest in Nebraska, may serve to increase the acquaintance with them. Both the Nebraska station number and the C. I. number (accession number of the Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. Dept. of Agriculture) are shown for each variety. Blackhull (Nebr. No, 1104, C. I. No. 6251).— This variety was selected, increased, and distributed by Earl G. Clark, a Kansas farmer. As the name indicates the glumes or chaff develop a black color in most seasons, serving as an easy method of identification. While extensive tests have shown the variety to be rather susceptible to winter injury it has become popular in some sections of Nebraska. It is earlier than Turkey and this enables it to escape rust injury in some years. Where winter - killing is not a factor it will usually outyield Turkey, and the grain usually has a higher test weight than that of other varieties but produces a lower percentage of straight flour. Blackhull flour is not liked by the trade since.it is not tolerant to severe mixing. In some areas millers and bakers object seriously to the variety, but in more recent years these objections have not been so serious, possibly because more is known regarding it. Blackhull is not recommended for Nebraska. jSheyenne (Nebr. No. 1050, C. I. No. 8885).— Cheyenne was the result of a plant selection made from Crimean (C. I. No. 1435) in 1922 at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Tested in plots at Lincoln since 1928, it has the highest average yield of any variety grown for this period. It has the highest average yield of any standard variety at North Platte, and ranks first in average yield at the three Nebraska stations. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 Cheyenne is characterized by a stiff straw, prolific stooling, and a short, erect head, making it a good variety for combine harvesting. It is tolerant to Hessian fly, which permits production of fair to good yields despite a heavy infestation. The variety is susceptible to bunt and to both leaf and stem rust, but is slightly more winterhardy than Turkey. Because of high yields the protein content may be a little lower than for other varieties. For best results in baking the dough must be mixed a little longer than for other varieties. Cheyenne was first distributed in 1930, and a purified supply again in 1933. Since that time it has spread through the state and has given very good results in the absence of rust. In southeastern Nebraska in 1936, 1937, and 1938 the variety was damaged rather severely by rust, and its popularity decreased. In 1939 it gave very good yields wherever tested. In western Nebraska it is still popular. Cheyenne is recommended for Nebraska. Chiefkan (Nebr. No. 1100, C. I. No. 11754).—Chiefkan is a beardless, black-glumed, hard red winter wheat. It was developed by Earl G. Clark, a Kansas farmer who originated Blackhull wheat. It was released in 1936 and was advertised as a "beardless Superhard Blackhull wheat." It prob - ably originated from a Blackhull x Harvest Queen natural cross. The variety has been tested in Nebraska for two years only and at Lincoln gave good yields but was not equal to Cheyenne at North Platte and Alliance. From cooperative tests in other states additional information has been obtained. The variety is known to be fairly high-yielding in the absence of winterkilling, but is nearly as winter tender as is Black - hull. It is very susceptible to bunt and loose smut, is susceptible to stem rust, but has some resistance to leaf rust. It is about equal to Blackhull as to time of maturity, and like Blackhull produces hard grain with good dark color and high test weight per bushel. The milling and baking characteristics are somewhat simiar to those of Blackhull, except that the flour yield is higher. The dough will not stand severe mixing, and usually gives a loaf of bread poorer than does Blackhull. So far, a ma - jority of the trade is against the use of Chiefkan. Both yield record and baking performance indicate no reason for growing the variety in the state. It is not recommended for Nebraska. Clarkan (Nebr. No. 1084, C. I. No. 8858).—This is a variety of soft red winter wheat produced by Earl G. Clark, a Kansas farmer. Clarkan is characterized by tall straw, beardless heads, susceptibility to stem and leaf rust, and only a fair amount of winterhardiness. The variety has yielded very well at Lincoln but is not recommended because the grain is soft and might be discounted at the local market. If a soft variety is to be grown Clarkan is probably one of the best to use. Early Blackhull (Nebr. No. 1057, C. I. No. 8856).—This very early wheat was selected from a field of Blackhull in 1921 by A. P. Haeberle of Clearwater, Kansas. The variety differs from Blackhull in being five to eight days earlier and in usually having shorter straw. It is the earliest </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska .' '-S: : %M ¦'"¦¦.' . ¦ ¦ ¦ .^hJISMMH Fio. 4.—Cheyenne winter wheat (center) and Crimean (C. I. H35), from which Jit was selected, on the right, winter wheat now being raised on farms and also the most winter - tender one. So far as known, the variety is not grown commercially in Nebraska although at times growers confuse it with Blackhull. It is not recommended for Nebraska under any circumstances. lobred (Nebr. No. 1023, C. I. No. 6934).—Although dropped from the Lincoln tests in 1932 because of low yield, it was again tested in 1939 because of unusual interest in the eastern part of the state. lobred was selected from Banat at the lowa Agricultural Experiment Station in 1915. It is a brown-chaffed variety with much shorter and broader kernels than most varieties o£ the hard red winter class. It is about equal to Turkey in wjinterhardiness, has a stiff straw, is resistant to leaf rust, and has some resistance to stem rust. Under dry conditions it shatters very badly. At Lincoln lobred has yielded from 6 to 10 per cent less than Turkey. Its milling and:baking.characteristics seem to be acceptable. iWing recent years the variety has become popular in the counties along the Missouri river where farmers say that it gives very good yields. This! yielding ability has never been demonstrated in cooperative trials in the state, but because of rust resistance its test weight has been better thanl for. Turkey wheats. For the extreme eastern counties lobred may be a good variety but farther west its use can not be recommended. •''¦'. lowin (Nebr. No. 1059, C. I. No. 10017).—Iowin is a selection from Theiss wheat made at the lowa Agricultural Experiment Station and was Ireleased in lowa in 1930. It differs from Turkey in having purple sterns, slightly softer kernels, and some resistance to stem rust. The variety was tested for several years at Lincoln but failed to equal the average yield of the Turkey check. Eanred (Nebr. No. 1006, C. I. No. 5146).—This variety was selected, fromj Crimean (C. I. 1435) at the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Sta- </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 tion. In yield tests in Nebraska it has not differed greatly from the Turkey check. It has resistance to some races of stem rust, is sufficiently winterhardy for Nebraska, and has good milling and baking characteristics. The principal fault of the variety is weak straw, a characteristic that has probably prevented a wider spread. Kanred was widely grown in the state in 1924 but since that time its popularity has been decreasing. Kawvale (Nebr. No. 1052, C. I. No. 8180).—Kawvale is a semi - hard variety developed by the Kansas station and distributed in the eastern part of that state. Over a period of nine years at Lincoln it has been second in yield to Cheyenne. It has considerable resistance to leaf rust, is known as a "late ruster" with regard to stem rust, and has some resistance to Hessian fly. Kawvale is fairly early in maturity, is not especially winterhardy, and shatters easily as soon as ripe. The test weight is not high and the variety is neither a typical hard nor a typical soft wheat. For this reason it may be docked in price at some elevators. In ¦ milling and baking characteristics the variety more nearly equals hard than it does soft wheat. Chiefly because of grain characters it is not recommended for Nebraska, although its resistance to leaf rust makes it a good parent to use in crosses. ; Kruse (Nebr. No. 1058, C. I. No. 11524).—This variety was selected from a field of Kanred in 1922 by Herman Kruse of Bercail, Montana. The selection did not do well there. Some seed was sent to F. C. Kruse of Douglas county, who increased it and distributed seed in 1929. The variety is characterized by stiff straw, hairy glumes, and short, soft kernels, and is not a Turkey type wheat. It was probably the result of a Kanted x [ones Winter Fife natural cross. It has resistance to bunt and is tolerant to Hessian fly, but at Lincoln has yielded about 10 per cent less th:in Turkey. It has never been an important variety in the state and is not recommended. Minturki (Nebr. No. 1012, C. I. No. 6155).—Minturki was selected from a Turkey x Odessa cross at the Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station. The variety is very winterhardy, has resistance to certain races of bunt, and is resistant to some races of stem rust but is susceptible to leaf rust. The variety is tall, late, and the kernels are long and inclined to be soft. The flour makes a loaf of bread with a good volume but the color may be slightly yellow. • j Nebraska No. 60 (C. I. No. 6250).—This selection was made from Turkey in 1908 at the Nebraska station. It differed from Turkey chiefly in being more winterhardy, slightly later, and less tolerant to Hessian fly. ¦¦ In early tests Nebraska No. 60 yielded well and was distributed in 1918. V It became rather widely grown in the state, but since 1934 its popularity ;•' has decreased. During the last ten-year period it has had an average J - yield at Lincoln that is slightly less than Turkey, the reason being that during these years winterkilling was not a factor in yield and late matur- ;¦'¦ ing wheats have been at a disadvantage because of drouth conditions. ; At North Platte it is about equal to Turkey, and at the Alliance station it ,V </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska i•' ¦ ;. .''¦'¦¦'. ¦ ¦ ': ¦ ¦:¦¦¦ ..- ¦ Fie s.—Winter-wheat test plots showing differences in varietal resistance to Hessian fly under epidemic conditions (1932). The lodged, wheat is down because of fly-injury. has done relatively better. The variety was removed from the recommended list in 1938. Nebred (Nebr. No. 1063, C. I. No. 10094).— This strain was selected from Turkey (S. Dak. 144) in 1924 at the Nebraska Experiment Station. The seed for the plot from which the selection was made had been smut :ed and an epidemic of stem rust was created in the spring. Heads were selected from plants free of bunt and practically free from rust. In succeeding years the seed of the selections was bunted and only the re - sistant lines were continued. A number of good selections were obtained in this work, all of which are resistant to the forms of smut known to be present in Nebraska. Nebred has made the best agronomic record of the group. N ( ebred is a winter wheat of the Turkey type. The heads are bearded, glumes white and smooth, and the kernels hard and red! -The variety is more winterhardy than ordinary Turkey, and is midseason as to maturity. The straw is not so stiff as that of Cheyenne and the variety is less tolerant to Hessian fly.. Nebred is susceptible to leaf and stem rust but seems to be able to produce a relatively good crop of grain under a rather heavy rust epidemic. For all the years tested Nebred does not equal Cheyenne in yield but for the period 1935-39 has ouryielded Cheyenne at Lincoln. The yields at North Platte and Alliance have been good but the variety has ranked below: Cheyenne. In regional tests through the hard winter wheat region Nebred has yielded very well for several years. The milling character - istics [of the grain are very good and the flour gives a good loaf of bread, although the color of crumb may be slightly yellow unless the flour is bleached. The milling and baking characteristics of the variety are more like those of Turkey than is the case with Cheyenne. </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 In the fall of 1938 the variety was released to growers. At that time the supply of certified seed amounted to about 1100 bushels, most of which was seeded. Nebred seemed rather susceptible to drouth in the spring of 1939, and did not make a good yield record in the eastern part of the state. The variety is recommended for the entire state, but espe - cially for the eastern half where it will probably suffer less from rust than will Cheyenne. In the western half of the state it will probably be no better than Cheyenne, except for resistance to bunt, and will not be as good for combine harvesting. Oro (Nebr. No. 1032, C. I. No. 8220).—0r0 is a selection of Turkey made at the Sherman Branch Experiment Station in eastern Oregon. It is rather highly resistant to the races of stinking smut or bunt now known in Nebraska. Oro is just a little later than regular Turkey and in Nebraska has never yielded any more than Turkey. Oro has been used rather extensively in crosses and has proved to be a good source of factors for bunt resistance. Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1030, C. I. No. 6936).—Tenmarq was selected from a Marquis (spring) x Crimean selection (winter) wheat cross at the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station. It was distributed in Kansas in 1932 and rhe acreage has increased very rapidly in Kansas, Oklahoma, and Texas. The variety is early, rather winter tender, has a fairly stiff straw, short plump kernels, and yields well in the absence of winterkilling. The variety has some resistance to leaf rust and because of earliness may escape serious damage from stem rust. The grain is inclined to "yellow berry" rather easily, but the milling and baking characteristics are very good, often being considered as superior to Turkey. Tenmarq has given a good yield record at Lincoln, North Platte, and Alliance, but as a result of lack of winterhardiness has not been recommended for the state. It is being grown on a limited acreage in south-central Nebraska and would be preferable to Blackhull for that area because of more desirable milling and baking characteristics. Turkey.—Turkey is a name applied to a large group of rather similar wheats. Usually if a wheat has a bearded head, white chaff, and hard red grain it is called Turkey. Wheats such as Kharkof, Malakof, and Crimean are of this general type and differ chiefly in point of origin in Russia and time of importation into this country. In general, Turkey ¦wheats show lack of uniformity, or may be rather badly mixed. One of. these (Nebr. No. 1) is still used as a standard of comparison in plot trials at Lincoln and a local Turkey is used at North Platte. The variety is still considered as among the good ones for the state, and only a few new strains outyield it in comparable tests. Some unimproved Turkey wheats deserve recognition as, for example, Seward County Turkey (Nebr. No. 1005). This strain has been a consistently high yielder during the last nine years. Turkey has been, and still is, a very good source of selections. Such different varieties as Blackhull, Oro, Nebraska No. 60, Nebred, Cheyenne, </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Varieties of Winter Wheat in Nebraska '¦¦ and Kanred were selected from Turkey or similar parents. While less emphasis is being placed on selection as a method of improvement, some work is still going on. • . .' Turkey selections.—At various times large numbers of selections have been j made from various Turkey wheats. Some of the types recovered are worthy of mention. From a strain known as Turkey (S. Dak. No. 144) a number of selections were made. One of these (Nebr. No. 1069) is early and fairly winter hardy and resistant to Nebraska races of bunt. It has a rather short straw and.is inclined to shatter when ripe. Because of its earliness it does not give, a very high yield although on the average it has outyielded the check. This wheat is not being recommended, because of baking characteristics that are not liked by the trade. Another Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1062) isa bunt-resistant strain, rather late and winterhardy, whose best record has been made at Alliance. Several additional selections are being tested which are resistant to smut forms now in Nebraska and have some resistance to Hessian fly. So far the most promising of these selections has beeri Nebred. Ypgo (C. I. No. 8033).—This variety was produced at the Moccasin* Montana, Experiment Station and is the result of the Beloglina-Buffum x Mmturki cross. The object was to combine extreme winterhardiness withjhigh yield and good grain quality. Togo is very winterhardy, yields well in northern areas, and has only fair quality. It is very late in maturity, is re istant to most forms of bunt, but has a very unattractive type of head in that it is long, lax, bearded, and nodding. The variety has been grown at Alliance for two years and has yielded about 10 per cent more than the Kharkof check. : •¦ ¦;' .";::: .....¦.:,::... :K summary Spring wheat constituted more than 80 per cent of the total wheat acreage grown in Nebraska prior to 1900. Since that time the proportion of spring wheat has decreased until at present more than 90 per cent of the acreage in the state is seeded to winter wheat. The change was pri - marily due to the introduction of Turkey wheat from Russia and to the development of other adapted varieties of hard red winter wheat. Selection has been widely used as a method of wheat improvement work! in Nebraska. By this method such varieties as Nebraska No. 60, Cheyenne, and Nebred were developed. At present hybridization followed by selection for purification is used as the principal method of developing the desired types or varieties. AH wheats are studied in the field for several years and in addition are grown in controlled.tests to permit a study of winterhardiness, bunt and rust resistance, and resistance to Hessian fly. The milling and baking characteristics of all varieties are determined and any having characteristics that are undesirable are discarded. Ne - braska should grow only those varieties of hard red winter wheat that are acceptable for milling and baking. </seg>
         <seg id="p028"/>
         <seg id="p029"/>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 326 Yield and agronomic data arc reported from varietal trials conducted at Lincoln, North Platte, and Alliance. At Lincoln, for the last ten years (1930-39), Cheyenne has the highest average yield, followed by Kawvale, Tenmarq, Turkey (S. Dak. No. 144), and Nebred. At North Platte, for an eight-year period Cheyenne, Nebraska No. 60, and a local Turkey have given the highest yields. Tenmarq and Nebred are also high yield - ing at this station. At Alliance, Cheyenne and Nebraska No. 60 have given good yields. The outstanding characteristics of wheats of interest in Nebraska are presented. The varieties recommended for the state are Nebred, Cheyenne, and Turkey. Nebred is a selection from Turkey (S. Dak. 144) made at Nebraska. It is resistant to the forms of bunt now known to be present in the state. ;. It has given a good average yield, is more winterhardy than ordinary ; Turkey, and has acceptable milling and baking characteristics. It was ; released to farmers in 1938. Cheyenne was selected from Crimean and distributed in 1933. The variety is characterized by high yield, stiff straw, erect head, and tolerance , to Hessian fly. The worst faults of the variety are susceptibility to bunt and to both leaf and stem rust. During years of stem-rust epidemics Cheyenne suffers badly, and for that reason is losing some of its popularity in the eastern part of the state. Turkey is the variety most widely grown in the state. There are various i types or strains of the variety and often there may be considerable varia - bility. Usually Turkey will compare fairly well with other varieties, giv - ing a fair yield. It has average winterhardiness, is medium in time of ;. maturity, and the grain quality is more or less standard with the trade. Cio mi \ f i i ! I i f 1 i ¦ I </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>