<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00031.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00031.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF John H. Morehead Governor of Nebraska TO THE 34th Session Nebraska Legislature 1915</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">MESSAGE OF John H. Morehead Governor of Nebraska TO THE 34th Session Nebraska Legislature 1915 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Legislature : f the Thirty-fourth Session of the N.-m-aska GENTLEMEN:— In accordance with the constitution of our state, I a; before you this afternoon to lay before you such information as I have gained during my term of service as governor and to suggest, for your consideration, such measures as a, to me deserving of special consideration. There were many good laws enacted by the last legislature, and I am glad to see so many members of that legislature returned for the present session. Notwithstanding the good work of the session of 1913, there is still much work for you to do, and I know that you are coming here fresh from the people, determined to do your duty as you see it. The reports of the heads of departments will be submitted to you, in addition to the reports of si commissions appointed ; notably, the commission for the re - vision of our school laws; the commission on water power and the commission on revenue and taxation. For of these reports, I bespeak your careful scrutiny and earnest consideration. They are submitted in the hope that they may be of service to you, and I believe you will find much valua - ble information. It is not possible, in a message, to treat in detail, all the matters that will be the subject of legislation. and I merely expect to point out a few of the important mat- ters which I hope will engage your attention. Counties Pay for Return of Fugitives. P present the cost of returning fugitives from justice is out of the state general fund, and I am led to believe this often leads to arrest and return of parties at great expense to the state, when actual prosecutions do not follow. tdearned of instances where complaints were filed men and after they were brought back at an ex; or $300 to the state no prosecutions were made. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 GOVERNORS MESSAGE County officers, being familiar with all the facts and cir - cumstances, are better able to determine whether a requisition ought to be issued at public expense for the return of a fugitive than the governor can possibly be. The governor is bound by the record that is presented to him, and when the papers are regular, he has no alternative but to grant the requisition. Two years ago $20,000 was appropriated to pay the cost of the return of fugitives from justice and for con - veying prisoners to the penitentiary. The bills for convey - ing prisoners to the penitentiary are audited by the state auditor without passing through the governor's office, while the bills for returning fugitives are audited by the governor, and he has no means of knowing how much money there is in the fund, unless he runs to the auditor's office each time and gets this information. I strongly recommend that the law be so amended that each county will pay the cost of transporting its own prisoners to the penitentiary, and the cost of return - ing its own fugitives from justice. The Dope Traffic. PNe now have a statute making it a felony to introduce rphine, cocaine, etc., into the penitentiary and the strict enforcement of this statute by the present warden has brought about a splendid improvement in the moral of that institution. I am convinced, however, that the law reg - ulating the sale of these habit-forming drugs ought to be more stringent, and that there ought to be a rigid inspection of all places dealing in these habit-forming drugs. To this end I recommend the passage of an act which will authorize the food, drug, dairy and oil commission to make inspections of drug stores, and requiring all druggists to keep a correct record of the sale of these drugs. Live Stock. I have, from the first, advocated the consolidation of de- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 5 put this policy in operation, it has shown a saving in expense and an improvement in efficiency. As the statute stands to - day, the state veterinary department is controlled by the sanitary live stock board, while the stallion registration de - partment is controlled by still a different board, although there is a sort of interlocking working arrangement. Re - sponsibility ought to be placed with one board or another, and I recommend that the statutes be so amended that these two boards be consolidated. I feel, too, that the law regulat - ing the inspection of stallions should be so amended that an inspection be made only every three years, and that inspec - tions made during the past biennium be validated for the term of three years from the inspection. The swine industry of this state is an important one, and every encouragement should be given for its further development. I hope you will make provision for the manufacture of anti-cholera serum and provide for its sale to farmers at actual cost. Bacteriological Laboratory. Having observed the work in the bacteriological laboratory for nearly two years, and having had to do with the law gOT - erning this work. I am convinced that the present law is very bunglesome. As it stands today, there is no one in control. The supervisor has a double set of officers over him, without being directly responsible to anybody. This law ought to be so amended as to take this bureau entirely out of the jurisdiction of the board of secretaries of the state board of health, and place it under the direction of the board of health proper. State Finances. Our state finances are in excellent condition. No de - ficiencies of any consequence exist in any department of the state. Our institutions are probably in better condition than ever before in our history. We have acquired more farm </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GOVERNORS MESSAGE caring for our wards. However, I believe, it advisable to secure more farm land in connection with certain of our in - stitutions, notably our penitentiary. Our capitol building has been put in repair and is now adequate for all our immediate demands. Two years ago we found a floating debt against the state, the buildings at the various institutions dilapidated ami erally out of repair and no adequate provision made for tin - extension of our normal schools and university. Appropria - tions were then made to pay our floating debt and to put our buildings and institutions in good repair, and provision was made for the growth of our normal schools and university. I believe the time is at hand when we may well reduce our appropriations. To this end, I ask that appropriation bills be carefully scrutinized and that no money be appropriated except where absolute necessity exists. State University. r state university, which is both our largest and our expensive institution, has long been a subject of much discussion and contention. I congratulate the friends of this institution upon the settlement of all strife connected with its location. By direct vote of the people, it has been determined that this institution shall be maintained upon its present site. With this question settled, the development of the university ought to go forward, the necessary buildings be erected, and an institution developed that will be the pride of our state. Printing. The printing of the reports of the various departments ap - peals to me as a bunglesome and extravagant method of get - ting such facts before the people as would be of interest to Pere is a disposition on the part of certain departments to llish their reports with high grade engravings of the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 7 officials past and present, ami other subjects, all of which though very pleasing to the eye, are an unnecessary ex to the state. I will give one report for example: Th&gt; biennial report of one of the departments contained 780 ; and cost $1,162.20 for 1,000 copies. This work has about pages of half-tone inserts; 116 pages of normal training high schools, most or all of which had been previously issued in bulletin form; 2 pages of fire prevention, which is doubtless issued by the fire commisison in bulletin form and sent to all schools; reports, addresses of prominent school men and women occupy a large number of pages, which is of doubtful value unless the report is put into the hands of the general public. tThis is not possible where the issue is limited to 1,000 copies, d it is undoubtedly true that all of these matters ha 1 ready reached the public through the various school publica - tions and the secular press. What is true of this department is also true, of most of the others, except that they do not get out as exhaustive reports. I selected this because it was the largest and would give the greatest range of subjects that I wished to report upon. To go over all the others in detail, there being approximately twenty of them, including annual reports and other publications of a similar nature, would make this report too lengthy ; hence I have thought it best to make suggestions for the betterment of the present condition rather than to give unlimited figures on the cost of what has been done. This character of printing now approximates $25,000 a bi - ennium, and I suggest that instead of publishing a large num - ber of separate reports for each department, that a single volume might be produced in the form of a blue book of biennial publication that would contain all the important facts in condensed form in a more comprehensive shape without duplication and useless verbiage, that would answer every Ee to which the various reports are now put. A larger r would be required, it is true, and they should be well to present a creditable appearance in comparison with </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GOVERNORS MESSAGE similar works from other states in the public libraries 01 the nation, but even so, the work could be published for $5,000, making a direct saving to the state of approximately $20,000 tTo do this intelligently and economically, it would be neces - ry that the work be edited by competent authority that mid be authorized to abbreviate and eliminate the different rts of the work so as not to destroy or mutilate the use - fulness of the reports as state papers. It would seem to me that the legislative reference bureau, or some other statistical department of the state already in existence, would be in a position to do the editing, and with the co-operation of the bureau of printing, a publication of all important state mat - ters might be produced that would be alike creditable and economical compared with present expenditures. This would not interfere with the publication of such bulletins or separate parts of the work as there might be a usual demand for ; these could be issued in the same type used for the large volume, cheaply bound and put out at a minimum price. I have had the assistance of the secretary of the state bureau of printing in this work, as I know him to be competent and painstaking, and have great confidence in the report he has The suitable employment of the inmates of the penitentiary is one of the most serious problems which you will have to face. Experience demonstrates that it is impossible to main - tain proper discipline where men are kept in idleness. We have constantly in this institution, more than 300 able-bodied men. It costs the state much money to maintain the institu - tion, and I believe if properly managed, the institution could be operated without expense to the taxpayers. I am opposed t state convict labor in competition with goods made by free bor. In my opinion the state ought to employ these men in making articles that the state must use, and with this in view, I recommend that a printing plant be established in this insti - tution to do the printing for the state, and for the various </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 9 state institutions, but not be permited to sell any of its pro - ducts. Banking Eterpreted by our supreme court, the laws touching the 1 of banks, enables them to avoid paying their share taxes. This is unfair, and I strongly recommend that the law be so amended that each bank pay its pro rata of the taxes, to maintain our government. The present law is unfair to the great majority of the taxpayers, and these bur - lens ought to be laid alike on all. ranges ought to be made in our banking and investment also. We have found it difficult under some circum - stances, to prevent the organization of companies without paid up capital stock, and in one or two instances where we have refused to grant a charter to companies promising to loan money at 6 per cent and to pay the invester 10 per we have been obliged to go into court to defend our action, and there is still some doubt as to the authority of this board. This law ought to be so written that the board may abso - lutely deny charters to projects of this kind. Bthe matter of granting bank charters, the board also it to be given discretionary powers. Promoters are apt to nize banks where the business of the community will not warrant an increase of banking institutions. They are able to make a very flattering showing to would-be purchasers of stock, and they unload this stock on investors who have had no experience in the banking business and who are unfamiliar with the true needs of the community. There may be ob - jections to placing so much power in the hands of the bank - ing board, and if deemed necessary, suitable provision for an appeal to the courts might be made. State Mileage. ■lough neither myself nor any member of my office I used state mileage, a good deal of mileage 1 by </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 tors in the departments under me. And in these de - partments I have required an itemized report of mileage to be filed with each voucher. I believe this system Mgfct to be installed generally, and that every person who trav. the expense of the state, be required to file an itemized sworn statement, showing exactly when and where the mileage was Four Years Term for State Officers. Kngly believe in the policy of a four-year term for state and in making them ineligible for re-election. In f we can have our business affairs looked after better than when men are elected for a short term, and soon feel the Eessity of preparing for a new campaign in order to secure ■lection. Our Primary Law In theory, our primary law meets the approval of our peo - ple, but like all other human instruments, it has its imper - fections. Our sister states have laws something like our own, yet each one differing somewhat in its provisions. In other t notably South Dakota, party committees are required tify out names before they are printed on the ballot, ve amendments to our law which will provide for some lethod should be made. This will have a tendency to into public service, men of the highest type ; it will it more nearly possible for the people to select, it will . i bring the candidate before the voter with a certificate of his standing, by the people who know him and are acquainted with his qualifications. As our law stands today, the average voter is not acquainted with a large percentage of the men who are candidates for state office, and when he comes to the booth to vote, he has nothing on which to base his choice. No bank or business house would select its em - ployees in this haphazard way. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 11 Our Judiciary. P constitution guarantees to every man liis day in court, is guarantee is of little value if that day is too lorn: Our supreme court docket is now so congested that work is approximately two and one-half years behind. Delay to this extent is often equivalent to a denial of justice. For two years I have watched the work done by jodgM of this court, and am convinced that they are diligent and MO - scientions, striving to the best of their ability, to keep up with the work. Hut despite their industry and persever they are falling farther behind. After careful consider of the situation, I am convinced that the only way to briny; about immediate relief is the creation of a supreme commis - sion, to assist the judges with their work. This is a method that has been resorted to in the past, and while I am aware that it has its limitations and drawbacks, under our present constitution, I see no better means in sight and no other way for clearing up the docket and putting the court once more abreast of its work. I believe that by the creation of a suitable commission, the work now on the docket can be cleared up during the persent bienninm, and that when once the court catches up with current business, by the adoption of a few simple changes in procedure, it will be able to handle the business of the state. Election of Supreme Judges by Districts. And in connection with this suggestion for a court coin - on to bring the work down to date, I desire to strongly urge the submission of a constitutional amendment which will make possible the election of supreme judges by districts. Under the present method where judges are elected from the state at large, it is not possible for voters of the state to have a personal acquaintance with the candidates, nor is it possible for the candidate to make himself known to any considerable number of the voters without a violation of our corrupt prac- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE tices act, and incurring a serious financial drain upon his resources. tin drafting this proposed amendment, provisions may also made for the creation of an intermediate court to be com - posed of district judges requiring them to sit from time to time and dispose of certain classes of cases, thereby relieving the supreme court of the duty of passing upon the less im - portant questions of litigation. I am convinced that these judges can be formed into a court of this kind without much Eitional expense, and to the great advantage of our judi - 8ystem. Good Roads. Ke subject of good roads has occupied the attention of our le for several years, but with all the agitation, we do not ar to have attained tangible results. There is nothing that will add more to the value of our state than a genera) system of good roads. A road can be built and maintained in Nebraska, cheaper than almost anywhere else, and a comprehensive road law ought to be enacted, one that will systematize the building and upkeep of onr public highways, and the erection and maintenance of bridges and culverts, so that we may make our highways system a model for our sister states. In this work convict labor may be profitably em - ployed. The penitentiary ought to be so operated that it will work for the permanent reformation of its inmates. An idle man cannot be reformed. Suitable labor must be pro - vided for the inmates of this institution and there are many objections to the contract labor system. A part of this labor can be suitably employed in the manu - facture of articles used exclusive by the state, but it cannot all be so employed, and other means must be found to keep the men busy. I recommend a law which will make it pos - sible to take the inmates of this institution, and under suit - able supervision, find them employment upon the public roads. This will be to their benefit and to the lasting good of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 13 Game and Fish. Since our game and fish law was enacted, congress has leg - islated on the same subject, and we find that many of the provisions of the federal statute are more restrictive than our own. Periods of the year when game is permitted to be taken in Nebraska, are "closed seasons" under the federal statute. The result is that parties taking a license under the state law, and believing themselves fully protected, and en - titled to take game during the period designated in their license, find themselves violating this federal statute. It is well known that where there is a conflict between the state and the federal statutes, the federal laws prevail. But it is unfair to the man who possesses a license under the state law and believes he has the right to fish and hunt, for the period thereon stated, to find himself a violator of the federal statute. I. therefore, recommend such changes in our laws as will make it work in harmony with the federal law. The Schools Out of Politics. Two years ago, by the enactment of the non-partisan jiuli - ciary law, we took the courts of the state out of politics. This was a long step forward, and so far as I have been al&gt;lt&gt; to learn, it meets with almost universal approval. I feel that it is now our duty to take another advance step. The stability of a republican form of government depends upon the intel - ligence of its citizenship and this intelligence is fostered and developed by our public school system. The schools, how cannot do their best work when enmeshed in party politics. Like the courts, they ought to be free and above party politics, and I, therefore, recommend the enactment of a law for the nomination and election of our school superintendents, county and state, similar to that under which we now elect our judiciarv </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Public Warehouse Law. Iae of the pledget made in the democratic platform, is the tment of a public warehouse law. The question is too plex, to permit me to treat in detail, an enactment of this 1, but some of our sister states already have statutes of kind, and I am sure that by studying these, together with an investigation of the success they have achieved where tried will enable you to enact a statute which will be fair to all. It will enable the Nebraska farmer to store his grain after harvest, and to wait, if he so desires, an advance in the mar - ket price, which generally occurs later in the season. Proper safeguards ought to be thrown around this law,, so that the farmer who stores his grain will not suffer the loss thereof in case of the failure of the warehouse man. I would suggest that before the warehouse man be permitted to accept the grain for storage, that he be required to apply to the state railway commission for a license to do business, and com - pelled to give a bond in sufficient amount to indemnify the seller against his failure, or prevent his sale of the grain with - out the written authorization of the seller. Appropriations to Be Passed During the First Forty Days Eeretofore appropriation bills, although introduced early in session, have been delayed in passage, and held back for action until the conclusion of the session. This has pre - vented members from making the careful investigation of the various items which the public welfare demands. It has often, too, denied the governor the opportunity to make care - ful investigation for the necessity of the various items going to make up the appropriation. Bills carrying vast sums of money have been rushed through under high pressure, just at (time when the members were worn out from their arduous bors, and they are rushed to the governor's office when his desk is already piled with bills waiting for his approval or rejection. This is an unwise and, therefore, an undesirable </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 15 way of transacting business. I believe the rules ought modeled so that appropriation bills be given precedence, ami that they be made a special order of business from time to time, bthat every bill carrying an appropriation ought to be d and in the hands of the governor before the fortieth )f the session. Ey experience as a member of the legislature, as well . ?rience as chief executive, impresses very strongly upon mind the wisdom of such a course as this which I ai: ing, and I desire to urge the same upon you without Public Service Corporations. The increase in population of the state, and the rapid de - velopment of our towns and cities makes the subject of public service corporations important. The method of dealing with this class of property should receive your earnest and careful consideration. Other states have passed legislation that is said to completely and satisfactorily deal with the subject and I recommend that you consider the legislation of these states, as it is unwise to pass eperimental legislation or to adopt new and untried methods, when we may profit by the rience of others. I urge a careful study of the laws of these states, and that these corporations be placed under the juris - diction of our State Railway Commission, and that we adopt a system which will adequately and successfully deal with this far-reaching question. Conservation of Water Power. There is still another matter which I wish to urge for your consideration, and that is the proper conservation and devel - opment of our water power. In my message two years ago, ' ' I am in favor of the conservation of the resources of the state of Nebraska. Among these, is the proper protection of </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE the water power in public streams of this state, and I would recommend that the legislature make a small appropriation for investigation of the water power resources of Nebraska." No appropriation was made, but the house of representa - tives adopted a resolution, authorizing me to appoint a com - mission of five to make an investigation and report. This commission has acted without pay, and has gathered data which is on file in my office. It gives much light on the sub - ject of water power development. I wish it printed and dis - tributed among the members of the legislature for their con - sideration. It shows what other states and countries have done, but as it was not equipped with funds, no surveys were made and no measurements of our waters taken. To learn the possibilities of our water resources, it will be necessary to make exhaustive and comprehensive surveys and measure - ments. This ought to be done, and the investigation should be thorough. Already the federal government has sent ex - perts into southwestern Nebraska who have done some work for the purpose of ascertaining the feasibility of taking the Platte waters in flood times and running them over fertile prairie lands of that section of the state, where the water may be absorbed into the subsoil, to be given up during the crop growing period. I. scheme of this kind I believe to be entirely practicable, while of benefit to the farmer of Nebraska, it will also tect the planter in the south from the freshets alony the Mississippi river. Projects of this kind need federal aid, and I am convinced that in our efforts to develop the water power of the state, we should call for federal aid in making the pre - liminary surveys and investigations. Klvery true American is proud when he contemplates the cements of our American engineers in Panama. This tic undertaking was carried to a successful conclusion by our able corps of army engineers. The war department has, perhaps, the ablest engineering corps in the world, as is demonstrated by the completion of the Panama canal. I see no reason why the people of the several states may not avail </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1915 17 themselves of this talent, and I recommend that by joint resolution you memorialize our representatives in congress to call upon the proper federal department, and secure its aid and co-operation. Either by executive order, or by fed - eral statute, I believe it possible to secure the services of a corps of suitable engineers, having them detailed to work in Nebraska, and have the most thorough investigation made, that we may know definitely what our possibilities are. To make the necessary investigation ourselves will require the outlay of a vast amount of money. Besides, it is doubtful if we, will be able to employ, on reasonable salaries, engineers possessed of the ability and experience of those now in the services of the federal government. Before you grant any new rights or before we embark upon the development of our water power, this information ought to be at hand. Employees. I have great confidence in your desire to keep down the expenses of this session. There has been just complaint made against the old practice of allowing employees pay for two days for one day's service. This has been done on the theory that they are are entitled to extra time when they come back for a little work in the evening. The per diem fixed is generally adequate and in order that this may be absolutely eliminated, I urge the adoption of a rule which will allow pay for only one day for ever calendar day of the session. You will have no trouble in securing help on this basis, and it will effectively stop this abuse. In conclusion, permit me to express my confidence in you as individuals and as a body. I feel that you will exercise your best judgment in dealing with the questions which will come before you. I wish also to say to you and to the people of the state that I am deeply conscious of the great honor conferred upon me in entrusting to me, for another term, the office which I hold. My earnest wish is that we may </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 work together for the common good of the great state «r&lt; Respectfully submitted JOHN II. MOREHEAD. Governor of Nebraska. ADDENDUM. t keeping with Section 9231 of the Revised Statut. jka, I report the number of cases of commutations, par - or reprieves granted during the past biennium : the of convict, nature of crime, date of sentence, and date of clemency. And the same is made a part of this message. EDWARD MORGAL— Rape— Sentenced December 21, 190] — 17 years, had served 12 years; had been in tin* Asylum — clemency recommended by Pardon Bo —Pardoned March 12, 1913. I NINA HARDY — Larceny — Sentenced November 29. 1911 — one to seven years — she was a mother ami her child was very sick — clemency recommended by Pardon Board— Pardoned March 28, 1913. PAIL POWERS— Robbery— Sentenced September 26, 1914— one to ten years — was discovered to be insane and had escaped from an asylum in Ohio — sentence com - muted November 9th, 1914, and he was returned to Ohio. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>