<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, EXPERIMENTS WITH DAIRY HERD.</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 76. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA Vol. XV, Article II. EXPERIMENTS WITH DAIRY HERD. Part I. The Herd Record Part II. Ration Tests for Dairy Cows. Part III. The Best Week in a Cow's Lactation Period. By A. L. Haecker. Distributed Jakua»y 24, 19QS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD ■ F. KEXOWER, lesitLut, Wisner FORELL, Kearney fN C. RICH. Omaha L. TEETERS, Lincoln CALKINS, Kearney ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS B. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Directorand Anima' ffuthanrfma* T. L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and AgncuUunst J. S. DALES, M. PH., Financial Secretary WM W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF K PETERS, D. V. M , Animal Pathologist 2&amp; E. Besset, Ph. D., Botanist S. AVERY, Ph D., Chemist KHAECKER, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman ence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist I H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist B Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulturist . P. STOUT, C. E., Irrigation Engineer . Swezet, M. A., Meteorologist ■ Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman GAIN, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist Perin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm (th&lt; I or M u.,v&lt;..,T.) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Part I. THE HERD RECORD. The dairy herd was founded in October, 1896, by the pur - chase of ten grade Jersey heifers. These young heifers were all about two years old and due to calve in the late fall and early winter. As but a small amount of money was set aside for the purchase of this herd, it was found necessary to ob - tain animals at a nominal cost, and the ten heifers were purchased in southern Wisconsin and delivered in Lincoln at $32 per head. The breeding of this herd can be described briefly as follows: Full-blooded Jersey sires of the same family were used on native stock for several generations, thus producing high grade Jerseys of similar breeding and type. Aside from the ten heifers, two animals were obtained from local parties and were bred differently, one being a full - blooded Jersey, and the other a crossbred with Jersey dam and Shorthorn sire. From the day the herd arrived at the Station, careful rec - ords were kept of each individual, not only as to milk and butter production, but also as to amount and weight of food consumed and weight of animal. In order to obtain accurate weights, the animals were weighed each Monday morning fore being turned to water, thus avoiding variation caused large and small amounts of water consumed. Each milk - ing was weighed and a sample taken of the same immediately after milking. The milk was tested by the Babcock method, and each week's production was recorded as a separate unit in the record book. Under this method it was possible to obtain a weekly balance as to the cow's performance and her condition. During the five years covered by the records, many changes </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 were made in the herd as new animals were purchased and some of the old ones sold. Different breeds and grades were introduced, lmt not with the intent to carry on a lined ex - periment. However, the aim was to select representative inieus of each clu In the following tables a year constitutes a lactation period within the 'limits of twelve consecutive months after the cow's earring. The amount of "estimated" butter is deter - mined from the butter fat by adding the regular one sixth overrun to the butter fat. In order to avoid a great number of figures, the entire record of each member of the herd is condensed and the totals for the year are tjiveu. Table I.—. Herd record Name of Cow. Milk. Pounds. Annie Cora . 6977.25 5734.70 8074.22 Diana . F.lcise. Gertie. Hattie. Io Juno Mabel Ruth 61300.38 Total Average. 6130.04 292.27 340.98 All the members of the herd in the year ls'.»7 were beil with their first calf, except the Jersey cow Uuth which \va. - three years old and with her second calf. a in mi'k and butter for rS Fat. Butter. I Breed of Cow. I I '■'on mis. ] I'vun 313.39 .rade Jersey. 411.0* 312.19 " " 273.79 319 42 17 243.21 238." 1 247.09 288.27 Shorthorn-Jersey cross. 473.24 552.11 Jersey. 3409.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Table II.— Herd ret cord in milk aid butler for /89S. Name of Cow. Milk. Fat. Butter. Breed of Cow. — - Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. Annie 6907.19 314.64 Bess 7528.30 373.78 Cora 7302.15 313.26 Diana 6536.70 3J8.51 Eloise 6912.10 337:23 Gertie 5584.81 284.26 Hattie 5527.45 268.56 Io 5702.56 259.52 Juno 6711.36 259.53 Mabel 7535.21 329 12 Ruth 6385.69 409.73 6907.19 7528.30 7302.15 6036.70 6912.10 5584.81 5527.45 5702.56 5711.36 7535.21 6385.69 314.64 373.78 313.26 3J8.51 337.03 284.26 268.56 259.52 259.53 329 12 409.73 367.03 430.08 315.47 383.26 393.44 331.64 313.32 3U2.77 302.78 383.96 478.02 Grade Jersey. It ti 1 1 it Shorthorn-Jersey cross. Jersey. Total 71633.52 3478.14 71633.52 3478.14 4067.84 Average 6512.14 316.19 6512.14 316.19 368.89 j i The record for 1898 shows th&lt; best average of any in the Gained largely by the favor- :y were all in their se&lt; five years' tests. This can be ex] able condition of the herd. Th lactation and in the best of healt i, while they received rather heavy rations during the winte: ABLE 'ere re&gt; ■on tn nit. an &gt;H &gt;er r ori, '99- Name of Cow. Milk. Fat. Butter. Breed of Cow. Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. Annie Cora Diana 2d Eloise Fannie 2d Hattie Juno 2d Katheleta Lill Mabel Mabel 2d Olive Ruth2d Sady 5250.39 7U99.52 4971.66 5529.47 4188.86 6936.74 1278.76 3977.25 4407.47 6954.86 3446.74 am.K 3402.92 4332.99 251.85 295.92 261.10 251.49 246.29 329 53 52.77 138.65 159.37 310.10 171.66 134.21 210.58 150.93 298.82 345.24 34.62 293.40 287.34 384.46 61.55 161.74 185.9:$ 361.78 200.26 156.58 245.67 176.07 Jersey grade. H II II If ■rd grade. Shorthorn grade. Jersey-Shorthorn cross. Jersey-Shorthorn cross. Hereford grade. Jersey grade. Hereford grade. ToUl 65446.18 ■J964.45 3458 46 4674.73 211.74 247.03 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 During 1899 many changes were made in the herd, as, the introduction of new cows and the disposition of some of the original animals. The cows Katheleta, Lill, Olive, and Sady were range cattle obtained in western Nebraska and had not qnly beef breeding, but a natural tendency to fatten when well fed. The herd made its poorest record this year as a result of the above animals and the cow Juno 2d, which made a very poor yearly record. The cows Annie, Eloise, and Fannie 2d aborted at seveu months, which also caused a shrinkage in their records. Table IV. — Herd record in milk and butter for /goo Through lack of barn room the herd was greatly redi. in 1900, and but seven complete yearly records were obtained. The cows Diamond and Diana 2d were in poor health, which made it necessary to dry them off at six months after Name of Cow. Butter. Breed of Cow. Milk. Fat. Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. .ora )iamond )iana 2d. . lauie label Jymph Luth3d 2772.25 2447.36 5963.23 7779.70 5062.96 4546.38 298.68 157.78 142.32 265.46 318.60 253.33 240.54 348.46 184.08 166.01 309.66 371.70 2H5.55 280.57 Jersey grade. Jersey. Grade Jersey. " Shorthorn-Jersey cross. Jersey. Total 35660.78 1676.71 1956.03 Average 5094.39 239.44 279.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 The results obtained from this herd are not abnormal and ABLE 'erd r cord in milk and butler for 190/. Name of Cow. Butter. Milk Fat. Breed of Cow. Pounds. Pounds. Poundi. 341.10 Holstein-Friesian 374.61 Gral 433.66 Jersey. 3S6.63 Grade Jersey. 360.70 4 9"&gt;8 Shorthorn-Jersey cross. 387.96 Holstein-Friesian. 348.81 Jersey. 209.54 269.65 Bessie McKinley 8518.90 Cora 7319.00 Diamond 7065.10 Diana 2d 5434.10 Hattie.... . . C828.50 Mabel 941H.10 Maude 97- Ruth 3d 748120 Snowflake 3380.80 Whitelick 4048 '23 292.37 321.10 373.44 288.54 309.17 4ffc!. 50 332.54 29-1.98 179.61 231.13 Total . I 3534.29 Average . 0928.41 302.94 353.43 In the year 1901, two Holstein-Friesian cows were ad&lt;l&lt;*&lt;l tj the herd — Bessie McKinley, live years old, and Maude, :\vo years old with her first calf. The cow Snowflake which rtas twelve years old failed to be a profitable producer. Ma k 1. the crossbred Shorthorn- Jersey, made her best record luring this year, giving 9,419.10 pounds of milk in eight nonths. Table VI. — Total and average production of herd for pas! five years. Year. L i- 5 ll ll IS |1 I il i — Pounds. I Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. I Pounds. 1897 lsys 18 9 1900 1901 10 11 14 7 10 61300.38 i 71633.52 65446.18 ! 35660.78 69284.13 ■^ . 4o J47 . 03 5094.39 1676.71 239.44 1906. OT 27H.35 6928.41 3029.38 302.94 3534.29 353.43 Average of 52 early records . . 17 . 270.70 315.82 . </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 can be equaled if not surpassed by any farmer or dairyman in Nebraska. No effort was made to crowd or force any ani - mal to a high record, but on the contrary they were fed light rations, and, very often to their disadvantage, were changed suddenly from one feed to another as the character of the feeding experiment might demand. The young stock were principally disposed of in the form of veal, but exceptional heifers from some of the best cows wore saved. It will be seen from Table VI that the average of fifty-two yearly rec - ords was as follows: This includes an average of all the members of the herd, which contained both good and poor producers. It might therefore be interesting as well as instructive to single out a few of the members that made the best records and also others that made the poorest records. [ilk I utter fat 5,833.17 poun 270.70 " utter 315.82 « </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Experiments tcith Dairy Herd. 9 Tabi.* VII — Record of the cow Cora, a high grade Jersey Year Milk. Butter fat. The cow Cora was born November 1, 1894, which makes her eight years old this fall, and it is safe to say she is in her prime. She came fresh August 6 and is now gi eight pounds butter fat per week. Cora is a small cow weighing on an average 725 pounds and is a most economical butter producer. A good example of type is shown by con - trasting the cow Cora with Juno 2d, a cow of similar breed - ing but very different in form. Cora is wedge-shaped as viewed from side and top, and has a deep, well-developed barrel, but at the same time light shoulders and withers. On the other hand, Juno is steer-like in build, with heavy shoulders, and is narrow through barrel. The mammary glands, especially the milk veins, in the cow Cora are exceptionally well developed, branching in sev - eral veins before they enter the abdominal wall. She has light bone and is fine in quality, perhaps too much so, for she has difficulty in holding her own in the herd, being timid and averse to fighting. She has been a regular breeder, dropping a healthy calf every year from the time she was two years old, and keeping in the best of health. She is no doubt a very profitable cow and will probably continue to be so for some years to come. Bounds. Pounds. /W, 1897 1898 1899 1900 1901 8073.82 7307.15 7009.52 7319.00 352.32 313 26 295.92 298.68 321.10 Total r sms.ag 36888.39 1581.28 1844.82 Average . . . . 7377.68 7377.68 316.25 ».N </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 HATTIE. Table VIII— Record of the cow Hatiie, a high grade Jersey Year. Milk. Butter fat. Butter. The cow Hattie is bred very much the same as Cora, but has a little Holstein-Friesian blood several generations back, which accounts for her black and white color. She is a little more rugged than Cora and is coarser of bone, but has much the same type. Hattie weighs on an average about 750 ids. She is also in her prime and is making her best Pounds. Pounds. 1897 5784.80 .896 6527.45 £99 6836.74 .900 5963.23 .901 6S28.50 273.79 263.56 329.53 265.46 309.17 309.66 Total 31040.72 1446 51 1&amp;S7.56 Average 6208.14 289.30 337.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 MABEL. Mabel shows her Shorthorn blood in size and color, weigh - iDg about 950 pounds and having a dark red color, but she gives a rich flow of milk, in this respect resembling the Jer- She has the best five-year record of any cow in the herd as may be seen by a comparison of the tables, giving her high - est yield in 1901. She is at the ] ing a large flow and promises to muke her he&gt; 1 this \&lt; Table IX. '.. — Record oj he cow 1 , a cross: &gt;e 'ersey-. &lt;rt, \om. Year. Milk. Butter fat. Pounds. Pounds. 897 89S 899 900 .901 5734.70 7779.70 9419.10 247.09 329.12 310.10 318.60 402.50 II Total 37423.57 1607.41 Average 7454.71 321 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">ith Dairy Herd. 12 JUNO 2D. Table X.— Record of the cow Juno 2d, a grade Jersey. Milk. Butter fat. Putter Year Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. 1278.76 52.77 61.55 1899 52.77 The cow Judo 2d makes a contrast to the other animals shown, but offers a good example of poor type for dairy pur - poses. Dairymen, look out for the Juno 2ds ! They are expensive to keep and worse to breed from. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experiments with Dairy Herd 13 Table XI. — Record of the cow Ruth, a full-blooded Jersey. Year. Milk. Butter fat. Butter. As the record of the cow Ruth is exceptionally good, it is given here. This cow had a fine dairy type and large ca - pacity. She unfortunately died after her second year and we are not in possession of her picture. Pounds. Pounds. .897 .898 8074.22 6385.69 473.24 409.73 SS r Total 14459.91 882.97 m 97 1020.13 1020.13 Average . . . 7229.96 7229.95 441.48 441.48 510.06 510.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Part II. RATION TESTS FOR DAIRY COWS. |)uring the past few he dairy industry has received ch attention throughout the entire State, and in nties where but u few years ago dairying was praci vy limited degree we now find a pr liter- Be. This condition has no doubt been greatly stimulated the establishment of markets for both milk and cream, rough the development of the skimming stations and the id-separator system, milk, and especially cream, can be rketed as a farm product at nearly any railway depot in State. With the increased interest in dairy husbandry, ch information has been called for regarding native foods I the feeding of them to dairy cows. ALFALFA VS. WILD HAY. Eihe chief grasses used for hay in the State are alfalfa and ;irie or wild grass. These are generally fed as roughness the feeding seasons and many farmers either have an indance of each kind or can obtain them with little diffi - ty. The question as to which hay is the best for milk and ter production is therefore an important one to dairy - a. PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT On January 1, 1902, after the dairy herd had been on dry f&lt;-ed for eight weeks and were in a normal feeding condition, \e cows were selected and divided into two lots. In making the division, care was taken to have each lot about equal as to their production of milk and butter fat. Lot I was put on a ration of alfalfa hay and Lot II on wild hay. Besides all the hay they would eat up clean, each eceived 16 pounds of beets daily and a small grain ration of one-half bran and. one-half corn by weight. f~4 1 ♦• «kta #as1 1# 1# tl ■"!! Ho 1 t* u" </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 weeks and then changed about, Lot I getting wild hay and Lot II alfalfa for another period of six weeks. RESULTS. At the end of twelve weeks the experiment was closed with the following results: Table XII.— Alfalfa vs. wild hay for Period I. Lot I. Six cows fed on alfalfa hay for six weeks Lot II. Six cows fed on wild hay for six weeks. Difference in favor of alfalfa hay Period II. Lot I. Fed wild hay for six weeks . . Lot II. Fed alfalfa hay for six weeks. Difference in favor of alfalfa. Lot I. lost in changing from alfalfa to wild hay Lot II. Lost in changing from wild hay to alfalfa Difference in favor of alfalfa. Lots I and II when fed alfalfa hay produced: Lot I. First six weeks Lot II Second six weeks Twelve cows produced in twelye weeks. Lots I and II when fed wild hay produced: Lot II. First six weeks Lot I. Second six weeks. Twelve cows produced in twelve weeks Diffrrence in lavor of alfalfa hay The decrease of milk and butter pr six weeks of the test was largely due age from advance in lactation, but it will be noticed that the shrinkage was greater when wild hay was fed. When Lot II was changed from wild hay to alfalfa in the starting of the second six weeks, they were at a disadvan - tage, having been reduced in the first six-weeks test. It is hi, '&lt;! Milk produced. pr^u«d. • six wetks. six weeks. . Pounds 5082.40 4962.29 H 120.11 ,» 4760.20 47b0.34 » 20.14 ,, to wild hay . y to alfalfa 322.20 221.95 H 100.25 ... produced: 508-2.40 4780. 34 H ks 9662.71 ■"" roduced: 4962.29 4760.20 « ks 9722.49 502.07 140.25 9.40 I tter pro uction in the second i\\ due 1 ) the natural shrink </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Experiments with Dairy Herd. therefore safe to assume that alfalfa gave even better results than is shown in the above tables. The quality of both alfalfa and wild hay was of the best, the latter being exceptionally fine as a result of the dry season of 1901. The animals in both lots had free acces water and salt during the experiment. It required a little more wild hay than alfalfa hay. This was due to the larger per cent of waste in the former. In live weight the animals changed but slightly, showing a slight increase when on alfalfa. In conclusion, it is evident from the results of the experi - ment that normally cured alfalfa hay is more conduch milk and butter production than wild hay. COEN ENSILAGE VS. SUGAE BEETS. It is well known among feeders of dairy cattle that green or succulent feed is favorable to milk secretion, and a suitable substitute for grass during the winter season is an important factor in the ration. Corn silage and beets are the most common crops used as succulent food stuffs during the feeding period, and to find if possible the comparative value of the two was the aim of the experiment In the winter of 1897, after the herd had been on dry feed for four weeks, they were divided into two lots, of five in each, the lots being about equal as to milk and butter pro - duction. Lot I was given 30 pounds of sugar beets per day, while Lot II received the same amount of corn silage. The bal - ance of the ration was composed of 10 pounds alfalfa hay with a grain ration made up of two parts oats, two parts corn, and two parts wheat bran, and was fed according to the capacities of the cows, ranging from six to ten pounds per day. The experiment lasted for five weeks, at the end of which time the records showed the following results: </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 In forming the two lots, it was impossible to divide them bo that they would be equal in milk and butter fat produc - tion. It was therefore thought advisable to give record of Period I, which was the result of the five weeks before the test started. In Period II, which comprised the time covered by the teat, ■ natural shrinkage took place in both lots, due to advance - ment in lactation. Lot I, it will be seen, produced a little more milk and butter fat than Lot II, but only a-very little more compared with the time required and number of ani - mals used. This test, then, shows a slight difference in favor of corn ensilage, Lot I producing 92.20 pounds milk and 1 pounds butter more than Lot II, the beet fed lot. (his difference might be accounted for by the variation in individual animals through the many conditions that ict dairy cows. The test, however, was made during very arable conditions of weather and good health of all the mals in the test The herd was uncommonly uniform, being two-year-old heifers with their first calf. As to the quality of the food given, the sugar beets were of average grade, while the corn silage was good, all mouldy side or top silage being rejected and only the good ensilage f\ f^ I/O LIHJ 1 vile* L I VC V. vJ?* I ' ' I \ vU ll' U 1 'll, V. \J l 11 viiijiiugc 1 1 abi.e XIII. — Results of five weeks' feeding test with sugar bets and a im silage. Milk. Butter fat. Butter. » Period I. I. Production of five cows for five weeks before test when fed on ensilage. . . . II. Production of five cows for five weeks before test when fed on ensilage Pounds. 3212.50 Pounds. 154.30 Pounds. 180.01 3083.30 148.60 173.37 Difference in favor of Lot I 129.20 5.70 - Period II. 3040. 60 2819.20 147.20 137.20 160.07 Lot I. Five weeks on ensilage Lot II. Five weeks on sugar beets Perence in favor of Lot I erence between Lots I and II, 1 eriod I ... 221.40 129.30 10.00 5.70 1106 6.64 Difference in favor of ensilage 92.20 4.30 ft. 01 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">f« xcith Dairy Herd. 18 tainly mnch cheaper than sugar beets, but the former requiros expensive machinery for cutting and a silo for storing, while sugar beets need only be put in a place where they will not freeze. Ensilage will keep until fresh grass comes in the spring, while it is difficult to keep sugar beets after the last of March. -ION. While corn ensilage gave slightly better results than sugar beets when fed to dairy cows, the difference was so small tint it. is R*i f &lt;* to s'iv thpv 3ro ouitt* ooii*il in fppdinf? vflliif* </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Part III. THE BEST WEEK IN A COWS LACTATION PERIOD. It is often of much importance to know at what time in a cow's lactation she is liable to make her best record. Nearly all of the associations of our improved dairy breeds favor the animals making large milk or butter records. In some cases certain fixed standards are set, as, for example, in the American Jersey Cattle Club Association where fourteen pounds or over of butter is required to admit animals to what is known as the "tested list." In looking over the herd records, it was found that a great variation existed as to the best week of lactation. This vari - ation was not only among certain individual cows but it also existed with the same cow from year to year. In order to get reliable data it was quite evident a large number of records would be required to overcome the vary - ing influence and find a fair average. Minnesota Experi ment Station was therefore called on to co-operate with the Nebraska Station, and they were able to furnish 155 records. This, combined with 84 records from the Nebraska Station, gave a total of 239. Out of this large number of carefully compiled records the following table and results are drawn. It was found that nine-tenths of the cows made their best records during the first ten weeks of lactation and that over one-half made their best records during the first month. The first week is calculated beginning four days after calv - ing, thus making the end of the first week eleven days after calving. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 ■ I J 5 ,5. o 5 h° I I 9 5 - . !l 3 -s * H -z 4 -&lt;; •«'f/# </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 It will be seen from this table that the greatest number of cows on experiment made their best milk flow the third week, while the best butter production was made in the second week. CONCLUSIONS. Prom the results obtained in this test, which bid fair to be average, the second and third weeks of a cow's lactation are the best, and there is not much difference between the two. A cow reaches her highest production of butter fat at an earlier period than she does her greatest milk flow. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>