<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Utlization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VIII. A Comparison of Alfalfa Meal and Artifically Dried Sudan Grass Meal In Rations for Growing Chicks</title>
               <date value="18??">December 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 116 The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VIII. A Comparison of Alfalfa Meal and Artificially Dried Sudan Grass Meal In Rations for Growing Chicks C. W. Ackerson, M. I. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl ) LINCOLN, NEBRASKA | DECEMBER, 1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. The effect of replacing the ten parts of alfalfa meal in a ration with iiriihcially dried Sudan-grass meal on an equivalent protein basis was studied in a growth and body-analysis experiment with two lots of day - old chicks. 2. The chicks of both lots consumed equal amounts of dry matter dur - ing the feeding trial. }. There were no significant differences in the growth rate or composi - tion of the chicks at the end of a six weeks' feeding trial. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VIII. A Comparison of Alfalfa Meal and Artificially Dried Sudan Grass Meal In a Ration for Growing Chicks C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. BUSH, AND F. E. MUSSEHL The past few years have seen a decrease of about 50 per cent in the alfalfa acreage in Nebraska with a like drop in tonnage of hay produced. Sorghums, grown for grain or forage, and Sudan grass have replaced a considerable portion of the lost acreage. With adverse moisture conditions it is necessary to use Sudan grass as an emergency crop for pasture and forage. Digestion coefficients for cattle, sheep, and swine for Sudan grass cut at various stages;of maturity and dried under field conditions rriay be found in the literature. The advent of artificial and quick drying of hays to conserve the carotene present in the green plant led Newlander (1,2) to investigate the digestibility of artificially dried Sudan grass. He used young Sudan grass by making four cuttings during the season and dried it artificially. By this method he obtained hay of higher protein and lower fiber content than is 'the rule in matured hay. ' I PREPARATION OF THE RATIONS At this Station Sudan-grass meals have been prepared from young grass 12 to 18 inches tall. By varying the conditions of cutting and drying, Sudan-grass meals ranging from 12 ——- AUa i fa . m(:a i Sudan - B rass to 25 per cent protein and from 2 ingredients ration meal ration t o 68 mg. per cent of carotene on ;—. ¦ ¦' .- ,—: — .the dry-matter basis have been Lbs. Lbs. obtained. With meals of this type Ground yellow 3,-3! ; available fbr feeding trials it was Shorts" ...... 2oi 20: felt desirable to gain some informa- Bran ......:... 10 10 : tion on their value as substitutes for Pulverized oats..: 10 ¦¦ ;¦ • 10 alfalfa meal in a ration for grow- Alfalfa meal... 10 0_ j ng c hicks. A previous paper of SJSSM 0 :¦.;¦&gt;": this series (3) showed that the sub- Meat meal.'". 5 .'-;¦ 5 . ¦ stitution of ground kalo for the 31 Fish mea1...... 5 5 per cent of ground yellow corn in a Corn gluten meal 5 5 nation has no significant effect on SSd&amp;g r -'- 1 the growth of chicks up to six weeks —— : ——— ; —- of age. . . The purpose of this experiment was to compare the utilization of food elements by growing chicks on two rations differing only by the substi - tution of Sudan-grass meal for alfalfa meal. The Sudan-grass meal was prepared from ¦ locally grown grass cut on August 3 when 12 inches tall. It was dried in a room in subdued light but no heat was used to hasten the process. After it had become air dry it was ground into </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Aorl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 116 a fine meal, which contained 23.0 per cent protein and 15.4 trig, per cent of carotene. It was thus a very good product from the standpoint of pro - tein content, and better than average hay in carotene. The ration used for the basis oi comparison differed from those reported in previous papers of this series by the replacement of soybean meal by corn gluten meal. In pre - paring the rations the protein levels were kept the same by standardizing Table I.— Analyses of the rations. Rj,,„n Wntcr Ash Ninuiicn Calcium Phosphorus /&gt;.&lt;-/. /'.&lt;-/. P.et. P.cl. P.ct. Allall., moil . M »•' 3.35 1.56 0.83 SmUn-Kuy. meal ¦ M ''-2 3-37 lAi °-85 Crude Crude Protein N-frcc Ratio R,,li, m fat liber extract Ca:P Pxt. P.ct. Pxt. Pxt. Altai!., meal U 7.1) 211.V 51.5 1.88 Suil.in-i.ra&gt;&gt; meal ¦»¦! "¦! 21.1) 51.2 1.67 the Sudan-grass meal with starch to the level of the alfalfa meal. These meals furnished 10 per cent of the ration while the balance of the formula was identical. The Sudan-grass and alfalfa meals were each mixed with ul) parts of the base which had been mixed in sufficient quantity for the two rations. After mixing, each ration was pelleted by means of a 5/32 - -inch die. The experimental variable thus lay in the substitution of Sudan grass meal for alfalfa meal. The rations were mixed according to the formulas given, and their compositions are shown in Table 1. EXPERIMENTAL FEEDING The chicks used in this feeding trial were Single Comb White Leghorn chicks chosen in a weight range of 36 to 41 grams with an average initial weight of 39 in each lot. All chicks were fed the same amount of the pelleted rations daily in the manner described in an earlier paper (4). Three chicks of the lot on the Sudan-grass-meal ration did not take the feed at the required rate in the preliminary feeding and were discarded. One chick was lost by accident and another lost during analysis of the final digest. As a result data are available on 22 chicks in the alfalfa-meal and on 17 of the Sudan-grass-meal lot. The chicks carried through the trial were fed identical quantities of feed. They were kept in electrically heated brooders in a room maintained above 70°F. Cod-liver oil was fed in - dividually by burette at a level of 0.5 per cent of the ration. The chicks developed normally, with no evidences of nutritional deficiencies. Wing and toe picking was not in evidence in either lot. Average rates of gain for each sex of both lots are given in Table 2. Incremental and period gains did not vary significantly in the two lots. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">.-'-. ¦ Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks Table 2.— Rates of gain of chicks. Rates ok Gai.v on Successive Increments of Drv Matter Age of chick (_yr). ..¦..;........:, 17 -24 30 35 39 43 Dry matter increment (g.) .;........ '. 143 127 146 136 134 137 Lot Fed Alfalfa-Meal Ratios 8 males, rate of K ain('p.c..;:........ 48 54 48 43 50 27 H females, rate of gain (pxt.)....... 46 48 45 45 44 27 Lot Fed Sudan-Grass-Meal Ration 7 males, rate of gain (pxt.)......... ,47 52 45 41 51 34 11 females, rate of gain fp._ J...... . 47 48 42^^_48 41 .34 Rates of Gain of Chicks, Calculated at Attained Wek-.ut on Gain Over. Initial Weight.-' . Total dry matter fed (g.) :... .:.¦¦.. 143 270 416 552 686 823 Lot Fed Alfalfa-Meal Ration '.'""¦,..,'•'"•' 8 males, rate of gain (pxt.) ....'. -... 48 51 50 48 49 45 14 females, rate of gain (pxt.) .46 47 46 46 45 42 Lot Fed Sudan-Grass-Meal Ration 7 males, rate of gain (pxt.)......... 47 49 48 46 47 45 11 females, rate of gain (pxt.) ..... ¦ .47 47 46 46 45 43 ¦';."'• DISCUSSION The experimental feeding was started February 15 and continued to March 30, at which time the chicks were killed by ether anesthesia. In - dividual live weights were taken and the contents of the digestive tract removed, after which the mean net weight of each chick was noted. The mean net weights of the males of both lots were identical and those of the females agreed within 1.5 per cent, while all values had a low standard error. These data are given in Table 3, while the analytical data are shown in Table 4. From the latter table it is evident that oyer the period Table 3.— Mean net weights ' and their standard errors. '¦:¦¦•'„, -'¦ '_ , Males and females Lot I ;•/¦¦¦¦ ; Males Females (unweignte(l mean ) Alfalfa-meal ration .... J.. ':. ..'..' 396.50+3.67 374.50_2.78 385.50+2.22 Sudan-grass-meal ration .i 396.71+3.93 380.18+3.16 388.45_:2.45 Unweighted mean.......;..;:.. 396.61+2.69 377.34+2.08 386.98+1.64 ¦The net weight ii the weight of the chick after removal of the contents of the digestive tract. . covered by the feeding trial the rate of gain and the gain in weight per gram of nitrogen fed i were not influenced by the rations. Furthermore the differences in the percentages of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus in the gain and the retention of these elements do not vary significantly be - tween the two rations. 1 The slight difference observed in the retention of calcium can be accounted for by the higher intake of calcium in the lot fed the alfalfa-meal ration.! It is to be noted that the amounts retained in the </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 116 Table 4. — Summary of growth and analytical data on chicks. Alfalfa-meal ration Sutlan-grass-mcal ration Male Female Male Female Number ..f chicks 8 14 6 11 Net ueight ig .l 397 374 397 380 Gain in weight fg./ 35" 335 357 341 llrv matter fed (g.l "23 823 823 823 Rate ..I earn I pxt. I 43.4 40.8 43.4 41.4 Gain per gram nitrogen fed Ig.) 11.9 11.2 1 1.8 11.2 Nitrogen in chick ipxl.) 3.53 3.57 3.46 3.48 Calcium in chick Ipxl.) (1.95 0.96 0.96 0.94 Phosphi.ru&gt; in chick Ipxl.) 0-64 0.66 0.66 0.66 Rati,,. Ca-.P in chick 1.49 1.46 1.45 1.43 Nitrogen in gain Ipxt.) -. 3.66 3.70 3.59 3.60 Calcium in g...n Ipxl.) I.M l._ 1.02 1.00 Ph„&gt;ph„rus in gain ipxl.) "-68 0.70 0.70 0.70 Rati... (_!&gt; in gain 1.50 1.46 1.46 1.43 l-.ther extract I pxt.) 3." 3.1 3.9 3.6 Nitrogen intake Ig.) 3(M)5 3(105 30J3 30.33 Nitrogen in gain Ig.) 13.05 12.39 12.80 12.29 Nitrogen retained I pxt.) 43.4 41.2 42.2 40.5 Calcium intake Ig.) UM UM RH UIT Calcium in gain Ig.) if&gt;i 3.43 3.64 3.42 Calcium retained Ipxl.) 253 23.9 27.7 26.0 Phosphorus intake I g.l 7.63 7.63 7.87 7.87 Phosphorus in gain I g.l 2.42 2.35 2.50 2.39 Phosphorus retained I pxt.) 31.7 30.8 31.8 30.4 gain are identical for the two sexes in the two lots. Thus the lot receiv - ing the larger quantity retained a smaller percentage of ingested calcium. It thus appears practical to make use of an emergency forage crop in rations for growing chicks. The protein content of the meal as prepared may appear unusually high but Sudan grass cut at a height of 12 inches is still a very young plant, and it is well established that immature plants have a higher content of protein than older plants when considered on the dry-matter basis. In this connection Prince, Phillips, Blood, and Percival (5) show that while the dry-matter yield increased, the percentage of pro - tein and the yield of protein per acre decreased as the date of cutting of grass hay was advanced from [une 10 to [uly 30. This indicates that if pro - tein feed is required it is advantageous to cut grass hay at an early stage of growth. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks CONCLUSIONS 1. The substitution of an artificially dried Sudan-grass meal for alfalfa meal in a complete ration for growing chicks had no significant effect on the growth rate of White Leghorn chicks up to six weeks of age. 2. The retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus was not sig - nificantly altered by the substitution of Sudan-grass meal for alfalfa meal. 3. Sudan-grass meal, prepared from grass cut at a height of 12 inches and artificially dried can be used to replace the alfalfa meal in a ration for growing chicks. LITERATURE CITED 1. Newlander, J. A. 1935. Vt. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 386. 2. Newlander, J. A. 1935. Vl Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 400. 3. Ackehson, C. W., Hlish, M. J., and Mussehl, F. E. 1939. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 109. 4.: Ackerson, C. W., Blish, M. J., and Mussehl, F. E. 1938. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 100. 5. Prince, F. S., Pjiillips, T. G., Blood, P. T„ and Percival, G. P. 1938. N. H. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 306. i .... . . |2KMI </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>