<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00069.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0069.0003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Final Report OF THE Banking Investigation Authorized by House Rolle No 585</title>
               <date value="1930-08-01">1930-08-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Final Report OF THE Banking Investigation Authorized by House Roll No 585 Beginning May 2 1929 and Ending August 1st 1930 A. C. SHALLENBERGER Chitf Examiner To his Excellency the Governor and the Legislature of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">. To GOVERNOR ARTHUR i. WEAVER, Lincoln, Nebraska. Your Excellency: As required by House Roll No. 585 enacted by the Legislature of Nebraska under which I have been acting, I have the honor to submit to you and to the Legislature, as required by law, the following report of the investigation and audit of failed banks m Nebraska and the various departments charged under state laws with the administration and management of the banking business and the enforcement of the bank - ing laws of Nebraska. 1 was commissioned Chief Examiner by your Excellency to direct the investigation and audit as provided m House .Roll No. 585, ap - proved April 22, 1929. My commission was dated May 2, 1929. Bids and estimates for the work of the audit were considered for about six weeks. The contract to" do the work of auditing and investigation was finally made with The Associated Certified Public Accountants of Nebraska and was signed June 13, 1929. Three managing partners \vtre directly m charge of the audit and making all reports to the Chief Examiner. .The managing partners were Raymond H. Walker, C. P. A, of Lincoln, Henry S. Moeller, C. P. A., of Omaha, and M. J. Holland. C. P. A., of Omaha.- The work of investigation was im - mediately begun by the force of auditors and assistants, conducting the I various audits. Offices were established m the State Capitol at Lincoln, Nebraska. A copy of the contract with The Associated Certified Public Accountants of Nebraska accompanies this ■ report as a part of the record of the investigation! '■-._.'■• I awarded the audit contract to a partnership of Nebraska certified public accountants for the reason that I satisfied myself that they were qualified to do the work. Their bid was much the lowest made, both as to per diem cost and other expenses. lam glad to report that the work of the Nebraska accountants has been thorough and satis - factory.. Actual work by the auditors began m; June, 1929. I had hoped to complete the investigation by July Ist, 1930. Investigation and audits of certain banks and ' departments of banking could not be completed at that date, so I have continued the investigation for an - other month and the work under my direction as Chief Examiner was 'finished on August 1, 1930. The investigation has covered the entire field of state banking m Nebraska. It has included an examination into the operations and management of the Department of Trade and Commerce and an audit of their financial statements, administrative expenses and collection and ' disbursements of the Guaranty Fund assessments. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">During the period from 1919 to May 1, 1929, when the Guarantee Fund Commission was abolished, 270 banks were closed by the Depart - ment of Banking. From May 1, 1929, to July 1, 1930, 83 state banks were closed, or a total of 353 banks failed, since 1919. 225 were closed m the six year period during which the Guarantee Fund Commission operated. Since June, 1929, this office has had under investigation and audit 116 banks, 74 sale asset trusts and the auditors' reports are on file m this office or with the Attorney General for his information. In addition to the above reports the auditors have made to this oflic 7 special reports nn certain bank^ and three general reports as follows: Operation and Disposition of Depositors' Guaranty Fun. l, The Adminis - tration Fund of the Guarantee Fund Commission and the 74 Sale Asset Trusts Fund. This investigation has served its purpose and finished the work it was appointed to do. Every failed bank for which there has been a request for an investigation from depositors'; committees has been audited. Wherever reliable information indicated reasons for an audit, it has been ordered without demand from interested parties. No petitions for further investigations are (m file m this office.- PUBLIC HEARINGS Public hearing? have been hold wherever ■ petitioned for by de - positors' committees. A representative of the .Attorney General's office has attended each hearing to conduct thejlegal examinations and a competent court reporter has made a record of the evidence intro - duced. The record of these hearings is on tile m this ofliee. The public hearings held had a salutary effect on public ; opinion and, together" with the reports of bank audits published m the public press, have given the people the information necessary to a correct understanding of the reasons for the disastrous bank' failures that came upon them. NEW LAW AND NEW POLICY PUT IN FORCE The Department of Trade and Commerce, j acting under th'e new - law recommended by your Excellency, is investigating with its own auditors and examiners, all banks that have .failed since the new law was enacted. The Attorney General is conducting the prosecutions of all violations of the state's banking laws when reported to him. If the present rule of strict administrative supervision, rigid enforcement of banking laws and prompt punishment of those who violate them had been pursued m the past, there would have been no nee-J for the crea - tion of this office. . ADMINISTRATIVE IMPROVEMENT During the year this office has been investigating bank failures, their causes and results., great improvements have taken place both a., to bank management and administrative supervision by the Banking 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Bmvau. Under the management ol the new Banking Commissioner, Mr. George Woods, our banking laws- are being enforced. Past abuses are no longer- permitted. As a consequence, failures are few and should -ioiiii 'be a thing of tin- past. Restoration of sound banking is rapidly building the 'foundation, of public confidence and credit, which is es - sential t&lt;i public- prosperity. The Banking; Commissioner is appointed liii- six years and can only be removed for cause, thereby taking the supervision "of banks out of the field of politics. With banks and hank credits on a sound basis, further expenditure of public money for investigation of past failures where possibilities of prosecution or re - coveri.es are out-law'ed, is unwarranted. 1 wish tv thank your Excellency for the very earnest and un - qualified support you have given me while endeavoring to carry out 1 ..c mandate of the Legislature and the important duties you en - trusted u&gt; me when you appointed me to the management of this office lib Chief Examiner, I have had much valuable assistance from the various departments of state dealing with the state banking business ahd'tho Attorney General's office.' AUTHORITY FOB THIS INVESTIGATION The title- and first section of the Act of the Legislature authorizing the creation of this office defines the purpose of the investigation and audit as follows: •TITLE: - AN ACT relating to banks and banking and providing for an in - vestigation, and audit of the business transactions and activities of the Guarantee Fund Commission, the Department of Trade and Commerce and Bureau of Banking, and receivers of state banks m receivership; providing methods Of procedure and rales and regulations for said investigation and audit; providing that the Attorney General shall give such assistance and help m said investigation and audit as shall be requested by the Governor and that all information arising out of said' investigation and audit -which indicates violation of law, fraud or negligence, shall be reported to the Attorney General . for action; •providing penalties for the violation of this ACT and for failure to comply with the. requests of the Governor and those acting for or with him m conducting .said investigation and audit; providing for a report of said investigation and audit; providing for an appropration of $150,000.00, or as much thereof as may be necessary, for the purpose of carrying out the intent and object of this ACT, and declaring an emergency to exist. 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">BE IT EXACTED BY THE PEOPLE OF THE ' STATE OF NEBRASKA: I Section 1. The Governor of the State of Nebraska is hereby empowered, authorized and directed to cause !at once to be made a thorough investigation and audit of the bjiiiness transactions and activities of: (a) The Guarantee Fund Commission and its members, officers, agents and employees, m connection with the handling and manage - ment of the affairs and assets of such state banks as have come under the control or supervision of the Guarantee Fund Commission since its creation by law. (b) The Department of Trade and Commerce and Bureau of Banking and their officers, agents, examiners and employees, since January 1, 1919, m connection with the supervision and examination of going state banks and the liquidation of failed state banks. (c) All receivers of state banks m receivership, appointed since January 1, 1919. and their agents and employees, m connection with the sale of the assets of said banks and the expense of liquidation. (d) All hearings m this inquiry shall be made public after due notice given, and m so far as practicable, shall be held m the localities where the bank under inquiry is or was located anil doing business. All general hearings shall be held at the State Capitol." GENERAL I'IIU'OSES OF THE AUDIT In conformity with the language and mandate of the ACT, thi* investigation has had certain principal purposes m view: First — The audit of a sufficient number of banks to determine the cause of the many bank failures m Nebraska and to secure evidence of law violations by bank officers that would ] result m the punishment of guilty offenders. Second — To investigate the liquidation and disposition of bank - assets and to protect as far as possible the interests of depositors. I ' ■■ Third — To investigate and report on the. work of the Guarantee Fund Commission as administrators of the affairs of failed banks. i Fourth — To investigate and report on the efficiency and. effective - ness of the supervision and examination of istate banks as conducted by the Department of Trade and Commerce. ■ The auditors' reports on file m this office show the causes and reasons for the bank failures of the past and indicate needed ad - 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">ministrativc reforms necessary to insure sound banking .m. the future. Most of the reforms- recommended have, been enacted into law by the Legislature upon recommendation of your Excellency. The investigation was authorized by Legislative Act to cover a period of ten years beginning with 1919 but, since the Statute of Limitations begins to run against most violations of criminal statutes after three years, I centered the work of the auditors and examiners upon failures since May Ist, 1923, when the ■ Guarantee Fund Com - mission was established. It would be a waste of public money to work on cases that could only result m findings of no value as basis for legal action m the courts because outlawed by Statute of Limitations. . The banks that have failed since the Guarantee Fund Commission si-as abolished by Act of Legislature m May, 1929, are now m the hands of- the Department of Trade and Commerce. A large number of them have been reorganized and reopened under the' law signed by your Excellency and the others are having audited and examined by that department. In all, 37 closed banks have been reorganized and re - opened since May, 1929; 4 as a result of stockholders making satis - factory ;ui alignments with the Department of Banking and 33 by depositors reducing 'their claims m a sufficient amount to absorb the losses m the bank. APPROPRIATION AND EXPENDITURES The Legislature appropriated $150,000.00 for the expenses of the investigation authorized. The entire amount was available for the expenses pf the audit, as well as the costs of the Attorney General's office because of legal actions resulting from the investigation. Some legal expenditures will necessarily continue after the audit is finished. There are -.still pending numerous actions m state courts to recover large sums of money due from stockholders, bank directors and others. Also, many indictments for criminal violations of banking laws are &gt;till pending. To date of August 1, 1930, there has been expended by this office ?yj,027.82 divided as follows: 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">EXPENDITURES OF THE AUDITING j DEPARTMENT Salaries to August 1, 1930 „_ $61827 32 • EXPenSe ! 2^49 $64,080.81 LEGAL EXPENDITURES UNDER DIRECTION OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL Salaries to August 1, 1930 $10,779,82 ExpenSC •■ " MS2JS; $17,232.05 CHIEF EXAMINERS- OFFICE Salaries to August 1. 1930 Sl5 395 34 Expense, including traveling, supplies, ■ postage, telephone, telegraph, express and equipment , , 2 ,319.G2 $17,714.&lt;j6 TOT X I U AL .-. :.$99,02752 There have been varying numbers of auditors and assistants em - ployed. Per diem pay was fixed by contract. The certified public accountants received $20.00 per day when actually at work and ass.stant accountant. $12.50 per day. No charges for expenses while employed m Lincoln were allowed. Actual expenses only whtn on • work outside of Lincoln or Omaha were paid. CAUSES OF HANK FAILURES In my preliminary report, dated March :i, 1030. to your Excellency.' I analyzed at some length the causes of bank failures during the past decade. The reasons stated and conclusions, arrived at were the results of study of the history of banking m Nebraska for the period ' covered by this audit and careful consideration of .the facts disclosed by the investigation. Investigation and study since my preliminary report has only confirmed the statements ami recommendations made m that document. In analyzing almost every bank failure there are important facts and law violations disclosed that pertain to that bank alone,- but there are certain economic causes as well as violations of both statutory law and sound business practice that are constantly disclosed as the under - lying reasons for failures m almost every case. Since the World War economic causes general m scope and character destroyed agricultural 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">and commercial credit and made bankruptcy widespread throughout the middle west with consequent disaster to the banks of Nebraska and to the states surrounding her. . The World War inflated prices, both of land and other property, U&gt; such an extent that a business boom developed which swept many bankers, business men and even farmers into a maelstrom of specula - tion. Standards of values and normal basis of credit were completely lost sicht of and sound business principles were forgotten. Banks were increased m numbers until competition brought disaster because there was not sufficient safe and profitable business for all who were fighting . for it. Land speculation, a most dangerous economic disease for bankers to contract, became epidemic either through loans on lands or by indirect purchases by bank officers. The fall m value of farm property has swept away supposed securities and caused a serious destruction of credit. Federal statistics show that agricultural values shrunk eight billions m one. year. Only the strong, careful and experienced banker could weather this storm. During the war boom period 315 additional state banks were chartered. In the year 1917, one hundred and one new banks were opened and during 1918, one hundred and two more were chartered. The courts decreed that, under the existing law, the State Banking Department could not refuse charters. This decision denied to the state's officers a. power essential to the safety of banking and the security and sufficiency of the Bank Guaranty Fund. The Legislature later passed a law giving the authority to the Banking Department to refuse charters for good cause, requiring officers m management of hanks to secure a license from the Banking Department certifying the bankers' ability and character. This law was suspended by a refer - endum petition and later was defeated by a vote of the people. Subsequently, hundreds of banks were chartered for which there was no economic use and men permitted to operate them who, for want of ability and honesty, have disgraced the business of banking. Too many banks and too few bankers bred bankruptcy m the banking business. The irresistible economic law that unprofitable banks must finally fail or discontinue has reduced the number of state banks to the requirements of banking and commerce. The law now permits the Banking Department to judge as to. the need for a bank m a com - lnunity and as to the ability and. character of the officers. As a result m the past year only one new state bank has been chartered m Nebraska. No one protests that any just demand has been denied. 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">UNSAFE EXPANSION OF CREDIT and dangerous increase m loan, ,„ V j *" extlaor(ii ™'y make competition ru nous bad w T Where t0 ° man - v ba »^ are not enough safe borrowers to absorb t^T T^" "W""?: **"&lt;«• notes m failed bank* wee foun d worth! , m °'' C th " n half of tht ' them were speculator*. not b'nk , n ? * "^ ?IBWi * dishonest and incompetent ££? """^^ "^cultural credit, enforcement were 2 S^K^tS^ " THE GUARANTY LAW ■ Public, if bankers are permitt,, I T *. he d ?P osi *«s and Uit important provisions. TheGu" rant "™. aBI » II » violate m , lst Nebraska established an inZZS T Z " ** b ? nk{ " g ilf tors. The annual a B sessmenT for S ■ Pr °^^ 11 ° f &lt;k '" f '^ based upon federal report of th *?***? ° f Io * Ses ««e during the life of that £tZ s n T'^ '"^ '" natio "al banks fifteen years before the w, boom ■T* " t&lt;lblished ™ «.««. For inaugurated an area of IpLEn 1? '™ I *' ° f ba » fcs «"" - .one, and public con^ri^ M P-io, No bank that can "C - -deparTnTS^C T£ IZZT™ *&gt; ** these =^SMi^S 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">The Guaranty Law brought prosperity and strength to the state banks and saved depositors from losses of millions of dollars. It has been discredited and destroyed by those who should have been its staunchest defenders. Betrayal of their trust by faithless bankers and inefficient supervision nullified, the law and destroyed the confidence it had established. LAX ADMINISTRATION BY DEPARTMENT OF BANKING The Department of Banking Administration is required by law to close Banks .shown insolvent by its .examiners. It is a felony for . officers of a bank to receive deposits after it is insolvent. If an in - solvent bank is permitted to operate, the depositor is grossly deceived and his supposed security becomes a state swindle. In case of failure .stockholders are liable for an additional amount equal to their capital investment. Under . careful supervision the double liability should in - sure liquidation with little loss to depositors. A former Governor .stated m a message to the Legislature that early m his administration his Banking Commissioner reported to him that there were 125 state banks hopelessly insolvent. A Banking Com - missioner of another administration stated to me that a few months after he took office he made a written report that 150 banks were at that date insolvent. Permitting broken banks to run only delayed the deluge. Lax law enforcement did not save the banks. It did cost de - positors large losses and piled up a mountain of bank failures when conditions could no longer be concealed. The greatest blot on our state and national governments is failure to enforce laws enacted for the protection of property and the punishment of crime. THE GUARANTEE FUND COMMISSION The Guarantee Fund Commission was the chief agency of the state for the liquidation of failed, banks during the period covered by this audit and investigation. The Commission first -organized and took onth of office May 4, 1923. It was advocated by bankers and composed of bankers recommended to the Governor by banking groups. The law provided that the Commission took charge and acted for the stock - holders of closed banks when directed to do so by the Department of Trade and Commerce. The Commission was authorized to reopen failed banks, receive and pay out deposits without regard to the solvency of the institution. Every bank so operated showed a continual monthly operating loss and . few reorganizations and sale of closed- banks resulted. from this policy. ■ Delayed liquidations were only profitable to those m charge of them. 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The operation of banks by the Guarantee Fund Commission re - sulted m payment of millions of dollars of discriminations and Ref - erences m payment of deposits. It has been charged that the Com - mission used the funds belonging to the assets of one bank to &gt;ay claims or deposits of another, but the record shows this was not t ue. No breach of trust by the Commissioners was disclosed. by this audit. : Governor Weaver pointed out, m his statement issued when (on - vening the extra session, that m 73 banks operated by the Commis ion there were preferences' paid some depositors to the amount of $5,000,000. It should be said that the Commissioners claim that be 'ore December 1, 1927, it was represented to them by the Department of Trade and Commerce that losses would finally be paid m full from the Guaranty Fund. All unequal preferences m payments to depositors were discontinued after December, 1U27. This audit first disclosed the magnitude of these discriminations. There have been many cases reported to this office of com iro - mises of debts owing to failed banks. Also numerous reports- of sale of lands or property at unfair prices. AH these reports have iieen carefully investigated. The Commission has left a complete and w.H kept set of records showing the history of every transaction per - formed by itself or its agents. Compromises on loans and sale of real estate were all approved by district court judges after being author - ized and reviewed by heads of departments. Because of the constant fall m values during recent years, delay' m sale of land and"&gt;lher assets resulted m severe losses m many cases. DEFICIT IN PAYMENT OF DEPOSITORS From 1909, when the guaranty law was enacted, to 1925, .wh.'ii ;i long series of bank disasters began to undermine the Guaranty I' unii. deposits m Nebraska state banks increased almost 500' per cent. The increases was from 62 million to 272 million dollars. During that p rriod 91 banks closed but depositors suffered no losses. From 191!) to June 30, 1930, 353 state banks were closed m Nebraska. There were 615 state banks m operation m 1908. By 1921 the number was 1,00! , an increase of 394 banks. On June 30, 1930, GO2 state banks rep &gt;rted to the Department of Banking, a decrease of 402 banks from the high water mark of 1921. Liabilities of all banks closed prior to May 1, 1929, when the Guarantee Fund Commission was abolished $ 79,1 00,5 ;i9.7.S Liabilities of banks closed since May 1, 1929 :.. 22,874,(1 :i4.2!l Grand total of Liabilities , , $101,981,4;i4.07 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">In his final report Mr. Van' Peterson, Secretary of the Guarantee Fund Commission, estimated the deficit from the 79 million of liabilities as of May 1, 1929, at 10 millions of dollars. The following is a summary of the consolidated statement of the condition of receiverships of the Department of Trade' and Commerce :is of .lime 30, 11130. 3S OLD RECEIVERSHIPS 1-11 NEW RECEIVERSHIPS 106 DEPARTMENT RECEIVERSHIPS 285 TOTAL NUMBER RECEIVERSHIPS GASH IN BANKS $ 1,644,146.79 ASSETS NOT 'REALIZED: Bills Receivable &#132; ....,=.... ...$1G,892,239.24 Bonds. Stocks &amp; Warrants.. 233,952.02 Furniture &amp; Fixtures ; 313,292.99 Judgments 1,332,165.03 Other Assets _ 710,097.37 Overdrafts 94,053.50 Real Estate '. 3,887,579.20 Acquired &amp; Discovered: Bills Receivable. 262,405.80 . Judgment? ..'. 567,174.74 Other Assets 194,185.60 •Real Estate - , 446,338.22 $24,933,483.80 OPERATING COSTS: ■ General Expense :_. 843,320.78 Le K al Expense '. 363,860.71 1,207,181.49 SUPPLEMENTARY CHARGES: Protection of Real Estate 585,752.51 Interest Paiil 419,576.11 Claims Estab., Not. on Books 2,148,387.69 Claims m Disp., Not on Books 352,274.20 Loss on Assets 16,803,076.10 $20,308,066.61 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CAPITAL IMPAIRMENT 7,278,773.02 $55,371,351.71 LIABILITIES NOT LIQUIDATED: Deposits Not Classified....? 1,517,743.45 . . Preferred Claims 27,689,064.76 , - ■ . Total ■ $29,206,808.21 Claims m Dispute 786 615 78 General Claims "[[ 547,080 20 Bills Payable 225,518.34 Other Liabilities 17 472 18 Bank Overdrafts "''.'.. leWoO TrUSt Funds ' -. 22,810.71 ?30,823,2G0.51 Due Depositors Guaranty Fund ■. $12,553;809.88 Depositors' Final Settlement Fund '245,512.52 T ° tal ■ $12,799. 522.40 SUPPLEMENTARY CREDITS: . Deferred Credits \ $ 864j8W98 Interest Received ; 673,429 28 Real Estate Income , 445,235.89 ■ Realized Thru Assets Disc 231,459 01 Stockholders Liab. Settled 1 Wsso'si &lt;! Iso &lt; , ,« „ - CAPITAL STOCK 1.-09,8.9.81 $ 3,424^48.95 SURPLUS 7,811,125.00 — ■ '512,: 85.85 «55.371,( 51.71 *h n t" 6 f atemCnt of the De Partment of Trade and Commerce " shows that on June 30, 1930, the total amount of allowed clainL on ss tli*: unpaid was - kwZosZ . - ■• 1,644,146.79 Balance due depositors less cash on hand , ■ 527 561&lt;877^ Estimated realization from remaining assets and '■ '' aol ' tBl-4 - -directors and stockholders liabilities... , 7.000,(00.00 Leaving an estimated deficit or loss to depositors of. ... .$20,561,* 8^42" ■ The estimate of realization is arrived at as follows: 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Assets on hand, other" than cash, have a hook value of $24,933, - -•483.80. What they are worth under present conditions is problematical but at least $5,000,000.00 should be realized from them. Stockholders uncollected liability is over $6,000,000.00. Suits for collection of large amounts against directors for approval of illegal loans are pending. $2,000,000.00 should be collected from unpaid liabilities of stockholders and directors. RECEIVERSHIP DEPOSITS The cash on hand shown m the above statement is on deposit m certain banks. On date of July 1, 1930, there was $496,000 still m the hands of receivers of Guarantee Fund Commission banks. Of this anißunt 51G7.223.52 is secured by bonds. Most of the fund is de - posited m reserve banks. All funds of failed banks now m receiver - ship under control of Secretary Bliss of the Department of Trade and Commerce are secured by bonds. The amount of the Department of Trade and Commerce receivership funds on deposit m bonded banks was $1,131,102.02 on July 1, 1930. The Commission Bank reoeiverships are hein X taken over by Secretary Bliss as rapidly as possible. Administration of receiverships was transferred to the Depart - ■ nient o f Trade and Commerce April 30, 1929. Statement of administra - tion, and receipts and disbursements by the Receivership Division of the Department of Trade and Commerce from April, 1929, to June ■ 30, IOSO, follows: ADMINISTRATION FUND . of the Department of Trade &amp; Commerce Receivership Division . April 30, 1929, to June 30, 1930. Cash Receipts and Disbursements Balance transferred May 1, 1929, from Guarantee Fund Commission * no ana en r, . , * Zd,0&lt;59.09 Receipts: Assessments on Department ■ . Receiverships $ 64,709.50 Assessments on Commission Receiverships 31,760.50 Assessments on Old Receiverships 2,908.38 . ' Assessments on Sale Assets '. 7,149.31 Interest on Cash Balances 1,305 94 ■ Miscellaneous ; ..: 109,139.66 $ 132,969.35 ■' </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Disbursements: Expenses Employees' salaries $94,491.50 Employees' traveling expense 17,485.85 Office supplies and printing 4,754.65 Postage 2,730.00 Special Atty. fees and court costs 147.00 . Telephone &amp; telegraph 1,195.70 Employees' Bond Premium.... 845.69 Service contracts 249.45 • Miscellaneous 187.07 $ 122,086.91 Office Equipment Purchased 3,102.79 Revolving Fund 178,46 $ . 125,368.16 BALANCE, JUNE 30, 1930 $ 7,601.19 National Bank of Commerce $2,821.86 Continental National Bank 4,779.33 $7,601.19 CASH COLLECTIONS FROM FAILED STATE BANKS IN NE - BRASKA MADE BY THE DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE SINCE TAKING OVER RECEIVERSHIPS May 1, 1929 to June 30, 1930 Old Receiverships, being those pending when Guarantee Fund Commission created (38 Banks) and Commission Receiverships, being those of which members of the Guarantee Fund Commission were the original receivers. (140 banks) &#132;..'. $ 1,257,239.12 • Department Receiverships, being those banks placed m . Receivership since May 1, 1929, and of which the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Com - merce is the receiver (106 banks) 4,034,768.57 Sale Assets, being those purchased at public sale by the Guarantee Fund Commission and . being liquidated for the benefit of the Depositors Final Settlement Fund (70 trusts) '. 79,938.82 TOTAL &#132;.,..$ 5,371,944.51 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">COMPARATIVE STATEMENT OF ADMINISTRATION COSTS OF RECEIVERSHIPS. UNDER THE MANAGEMENT OF THE GUARANTEE FUND COMMISSION AND FOR A LIKE PERIOD UNDER THE RECEIVERSHIP DIVISION OF THE DEPARTMENT OF . TRADE AND COMMERCE . RECEIVERSHIP DIVISION COSTS Department of Trade and Commerce From May l, 1929, to June 30, 1930 (14 months) Paid from Administration Fund.: $ !2 5 368 16 Paid from State Appropriation _ M^^O $ 142,857.56 GUARANTEE FUND COMMISSION COSTS From March 1; 1928, to May 1, 1929 (the preceding 14 months) Paid from Administration Fund $ 147425 56 Paid from State Appropriation... _± 22,53418 ? 169,961.74 The Legislature made appropriations for payment of expense of the Guarantee Fund Commission as follows: I 109"! • , ? 30,000.00 1025 •• ■ 30,000.00 1927 ; : » 30,000.00 : • ? 90,000.00 Of this amount the Commission expended ...._ 89 627 89 ' Leaving an unexpended balance of ~T Z77" for the six years '"""" ' U At termination of his office as Secretary to the Commission, Mr Van Peterson, submitted to me a statement showing the total cost of : r:^::, under f Guarantee Fund c °— — ent to 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Operating costs of liquidation of 58 banks closed prior to May 4, 1923 ? 1,008,585.99 226 banks closed after May 4, 1923, and prior to May 1, 1929 _ .'. 2,370,312.26 Total operating cost under Commission management :% 3,378,898.25 All costs of liquidation by Guarantee Fund Commission and De - partment of Trade and Commerce such as salaries of receivers, auditors, attorneys' fees, collectors, clerical salaries and administration expenses ■are paid out of the assets of failed banks. All expenses chargeable to this office are paid out of the appropriation made by the Legislature for its use. . STATEMENT SHOWING DIVIDENDS PAID BY THE DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE TO DEPOSITORS IN FAILED BANKS May, 1929 $141,933.81 June, 1929 _ : 148,792.90 July, 1929 72,564.06 August, 1929 152,385.01 September, 1929 227,668.37 October, 1929 234,934.45 November, 1929 _ 232,837.72 December, 1929 302,385.35 January, 1930 , 336,184.67 February, 1930 388,798.67 March, 1930 451,744.42 April, 1930 : 476,350.69 May, 1930 403,787.73 June, 1930 „ '. 713,214.97 Total Dividend payments from Assets $4,281,583.02 ■ Following amounts paid from Depositors Final -Settlement Fund: May, 1930 $129,487.77 Following Dividends paid entirely from the Depositors Final Settlement Fund: May, 1930 ...,....$114,507.55 Total Dividend payments from Depositors Final Settlement Fund : „ 243,995.32 Amount of Dividends on Belated Claims paid daring period of May 1, 1929, to June 30, 1930.! 12,643.17 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">GRAND TOTAL OP DIVIDENDS PAID DURING PERIOD OF MAY 1, 1929, to JUNE 30, 1930 ? 4,538,221.61 In addition to the foregoing Dividends there has been paid to claimants' of the above banks the following: PRIORITY CLAIMS FOR TRUST FUND 5....5130,753.65 SECURED DEPOSITS 282,520.20 413,273.85 TOTAL AMOUNT PAID TO DEPOSITORS $ 4,951,495.36 SUMMARY SHOWING ASSESSMENTS AND DISBURSEMENTS OP THE GUARANTY FUND Total Guaranty Fund Assessments to Jan. 2, 1930 $19,811,378.83 Refunds to Jan. 2, 1930 2,211,258.75 Total charges to banks for Guaranty Fund to Jan. 2, 1930 22,022,637.58 Drafts — Paid by banks for Guaranty Fund to Jan. 2, 1930 — $18,694,668.59 Miscellaneous credits ........ 28,907.62 Total credits allowed banks to Jan. 2, 1930 $18,723,576.21 Due Guaranty Fund Jan. 2, 1930 3,299,061.37 $22,022,637.58 Unpaid assessments due from 'going banks Jan. 2, 1930 2,954,108.59 Unpaid assessments due from closed banks Jan. 2, 1930 344,952.78 Total balance due from banks to Guaranty Fund Jan. 2, 1930 .' % 3,299,061.37 Examination of Guaranty Fund books subsequent to January 2, 1930, shows that on May 28, 1930, drafts were drawn on going banks . aggregating $203,492.22 of which only $21,117.05 was paid by banks. Further disposition of the matter, of unpaid assessments is - awaiting the ruling of the Supreme Court of the United States on the appeal from the decision of the Supreme Court of Nebraska sustaining the validity of the unpaid assessments. AH Guaranty Fund assessments required by law have been made by the Department of Trade and Commerce. 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE Mr. C. C. Bliss, Secretary of the Department of Trade and Com - merce, reports the following summary of cash settlements and re - coveries made by the Department growing out of the banking investi - gation and amounts involved m suits pending to recover from stock - holders and directors. A more detailed statement is attached to this report. SUMMARY OF DEPARTMENT ACTIVITIES . Direct settlements and recoveries collected .....$ 152.19G.0G Collections made by legal department ..: : 14,9(57.10 Total Cash Collections .:....$ 167,163.25 Stockholders double liability suits pending by legal department ....: ..:............::.. ..$ 188,755.00 Directors' liability suits pending , .....:.... ." 688,529.00 Total collections and suits pending S 1,044,447.25 LEGAL ACTIVITIES, TRIALS. INDICTMENTS. CONVICTIONS. RECOVERIES AND SUITS PENDNG During the period of this investigation, the findings and reports by examiners and auditors of this office and that of the Department of Trade and Commerce and the work of the various legal depart - ments under the Attorney General's and Judge Skiles' supervision have resulted m a large number of indictments, trials and convictions followed by prison sentences, lawsuits for recoveries from stockholders, directors, bank officers and others have been instituted. Sufficient fund - to carry on this important work is available m the unexpended balance m the fund appropriated for this investigation. A statement of re - coveries, settlements of prosecutions and other activities of the several legal departments under supervision of the Attorney General's office is attached to this report showing cases growing out of the banking investigation. DEPOSITORS' COMMITTEES Early m his administration, as a result of dissatisfaction of de - positors with past compromises and settlement, Governor Weaver authorized establishment of depositors' committees for each failed bank m receivership. Each committee is given full information con - cerning the receivership and no compromises or settlements are made without their consideration and approval. 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">EXAMINATIONS One of the most' important advances made m supervision is m the character and thoroughness of examinations. All notes and bills receivable are examined and classified and listed so that a banker has ;im inventory and statement of the value of the contents of his note case and the Bureau of Banking has this' classified list of notes for its information. Examinations that were formerly made by one man and were too hurried to be thorough, now require two examiners working two- or more days- to complete them. Examinations are made more frequently, than before. Periods between examinations are still too limj: because much of the time of examiners is taken up -with the affairs of closed banks. This delay will soon be a thing of the past and the whole corps of examiners can be used m supervision of the banks m operation. Notwithstanding the greatly reduced number of banks, a very material increase has been made m the number of bank examiners m the field.. Follow up men are sent out to see that rcommendations (&gt;f the. department are obeyed. and that promises of making good any losses and better management are carried out All expenses of examina - tion and 'supervision by the Bureau of -Banking including the Banking Commissioner's salary are now paid by the banks. Bank examiners should have authority and be instructed to verify the validity and amounts payable of all notes and bills receivable carried as the assets of a bank. They should reconcile depositors' balances and outstanding Certificates "of Deposit when deemed neces - sary. If this practice had been m force heretofore the forgeries and fraudulent bank balances that cost depositors a loss of $800,000.00 m the Wupper bank at Beemer and the long series of forgeries and frauds that wrecked the Monowi Bank and sent its manager to the penitentiary for fifty years would have been prevented. The double liability of stockholders of banks is security m addi - tion to the capital stock to insure the payment of. depositors' claims m case of failure. Experience has proven that only a small portion of the additional liability has been collected from stockholders m the past. If the constitutional amendment is adopted giving broader powers jor legislation to insure immediate payment of stockholders' liability, the Legislature should promptly correct the disclosed weak- 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Respectfully submitted, APPROVED- A ' C ' SHALLE NBERGER, (Signed), ARTHUR J. WEAVER (Si K nod), EXami " er - Governor. County for trial. c.,e n d£. """ *° DhMct Court G^ SaviS^^tt^j^S^^ Ga - bounty. Seiity misapplication. Prelimnarv hi- Z h^ iII&lt;?CTI »"" Gage County for trial . Ca £c pcS; "'" *° DiStHct CoUlt District Court P ollf £^I^^ " 0U "" °™/* over to District C^^^^'^^A^ Boon^t y n?r m l s G Se an Blnr o f E B Ne ; S( r- «^ W "f -ith makin, false entry * ££ o °/ ad . lSh : Nebraska ' Pleaded and paro.ed. V Ki^ p^ ? G " trU 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">years on several co.unts running concurrently, appealed Supreme Court ' where judgment and sentence were sustained. State v. Frank Pilger and Daniel C. Diebler, County Court of Pierce County. Pierce State Bank, Pierce, Nebraska, charged Pilger with embezzlement; Diebler charged with making false entry upon Looks of the bank. . Pilger tried, convicted and sentenced five years m penitentiary. Diebler's case still pending m County Court of Pierce County. . State of Nebraska v. Benson, F. J. Kirchman, Max A. Kirchman, Charles C. Carek, Justina ' Carek and W. H. Kirchman (separate ac - tions). Saunders County Bank, Wahoo, Nebraska. Benson charged with" using bank with intent to defraud, convicted and sentenced to five years m penitentiary. F. J. Kirchman charged with same offense, sentenced to sixty-five years m penitentiary. Max A. Kirchman charged with misapplication of bank's funds plead guilty and sentenced to one-ten years m penitentiary. Charles C. Carek and Justina Carek charged with wilful misapplication and forgery and cases against W. H. Kirchma"n, charging him with using the bank with, intent to de - fii.ud, are pending. State v. Thomas J. Rustic, District Court Dodge County. First State Bank of North Bend. Charged with receiving deposits from persons at the time he knew the bank was insolvent. Kastle acquitted. State v. Peart, District Court of Franklin County. Charged with embezzlement of $6,780.00 from Peoples Bank, Upland, Nebr. Con - victed, now m State Reformatory, Hawthorne Apartment. State v. Elizabeth Brown Hogoboom, District Court of Frontier County. Charged with embezzlement. Convicted. Appeal pending m Supreme Court of Nebraska. State v. Louis Verne Hogoboom, District Court of Frontier County. Charged with aiding and abetting embezzlement. Found not guilty. State v. Westbrook, District Court of .Otoe County. Charged with embezzlement. Convicted. Now serving sentence. This grew out of failure of Dunbar State Bank. State v. Harry D. Hancock, District Court of Thurston County. Charged 'with E. Gerald Hancock and Mike Minarik with making false reports as accessory. Case pending. Now set for September term. State v. E. Gerald Hancock, District Court of Thurston County. Charged with Mike Minarik with making false reports to Banking Department. Case pending and now on list for Septembar term. State v. Mike Minarik, District Court of Thurston County. Charged jointly with E. Gerald Hancock m making false reports of the con - 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">dition of the Thurston State Bank. Case pending and on list for September term. State v. Bert Spearman, District Court of Morrill County. Charged with making false reports to Banking Department. Nebraska State Bank, Bridgeport. Nebr. Defendant convicted. Case pending on appeal to Supreme Court. State v. Robert J. Wilson, District Court of " Morrill County. Charged with false entries m books and reports of Nebraska State Bank. Case dismissed upon conviction of. Spearman. State v. Joseph E. Weir, District Court of Nuckolls County. Charged with receiving deposits when bank insolvent. Case pending. State v. George S. Al.lrieh. District Court of Nuckolls County. Charged with receiving deposits after bank insolvent. Case pending. State v. Wupper. District Court of Cuming County. Charged m a number of counts m embezzlement. Defendant a fugitive, from justice. State v. Johnson, District Court of Scotts Bluff County. Charged with taking bank funds. Case pending. State v. Arthur A. Foreman, District Court Dawson County. 1-1 Counts charging false statements m reports and books. Farmers State Bank, Overton. Nebraska. Defendant under bond to appear at the fall term of court for triaf. State v. William W. Vanatta and Earl R. Vanatta, District Court Morrill County. Bank of Bayard, Bayard, Nebraska. Preliminary hearing pending. State v. Agnes J. Vanatta, District Court of Morrill County, Ne - braska. Bank of Bayard, Bayard, Nebraska. Preliminary hearing pending. State v. Earl R. Vanatta, District Court of Morrill County, Ne - braska. Bank of Bayard, Bayard, Nebraska. Preliminary hearing pending. State v. John W. Fieselman, District Court Morrill County, Ne - braska. Bank of Bayard, Bayard, Nebraska. Preliminary hearing pending. R. 0. Brownell v. T. J. Kastle, District Court of Dodge County, Nebraska. North Bend, Nebraska. ■ Attachment for the recovery of double stock liability. This case was filed m conjunction with Mr. Skiles and Mr. Beynon representing the Guarantee Fund Commission. An attachment was levied upon certain lands and properties m Dodge County, Nebraska, and the case is pending m the District Court of that county. State v. Thomas J. Kastle, District Court of Dodge County, Ne - braska. First State Bank, North Bend, Nebr. Preliminary hearing pending. 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">ft ADMINISTRATION FUND OF THE GUARANTEE FUND COM - MISSION DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE May 4, 1923— December 31, 1929 The Guarantee Fund Commission took oath of office May 4, 1923. RECEIPTS: Assessments— Going Banks $164,212.86 Assessments — New Receiverships..... 123,925.03 Assessments — Old Receiverships 54,478.89 Sale Assets :.... 33,443.77 Interest on Cash Balances '. 6,681.75 Miscellaneous Income .^ 864.94 Assessments Unaccounted For — Sale Assets, New Receiverships &amp; Ol&lt;l Receiverships prior to June HO. 1925 • .'. 191.57 TOTAL RECEIPTS : $383,801.81 DISBURSEMENTS: Expense: ' Salaries $273,860.30 Employees', Miscellaneous Salaries &amp; Traveling Expense.... 58,510.92 Printing, Stationery, Office Supplies and Postage '.. 9,418.17 Advertising— Real Estate 1,514.63 Surety Bond Premiums 2,108.80 Telephone &amp; Telegraph 820.11 Express and Drayage 209.14 . Repairs — Office Machines 128.42 Special Attorney's Fees and Court Cost's .2,852.64 Accountant's Fees 1,603.43 Miscellaneous Office Expense 1,965.07 TOTAL EXPENSE $352,991.63 Office Equipment Purchase... 6,980.49 TOTAL DISBURSEMENTS $359,972.12 Cash Transferred to the Department of Trade and Commerce $ 23,829.00 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">ADMINISTRATION FIJND GUARANTEE FUND COMMISSION May 4, 1923— December 31, 1929 DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE . May 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929 RECEIPTS: . • Cash Transferred from the Guarantee Fund Commission....? 23,829.69 Assessments — Going Banks (Burchard Bank) $ 50.00 Assessments — Department Receiverships (Bliss) , 29,594.50 Assessments — Commission Receiverships (New) 20,550.50 Assessments — Old Receiverships 1,540.00 Assessments — Sale Assets 3,689.11 Interest on Cash Balances - 93.99 Miscellaneous Income 59.83 Total Receipts : 55,577.93 Total Receipts and balances transferred . from Commission : $ 79,407.62 DISBURSEMENTS: Expense: $ 52,876.59 Employees', Miscellaneous Salaries &amp; traveling expense 10,287.15 Printing, Stationery, Office Supplies &amp; Postage 3,868.01 Surety Bond Premiums 322.56 Telephone &amp; Telegraph 674.69 Repairs— Office Machines ~ 201.30 Miscellaneous ... 104.20 Total Expense. „ $68,334.50 Office Equipment Purchased...... 2,042.81 Total Disbursements $70,377.31 Balance due December 31, 1929..... $ 9,030.31 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Cash December 31, 1929: • " Continental National Bank $4,779.33 National Bank of Commerce 3,717.63 . Revolving Fund due from York and Newport Banks 533.35 $9,030.31 SUMMARY Guarantee Fund Commission— May 4, 1923 — April 30, 1929 Department of Trade and Commerce—May 1, 1929— December 31, 1929 UECEIPTS:— May. 4, 1923, to April 30, 1929 " Assessments .....$370,252.12 Interest on Cash Balances 6,681.75 Miscellaneous 867.94 • Total Receipts... : $383,801.81 DISBURSEMENTS:— May 4, 1923, to April 30, 1929 Office Salaries :..$273,860.30 Office Expense :...., '. 79,131.33 Office Equipment 6,980.49 Total Disbursements..... 359,972.12 Cash transferred to Department of Trade and Commerce 23,829.69 RECEIPTS:— May 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929 Assessments : $ 55,424.11 Interest on Cash Balances ....' .93.99 Miscellaneous ■ ■ 59.83 Total Receipts...... :.. $ 55,577.93 $ 79,407.62 DISBURSEMENTS:— May 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929 Office Salaries..'. $ 52,876.59 Office Expense : 15,457.91 Office Equipment : 2,042.81 Total Disbursements : .'. .'. 70,377.31 Cash on hand December 31, 1929 ■ $ 9,030.31 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OX DEPOSITORS' GUARANTY FUXD Mr. A. C. Shallenberger, * August 12, 1930. Chief Examiner, . . ' State Capitol Bide., Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: -":.«t ssfs" r «— - «■• «*£ which con.s is ts of a list of the &lt;v ' h l IT ** tHs r( '" &lt; " t alphabetically, showing the Gu, p , ° f Nebraska ' arra "*'' each, so that any bank desired m ayb iS . "^ " f by certificate number. ' ly loeatec f m Exhibit -.V Respectfully submitted, IcCoUVt°^t\ TED CERTI ™ PUBLIC ACCOLNTANTS OF NEBRASKA By R. H. WALKER, . ' ■ Certified Public Accountant/ scope and Satire of audit s=r r rt-d b^ b rt «r^i?S the assessments for the benefit of th n" * f ° r Statements submitted as a basTs f or t De P°»»t« i « Guaranty Fund, period audited were mtadn. mH i ■ MK " lnmts mat »e during the of minor tapo £L^£^2! t'V^f A '^"-orl examined. &gt;sco\ered ln a few of the statements The assessments shown by tho stntn * pared with those made against nh StatCments examined were com- ' ledger accounts. each ltldmd^ bank as entered m the 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Schedules were prepared from the books of the Department of Trade and Commerce showing the assessments, withdrawals, refunds and other data affecting each of the 1,126 banks contributing to the Depositors' Guaranty Fund. The drafts drawn on these banks, con - stituting withdrawals from the going banks for the payment of losses m failed banks, were checked against the books ov reports of the various receivers who received and disbursed the money to claimants. The refunds made by the various receivers, m the case of receiver - ships, or the -Guarantee Fund Commission,- m the case of "sale asset" trusts to the Department of Trade and Commerce for the benefit of the Guaranty Fund were checked against the books and reports of the receivers and the Guarantee Fund Commission. The cash as shown by the books of the Department of Trade and Commerce to have been on- hand to the credit of the Depositors' Guaranty Fund on January 2, 1930, was verified by certificates obtained from the depositories and examination of bank statements m the case of funds on hand but not deposited until subsequent to this date. We did not verify the balances due the Guaranty Fund from going banks, by, correspondence with them, for the reason that many of the hunks have not credited recent assessments to the Guaranty Fund on their books due to the litigation pending involving the legality of same. The balances due the Guaranty Fund from failed banks represented by the difference between amounts received from the fund and those refunded to it were taken from the books and reports of the various receivers and the total was reconciled with the monies shown to have been- received and disbursed by the books of the Department of Trade ;nd Commerce.. OPERATIONS OF DEPOSITORS' GUARANTY FUND From January 3, 1911, to January 2, 1930. Accompanying this report and designated as Exhibit "A" is a list if the state banks of Nebraska, 1,126 m number, which contributed to the Depositors' Guaranty Fund m accordance with the law which became effective January 3, 1911. This exhibit shows for each bank the transactions, m summary form, between it and the Department of Trade and Commerce on account of the Depositors' Guaranty Fund. Below are shown the grand totals for all banks' during the nineteen year period covered by our audit as shown by Exhibit "A* 1 : total Guaranty Fund Assessments Made!.-. -. $10,811,378.83 Refunds Deposited with Banks by Department of Trade and Commerce 2,211,258.75 Charges Due to Bank' Consolidations 83,614.71 Total Charges to Banks $22,106,252.29 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Drafts Paid by Banks from Assessments and Refunds Made Credits Due to Bank Consolidations [ Miscellaneous Credits to Banks Z~~~Z 28,907.82 Total Credits to Banks J Balances of Unpaid Assessments and Refunds Due Fund January 2, 1930 - -?a Ba B t ks ; ; •■• z $*&amp;$. :- 344,952.78 $ 3,200,061.37 We found that the balances shown to have been due from banks as of January 2, 1930, per the individual ledger accounts kept by the department, were m agreement with the controlling account How - ever, m auditing these accounts we found errors m the accounts of thirteen banks of $195.08. net. which, when corrected/increased the balances shown to have been due from banks' by the same amount We conclude that the controlling account kept by the department was found to be m agreement with the individual balances, m the ledgers because of arbitrary adjustments made therein. The attention of the department will be called to these errors so that corrections may be made. In checking the monies drawn from the various banks by the De - partment of Trade and Commerce for the payment of losses m failed banks, we found that the books and records of the receivers of failed lanks. which were made available to us, showed the receipt of 518.695.101.34, while the books of the Department of Trade and Com - merce show only $18,694,668.59, or a difference of $432.75 The books of the department show less money paid to receivers than the tetter's books show, it will be observed. We were unable to locate the differ - ence because some of the receivers' records were incomplete or missing. In the case of refunds made to the department by receivers, m the case of receiverships, and by the Guarantee Fund Commission, m the case of "sale asset" trusts, arising f rom the. realization of assets m their charge, the department's records show the receipt of $2 250 817.90, while the records of the receivers "and the Guarantee Fund Commjss.on show refunds made " of $2,253,702.93, a difference of 12,885.03. It will be noted that the ,ecords of the department show 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">less money received than those of the ■ receivers and the commission. This difference could not be located from the records available to us. - Of the amount shown by the department's books to have been re - ceived by it from refunds, the sum of $2,208,741.31 was deposited with and charged to the contributing banks. Deposits of these refunds were not made with the contributing banks subsequent to April 29, 1929, although received by the depart - ment. Consequently, the balance of the refunds amounting to $•12,070.59 received by the department to January 2, 1930, not turned back to contributing banks, must be accounted for separately. This is accounted for below: PAID, TO PREFERRED CLAIMANTS OR RECEIVERS IN FAILED HANKS AS FOLLOWS: First State Bank, Litchfield $ 5,000.00 Nebraska State Bank, Milligan 800.00 Farmers State Bank, Cotesfield : 1,016.06 Citizens State Bank, Potter : 18,101.47 Farmers State Bank, Bushnell 522.30 $25,440.43 Cash on Deposit: Continental National Bank, Lincoln $ 2,724.18 Stevens National Bank, Fremont....! 731.93 • . 3,456.11 Cash on Hand: Draft on Receiver, Atlas Bank of Neligh .. 13,179.95 (Deposited m Continental. Nat'l Bank 3-4-30) Error' m Drafts .10 $42,076.59 Accompanying this report and designated as Exhibit "B" is a list of the trusts' which have made refunds to the Department of Trade and Commerce, as shown by its books for the benefit of the Depositors' Guaranty Fund which amounts have, m turn, been deposited and charged to the contributing banks, (except a balance of $732.03 re - maining on hand) during the nineteen year period audited. The total amount thus refunded by receiverships was $2,036,195.53, and the amount refunded by "sale asset" trusts was $173,277.81, a total of $2,209,473.34. Of this total the sum of $732.03 was not de - 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">posited with the contributing banks, leaving $2,208,741 31 as the .mount refunded and deposited from this source. To this amount is added the sum of $2,517.44, likewise deposited, which was obtained f:om amounts previously withdrawn from banks for the purpose o f paying losses m failed banks. The total thus arrived at is $2 211 - -208.75, whu-h is m agreement with the total shown iit Exhibit ' "A" as refunds deposited with banks by the department. It was previously stated herein that the total refunds- made to the (.r ra rtment, according to its books, by receivers and "sale asset" trusts 'vas 52.250.817.90, which amount is $41,344.56 m excess of the amount shown above as having been received by the department from re - covers and "sal,, asset" trusts. This difference consists of refunds made to the department subsequent to April 2'J, 1929, by the following t-usts which monies were accounted for previously herein: Receiverships "Sale Assets" Total Homer State Bank. Homer 3000 . 00 . 3 Wayne County Bank. Sholes $ 1, G 64.&lt;U ,S Ndigh State Bank. Wn 3 ,000.00 .' o Security State Bank. Lynch &#132; . 4,000.00 4 000 00 Atlas Bank. Ne.igh 13j7; , y5 Jj™jW $18,844.5tj 522.. r )00.0() $41,344.56 .™ v to ' a | '-'^'Hi* I'"- the period audited would, therefore'; be divided as follows: Receiverships ....$2,055,040.00 ' Sal, Asset" Trusts . , ; j 05f777 . 8 , $2,250,817.90 Reference is made to Exhibit »C», attached, which shows the failed state banks of Xebraska, m the order of payment,. which re - ceived payments from the Depositors' Guaranty Fund to pay. their losses "8 7n02, c ,r eteen n yt K r Peri ° (l aUditeA These Pil - Vlllcnts a^^te $18 7,021.1 as w,ll be noted. Of this amount $18,691,680.70 was Paul from the proceeds of drafts drawn on and paid by solvent banks Apnl 29 1929, from refunds made to the Guaranty Fund by receiver - ships and "sale asset" trusts, as was set out previously herein. ; Slßfi^/rr^ 1 ,' I'^1 '^ draWn ° ni aml Pai(l b &gt;-' solven t banks was $18.694.b68. a9 during this period, as is shown by Exhibit "V The balance of $3,087.89 thus withdrawn but nof paid to fa ed banks ' pay losses therein is accounted for below: 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Deposited with Contributing Banks " (Considered as Refund) &#132;'. §2,517.44 Check to Bridgeport State Bank (Error m Draft) 459.12 .Check to State Treasurer (Paid m Error) , 94.03 Collection Expense .". 17.24 $3,087.89 ■There/were 125 failed banks during the period audited whose losses were paid from the Depositors' Guaranty Fund, as shown by Exhibit "C", of which number, 81) refunded to the Guaranty Fund a portion of 'the amounts received from, the realization of assets. In addition, the Guarantee Fund Commission m charge of the "sale asset" trusts made refunds to the fund from 30 of these trusts. The largest paymentonade from the Guaranty Fund to any failed bank during the period audited was to the Atlas Bank of Nyligh, Nebraska, m the amount of $800,348.80 and the smallest amount paid was to the Trumbull State Bank of Trumbull, Nebraska, m the amount (!' .?.'J,072.. r )0. The Iju-pest refund made to the Guaranty Fund by receivevships during the period audited was from thei American State Bank of Lincoln. Nebraska, m the amount of $307,358.38 and the smallest amount was $1,000.00 made by each of sixl receiverships. The largest refund made by "sale asset" trusts to the jGuaranty Fund was by ths American Bank of Sidney, Nebraska, m the, amount of $34,250.00. Th:i smallest refund made by these trusts was by the Bostwick State Bank m the amount of $400.00. The balances due from failed banks represented, by the .difference between the amounts paid to them from the Guaranty Fund and the refunds to the fund, plus credits on account of assets purchased by the Guarantee Fund Commission at receivers' sales are shown m Exhibit "D", as shown by the books of the various receivers. These ; mounts aggregate $10,3:50,020.92. The books of the Department of Trade and Commerce are not kept so as; to show the amounts due from failed banks, but we aye able to reconcile the total shown above with the total indicated by data compiled j from the books of the D2 - partment of Trade and Commerce as follows: Payments to Failed Banks from Guaranty; Fund , 518,717,021.13 Refunds from Receiverships 2.055,040.09 . Balance $16,661,981.01 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Deduct: Bid Price of "Sale Assets" Allowed as Credit ! $331,509.37 Difference Between Refunds to Guaranty Fund per books of Receivers and Department of Trade and Commerce 2,885.03 334,304.40 $16,327,586.64 Add: Payments to Receivers by Guarantee Fund Commission from Sale Assets (Considered as Charge) 2J601.53 ■ Difference Between Payments from Guaranty Fund per books of Receivers and Department of Trade and Commerce ■...:....,... 432.75 3,03438 Balance due from Failed Banks per _ Exhibit "D". .. : .....$16,330,620.92 Of the total bid price of the Guarantee Fund Commission for the assets acquired by it at receivers' sales m the amount of $331,509.37, the sum of $195,777.81 has been refunded to the Guaranty Fund, to December 31, 1929, as is shown by our summary report on audit of . 74 "sale asset" trusts dated July 29, 1930. It is estimated that the remaining assets of these "sale asset" trusts had a value of $163,426.91, as cf December 31, 1929, which, would provide for the refund of the balance of the Guaranty Fund's investment therein amounting to $135,731.56 and $27,695.35 m excess thereof. The sum of $2,601.53 has already been paid back to receivers as provided by law for the pay - ment of expenses, which amount has gone to reduce the total payments to failed banks from the Guaranty Fund. The balances due the Depositors' Guaranty Fund for unpaid assessments and refunds from 652 solvent banks on January 2, 1930, was $2,954,108.59, while the balance due from 314. failed banks amounted to $344,952.78 on the same date. Attention is directed to the fact that, m our opinion, the De - partment of Trade and Commerce did not protect the interests of the Depositors' Guaranty Fund, except m a few cases, with reference to the balances due the fund from failed banks, aggregating $344,952.78 on January 2, 1930, by filing claims with the "various District Courts at proper times. These claims would, of course, be classified. as general 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">claims but would share m any amounts [recovered on stockholders' double liability with the preferred and o(her general creditors, ac - cording to. the decisions of the Nebraska Supreme Court on this ques - tion. While the recovery might not have been large by the filing of claims m the case of each failed bank owing the Guaranty Fund, it would have, no doubt, been worth while, • ■ We recommend that claims bo filed jfor these amounts m the . future and that steps be taken to file claims In the case of past failures, where possible. . ■ | During the nineteen year period audited there were 38 regular semi-annual • assessments made against solvent banks aggregating !-w,(580.337.08 and 21 special assessments (aggregating $15,131,041.75, a grand total of $19,811,378.83. This is an average of over one million dollars- per year for the past nineteen years. Drafts were drawn by the Department of Trade and Commerce against these assessments 66 times for amounts aggregating $18,694,668.59. Refunds received from receiverships and "sale asset" trusts by thej department were returned to, and deposited with, solvent banks 27 times m amounts aggregating $2,211,258.75. HOOKS AND RECORDS Our audit of the Depositors' Guaranty Fund, proper, was some - what handicapped by the inadequate books and records kept by the ; Department of Trade and Commerce. . ■ Ledger accounts were kept with eachj solvent bank showing the assessments, -refunds, withdrawals and balances as to each. A con - trolling account was also kept. We have no serious criticism to make of this portion of the' department's records. The other books kept were not adapted to the department's needs and, m fact, only served as memorandum books.- Neither a regular cash book was kept showing the receipts of cash nor was a check register used to entir all checks drawn by the department m connection with the Guaranty Fund. One of the most serious defects m thd accounting records m this department, m our opinion, is the absence of a permanent ■ record containing- accounts with the failed banks which have received pay - ments from the Guaranty Fund. There is 'no record available m this department at present showing the balances' owing the fund from failed banks which have received payments therefrom on account of losses. In our audit we' were obliged to obtain this information from the re - ceivers' books. It is our judgment that the department should keep such records that it will be able to account for all moneys coming under its control 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">m such form that it can be readily verified and comprehended by those interested. We were obliged to spend an unsual amount of time m auditing the records kept to' obtain .and verify the data and information desired. An adequate system would have eliminated a large part of this work. As to the method of keeping documents belonging to the office, we found considerable carelessness and laxity. We could not locate the bank statements from 1914 to 1923, inclusive, and no one seemed to know their whereabouts. Drafts for the earlier years were not available. Some of the statements of average daily deposits submitted, by banks were also missing. No uniform system of filing, such docu - ments seems to have been m use. Needless to say this matter should have attention with a view to correcting such methods. All of the* records pertaining to the department should be systematically filed and kept so that they can be readily examined. The department's officials and employees should desire this for their 1 own protection. REPORT ON THE ADMINISTRATION FUND OK GUARANTY FUND COMMISSION AND THE SECRETARY OK THE DE - PARTMENT OK TRADE AND COMMERCE August 1, 19?&gt;0. Mr. A. C. Shallenberger, Chief Examiner, State Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska. In re: Administration Fund of Guarantee Fund Commission . and its successor, the Secretary- of the Department of Trade and Commerce. Dear Sir: We have audited the books and records of the Guarantee Fund Commission, the Department of Trade and Commerce and the State Auditor, with reference to the Administration Fund of the Guarantee Fund Commission, from May 4, 1923, to April 30, 1929, inclusive, and its successor, the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce from May 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929, inclusive, and present the results of our examination m the accompanying twenty exhibits and schedules of 66 pages, with comments. Respectfully submitted, THE ASSOCIATED CERTIFIED PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS OF NEBRASKA, By M. J. Holland, ... Certified Public Accountant. 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">.■ I ■ COMMENTS ON THE I AUDIT The various sources from which monies] were received and purposes for which disbursed, which may be found m detail m the exhibits and schedules, are condensed m the following! statement, which includes the whole period under examination, as well as the total receipts and disbursements with amounts on hand and available. SUMMARY OF RECEIPTS AND DISBURSEMENTS OF THE ADMINISTRATION AND ADMINISTRATIVE FUNDS MAY 3, 1923. TO DECEMBER 31. 1929 I . "■'.' • ■ ; Receipts i ... ■ &gt; . ■■ Assessments $436,214.46 Appropriations ......■.'.... 99,617.80 Interest on Cash Balances.... 6,775.74 .Miscellaneous :.-, 927.77 Total Receipts $543,535.77 Disbursements Salaries , ..$380,021.35 Office Expenses '. ...-. 142,821.16 Office Equipment 10,462.95 Compensation and Damages 1,200.00 Total Disbursements $534,505.46 Cash in' Banks December 31, 1929 9,030.31 CASH AVAILABLE FOR USE DECEMBER 31. 1929 Appropriation 1929 (Under House Roll 280) $100,000.00 Amount Used L: l 9,989.91 Amount Unexpended ..... 90,010.09 Add: Cash m Banks December 31, 1929 9,030.31 Cash Available for use by Secretary of Department of Trade and Commerce, December 31, 1928 ..... '. $ 99,040.40 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">THE ADMINISTRATION FUND ■For the purpose of this Audit we have included under the term "Administration Fund", the amounts obtained m the manner and from the sources immediately hereafter set out undef I, 11, 111, IV and V. I This item, m a total amount of 54,538.23 as shown by the minutes • of meeting of Guarantee Fund Commission, under date of &gt; May 29, 1923. was derived from an assessment levied and collected &gt;by the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, uiider Section 9, House Roll 272. Guarantee Fund Commission Law of 1923, on all state banks and transferred to the Secretary of the Guarantee Fund Commission for the use thereof as Commission directed. II • This item, m a total of $89,627.89, came from three Legislative appropriations, one under House Roll C 72 m 1923, of $30,000.00 for the "Bureau of Banking support of Guarantee Fund Commission, under provisions of Housi- Roll No. 212", and similar appropriations •of the same amount by the Legislatures &lt;&gt;f 1925 and 1027, under House Rolls 329 and 295. The appropriations were for the Bienniums enilinsr June 30. 1925, 1927 and 1929, respectively, and the amounts used and returned to the State Treasurer were as follows: L'st-d . Returned Date' 1923 Appropriation $29,(M4.G1 $355.39 7-2. r &gt;-2r, 1925 Appropriation 29,997.31 2.&lt;&gt;9 8--211-27 1927 Appropriation 29,985.97 ' 14.03 . 7-30-2.» Totals $89,627.89 5372.1 l 111 This item, m a total of $431,1i7(!.23, was received from what may he terme&lt;l Assessments, made by the Guarantee Fund Commission, on the banks m its charge m the amount of $37"&gt;,252.12, during, the period May 4, 1923, to April 30, 1929, and from assessments made by the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce on all hanks and assets turned over to him by the Guaranty Fund Commission, under section 8, of House Roll No. 249, 1929 laws,' .id other banks for which he was receiver, m the amount of $55,424.11, during the period May 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929. " 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Of this 5376.252.12 received from assessments, and the $7,549.69 from interest and miscellaneous income by the Guarantee Fund Com - mission, the unexpended portion, $23,829.69, was turned over to the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, at the termina - tion of the Guarantee Fund Commission, and of this $23,829.69 and the $55,424.11 received from assessments, with 5153.82 from interest uvd miscellaneous, from -May 1 to -December 31, 1929, there was un - expended at the ck.se of business, December 31, 1929, $9,031.31. IV This item, m a total of $9,989.91 came from a Legislative appro - priation of SIOO.OCO.fIO, under House Roll No. 280 of 1929, under title "Department of Trade and Commerce" for "expense of organization and administration of state receiverships as successor of the Guarantee Furvl Commission, including the checking of all assets m transfer and ■&lt;:&lt;■ ministration of assets and property after transfer." The balance of the $100,000.00 appropriation, after deducting the 59,989.91 used as above indicated, is available, and, we are informed, leink used m the period following December 31, 1929. Under this 'item we include interest received on cash balances m hanks by Guarantee Fund Commission" of $6,681.75 and by Secretary .of Department of Trade and- Commerce of $93.99, makinjr a total inter - est received of $6,775.74, and miscellaneous income of $867.94 received by the Guarantee Fund Commission and $59.83 by the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, making a total miscellaneous income of $927.77. AUTHORITY AND BASIS FOR ASSESSMENTS MADE BY THE GUARANTEE FUND COMMISSION AND SECRETARY OF THE DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE The assessments from which the $37G,252.12 was received by the Guarantee Fund Commission, probably were based on the idea in - corporated m Section 13 of House Roll No. 249 of 1929 laws, which provide the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, shall, from 'time, to time, allocate to the various receiverships the expense, by reason of such receiverships.. ■ They seem to have been based solely on the need of the revenue and the presumption that as the banks and various assets under the super - vision of the Guarantee Fund Commission, as later under the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, were the beneficiaries of 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">the services rendered- and various other items of expense incurred, they were the proper subjects for levy to obtain the revnue. In any event, the assessments were made, and the money expended was received from the banks and various assets under the supervision of the Guarantee Fund Commission, as later was done under the bti-rttary of Department of Trade and Commerce. - The basis for making the assessments was not uniform. That is, it was not wholly a percentage on assets, or a percentage on deposits, end it varied at times from one assessment to another. We are ad - vised it was the purpose to make the assessments so that the charge to each bank or asset would be proportioned m part to the relative \alue cf that bank or asset to the .others, and also m part to the value or benefit received, as well as the relative proportion of the cost. Taking; the different elements into consideration, it is our opinion the assesments were fairly equitably made and the burden shared proportionally by the recipients of the benefits. As previously indicated, the allocation by the Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commero? was specifically authorized m Section 13 of House Roll No. 249 of 1929 laws. TOTAL DISBURSEMENT $534,505.46 The total disbursements of $534,505.46 as shown above are for the entire period, May 4, 1923, to December 31, 1929, and are made up of the items immediately hereafter listed with comment. ' • SALARIES 8380,621.31 This includes all regular salaries paid during the whole period of fh 1 Commission. Salaries' ranged all the way from $10.00 per day to members of the commission and $60.00 to $150.00 per month for stenog - raphers; $250.00 per month for assistant secretary and $850.00 for Counsel; to $625.00 per month for secretary. The increase m number of employees as well as increase m salaries of permanent employees appeared to extend gradually over the whole period. Any information as to any particular person or time during the period may be obtained by referring to schedules accompanying report. OFFICE EXPENSES $142,821.16 This item also includes the whole period and the following items: Employees Miscellaneous,. Salaries and Traveling Expenses....? 98,583.57 Printing, Stationery, Office Supplies . and Postage 24,385.75 Advertising Real Estate :...". 1,514.63 Surety Bond Premiums 3,049.36 ' 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Telephone and Telegraph 7,936.95 Express and Drayage : ; .... 209.14 Repairs — Office Machines . 329.72 Special Attorney Fees and Court Costs : ; 2,852.64 Accountants Fees , 1,603.43 Miscellaneous '. 2,355.97 Total as above .". &#132; $142,821.16 The . salaries included m the first, item above are nearly wholly those of occasional employees m connection with whom our information .as to the parts pertaining to salary and to expense were not clearly defined. OFFICE EQUIPMENT 510,462.95 This includes 'desks, files, typewriters, machines and various other items of equipment. COMPENSATION AND DAMAGES $1,200.00 This item represents amount paid m settlement of claim for damages for injury sustained by an employee while m service of Commission. * CASH IN BANK DECEMBER 31, 1929 $9,031.31 This item was verified by certificates from the depositories, and, • with the balance of appropriation of 1929 m the hands of the State Treasurer, makes up the $99,041.40 cash available for use December 31, 1929. The audit was made m detail, except as otherwise hereafter stated, and covered the whole period from May 4, 1923, when the members of the Guarantee Fund Commission took the oath of office to December 31, 1929. It also included an examination of the records of the State Auditor with reference to the expenditures from the various appropria - tions, as payments for those expenditures were made direct from the State Treasury on warrants for claims duly filed and approved by the State Auditor. " The minutes of the meeting of the Commission were accepted as evidence of payment of the $4,538.23 received from the appropriation under House Roll No. 272 m 1923. BOOKS AND RECORDS Aside from the period covered by the expenditure of the $4,538.23 for May, June, July and August, 1923, to which reference is made m the preceding paragraph, the books and records of the Guarantee Fund Commission, the' Department of Trade and Commerce, and the office of the State Auditor, were m good order with the desired evidence and information readily available. 39 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>