<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Fifth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1922-02-01">1922-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor Februrary I, 1922 LINCOLN. NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (the regents of the university) Hov U \mn D. LAKM, President. Seward Term expires January, 1923 Hon. Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Hon. Run W. Judson, Omaha... Hon. John R. Webster, Omaha .... Hos. William L. Bates, Lodgepule Hon. George N. Seymour, Elgin... Term expires January, 1923 Term expire* January, 1925 Term expires January, 192S Term expires January, 1927 Term expires January, 1927 Samuel Averv, Ph. I)., LL. D., Chan L. E. Gunderson, Finance Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. Burnett, D. So, Director W. \V. Burr, B. Sc., Assistant Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service W \V. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF Arthur Anderson, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy M. J. Blish, Ph. D., Chemistry E. E. BrackETT, B. Sc. in E. E., Associate in Agricultural Engineering V. M. Brouse, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine \V. \V. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy (Chairman) H. P. Davis, M. Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) K. \V. DMMM, B. Sc, Assistant in Entomology H. C Fli.LEY, A. M., Rural Economics (Chairman) R. W. Ck)ss, M. S., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physiology H. J. Gramuch, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) J. W. Hendrickson, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry J. A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture (Chairman) F. D. Keim, M. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy T. A. Kiessei bach. Ph. D., Agronomy W. J. Loeffei., B. Sc., Assistant in Animal Husbandry G. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology John A. Luithly, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry \V. E. Lyness, B. Sc. in Acr., Assistant in Agronomy |. Marsden, B. Sc. Assistant in Poultry H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc, Poultry Husbandry F. R. Nohavec, B. Sc. in A. E., Assistant in Agricultural Engineering G. L. Peltier, Ph. Yi.. Plant Pathology J. O. Raskin, A.M., Assistant in Rural Ecanamus J. C. RUSSEL, M. S., Assistant in Agronomy W. H. Savin, M. S., Assistant in Animal Husbandry O XV. Sjocren, B. Sc. in A. E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) I.. V. Skidmore, rl. Sc in Acr., D. V. M., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte M. H. SWENK, A. M., Entomology (Chairman) L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene (Chairman) E. E. Wehr, M. S., Assistant in Entomology H. O. Werner, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture C. C Wigcans, Ph. D., Assistant in Horticulture 'L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist. North Platte 'By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect Feb - ruary 15, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1. 1899. 5 Detailed from &lt; )ffice of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of At^i culture, Washington, D. C. ellor </seg>
            <seg id="p004">•I'l" f wit i tv-tift n LETTER OF TRAXSMITTAL Tiik I'mvkhsity or Nhikaska To Ilix K.n i Hi in i/. S. R. Mi l\i I I'ii . Governor of A Sir: In accordance with tin 1 art &lt;&gt;f Conjjre March •_'. IMS., ami the act &lt;&gt;f the (reneral .VsseinMv Stah' of N'cl)ra&gt;ka. approved March SI, 1887, estahlishii rcfrulatiiifr experiment station-. I have the boooi submit the Thirty-fifth Annnal Report of the A Experiment Station of Nebraska K. A. Bcbm (iOVKHXOKS CEKTIl'K A II State or Nkiikank a. Kxkutiu. Dei'aktmi Lincoln. Februai Mr. K. .1. K a mi ft. Director Nebraska AyrirultMral h Stut inn : Sir: I hereby acknuwlt&gt;(l&lt;.'f receipt of the Tl Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment S Nebraska. S.\Ml Kl- II. M&lt; Km \ \t dor, , i \&lt;;RI&lt; I LTlTtAL Exi'KlilMKNT STATION February 1. 1922. 1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS 5 Official Roster of the Station S n Leti Gov Con Din Ii ter of Transniittal 4 ernor's Certificate 4 tent* 5 ector's Review estigational Work 7 Adams Projects- Corn Breeding Experiments 7 Water Requirements of Corn 8 Winter Injury Investigations 9 The Life-History of Several Common Cutworms 9 The Study of Degeneracy in Potatoes 10 Hemorrhagic Septicemia. 10 * Study of the Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks 12 A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the De - velopment of Stem Rust, in the Absence of an Alternate Host (Barberry) 13 (Barberry) \ Study of Fusarium Wilt and Tuber Rot of Irish Potatoes in Reference to the Relation of the Environmental Conditions to the Infection and Progress of the Disease 13 Hatch and State Projects — Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies of Small Grains 14 Crop Rotation and Fertilization Experiments 15 Rodent Investigations 15 Investigation and Control of the Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds 16 Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits 16 Fruit Breeding 16 Factors Affecting the Efficiency of Hand Separators and Causes of Variation in Cream Tests ;. 17 Fattening Cattle 17 Roughage as a Feed for Dairy Cows 18 Rations for Fattening Lambs 18 Forage Crop Investigations 19 Tractor Testing 19 Rations for Fattening Hogs 20 Potato Selection for Seed Purposes 21 Inheritance in Egg Production 21 Some Factors Influencing the Palatability of Poultry Feed 22 Cost of Milk Production 22 Cost of Fattening Beef Cattle 22 Farm Tenancy 22 Egg Production 22 Cost of Producing Farm Crops 23 A Comparison of the Feeding Values of White and Yellow Corn.. ..23 Draft Investigations of Farm Machinery 23 The Practicability of a Self-Feeder for Raising Calves 24 A Survey of the Poultry Diseases of Nebraska 3A Soil Acidity Soil Acidity 24 Cooperative Studies with Commercial Fertilizers 25 A Study of the Influence of Certain Physical Qualities of Eggs, Mainly Size and Specific Gravity, on the Fertility, Hatching Power, and Size and Rate of Growth of Chicks 25 Hog Cholera Serum .25 Official Test for Milk and Butter Production. _ XI </seg>
            <seg id="p006">CONTENTS — Continued Page North Platte Substation Crops Spring Grains Pump Irrigation Forestry Horticulture Beef Cattle Hogs Poultry Dairy 28 28 29 :!0 :IO 30 30 ■M) 30 SI :il Valentine Substation Forage Crops Alfalfa Cereal Crops Winter Grain Spring Grain Soy Beans Sunflowers Dairy u Scottsbluff Substation Sugar Beets Potatoes Corn Small Grains Cultural Tests on Sugar Be Soil Fertility Tests Grass Pasture Sweet Clover Pastun Dry Land Crops Lamb Feeding Experiment Needed Investigations Changes in Station Staff Publications Acknowledgments Annual Report of the Agricultural Extension Ser Relationship with Farm Organizations County Agricultural Work Home Demonstration Work Boys and Girls Club Work Agronomy Animal Husbandry Clothing Dairy Husbandry Engineering Farm Management Foods and Nutrition Horticulture Home Health and Hygiene Home Management Market Organizations Poultry Husbandry Rodent Eradication Fairs . 40 4J 13 41 4.'. 4.". M « 4n -IN :&gt;o 50 50 51 52 69 Financial Statement — Agricultural Experiment Station Agricultural Extension Service .".4 68 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT- The year covered by this Report lias approached more Dearly what might lx- called normal conditions than any pre- viou- one for the past WVCtal years. There lias been less change in the /in-xi •nnrl of the Station &gt;tatf an&lt;l consequently less dis- ruption of the inrrntiflrtl—i work. There lias been considera - ble readjustment in the cost of labor and some reduction in the price- of nece— nry supplies. This has permitted some expan - -ion in the investigations! work. On the whole, the year has ' a — — — . — been quite satisfactory. Marked progress has been made on the Viiiioii- problems under investigation, and valuable results, directly bearing upon the ajrriculture of the State, have l&gt;een . — u I — r~ — j " obtained. Many of the results are capable of immediate appli - cation: oilier- serve to throw lijfht on fundamental problems that require further investigation. The importance of fundamental research is clearly shown ie demand that conic- to the Experiment Station for in- formation. A portion of this demand the Station can meet: -nine of ii cannot be answered because the problems are yet un - touched, because of lack either of funds or of trained men to lertakc the investigations. These problems should and will liikcn up as condition! iM'rmit. . • The following report will show most of the major projects ler investigation. IXVEST1GAT10NAL WORK The following i^- a brief summary of some of the more im - rtant line- of investigati il work that arc beinjr carried on • • ■■" " ■ •■■■•■■ "j~" « ••-■• i« • .•■■».» mmii &lt;i m » i^ »iifi &gt; «i i iru UII ma the progresfl that has U»en made. The inrestigational irk i- grouped according to the funds from which the chief pport i&gt; obtained. The Adam&lt; fund is appropriated for re - iirch pnrposes only. Hatdl and State funds may be used for oader line- &lt;&gt;f investigation. ADAMS PROJECTS The iiive-ti&lt;rations under this project are calculated to in - iva-c tlie yield and improve the quality of corn and if possible ■Acknowledgment is due Assistant Director W. W. Burr for the preparation of this Report. Project Xn. II. Com Breeding ExperuBeata. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska A&lt;;rm ti.tirai. Kxi'khimkxt Station 8 to estal)li-h principles of breeding. Study of the rarioas meth - (.d- at can breeding does not indicate a possibility of materially ITWIIBg the yields of corn where a well-adapted variety is already heiag &lt;rro\vn. fMaanrliag &lt;&gt;f alternate row- in the aeed plat does not jrive profitable return-. Competition by increaaing usinir the rate of pl:i nt in&lt;r in the Heed plal ha- failed to inrreaa HIM In type selection the rather leas, -lender ear-, with nlll r lively smooth. flinty kernel-, have given higher yields thai larger ears with deep and xtarchy kernel-. The differeno re&lt;|uir.'iiicnt Cor crop- on fertile -o tar produced than on an infertile aajreuent i- greater on the ferti are prodnred. Reyfional adaptatio type which use- le— water per pi l&gt;ut &gt;how- little water economy win matter produced. .11 of lant than tin' laroer vai en liirnn'd on i ►f ,lrv The following publications have been made on tliis project: IN Aimual Report of the NeKra-ka Agricultural Experiment Station. Transpiration Kxpeiiment- with the Coin Plant: J4th Annual Report. The Relation of Climatic Factors to the Water Used l»y the Corn Plant: also, in the -Mine Report, Correlation tt-riallv tin' vigor &lt;&gt;r productivity of the seed. Iiween the Miiootl) ami mnjrli tvpex bat) bm approximali IT I &gt; 1 1 — 1 i • » 1 ~ per aiic in favor of the -mouther type, ami h M true far three different varieties of ronv ami tin- resu vc been borne mil by irorfc carried oo in different part- of t iU\ 'I he difference i- •&gt;(' Material importance ami thf pri ilf i&gt; capable of immediate application. Dui'ini: ilif fiscal Tear an retentive -tndy wa- made to i mine the prevalence of the disease known a- mot. -t-ilk. ai • rot. Corn wa- brought in ficin many different -action- i State. Investigation iloew noi iiulicate thai ilii- (li&lt;4ea&gt;f me in Nel.ra-ki at this time. A report -iiiiiiiiaii/ini; t ire twelve year- work on corn improvement i- in prtMfss ll i I i il i I preparation. Projertjfo. /.'. Water Requirements of Corn. 'I hi- project i- an attempt to relate the use of water m i lotion to ill tin' kind of rrop. I ■_' i \ariety of crop, i ;'. i pla eluiraeteri-tie-. ( li aeel imat i/at ion. (5) -oil fertility. (&lt;i) climat conditions, and (7) the intake of -oil mlntes. The work of t pa-t fi-eal year the results niitaintnl in pr?vi«i years. I he water requirement varies jrr.'atU from vear to \&lt;-n depentling upon seasonal nmditiftns. It i- in fairly dimi rat to the rate of evaporation from a free water -nrfa.-r. Tile wal i t I i :l 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirty-Fifth Anniai. Rf.port 9 \ ( Studies of (urn: Bulletin 1J S . Nebraska Experiment Station, Studies in Water Requirements of Corn: and Research Bulletin No. •■. Tran-piration as a Factor in Crop Production. Project Xo. 111. Winter Injury Investigations. Thin project was inaugurated to determine the factors, and itivc importance of each, tliat cause winter injury to the root ■ — ■■ » ■ — .-.-. » — ... — j — t . ... — systems of fruit trees. It baa ben found that 1&lt;&gt; to 1"&gt; decrees below freezing, !■'.. is ■ critical temperature for apple tree Mate Mo-I apple -tock-. such as the French Crab, seedling, and Ver - mont -lock-, will l&gt;e injured or killed l&gt;v two hours" exposure to — ■ * — — . i — — [hi- temperature. There is a wide variation in the hardiness of ill of the different apple stock.-. Some individual may Ih' unin- jured by the temperature at which other- are killed. This prol&gt; - ililv accounts for certain individual apple trees Ikmiijt killed in the ml the fir-t year or two after planting. In general, the rion mot- coming from the wood of our lard varieties are aide to withstand more fraexing than the ;- upon which tlie-e tree- are ordinarily propagated. For reason it i- believed that piece root grafted trees will hetter stand our severe winters than lmdded trees, becaasa a larjre rtiofl of the root -ystem of the former will Ih&gt; ptudauad from Midwinter soil temperatures, taken at T 1^ and 10'^ inches k the -inlace. occasionally show (&gt; to in degreea of freezing. more -u&gt;ceptil)le to atmo-|)heric chanjres of tem - »re moi-t soils. This lead- to the conclusion that — danger of winter injury to the root system- of cultural practice- are employed which will tend in ;i moist condition. 1'n'H-t Xt&gt;. '&gt;'!'. The Life Historv of Several Common Cut- l'hi- project was begm in IvlC and has tor its ohject a 1 of the distribution, life history, injury, and methods of ■ol of the numerous gpeciea of cutworms which are found nj tiring crop-, especially corn and alfalfa. In the pa&gt;t lacaj ear the true armv worm and the fall army worm were the uliject- of -pecial -tmlv. Additional data have also l&gt;een se- Hied on about half a dozen other s|H&gt;cies of true cutworms. Considerable work hits ban done in working out means of tell - ing different kiml- of cutworm- apart while in the exceedingly -imilar cutworm stage. It is proposed to continue this project ictivelv for several seasons. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nkhhaska 4—1 III Illlll Experiment Station I'mjci t Xn. .s7. The Study of Degeneracy in Potato 1 -. The objects of this project are (1) to determine the rapidity with which degenerate strains of potatoes may arise when grown on the drv land in western Nebraska. (2) to determine the fac- tor- causing this degeneracy, (3) to determine the most practical methods of producing and selecting seed potatoes, and 1 4) t&lt; isolate high yielding strain This project ha- been in operation for five years, and -e\ ernl of the principal varieties of potatoes rrowa in tin- we-iern part of the State have been included in the study. The work indicates very conclusively that most of the potatoes prows under irrigation in western Nebraska are not suitable for seed purpose*, bul that the potatoes grown under dry land condi- tions, from well-selected -ceil -tock. atv equal for wed purposi to ]ii)tat(K's from any of the important seed potato district* of the country. In case of the Triumph variety, the - I f potatoes grown under irrigation for one year prodHced cent le — yield than did the seed grown under drv land tions. tho-e irritated two years 58.5 per cent le— than t land -eed. ami tlio-c irrigated for three year- produced on jht cent as jjxeat ■ yield a- the dry land -eed. In a where six varietie- were grown on three drv land far four irrigated farm-, the average vield of the seed from st that had been irrigated one year Was 10 per cent tha from the drv land seed for the -ame variety. 1 bam irrigated two years produced : * (| | land seed when grown under irrigation. A carefully conducted experiment in strains of potatoes were u-&lt;-«l indicate- thai potat dry land were superior for seed porpoa \ light irrigation; and these, in turn, were superior to tit ceivinfr medium or heavier irrigation. Seed froi duced under heavy irrigation for one year produced but 66 per cent a&lt; much yield as tin- seed from drv land stock. These data are being compiled for publication as an Experiment St This project is active, and the following phases of tin- pro lein have been studied daring the vear now closini 1. Studies in the pathogenicity of the R bipolaris in cat - tle. Previous attempts to deaaonstrate the pathogenic nature of B. bipohiris were unsuccessful, so far as the production is con- cerned of ■ disease similar to the type alleged to be the result of natural infection. Those ex])erinient- were repeated on a larger bulletin. Projrrf X&lt;&gt;. 87. Ilciiuirrlia'ric Septicemia. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-Fifth Annul Rf.pokt 11 &lt;-ale and with new materials. They are not yet concluded, but 0 tin- present they have shown: (1) That the injection of virulent cultures of B. bipolaris (borim) in normal calves produced only transitory illness, namely, characterized by articular disturl)ance and from which prompt recovery always occurred. _' i Thai when the injection is undertaken in connection a nonfatal anaphvlactic reaction, more severe illness and it ii may result in which it could be shown that the B. bi- •"&gt; I That against such a positive result the repeated injec - with au(o&lt;renous hacteriiis afford no protection. 4) That even under circumstances very favorable to B. iri- pathoir&lt;'iie-i-. it was possible in only one CM to pro - anything like the type of disease described from the Held Thai the apparent proclivity of the organism to local - cause lesions in bones and joints is a prominent dittVr- ii induced and alleged natural infection. Studies of the nature of the immunity against B. bi- igresM i- l)ein&lt;r made with this phase of the problem. ult-- so far obtained show: That immune -ermn against B. bipolaris can ha pre- isual manner. That injections of such sera, either made bv ourselves ed from couunercial sources, protect the animals apuu-t ■ virulent injections That this protection is of but short duration. That in many eases the virus used to test the protection remains latent as lonjr as the serum immunity la-ts suddenly -prints into action and kills sis soon as the That the positive immunity conferred bv the serum is ly not changed into an active one by injections of vim ippa lent material :'.. Studies especially related to the immunization of fowls lin-t fowl cholera. Serum was prepared by the injection of goats with fowl choler;i lilgailil— II Difficulty was experienced thru the fact that the floats as a rule tolerated larjre antigen doses very badly. The senna of the goals, is now being I on rabbit-. Apparently it protected to a considerable extant, but the solidity of the immunity is as yet an unknown quantity. A new series of serum &lt;roats are prepared now and an at- keaths niiiv result in winch it c&lt; Kil;ii'i~ wii- a determining factor. B. bipolar infection. expired. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Aukk ti.ti kai. Kxpkhimknt Station &gt; tpt M made to avoid t lit- breakdown of the animals m tin rse of immunization. The first mtiiim —pin has Won col - lected from those animal- ami will soon be tested in regard to it- potency. &gt;&lt;M&gt;n m possible aft«-r the beginning of the new fiscal r. tests with poultry will U- undertaken. 4. Studio designed to ascertain the role played by B rris m ■ — rce of In-— of Kebnuka live stack, ThoM' studio &lt;■&lt; ni^i — i of l&gt;actfrioli)irif analyses of i icria coming to the laboratory for pw] f diagnosis. ('&lt; i- being diajriu leu for biologic &lt;■- itrarv es — — ■ — . I I to the frequency with which the di ea- This project i- a study of t different ration- have hem U Each lot consisted of ten rigorous Sii &lt; w chick- at the beginning of \ i were obtained each week, an well The following obflervations hav« ( 1 1 Yellow corn ( maize) i&gt; ! I I t alone. Supplementing the corn with \ r iviii of a enable the ash mixture improved the ratioi i Ek&gt;. Tlic three factors under -tu of siidi ration- arc ( 1 ) proteii lit it's, and &lt;:}) f&lt;M&gt;&lt;l Brcessorv tial i|iialitics neemnry for tli- romplel ■ chicks. A deficiency in mh rontenl *« early failure of babv chicfe irhen restrict make slow Inn perxutral prrowth. (•_') Yellow corn i- deficient in quality and quantity of | ti'in required for aormal growth &lt;&gt;f r hicks. 11,, ■ addition IennananK, wrum producers and salesmen for biologic In rarely encountered the 1&gt;. bipolarix in the material* tti'il. An exception lo thi- is ilie ra-e of poultry, iii " disease fowl cholera i a B. bipolari* infection) i- pet ino-t di&gt;a&gt;trou- one in (lie State. The work i- h-in^ ne«l. alt ho we in,' now Katisfrtl thai the disease in swine lie i- imt a probtew of great iirgenry. In (xMiltry the \ i i&gt; of the ino-i ini|)ortanrc and hence we are more and ectinc our attention to the hitter phase of th &gt; pro •"). Mi~cellaiieoii- detail- relating to the pr«»jert. A previous gaapieion that the 15. bipolari* niijrht absorii rv hd&lt;r cli(iler;t vim.- *aa not —»i -t lined by Hiib-&lt;eqiieiit ex Project So. '■&gt;';. A Study of the Nutrient Requir iwins Chick-. &gt;\ r I I &gt; c i! </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-Fifth Axxt ai. Rki&gt;&lt;&gt;rt 13 i i pur i ! Kot \ I) i protein, including em gluten, did not markedly improve efficiency of the corn ration. The addition of 15 per cent tied casein to a ration of yellow corn and ash did improve ration quite decidedly. Supplementing the basal yellow ration with certain other proteins, namely, egg albumen relatin. lowered rather than raised the efficiency of the n. This was probably due to a physical rather than a tivc effect of the ration. Green feed makes certain verv valuable contributions r growing chicks. This improvement of the ra v the addition of wheat gneaw i&gt; probably due to (a) an tnent of the physical condition of the ration, (b) a food &gt;\ v contribution, and (&lt;•) an increased food consumption i stimulatory effect on the appetite. In a comparison of the nutritive qualities of white and corn for growing chick*, better iv-ult- have hen ob - .vith vellow corn than with white corn. maturity in confinement if all nutritive require- r.' met. A Studv of the Environmental Condition* \ •iug tin 1 Development of Stem Bus) in the Absence of an te Ho-t i Barherrv). 1 nt&gt; carried out during the fall, winter, ami spring ivelv that under the conditions prevailing at i-t. on the other hand, was found on a otunber of t the winter. ii- have shown that, while barberry was infected &lt; tin' -i'i-im. the -pi-ead of rust from barberry was lions point to the fact that stem rost c-iine in ither than spread from the barbernr. been made diirinjr the past year in working the life history of sten rust. Constant temperatan sary for the work have been built ami other equip - ■en added. t Project So. /"I. A Study of Fmmrhtm Wilt and Tuber of Irish Potatoes in Reference to the Relation of the Kn - iiiiiental Conditidnu to the Infection and Pragma of the a-t The stuilv has been carried on both in the field and under trolled conditions in the greenhouse. Three different strains rk ilciiiuii-iratc- that it i&gt; po»il&gt;l" to raise cliicks tin- |&gt;n-t wint r waon tin- nreduumpara &lt;&gt;f winter onr and pnulm- • infectioa in &gt;prinp. for further experiments calculated to a&gt;«i&gt;i in </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nkiu;\m\\ A&lt;.rm i in rai. Kxpkrimknt Station 14 IV,,xarinm oxysponm were studied. M well H I new Mram jted in Nebraska the past year. . Striking differences were noted in the symptoms Of tins ase under dry land and irrigation conditions. The progress he di-ease was much more rapid in the presence of high soil IKM-aMiivs and moisture, which together produce conditions t favoral&gt;le for the rotting of the underground portion- ol plant. The prevailing type of infection found in Nebraska eared to be from the -oil. rather than from infected -ed .,-. Infection took place either thru the root- or thru the iii f ; ,v of the -eed piece. The highest percentage was obu rowing the plant- at 18 degrees centigrade until they iral indie- above the grand, il temperature of :'&gt;&lt;'&gt; degrees iture it was found thai the -&lt; linjr rapacity produced men ,. wa- |c— moi-tiire. Tlii- ii moisture content or the soil er which the plant i- more and then transferring t •cntiiri'ade. At the hiirli s() per cent of fected plants ,li.;it - thai temperature t to t disease. It wax al-o found thai t The new -train of b browning extending the length inoculation it has proved to being continued and additional ex| to determine the relation id" poi potato*- to different environmental progres* of the diseases HATCH AND STATE PROJECTS Project \&lt;&gt;. !'■&gt;■ Variety Testing, Breeding, A. tion. anil Cultural Studies of Small (trains. About fifty selected strains of winter wheat an being re - tained from a large number of selection-. A number are being grown for test in field plat&gt;. Daring Ihe pa&gt;t year the Station grew for distrihution considerate amounts of Kanred. Nuhraakl Et porn hi ivact differently u&gt; ten»i&gt;era1 r accounts for the dwcrepanciw foul •t- on living |il;ini- mi rarioas ti- ture cl ml in ■nipen organism. A paper summarizing m portion oi and Iluiniility Studies of the Fnm Iri-h Potato." lia- been published in 1 1 »•• Journ tmal liwiuvli. Vol. i'-'. SO. % |'=&lt;ir-- «5 to 80. th.- ii la Hi m\ &lt;&gt;f Thii - </seg>
            <seg id="p015">I'mitTY-Firm Axmai. Report 15 1 N Nebraska No. «''&lt;) wheat. In our own te&gt;t- and those with farmers then wbaata have proved aaparia* in ilitv to ordinary Turkey Red wheat. Crosses of an •;» t (Nebraska No. •_'*) with hardier wheat- have l&gt;een opes &lt;&gt;f "rettinjr an earlier wheat that is sufficiently i r* r- 1 has satisfactory yielding and milling qualities. . . —^&gt; -• - i — — • Considerable seed of Nebraska No. 21 oats was &lt;rrown at Station and distributed ainonir hlJMtia, A lar&lt;re number »&gt; both Hurt and Texas Red oats have been made rown in the nursery. Each of these varieties is A &lt;-on&gt;ideral&gt;le amount of seed of Minnesota l*t barley was need and has been distributed to farmers. The following ■tin- on wheat and oats have Ihh-ii published: Bulletin No. Tile Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. l'.MVJ; No. 7s. Macaroni Wheats. l«&gt;03; Bulletin No. v_\ The -on Oat. l!&gt;04: Bulletin No. S'.). Winter Wheat. 1905; Bul - \o. lo4. The Us»&gt; of the Fanning Mill for Selecting Seed l\ w Oat-. 190S; Bulletin No. 11:5. Oats. 1910; Bul- \n. ]•_'."). Wheat Breeding Experiment-. 1912; Bulletin No. O-it In\c-tiirations. 1917; Research Bulletin No. 11. Rela- : Size of Seed and Sprout Value to the Yield of Small CroDs. 1 ( .»17. Crop Rotation and Fertilization Ezpari- rk has been removed from the Main Station to the Agronomy Farm and the first year's results have been obtained. U'l,;i.. I I,.. arA\ .it tlw, I ■■!■!■ II. I ■ I.\.,.,,. I. ,,-.&gt;..,, tl,.,r. tl,..t lie soil at the Agronomy Farm is more worn than that Mam Station, we did not find the application of oom- ertilizers profitable under the climatic conditions that iring the pas! year. Some response was shown by the pliorus. hut the beneficial effect was not sufficient application profitable. Thi&gt; work i- now being carried on permanently located )lat-. One hundred and eiirhty-four one-tenth-acre plats are now employed and there are some plat- left over for taking up idditional work if found desirable. Proiert X". -•". Rodent Investigations. This project was l&gt;efrun in 101-2 and has as its object the horo -tudy of the distribution, biology, injury, and means of •ontrol of the more important rodent pests of Nebraska. It in - •ludes four principal lines o f investigation, namely: (1) Hou.se r- r- — — .-• Ider and early type of oati ppliratiom of different fertilizers, e-perinllv nitro- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">XkBKA.nKA At.KK I I.Tl RA1. KxTKRI M EXT STATION 16 ir, i mi ria I twecn thv of rats and mice. {-2) pocket gophers, (3) prairie dogs, and il ground moirrela and kangaroo rats. Daring the fiscal vt ditional data were secured on tin* biology and distribul our Nebraska pocket gopher. With thi- additional mat technical bulletin will -oon be prepared covering quit pletelv the whole pocket gopher problem. Studies \\&lt; made with the around aquirrel. which will !«• th \ Inserts. Mammals, and Bin On this project, during 1 1 1 « • current Tear, t! the western stem maggot was studied. Investigi i parisons of poison baits fm' grasshoppers werec of the life history &lt;&gt;f the crown borer of the -ti ( \ Project Xo. 29. Pruning Apple-. Pe»i t of tin' plants. Ii anil will not. therefor i pruning upon fruit The influence of tin- tr ii so far -••(■in&gt; to indicate tli made ■ greater growth. Sixty The following plan i- Keiiijr folio* (1) Moderate dormant prui loader. ( i! i Moderate dormant pruning, tra &lt;:?) Checks, — no pruning. p (."&gt;) I^i&lt;;lit dormant pruning, with no clipping of lea (r&gt;) Heavy June pruning, with leaders clipped back. &lt; ' — . i *— i r (T) Light summer pruning, leaders not clip] ied. I'ru'i'it X,,. ■!■&gt;. Fruit Breeding. From several hundred crosses that have l&gt;een made 1 commercial varieties of apples and strawberries, eleven hybrid apples and six hybrid itiawberriea have bees deemed wor rodent pests to !»■ taken up. Protest \". 26. Investigation and Control «&gt;f the Ii biting lice present in the St tent ion was also pven to the ■eriously injurious infcstatioi different methods and hud formation, reeulai tin 1 pruning is door i ness dt fruil ins. total of fruiting. Tin- tr more than 800 apple tr&lt;&gt; (4) Heavy dormant pruning, with leaders </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty- Fifth Anniai. Baran 17 irtber trial ami dissemination. A quantity of hybrid straw - rry plant- was placed in the haml&gt; of *X\ MMntMl in the iring of 1921, in an attempt to determine tlu'ir behavior in litferent parts of the State. Apple grafts are l&gt;eiug made this vinter from ten of the hybrid apples, with a view of di&gt;seini- f these hybrids for trial in different part&gt; of the '■&gt;. Factors Affecting the Efficiency of Hand / eparaton and Causes of Variation in Creain Te-t-. From the studies that have !x&gt;en made, it appean that the reinrut of ill t«-riia 1 device- within the l«&gt;wl of the cen - il cream -eparators ha- a marked effect upon the cleanness I when -cparating cold milk. Certain well-known paraton do not in practice skim uj&gt; to their rated i • i - i v. Certain mechanical feature- of separator construc - pparently affect the efficiency of skimming, especially i-e condition-. Additional data are required and the ontinued. Yo. ',/. Fattening Cattl I the i&gt;a-t fiscal year, two different e.\|&gt;eriineiit- were under this --nbhead. EXPERIMENT NO. 1 tc-t involved the ft tiding of thirty head of -teer&gt;. corn - ten two-year-olds, ten yearlings, ami ten calves. These purchased from a angle ranch and were uniformly i w . he object of the experiment \va- to ascertain the effect pon the rate and economy of gain. The steers were hree lot- according to a^re and fed for a period of !\ Their ration ronsisted of corn, ulage, alfalfa, and oil meal. ill lots, l'lie-e feeds were H&lt;riired at the following prices: cut- per bushel, alfalfa *10.(M&gt; per ton. -ilajre fB.00 per iieal s.".(».im) per ton. The average initial weights per head were: for the tw o-year-oldr- 784.8 pounds, yearling! "i&lt;;-_'.-j. calves :"&gt;mi.~. For the 200-day period the average daily gain was: for the two-year-olds, &amp;&amp;] pounds |ht head: for the yearlings. 2.21 : and •_'.(&gt; for the calves. The cost of the gain wa- SV.&gt;4. $7.68, and St'&gt;.;i:5 re-pectively par 100 pounds: the youn&lt;re-t cattle |W&lt;&gt;| ia)g to lie the most economical gainers, indi - cating a consistent decrease in the cost of jrain with the decrea-e in the aga of the cattle. The calves made as muc-h giiin from TT'o pounds of feed as the yearlings did from 86 pounds or the t wo-vear-olds from 100 pounds. These cattle cost nine cents a </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nkbkaska A&lt;;hk i i.n rai. Exi-krimknt Station 18 pound in the feeding lot. They sold in Omaha ;it $8.60, &gt; v . ■*.'.. and !&gt;vii&lt;t res|&gt;fctivelv. for the two-year-olds, yearlings, and calves. On the basis of tlie original rosi. cost of feeding, in - terest on investment, and cost of marketing, the two-year-old steers showed a loss of *10. ."&gt;■_' jmt head, the yearlings ■ profit of M cents par head, and the calves a profit of £4.4&lt;&gt; per head. EXPERIMENT NO Fifty western steer-- were included in 1 1 » i - experiment were fed far a total of Il'7 days. They were divided into lots of ten atom each, and were fed the following ration-: I tiv. n This project is for the purpose of comparing NMCh feed- for dairv cow-. Three lots of three c used in the test. To dale alfalf'.i. -udan m sorjrhum have been compared. The work i- being Project No. 95. Rations for Fattening Lai Daring the past fiscal year six lot&gt;. cent; la nun each, were fed for a period of 112 days,— from No\ 1980, to March 1. 1991,— the object being to ■scertaii he visahility. first, of adding silage to corn and alfalfa ItlOlls second, of feeding molas-e- meal both with and without silage; and. third, of feeding oil meal with and without silage. The following rations were used for the different lots. I.K&gt;t 1. Com and alfalfa. Ij&lt;&gt;t 2. Corn, alfalfa, and silage Lot S, Corn. alfalfa, silage, and alfalfa molasses meal. Ixt 4. Corn, alfalfa, silage, and oil meal. Lot ."&gt;. Alfalfa, silage, and oil meal. Then* feeds were figured at the -aim- prices as in Ex lnent NO. 1. The additional alfalfa inola— c- meal wii&gt; H&lt;r at s.',((.(ki per ton. Results showed that the cheapen gains made l&gt;\ the rattle in Lot 1. receiving corn and alfalfa Tin- co-t per 1 H(| |iohih!- was $8.72, in comparison witli s in Lot _'. $13.40 in Lot :'.. sil.7.'. in Lot +. and si_'..".&lt;; lh L The jrain- were comparatively light, the avenge daily ir-iii in&lt;r -JA't. \&gt;'-'k 1.71. !'.:'&gt;(». ami 1.93 pounds jht head, for lot- ."&gt; respectively. Tlic steers oos4 nine rent- per pound in the lot&gt;. Figuring the coat of feed, interest on invpstiikPiit. otlicr items, and the selling price of $7.80, $7.50. &gt;7.f&gt;n. s and $7.fiO respectively, for tli&lt;' various lot~. the losses ~ii-ta were $80.90. $28.40. s:',:',.Hi. s-_".».ll. and s:;;,.^ per bead. f»»i various lota, Project No. &lt;:' t . Roughage as ■ Feed for Dairy Cow-. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THIRTY-FIFTH Ax.MAI. RkPORT 19 Lot 1. Shelled corn and alfalfa hay. I&gt;&gt;t •_'. Shelled corn. lilaiT. and alfalfa hay. I^&lt;»t 3, Shelled corn, molasses meal, and alfalfa hay. Lot 4, Shelled corn, molasses meal, silajje. and alfalfa hay. Lot ."). Shelled corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa hay. Lot r&gt;. Shelled corn, linked oil meal, silajre. and alfalfa hay. The lambs made gaina varying from r2'tH pound m day in Lot -1 to a- hi&lt;rh a- .889 pound in I^ot ."&gt;. In each instance where do -ilajre was included in the ration, not only did the lainl&gt;- gain more, hut the jjain was cheaper than where it was ncluded. The use of sila&lt;re deoraaaai the rate of mim l&gt;y Ji i. inn. I pci- day and iinrca&gt;cd the cost. |h&gt;r UM) pounds. s!&gt; cents, reaped the coal per lani!&gt; 7&lt;« cent The addition of molasses meal to the corn and alfalfa n did not affect the jrain. hut increased the cost }ht 100 d- approximately 7"&gt; cents, and increased the loss per head nt-. The addition of linseed oil meal to corn and alfalfa ■aed the daily gain .&lt;W pound and the cost of 1 1 M » pounds i in &gt;'&gt;- cents and increased the loss per head l&gt;v '.' cent-. li.l not affect the market price when sold. The lainhs In- experiment were purchased at si±&lt;Mi | H . r hundred and s ( .».7."&gt; to SK».(M) per hundred. In an identically peiiinent a year ago, the lambs coal $11.00 act lnin- I for #20.00. The financial outcome was materially n tleieiit tlii- year from that experienced a year agfe This year '. and S&lt;».'.il for lot- ■_' to &lt;'• re-pectively. Proiert \&gt;&gt;. ,* .'. Fora«re Cron Investiira Porage Crop Investijration ijeit of thi- project i- a comparison of the various iarilv ii-ed a- iinnual fonuee crops, together with a the -eed bed preparation, rate, and time of i The work wa- continued mi an extensive scale at the AfNay- Farm. ( 'ompari-ons were made of all of the annual forajre ■ produced in this locality. In addition to a -tudv Off the annual forage crops, a study of the effect- of cultivation, fertilization, and dates of harvest - ing wa- inaugurated, with alfalfa. Previous work alonjr this line wa- summarized in Bulletin No. U&gt;!&gt;. Forajre Crops. Project Xo. i'i. Tractor Testing, Thi- work is bring carried on in accordance with a hill pa— eel at the 37th session of the Xel&gt;ra-ka State Le&lt;ri&gt;lature. requiring the testing of one -tock model of each type of tractor •i| 111 ,i ](i»~ iii every case, the loweM lo~s of M cents |xt iij: iii I.&lt; it 1. Mini rHiisins in losses of $1.(H». $0.50, $1.36, </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Acricii.tikai. Expkkimknt Station Ein the State, the test to l&gt;e made tit the Agricultural C'ol- The 38th session of the Nebraska Slate Legislature ged the law. to the extent of ■ tiding a fee of S;j."&gt;(&gt;.0&lt;&gt; for tractor tested, the fee to be paid by the company putting out the tractor. During the first year of the operation of this law. the University tested M tractors. I)urin&lt;r the fiscal year just passed, there were 32 requests for test. 17 of which were indefinitely postponed and 1"&gt; completed. Of the completed tests. 6 were made on kerosene ami I on gasoline. Three failed to make the rating as originally submitted. te. and two changed from kern ir parts or equipment, to a - improve performance, and two or adjustments. One company lowered its rat ■ene to gasoline. Seven change) i-t in making the rating or t&lt; completed test- without repair; at the beginning of the trial being 126 poi The second experiment consisted of ltS pounds at the beginning of the trial. They were fed f 4 . — _ _ •lays. The food supplements u - milk. Milkolinc. and Ton (tors | Corn and tankage formed the 1 io\\ "deivd butteni asic food ration. The addition of shorts to a reduced the rate of gain and de corn and tankair •rea-eil I he ecmio the fir.st trial. 187.80 pounils of shorts replaced 19.86 pounds of tankage and 117.68 pound- of -helled corn. In th trial ■V-\X&gt; pounds of shorts effected no saving of tankage. l&gt;ut replao ■J»;&gt; pounds of corn. As in the previous experimental work, the aae of sei buttermilk increased the average dailv «rain but did not reduei the cost of pork prodwetkm. Because of the tendency of solid buttermilk to accelerate the rate of gain, it was thought advisable to include it in order to procure the .dvantaire of th stimulating effect on jrrowtli. Gains were made where this food was included. each. TWm wen crown on the [Tniversitv 1 A summarv of the fin* year's lot was published a- Ex per inent Station Bulletin 177. Tlie present yen"- work has bee tabulated and will probably l&gt;e issued a- ■ supplement to tin bulletin. Project Xo. 79. Ration* for Fattening Hogs. Dtirinjr tin* past Iseal year two teats were carried on reli tive to protein supplements for fattening liujr- in dry lots. Tli first trial consisted i&gt;f seven lots of ten |&gt;i;r- each, fed for pei-Hn.1 of W day-. These pigs were purchased locally &gt;n divided into a- nearly equal lot- a- possible, tin average weiirl :-i- at I be ■ id ll! </seg>
            <seg id="p021">TllIHTY-Flnll AxM AI, REPORT 21 I I i wit Illl f pa&lt; \\ i \v Avenging l&gt;utli trials. -_!4.t&gt;."&gt; pound* of seinisolid buttermilk laced l^.f.7 pounds of taiikaire and :W. - J* pounds of corn. e other two amity by-product feeds, afilkolim and Ton Oors irdered buttermilk ho&lt;r builder, had the effect of accelerating 11. hut inerea.-ed the eo&gt;t of prtxhiction. Results of the &gt;w tin- cheapest &lt;rain&gt; were made from corn and tankage t supplementary feed. This study is l&gt;einfr continued. ■nji't So. 80, Potato Selection for Seed Purposes. / This work is l&gt;ein&lt;r carried on at a iiiiiul&gt;er of points in the ito growing area of western Nebraska and includes the sev - -tandard varieties of potatoes. The object is to determine: ) The relative value of western Nebraska seed potataaa piiri&gt;oii with those from otlier regions. _') The value of irrigated potatoes for seed purpose-, a. - ■red with those produced on dry land. :'. i The study of cultural conditions in the production of potatoes. me phases of thi- work are done in cooperation with the Department of Agriculture. The work done under this indicate- thai if proper attention is paid to seed selec- control, potatoes jrrown on dry land- in the ;ii ilt it 1 1 » I «'- of western Nebraska an equal for ned parpasea &gt;-c from anv other reirion of the I'nited State-. Three irieties Triumph. Early Ohio. mid Iri&gt;h Cobbler— •ulterior as commercial table stock varieties for drv land ■ I' the latp varieties, as RusMets Rural New-Yorkers, !&gt; -. are well adapted to certain types of soil under 1 -hould !*&gt; crown on a commercial scale for seed f the dry land &gt;ection&gt;. This work lias pro- ui-f;iciorilv. The information obtained is now for publication and should be ready for di itioii in a few months. This project i&gt; to l&gt;e continued. /'/"/' '/ \n. vj. Inheritance in K&lt;:&lt;r Production. Thi- project ha- been continued during the past year and tK. &gt; -— — - r* ■ — . — -- — t time ti.'i birds, with production records of -J(X) i ir better, are l&gt;einjr aaed in the project. A few individuals tli poo!' production records are also" being used for experi - ■lital purposes. A sufficient incn-ase in the rate of maturity the pallets, in these production bred matinirs. has beea noted ■h year. Karly matuiity. or precocity, Em baea obtained ihout sacrificing size or viL r &lt;&gt;r. in the White I&gt;'&lt;rhorns. In the ivier breeds early maturity is often a— ociated with a MM - int smaller size than i&gt; desirable. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nkbhaska AiiRicrui rai, Expbuxkxt Station importance, this factor and the fundamentals of its eritanee are also being closely studied. This project i&gt; l&gt;ein&lt;: continued. Project X". 83. Sonic Factor-- Influencing the Palatabilit of Poultrv Feed tlic fundamental factors that influence the 1 i k i 1 1 «r for vai ration.-, particularly the dry ma-h constituents. A coinpa of the palatahility of the most c mon animal protein &lt;-■» 1 it craps, dried buttermilk, and combinations of dried l&gt;utt i unit meat -crap- arc equally palatable when these fa&lt; arc changed in the rat Project X". H\. &lt; \&gt;-t of Milk Product This project ha- been completed and p operative ajrrceincnt with the I'. S. I )ep:irtiuent of Air Th&lt;- publication i- I Department ,&gt;f Am !»"•_'. entitled. "UtHiuireiiteiit^ »f IViMlucins M en Xel.ra I',-.),. &lt; 'I'lii- per intent St The -Huh i- lM'iii&lt;' made tin farm- m'ar &lt; &gt;:kl data have alreadv of -tiulv and when coi t Money on their feeding! i»per Project Xi&gt;. 89. Parn Tena work i&gt; in cooperation with the I*. S. I) teacher-, wlio combine it with This projed ha- bern continued and the -eci pletetl. The average production of the birds remaining th the entire second test wa- 154.6 egy*. which probablv i- twi t production of the BTcrace farm hen. Of the .')70 liinls entered in tlii- test, about Aniprinni Record of Performance li-t. Nearly all of the breed Size of efrjrs laid by each individual bein&lt;r of considerabli Tlii- project ha^ Ihm'h continued in an attempt to ■nairn indicate* no frreal difference. Good liijrli grade tanka I)uriiii_ r the i&gt;;i-i two mrs, t 'I'll is projeH \r.\- been emit «&lt;&gt;1K l&gt; Ml cooper;!! Inn \v 1 1 1 1 Mm ture. About 1&lt;MM) farm wirve&gt; fisral year. of tin- \\&lt;&gt;i Iht-. who combine it with their summer I he data are being ■ — entitled and preuai Project So. 91. Ear I'i \n me »»u mru&gt; eniemi in tin- test, about l-&gt; per cent made ■vearda of MO np or better, allowing them to be cut. red in the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">IVH \ I \ I \\ test in ih Thirty-Fifth Anmai. Report a licate tbeir intention to carry on breeding projects, as d in Station Circular No. 7. The indirect influence of a few hirds with e&lt;rg production records of -J00 eggs etter, m each community, is already apparent. The l»reed- roducing, from the l&gt;irds making hijrh records, pedi - lo'iel- for distribution in their own communities. Project Xo. '■&gt;'. C Co-t of Producing Farm Crops. I'his project is U-injr carried in cooperation with the County it-. A study is l&gt;ein&lt;r made on the l&gt;asi&gt; of obtaining the &gt;er of boun of bant ami man Ubav used in producing the rops and the expense- incidental to their production. &gt;f allowing intend on capital invested in the land. and other expenses of land ownership, share rent is al- hased on the share most commonly pud in the region. &lt;&gt;)t&lt;t \n. !)■'). A Comparison of toe Feeding Values of ind Yellow Corn. In this experiment twenty pifTs were divided into two Kit - fed for 147 days. The ■rerun ration consisted of corn and Phe white and yellow corn were of equal grade. Ten ration was high grade 80 per cent tankage. The i f the trial showed favorably for the. yellow corn, a- to rale of gain and the economy of jrain. The lot receiv- rn ate more and gained more rapidly, — the average Dg 1.01 pound- for the lot receiving yellow corn 1 for the lot receiving white corn. The cost )&gt;er mils of jrain wm $l&amp;.08 ami flC6t respertiveJy. lifference is quite material, further work on this t i- needed. Judfriiifr from work done at other Stations, v witli smaller animals, it is very probable that when the itv supplemental feeds found on the average farm are fed porn, the feeding value of white and vellow corn is much irlv the -aim 1 than would l»e indicated bv the results of -t Project X". 97. Draft In vest ijrat ions of Farm Machinery. \ large niimher of plow tests, tinder varying depths ami 1-. have been made. The results varv widely in the ca-e of draft tests hut are fairly consistent for the depth draft The increase in draft due to increase in depth frutn five to ten inches was approximately -J7 par cent of the draft it five mciH rests have also been made to determine the draft of a disk w for different angles of the disk section: also to determine ffect on the draft due to weighting the disk. The increase n draft due to fully an«rlin«r the sections was aliout 17."&gt; per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 XkBUASKA AliKK'l I.TIKAI. K.M'F.HI M EXT S I A nox raft ,1 r&gt;() per cvi i iv-ult i v-six area niimer piests for Ef the draft at no anjrle. The increase in the i eightinjr the diak with a wwighl of lso pounds wu ' tlie no weight draft. Raining Calve-. Twenty-nine animal - ii^r feil for a period of i nf-feeder rrwip and 1 1 ►filler a&gt;x'inliled for |iu!i|| 'he data indicate that th actory a- the ordinary li /',,.;,, f x,,. /'-..'. a eforaska. IX month-. ( )f the-e. |.) Wei The ( 'ollejpe i- cunt poult n' diseases and th E specimen- &lt;&gt;f .|i-.;i - ved. the owner- are ial for investimttioii. t I'lllletrlll Mi-, F,,« Tubemi Fowl tv Rarillarr \ Fowl pox lvollp lihlekhead Parasite rounties. tubercnlosifl ttpecimens from 2fi counties, fowl t -|M-&lt;iinen- from 8 counties. from 10 counties, fowl p&lt; s|K'ciinen&gt; from 11 count ie tie-, parasitic specimens fn inens from 14 count ie-. liaiillarv &gt;.\ specimens t -. hhlckhead -li f tn ."&gt; counties, defi Project \". 103. Soil Acidity Three hundred and fifty -oil -ample- from -ixt have been collected for study. In addition to these samples have lx&gt;en received from farmer-, with n acidity tests. Project X». 99. The Practicability &lt;&gt;f a Srlf-Femler I Inive Imm'Ii n-fd for this t iii tlir rberk group. The r •iitiiin. The project will lii&gt; &lt; • Mr of I -clf-fccdiT i- fllll\ iiixl method iif raising c-iil\&lt;- Siirvev "f tin- Poultrv l&gt;i Ix-'-n made and i LDcticiciicv disramfi i '. \ . A atadj of the dintribution i imps -hows that fowl cholera </seg>
            <seg id="p025">TitiRTV- Firm Anxiai. Rkpokt 25 ( f II i i t « a sui for )bser\ at inns have been made on many points. While the ■tative iK-hiivior. and in fact some of the plant species, indi - &gt;tronjjly an acid condition, demonstrations of applications me, at a number of points, have failed to produce beneficial t~. The present knowledge of the subject does not indicate soil acidity i^- ■ serious problem in Nebraska at this time. V". /"J. Cooperative Studies with Commercial The work during the past year has lieen confined largely to Count v. The second year&gt; work has l&gt;een completed for of tin' soil types in this county. Considerable raanoUM has niid to applications of barnyard manure, especially oa ter and sandier soils. Acid phosphate, at the rate of Miiinds per acre, gave strong indications of profit during trlicr part of the season, but failed to produce a profit at &gt;t. This ma v l&gt;e due to the fact that moisture Ix-came a factor. Complete high grade fertilizers gave no greater than phosphate alone. I)iniiiir the pa&gt;t season, potash failed to show profitable re - -. a- it had done the previous year. Sulphur, applied for Project So. 108. A Study of the Inttueiuv of Certain -icai Qualities of EggH, Mainly Size and Specific (Jravity, Fertility, Hatching Power, and Size and Rate of Growth) ig» conclusioiw are baaed on a close observation the subsequent growth of one lot of 150 chicks here is no apparent correlation between hijih specific rtilitv. and hatchahilitv of hens" e&lt;r&lt;rs. I'lie specific parity (| f the ejrir has no relation to the of the chick hatched, or to its growth rate the first 'ter hatching. Variations in the thickness of the shell are more likely ■ the specific gravity of fat content. eir«rs than are variations in HOG CHOLERA SERUM The ~uit brought by certain plaintiffs against the Regents of University relative to the handling of hog cholera serum pgjucd upon by the lower court and was appealed to the feme Court in the fall of 1W0, The caaa lias not come up decision and &gt;till rest~ with the Supreme Court. f controlling se;»l&gt; &lt;&gt;f p«&gt;tat*n i -. was without effect </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska A&lt;;ui&lt;n/n rai. Experiment Station 26 &gt;. 1 1 In the meantime, the MMi Iyjrislature of tin- State of Ne - braska remodeled the Hojr Cholera Serum Rill, authori/.in&lt;r tin Regents of the I'liiversily to cither manufacture or puTChftBI hojr cholera serum. a&gt; their In-st judgment might determine, mm thori/.injr them to keep on hand a supply of mm raficient meet any ordinary emerirency. Owing to the fact that the nt is not iiKxlenilv equipped, tliat tlic demand for mm is •ertain. together with the financial conditions that have ob - lied, it was deemed more advi-al&gt;le to purchase serum dwiag past taeal vear than to attempt to luanufactiire it. The following statement shows the activities in tlii~ trot for the (Mai year: V»bi Serum purchased during the year Total !?7r,.l-_&gt;l.l-j Mi i nl inn ft .5,069,13 Total S.023,030 ot;i I //"'/.v, &gt;* t'H III . S,il, | / ' nliii &lt; ' n/ii' ii iitmii ti /■* ri iitmii ti r* January 3.80."i !&gt;7.i;n February *'.1 ;1 &gt;" 101,750 March '. 3..V.»."i I&lt;i7.7.".&lt;&gt; April •_'.'.&gt;7u fiO.KW M:iv 9J&lt;10 24.1.H.V) .Imih' 17.0SM1 l'ij._''»i July Jl.'.Mi:. J548.4O5 A.ogust :V-\.-^x&lt; 1.0±i.W)o September •_'■_'. |n.'» R*27.fi - J."i October 6S.1S0 l.874.«7."i Nov.-ihIht W.75H) i»8'J.J)7."&gt; IK-cciiiIkt 14.7(mi 121.075 Tata] 228.675 f,.:.;i:',.&lt;K(o Scruiii on hand January 1. 1922 1.430,000 Total for the your 8.023.030 Collection-. .Tiiiiiiiirv 1. l'.'^l. to January 1. 1!&gt;-J-J. ami turn nto the Revolving Fund: From s^ruin sold $05,930.30 From virus sold 2,286.7S From live st&lt;K-k. etc &lt;i,!K)4.O7 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">TllIIiTY-FlFTII AnMAI, IlEPORT 27 (Jexeral Statement for 1!&gt; - J1 N f Farm Bureaus on ledger 38 i N amber of individual customers on ledger 787 Number &lt;&gt;f orders during the vear 1,465 Number &lt;&gt;f applicants for hlackleg vaccine 630 NumU-r of pigs used in making simultaneous virus 163 Number of pi&lt;rs used in making: siniultaneous virus 163 Number of pi&lt;:- &lt;ni band, January 1. r.&gt;±2 30 The wisdom of the policy of sonic agency carrying a reserve supply of wn wa&gt; dearly demonstrated during the past sea- W was dearly dt'inonstrated during the past sea- v of ... .... -. -^. - j_, - R I'he &lt;ales showed a marked increase in the demand for during the latter half of the year. During this period son. The -ales -liowed a marked increase in the demand for serum daring the latter half of the year. During this period there were had outbreaks of cholera in a nuinl&gt;er of different '•- * ... - . ...... .-. &gt; .- — - — f* 4 had outbreaks of cholera in a muulwr of different sections of the State, and the demand for MOT was large. At the State, and the demand for MOT was large. At of thi- time many of the private companies ran out of serum anil nv of the private companies ran out of serum and an actual shortage. Had there l**en no reserve on there was an actual -hortage. Had there l&gt;een no reserve on hand at the College, the loam from cholera would undoubtedly College, the losses from cholera would undoubtedly it have been verv heavy. OFFICIAL TEST FOR MILK AND BITTER PRODUCTION Tin' |iur|io--e of thi- work i&gt; to give to the dairymen of the VL TEST FOR MILK AND BITTER PRODUCTION Dl I in of till— work U to irive to the dairymen of the State accurate information concerning the individual production information concerning the individual production of the row- of their herds. The work for 1981 has shown a of their herds. The work for 1921 has shown ■ marked growth in spite of the national economic depre--ion. ite of the national economic depres&gt;ion. which ha- added many difficulties to the dairyman"- advance- led inanv difficulties to the dairyman's advance- ment. The total num!«T of te&gt;ts for the year ending December •r of testa for the year ending December :'l. llhil. i- 2,S0f&gt;, a- compared with a total of 1.-J7-J for the year i- compared with a total of 1.-J7-J for the year ending December 21. 1940. The following table -hows the niini- ber "t tests made during the past fiscal year: ade din-ing the past fiscal year: COW! ON TEST IN NEBRASKA JAN. 1. 1921. TO DEC. 31, 1921. INCLUSIVE NEBRASKA JAN. 1. 1921. TO DEC. 31, 1921. INCLUSIVE Ilol-tciu thirty-day tests (official) 47 thirtv-dav tots (official) 47 Holstein -c\,n-day tests (official) Ill &gt;fncial) Ill Ilol-tcin -■mi -official tests (161 x IS month-) l«Mfl Total Hoktein testa TTolstein semi-official te-ts ( 1C.1 x 12) 1.032 TTolstein semi-oflicial te-ts ( 161 x 12) 1.032 ,lcr-ev -eini-otficial te-ts ( 1!' x 12) - &gt;t5 * Ayrshire -eini-ollicial tc-t&gt; ( ."&gt; x 12) 60 ( Mieni-ev -eini-oflicial te.^t^ (2 X 12) 24 otal sfini-official tests for 1921 - ) . ( ' &gt; 04 otal official tests for 1921, (47 + 158, as above) Ml Grand total tests. .Ian. 1. 19*1, to Dee. 81, li»-_'l 2,800 (iran.l total te-ts. Jan. 1. 19-20, to IVc. 51, VW 1,278 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Xkhraska A(;kk ii.tikai. ExronXEXT Station unl tinit i vea I&lt;i ii NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Experimental work with tit-Id crops, including cultun rotation exix'riments. testing of varieties methods, rate, aiul of seeding, has proceeded without material i hangi in plai previously reported. Crops. — The crop BMMa of 1!W1 VM more than usuallv favorable, and &lt;rood yields of all crops were &gt;eciired. The corn yield was 8&amp;£ 1 u i-lu-l- per acre from the rotation pl;«t -. which five bushels above the highest previous year, and inure tha double the average yield from these plats. It i^ the h"r-t yet (4) Packing plowed ground increased the v amount sufficient to pay for il- rout. ( .") ) Disking only, produced pool averaife \ ])lo\viii&lt;r at any depth. The second bulletin. No. 179. on "Winter Wheat it Nebraska." summarizes the work at North Platte ai \\\ •«. in a 14-year period in these investigations in which tin- v com following corn failed to exceed the yield of eon fill small grains. The winter wheat average yield for 1021 was 28.3 per acre which i- lo.'.t bushels above the average of p years. The average yield on disked corn land «a- 28.6 aar acre. The average yield from summer tillage wi bushels per acre. The* 1 yields are in accord wiih those &lt;&gt; ions ycai---. the conclusion 1 &gt;«■ 1 1 1 &lt;jr that intensive practice-. - summer tillage and green manure, can l&gt;e expected t&lt;&gt; pi small increase over wheat following corn in fears when v condition- are favorable. Two publications on winter wheat have been i — lied ink, under the title of Winter Wheat Seed-I'.eil I'l-ep.-i (Bulletin ITS), summarize* eight year-' experiment- in and time of plowing, effect of packing- and prejwrai disking only. The following conclusions are drawn: (11 On t hi- and similar soils, no advantage can \&gt; ■ by very deep plowing. Plowing 7 inclie- deep [&gt;riMluce&lt;l ; yields of wheat a- plowing Id in 1 I inches. (-2) \'ery shallow plowing gave poorer results than in&lt;j; at medium depth, tlie gain from 7 inch plowing Ihmi (icii'iit to |.a\ fur the additional rt»sl id' plowing at tin- depth than three inches. (:'&gt;) Depth of plowing had no appreciable effect on tl age or n&gt;e of -oil nidi-tnii-. Light "fain- were secured l&gt; plowing. -&lt; I. &lt;&gt; a </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Heron 29 Thirty-Fifth Ann i ai Nebraska: Akron. Colorado; and Ardmore. South Dakota: t it is applicable to ■ considerable wgi— The work from -t two Station tu furnished by tht DeputBMl W Agn - ,• officials. This bulletin compares the methods of growiag • i ,uslv on the same land, rotating with corn, alter - tmner tillage, and alternating with CfOpi plowed i manure. The following summaries are made: ■reage and production, winter wheat is one of the i targe section of western Nebraska. it ing factor is insufficient and variable rain it. l7v making its greatest growth during the u itt~t average rainfall and before the time of great- it l&lt; -I 11 " iu^\ i«""" M ••■ r - evaporation, adapts itM'lf Letter than nianv other (H-oiiomical and efficient use of the moisture avail- e-t vicld- per acre, at all Station*, were -eciired by nir t" wheat f wheat followinc corn bare been secured at t lave been about equal. Ten rears' work in comparing spring wheat. ported in Bulletin Hi. The irk. the earlv seeding* have tion. nativ varieties, in practically all (Jain- of from 20 in •"" per cent in tonnage of atom of iriL'ation have been produced by the u-e of intro - f larger and later varieties. wheat has shown -uperior yielding qualities, ru-t Kaiu t;ii f spring wheat on account of superior rust re-i-tanc ■i yielded the common varieties bv substantial amounts. the valor &lt;&gt;f taw corn prop and the relatively hi Km. the mosl profitable jriekb oi wheat hare a i 1 1 ir &lt;i&gt;ni: the yields are Kmetrhat Ins than -iiiiiiiicr lilliiiri'. the saving in seeding an&lt;l barreling coats sr. tin 1 uvenpe profits fron tlii&gt; method ami li:i- failed t&lt;&gt; inmase vicM- or« thaw f&lt;&gt;l- e and Im- proved theletsl i &gt;r«»tit;il »!*■ method r wci&lt;' rcporlcU in imlU'iin Its. ■■&gt; •;il vc:M- li'itr- uiit tin- ponHiision.H ilmwn ii' n:i-i vc;ir surins rve was -ul &gt;-t itutetl vioii- work, tlit" Miriy sealing* m;»\c n«r~ bv — «il»-t:iiitijil miioiiiiK native corn vnricii— - haw prowd (I win-ill has Miown superior vhmuiiij: i|wiiurv ■ "^&lt;. and winter hardinesfl to other varieties. Diiriun </seg>
            <seg id="p030">NEBRASKA Al.llK H.HRAI. Kxl'KHIMKNT STATION 30 Earlv varieties of oats outyielded later varieties, tho show ing special promise for Nebraska No. -21 oat Half stand corn, see tired l&gt;v planting onlv alternate row has failed to yield as much corn as the full stand, the ditferen being? V per cent in favor of the full -tand I'u in ji Irrigation. — l'imip irrigation has assisted materially in increasing the yields of all crops to which water was applied but has Urn especially valuable in establishing new stands of alfalfa. On land that was thorolv irrigated before seeding, a fine &gt;tand of deeply rooted alfalfa waa ■emj when the m ■Hiding wa- a failure on adjoining land not irrigated. The chief item of com of pump irrigation i- the labor, rather than th cn-t of fuel or upkeep. Operations have not been sufficient V ex tensive to give dependable estimates of the cost of irrigal &gt;n this method. Fm i strif. — The forestry plantation set out in 1807 a f.,i lowing years continues to show both favorable and unfav result-. Sonic species arc making satisfactory gro othci- species are failing. The bull pine -a\\ ll\ l)iill pine. We had considered 1 1 1 i — our mosl promising w&gt; White elm. hackberrv, ■ promising of the -cm Ili'ifiiiltiin. — One of the ino-t satisfy the grow i 1 1 &lt;_ r of plums, cherries, and otl ,1 vi-it the Substation and will lie refle&lt; re comfortable and more snbstanti /;. - / Cattle. Tin' beef cattle h&lt; and U-ef qualities to the erradi t Im-cii no experimental cattle feeding conducted daring t year, ata the breeding herds occupv all the a\ shed&gt;. leaving no facilities fur experimental feeding. t ex- perimental feeding has been done. Mote than &gt;w- a i bred for spring litter-, to furnish pigs for experi ntal feeding Poultry. — The poultry plant, established late in 1919 in full operation, with the plant fully equipped and -t The winter flock con-i-t- of 1,200 hen- and pullet- and the neces - sary cock- and cockerel-. Thi- rear considerable numbi- of Kd.&lt; lir-t place on ilif valley laiiil. Tli&lt;' i\-c -m\. ire nukins satisifartorv kto« tof ornamental trees, shrill cd iiloiiir these 1 i i n*— i- pvi ■ambers and in qualitr. 11 rrtcis for feeding experiments an necm.wry lloyx — The lui&lt;r liciii lin~ bera maintaiiu </seg>
            <seg id="p031">TuiRTY-FlFTH AnMAI Baron 31 ni(iii&gt;tr poultrv I ( i ) i It fail k.-.l | !•&gt; I in took and hatching eggi were mU, as well as jMMiltry for market purpo— . The plant is proving useful m iitiiijr the mo-t modern equipment and method* of hand- Dairy.— The dairy herd baa* made satisfactory progress dur - tlic pa-t year. The herd now consists of 38 pure bred Hol- Fnesian cowa and heifers and about :50 grade cows. Several ■-&lt;■ cowa hare been admitted to advanced registry. The dairy, with its equipment and good line of cows, is one )r chief points of interest to visitors at the Station. It i.-s ig considerable influence in creating more interest in dairy- Hid in teaching better methods of handling dairy cows and products. There is a strong demand for every dairy fe- for sal;- from this herd. Thirty milk cows and bred ulv all of which were high grade IIolstein-Friesian. VALENTINE SUBSTATION B condition- were extremely unfavorable at Valentine past year. The sea-on opened with a deficiency of which by the cJoaa of the year had increased to a total inches,— hot about one-third of the normal annual pre- The mean temperature was several degrees above Vn extended drought from tin- middle of June to the a- very detrimental to crop product ion. Keil Amber and Dakota Amber were th- i : varieties among the forage crops, producing pounds per acre Darso, a grain sorghum, gave pounds per ai re. and Milo and Kafir apprnxi- per acre. each. Kursk millet produced L^OO and Siberian and Prom about ijMQ pounds (ting of Sudan gra-&gt; was obtained, the higlie-t 1350 poonda per acre. l.:'&gt;o&lt;&gt; pounds per acre was i fodder yield from corn. Hairy vetch completely and field pea&gt; failed to survive the summer drought. beans have been under te-t for one season, and altho \va- only U-llt pound- per acre they appear worthy of rial. Cow pea- were drilled with Sudan gra&gt;s. but did much ifrowth. tlfm, -Due to weather condition-, seeding on old ground A tract of early spring breaking that hud been thorolv traduced an excellent -tand. which made a growth of 8 •he-. A permanent start is more easily oUained on land ii sold (hirinj: the pa&gt;t year. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">XkHHASKA AliRH I I.TIHAI. Kxl'KH I M KM STATION 32 (ioo &lt;rrew t ;in in 1 n ■urviv t nor more recently broken than on old land. On mbirrigated land the life of alfalfa is shortened when the water table rises dosei than five feet to the surface. Re-ult- with Hiibain and whit sweet clover were quite unsatisfactory on the upland. stands were obtained but did not &gt;urvive the drought. Most of the plants had dried up by the middle &lt;if July and MM more than six inches in height. On the wet lowlands inense growth of ordinary white sweei clover was produ (iraiw seed ins was a failure. Five tame grasses and the native &lt;rra"e» wire needed in row Ml failed to The western wheel &lt;_Ta— and bronn Broadcasting red and alsike rhn in the late winter or curly spring, ina (Uite an impr Nil of M bushels per aci &lt; bushels per acre. This wi 1 on th&lt;- cornstalk land. If Kanred wheat pive I Sjiriml (irii/ii. — A I wheat. .\ bnicker Imrlev. eniiutT. ai weather came while the\ r aeed production. Manchu in earlv va to the acre. Ito San &lt;ra\ M late to niatiir.' -c ■&lt;! and was cut foi beans produced 8 bushels per acre. 'I later, the difference in yield was v.-rv small. A leaf stroved most of the letves on the -mill ►wets, srreatlv reducing th quality of the. silage produced. The lama ere was inn I . r- . pronounced on the early planting rvivrtl the longest. on tin- lowland mea in the quality and qnantity &lt;&gt;f h.-iv. &lt; i n nl i it'll.- . Corn iilanivil on i it heijrlit &lt;»f - t&lt;&gt; •"&gt; f (-( '! :■ * ■ &lt; 1 nimlf .in approximate l)u&gt;licl&gt; per iicr". Planting June 10th ptrvw bImhiI height, had larger pars. )&gt;ut only a ~n •;: 1 1 percpnta Rainlmw flint corn planted the 1;i-i &lt;&gt;f M,i\ ir;i\c a ]| /'/i/( / Grain. Iv&lt; &gt;-&lt;■! i eon Mil Ik ijT'iimd :i ii&lt; I follow Uo-eii ive viclili-il l."i. I ImisI &lt;|iii&gt; &gt;nd Kubanka &gt;\&gt;v\ the noriiiiil period of lilln Sm/ Hi ntiJt. rinci 1 v ma) tire. Sunffitirt ,-x. — Early planted sunflowers &lt;_';i tonii:i&lt;ri- a- was prodimd l&gt;v rorn. From ■ phi </seg>
            <seg id="p033">I'misTY-Firm Axxiai. Report 33 ,i/. — The progress of the dairy herd has liwn quite sati&gt; Dailv production records have U'en kept — also feeding The ] !• individuals have lieen rulled from the herd. ducts of the dairy, largely milk, found a ready sale on fa. S( OTTSBLIFF SUBSTATION l'lie pa-t year \va- ii very stti-factoiy one for crop produc - ihi the North IMatte proji'ct. The yields. e&gt;|&gt;ecially .-mall lie 17. The result was that no water was carried mil for a period tlierea fter a rotation oi water waji feet, which did not furnish a sufficient supply to frt crop-. The tv-ult wa- tliat mm of the -mall I very low yields ami aaaat of the new -tand- of ere lo-t I',, i is.- As the price of beets was practically cut in Mr, the heel crop has not l&gt;"i'ii very profitable, es- to realize that they niu&gt;t grow more licet-, to ivali/i -e previously found to application- of !&gt;arn - tlic growing of man beets sliowed asain during \ yearn -how- I0lS6 tons per acre of nufrar beel I plats, 16.75 ton- from the plat- whi.h were BM i- froBH the alfalfa plat — an increase of m &gt;r&lt; - favor of bamvard manure. This make- a the profit on the bad Potatoes were the DKtol profitable crop for the ir - iliiriiiir the pa-t wattOU. While the yield wa- 1c — year ago, the price was better. Potatoes, like re shown great response to increased fertility of following tal&gt;le -how- the yield in 1921 from tli« s yi M 41. of ilfalfa. were reduced l&gt;v ;i utnam break in the M-iin landlord's standpoint B«&lt; powers m residual effect &lt;&gt;f ulfalfa. the urrnf Che:k plat T.TanureU plat Alfalfa pht I I 4 132.3 200.8 2'JT.Z 42.0 74.6 132.3 100.9 142.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nkhkaska A&lt;;kh ii.ti rai. Expkrimkxt Station I An eight-year average yield from tlie.se methods riwtl U average of ."&gt;" bushels per acre more following application of barnvard inanure. and 141.!» bushels more following alfalfa, than on untreated check plat:-. Tht affected by the length of tht grown on the same land or in as to !*■ hardlv marketable. (|ii!ility of potatoe- is wry much rotation. Potatoes continuously short time rotations are so scabby When potatoes occur only once in a six-year rotation, thev are generally quite free from seal (Urn. — Corn offers more po - ordinarilv supposed. Very -at i usually Uvn obtained ami where are obtained. The residual effect bushels more grain where corn fo ihilities in this district than i - factory yield- of grain ban it follow- alfalfa good yield* of alfalfa cm corn showed - 1 lowed alfalfa. i\\ i Small (•ruins. Small gi under irrigation. They are i starting alfalfa. Bar lev seem; lli- - are not wrte II V LTOWII ;l- ;| r oat- or wheat. Cultural 1 I. important factor ii pen- that the sprin; the plowing done a i rod i- ear frequently happen* thai I order lo determine whether torily prepared with a d ■e laid out. four of whirl &gt;i wen tisidering tli^ response to early plan v he snlwti tilted for plowing whei Soil Fertilit* Tent*. -In 1917, rat commercial fertilizer in the form of li were applied to certain plat-. Other | of Manure, and since then -onie plat- I of manure. From these studies it seel rewponxf from coivmicv' -1 ferttliE^r tl tions of barnyard manure. The appl growing of alfalfa or sweet clover a more profitable method of increasing than attempting to use commercial f&lt; residual effect of application- of gi dearly evident for at least three years ,1 i\ t 111 t ihel here I- fro cation of inanure. or th&gt; in rotation, is doubt les' the productiveness of mi rni- of plant f 1. The hi. I liarnvard manure i Et'&lt;l. I lie plowing and disking w Tin- yield- wttt very cl'i-c. tli a lx'in^ 15.18 Mini from th* diske the plowing ciinnipt !&gt;■ done tmri} </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Tiiirty-Kiftii Anm ai. Rkport 35 I i i i 1 f in ( I i Gram Pasture.— Tht study of tin- carrying capacity of pas - re land under irrigation was continued. The work was not rely satisfactory, since the break in the canal caused a short - of water. A- with as many other crops on this type of soil. gra»&gt; make- great response to applications of barnvard nia- ire. It wa&gt; found in actual tests, this year, that the carrying parity of pasture which had received an annual application of inure for two years was doubled over that receiving no ma- Sheep iibbq in the laal were pastured 1O2 days. The land Manured carried eight -beep j«-r acre, while the land ma I carried 16 sheep per acre. Smu t I to pasture l&gt;oth sheep and cattle. This pasture carried at ite of 28 -heep per acre, for a period of four months. In icre sweet clover pasture. VI cows were put on in the Because of the shortage of water In-fore mentioned, it caary In remove them from the pa-ture for about two ime. Had this not occurred, it is very probable that the would have wiled tin 1 12 cows during the year, which have been four cows per acre. The popularity of sweat clover for pasture purposes is in - iing in this section. It seenis to require less water than grass re and is more quickly established. As a soil builder it itself to the cropping nyotean better than gra-&gt;. I.ni'il Crow*. — A portion of this Station is held for dry land farming. The yields obtained from this par- imi-1v much le~&gt; than under irrigation, ruder dry n&gt;. rotations seem to 1m&gt; much less important than miration, the big factor in dry fanning being the efficient the water. Under dry land conditions surface planted s superior to li&gt;iiiifr. Disking for small grain has prove. 1 profitable than either fall or nprif plowing. All crop- own considerable response to summer tillage, hut the ex - f i In- method baa been m aieal that it has not been the t profitable. Lamb Feeding Experiment, — An experiment in fattening &gt;- wa&gt; carried on with IS lot-, each containing •_'") lanih-. hey were fed for a |M l riod of 1-20 days. They averaged 44 onnds apiece at the beginning of the experiment. All lots were •d all tl&gt;e alfalfa bay they would eat. The experiment was lade to compare the efficiency of certain &gt;iippleuientarv feeds, 'orn in Men raat made more and cheaper gains than dried beet ulp. Cottomeed cake, when fed with corn and dried pulp, in - rea-ed the gain- made and lowered the co-t per 100 pounds of Pasture, — SiumII p:i&gt;tinv&gt; of sweH clovtr W€l </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 NkIUIASKA Al.KK I 1 .11 KAI. Kxi'EHlMKNT STATION" I jfaili. Beet tops proved a cheap feed with corn or dried pulp Ileet torn produced a little more jrain at less ml than con &gt;ila&lt;re. The cod per HH) pounds of &lt;rain ranged from *&lt;i.i7 fm nlftilfa. corn and beet top-,, to $11.81 per l'X&lt; pounds for alfalfi iind dried palp. The luml&gt;s cost $12.00 per hundred in tin feed lot. Marc (weight All lot per Limb, for tli ,'reatest loss. $2.8 NEEDED INVESTIGAT IONS While the Station i- carr\ fiindauieiital ri'-earch in an attempt t appear to he in ntotd urgvnl need o vc 1 1 pn there aii ire of an problems which are not Keinjr g others not vet undertaken. t;i nir f in i ruiat I study, together with an of all farm products. in&lt; of the econoliili' pfolilei should l&gt;c increase*!. There has lieen ai (lie farmers Inn on the part i investigation calculated t&lt;i imi it i*'~ of Nebraska wheats. Tl culty in Helling their flours in wheat from some other sections. Tli the price paid to the farmers for thei r i w of the Station Chemist, under wav. livsicn that determine the productivity of noil ai The demand for information along thi- li durinir the past two or three year-. Real is now under way at the Main Station. l&gt; renter, while verv valuable, mav not giv* a- ii n t it mv .it results cut irelv . ---.- — ---- — • r- * * ......... alile to different localities. The importance of thi- work MlM w undoubtodly justify the expenditure necessary to make time position for this study. full i The lines of investigation above mentioned are onlv •me of the more ur&lt;rent ones. The demands for information oil all line •."Mil tlicv m&gt;I&lt;1 in Onahl at $0.75 per hiunlre Invr&gt;ti&lt;riitioM&gt; of By not adequate to the dema Investigations &lt;&gt;f liuili th -howcd a l(is&gt;. Tilt' 1 * &gt; \\ t *— t lo^&gt; \\;|- 93 ci'lit ot rccj'ix inir alfalfa, corn, and htti tops. Tin mt 1st 1 nl &gt;. wa- from alfalfa and » 1 i-i &lt; •&lt; I piilp. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">rmwrr— Fifth Axxr.u. Rerun 37 M \ ! 1 h ry. 1 I 1 June itci- t ha Station can meet with its present equip- Vnionjr tlu 1 equipment urgently needed by the Expert- first, an adequate provision of greenhouses, ow under investigation are Ikmujt dalajad be- ihouse space available for carrying on the umber of problnm thai cannot bjp undertaken tliout additional land. The&gt;e include phases iihiction. pasture iri - a.~s mixtures, pasture inan - veslinjf of cpopfl with live stock. \ a i~ liailly needed for housing the Department of l'lii- I &gt;&lt;-| &gt;:irt nu-tit is handicapped at the present used in four different luiildinjrs. making it im - proper coordination of the work. CHANGES IN STATION STAFF A. Lewis resigned as Bulletin Editor, August 15, 1921 Eli Duncombe resigned as Analyst, August 31, 1921 &gt;ales retired as Financial Secretary. lunderson was appointed Finance Secretary of the Uni K. ( be i 1, 1921 W. H. Savin is in charge of sheep experiments, Animal Hus E. E. I has been added to the staff, in charge of Tractor Agricultural Engineering. Wehr was appointed Assistant in Entomology July 1 ivis was appointed Chairman of the Department of August 1. 1921. I. M was appointed Assistant in Poultry Husbandry Mr. M. .1. Blish has been appointed Chemist, beginning March 1, IHBLICATIONS the Station since those named in the last An- InWS Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February lletin No. 177. The Nebraska Tractor Tests. By Board of • Test Engineers: 0. W. Sjogren, E. E. Brackett, and C. W. and Acting Manager of Tractor Tests, F. R. Nohavec. Janu - 21. 10,000 copies. ulletin No. 178 (Report of North Platte Experimental Substation, in 22). Winter Wheat Seed Bed Preparation. By L. L. Zook. 1921. 5 000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Aurktltvral Exruunt Station 38 Bulletin No. 179 (Bulletin No. 23 of the North Platte Experimenta Substation). Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska. By L. L. Zook 7,000 copies. (In press.) Research Bulletin No. 19. The Regional Adaptation of Corn in Nebraska. By T. A. Kiesselbach and F. D. Keim. Distributed April 1, 1921. 3,000 copies. Experiment Station Circular No. 13. The Nebraska Tractor Law and Rules for Official Tractor Tests. By Board of Tractor Test En - gineers, O. W. Sjogren, E. E. Brackett, and C. W. Smith; and Acting Manager of Tractor Tests, F. R. Nohavec. April, 1921. 5,000 copies. (This Circular is a revision of Experiment Station Circular No. 10.) Experiment Station Circular No. 14. Hog Houses for N'ebraska By 0. W. Sjogren and I. D. Wood. 5.000 copies. (In press.) Experiment Station Circular No. 15. Insect Pests of Stored Gra and Their Control. By M. H. Swenk. 3,000 copies. (In press. I Temperature and Humidity Studies of Some Fusaria R Irish Potato. By R. W. Goss. Journal of Agricultural Research, V XXII, No. 2. Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. Journal of A Research, Vol. XXII, No. 3. By F. E. Mussehl. ACKNOWl eim;ments Tlif agricultural press ami the dailv and \\ papers, especially those papery shown their appreciation of tin liv &lt;rivinsr liberal space to ezp every way facilitating the extern edge. •rated within t oik of tlif K\ih I w mi tnl work !■( f usef </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Tiiiisty-Fii-tii Anmai. Keport 39 I I ( ANNUAL REPORT OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SERVICE work in Agriculture and Home Economics was Nebraska during 1!&gt;*J1 with practically no varia - geoeral plan of previous years. Am lias been i . i &gt; increase the Masher of eaanerativa counties, ar then- were three added. At the end of the t mail hen were 4»&gt; organized comiiee employing agents ie-e counties were employing two agents, In each of — i . — r* - employing a second agent the additional one was a certain definite purpose. In eight of the counties m ployed to further the Home Kconomio work. &gt;f the counties associate agents were employed to '- — ■ — i. — irk of Bovs and (lirls. The large&gt;t work of Ex- UKI.ATIONSHIP WITH FARM ORGANIZATIONS ng Nelira-ka statute, known a- Senate File 17'J of fines the count v body that shall cooperate Kxtension Service of the College «f Agriculture. Under -,\ petitionary body and exi-t- -i&gt;lel\ for the par- ration with the Extension Service in its educa Tlii&gt; county farm bureau i&gt; ■ puMic aerviei rganized for the purpow of cooperation with tin d department&gt; in agricultural demonstrations. of the countv agricultural extension agent to 1 mizations within the countv i&gt; dearly aH out in uU a- follow&gt;: "The countv agricultural agent rganization and direction of agriculture in the is employed and shall cooperate with individ- ili- and other associations and organisation the U'ttertueiit of rural conditions tliruoiit ty." Since tlii- i- tlie relationship defined within the be Kxtension Service accepts it as the relationship tliru- tate and holds it&gt;elf open and ready to cooperate with ii/ation within the State whoxe object is the betterment rural condition-. In carrying out it&gt; program of work, the xtensioii Service has Keen assisted in different instances l&gt;v the pp, the Fanner- ["nion. the Equity 1'nion, the Farm Hn- Federation. Community Clubs, Breeders' Associations, etc. ir lia- Im-cii in the improvement of demonstration </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 NeHRASKA AtiRICl I.TIRAL EXPERIMENT STATIC N orgamza obtained i coin tin- orirai \ ■- incut ill pro .iL'elit 1,1 \ ( ) t 11 As the work has been carried on thru these different tions. very definite and outstanding results have lx*en COUNTY AGRICULTURAL WORK Agricultural work for the year 1921 consisted of nation of the definite lines of work already started in I ized counties, and the development of more extent work thru precinct and community organization*. emphasi- ra given during the past year to the devek community program* of work. In several counties. | all Extension work was conducted in this manner. quaint the fanner- with the relatH proved strains and varieties of props v during the year in order to establish a sup| which would lie available for seeding purposes. M farmer- availed themselves of thi- work. The cei Bale in the State as a result of this work i- as t 4:W.(KK) bushels: oats. Il'Ii.imio bush proved med corn were -ecured liv the Extension Agi farmers of the State. Great progress was made in the "Purebi campaign during the year. The number enrolled increased more than 200 per cent. Ncarlv 1.000 far cattle for bovine tuberculosis t ion &lt;liirinir the year. I &gt;i-it n h i~t r:i t by the Experiment Stations. S potatoes. 44.IHM) Ihi-IicU. Approximate] pledged to keep only pur»" bred sins &lt;&gt;n their farms. More tha 8.."&gt;(K) registered animal- hare brni secured l&gt;v farmer* thru tli efforts of Extension Acentft. Active a-.- Mance wag rendered i i&gt;rpiiiizin&lt;r &lt;rr&lt;di|&gt;&gt; of nnoers for tbe !c&gt;iinii of 31.915 head &lt; 1 lie Extension Agents in many &lt;•&lt; mm t&lt;&gt;~ hare I upon to handle the labor — 1 1 1 &gt; j &gt; 1 \" ami to art a- lal MpacMlly during the barveal -ea-&lt;&gt;n. In nevera! in- ;i«vnt&gt; have lieen called upon to nnike li &gt;nir tri|i&gt; and -ion ;i«l\erti&gt;in«r in order t&lt;&gt; wcure laborers t« &gt; supply t during harretit. During 1 1 1 i — ru«h warno the ipent&gt;* t lit* State Extension &lt; )Hiee informed us to their daily ii daily labor bulletin was issued in an effort in dire to sections wlieVe they were nio-t needed. Tlie agents supplying of S.619 bliorers for the fanner- of the St the year I92L The crop improvenienl work was given consider </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-Fifth Ansiai. Kkiiikt 41 II I I I 1 i I \ i 17 li Illct I I i-n food \grictiltural engineering work for the year has consisted Iv in giving assistance to % 27~&gt; fanners in diUMa and in 1\ ishing plans for remodeling or coniitructing farm buildings. ity-six drainage system- were plaWMn and adopted, ity water supply systems and M sewage systems were istalleri. Miinv soil aviai dams were in-tailed straightened, thus reclaiming ■ large amount of wasted land. Hie following activities have been conducted along norti - ial line»: Orchards pruned, 18&amp;, comprising 4i»i acres; irds sprayed. 138, 484 acre- involved. Assistance was given intiiifj: 69 orchard- averaging two acres each. In the potato i.iHMi bushels of improved wed vaa -ecured by tlie Ex- Agents for farmers of the State. ■"•el and rodent extermination work for the year was con - on HJO2&amp; farm- with a total acreage of 338,105. Over •_'•"• nf poisoned feed were used in carrying on this work. V- ■ re-nit of poultry activities 4.!W&lt;i farmers report inodi- ieir practice- in raising poultry. The-*' practices pertain in railing, fettling, and housing. HOME DEMONSTRATION WORK The principal activities of the Home work nave been alone ine- ui Clothine, Food and Nutrition. Home Health and e. and Home Management. -" ■ -- &gt;iv— Form work has Urn carried on in twenty-eight coun- I'lii- ha- proved to Ik- one of the most popular line- of attempted during the year. These counties conducting vpe of work report the inakinjr of a total of 2,405 forms. t Ionic Millinery km started in the early apruag and ap- itrly -i\ inciiiths" time deroted to it during the year. This i- barn conducted largely having in mind the training of aders. I'lu-e leaden in turn are carrying the infoi-m.i HI itained thru demonstration meetings hack to their reapaC' The report from one county indicate- that •liiiiiiii local leader- hare conducted -even local millinery -chools i total attendance of :i!&gt; women. These women have made it- with a total saving of # % 23&lt;&gt;.&lt;)O. Millinery work wa- cou - •d in 1-J counties during the vear. (mmI ami Nutrition work has been conducted in practically unties of the State during the year. This work ha- con - largely of instructions in canning of foods, drving of . meal planning, f(Mnl election, and hot school lunches. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Aouctxti hai. EimiMlXT Station 42 Health work ha&gt; U-en promoted in all organized countu of the State and in a few counties which do not have resident Extension representatives. The work has consisted largely of a health campaign conducted during the spring &lt;&gt;t' the Tear. TV campaign resulted in ■ large number of children taking up tin health game. Other phases of health work promoteil wet Home Nursing, Child Can', and Health Habit Home Management work has consisted of the household ai poultry account-. A number of demonstrations were established in the keeping of these accounts, having in view ■ study of bom management problems. Home equipment such a&gt; firele — ers. pressure cookers, and home convenience*! were establis a- demonstrations in several counties BOYS AM) GIRLS CLUB WORK During IJhil the clul&gt;- organized in Bovs ami &lt;&gt;irl&gt; ( Work were: coin, potato, garden, pig. sow and litter, da cow and calf, beef calf, sheep, poultry, canning. in;.', iiiul hot lunch. The Standard Clul&gt; \\a- enipha hundrecl and eichtv-sis Standard Clul&gt;- were orga membership of 4..VV.I. The value of produ :it a profit of ♦."i3.874.74. Of tin- Standard Clubs org of tin-in ri)iii|)lcic&lt;| all ;iiti\iii&lt;— required of ■ Stain as jinl«riii&lt;r. demonstration, exhibit : and with ;it lra-t (»f tin- enrolled members liliii&lt;_ r their final reports. then Achievement Cluh* were awarded their wvui these Achievement Clul*- were awai \ incut Seal. 7 their third seal, and 1 the fourth semi, meiit Seal. 7 their third &gt;eal. and 1 tl that they had r;"orjtani»*d their work and were taking that ihev had r orirani/.ed their work a cotirses. Boy- ami (iirl&gt;. Cluli Veek held the tir-t wee! courses. Boy- and (iirl* Clul&gt; \Veck held tlte first week 1921, was the lanpext ever helil. 'Kti cluli menilters Im Itil, \\ii- the largMl pvw lidil. -_'(i^ rluli memliers b tendance. Of thi- number, all except 13 had earned a&gt; County ( 'lianipion- or for excellent records in (lenionst rat ions. \t the State Fair '2r2 demonstratitH team&gt; competed for honor-. One thousand ninety-f ii were made. A Imi\&gt;" Cluli Camp &lt;&gt;ti the Fair (itoiuhIs 1 s7 Imivs during the week. A similar camp at the Agricultura College campus housed the girls who took part in dub activit at the State Fair. \ judging team and two demonstration team-, together witl tine exhibits in clothing, canning, corn, ami hojr-. represented Nebraska at the Interstate Fair at Sioux City, low; </seg>
            <seg id="p043">\ I \ ■ i for he-t results •X1HT1I inn rotatioi I'miici v-KiKTii Annul Kaon y.\ ite C led ■ free trip t»&gt; tke International St&lt;M-k Show at III,- state Dairy Clul&gt; demonstration team attended il Dairy Show" and the judging team the Interna- Clul&gt; Judging contest held at Atlanta. Georgia. \&lt;;konomy Kxtfii-ion work in Agronomy carried on daring 1921 may i- follow-: Improved Crops, their inspection and Water Erosion, Pastures, Soil Acidity and Liniinjr. Rotation her work was carried on in distributing improved crops Kanred wheat. Nebraska No. t; and No. 80 wheat-. Ne- it-. Hurt oat-. Ko-eu rye, and Minnesota 1 S 4 bar- high yielding -train- arc now U-injr jrrown in prae - y county in Nclua-ka. In the -cod in-|H'ction and &gt;rk. tield&gt; of these grains were traced a&gt; to the i'liirteon coinnmnity corn \aricty te-t- were carried on at - Jl - in thirteen counties. Shipped-in and local varieties, to - wa- furnished for ."&gt;."&gt; demonstrations of soy lodiiclion and for hojryin^ down with corn. Two re than li» awn in Nebraska were growing -"&gt; there will be more tiara 4&lt;mi growing them as :» t rat ions. I'ortv demonstrations of wavs to control water erosion wen re largely brush dam demonstrations. Id !«■ aaed and how they should 1h&gt; handled Ki\c demonstration trial- of various fertilizer- were con ed in three counties. The-c are in the nature of coo(&gt;orativ&lt; il-. and results are not vet availalilt Soil acidity te-t- were made on more than ."&gt;0 farms, and nine demonstrations conducted. Two liadlv eroded and run-down farm- were worked on to -tiaijrliteii out fields, rebuild the soil, and establish a definite I'ij.'. Ciilf. ami Poultry Clul&gt; champions eed, inspected for mixtures, impurities, disease. and if Dp to ~t uiulsinl. listed in ■ cert i tied mhmI I of 4: &gt; . - _'. s i&lt;H) l&gt;u~liel~ of seed of the improved kind oti *&gt;"&gt;.! hiM in 41 eoantifw of the Stnte. I'nic- 1 1 a i — will 1h- mwd for 9M"d in UY22. ions t\"|H' -election^, were gn/WU ill eii!M|&gt;iiri-oii. pasture mixtare ihtmiitratio— and ■ ■**■( many flemonfltratioM mt stiirtcd to riMtw wluit mMi </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nkhka.-ka Ac.iuc i i.ti bal Exnmnn Statjos 44 In carrying on this work. 8*2 nuttings were held with 3:SM people present, forty-five fairs were judged, 15 articles prepared for fariii papers, ami U visits made to farms other than for crop inspection work. ANIMAL HUSBANDRY Extension work in Animal Husbandry hu beea dividei into four divisions during the year, namely: Home Butchering Live Stock Improvement. County Breeders' A — ociations, aii' Sheep Management. llonie Butchering work ha- been confined largely The work baa had in view the instructing of farmers ami th wives in methods of producing a home meat supply. 1 demonstrations consisted of slaughtering, cutting, curing, a sausage making. In conjunction with this work the worn were given work in tin- canning of meats ami making of soi only purebred sire- on their farms dm County Breeders Associations have been furthered d the year. Suggestions have been given them fur enlarging activities. The field of the live stock breeders' association large one ami they are serving many useful purposes in counties. Among their mo-t active work we find the pron of the live stock exhibits at county fair and live stock -a l&gt;e outstanding. Six county associations were organised d the year. Sheep Management work has been at a disadvantage durinjr the last year because of the condition of the wool market. People were reluctmit to Ix-come at all interested in any phase of wool work. However, more than ten meetings were held at which demonstrations were conducted. The work consisted largely of in-truction- in fitting the lamb for market, condition ami quality of the wool clip, grading of wool, and -hearing demonstrations During the season •_"•' slaughtering and 24 cutting &lt; !&lt;• tioiir- were conducted on •_"•' farms with an avenge ;it of \~&gt; people. Lire Stock Improvement work ha- been centered one 111:1111 idea. iIkii of replacing knot-head, grade, ai -in-&gt; with good purebred*. The problem iru approach avrvnl different angles, mainly thru county live stoi comity fairs, lectures, and newspaper articles. Each one methods has provided 1 different means of etnpha.si value of the purebred sire. Available records indicate match ■ -j&lt;m) per cent increase in the Dumber of farnu </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Tiiiim v-FiKTii Anmai. Sbwi 45 1 I \ 1 V lite-t with tl: opporti Dai rv CLOTHING principal phases of rlnthhlg work conducted during the : die— forms, the use of sewing nachine attachments, nerv nuking of homemade dress forms lias been one of the ular phase* of Extension Work conducted in the State war. The women of the State have readily seen the of the dress form, and many more requests have been hi- assistance than coaM be met. Ninety-five dress form tions were held ill -Js counties of the State with a idance of 2,201. A- a result of these demonstrations. I ers of sewing machines are unable to make the se of the sewinjr machine attachments. The -ew - taehment work, therefore, baa in view the instruc ■ of these parts. A total of :&gt;•"&gt; demonstration*! -ewinjr machine attachment- were deinon - ith a total attendance of 710. rork in millinery was started during the tir-t of proximatelv six month- devoted to it. This has i very popular phase of clothing work and is in by the women of the State. During the year the - Was demonstrated at HM&gt; meetings in U countie-. ulal attendance of -J.-JTl women who in turn made DAIRY HISBANDRY Dairying has consisted primarily in itle. organizing Boys and Girls Dairy Calf nil members for judging contest-, and the or - iperative cow testing associations. desiring irood dairy cattle wen- assisted in the purchasing of five carloads of good dairy cattle in sting cattle for sale within the State. This tyjM' (■&lt;• ha- been in great demand, -ince dairying has beca mm iid-t profitable farm enterpriaei during the year, flit Dairy Calf dabs with a membership of 7."&gt; boya and ■i-e organised during the year. A Junior Dairy judging at which clnh members t(M&gt;k part was held in connection ie State Fair. The judging contest affords an excellent unity of training l&gt;oys and «-irls in live sttn-k selection. V Stock Judging Team was selected and trained to reprc- iii~ have been made at an approximate nrng to s-_'l.-_".&gt;.ViM1. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">XkBKASKA AcKK I I.TIRAI. KXPKKIMKNT STATION 46 wit I ;l 1 1 1 Z»m I w in ■u It t ! t I t t sent Nebraska at tin- National contest held in connect ion the National Dairy Snow. Thia toaai won neoMd place in petition with the sixteen represented. The l'liitte Valley Cow Testing Aasociatioa m orgi in Scotts Bluff County. Twenty-six herds containing ."i&lt; m » were entered in the association. The dairymca in thi- c are very much interested in the association and feel tliat well worth while. Reports indicate the association a nieces of great benefit t&lt;&gt; the larwen in that section of the St&lt; that it enables them to know which rows in their herds an ducinji economically. I— | l &gt; ro&lt;jTt'» in dairy development has been handicapped the year liy the financial situation. Many fanner- wen aatad in wearing better dairy cattle Imt were nnalile ti financial arrangements for |)iircha&gt;in!_ r them. With a . np of the present financial situation it i- believed mark vanceinetit will be made in the dairy industry of the St; ENGINEERING Extension work in Agricultural Mi to the following subjects: Drainage. Erosion. Farms! Motor-. Home Equipment, [rrigation. and Rural A The work in Agricultural Engineei means of actual demonstrations installe County Extension Agent ch&lt; t place the demonstration i- installed. It the demonstration -hall he absolutely tvi iiin county. For instance, if a parti Met land, a drainage demo -tratioi -i lMMielit&gt; of tile. The Extension En specifications, and complete engineei leel tion. During the rear 1921, !•".! demonstr wci-e -tailed in Nebraska. Of theae. M are finished an unfinished. The* demonstrations may 1h&gt; classified as Fair Ground Buildings, 4: Water Supply. 5; Building 3: Tractor Deaaonstrations, 1: Drainage Demonstrati Septic Tank Demonstrations. I: Erosion Demonstrati Irrigation Demonstrations. &gt;: Farmstead Demonstrati Sales Karn Plans. (&gt;. Daring the year. 1,990 -et- of blueprints were -cut fanners. 10.623 engineering bulletins were distributed, an letters of information were written from the office. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Thirty-Fifth Anniai. Hkimkt 47 II wil in i Fiv S I \ I \ \ \ I I i ma is planned that daring the year 1922 considerable help gives to County Fair Associations in the design and ar- ment of County Fair buildings, also we will continue tlu&gt; mi -ale- barn construction. During the past year ( lt&gt;_J 1 ) m baa U't'ii one of the main topics which have l&gt;een stressed. •in&lt;r demonstrations have l&gt;een installed in southeast- emi ka up to the present time, this l&gt;eing the first terrac- lira ■ done in the State These are bein^ watched with &gt;rk t -t Ipv land owners of this section ten FARM MANAGEMENT -inn work in Farm Management was carried on in with Farm Accounts. Enterprise Cost Records, Cost Farm leases, and Farm Organization. \t. n Account IxMiks were distributed in cooperation with Extension Agents. Due to the aafaTorabk financial le banks I »«m&lt;rlit only ."&gt;.&lt;MM) books. It is true, however. of tlie banks had l&gt;ooks left over from the previous ii .1 ■lit y-nine Extension Agents report that a total «f 1.362 ok- were distributed thru their offices and they further tat t'.'-J of these hook- were kept. Seven Extension ri that 15] fanner- made changes in their farm husi- i- a result of keeping farm account-. The Farm Demonstrator held 18 farm account schools with an I ;i-e project wa- drawn up to meet the situation i- ■ result of the increase of tenantry. ii iri-c co-t account- were pre&gt;ented in 10 countie- at - with 931 persons in attendance. Extension Agents i tit if- placed enterprise coal records. In all. ap - i«h» &gt;ii&lt;li records were placed. During the year. v Management Demonstrator munaaarised 1'T enterprise i-. Manv fanner- summarized their own records. •■pi complete eoat account- on crop and live stock ■e irganization exhibits were made at five county fairs II ivering a period of 17 day-, at which it was estimated that l.riiii people gave the exhibit more than passing interest. The farm dealt with the farm-tead. field arrangement, the mil cropping system, and the amount of live stork tliat a well-hal- farm -hould have for the region where the exhibit was </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Acrhti.ti rai, Exi-kkimext Station beei •chool of th I witl mill their B rura \s" ail' tl weir i tri ez Ilio-t wa FOODS AND NUTRITION The Extension work in Foods and Nutrition ha: divided into Meal Planning. Hot Lunches for rural s Preservation of Foods, Child Feed in jr. and Soap Making. Meal Planning work was conducted in ten counties State during the year. A total of •!' meetings were hel !S:&gt;:5 in attendance. A&gt; a result of these meetings ."&gt;!&gt; f have ke|)t weekly food calendar* a- a means of studying daily diet. Hot School Lunches have been promoted thru thf schools. followm«r two general methods: (1) thru the Boj (iirl&gt;" Clul»s. (-_') n&gt; ;i iiKire general plan in cooperation w patrons of the school. In promotinfi the second plan &lt;&gt;f visit&gt; wen- made to I s schools in '.' counties. Sixteen have adopted the project and arc now -crvin&lt;r hot hmcht Meat Canning and Soap Making work wa- eondi conjunction with the home butchering work. A tuta demonstration meetings were held in 1&lt;i counties. The ance at these meetings was 1.120. Reports from tin* we cate the following results: Fourteen w«i of meat, and other women 1. - 2&lt;mi poi Reports also indicate thai those attending passed the in formation to other- in their HOKTICl l/TTKE Extension Work in Horticultin two main headings, namelv: I all fruits, including a small •mount of foi culture, which has been confined proveinent work. Pomology work lia&gt; hen bearing orchards, the e-taUi-ln c care of irrapc-. During 1921. fifty pruning den jriven iii 18 different counties with ■ total at! apraying demonstrations in 11 different count ance of 1 15. Iii order to demonstrate that the home orchard n a profitable side issue on the general farm., oooperat Management work was carried on with 14 orchard ow eipht different counties. The disastrous late spring destroyed the crop prospects, mi that the re~uli^ wen nil mi far as fruit was concerned. In i I eaaea, sprayi earned oa until the middle of June, and the difference in th </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Tiiiktv-Fiktii An mai. Report 49 a pi I ici 1 I I 1 xiHiimc of the foliage of sprayed and unsprayed trees was te conspicuous. mspicuous. p was given in the establishing of two commercial ■ totaling 80 acres, and five home orchards totaling 3Vg i In this connect ion it might lx&gt; stated that an Extension ii. "Kstablislnng tlie Home Orchard," was issued during t year. Moreover, to encourage letter care of the home i I- already planted, a circular called "Fruit Notes" has irted. Three issues have l&gt;een sent to 1.500 home orchard tpc growing demonstrations were established in five ( and comprised eight home vineyards totaling :W."i vines, il from the* 1 vines amounted to 2,550 pounds, or an f about seven pounds per vine. ion work with potato production consisted prin - l&gt;evelopmcnt of the seed potato industry in the dry 18, demonstrating the value of good dry land seed ii the irrigated sections and in eastern and central Ne- mproving cultural practices, and reducing loses caused i toraire and transit. developing of the seed potato industry in the dry land Ih'cii promoted thru the seed potato certification. The f the h&gt;l!&gt; and !'.»•_'(» seasons in the certification of seed tat oe* demonstrated its immediate financial gain to the pro- \- a result the need certification for 1981 was put on a ng ba^is. Tlnve ins|)ectioii» were made during the field inspections and a bin inspection. This season ved for certified seed potatoes has ranged from per hundred, with mbbc growers asking for $8J0 During tlie ~:iine period, uncertified Bead potatoes Ion have mid at from si.ihi to $1.7."&gt; per -tribiition of liu-liel- certified was as follows: Bos tv. l&gt;.:.tn l&gt;ii-hels: Dawes Countv, 1 '2.730 bushels: bushels; Sioux Count v. 4.75O bushels; ■tribut ion of good wed potatoes has b.-en a very valu- i-i-i' of work. Demonstrations with western Nebraska 1 -ecd potatoes grown on irrigated sections and in the and pastern portions of the Slate haw given good re- Thev demonstrated thai in the mme localitv in western licl- per aire in yielding rapacity. They also demonstrated -t tain at an avenge priec of *l.."&gt;0 jmm- lnin- County. 7.960 boa Coimtv. 300 bushel turns. Ihey ileniunst rated that m the mum locality in western Xe1&gt;ra-ka. fariner&gt; were plant in&lt;r pototam that varied ovi-r 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 NkHKASKA Al.fCK I l.Tl KA1. Kxi'KlllMKM SlATlci.N that in central and eastern Xebrai only 100 bushels j&gt;er acre or less, using ttetter BBad potatoes it wa&gt; vield to l"&gt;0 bushels. ika inaiiv fanner- were getting whereas on the same land by quite possible to increase the The reduction of loss due to storage and transit was given special emphasis thru meetings held at eight of the most im portant potato flipping ]&gt;oints in western Nebraska daring October. At thaac aaaatnpi the better methods of handling potatoes so M to reduce the Io--c- l&gt;v di-ease in storage and transit were discussed. HOME HEALTH AND HYGIENE I'he Home Health and Hygiene work developed during vear has consisted of: Child Care. Home Health Habits f Children. Home Nursing. Home Emergencies, Adult lh Habit-, and Prevention of Communicable Diseases. K:i of the work ha- proved rery interesting. a&gt; the hous ally feels a need id' knowing more 01 The activities in market organisation iiniv be briefly stated as (1) of market information. (2) organisation of co - ojx'rative &lt;rniin elevator-, i :'&gt; i organization of live stock ship - ping associations. (4) organization of cooperative rraunariea, emergencies. Much of tin- work ha- l»een conducted roopei lively with Red Cross imr-r- and local doctors. A -uiniiiiiiv of the Home Health and Hygiene work for i year indicates a total of in Home Nursing ami Home Emei emie- demonstration-. &lt;'&gt;7 demonstrations in Health Habits, a •J.-1 demonstration* in Infant ami Child Care. Assistance u al&gt;u given in the weighing and measuring of 1 tj children, baby dimes, and assistance in Boys ami Girl* Club work. Dun the year a total of 9,780 people \\;i- reached thru tlii- work. M Illl home mana&lt;;emf\t KxttMi&gt;ioii work in Home Management \\a- nrnducted I a period &lt;&gt;f approximately eight months. The work nnisisl largely of establishing demonstrations in: \\\ House h&lt; Budgets and Accounts, i J ) Home iCquiptnent, ( :&gt; &gt; • Home Fi aishings. (4) Laandrrinf and House Cleaning. (5) Soap Makii and (&lt;&gt;) How Plaiuiinjr. Since the work wm conducted &lt;&gt;i such a &gt;liort period of time it lia&gt; 1 n impossible to new definite resultM. MARKET ORGANIZATIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Thirty-Fifth Asm al Report 51 (&amp;) organization of coo|H'rative egg circles. All of the market organization work has had in view giving of instruction as to the correct type of organization for cooperative market organi - zation. In demonstrating the value of those organizations a few organizations have ln-en perfected in various counties and assist - ance given in the reorganization of other associations in order thai they might comply with the state cooperative law. 1 'he ever-increasing interest in marketing problems has roiight forth a great demand for market information. As a re- ult a peal amount of time has l)een s|H&gt;nt in rural meeting* liscussing market conditions and market organizations. A bet ter idea of the demand for this type of information is obtained when we learn that ±20 meetings were attended at which market rohlems were discussed. The following report is taken from the work of a coopera - tive Shipping Association organized in one of the counties and illustrates the success of the cooperative marketing associations. During the quarter ending July 1st. 4."&gt; carloads of live stock eight to the shipper, or a net saving of #11.017. During ontli of June. 129 cans of cream and &lt;V25 cases of eggs hipped at a wring to the shipper all told for the period 1.0(10.00 after all handling charges were deducted. These have been obtained without a dollar of capital to start mm. The namoriatim is a nonstock, non-profit orjrani- It i- l&gt;a-ed on true coo|&gt;erative principles. POULTRY HUSBANDRY The principal farm and home problems considered during the year in poultry work were: standard l&gt;red poultry, demon- farms, culling, and Bovs' and Girls' 1'oultrv Clubs. In lion with these main problems a nunilier of others have nipha&gt;izeil. Culling ha* proved the most important piece of work in the year'a program. Thirty-four counties have received assist - ance, a total of 5,009 people attending demonstrations. Culling work has l&gt;cen conducted until it is now to the point where one |M-rsoii iii alniosi every community is able to do this work. The result- are ea-ily noticeable in the average yearly production. ■ — — — — —^~ . . i The mating of poultry flocks is one of the most important pieces of work for the future. This work will consist primarily in the election of breeding stock and the Draper mating of the same for standard requirement! and for egg production. The hipped, valued at $60,725.25 at a &gt;avin*r of $1.95 \wr him- </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nkhhaska A&lt;;km ri.TVRAi. Experimknt Station 52 I. f v E-k was started in nine counties the pa&gt;t year. includin&lt;r - ks. Considering the large nunil&gt;er of accredited farm Hoi ilications received by November 1st. it will make this om &lt; major feature- of work for the ooaaiag year. Demonstrations in the nuxing of feeils were given durinj the fall. Comparison- were made with home mixed and com meri-ial feeds. In one county it km found that homemade i\r} mash cost *l. ; i s per hundredweight and commercial dry mas! of pood quality cost $3.50 per hundredweight. The importanei of this work is readily appivcia! &gt;d when the possibility of sav injr two-thirds of the cost of feeding poultry i&gt; considered. Preservation of egga and the infertile egg campaign wn farthered largely thru publicity. Thirtj demonstrations witl an attendance of J.js."i were held in nine counties on the pre-cr ration of eg&lt;r». In addition, "&gt;..".."&gt;o pieces of publicity mattei wen- distributed. The infertile egg campaign was conductec thru the local egg lnivei&gt; of the State, railing the the campaign and requesting them t&lt;&gt; indicate t copies of publicity matter they could u&gt;&lt;- to go A total of :&gt;o.(MNi copies of a circular dea pnxluction wib dintrihuted to farmer* am Prairie &lt;1&lt;&gt;&lt;z eradication was conducted in practically a wer-teni counties of the State. In one county every known praii do&gt;r town baa been mapped, and poison has been scattered ov many of them. The elimination of the prairie do&lt;jr a- ai iioiiiic pest is jrraduallv being accomplished. There has been a great demand for rat extermination work. In March the first work of this kind was {riven thru four demon strations. with !»!&gt; people in attendance. The rat is the one |IWl animal j&gt;est thrnout the whole of the State. There are few RODENT ERADICATION Rodent eradication work in Nebraska i- rarrii o|MTiitii)n with the Huifiiii of Biological Survey i I &gt;«-] •;■ l't 11 i&lt;&gt;iit i»f Afrriciiltiifc. The principal phase* i)li:i-izc&lt;l in ihi&gt; State wt-iv : Gopher Eradication Pop ami Kai Extermination. Intensive gopher eradication campaign** wet* i Cii— . I)oui^lii&gt;. Madison. Nmikc. Seward. Lancaati nml Dakota counties. In each of these counties m ~m selected with a riew of freeing it fruni poph**rs ai incnasinp the sixe of tin* area. The work was ihhkIii ed »f ■ ri i pr na 11(1 K1 I on III.' f WOT in. I P induct •. F ( II are I p*a&lt; ted en thru &lt;li'tiii)ii.-triii ion-. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Thirty-Fifth Axniai. Kkp«&gt;kt 53 farn out a I ) nal n l-eiill that are not infested with the j&gt;est.s. The eliniination of it i- possible only by permanent repressive measures, mt proof buildings. ;i systematic education campaign, the elimina- i — r* ,\ — - " _ — i — r* — — t ion. in m fur a- possible, of outside breeding and feeding places urban, and 1&gt;\ storing of foodstuffs and grain in rat-proof nen Demonstrations] work has consisted in the poisoning ipping of rats together with discussions of other means of xtermination. V summary of all rodent work shows that ii.»&gt;lt&gt; ln&gt;xes of «•!• poiooB and i.^-J't of poisoned grain were distributed dur- nr. Two tliousand fifty-one local roo|RTa,tors haw the work. FAIRS riu- Kxtension Service has always felt that the County and • Fain were excellent means for conducting demonstrations. contact obtained at these fairs the Service is able, by -tudied exhibits and carefully planned demonstrations. The County Fairs are a studied factor in the development i»V« and (iirl- Club work within the county while the State lears the same relation to the State that the County Fair to the comity. At the State Fair are determined the chaiii - iiulirinir and denionstrat icmal teams for the whole State. past vear 7(7 boys and girls exhibited at the State Fair, taking down a total of $1,035.75 in prises. During Lftil, two circuit- of county fair&gt; were attended bv Agricultural College. In the nine county fairs visited in 1 ( .»-J1 The Extension Service has become a very definite factor ng of judges for county fairs. During the past i ■ear I total of ."&gt;!• fairs asked for judges and were supplied to he extent of ls4 judges. The reason that this Service is able o reach approximately !&gt;&lt;&gt; per cent of the fairs of the State of Nelmi-ka i- thai the judfjiw are expected to give n running lecture with their placings. thus giving a very practical educa - tional demonstration to l&gt;oth exhibitor and spectator. The pop- ty of this service is evidenced by the high percentage of fairs -ting this service. xhihit 11 1 :i &gt; 1&lt;- up of demonstrations] exhibits from the xiinatt'lv 30.000 people were reached. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska A&lt;;ri&lt; i i.tirai. Experiment Station 54 i THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the University ( State ( treasurer from the treasurer of the United States installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1921, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, (Hatch fund) I 15,000.00 Expenditure Salaries Labor Publications Postage and stationery Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Library Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures Scientific apparatus and specimens Live stock Traveling expenses Total 15.000.00 $15,0' L. E. GUNDERSOX January 10, 1922. Finance Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p055">r. ■ Lai Pos Fr &lt;h * F T I Tra J l'liiicTY-Kirm Annual Reran ...» FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the University ( State ) treasurer from * treasurer of the United States installment r the fiscal year ended June 30 '921, under act of Congress approved March 16, 1906, Adams fund) $15,000.00 "&gt;,' Expenditures iries or tage and stationery ight and express micals and laboratory supplies ds, plants, and sundry supplies dinp stuffs Is, machinery, and appliances 'ntitic apparatus and specimens e stock veling expenses $11,666.10 618.87 2.89 2.92 .•. 88.40 374.55 208.70 370.81 662.24 844.18 160.34 Total $15,000.00 $15,000.00 anuary 10, 1922. L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">hi otlu Expel Tota 14,139.01 ,•'.' il 1.20 'i 1 NKIlltASKA AliHM I Ml ltU. KXI'KIIIMKNT STATION FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDS Receipts Moneys received by the University (State) treasurer frc sources than the United States, for the use and benefit of tht for the use and benefit of tht ment Station and Substations, f. r the year ended June 30. 1921 State appropriations Sales $ 7,957.76 $ 6.1X1. 2.') * Balance on hand July 1, 1920 Receipts Total $34,031.50 $79,681 Expenditures Salaries Labor Publications Postage and stationery Freight and express 41.80 427 105.42 Heat, light, water, and power Chemicals and laboratory supplies 1 ,25. r &gt;. ( . 12 Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies 3,321 Feeding stuffs 2,383.1 'Ol.ll* Library A Tools, machinery, and appliances 1,597.79 Furniture and fixtures Scientific apparatus and specimens IJU1M 1,502. C Live stock Traveling expenses Contingent expenses Buildings and land Balance Total January 10, 1922. 26,073.74 73.499.9K $ 4,910.09 $ 3,142.78 7,063.07 3,864.5i; 170.25 673.32 521.86 1.422." 394.61 :{;i4fi,- 3,909.09 62&gt; 7.00554 6.352 &gt; $34,031.50 $79,681 L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p057">i Ac Kx v Expe .1 Tniifi y-Fiktii Asm u. Kkimkt FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Concluded APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE Experimental Substations e July 1, 1920, of legislative ap - riation of 1919 from the State vities fund for the benefit of the erimental Substations, for the years ending March 31, 1921 — jrth Platte ! &gt;! N s, ttsbluff entine tive appropriation of 1919 for ears ending March SI, 1921 — N Jrth Platte ottsblutf \ entin iitures, year ending June 30, , for superintendence, supplies, 1 tock, feed, seeds, machin - and betterment of the in N. tsbluff ntine \ None None None Vi n None $25,649.81 $25,649.81 L. E. GUNDERSON, io, 19: Finance Secretary. rth Plat ropriation balances June 30, 1921 North Platte Scottsbluff </seg>
            <seg id="p058">NeMKAKKA AuKK'l I.Tl ItAI. KxTEKl -M KXT STATION 58 OF I 246,007.4 4 1 he period [2,000] THE AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SERVICE NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT EXPENDITURES Fiscal year July 1, 1920-June 30, 1921 Federal State County appropriations appro- appro- Smith-Lever priations priations Salaries $hi,089 $48,741.47 $113,176.41 Printing and distribution of publications 2.270 .61 2,963.81 Stationery and small printing 1.1 !6 Postage, telegraph, and freight .60 1 ,298.94 ,87 1,271.15 I 827.00 Supplies Library 1 2L&gt; Til 61 30.31 Tools, machinery, and appliances 1\ 52 ■v 711.77 Furniture and fixture Scientific apparatus Traveling expenses Contingent expenses 40 ii.; 1 .34 960.50 1,7 4.350 1 6 .46 72.83 .68 Total $92,1 17 $80,0 ).&gt; L. E. GUNDERSON January 10, 1922 Finance The accounting of expenditure of funds up to July 1, here reported, was under the supervision of Mr. J. S. Dales ,036.96 6,290.41 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>