<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1931-1932</title>
               <date value="1933-01-01">1933-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1931 - 1932 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1933 From: The Adjutant. General of Nebraska. To: His Excellency. Charles W. Bryan. Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Subject: Biennial Report of 1931 and 1932. 1. In compliance with requirements of Sections 1 to 5, Chapter 55, Article 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1929, the following Biennial Report for the calendar years 1931 and 1932 is respectfully submitted. The Nebraska National Guard occupies an. enviable pcsition in its standing in the National Guard of the United States and that steady improvement which has so richly rewarded the efforts of its personnel for years has never been more potent than during the period covered by this report. Each year training has materially improved in a logical and progressive manner, and notwithstanding the fact that many states allot much more money for use of the National Guard, I sincerely believe there is not a better organization in any State in the Union than has Nebraska at this time. 2. The community interest in our units and the assistance siven by committees' of Chambers of Commerce and by the citizenship as a whole has been most gratifying and most helpful and I feel that this support is well warranted for it has become known throughout the State that our training camps are absolutely clean and wholesome and the fear of young men acquiring any bad habits in the Nebraska National Guard is a thing of the past. - 3. Annual armory inspections are made by nfricers of the United States Army detailed for that purpose. The results of our last armory inspections evidenced the closest conformity to prescribed schedules and found our organizations as a whole very satisfactory. 4. As previously reported, the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Nebraska National Guard have to contend is </seg>
            <seg id="p004">RLTORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the rental of armories. It is almrst impossible to rent suitable buildings and we conduct a continual fi&lt;rht tn h' li the rentals dnwn; on the other hand, the government is very irsistent th"!. we have armories that afford adequate proteclion to government property and that have ample space for armory drills and training. It is realized that Nebraska is behind ninny of Ire other States that have State owned armories and tie State is frequently criticised by inspectors on this ncc unt Lut th uuh c-nstantly urged to do so, I have not been willing and am not new willing to submit an rrmory biilding program for vour c-hsidcati-in, as well as that of the Legislature, until conditions generally speaking have become nearer normal. 5. The results of the Armory Drill Training and the Field Train - ing for the nerird of this report have been very satisfactory. The reports of officers from the War Department assigned to make in - spections indicate that the slate of tiarri'-a of nil organizations has steadily improved and that cur National Guard of today is better fitted to serve tl^e State or Nation in the event of an emergency than ever before in its history. In connection with the armory drills it is [.■ratifying to note that the attendance is Letter than it has ever been I'.efore and that many of rur companies h- ve enlisted to full strength authorized by the War Department and have a waiting list of those anxious to join. 6. The following is a list of ibe Urited States Army Officers and Sergeants who are detailed by the \\ ar Department to the State of Nebraska for instructional r.urposcs, and in reporting the increased efficiency of our National Guard pre per eppreciation of all lhe elements concerned therein would be lacking were not the regular army instructors on duty with cur troors accorded due recognition for their fine services to us. They have all given us the finest of co - operation, the most understanding and sympathetic aid in our problems and. in general, every opportunity to make the most of their ef - ficiency and time. Major Laurence W. Young, Inf. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska Major Emil H. Burgher, MC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska Captain Jack L. Meyer, QMC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska Captain Harold H. Elarth, Inf. DOL., Omaha, Nebraska Master Sgt. Lee R. G. Ward. Inf. DEML., Omaha, Nebraska Sergeant Emet G. Roach, Inf. DEML., Geiing. Nebraska Sergeant Hjalmar R. Strom, QMC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Sergeant Zack T. Scarborough, MC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska Sergeant Joel G. Gerard, Inf. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska 7. In conclusion I wish to express my rir-precintion to the officers and enlisted men of the National Guard who have through their hearty cooperation, assisted in bringing the Kel rast-a National Guard to the nresent high state of efficiency and the personnel thereof to a much higher standard. I also desire to extend my appreciation to the dozens of Chambers of Commerce and to the thrusnnds of loyal cit - izens who have given us their moral support and thireby assisted in rhaking the Nebraska National Guard a bigger and better organization. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. FINANCIAL STATEMENT NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Appropriation For biennium July 1, 1931, to July 1, 1933 8175,000.00 Expenditures July 1, 1931, to December 1, 1932 Office salaries . S12 290.00 Office maintenance ' 2 529.69 Miscellaneous 3,957.70 Labor at Rifle Range. ._ 4,16450 Rifle Range miscellaneous 10,441.57 Arsenal ... 1,103.81 Armory rental, light and heat 49,332.00 Pay enlisted men.... .... 24 358.00 116 325.15 Balance $ 58,674.85 STRENGTH BY CAMPANY AND DETACHMENT AS OF DECEMBER 1, 1932 Enl. War. Officers Men Officers State Staff- and State Detach. 7 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35TH DIVISION 69th Brigade Headquarters : 1 134th Infantry Headquarters 6 Med. Dept Det. 5 30 Headquarters Co. 2 62 Service Co. 3 97 1 Howitzer Co. 3 63 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 1st Bn. .. . 3 24 Company A . 3 64 Company B 3 64 Company C ' 3 .64 Company D 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 2nd Bn . 3 24 Company E 3 64 Company F 3 63 Company G 3 64 Company H 3 62 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 3rd Bn. 3 25 Company I . 3 63 Company K 'i 64 Company L 3 62 Company M 2 64 71 1108 1 UOlh Med. Regt. Headquarters . 8 Service Company 4 65 1 130th Collecting Company 1 64 130th Ambulance Company 2 48 166th Hospital Company . 5 64 110th Veterinary Company . 2 40 22 281 1 35th Div. Qm. Tn. Headquarters , 1 Hq. Detachment 2 14 Med. Dept. Det. 1 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 137th Motor Transport Company 2 48 138th Motor Transport Company , 2 48 119th Motor Repair Section . 1 20 119th Wagon Company 3 51 12()th Wagon Company 3 54 15 251 Grand Total 108 Officers 1640 Enlisted Men 2 War. Officers J ROSTER OF OFFICERS Name, Rank, Ann of Service Address STATE STAFF AND STATE DETACHMENT Paul, H. J, Brig. Gen., AGD, State Capitol, Lincoln O'Connell. Frank B., Major, AGD, State Capitol, Lincoln Stout, Richard F.,' Major, JAGD, Stele Ciipitol Lincoln Stein, H. C, Major, QMC, State Capitol. Lincoln McConnaughey, W. E. Major, QMC, State Capitol Lincoln Yoder, Byron E., Capt, QMC, 719 Fed. Trust Bldg., Lincoln Gillaspie, Trev. E., Capt, Ord., Post Office, Lincoln 35th DIVISION 69lh Brigade Headquarters Thomas. Amos, Brig. Gen., Inf., 824 Omaha Nat'l Bank Bldg., Omaha 134th Infant ry Hcadquarters Douglas, Robert G., Col., Inf., State Capitol, Lincoln McCormick, Clyde E., Lt. CcL, Inf., 808 So. 59th St., Omaha Blodgett, M. A., Capt, Inf., U. P. Res., North Platte Thornton, Thomas Q., Capt, Inf., 309 Elec. Bldg., Omaha Utterback, Wm. G., Capt., Inf., Box 452, Nebraska City Capsey, Harold -C, Major, Chaplain, 514 Main St, Wayne </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL .Med. Dept. Det. Ensor, Holland R.. Major, MC. Box 83 South Sid--, Omaha Achenbach, Wm. H„ Capt, DC, 804 Central Ave. Nebraska City Altwood, Norman II., Copt.. MC, 813 Med. Arts Bldg.; Omaha Kinvoun, Floyd H., Capt, MC, 11-1 So. 50th St., Omaha Sands, Robt. L., Capt., MC. L012 Decatur St., Omaha Headquarters Company McGill. Albert L., Capt., Inf., 1505 Olin A\e. Omaha Bradley, James A. 2i.d l.t., ;';2::2 Fc-p|.leton St. Omaha Service Company Beckley, Harry A., Capt. Inf., 613 Grant Ave. York Anderson, Raymond .)„ 1st Lt, Inf.. 415 W. 7th St. York Davis, James W., 2nd Lt, Inf., 1011 Burlington Ave.. York McCall, George A., War. Off.. 0:;7 W. 7th St., York Howitzer Company Ilinze. Alfred F., Capt, Inf.. Gciing Laughlin, Leslie J.. 1st Lt.. Inf... Gering Wood. Warren C, 2nd Lt., Inf., Gering- Hq. 1st Bn. Stoll. Fred IL, Major, Inf., 915 So. 12th St., Beatrice Hq. Co., 1st Bn. Yager, Leslie, Jr.. 1st Lt. Inf., 1116 Fourth Ave., Nebraska City .lames, Benny C, 2nd Lt. Int., 2tith St &amp; 1st Ave., Nebraska City Company A Thurman, Ray A..- Capt. Inf., oth St. &amp; 3rd Ave., Nebraska City Morton, Thos. S., 1st Lt. Inf. 823 Park Ave., Nebraska City Wilson R,obt R., 2nd Lt, Inf., 19i8 First Ave., Nebraska City Company B Myers, Merven F., Capt Inf., 16th &amp; Dewey Sts., Falls. City Smith, Leo L., 1st Lt, Inf. 1821 Towle St., Falls City Spencer, Harold J., 2nd Lt, Inf. 1713 Fulton St., Falls City </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Company C • Coonley, Dean E., Cant, Inf. IU9 S -. Sunnier St., Beatrice Collier, Harold L. 1st Lt.. Inf., 821 Beaver St., Beatrice Boatsman, Alford C, 2nd Lt, Inf., 923 No. 7th St., Beatrice Company D Miltonberger, Butler B., Cunt., Inf. 1202 No. Locust St, North Platte Petersen, Fred C, 1st Lt. Inf.. 1018 W. 3rd St., North Platte Wilson, Denver W. 2nd Lt, Inf., Apt. 4. Reynolds Tcr., North Platte Hq. 2d Bn. Eby, Louis It., Major, Inf.. Harrington Hq. Co. 2d Bn. Davis, Guy T., 1st Lt., Inf., Armory 1-th &amp; Dodge Sts., Omaha Trout, John T., 2nd LU Inf., 5012 Burt St., Omaha Company E Eatwell. Ora A., Capt., Inf., 2120 Ave. D, Scottsbluff Runyon, Harold M., 1st Lt, Inf., 1806 Sth Ave., Scottsbluff Cooper, Basil A., 2nd Lt., Inf., 2119 Ave. B„ Scottsbluff Company F Hardy, Lloyd R., Capt, Inf., Hartington Steiskal, Julius. 1st Lt., Inf., Hartington Ready, George E., 2nd Lt, Inf., Hartington Company G Riley, Ivan C, Capt., Inf., Hustings Nat'l Bank, Hastings Van Fleet, Robt. J., 1st Lt, Inf., 315 Saunders Ave., Hastings Lovell, Robt. A., 2nd Lt., Inf., 815 No. Lexington, Hastings Company H Barratt, Edgar, Capt, Inf., 112 So." Clark St., Grand Island James, Percy F., 1st Lt, Inf., 201 W. 7th St.. Grand Island McElroy, Francis L., 2nd Lt, Inf., 210 W. 11th St, Grand Lslund Hq. 3d Bn. Grasborg, Bert C, Major, Inf., 204 L'.P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. Co., 3d Rn. Van Kirk. Rolla C, 1st.Lt., Inf., 802 First Nat'l Bank Bldg., Lincoln Dier : Clifford L., 2nd Lt, Inf.. 2845 P St.. Lincoln Company 1 Hoke, Edwin F., Capt, Inf. Post Office, Lincoln Stewart, Clarence J.. 1st Lt, Inf., 1127 Hum St., Lincoln \veyand, Foster H., 2nd Lt, Inf., 834 Llmwood St., Lincoln . Company K Peterson, Emil B.. Capt, Inf., 204 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha Crocker, Judd W., 1st Lt, Inf., 2423 Manderson St, Omah:i Gatz, Edwin C, 2nd Lt, Inf., 3105 No. 59th St, Omaha Company L Thomsen, Alfred. Capt, Inf., Rt 8, Florence Sta, Omaha Kelso, Earl H, 1st Lt Inf., 1919 Emmet St, Omaha Roberts, Donald L, 2nd Lt, Inf., 3948 No. 38th St, Omaha Company M Geesen, Edward J, Capt, Inf., 641 Seward St., Seward Jones, Erwin A, 1st Lt, Inf., 222 So. Columbia Ave, Seward 110th Med. Regt. Headquarters Hilton, David C, Col.. MC, 305 Richards Blk'., Lincoln Bartholomew, Phillip H, Lt. Col, MC State Capitol, Lincoln Evans, J. North, Major, MC, Columbus Brooks. Earl B, Major, MC, 939 Stuart Bldg, Lincoln Bennett, John R, Major, DC, 917 Stuart, bldg, Lincoln Norden, Carl J, Major, VC, 227 No. 9th St, Lincoln Deppen, Earl N, Capt, MC, 911 Sec. Mut Bldg, Lincoln Leonard, John C, Capt, Chaplain, 7012 Francis St, Lincoln Service Company Ball, Harry R, Capt, MAC. 1120 N St, Lincoln Stearns, Harry A, Capt, MAC, Post Office, Lincoln Neely, J. Marshall. 1st Lt, MC, 709 So. 31st St, Lincoln Strickland, Henry H, 1st Lt, MAC, 709 So. 29th St, Lincoln Havlicek, Lumir C, War. Off, 620 Main St., Crete </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 130th Collecting Co. Evans, Carroll D, Jr., Capt, MC, Columbus 1 30th Ambulance Co. Swanson Leonard A, Capt, MC. 412 No. Hastings Ave, Hastings Thomas, Dwight P., 1st Lt, MAC, 510 E. 5th St, Hastings ■ 6£th Hospital Co. Johnson, Rodney K.. Capt, MC, Friend Wells, Francis A, Capt, MC, 101J Sharp Bldg, Lincoln Johnston, Leonard R, Capt, DC, 916 Stuart Bldg, Lincoln Anderson, James B, Capt, MC 1119 Fed. Trust Bldg, Lincoln Merideth, John A, Capt, MC, 914 Fed. Trust Bldg.. Lincoln Barber. George H, 1st Lt, MAC, 2248 Sewell St, Lincoln 110th Veterinary Co. Alford„ S. W, Cnpt, VC, 1311 No. 37th St.. Lincoln Skidmo.-e, Lcuis V, 1st Lt, VC, 3859 Dudley St, Lincoln 35th Div. Qm. Tn. Headquarters Poteet, Marcus L, Major, QMC, 705 First Natl Bank Bldg, Lincoln Hq. Detachment Turner, Howard R. 1st Lt, QMC, 2025 Harwood St, Lincoln Browne, Wm. H, 2nd Lt, QMC, 2701 Eveictt St, Lincoln Med. Dept. Det. Rose, Wallace E, Capt, MC. 2218 V« Central Ave, Kearney 137th Mot. Tr. Co. Ellis, Harry H, 1st Lt, QMC, 1st Natl Bank Bldg, Holdrege Leffler, Delbert C, 2nd Lt, QMC 210 Fourth Ave, Holdrege 138th Mot. Tr. Co. Olson, Nels A, 1st Lt, QMC, 537 M: No. Broad St, Fremont Peterson, Vaughn, 2nd Lt.. QMC, No. Hancock St, Fremont </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 119lh Mot. Rep. Sec. Yakish, Wesley II, 1st Lt, QMC, 1518 No. Clarkson St, Fremont 119th Wagon Co. Bates, Merton 0, Cant, QMC. Court House, Lexington Nielsen, Frederick, let Lt, QMC. 131)8 No. Grant St, Lexington Burnett, Oliver H, 2nd Lt. QMC, 1001 Jackson St, Lexington 120th Wagon Co. Henninger, Guy N, Capt, QMC. Court House, Kearney Atkinson, William J. 1st Lt, QMC, 927 W. 28th St.. Kearney Mattson, Herman G, 2nd Lt:, QMC, 107 E. 27th St., Kearney STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1931 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1931, to December 1, 1931. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA . ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 16, 1931 General Orders No. 2 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Saturday, May 30, 1931, conse - crated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National Flag, will, in accordance with par. 2, sub-par. 11, Army Regulations 260-10, lie displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organizations in the ob - servance of the day, C-'iuniniuling Officers of National Guard Organ - izations will place their respective commands at the disposal of local lepKesentatives of the Gtand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact thi't credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: It J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 15, 1931 General Orders No. 3 1. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. 43-1, file MB-354.1 Nebraska-23, May 21, 1931, the State Staff and Stale- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Detachment, 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train QMC, and 110th Medi - cal Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebr; ska August 3 to 17, 1931, inclusive, under com - mand of Brigadier General Herbert J, Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty the above named organizations will return to their home stations. a. Company E and Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will leave their home stations August 2, 1931. Co. E will leave camp A r gust 16, 193L so as to arrive at their home station August 17, 1931. The Howitzer Company will Lave camp August 17, 1931, so as to arrive at their home station August 18, 1931. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C. Stein and two enlisted men- of the State Detachment, will go into camp at the eailiest possible moment July 31, 1931, and will remain in ".amp August 18 and 19, 1931. 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment August 1. 1931, taking the fiist train ayailable for that purpose: Stute Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, one Cap - tain, QMC, one Crptain, Ord.. and nineteen enlisted men; Service De - tachment, Service Company, 134th Infantry, consisting of one Captain. S. O, one First Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detachment. 35th Livision Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six enlisted men; and Service Detachment, Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain, S. O, and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance detachment for the purpose of pre - paring camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to Major H. C. Stein August 1, 1931. The Commanding Officer of the 110th Medical Regiment will designate one Captain, MC, to accompany the advance detachment of his regiment and will see that he is provided with the necessary medical equipment to establish a camp infirmary. This Captain will remain in camp with the rear de - tachment August 18, 1931. 4. Upon arrival in camp August 1 1931, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134th Infantry, will establish mess for his Detach - ment, and the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 110th Medical Regiment, will immediately establish mess for the State Detachment, Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, and his Detachment The officers in charge should see that at least one regular cook is in - cluded for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train and 110th Medical Regiment will see that equipment necessary ft r establishing commissaries is forwarded with advance detachments. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5. A rear detachment consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, and one Captain, Ord, of the State Staff, and nineteen enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 18, 1931, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, epuip - ment. etc, will be handled by circular letters from this office. 7. The Commanding Officer of the 110th Medical Regiment will see that all officers are physically examined in accordance with para - graph 4, NGR 27. He will designate such medical officers as are neces - sary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph; he will see that physical examination papers are turned in to him by August 10, 1931, and will furnish the Camp Adjutant with a list of those officers who have not been examined. 8. All enlisted men will he physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp and company and detachment commanders will cooperate with the medical department in seeing that all men are present and that their men are so examined. The following named officers are designated to make the examinations called for in this paragraph and will report to the Camp Commander at 9:00 A. M. on the morning of August 3. 1931, for instructions pertaining thereto: Major Earl B. Brooks, MC Major John R. Bennett, DC Captain Herbert M. Eisler, MC Captain James B. Anderson, MC Captain Floyd H. Kinyoun, MC Captain Wallace A. Gerrie, MC 9. Travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The. Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 16, 1931 General Orders No. 4 - ■ 1. The Annual Inventory of Property Pertaining to the organiz - ations of the Nebraska National Guard herein mentioned, as required by paragraph 3 NGR 75-11, dated June 30, 1927, will be made on the following dates: October 20, 1931 Hq. Det, 35th Div.. Tn. Lincoln October 21. 1931 110th Vet Co, 110th Med. Reijl. Lincoln October 22, 1931 Company I, 134th Inf. Lincoln October 20, 1931 Hq. Co, 1st Bn, 134th Inf. Nebraska City October 27, 1931 Company A, 134th Inf. Nebraska Cit&gt; October 28, 1931 Company B, 134th Inf. Falls City . November 5, 1931 Service Co, 110th Med. Regt Lincoln November 6, 1931 Hq. Co, 3d Bn, 134th Inf. Lincoln November 9, 1931 166th Hosp. Co, 110th Med. Regt Lincoln November 12, 1931 Company C,. 134th Inf. Beatrice November 13, 1931 Band Sec, 110th Med. Regt. Crete November 16, 1931 Company E, 134th Inf. Scottsbluff November 17, 1931 How. Co, 134th Inf. Gering November 19, 1931 Company D, 134th Inf. North Platte November 20, 1931 119th Wagon Co, 35th Div. Tn. Lexington November 23, 1931 138th Mot. Tr. Co, 35th Div. Tn. Fremont November 24, 1931 119th Mot Rep. Sec, 35th Div. Tn. Fremont November 30, 1931 137th Mot Tr. Co, 35th Div. Tn. Holdrege December 1, 193] 120th Wagon Co, 35th Div. Tn. Kearney December 2, 1931 Med. Dept Det, 35th Div. Tn. Kearney December 3, 1931 Company H, 134th Inf. Grand Island December 4, 1931 130th Coll. Co, 110th Med. Regt Columbus December 7, 1931 Company M, 134th Inf. Seward December 8, 1931 Service Co, 134th Inf. York December 9, 1931 Company G, 134th' Inf. Hastings December 10, 1931 130th Amb. Co, 110th Med. Regt Hastings December 14, 1931 Company F, 134th Inf. . Hartington December 16, 1931 Company K, 134th Inf. Omaha December 17, 1931 Med. Dept. Det, 134th Inf. Omaha December 18, 1931 Hq. Co, 2nd Bn, 134th Inf. Omaha December 19, 1931 Reirtl. Hq. Co, 134th Inf. Omaha December 21, 1931 Company L, 134th Inf. Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. A1J property will he arranged so that it may be counted with the least pessil le delay. Individual equipment records, Form No. 30, WD-MB. will be posted to date so as to be authentic and can be con - sidered in the inventory. 3. Attention invited to the provisions of NGR 75-3, dated January 22, 1927, which requires that all property be kept in the armory. 4. Responsible Office with Supply Sergeant and two (2) assistants will be present to resist in the inventory on the date set. By order of the Governor: II. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1932 General Orders No. 1 ? 1. The current season of Kan&gt;&gt;e Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, D)32, .to October 31, 1932. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst Adjutant General Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 4, 1932 General Orders No. 2 1. The Commander-in-Chief announces with profound sor - row the death of Second Lieutenant Raymond R. Sorensen, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard. 2. Lieutenant Raymond R. Sorensen enlisted in Hq. Co, 2nd Bn, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, July 7, 1921. Appointed Pvt lcl. July 7, 1921. Appointed Corporal April 9, 1924. Honorably discharged July 6, 1924, expiration term of service. Reenlisted July 7, 1924, warrant as Corporal con - tinued on reenlistment Honorably discharged July 6, 1925, expiration term of service. Reenlisted July 18, 1925. Trans - ferred to Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, April 1, 1926. Appointed Sergeant April 15,' 1926. Honorably discharged July 17, 1926, expiration term of service. Reenlisted July 18, 1926, warrant as Sergeant continued on reenlistment Honorably discharged July 17, 1927, expiration term of service. Reenlisted July 18, 1927, warrant as Sergeant continued on reenlistment. Honorably discharged July 17, 1928, expira - tion term of service. Reenlisted July 18, 1929, .warrant as Sergeant continued on reenlistment Appointed 1st Sergeant October 1, 1928. Honorably discharged July 17, 1929, expira - tion term of service, Reenlisted July 18, 1929, warrant as 1st Sergeant continued on reenlistment. Honorably discharged August 20, 1929, to accept commission. Commissioned Second Lieutenant, Infantry, August 21, 1929. Federally recognized August 22, 1929. Served to death, January 2, 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 . REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. Lieutenant Sorenscn's service has been most valuable to the National Guard of this State, having been an active supporter and a diligent worker since he enlisted in same and his services were recognized as outstanding when he was pro - moted . and commissioned. Lieutenant Sorensen's military career as well as his work in civilian life has been a splendid example for the young men of his command with whom he has been closely associated and he will long be remembered as one of the able and efficient officers of the Nebraska National Guard, the sympathy of which is extended to his family in '.his, their hour of sorrow. By order of the Governor: II. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 11, 1932 General Orders No. 3 1. The safety rules for small arms firing set out below are pub - lished for the information and .midance of all members of the National Guard, and will be enforced at home ranges as well as at camp when - ever any firing is being done. 2. All officers are hereby charged not to permit any man to fiie with any weapon until he has been instructed and examined in these general safely rules and in the special' lules pertaining to the weapon he is about to fire. 3. While men are waiting on the "ready line", or just prior to that time, they will be examined in these rules by a commissioned officer. 4. No man will be allowed to take his place on the firing line who has not in his personal possession, a copy of these rules. GENERAL SAFETY RULES a. Before firing is done on any range, the danger area will be ex - amined and all persons and livestock will be excluded therefrom. b. Range guards, properly instructed in their duties, will be posted in such a manner that all approaches to the danger area will be covered. c. Red danger flags and, when deemed necessary, warning signs will be displayed at appropriate points to warn persons that firing is going on. d. A red flag will be displayed from a prominent point on this range at all times during firing. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL e. Arrangements will he made to notify the general public in that. locality, at least 2-1 hours in advance, that firing with ball ammunition is to be done. f. Whenever any firearm is first taken in hand, it will be presumed to be loaded and cocked until a caicful examination has proved the contrary. g. Any officer or soldier who observes ary conditions which make firing dangerous will immediately con.niand or signal "cease firing". h. The command "ceape firing" given on the range will always be i.he**ed instantly and proper investigation as to its propriety will be in.-.do afterwards. i. Ball ammunition will be issued to the firer only after his arrival on the firing, line. j. No ball ammunition will he tal en from the firing line by firer. k. Men will remain on the filing line until ordered off by the offi - cer in charge of firing. 1. Upon completion if the firing of any order, each weapon used ivll be inspected! on an '"inhpection line' which will he established be - tween the firing line and the ready line. m. In case of a "miss-fire" or "jam", tie weapon will be held point - ing toward the target and without further movement until it has been examined by an officer. n. No firing will be done bef&lt; re the command "commence firing" has been given or after the command "cease firing." has been given. o. . All weapons within 50 yards of the firing line will be kept with the- firing mechanism in the "open" position. n. No loud talking and no instruction of any kind, no classes or group, will he permitted within 50 yards of the firing line. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL q. Before a unit leaves the range, it will be assembled and in - spected by its commander to see that weapons are clean and that no man has any ball ammunition in his possession. Its commander will then report personally to the officer in charge of firing the results of his inspection, and request permission to leave the range. „ RIFLE a. Special care will be taken to avoid the following causes of acci - dents: (1) cartridges becoming hot from prolonged exposure to the direct rays of the sun, (2) dirt or other obstruction in the bore, (3) undue amount of oil in the bore and (4) badly fitting (loose) bolt b. Each man will fire his own rifle. c. At the completion of firing, sights will be laid and bolls will be left open. d. Rifles not in the hands of the men will be kept in racks. e. Shoulder and elbow pads will be used. The use of cotton in the ears will be encouraged. PISTOL a. Before any firing is begun, the detail will be formed in single rank and pistols will first be inspected for general condition, and then, at the command of the inspector, will be tested for (1) safety lock, (2) grip safety, (3) half-cock notch safety, and (4) action of disconnection. Any pistol failing in any of these tests will be tagged and removed from the vicinity of the firing line. | b. Only one man per target will be allowed on the firing line. c. No pistol will be loaded until the firer is on the firing line and the command "load" has been given. d. Pistols will be kept locked, after loading, until the command "ready" is given. e. Finger will not be placed in the trigger until pistol is pointing at the target </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL f. In. case of a "miss-fire" or "jam", the firer will first remove the magazine and then wait for orders from the officer in charge of firing. g. When on the firing line the firer will not turn his head or body to the side or rear without first removing the magazine and slide to the "open" position. h. Anyone picking up a pistol will always execute "unload" imme - diately. i. Except in the firing line when pistol is pointing at the target, a pistol in the hand will always be carried at "inspection pistol". AUTOMATIC RIFLE a. Magazine will not be inserted until firer is on the firing line. b. Except when on the firing line, bolt will be in the "forward" position and no magazine will be in the magazine opening. c. After firing, no man will leave the firing line until "b" has been done. MACHINE GUN Wooden safety I locks will be inserted in the breech before the com - mand "stand clear'' is given and will not be removed until a new fire order is given. 3-INCH MORTAR a. The mortar will not be fired at a rate exceeding 10 rounds per minute. b. Projectiles will not be assembled until ready to fire. c. Green cartridges only and practice shell MK.I only will be used. d. More than three (3) powder lings will never be used. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL e. In case of "n.iss-fire", the projectile will be removed only by an officer or a noncommissioned officer and- only after two minutes have elapsed. f. Record will be kept of all "duds" fired and at the conclusion of the firing for the day they will be collected carefully and buried suffi - ciently deep to preclude any danger. COMBAT AND FIELD EXERCISES a. When blank cartridges are used, no rifle will be fired at anyone within 50 yards. b. When ball ammunition is used, no men except those in the most advanced firing position, will be permitted to fire. c. When an advance is contemplated firing must cease, rifles must be unloaded and locked, before the advance begins. Men arriving at the new and most advanced firing position may open fire without waiting for those who are in the rear to come up. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 18, 1932 General Orders No. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Pursuant to authori'y contained in Training Authority No. 43-1, file MB-354.1 Nebraska-24, July 14, 1932, the State Staff and State De - tachment, 134th Infantry, 35th Division. Train QMC, and 110th Medical Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 1 to 15, 1932, inclusive, under com - mand of Brigadier General Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty the above named organizations will return to their home stations. a. Company E. 134th Infantry, will be allowed sixteen days' pay and the Howitzer Ci nipany, 134th Infantry, will be al - lowed seventeen days', pay. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C. Stein, QMC, and two enlisted men of the State Letachment will go into camp at the earliest possible moment July 29, 1932, and will remain in camp August 16 and 17, 1932. 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment July 30; 1932. taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, one Captain, Ordnance, and nineteen enlisted men; Service Detachment Service Company, 134th Infantry, consisting of one Captain, S. O, one Fiist Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detachment 35th Livision Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six en - listed men; and Service i^elachinent, Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain, S. O, and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to Major H. C. Stein, July 30. 1932. The Commanding Officer of the 110th Medical Regiment will designate one Captain, MC, to accompany the advance detachment of l.is regiment and will see that he is provided with the necessary meuicol. equ.pment to establish a camp infirmary. This Captain will remain in camp with the rear detachment August 16, 1932. 4. Upon arrival in camp July 30, 1932. the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, liMth. Infantry, will establish mess for his Detach - ment, and the Commanding Oflicer, fcervice Detachment, 110th Medical Regiment, will immediately establish mess for the State Detachment, Headouartets Detachment, both Division Train, and his Detachment The officers in charge snould see that at least one regular cook is in - cluded for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134th In - fantry, 35th Division Train and ilOth Medical Regiment will see that </seg>
            <seg id="p026">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL equipment necessary for establishing commissaries is forwarded with advance detachments. . . 5. A rear detachment consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, and one Captain, Ordnance, of the State Staff, and nineteen en - listed men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 16, 1932, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc, wil be handled by circular letters from this office. 7. The Camp Commander of the Nebraska National Guard will see that all officers are physically examined in accordance with paragraph 4, NGR 27. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp. 8. The following named officers, residing at places other than the headquarters or organization to which they belong, are authorized trans - portation in kind from their actual residence, which is shown opposite their names, to the annual field training of the Nebraska National Guard at Ashland, Nebraska, August 1 to 15 inclusive, and return to their home station. Lt. Col. Robert G. Douglas, Hq. 134th Inf., Lincoln Capt. Wm. G. Utterback, Hq. 134th Inf., Nebraska City Major Harold C. Capsey, Chaplain, 134th Inf, Wayne Capt Wm. H. Achenbach, Med. Dept. Det. 134th Inf, Nebraska City Major Fred H. Stoll, Hq. 1st Bn, 134th Inf, Beatrice Major J. North Evans, Hq. 110th Med Regt, Columbus 9. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 17, 1932 General Orders No. 5 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Monday, May 30, 1932, conse - crated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National Flag will, in accordance with par. 2, sub-par. 11, AR 260-10, be displayed on all armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist. Veteran organizations in the observance of the day Commanding Officers of the National Guard Organizations will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">28 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28, 1932 General Orders No. 6 1. The Commander-in-Chief announces with profound sor - row the death of Captain Henning F. Elsasser, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard. 2. Henning F. Elasser was born at Fremont, Nebraska, October 10, 1883. He enlisted in Company L, 1st Regt. Inf. Nebraska National Guard, June 20, 1903, at the age of 20 years by Baehr. Appointed Corporal June 20, 1905. Appointed Ser - geant October 2, 1905. Reenlisted as a Sergeant June 20, 1906. Honorably discharged to accept commission March 26, 1907. Commissioned Second Lieutenant March 27, 1907. Commissioned Captain December 8, 1910, to rank from January 13, 1908. Recommissioned Captain S. O. No. 9, AGO, 1911, for five years. Commissioned Major, Third Battalion, 4th Inf, May 20, 1915, to rank from April 23, 1915. Mexican Border Service un - der call of President, June 18, 1916. Mustered out January 15, 1917. Commissioned Lt. Colonel, 4th Infantry, March 3, 1917, to rank from March 1, 1917, 'g. O. No. 6, AGD, 1917. Called into Federal service under call of the President March 25, 1917. Drafted into Federal service August 5, 1917, as Lt. Colonel Infantry, from National Guard. Assigned to Infantry to dis - charge. Honorably discharged October 17, 1918. Commissioned Captain, Company L, 134th Infantry, NNG, May 5, 1923, S. O. No. 62, AGO-Neb. 1926. Federally recognized May 16, 1923. Commissioned Captain, Infantry, ORC, November 20, 1923. Prior service in ORC two years, one month and sixteen days. Captain, Infantry, ORC, March 22, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">29 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL H^aMMnH^^HI^HMHMMHMMflHHHflBMHainflHaBQM«ka^H2aH3i^HEfiMDluS.^^^HH 3. Captain Elsasser's service has been. of most unusual value to the National Guard of this State he having been an active supporter and diligent worker in same for years pre - vious to the World War, when his regiment the 4th Nebraska National Guard, entered the World War and was later con - verted into the 127th Field' Artillery, with which he served with credit to himself and his comrades. After the World War he voluntarily reduced himself in rank and took over company L of the 134th' Nebraska National Guard, in an endeavor to bring it up to a higher state of efficiency, which he was ab - solutely successful in doing. Had Captain Elsasser lived for a very few week' longer he would have again started to climb up the military ladder, as he was next in line and would have been promoted to the grade of Major. 4. Captain Elsasser was commonly known among his friends as "Heine", a nickname which he has carried through life and which perhaps would have been dropped long ago had it not been for his many close and intimate friends that had known him for so many years. He was of a sunny disposition, always true and reliable, a very efficient officer, one that could be depended upon to do the right thing at the right time and he will long be remembered as one of the most able and efficient officers of the Nebraska National Guard, the sympathy of which is extended to his entire family in this, their hour of sorrow. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, • Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 11, 1932 General Orders o •, , No. 7 1. The Annual Inventory of Property pertaining to the organiza - tions of the Nebraska National Guard herein mentioned as required by paragraph 3, NGR 75-11, dated June 30, 1927, will be made on the following dates: October 25, 1932 Hq. Det., 35th Div. Tn. Lincoln October 26, 1932 110th Vet. Co, 110th Med. Regt. Lincoln October 27, 1932 Company I, 134th Inf. Lincoln October 28, 1932 Hq. Co, 1st Bn, 134th Inf. Lincoln November 1, 1932 Hq. Co. 1st Bn, 134th Inf. Nebraska City November 2, 1932 Co. A. 134th Inf. Nebraska City November 3, 1932 Co. B, 134th Inf. Falls City November 7, 1932 Band Sec. Ser. Co, 110th Med Regt. Crete November 8, 1932 Co. C, 134th Inf. Beatrice November 9, 1932 Co. M, 134th Inf. Seward November 14, 1932 Co. E. 134th Inf. Scottsbluff November 15, 1932 How. Co, 134th Inf. Gering November 17, 1932 Co. D, 134th Inf. North Platte November 21, 1932 166th Hosp. Co, 110th Med Regt Lincoln November 22, 1932 Ser. Co, 110th Med Regt. Lincoln November 28, 1932 137th Mot Tr. Co, 35th Div. Tn. Holdrege November 29, 1932 119th Wag. Co, 35th Div. Tn. Lexington November 30, 1932 120th Wag. Co,. 35th Div. Tn. Kearney December 1, 1932 Med. Dept. Det, 35th Div. Tn. Kearney December 2, 1932 130th Coll. Co, 110th Med Regt. Columbus December 5, 1932 Co. G, 134th Inf. Hastings December 6, 1932 130th Amb. Co, 110th Med. Regt. Hastings December 7, 1932 Co. H, 134th Inf. Grand Island December 8, 1932 138th Mot. Tr. Co, 35th Div. Tn. Fremont December 9, 1932 119th Mot. Rep. Sec, 35th Div. Tn. Fremont December 12, 1932 Co. F, 134th Inf. Hartington December 14, 1932 Regtl. Hq. Co, 134th Inf. Omaha December 15, 1932 Co. K. 134th Inf. Omaha December 16, 1932 Hq. Co, 2nd Bn, 134th Inf. Omaha December 17, 1932 Med. Dept. Det, 134th Inf. Omaha December 19, 1932 Co. L. 134th Inf. Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p033">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 31 2: All property will he arranged so that it may be counted with the least possible delay. Individual equipment records, Form No. 30, WD-MB. will be posted to date so as to he authentic and can be con - sidered in the inventory. 3. Attention invited to the Drovisions of NGR 75-3, dated January 22, 1927, which requires that all property be kept in the armory. 4. Responsible Officer with Supply Sergeant and two (2) assistants will be present to assist in the inventory on the date set. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 17, 1931 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Maximum Allowance of Clothing. To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Due to the great difference of items of clothing held by re - sponsible officers and the desire of this office to treat all alike the inclosed chart, "Maximum Allowance of Clothing", will be a guide for the maximum allowances. Responsible officers will not be allowed to requisition beyond this table. 2. Inventory and Inspection Report, MB 14, Report of Survey, AGO 15, and Statement of Property Lost, MB. 18, must actually be credited to the account. Before these papers can' be credited they must have been acted upon and approved. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. It therefore behooves everyone to keep their accountability up to the minute and before any requisition will be approved the prop - erty accounts must be down s &gt; that your requirements will not exceed this chart. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. 1 Inch Chart STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ** . ■ ' April 10, 1931 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Target Practice, Small Arms, 1931. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. COURSES TO BE FIRED. The following courses only are authorized during the year 1931. For rifle practice: Course D, T. R. 150-10. For machine gun practice: Course B, T.R. 150-35. For pistol practice: Dismounted course.. T. R. 150-20. 2. RECORD PRACTICE. Rec-rd practice for rifles, machine guns and pistols will he fired during the 1931 field training period. Organizations will complete the preparatory exercises and instruction practice at their home ranges. No instruction practice except a limited number of sighting shots will be permitted during the field training period. 3. PREPARATORY INSTRUCTION AND PRACTICE. No man will be permitted to fire record practice with the rifle, pistol or mach - ine gun who has not completed the preparatory exercises prescribed in T. R. 150-5, 150-10, 150-35, and who has not fired sufficient instruc - tion practice to demonstrate his ability to apply the principles taught in the preparatory exercises. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. RECORDS OF PROGRESS OF INSTRUCTION. Marksmanship (Preparatory) forms to show the state of instruction of individuals before starting range practice, and in addition, score books for rifle instruction practice and score cards for rifle, pistol, and machine guns will be mailed to unit commanders on requisition. Regimental and company commanders will require that these be kept in the manner required by Training Regulations, and regimental commanders will require that these marksmanship records, certified by the company commander, be brought to camp and submitted to their respective regimental commanders not later' than August 4,. 1931. 5. AMMUNITION. a. Ammunition allowances that may be expended at home sta - tions for instruction practice will not exceed the following: Unit Cal. .3,1 Cal. .45 Machine Gun Company 12000 1500 Eifle Company '. 6000 500 Hq. Company, Inf. Regt 1200 150) Service Company, Inf. Regt... 3600 1500 Howitzer Company i 1200 1000 Hq. Company, Inf. Bn . 2400 400 Hq. Det, Div. Tn 1200 400 Wagon Company L. 4800 300 Motor Transport Company 3600 300 Motor Repair Section None 700 b. Company commanders should submit requisitions for the am - munition required for instruction practice. Initial Allowance Ammuni - tion Must Not Be Used. 6. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 5, March 25, 1930, is hereby - revoked. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 1. 1931 Circular Letter No. 3 ' • Subject: Mother's Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The second Sunday in May haying been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization who may be separated from their mothers on May 10 the duty which they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mother's Day. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 15. 1931 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Annuel Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1931. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1931, having been set i. e, August 3 to 17, 1931, inclusive, no organization will be excused </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL from attendance except when it does not comply with the provisions of Section III, NGR 45. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non-compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of- pay of company officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to the exact hour of departure from heme station, rations, handling of bag - gage, train schedules, transportation requests, hills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company commanders are authorized to purchase subsistence for enlisted men not to exceed 40c per meal and will follow instructions received from the USP &amp; DO pertaining thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line oiTicer will assume command of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained, i. e, no men on top of the cars or on platjform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct correct All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movement By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The commanding officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops en - train at home station and after they detrain at camp and report to the Camp Commander immediately upon arrival any defects or faults found with railroads transpoi ting troops. Each company and de - tachment commander upon arrival at detrs ining point will immedi - ately report to Transportation Officer with reference to baggage detail. 5. Travel Uniforms. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leg gins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Training Regulations 50-80 and 5'J-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc, and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag or foot locker. Company commanders shi.uld check each enlisted man to see that he </seg>
            <seg id="p038">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, toeth brush, paste, hand soap etc, and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e, cotton breeches, and O. D. shirt. Cotton blouses and new Melton Cloth uni - form will not be brought to camp. 7. Addition; 1 Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) orgar.izati n equipment and cleaning materials. In - formation pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment, and harness will be furnished in a separate circular letter. No target material will be brought to camp as i - . will be furnished there. No canvas cots will be brought to camp. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition exceft cal. .22, long rifle, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO, securing memorandum receipt for same; all empty cartridges (brass) in packing boxes, aim - ing devices, arm racks and lockers sufficient for men in camp, rifles, bayonets., and pist- Is for same and all other ordnance with which the individual and companies are equipped. The Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will biing only sufficient ammunition to be used in the con - duct of its fire on the range. 9. Special Equipment All Signal, Medical, and Engineer property, including lister bags, is to be carried. 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e. Property Records Individual Eecrds. Stationary, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in quadruplicate rf all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in quad - ruplicate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will l.e turned in immediately upon ar - rival in camp. 11. Transportation on equipment brought to camp other than enumerated above, which becomes excess equipment, will have to be paid for by the unit commander bringing or permitting same to he brought (M. B. file 554.4 Gen-81, May 25, 1931, Subject: Transportation of Equipment for Field Training.) 12. Messes. .All company officers will mess with their organization. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and mess sergeants, cs a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organisation. The Commanding </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, QMC, will establish officers' messes jf or the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such officers of the State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for nuss purposes. Messes are to be oper - ating so as to serve lunch at noon. August 3, 1931. 13. Attention is invited to Nebraska Circular Letter No. 24, 1929, and company commanders are admonished that same must be strictly complied with. 14. Owing to the fact that a large warehouse hrs been constructed on the area set aside for the enlisted men's automobiles and that there is now no available space on the camp site for the parking of same and ithat entraining at home station, travel en rcute to camp, and detraining upon' arrival constitutes a part of the instruction pertaining to trans - portation of troups incident to field training, no enlisted men's cars will be permitted to be brought to camp this year. 15. In the movement of troops to and from camp in units and sub - units having same, two officers, one of which shall be the company commander, must accompany troops en rorte and will not be permitted to travel by privately owned motor vehicles. 16. TSach unit and sub-unit emm-nder will appoint a mail orderly who will get mail for his unit or sub-unit direct from the camp post office. The camp post office will sell stamps and mail orders, register letters, and conduct a general business such as is done by post offices over the country. 17. The attention of all unit and s lb-unit commanders is called to the necessity of knowing their men are physically fit before taking them to camp as the number of major operations in our camp must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 18. Unit and sub-unit commanders will make sure that they are not bringing any venereal cases to camp and in case any are found on the physical examination that will be made on entering camp, they will be returned to their home station at their own expense, without pay or allowances, as they will not be permitted in camp; such men will also be required to refund both railroad fare and subsistence expended on them in bringing them to camp. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 19. Unit and sub-unit commanders will make every effort to ascer - tain that their men are physically lit befoie bringing them to camp and see that they do not come under the Lei ds mentioned above and will read this letter to their command at every armory drill between the time of its receipt and the time of entraining for camp. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 17. 1931 Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Transportation, Field Tr.-.ir.ing, 1931. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. MOUNTS. Mounts Will be furnished to the respective organi - zations as follows: a. State 8 Officers, 3 Orderlies, 1 Senior Instr, 1 for Staff The Governor 134th 1 Crl, 1 Lt. Col, 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., 1 Aux. Inf. Bn. Adj., 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T, 4 Orderlies (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hq.) 35th 1 C. O, 1 Adj., 1 S. 0, 1 Orderly, 1 Tech. Div. Tn. Sgt. (TM), 7 to ea. Wag. Co. (1 ea. Officer, 2 Color Guard, 1 First Sgt. and 1 Orderly) 2 to Med. Dept Det. 110th 1 Col, 1 Lt Col, 2 Majors (P. &amp; T, Veterin- Med. arian D.S. O.), I Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 2 Regt. Orderlies. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL b. The responsible officers for the following sub-units will furnish riding equipment with grain and feed bags. S. S. . Maj. W. E. McConnaughey, 13 sets 134th C. O. Regimental Hq. Co, 6 sets Inf.' C. O. Battalion Hq. Co.s, 3 sets, each C. O. Service Co, 2 sets C. O. Med Dept Det, 1 set 35th Div. Tn. C. O. 119th Wag. Co.. 7 sets C. O. 120th Wag. Co, 7 sets C. O. Headquarters Det, 4 sets C. O. Med. Dept. Det, 3 sets 110th Med. Regt. C. O. Service Co.. 8 sets 2. MULES, DRAFT. Mules will be assigned as follows: a. Camp Quartermaster .... 4 134th Infantry M. G. Companies 4 each ■ Howitzer Company 2 Service Company 16 35th Division Train 119th Wagon Co. 20 120th Wagon Co. 20 b. -Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows: USP&amp;DO — All escort wagons reouired. The C. O-s of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Company will furnish the necessary harness for the animals assigned them. 3. MOTOR VEHICLES. a. ■ USP&amp;DO will transport all availal le trucks and ambulances stored at the State Arsenal to Camp. b. The Commanding Officer, Hq. Co, 2nd Bn, 134th Infantry will detail two truck drivers for the purpese of transporting Class B, Liberty Truck, so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 3, not later than 9:00 A. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Drivers will report to Camp Transportation Officer immedi - ately upon their arrival. 4. All organizations having government owned motor vehicles assigned them will, immediately after arrival in Camp and unloading of equipment, have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Officer, to be placed in the camp, pool for the duration of camp. By. direction of the Governor:' H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 18, 1931 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Anual Encampment, 1931. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. -1, 1931, company commanders will purchase the. necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40 cents per meal per man for the time involved in assembling, travel, and arrival at camp. ' (See par. 15, MB Circular No. 25, 1930.) Balance of meals for first day will be Garrison Ration. 2. PubUc Vouchers, Standard Forms No. 1034 and 1034 a, with extra sheets, are enclosed for stating accounts due and must be accom - panied by invoices in duplicate. 3. To expedite the payment of vouchers attention is invited to the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL a. Insert Payee's name and address. h. Complete the Voucher in detail as to date of delivery, articles, quantity, unit price with cost and per unit with the amounts and the total. c. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across the face of the voucher, "Travel Rations, Co , Regt, (so many) Enlisted men, (so many) Meals." d. The use of crlored inks or carbon paper other than black and alterations or erasures will not he accepted. e. It is suggested that the subsistence be purchased from one firm to avoid delay in payment of Vouchers to determine whether the amount authorized has been exceeded. f. Have Payee sign the certificate, "I certify that the above bill is correct", etc. See * note at the bottom of voucher. g. Certificate, that articles have been received, etc, is to be signed by Company Commander and completed in accordance with No. 4. with the word "oral" opposite No. 4 on back of original and duplicate voucher. h. The report listed at bottom must be filled in and signed and turned in with voucher. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. Qo Home Station Show date and hour of assembly * , . - Show date and hour of arrival at Camp </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Enlisted strength actually traveling Name (Signed by C. O.) Rank and Branch * Par. 15 MB Circular No. 25 A-21, August 1930, allows not to exceed two hours prior to departure. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 20, 1931 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1931. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau, to submit a Return of Strength on the evening of June 30, 1931, therefore all unit and sub-unit commanders are requested to wire this office their strength Tuesday A. M, June 30, in order that we may compile same and for - ward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, that day. f 2. The following form of telegram, giving officers and enlisted men separately, should be used: , "Co. A, three officers, sixty-three enlisted men. ' (Signed) Smith, Captain" By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 22, 1931 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment. 1931. To: Officer ResponsiLle for Same. 1. In accordance with par. 73-c, NGR 71, Government Transpor - tation Request No. WQ is inclosed herewith to cover rail - road transportation (tickets) for your Company and any field or staff officers of the NNG residing at your station to Ashland Nebraska, and return, which should be completed as follows, after the number of persons for whom transportation is required has been determined: a. Enter with pen. ink, or indelible pencil under the block, "Number of Persons", the total (aggregate) to be transported. . b. Opposite "Est. cost S " enter the TOTAL cost c. Signature of Responsible Officer, with title thereunder, on the lower right hand corner of the Request. d. Postal card report (WD MB No. 36) in quadruplicate will be completed as required thereon, one to be given to the first conductor if he requests it and the second to be turned in im - mediately upon arrival at camp to the USP&amp;DO. The third and fourth copies will be used for the return movement, the third to be given to the first conductor if he requests it and the fourth copy to be mailed as indicated thereon, with any un - used tickets that yc.u may have. e. SERIAL NUMBER— See that ticket agents show on each ticket and on each coupon thereof the SERIAL NUMBER OF THE TRANSPORTATION REQUEST used in getting the ticket so </seg>
            <seg id="p046">REPORT OF. THE ADJUTANT GENERAL that tickets and transportation requests can be checked against each other. f. Secure a sufficient number of single tickets (not more than ten) to enable delivery to the conductor of the exact amount of transportation required and for the remaining tickets secure a party ticket. (Par. 95, NOR 71.) 2. If. prior to the surrender of Transportation Request to the ticket agent, it be found necessary to alter entries made thereon, such changes will be fully explained over y ur signature and rank in the blank space under par. 2 of the instructions on the reverse thereof. Postal card reports required above mutt he absolutely correct,. showing the number of persons actually traveling as me'mbers of your party for the incoming and the return movements. 3. The responsible officer in tl is case is acting as transportation officer and as train quartermaster and CI cck Lists B and C are in - closed for his information and guidance. \v ith reference to Form WD MB 35, this letter contains the information called for therein. Any accomodations in excess of those authorized by regulation will be charged against the lesponsil.le officer. 4. In addition to the above, the conductor of each division of the railroad is required to make a report in duplicate of the troops car - ried, which will be verified by the ofiicer in charge of the company, and signed by both. The duplicate co ( .y of this report is to be given to the offcier in charge and will be sent by him to the Finance Officer, U. S. Army, Transportation Bianch, v&gt; ashint.ton, D. C, and must com - pare with par. 1-d as to number of passengers. (Par. 2-b (3) Ch"ck List C.) By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein. Major. USP&amp;DO. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4 Incls. Inch 1, Original T/R Incl. 2, 4 post cards WD 36 Inch 3, Check List B, Trans. Off. Incl. 4. Check List C. Train QM STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 24, 1931 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Government Bill of Lading. Anru:.l Encnmpment, 1931. To: Officer Responsible for Same. 1. "Government Bill of Lading WO is inclosed herewith for freight (not checkable baggage) involved in movement of your Company to Ashland., Nebraska, which sh- uld be completed as follows: a. Opposite "Est. Cost S ", upper right hand corner, insert the total actual cost after ascertaining same from the agent. b. Insert number of packages under column "Number and Kind of Packages" (see par. 40 b (7) NGR 71), and the total weight under column "Weiehls"'. In case of M.G. and Ammunition Carts, or other wheeled material, add to Bill of Lading giving the number, description, and weights (see par. 40 b (6) NGR 71). c. Insert length of car furnished, the date, initials, and cai number. 2. Bill of Lading will be disposed of as follows: a. Original and three memos to be signed by your local agent </seg>
            <seg id="p048">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL b. Shipping Order to be" signed a.id surrendered to local a^ent. c. Original surrendered to agent at Ashland, Nebraska, prop - erly executed under "Consignee's Certificate of Delivery". d. Two memos to he immediately delivered to USP&amp;DO. upon arrival at camp.. e. Retain one memo for company files. 3. Property List, MB Form No. 34 (supply inclosed), is required by par. 30, NGR 71, as changed by C-2. Three of these will be pre - pared and one attached to each memorandum Bill of Lading. 4. In that a great many responsible officers have been shipping unnecessary equipment on Bills of Lading, the inclosed certificate is required and must be turned in with the two memos referred to in par. 2 d. (See par. 11, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 4, 1931.) Check List D is inclosed for your informr.toin arid guidance. 5. Transportation may be hiied at a reasonable rate for the pur - nose of transporting baggage and equipment from the armory to the depot and return. Invoices in duplicate should be furnished this office with public vi ucher, Standard Form No. 1034 and 1034 a, properly executed for the incoming and return movements. After the service has been listed, indicate thereunder :icr&lt; ss the face of the voucher, "Dray - age, Company : , Regiment". These accounts must be in by the last ot Auuust so that settlement may be made on the whole, to see that this allowance has not been exceeded. 6. C( nipany commanders will detail an officer and eight enlisted men as a baggage detail and see that they stay at the detraining point until the unloading is completed. 7. Bills of Lading for the return movement will be furnished while at camp and prior to departure the Property Lists referred to in par. 3 herein, the Certificate referred to in par. 4 herein, and the two memorandum Eills of Lading will be delivered to the USP&amp;DO. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein. Major, USP&amp;DO. Nebraska. 4 Incls. Incl. 1, Original B L with memos and S. O. Incl. 2, 3 copies of Property List Incl. 3, Check List D Incl. 4.- Public Voucher STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 25, 1931 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Athletic Program. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders,. NNG. 1. The following Athletic Program, Which may be changed slightly if circumtances -require is publisned for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this program his personal attention. 3. PROGRAM. a. FIELD MEET. Saturday, Aug. 15 (after 9:30 A. M.), is re - served as the Camp Athletic Field Day. (1) All entries in athletic events scheduled for that period will be released from all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared of troops prior to the above designated hour. (Field Training Directive 6 b (5) ) </seg>
            <seg id="p050">48 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (2) Track. AU track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event. b. SWIMMING. (1) Swimming events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event (2) The swimming pool may be used only when life guards are present and on duly at the pool. c. BOXING. (1) There will be competitition in each weight division and a medal awarded to the winner in each weight d. MASS ATHLETICS. (1) All enlisted men not employed during the afternoon period as provided in Sections 1 to 6 inclusive, Field Training Directive, will be assembled for physical training, athletics, recreational games and sports and training for athletics or military competitions during the period from 1:15 to 3:00 P. M. upon all clays except Aug. 3, 8, 9, 15, 16 and 17. (Field Training Directive 6 (7) ) (2) The above activities will be grouped as follows: games, and other sports requiring close supervision. Period from 1:15 to 2:00 P. M, mass athletics, group swimming, preparation for field meet, and similar activities. (Field Training Directive 6a (7) (a)) 4. GENERAL PROVISIONS. a. Each regimental and separate battalion commander will im - mediately upon arrival at camp designate a regimental or battalion athletic officer, who will immediately' report to the Camp Athletic Officer as his assistant in the supervision of the recreational and athletic activities of the camp. (Field Training Directive 6a (7)(c) ) b. At least one noncommissioned officer or qualified private in each company, or like unit, will be excused from school or other duties to have charge of the assembly and control of the men of his unit for the afternoon periods. .For that duty he will be under the direction and control of the regimental or battalion athletic officer. (Field Training Directive 6a (7) (d) ) </seg>
            <seg id="p051">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. The noncommissioned officers or o.u:lified privates detailed as provided 'in the above paragraph (b) will also be excused from school or other duties to attend the school of instruction in mass athletics in the morning of each day at an hour to be designated by the Camp Athletic Officer. &lt;1. All officers detaile-1 as above and others assigned as Camp Athletic Instructors will be under the orders of the Camp Athletic Officer and will report to him for duty. (Field Training Directive 6a (7) (e) ) e. All unit and sub-unit commanders will prior to leaving their respective home 6tatiors have all men who will be entered in the boxing contests accurately weighed and immediately upon arrival al camp will deliver to the Carrp Athletic Officer a list of their respective entries together with a statement of their accurate weights. f. All unit and sub-unit commanders will prior to leaving their respective home stations prepare lists of their respective or - ganizations' entries in the field, track, and swimming events and immediately upon arri.al at camp will deliver said lists to the Camp Athletic Officer. f&gt;. GENERAL'S TROPHY. a. Adjutrnt General Paul is p.eain offering a cup to the company showing the greatest activity and efficiency in athletics. J). Prints will be awarded to the various companies upon the fcllowr.ig basis: (1) Boxing Owing to. the difficulty that has been experienced in ar - ranging a card for the second' evening of Camp (Tuesday) it has been decided to avvrrct a greater number of points to the companies having entries in the boxing bouts upon that evening. Therefore, upun the first Tuesday evening, .25 points will be awarded for each entry at the ringside in condition to box, and 15 points wil be award for each . round that the bout goes. Upon all other evenings points will be awarded as follows: 10 points will be awarded for each- entry appearing Hi the ringside in condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. An additional 15 points will be awarded to the winning entry in each bout </seg>
            <seg id="p052">50 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 25 points will be awarded to each entry who enters the semi-final. 50 points will be awarded to the champion in each weight division. (2) Swimming. 25 points will be awarded for each 1st. 15 points will will be awarded for each 2nd. 10 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (3) Track. 25 points will be awarded for each 1st. 15 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 10 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Mass Athletics. 200 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 100 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the second greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 50 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the third greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July l-i, i9:;i Circular Letter ' • _-. ' K No. 11 . . w ►ti O Subject: Train Schedule To and Return From Annual Encampment, 1931, Ashland, Nebraska. JS To: All Company Commanders, Field and Staff Officers, NNG. ** 1. In accordance with Nebraska Circular Letter No. 4, 1931, the following train schedule is prescribed for £2 movement to camp: i-j i ' '. i No. Pass. Bag. , w Movements Organizations Location Approx. I Car bchedule &gt; xr n , Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln 22 I 1 Lv Lincoln Tn No. 8, 7:40 AM g CB&amp;O Co I 55 8. 3, 31 £ Ashland HO Vet Cc 30 i Ar. Ashland 8:13 AM Z Det D S 0 . j . H Hq 35 Div Tn O | , |; K No. 2 Co B . ' j Falls City 50 i l Lv. Falls City Tn No. 109, 4:50. "W M. P. i AM 8 3 31 F Omaha Co A | Nebr. City 40 1 Lv. Nebr. City 6:00 AM r CB&amp;Q "q Co 1st Bn j ' | 21 Ashland Regtl Hq Co I Omaha j 40 1 Lv. Omaha Q Spec. 9:15 AM Co K | 51 1 Co L I 61 1 Med Dept Det 22 ! I34th Inf. j i ' i Hq Cn 2nd Bn i 24 Ar. Ashland 10:05 AM </seg>
            <seg id="p054">52 ' " ~ Approx. Bag. b-i,ai1ii1» Movements Organizations Location No. Pass. Car No 3 120 Wag Co Kearney 54 1 Lv. Kearney Tn. No. 18, 6:30 AM A C ,h£„V Med D eptDet 13 , L v. Hastings Tn No. 18, 7:50 AM * Ashland Co G Beatrice 56 1 Lv. Beatrice Tn No. 24, 8:19 AM. W Band 110 MR Crete 20 Lv. Crete Tn No. 24, 9:25 AM g HO Coll Co Columbus 43 1 Lv. Columbus Tn No. 20, 8:00 AM § Ar. Ashland CB&amp;Q Spec. 11:35 h - ■ ' O No . t Co H Gr. Island .62 1 . Lv. Gr. Island Tn No. 32, 10:10 *&gt; ■ ™ Ar. Ashland Tn No. 16, 2:20 PM &gt; No 5 Co E Scottsbluff .46 1 Lv. Scottsbluff Tn No. 32, 9:48 rw kn PM 8/2 31 &gt; Ashland Ar. Lincoln Tn No. 42, 1:00 PM Z Lv. Lincoln Tn No. 16, 1:40 PM o Ar. Ashland Tn No. 16, 2:20 PM H Z ' H ' P0 m 0 6 Co F Hartington 49 1 Lv. Hartington Tn No. 44. 7:00 &gt; CSTPM&amp;O AM 8. 3-31 r Omah Lv. Emerson Tn No. 1, 9:35 AM CB&amp;q Ar. Omaha 12:30 PM Ashland Lv. Omaha Tn No. 7, 1:10 PM Ar. Ashland 2:00 PM </seg>
            <seg id="p055">53 . ' Approx. Bag. „ , . . Movements Organizations Location No pass Car scneauie . . No 7 How Co Gering 53 1 Lv. Gering Tn No. 54, 3:45 PM Fri'm^'nt Ar North Platte 9:10 PM g rnx,£ Lv. No. Platte Tn No. 4, 10:30 PM £ Ashland Ar. Fremont 5:05 AM. 8/3/31 o A CoD' No. Platte- 50 1 Lv. No Platte Tn No. 16, 7:50 » AM 8/3/ ol 119 Wag Co Lexington 50 1 Lv. {«£*•»$ No. 16. 9:22 AM O Lv. Fremont Spec. CB&amp;Q, 2:45 PM H Ar. Ashland 3:30 PM g — — &gt; Via 130 Amb Co Hastings 42 Lv. Hastings 7:03 AM 8. 3 31 £ C ov 't Ar. Camp 3:00 PM . S Motor Serv Co Lincoln 39 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 8 3/31 &gt; Vehicles 110 MR „„„„»„ ' 2 166 Hosp Co 63 Ar. Camp 9:30 AM . H 138 MT Co Fremont 46 Lv. Fremont 5:00 AM 8, 3, 31 O 119 MT Sec 15 Ar. Camp 9:00 AM W 137MTCo Holdrege 37 Lv. Holdrege 3:00 AM. 8/3/31 Z - Ar. Camp 5:00 PM U SS&amp;SD r inco i n 20 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 8/3 31 &gt; lj,nC0,n Ar. Camp 10:00 AM P (x) Tourist cai-s will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Co. E (Scottsbluff). </seg>
            <seg id="p056">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL . Movement No. 1. Co. I, Hq. C;&gt;. 3d. Bn., and 110th Vet. Co. will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 2. Co. A and Hq. Co., 1st Bn., will load in one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and Med. Dept Det. will load in one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co.. 2nd Bn., will load in one baggage car. Co. L will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Co. C will reserve space for Band, 110th M. R. 120th Wag. Co. and Med. Dept. Det., 35th Div. Tn., will load in one baggage car. 2. TICKETS Government Transportation Requests on the railroad concerned will be exchanged for round trip tickets at the local ticket office. Re - quests for berths will be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for ac - commodations actually furnished.. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT Baggage cars will be set the day preceding the movement to per - mit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is neces - sary. Tourist cars or coaches will be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner in ample lime to permit trains to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based on last year's transportation requests. 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, field desks, dispensaries, typewriter, etc., (par. 28 NGR 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with the name of the owner. Check - able baggage will not be included on Bill of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government BiU of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each sta - tion, at freight rates. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">55 5. The following train schedule is prescribed for the return movement: . Movements Organization Location | A PP™x. S ' Schedule No. Prss. Car : ; ; : __ g No. 8 Band, 110 MR Crete j 20 w Co C Lv. Ashland Spec. CB&amp;Q 9:20 CB&amp;Q ' AM 8 17 31 ' 2 Dest I Ar. Crete Tn No. 89, 11:17 AM 2 Co C Beatrice 55 1 Ar. Beatrice Tn No. 89, 12:15 PM // Co M Seward 42 1 Ar. Seward Tn No. 39, 11:37 AM 2 Serv Co 13-1 Inf York .56 1 Ar. York Tn No. 39, 12:24 PM Co II Gr. Island 52 1 Ar. Gr. Island Tn No. 39, 2:00 PM 3 Co G Hastings 59 1 Ar. Hastings, Tn No. 5, 3;05 1-M m Co B Falls City j 50 1 Ar.. Falls Cy Tn No 42-16, 4:43 PM &gt; No. 9 130 Cell Co CelumLus 43 1 Lv. Ashland CB&amp;Q Spec. 11:00 C CB&amp;Q AM 8 17 31 g Fremont Ar. Columbus, UP Spec. 2:00 PM 5 U. P. 120 Wag Co Kearney 64 1 Ar. Kearney, UP Spec. 4:30 PM H Dest M.d Dept let 13 • o 35 Liv Tn • ' W 119 Wag Co Lexington 50 1 Ar. Lexington UP Spec. 6:45 PM Z. Co D No. Platte . 50 1 Ar. No. Platte. UP Spec. 8:30 PM E How Co Gering 53 1 Ar. Gering UP No. 53, 11:05 AM C 00 8 18 31 r </seg>
            <seg id="p058">56 Movements Organization Location „ App ™ x ' e ' Schedule No. Pass. Car No. 10 Co K Omaha 51 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 24, 11:17 AM, CB&amp;Q Co L 61 1 8 17/31 Omaha Med Dept Det 22 Ar. Omaha 11:58 AM # M&amp;O 134 Inf K Dest. Regtl Hq Co 40 1 2 Hq Co 2d Bn 24 ' § Co F Hartington 49 1 Lv. Omaha CStPM&amp;O Tn No. 2, h 1:10 PM o Ar. Hartington Tn No. 11-43, 7:25 «^ PM h , , X No. 11 Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln 22 Lv. Ashland Spec. 1:50 PM, U. CB&amp;Q Co I 55 1 8,17,31 O Dest. 110 Vet Co '30 % Det D S O 3 Hq 35 Div Tn Ar. Lincoln 2:30 PM &gt; Hq Co 1st Bn Nebr. City 21 1 Ar. Nebr. Cy, Tn' No. 122, 5:20 PM Z Co A 40 H : , - • a No. 12 Co E Scottsbluff 45 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 23, 6:57 PM Z CB&amp;Q (x) 8 16 31 g Dest. Ar. Scottsbluff 2:33 PM, 8/17,31 &gt; ! J : ■ : . P </seg>
            <seg id="p059">57 Movements Organization Location APP«'ox. I a K- Schedule No. Pass. I Car Via 130 Amb Co Hastings 42 ■ Lv. Camp 7:00 AM 8 17, 31 Gov't • Ar. Hastings 3:00 PM Motor Serv Co Lincoln 39 Lv. Camp 1:00 PM « Vehicles 110 MR Ar. Lincoln 3:30 PM M 166 Hosp Co 63 Lv. Camp 1:00 PM 2 Ar. Lincoln 3:30 PM g 138 MT Co Fremont 46 Lv. Camp 3:00 PM q 119 MRS 15 Ar. Fremont 7:00 PM _ SS&amp;SD Lincoln 21 Lv. Camp 7:10 AM 8 18 31 5 Ar. Linccln 10:00 AM _ 137 MT Co Holdrege 37 Lv. Camp 4:00 PM 8 16 31 3 Ar. Holdrege 2:00 PM 8, 17, 31 K : — . ! ■ &gt; (x) Tourist Cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). G Z a • ' z &gt; p </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 8. Co. C and Band, 110 M. It, will use one baggage car. Movement No. 11. Hq. Co., 1st Bn., and Co. A will use one baggage car, Co. I, Hq. Co., 3rd Bn., Hq. 35th Div. Tn., and 110th Vet. Co. will use one baggage car. Movement No. 10. Med. Dept Det. and Regtl. Hq. Co. will use one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., will use one baggage car. 6. Postal Card Report WD MB No. 36 ' will be mailed to the USP&amp;DO as soon as possible after securing the signature of the con - ductor. The report required by par. 4, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 8, 1931, must be mailed to the Finance Officer, Washington, D. C, as soon as possible. 7. Two memorandum copies of Bill of Lading must be given to the USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent, prior to your de - parture. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN . t July 20, 1931 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Camp Attendance of State Employees Who are Members of the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Governor Bryan has announced to this office that his policy of permitting State employees of all departments over which he has con - trol, who are members of the Nebraska National Guard, to attend the National Guard encampments without loss of pay or vacation time, will be continued. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Julv 20. 1931 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Tent Houses for First Sergeants and Supply Sergeants. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. There has been constructed in each company area a tent house for the use of the first sergeant and supply sergeant. The regular up - right pole will be used, placing same upon the floor for foundation. Under no circumstances will holes be cut in these floors. 2. A sixteen penny nail may be placed in each corner for the pur - pose of holding the guy rope, which is deemed all that is necessary. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 22. 1931 Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, Fiscal Year 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, pertaining t» the above named subject is published for the information and guid - ance of all concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of drills to be held during the Fiscal Year 1932, will be limited as follows: (a) During the 1st and 2nd Quarteis (July 1 to December 31. 1931, inch), not to exceed 24 Federal pay drills. (b) During the 3rd Quarter (January 1 to March 31, 1932, inch), not to exceed 12 Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the 24 drills not held in the 1st and 2nd Quarteis. (c) During the 4th Quarter (April 1 to June 30, 1932, incl.) not to exceeel 12 Federal pay drills in adelition to any pari of the 36 drills not held timing the 1st, 2nd and 3rd Quarters. (d) In no event will the number of drills for which payment is made from Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year for any organization of the National Guard. W. H. Waldroii, Colonel, Infantry, M. B. For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 01 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ; September 4, 1931 Circular Lelter No. 15 Subject: Result of Ordnance Inspection at the Annual Encampment, 1931. To: All Unit .and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following extracts taken from the report of the Ordnance Officer who was in chnrpe of ordnance instruction at the annual en - campment of 1931 is published for the information and guitlance of ail concerned: "3. Ordnance material in the hands of units was inspected v\ith particular attention to the condition of the bore, and an elfort wrs made timing the time allotted to instruct individuals in the work necessary to increase the efficiency of firearms anel the practical application of cleaning and preserving material. During this inspection it was discovered that the principal de - fect in the rifles was a considerable deposit of carbon in approx - imately one-thiid of the length of the bore toward the muzzle. In general, the tvvo-thiids of the length of the bore from the breech entl was clean and- well cared for. It is thought that the carbon deposit mainly is a combination of oil, powler fouling lind dust which hi s been carbonized by the high temperatures in - cident to firing and being firmly packed by the passage of the bullet The fact thct only a portion of the rifle barrel appears well caret! for indicates that when rifles are being cleaned, the forward and backward motion of the patch is not being extended In the muzzle. 4. There appears some lack of understanding of the term "sweating" as some bores of all types of small arms were found rusty beneath the' thin coating of oil. Sweating may obtain from two causes, one by not entirely removing the products of com - bustion and the other by not thoroughly drying the piece before • iling. Careful cleaning and inspection of the bores of small arms should be maele at freeiuent intervals for not less than three days after firing, also after the use of water or ammonia solution, to </seg>
            <seg id="p064">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL insure the removal of rll moisture before final oiling. In some cases it was found that these frequent inspections were bein - made but that the fpr.Hcation of a light film of oil in the bore after these inspections was bring neglected and due to the moist atmosphere, especially in camp, nst wr.uld immediately form. 5. During the inspection directions for the necessary minor repairs discovered were piven some of which are here noted: Several machine gun tripods, M1917. were found without name plates. Effort shruld be made to locate and replace these at the home stations. If unable to do so, replacements should be requisitioned, giving the number cf the tripod so that the name plate can be properly stamped. Some replacement of broken and missing parts on machine gun carts and nachine gun ammuni - tion carts was noted and the units directed to requisition and replace these at their home stations. Carts which are stored at Ashland will be repaired during the 1932 training period by mechanics from this office." 2. This office wishes to call attention to the discrepancies noted in the above extracts and urge that all company and detachment commanders take the necessary precautions to correct same. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 12, 1931 Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equip - ment, and Maintenance of Organizational Equipment F Y 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Responsible Officers. NNG. 1. Jf funds are required by your organization it is directed that you furnish this office, not later than October 15, 1931, separate esti - mates for the following: a. Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equip - ment b. Maintenance of Organizational Equipment 2. In no case will any ohlh&gt;rti n be incurred until estimate called for above hr.s been approved by this office. 3. The authorizatio.li of funds for Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment is intended for articles where the enlisted men have been discharged and not for the purpose of clean - in!- clothing for active men. Pressing of the overcoats, uniforms and the shining of shoes will not be authorized. By direction of the Governor: II. .1. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Xebrr.ska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 17, 1931 Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: West Point Preliminary Competitive Examination, 1931, for the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit anil Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of one enlisted man of the Nebraska Nati inal Guard to take the competitive examination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office beginning November 2, 1931. at 9:00 A. M., and continuing through November 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an applicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Fetleral Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1932, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years and must not he less than 5 '4" in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. A pamphlet setting forth the requirements for admission to the Military Academy will be sent upon request -. e&gt; 3. The candidate, selecteel will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on or about March 1, 1932, and the appointment available on July 1, 1932, will be awarded to the qualified candidate in -the order of merit established at the examination, which is com - petitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously applicants have presented themselves to take this examinaton who were in no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an.appli - cant should have had at least one year in college, in addition to a high school education. The examination will be written and will con - sist of an exhaustive examination in the following subjects: Elementary Algebra, to and including quadratics, Plane Geometry, English Gram - mar, United States and General History, and English Literature and Composition. 5. No State Funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. i 6. A blank form to be used in making application to participate m the examination is inclosed. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 18, 1931 Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Information Required on Form 100. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. In compliance with instructions contained in WD MB Form 100, par. 3 d, a remark will be made opposite names of all personnel acquiring a status in the Officers' Reserve Corps during the month and will not be reported again until discharge. By direction of the Governor: II. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 19, 1931 Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y'. 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following voluminous letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. The President, through the Director of the Bureau of the Budget, has directed that no deficits be incurred in the Army appro - priations for the current fiscal' year. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Due to increased attendance at the field training camps of the National Guard last summer it is estimated that there will be a deficiency in the funds availatla for the conduct of the June, 1932, camps amounting to S600.000.00 3. Likewise, due to ircrersEd attendance at armory drill, it is anticipated that there -.rill be a deficiency in Armory Drill Pay, 1932, amounting to approximately 8860,000.00. This es'limuto is based upon the attendance during the fiscal year 1931 ant' that for the months of the fiscal year 1932 which lave passed. 4. It is thus apnarent that the Militia Bureau is facing a deficit for the fiscal year 1932 of 31,460,000.00. Of this amount, it is esti - mated that approximately S30J, 000.00 can be made up through the process of the transfer of funds from othei orojects of the item "Arming, Equipping and Training the National Guard" under the 10% interchangeability clause. This leaves a balance of 81,160.000.00 to be provided otherwise. 5. As stated above, in recommending a budget for the Army for the fiscal year 1933, the Director of the Bureau of the Budget stated that no deficiency estimated for the fiscal year 1932 would be approved. In view of this announced policy, it now becomes mandatory for the Militia Bureau to finance its activities for the fiscal year 1932 within the limiting figure of the sum appropriated for that year, and to meet the contemplated deficit indicated above through administrative action. 6. After a thorough study of the situation, it has beeii decided that of the expedients available for meeting the contemplated deficit, a reduc'ibn in the number of armory drill periods is the most feasible and will work less hardship on the National Guard i.s a whole. 7. In accordance with the above decision, the Secretary of War has directed that the arpuiy drill periods for Ihe fiscal year 1932 be reduced from 18 to 43, and he has excused all units and organizations of the National Guard. from participation in live (5) of the armory drills authorized for the fiscal year 1932 by letter of the Militia Bureau dated August 12, 1931. 8. The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the lumber of drills held during the remainder of the iisoal year 1932 ■ be limited as follows: a. During the 1st and 2nd quarters (July 1 to December 31, 1931, incl.) not to exceed twenty-three (23) Federal pay drills.. b. During the 3rd quarter (January 1 to March 31, 1932, incl.) </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL not to exceed ten (It)) Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the twenty-three (23) diilhs not held during the 1st and 2nd quarteis. c. During the 1th quarter (April 1 to .1 ne 30, 1932, incl.) not to exceed ten (10) Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the thirty-three (33) drills not held during the 1st, 2nd and 3rd quarters. d. In no event will the number of drills for which payment is made from Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-three (-!3) during the fiscal year for any individual or organization of the National Guard. !». This letter supersedes Militia Bureau letter of August 12, 1931, on the above subject. 10.- It is hardly necessary to say that the War Department re - grets more than it can say the necessity for the action taken. The National Guard may be assured that everything- humanly possible has been done by the War Department in this connection, even to the extent of suggesting the transfer of funds from items for the support of the Regular Army to make up the National Guard deficit. The condition of the Treasury however, has definitely precluded any solu - tion of the problem involving the expenditure of additional funds. (SIGNED) W. II. Waldron, Colonel, Infantry, MB, For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 21, 1931 Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commandeis, NNG. 1. The following telegram is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "FOLLOWING COMMUNICATION FRCM WAR DEPARTMENT TO CHIEF MILITIA BUREAU QUOTED FOR YOUR INFORMATION AND GUIDANCE QUOTE THE PRESIDENT THRU THE BUREAU OF THE BUDGET HAS AUTHORIZED THE CORRECTION OF THE SITUATION SET FORTH IN THE CIRCULAR LETTER FROM YOUR OFFICE OF NOVEMBER TWELFTH NINETEEN THIRTY ONE BY DIRECTING THE SUBMISSION OF A DEFICIENCY BILL PROVIDED IT CAN BE FINANCED FROM REGULAR ARMY SAVINGS PERIOD THIS WILL BE DONE PERIOD THE ABOVE MENTIONED CIRCU - LAR LETTER CURTAILING ARMORY DRILLS IS THEREFORE RESCINDED PERIOD DOUGLAS MACARTHUR GENERAL CHIEF OF STAFF UNQUOTE PERIOu" 2. Owing to the above communication it is with great pleasure that this office rescinds Nebraska Circular Letter No. 19, dated Novem - ber 19, 1931. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 1, 1931 Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. 1. There are inclosed herewith blank ' efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1931, which should have your immediate attention. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. After giving a thorough study to instructions contained in NGR 20, par. 74. Changes 2, dated September 12, 1930, make out your reports and forward same without delay to the officer to whom di - rected. 3. The reports should reach this office before the expiration of the month. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Let us all get them in. in pr.iper form, and AT ONCE. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENIRAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 9, 1931 Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Small Bore Qualification Couise for the National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following extract of letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, for - warded us by the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Experience has shown that the small bore qualification course laid down in paragraph 16!2. Training Regulations No. 150-10, as amended by Changes No. 1, dated January 2, 1930, is not entirely suitable for the training of National Guard troops. The course has proven to be rather extensive and consumes too much of the .limited time available for armory training. 2. The course outlined below having been approved by the Secretary of War in 3rd Indorsement, War Department, Adjutant General's Office, dated November 27, 1931, is authorized for the training of the National Guard in lieu of the course out - lined in Changes No. 4, Training Regulations 150-10, when lack </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL of proper facilities, equipment or time does not permit the firing of the regular course. However, all personnel of an organiza - tion will fire the same course. :&gt;. The abbreviated course ns approved by the Secretary of W ar is as follows: SMALL BORE COURSE * NATIONAL GUARD Kaniie :50 feet .1. INSTRUCTION PRACTICE. iTime .Shots . Target Position Table I (No limit 10 |SB-A-2 Prone No limit . 10 SB-A-3 IProne No limit 10 SB-A-2 'standing Table II (5 Kneeling ! Kneeling No limit (5 Sitting SB-A-3 !&amp; Silting '30 seconds, 2 strings, | 'each string 5 shots each SB-D-2 Standing Table III | [ to Sitting 40 seconds, 2 strings, | Standing each string 5 shots each SB-D-3 to Prone Note: — To be fired as often as possible. b. RECORD PRACTICE. Time Shots .Target Position Table IV No limit 10 SB-A-2 Standing Slow Fire No limit (5 Sitting j jKneeling (5 Kneeling SB-A-3 ,&amp; Sitting 30 seconds, 2 strings, . , Standing each string 5 shots each SB-D-2 to Sitting Table V .! | | Rapid Fire 40 seconds, 2 strings, ; Standing 'each string :5 shots each SB-D-3 ,to Prone c. QUALIFICATIONS. To be considered qualified as prescribed in Note 2 of para - graph 5 (1) of Training Circular No. 4, Office of the Chief of Militia Bureau, September 8, 1931, a total score of at least 163 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL must be attained. In order to be rated as a marksman, sharp - shooter or expeit, pel Sonne! must lire and qualify in the small bore course as prescribed in TR 150-10. 4. Rpports covering small bore practice should be submitted to the Militia Bureau in accordance with paragraphs 9, 15 and 16, Train - ing Circular No. 4, dated September 8, 1931. Reports will state which small bore course was fired." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 11, 1931 Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books. 1931. To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1931. in accordance with the following instructions: a. Council Book Q. M. C. 15. h. Company designation with words "State Fund" added on cover. c. The account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under "Other Funds" and in accordance with paragraphs 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 of the instructions. (See also the model.) </seg>
            <seg id="p074">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL d. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, regardless whether receipts or expenditures. e. Certificates for receipts and itemized invoices for expendi - tures are required for all transactions from January 1, 1931. f. In case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transactions cut off bottom of page above words "Total receipts and expenditures" and the top of the next page "In accordance with fund", etc., under the word "year" and above "months", and paste these pages together. g. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of December 81. 1931. h. Certificate must Le submitted as a voucher showing the officers that messed with your c.o'mpany and the amounts. 2. From the audits in the past it is noted that responsible officers in some cases do not post their hooks, when the transaction occurs. This practice must stop and every transaction should be actually post - ed on the date that it occurs. The canteen dividend for 1931 must be nicked up under this year's business. In cases where the Council Book has been used up and the Lst certificate has not been signed it will be necessary to send in the old and the new book. However, these books should be used until they are completely filled and they are good for a period of from 5 to 10 years. 3. These Council Books with vouchers will be sent immediately to Major H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska, who will audit and return same, making report to this office of any discrepancies' found. By direction of the Governor: i H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 30, 1931 Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Appropriation for the Nationr.1 Guard, F. Y. 1933. To: All Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. 1. I am advised by the Executive Council of the National Guard Association of the mcst serious situation that has faced the National Guard since its reorganization following the World War. 2. Items in the b-dpel as presented and recommended to the Seventy-second Congress by the Director of the Bureau of the Budget provide sufficient funds for or ly forty-two (42) armory drills and for the attendance at the summer camrs of only seventy-five (75) per cent of the present strength of the National Guard. 3. It further provides, ."that for the fiscal year 1933 armory drills shall be restricted to such number os can be provided without exceeding the amounts available in this act for such drills". Also "that attendance at camps of instruction shall be so limited that the cost of such camps, together with other expenses under this item, can be met wilhin the amounts made available in this Act for such camps". 4. These restrictive clauses if enacted into law annul the pro - visions of Section 91 of the Nationrl Defense Act, which now prescribes the minimum training that shall be had. This affects the training and pay of every officer and enlisted man in the National Guard. 5: With the above in view you are requested to immediately write to your representative in Congress from your district, both House and Senate, telling them of just the effect this reduction will have on the National Guard of our State. 6. Also suggest that this information be given to your Chamber of Commerce and Civic Clubs that are interested in maintaining the present high standard of our Guard. This is in no way asking for an increase over the fiscal year 1932 appropriations made by Congress. It is simply asking that the same number be trained as was in the </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL F. Y. 1932. In fact the amount rsked for the fiscal year 1933 is some - what less than the cost of the Guard for the fiscal year 1932 due to reductions made in other budget items, accounted for by lower costs. 7. It is not believed cur members of Congress will allow our State Guard to be crippled in so vital a feature as training if they are made acquainted with the situation that now threatens and it is my opinion that letteis from their respective districts will be more effective than only one fiom this office. 8. Please give this your immediate attention. Bv direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 4, 1932 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment, F. Y. 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. 1. In accordance with instructions received from the. Militia Bureau to the effect that all unobligated funds allotted to this Stale for supplies and equipment will be readjusted on March 31, 1932, it will be neces - sary 1.0 submit, not later than March 10, 1932, requisitions covering the requirements for your company for' the balance of the fiscal year 1932. 2. No reauisitions received after the date set forth above will be filled for this iiscal year. Requisitions submitted after the above date cannot possibly be acted upon prior to field training of 1932. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 10, 1932 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Small Arms Practice, 1932. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. WHO WILL FIRE AND CURS' S TO BE FIRED. Subject to the amount of ammunition available, the provisions of Training Circular No. 4, MB 1931, as amended, will govern small arms practice of all units in this state. 2. RECORD FIRING DURING THE FIELD TRAINING PERIOD. Record practice eluring the iield training period will be permitted only for such men as have not' been able to complete this firing on their home ranges. All pieparalory exerc'ses. all small bore firing, all pre - liminary firing with service ammunition, and as much of the record tiring as possible, will be completed at home stations. No instruction practice, except a limited number of sighting shots, will be permitted those firing record during the field training period anil no man who lias not completed the preliminary instruction firing will be permittei! to fire record. 3. RECORDS AND REPORTS. Blank examination forms (for re - cording the state of progress in preliminary marksmanship). Individual Score Books, and scoie cards will be sent to r. 11 units without requisi - tion, as soon as possible. Score. cards and Report of Individual Class - ification in Arms (Form AGO 110) must he submitted to cover small bore firing and the regular record filing. These reports will be in the hands of the regimental or similar unit commander not later than 5 P. M., August 1, 1932. Expenditure of ammunition is based on these two reports. 4. AMMUNITION, TARGETS, AND SUPPLIES. Upon the written request of a regimental or similar unit commander, ammunition, targets, target material, and supplies will be shipped, without further requisi - tion, in the amounts available for such regiment or similar unit. All ammunition will be accounted for at the annual encampment by the submission of special expenditure forms (which will be obtained at camp from the office of the USP&amp;DO) and by turning in the surplus </seg>
            <seg id="p078">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ammunition not so accounted for, to the Camp Ordnance Officer not later than noon. August 2, 1932. 5. . The cal. .30 hall ammunition allowances are based on the num - ber of men armed with the rifle, except that no cal. .30 ammunition is allowed for recruits or. other men who have not fired and qualified in tie small bore course, unless such men have previously qualified with the rifle. Under no consideration will recruits or unqualified personnel fire cal. .30 ball ammunition. Cal. .45 ball ammunition will not be allowed peisonnel who have qualiiied in either of the two preceding years. | ' 6. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 2, April 10, 1931, and letter from this office on "Small Arms Practice, 1931-1932", dated October 12, 1931, are rescinded effective this date. Ey direction of the G: vern~r: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 1, 1932 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Small Arms Practice, 1932. To: All Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. WHO WILL FIRE AND COURSES TO BE FIRED.. Subject to the amount of ammunition available, the provisions of Training Circu - lar No. 4, MB 1931, as amended, will govern small arms practice of all units in this State. 2. SMALL BCRE AND PRELIMINARY PRACTICE. All prepar - atory exercises, all small bore firing, and nil preliminary firing with service ammunition will be completed at home stations. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. RECORD PRACTICE. All record practice will be fired during the 1932 Annual Field Training period. 4. RECORDS AND REPORTS. . a. Blank examination forms (for recording the state of pro - gress in preliminary marksmanship), Individual Score Books, and score care's have been Sent to all units. Score cards and Reports of Individual Classification in Arms (Form AGO 110) must be submitted to ever small bore and preliminary firing. These reports will be in the hands of the regimental or similiar unit commander not later than 5 P. M.. August 1, 1932. b. Score cards will be filled out on the back thereof to show the individual's score at the various positions in preliminary practice and will he checkcel by the officer in charge of firing on the range prior to the start of record firing and any individual's score card that docs not show a complete record of preliminary practice will not be allowed to fire for record . 5. AMMUNITION, TARGETS, AND SUPPLIES. a. Ammunition, targets, and supplies will be furnished upon requisition by unit coinmrmileis direct to this effice. All ammunition will be acciunted for by filling out special expenditure forms (wl ich will be furnished by this office) and by turning in any remaining on hand to the camp ordnance officer not later than noon, August 2, 1932. b. In expending ammuni ion it must be borne in mind that the allownce per. man for firing the preliminary course is fixed by regulations and any expenditure for. an amount -greater than the number of rounds required based on the reports submitted will not be accepted. 6. The cal. .30 ball ammunition allowances are based on the number of men armed with the rifle, except that no cal. .30 ammunition n; allowed for recruits or other men who have not fired and qualified in the smalll bore course, unless such men have previously qualified with the rifle. Under no consideration will recruits or unqualified personnel fire cal. .30 ball ammunition. Cal. .45 ball ammunition will not be allowed personnel who have qualified in either of the two pre - ceding years. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">KM OUT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7. Nebraska Circular Letters No. 2. April 10, 1931. and February 10.. 1932, and letter from this ofiice on "Smr.il Arms Practice, 1931-1932".. dated Cctober 12, 1931, are rescinded, effective this date. py direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 5, 1932 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Duplicate Checks. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. The following letter from the Finance Officer, U. S. A., Fort Omaha. Nebraska, is published for the information and guidance of ■all concerned. "1. This office receives a great irany letters in connection with the loss or destruction of Arm ny drill pay checks and in order to avoid unnecessary correspondence in regard to these checks, it is re - quested the following instuctions he issued to the officers of the National Guard in your State. When a Government check is lost or destroyed, the Treasurer requires that the payee report the loss or destruction in writing over his own signature, payee's letter is to he sent to the disbuis - ing officer who issuctl the check. The signature of the payee en - ables The Treasurer to have on file for comparison a specimen of the payee's signature for determination of possible forgery if check should be presented for payment. The payee should also state in his letter whether or not check was indorsed. 2. When this office has received a letter reporting less or de - struction if check it will be forwarded to The Treasurer with a re- </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7!) quest that payment of same he stopped and that the payee be furnished a bond of indemnity which is required to be executed prior to the is - suance of a duplicate check. Payee should also he advised that a dupli - cate check can not be issued until thirty days have elapsed after the original was drawn. . . (Signed) E. C. Morton, Major, Finance Dept Finance Officer, U. S. A." By direction of the Governor: H..J. PAUL The Atljutant General, Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 2, 1932 Circular Letter No. 5' Subject: Mother's Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG... The second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of tho members of your organization who may be separated from their mothers on May 8 the duty they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mother's Day. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p082">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 12, 1932 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Athletic Program. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following Athletic Program, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. »««•«••■«.« 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this program his personal attention and will cooperate with the Camp Athletic Officer in all particulars to the end that the program may be most interesting entertaining, instructive, and beneficial to the enlisted men and of - 3. PROGRAM a. FIELD MEET. Saturday, August 13, after 9:30 AM is re - served as Athletic Field Day. (1) AH entries in athletic events scheduled for that period will be released from all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared of troops prior to the above designated hour. (Field Training Program .1932. 4 c.) (2) Track. All track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event. b. SWIMMING. (1) Swimming events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (2) The swimming pool may he used only when life guards are present and on duty at the pool. c. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS HAVE ALL MEN WHO WILL BE ENTERED IN THE BOX - ING CONTESTS ACCURATELY WEIGHED AND IMMED - ATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER A LIST OF THEIR RESPEC - TIVE ENTRIES TOGETHER WITH A STATEMENT OF THEIR ACCURATE WEIGHTS. d. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS PREPARE LISTS OF THEIR RESPECTIVE ORGANIZA - ■ TIONS'. ENTRIES IN THE FIELD, TRACK, AND SWIM - MING EVENTS AND IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER SAID LISTS TO. THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER. 5. GENERAL'S TROPHY. a. Adjutant General Paul is again offering a cUp to the company showing the greatest activity and efficiency in athletics. b. Points will be awarded to the various companies upon the following basis: (1) Boxing. Owing to the difficulty that has been experienced in ar - ranging a card for the second evening of camp (Tues - day), it has been decided to award a greater number of points to the companies having entries in the boxing bouts upon that evening. Therefore, upon the first Tues - day evening, 25 points will be awarded for each entry al the ringside in condition to box, and 15 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. Upon all other evenings, points will be awarded as follows: 10 points will be awarded for each entry appearing at the ringside in condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">82 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL An additional 15 points will he awarded to the winning entry in each bout. 25 points will be awarded to each entry, who enters the semi-final. 50 points will he awarded to the champion in each weight division. (2) Swimming. 25 points will be awarded for each 1st. 15 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 10 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (3) Track. 25 points will be awarded for each 1st. 15 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 10 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Mass Athletics. 250 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 200 points wiU be awarded to the company evidencing the second greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. \ 150 points will he awarded to the company evidencing the third greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 100 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the fourth greatest activity and efficiency in mass '-■ athletics. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OF. THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBR/ SKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 2, VJ32 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Disposition of Armory Drill Pay Checks applied on Prop - erty Shortage. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Comrr.andeis, NNG.. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. "1. It has been noted that the provisions of paragraph 25 c NGR 59, are not liein^ followed with respect to forwarding checks for cancellation. 2. Where checks are not delivered to payees on account of prop - erty adjustments, they sh uld be forwarded promptly to the Adju - tant, General of the stale for transmittal to the Finance Oilicer with lequest for cancellation, as provided in the Regulations cited. The practice of holding checks until proceedings under paragraphs 19 and 20, NGR 75-7. are instituted and completed and then transmitting the checks with- the Di-oceetHtigs should be discontinued. This will avoid the possibility of loss and eliminate the enormous amount of clerical work involved in recording and caring for the checks in the various offices through which they pass. 3. The various operations where a shortage exists which was not discovered until the check was received, are as follows: a. The check- -not being properly deliverable to the payee — should be returned for cancellation. b. Proceedings should be instituted to determine the amount of the shortage under paragraph 10 or 11, NGR 75 — 7, de - pending on which paragraph is applicable. . c. Militia Bureau Form No. 18, Statement of Charges, should be .prepared to accompany a pay roll — which may he supplemental- -at the earliest practicable date, i. e., either </seg>
            <seg id="p086">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL on approval of proceedings under paragraph 20 f, NGR 75-7, or upon notification that survey proceedings author - izing the shortage have been approved by the Secretary of War. d. Pay rolls should be submitted accompanied by the State - ment of Charges, in order that proper credit may be ob - tained. 4. In no case will either .-.hecks, Statements, of Charges (Militia Bureau Form 18), or supplemental pay rolls be forwarded to the Militia- Bureau with the reports of survey. In this connection attention is in - vited to paragraph 12, NGR 58. (SIGNED) W. H. Waldron, Colonel, Infantry, For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H.' J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 20, 1932 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau, to submit a Return of Strength on the evening of June 30, 1932, therefore all unit and sub-unit commanders are requested to wire this office their strength Thursday A. M., June 30, in order that we may compile same and forward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, that day. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. The following form of telegram, giving officers and enlisted men separately, shuld be used: "Co. A, three officers, sixty-three enlisted men. (Signed) Smith, Captain." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, - Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 21, 1932 Circular Letter . No. 9 Subject: War Records of National Guard Units. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. .The following letter from the office of the Chief of the Militia Bureau is published for the information and guidance of aU concerned. Anyone having such documents or records as is described in basic communication may,- if they so desire, forward same to this office when they will be forwarded to the Adjutant General of the Army through the Chief, Militia Bureau. "1. The publication of the historically valuable documents pertaining to the military operations of the United States in the World War (as those of the Civil War were published) will be the most enduring memorial to those who took part therein. 2. Before the publication of these records can be under - taken, the existing gaps in the files of the Adjutant General of the Army must be filled. Many important documents are in the possession of organizations or individuals. As an illustration of how prevalent this condition may be, the records of the First Division in the possession of the Adjutant General filled nine filing cases; those collected from units and individuals filled ten more. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">86 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. While most of the lecords pertaining t&gt; National Guard units are now in the files of The Adjutant General, where they are available for examination by members of the Historical Sec - lion, it is probable that foinier members of these organizations still have in their possession many historically valuable records. These scattered documents should be assembled and consolidated with those now in the archives. 4. Even apart from the eiuestion of publication, it is in the interest of National Guard units that ihe'se documents be collect - ed in one place under expert care before they are lost or dam - aged, where complete files may be available f' r use even before - they can be sifted, organized and edited for ultimate publication. It may be pointed out that the program of public construction in Washington includes provision for a fire-proof Archives Building, which will probably be complete within two years, with proper arrangements to facilitate research. 5. The value to the National Guard of thus concentrating the organization records as a source of military history is very great Troops can gain from history an experience in warfare more varied than that- of any one individual or unit. This eource of instruction will become of increasing value as time goes on and those who have had actual combat experience are re - placed by those who have not Units will be able to draw illus - trations for tactical, training, or administrative lessons from their own pest, thus increasing esprit-de-corps. 6. The Militia Bureau, therefore, suggests that the adjutant general of each state shall collect these scattered records and forward them to the Chief of the Militia Bureau for- transmission to the Historical Section) Army War CoUege. In forwarding these documents such restrictions or instructions should be made as may be deemed advisable. 7. The Historical Section, Army War College, will select the historically valuable documents, index and collate them, and prepare copies for the. printer. 8. It is desired that correspondence on this subject be with or through the Militia Bureau for its information. The Bureau will be glad to cooperate iii any way in this important work. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL S7 (SIGNED) W. II. Waldron, Colonel, Inf., MB, For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau". By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 5, 1932 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1932. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1932, having been bet, i. e., August 1 to 15, 1S132, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when it does not comply with the provisions of Section 111', NGR 45. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained theiein as non-compliance there - with will cause forfeiture of pay of company officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to train s-chedules, transportation requests, anel "bills of lading. 3. Company commanders are authorized to purchase subsistence for enlisted men iit not to exceed 40c per meal and will follow in - structions received from the USP&amp;DO pertaining thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume command of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained, i. e., no men on top of the cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without, orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct </seg>
            <seg id="p090">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The commanding officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp, and report to the camp commander immediately upon arrival any defects or faults found with railroads transporting troops. Each company and detachment commander up n arrival at detraining point will immedi - ately report to Detraining Officer with reference to baggage detail. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins, and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company commanders, will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Training Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag or foot locker. Company commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., cotton breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment and cleaning materials. In - formation pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment, and harness will be furnished in a separate circular letter. No target material or canvas cots will be brought to camp. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except cal. .22, long rifle will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO. .All empty cartridges (brass) in packing boxes, aiming devices, arm racks, and lockers suf - ficient for men in camp, rifles, bayonets, and pistols for same and all other ordnance with which the individual and companies are equipped will also be brought to camp. The Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only sufficient ammunition to be used in the conduct of its fire on the range. Machine gun companies will leave the new mount for guns recently issued at home station as same will be furnished at camp. 9. Special Equipment, All Signal, Medical, and Engineer prop - erty, including lister bags, is to be carried. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e.. Property Records, Individual Recirds, Stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in quad - mplicate of all officers antl men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will be turned in immediately upon ar - rival in camp. 11. Transportation on equipment brought to camp other than enumerated above, which becomes excess equipment, will have to be paid for by the Unit Commander bringing or permitting same to be brought. (M. B. file 544.4 Gen-81 May 25, 1931, Subject: Trans - portation of Equipment for Field Training.) 12. Messes. All Company Officers will mess with their organiza - tion. Every effort should be made to secuie the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer 110th Medical Regiment, with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, QMC, will establish officeis' messes for the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such officers of the State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 1, 1932. 13. Parking. The main road through camp and entrance thereto will be kept clear of traffic at aU times. No cars will be left standing or parked in the road. The cais of officers will be parked along the river bank against the dike back of their respective areas. Driving on or off the main highway through camp will not be permitted except at such places marked for such purpose. No motor transportation will be permitted in the enlisted men's camp area. Field, Staff, and Organ - ization Commanders only, will be i ermitted to bring private convey - ance to camp. Company or like orpanization commanders may detail one private to take their (company ce mmander's) car to camp and return same to home station. All other officers and men will be re - qired to travel with company on train. Any private conveyance brought to camp without special permission other than set out above will be immediately impounded and held during the field training period. Officers bringing automobiles to camp will present State registration certificates at Camp Headquarters and have same registered on day of arrival. 14. The attention of all unit and sub-unit commanders is called to the necessity of knowing their men' are physically fit before tak - ing thepi to camp as tne number of major operations in our camp </seg>
            <seg id="p092">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care - of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 15. Unit and sub-unit commanders will make sure that they are not bringing any venereal cases to camp and in case any are found on the physical examination that will be made on entering camp, they will be returned to their home station at their own expense, without pay or allowances, as they wiU not be permitted in camp; such men will also be required to refunel both railroad fare and subsistence ex - pended on them in bringing them to camp. 16. No companies, detachments, or tletails will be permitted in camp in advance of the time ordeied in. for the purpose of condition - ing kitchens, putting up tentage, or doing other routine work unless they have been designated by order or otherwise by this office. 17. Unit and sub-unit commanders will read this letter to their command at every armory drill between the time of its receipt and the time of entraining for camp. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 6, 1932 Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Transportation During the Field Training Period, 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. MOUNTS. Mounts will be furnished to the respective organiza - tions as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REI'CRT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL a. State 8 Officers, 3 Orderlies, 1 Senior Instr., 1 for Staff the Governor 134th 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., 1 Aux. Inf. . Bn. Adj., 1 Atlj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T., 4 Orderlies (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hqs.) 35th 1 C. O., 1 Adj. 1 S. O., 1 Orderly, 1 Tech. Sgt Div. Tn. (TM), 7 to ea. Wag. Co. (1 ea. Officer, 2 Color Guard, 1 First Sgt, and 1 Orderly, 2 to Med, Dept Det 110th 1 Col., 1 Lt Col., 2 Majors (P. &amp; T., Veterin- Med. aiian D.S.O.), 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer. 2 Regt. Orderlies The horses assigned to the 110th Med. Regt will also be used by the 110th Vet. Co. at a time that will not interfere with equitation, by mutual arrangement between the C. O. of the lloth Med. Regt and the C. O. of the 110th Vet. Co. NONE OF THE ABOVE HORSES WILL BE RIDDEN BY CIVILIANS OR MINORS. b. The responsible officers for the following sub-units will furnish riding equipment with grain and feed bags. S. S. Maj. W. E. McConnaughey, 13 sets 134th C. O. Regimental Hq. Co., 6 sets Inf. C. O. BattaUon Hq. Co.s, 3 sets, each C. O. Service Co., 2 sets C. O. Med. Dept. Det, 1 set 35th ' C. O. 119th Wag. Co., 7 sets Div. Tn. C. O. 120th Wag. Co., 7 sets C. O. headtruarters Det, 4 sets C. O. Med. Dept. Det, 3 sets 110th C. O. Service Co.; 8 sets Med. C. O. 110th Vet. Co., 8 sets Regt. 2. "MULES, DRAFT. Mules will be assigned as follows: a. Can.p Quartermaster !_ 4 134th Infantry M. G. Companies L 4 each </seg>
            <seg id="p094">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Howitzer Company 2 Service Company 16 35th Division Train 119th Wagon Company 20 120th Wagon Company 20 b. Equipment for the above wiU be furnished as follows: USP&amp;DO — All escort . wagons required. The C. Os of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Company will furnish the necessary harness for the animals assigned them. The C. Os of the Wagon Companies and the C. O. of the 134th Inf., Service Company, will furnish their own black - smith's, saddler's, and wheelwright's tools, etc., and will not under any consideration loan tools to any other outfit. 3. MOTOR VEHICLES. AH organizations having Government owned motor vehicles, will, immediately after arrival at camp and unloading of their equipment, have these vehicles reported to the Camp Trans - portation Officer, to be placed in the camp pool for the dura - tion of camp. No Government owned Ford trucks will be brought to camp this year. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 20, 1932 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Train Schedule To and Return From Annual Encamp - ment, Ashland, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">93 To: All Company Commanders, Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. In accordance with General Order No. 4, A.G.O. Nebraska, July 18, 1932, the following train schedule is prescribed for movement to camp: Movements Organizations Location x A p P, l , 0X - | £ aB ' Schedule ano. 1 ass. ! Lar *r* No. 1 How Co Gering 65 1 Lv. Gering Tn No. 54, 4:10 PM 6 U. P. (x) 7 3132 » Fremont Co D No. 1 latte 55 1 Lv. No. Platte UP Spec. 12:45 AM H CB&amp;Q 8 1 32 O Ashland 119 Wag Co. Lexington 50 1 Lv. Lexington UP Spec. 2:15 AM "* Co H Gr. Island 60 1 Lv. Gr. Island UP Spec. 4:15 AM 3 , , Ar. Ashland Q Spec. 7:45 AM g No. 2 Co B Falls City 55 1 Lv. Falls Cy Tn No. 113, 3:37 AM d M. P. . 8 1 32 £j Omaha Co A GO 1 Lv. Nebr City 5:15 AM 5 CB&amp;Q hq Co 1st Bn Nebr. City 21 &gt; Ashland Regtl Hq Co 50 1 Lv. Omaha Q Spec. 8:45 AM Co K Omaha 60 1 H Co L 61 1 O MD Det 134 Inf 22 ra Hq Co 2d Bn 24 Ar. Ashland 9:35 AM K A^?o 2. ?,°o \r , n Lincoln 22 1 Lv. Lincoln Tn No. 24, 10:45 AM h CB&amp;Q 110 Vet Co 55 8 1 32 r Ashland Hq 35 Div Tn 35 Hd Co cd Ln Ar. Ashland 11:17 AM </seg>
            <seg id="p096">Movements Organizations Locution No^'pass. Car' Schedule No 4 120 Wag Co Kearney 54 1 Lv. Kearney Tn No. 36, 6:45 AM CB&amp;Q MDDet35Dt 13 8,1,32 „,„.,, Ashland Co G Hastings 65 1 Lv. Hastings Q Spec. 8:10 AM Asmano. u Beatrice 60 1 Lv. Beatrice Tn No. 21, 8:28 AM » Band 110 MR ' Crete 20 Lv. Crete Tn No. 24, 9:25 AM W 130 Coll Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. Columbus Tn No. 20, 8:00 AM g Ar. Ashland Q Spec, 11:35 AM g No 5 Co E Scottsbluff 60 1 Lv. Scottsbluff Tn No. 32, 9:13 C CB&amp;Q W PM 7, 31 32 Ashland Serv Co 134 Inf York 70 1 . Lv - Q Yo^ Tn No ' 42 ' 11:12 A M g 8, 1/32 fp Co M Seward 55 1 Lv. Seward Tn No. 42, 11:59 AM ' Ar. Ashland Q Spec. 2:20 PM &gt; Inter- Co F Hartington 65 1 Lv. Hartington Bus 6:30 AM &gt; state ' 8/1/32 fe Transit Duck Lines Ar. Camp 11:30 AM t C No. 7 130 Amb Co Hastings 42 Lv. Hastings 7:00 AM 8. 1 32 pi Via Ar. Camp 3:0J PM » Gov't Serv Co 110 MR Lincoln 39 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 8 1 32 &gt; Motor 166 Hosp Co . 63 Ar. Camp 10:00 AM Vehicles 138 MT Co Fremont 46 Lv. Fremont 5:00 AM 8 1. 32 119 MR Sec 15 Ar. Camp 9:00 AM 137 MT Co llrldrege 37 Lv. Holdrege 3:00 AM 8 1/32 Ar. Camp 5:00 PM SS&amp;SD Lincoln 20 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 7 30 32 . Ar. Camp 10:00 AM </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (x) Tourists cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Co. E (Scottsbluff). Movement No. 2.. Co. A and Hq. Co. 1st Bn. will load in one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and Med. Dept. Det. will load in one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co. 2nd Bn. will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Organizations shown therein will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 4. Co. C will reserve space for Band, 110th M. R. 120th Wag. Co. and Med. Dept, 35th Div. Tn. will load in one baggage car. 2. TICKETS Government-Transportation Requests on the carrier concerned will be exchanged for round trip tickets at the local ticket office. Re - quests for berths will he exchanged With the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT i ■ ■ ' Baggage cars will be set the day preceding the movement to per - mit-loading of baggage and installation of field ranges where it is nec - essary. Tourist cars or coaches will be loaded in a eiuiet and orderly manner in ample time to permit carriers to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based en last year's transportation re - quests. 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for ench passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand bag - gage, field desks, dispensaries, typewriter, etc., (par. 28, NGR 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bill of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bill of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each station at freight rates. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">96 5. The following train schedule is prescribed for the return movement: ~ ! '. ~~~ ~t 7- | Approx. Bag. Schedule Movements Organizations Location j No Pass Car "• No. 1 110 MR Crete 20 Lv.Ashl.nd Q Spec. 9:20 AM | CB&amp;Q Ar. Crete Tn No. 89. 11:10 AM o Dest ' _ r Beatrice 60 1 Ar. Beatrice Tn No. 89, 12:15 PM M ToM Seward 55 { Ar. Seward Tn No. 39, 11:24 AM H gjrn 134 Inf YoriT 70 1 Ar. York Tn No. 39, 12:10 PM • g Serv Co 134 Inf X° rk Is , and 60 1 Ar. Gr. Island Tn No. 39, 1:20 PM . * rn r Hast inns 65 1 Ar. Hustings Tn No. 5 1:50 PM H Cog Falls City 55 1 Ar. Falls Cy Tn No. 42-16, 4:43 PM * CoB Lottsbkff 60 1 Ar.ScottsbfuffTnNo.31,5:55AM J (x) , 8 /. 16 /£? - — d , , . ■ - C* No. 9 130 Cell Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. g Ashland Q Spec. 11:00 AM g CB&amp;Q . Ar. Columbus UP Spec. 2:00 PM Z UP 120 Wag. Co Kearney 54 1 Ar. Kearney UP Spec. 4:30 PM H Dest ' n?w a V 3 ro DT Lexington 50 1 Ar. Lexington UP Spec. 5:30 PM 'E 119 Wag Co No Piatt" 55 } Ar. No. Hatte UP Spec. 7:00 PM g g^ Co Gering 65 1 Ar Gering UP No. 53. 11:15 AM | (x) ?/ Si A1 p No. 10 Co K Omaha 60 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 24. 11:17 AM CB&amp;Q CoL " 1 8,15,32 Omaha MD Det 134 Inf IS , Sfgo"** Bn 4 24 J Ar. Omaha 11:58 AM __„ </seg>
            <seg id="p099">97 Movements Organizations Location Car' Schedule No. 11 Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln 22 Lv. Ashland Spec. 1:50 PM CB&amp;Q Co I 55 1 8/15/32 Dest. 110 Vet Co 35 ■ , f- Hq 35 Div Tn Ar. Lincoln 2:30 PM H Hq Co 1st Bn Nebr City 21 1 Ar. Nebr Cy. Tn No. 122, 5:20 PM *o Co A 60 . g No. 12 Co F Hartington 65 1 Lv. Camp Bus 7:00 AM 8 15, 32 *j Inter- s t a te tiuck Ar. Hartington 12:00 M X' Transit ••'!!! Lines . ■_ ■ . g Cm No. 13 130 Amb Co Hastings 42 Lv. Camp 7:00 AM 8/15/32 q Via ~ Ar. Hastings 3:00 PM g Gov't Serv Co 110 MR Lincoln 39 Lv. Camp 1:00 PM z Motor 166 Hosp Co 63 Ar. Lincoln 4:00 PM H Vehicles 138 MT Co Fremont 46 Lv. Camp 3:00 PM q 119 MR Sec 15 Ar. Fremont 7:00 PM K 137 MT Co Holdrege 37 Lv. Camp 4:00 PM, 8/14/32 Z Ar. Holdrege 2:03 PM, 8/15/32 S SS&amp;SD Lincoln 21 Lv. Camp 7:00 AM 8/16/32 £ ; Ar. Lincoln 10:00 AM f- </seg>
            <seg id="p100">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (x) Tourist Cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). Movement No. 8. Co. C and Band, lll.th M. R., will use one baggage car. Movement No. 10. Med. Dept. Det. ane' Regtl. Hq. Co. wiU use one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co.. 2nd Bn., will use one bag - gage car. Movement No. 11, Hq. Co. 1st Bn. and Co. A will use one baggage car. Lincoln units will use one baggage car. C. Postal Card Report WD MB No. 30 will be mailed to the USP&amp;DO as soon as possible after arriving at home station, with any unused tickets and "Conductor's Report of Troops Carried". 7. Two memorandum copies of Bill of Lading must be given to tiic USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to departure. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN , July 21, 1932 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Government Transportation ReciuesLs, Annual Encampment, 1932. (ROUND TRIP) To: Officers Responsible for Same. 1. In accordance with par. 73-c, NGR 71, Government Transpor- </seg>
            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL tation Request No. WQ • is inclosed herewith, to cover rail - road transportation (tickets) for your Company and any field or staff officers of the NNG residing at your stalkn to Ashland, Nebraska, and return, which should he completed in accordance with Check List "B" attached in duplicate. 2. The responsible officer in this case is acting as transportation officer and as train quartermaster and any accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations will be charged against the responsible officer. 3. Arrangements have never been made to have the transportation requests exchanged for tickets on the train. It is therefore requested that they be exchanged with the local agent. Read carefully NGR 70 and 71, with changes. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. 3 Incls. Incl. 1, Original T/R Incl. 2, Check List "B" in dup. Incl. 3, Post Card WD MB 36, in dup. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 21. 1932 Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1932. To: . Officers .Responsible for Same. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">REFORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ is inclosed herewith for freight (not checKalle baggage) involved in movement of your Com - pany to Ashland, Nebrrska. Bill of Lading for the return movement will be furnished while at camp. These Bills of Lading should be completed in accordance with Check List "C" attached in duplicate. 2. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable . rate where there is no Government transportation available for the purpose of trans - porting baggage and equipment from the armory to the depot and return. 3. Company Commanders will detail sufficient personnel to handle baggage at the detraining point. 4. Read carofuUy NGR 71 and 72, with changes. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL.. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. . OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein. Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. 4 Incls. Incl. 1, Original B. L with memos and S. O. Incl. 2, Check List "C Incl. 3, Public Voucher Incl. 4, Property List, in trip. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 21, 1932 Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Annual Lncampment, 1932. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. In accordance with par. 15. MB Circular No. 25, A-21, August 30, 1930, responsible officers for companies or detachments are author - ized to purchase the necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40 cents per meal per man for the time involved in assembling, travel, and arrival at camp. Balance of meals for the first day will be the Garrison Ration. 2. There is inclosed Check List "A" in duplicate, which goes into detail and must be used in conjunction with purchase and settlement of the amount involved. 3. In accordance with the train schedule your company or de - tachment would be entitled to the following meals: Company July 31 August 1 \~~ S B D S i . I 1 S— Supper B— Breakfast D — Dinner O — None . GR — Garrison Ration M— Meal By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein. Major, QMC-NNG, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28, 1932 Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: Fishing. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: AH Unit nnd Sub-unit. Crmmanders, NNG. 1. For all those interested it is announced that the old swimming nool on the south and west side of the main camp will be thrown open to the members of the National Guard for fishing this year. 2. An effort has been made to keep all fishermen away from this nool for the last three years and it should now be well stocked so as to afford some real sport for those who enjoy wielding the rod. If you are a fisherman come prepared to get your share of fish out of this pool. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 5. 1932 Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, Fiscal Year 1933. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, pertaining to the above named subject is published for the information and guidance of aU concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of drills to be held during the Fiscal Year 1933, will be limited as follows: (a) During the 1st and 2nd Quarters (July 1 to' December 31, 1932, inch), not to exceed 24 Federal Pay drills. (b) During the 3rd Quarter (January 1 to March 3, 1933, incl.), not to exceed 12 Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL drills not held in the 1st and 2nd Quarters. (c) During the 4th Quarter (April 1 to June 30, 1933, inch), not to exceed 12 Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the 36 drills not held during the 1st, 2nd rind 3rd Quarters. (d) In no event will the number of drills for which payment is made from Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year for any organization of the National Guard. (SIGNED) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, Militia Eureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. ■ -- . STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 22. 1932 Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Seventh Corps Area N.R.A. Riile Matches to be Held at Fort Des Moines. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following communication from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The 7th Corps Area Rifle and Pistol Matches nf the National Rifle Association will be held at Fort Des Moines, Iowa, on September 3, 4, and 5. These matches are for the states of Minnesota, Iowa, Miss - ouri, Arkansas, North and South Dakota, Nebraska, and Kansas, and </seg>
            <seg id="p106">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL for this year they take the place of the National Matches which are ordinarily held annually at Camp Ferry but for which Congress did not appropriate funds this year. The Matches are held under the jurisdiction of Major General Johnson Hacood, Commander cf the 7th Corps Area. Colonel Charles E. Stodter, Commandinc Officer at Fort Des Moines, and well known to all rifle shooters, will be executive officer. A large number rf the National Rifle Association Matches will he staged including the clastic Wimbledon Cup Match at 1000 yards, and Free Rifle Matches. 1*1 ere will be matches for military rifles at 2u\J to 1000 yards, small bcre matches at !S0 to 200 yards, and pistol and revolver matches. Winners will be awarded the N.R.A. medals and trophies, and a large percentage of the entrance fees is also distributed in the form of cash prizes. These matches are open to any citizen of the United States over the ar;e of 18 years, inducing all elements of the Army of the United States. Any citizen in fact can attend, but all must be members of the National Rifle Association. They can join the association at the matches. As Congress has n^t appreciated any funds for thia competi - tion all attending must do so at their own expense, and' must provide tneir own rifles, pistols and ammunition, but the expense will be small. All competitois will be provided with sleeping accomodations in tents including bedding witi.out charge and' splendid mess arrange - ments at cost will be provided. They should arrive at Fort Des Moines, Iowa, not later than 6:00 i J . M.&lt; September 2. Programs containing full information can be had by addressing a postal to the Executive Officer, N.R.A. Matches, Fort Des Moines, Iowa. These matches will aifoid all who attend not only -an opportunity to compete in the important, interesting, and national matches which were formerly held at Lamp Perry, Ohio, but opportunity to meet fellow rifle and pistol shooters from all over the central portion of the United States. Friendships wil be formed and renewed, and there will be opportunity to meet many shooters of national reputation. These competitions form a purt of the plan of the Federal Government lor the promotion of skill in rifle shooting among our citizens, the National Rifle Association being the federally recognized body actively con - cerned in this work. A large attendance is anticipated." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">RE1 CRT OF THE ADJUTANT GLNER/ L STATE OF NLBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN . September 12. 1932 Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: West Point Preliminary Ccmpalitive Examination, 1E32 f-r the Nebraska Nationrl Guard. To: All Unit and Su!)-unit Commanders NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of o-ie enlisted man of the Nebrrska National Guard to take the competitive examination for appointment to the Urited Stales Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office beginning Tuesday, November 1, 1932, at 9:00 A. M.. and continuing through November 3. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an applicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Government He must, on- the date of admission, July 1, 1933, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years, and must nrt be less than 5'4" in height The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. A pamphlet setting forth the requirements for admission to the Military Academy will be sent upon request. 3. The candidate selected will, he authorized by the War De - partment to report for regular entrance examination, which is sched - uled to be held beginning on or alu-ut March 1 1933, and the appoint - ment available on July 1, 1933, will be awarded to the qualified can - didate in the order of merit established at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously applicanls have presented themselves to take this examination who were in no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an applicant should have had at least one year in college, in addition to a high school education.. The examination will be written and will consist of an exhaustive examination in the fcllowing subjects: Ele - mentary Algebra, to and including quadratics. Plane Geometry, English </seg>
            <seg id="p108"/>
            <seg id="p109"/>
            <seg id="p110">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Grammar, United States and General History and English Literature and Composition. 5. No State Funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination, 6. A blank form to he used in making application to participate in the examination is inclosed. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. (1) Appl. blank STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 20, 1932 Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Repair and Rem vaton of Clothing and Individual Equip - ment, and Maintenance of Organizational Equipment, F. Y. 1933. To: AU Responsible Officers, NNG. 1. If funds are required by your organization it is directed that you furnish this office, not later than October 20, 1932, separate itemr ized estimates (showing unit cost and totals) for the following: a. Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equip - ment. b. Maintenance of Organizational Equipment. 2. In no case will any obligation be incurred until estimate called for above has been approved by this office. Owing to financial con- </seg>
            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ditions with which you are conversant the amounts asked for must be kept down to actual requirements and necessities. 3. The authorization of funds for the Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment is intended for articles where the enlisted men have been discharged and not for the purpose of clean - ing clothing for active men. Pressing of overcoats and uniforms and the shining of shoes will not be authorized. By direction of the Governor; H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 2, 1932 Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Change in Allotment of Stranrjth. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1.. In accordance with MB 352.4-Nebr-5, November 19, 1932, the maximum allowed for the enlisted strength of the Nebraska National Guard for the following companies and detachments will be as follows: Enlisted Men State Detachment '__ '- i-21 Regtl. Hq. Co. Inf. .. L64 Serv. Co. Inf. (Less Band) :: 1-64 Serv. Co. Inf. (Band) L36 How. Co. Inf. L64 Bn. H'q. Co.s r 25 Rifle and M. G. Co.s 1.64 Med. Dept Det. Inf. ____ L32 Hq. Det Div. Tn. L14 M. T. Co.s Div. Tn. 46 M. R. S. Div. Tn . !_20 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Wag. Co.s Div. Tn. _ 52 Med. Dept. Det. Div. Tn. 16 Serv. Co. Med. Regt (Less Band) 42 Serv. Co. Med. Regt. (Band) 25 Arab. Co. Med. Regt . 48 Hosp. Co. Med. Regt. _63 Vet. Co. Med. Regt. .. 40 Coll. Co. Med. Regt. 63 2. Where there has been a change in the apportionment in some of the companies they will immediately discharge a sufficient number to come within these .figures. This allowance must not be exceeded until authority is granted by the Militia Bureau. 3. The companies or detachments affected by the change will have to reduce noncommissi ned officers and specialists within the number authorized by Tables of Organization -for the strength set out above. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 3, 1932 Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers. NNG. 1. There are inclosed herewith blank efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1932, which should have your immediate attention. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. After giving a thorough study to instructions contained in NGR 20, par. 74, Changes 2, dated September 12, 1930, make out your reports and forward same without delay to the officer to whom directed. 3. The reports should reach this office before the expiration of the month. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Let us all get them in, in proper form and AT ONCE. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska! STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL-S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 8, 1932 Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: Test of Tentative Infantry Drill Regulations. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. Pursuant to letter from Chief, Militia Bureau, copies of Tenta - tive Infantry Drill Regulations, 1932, have been furnished all National Guard Organizations which are drilled in close order infantry drill and upon receipt of this communication all such organizations will immediately adopt the Tentative Infantry Drill Regulations and make a thorough test of same until April 1. 1933, at' which time report and recommendations on same wiU be forwarded through channels to this office. 2. It is imperative that your report and recommendations reach this office as near April 1, 1933, as possible in order that same may be forwarded to the Corps Area Commander who must make his comments </seg>
            <seg id="p114">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL and recommendations so thev will reach the Militia Buler.u not later than May 20, 1933. \JJ By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 12, 1932 Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books, 1932. To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1932, in accordance with the following instructions: a. Council Book Q.M.C. 15. b. Company designation with words "State Fund" added on cover. c. The account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under '-Other Funds'' and in accordance with paragraphs 2, 3. 4, 5 and 6 of the instructions. (See also the model.) d. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, re - gardless of whether receipts or expenditures. e. Certificates for receipts and itemized invoices for expendi - tures are required for all transactions from January 1, 1932. f. In case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transactions, cut off bottom of page above words "Total re - ceipts and expenditures" and the top cf the next page "In </seg>
            <seg id="p115">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL accordance with j.! funds," etc., under the word "year" and above "month"', and paste these pages together. g. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of December 31, 1932. h. Certificate must be submitted as a voucher showing the of - ficers that messed with your company and the amounts. 2. From the audits in the past it is noted that resporsible officers in some cases do not post their books when the transaction occurs. This practice must stop and every transaction should be actually posted on the date that it occurs. The canteen dividend for 1932 must be picked up under this yeai's business. In cases where the Council Book has been filled and the last certificate has not been signed it will be neces - sary to send in the old and the new book. However, these books should be used until they are completely filled and they are good for a period of from five to ten. years. 3. These Council Books with vouchers will be sent immediately to Major H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska, who will audit and return same, making report to this office of any discrepancies found. By direction of the Governor: I H..J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT I LINCOLN December 14, 1932 Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Preparation of Supplemental Pay Rolls. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. The following communication from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: </seg>
            <seg id="p116">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "1. It has come to the attention of the. Militia Bureau that the General Accounting Office has disallowed payment of sup - plemental armory drill pay rolls for the reason that the supplement - al rolls contain entries which differed from those on the original rolls which were sworn to as being correct. 2. Request is made that all concerned with the preparation of supplemental pay rolls be cautioned to see that all data af - fecting an officer's or enlisted man's pay be entered opposite the name of the person concerned and such rolls verified by the affidavit of the officer commanding the organization in which he swears that "this pay roll is correct and has been pre - pared in accordance with the laws, regulations, and instructions governing the National Guard". 3. Supplemental pay rolls should also contain a full state - ment of Ihe actual reasons for the submission. (SIGNED) W. H. Waldron, Colonel, M. B. For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska.' STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 20, 1932 Circular Letter No. 26 SECRET By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who partici - pated in the service of the Spanish-American War in the First, Second and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry: COMPANY A— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Pvt Gelvin, Robert N S3.20 Pvt Allen, Roller C 3.20 Pvt. l.ensley, Minor N. 3.20 Pvt Kelly, Charles R. 3.20 Pvt h. renter, Cochron A. ... 4.00 Pvt. Morgenstern, Henry A. _ 3.20 Pvt. Sommers, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Shively, Bion ___' 3.20 Pvt Turner, Robert W 350 Pvt Freeman, Charlie O. ... 3.20 Pvt Wompler, Elmer B. 3.20 COMPANY B— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Garinger, Albert S0.80 Pvt Grainger, Louis I 1.60 Pvt. Andrews. Chas. J 4.00 Pvt. Killhom, Perry A 4.00 Pvt. Llach, John 4.00 Pvt. Ressekuie, Herbert L... 4.00 COMPANY C— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Johnson, Hans $3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 Pvt. Campbell, Roy G.. 3.20 COMPANY D— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due ' Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt Alley, John S - 84.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt Kcsharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.00 COMPANY' E— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Dunr.ing, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt Gilham, Wm. H. 1.60 Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Moffet, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W.._. . 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G. 3.20 Pvt. Bays, Wm. .80 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 350 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY F— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P S3.20 Pvt Gilbert, /Ivin W.._- 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E. 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua 3.20' Cpl. Fell, Joseph G. 3.20 Pvt Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt Brcwn, Lewis 3.20 Pvt Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L. 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F. 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston 3.20 Pvt Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D. _. 3.20 COMPANY G— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John _: $3.20 Pvt. Mohler, Chas. E. 3.20 Pvt. Deaver, Harvey W 350 Pvt. Underwood, Henry C 3.20 Pvt Dowis, Jonathan E 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt Merryman, John R 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 COMPANY H— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H S3.20 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W— - 1.60 Pvt, Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S 4.00 Pvt. Sutton, Roy O 1.60 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt Mengler, Frank .80 Pvt Winagel, Anthony J 2.40 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 COMPANY I— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. HotseL Leon V $4.00 Pvt Jones, Oliver J 4.00 Pvt. Berndtson, John E 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M. 4.00 COMPANY K— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. DeLong, Herbert B $3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt Crittenden, David L 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Pvt. Fingado, Harry Jr.. 4.00 Pvt Witsch, Max N. . 350 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY L FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Downs, James W S3.20 Pvt Lei'g, Marvin O. 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B. 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker Robert H 3.20 COMPANY M— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coxson. Alvin A 3.20 Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L 3.20 Fvt. Jack, Cecil B. 350 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.2U FIELD AND STAFF— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name' Amt. Due P. M. Brown, Robert S $4.00 . M.s. Murnhouse, F. Edd 4.00 ' COMPANY A SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name" Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H S3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Paine Lewis A 3.20 Pvt Miller Ned K.l 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mr.thew 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Formr.n, David A 3.2J Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.£0 Pvt. Williams .Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, \\ illiam 3.20' Pvt Woodiuff, Charles 3.20 COMPANY B- SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Frink, Alberto D $3.20 Pvt. Jackson, Wm. 3.20 Cpl. Whitmer, James K 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Wag. Crow, Wallace H 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Frank ___:. 3.20 Art. Grossett, Chas. E... 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank 350 Pvt Briggs, Ernest G. Pvt. Wilson. Eli A 3.20 (Died in service) 3.20 COMPANY C— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George. $3.20 Pvt Clark, Wm. B. 350 Pvt. Burnhau., Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Nnme Amt. Due R-ia!: Nrtne Am'. Due Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 Pvt. M-r.e, David 1.60 Pvt Lee, Ira E '_' . 3.20 Fvt McLain, Clarerce E 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, Joh 1 H. 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R 3.20 Pvt. ShanHin, Sylvest2i- 1.60 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 COMPANY D SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Nnmo Amt. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A S4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T too Pvt. French, John C. --. 3.20 Fvt. Ma«er, Cla-.ence E 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Pickers Walter R 4.0 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M... 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L.--_- 4.00 COMPANY E- SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name ■ Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick S3.20 Pvt Keen, Robert J. 3.20 Art Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Kra.icek, John 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W 3.20 Pvt Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt Oster! out, John H 3.20 Pvt Frame, George W 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E. ___.—_ 3.20 Pvt Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COMPANY F— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Aint. Due Rank I Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton, George S3.20 Pvt. Hall James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D. 4.80 COMPANY G— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli $350 Pvt, Hugh, Harry .80 Cpl. Hays, Robert A 350 Pvt. Johnscn, Martin T. .80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S .80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F .8J Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V .80 Pvt. Neucomb. Frank S 3.20 Pvt Deverall, Ralph H .80 Pvt. Newton, William , 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L .80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M .3.20 Pvt. Fisher, Leo .80 Pvt Quimby, Lucien E. .80 Pvt. Gainey, John H. .80 Pvt Kitter, David .80 ■Pvt Horn, George L., Jr 3.20 Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D .80 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">REIORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY H— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Am:. Due Rank Name ■ Amt. Due Cpl. Borland, John A S4.00 Pvt Johnston, George H. ._ 4.00 Art Niell, J .hn \ 4.00 Pvt. Lgan, Alvah 4.00 l-'vt Bo we is l.ehry II. 4.00 Pvt, Mtitner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Boyd V«m. J — 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, Jc hn 4.00 Pvt Davis, Larry E _... 4.00 Pvt Perry, 1 erbert N. 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler. Al 4.00 Pvt. Serer.sen Ole C 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, Lav id E. 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry O, 4.00 Pvt Hershey, \,ill I 4.00 Pvt Whitney, John A 4.00 COMPANY I SECOND REGIMENT Ra:;U Name Am'. Due . Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Rainey Jacob / $4.00 Pvt. Schuclke, Hcnn-n A 4.00 Fvt .Lvans F'etchcr 4.03 Pvt. 1 homps n, Theodore 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Cscar 4.00 Pvt. VnB.er, Joseph H 4.00 Pvt. Tenia nd, Jr-hn \'v .80 Pvt Way, Rueben D 4.00 ivt. Schoolr, J hn II 4.00 co:.:p/ny k second regimlnt Rn.iU Name Amt. Duo Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt -Eiickson, Frr.iuis T $3.20 Pvt West, Charles 3.2J Cpl. Hill, John T. 3.20 COMPANY L -SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Eue Rank Name Amt. Due C] 1. Jack, Charles V. $2.40 - Pvt Evans, John 350 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W.J 4.00 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Sage, John M. 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, .Wm. C. .80 \&gt;ag. Br.uman, John P.. 4.00 Pvt Powell, Joseph A 3.20 Pvt Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Ane'.eison. Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W. 1.60 Pvt Cottfell, Eugene W 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 Pvt. Clannden, Al . in T 4.00 COMPANY M— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Alfreds, Frank H $5.60 Pvt Scl.wart, Wm. 5.60 Pvt. Londloclge, l.e.iry W.._ 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncan C 5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R. 6.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">REPORT OF THE ADJUT/ NT GENERAL FIELD STAFF AND BAND THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, Roy D...S9.60 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L 12.00 RB Mus. Parkhurst, Harry — 3.20 COMPANY A THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Hue Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W.-.S32X5 Fvt. Gray Burton E 2.40 Cpl. Ford, John J. 5.60 Pvt. Horahan, Chas. 5.60 Cpl. Steinbach, George 12.72 Pvt. Hinckley, John S. 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Mathew 1.60- "Pvt Hurst, Arthur J..^ 1.60 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Pvt Koontz, Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N...1.60 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Michael, Wm ...14.61 Pvt. O'Leary, John J. 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt Pace P«;rle R. 2.40 Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A- 1.60 Mus. Lenker, Chrs. 2.40 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Art Ball, Wm. A. 18.39 Pvt. Schneider, Wm. ...... 2.40 Pvt. Allen, Thomas '. 4.S0 Pvt. Smith, John J. 1.60 Pvt Avery, John S 1.61 Pvt. Taylor, James J. 2.40. Pvt Eliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Trombly, Warden, A. F. 18.39 Pvt. Collins, John H. '.. 1.60 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr 2.40 COMPANY B— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Covell, Herbert E...S33.64 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter ...._. 3.20 Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt McGrew. Frank .80 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.21 ' Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W 33.64 Pvt. Bradford, George H. .. .86 Pvt O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas .80 Pvt I'eteison, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Custer, Elisha .80 Pvt. Place John F 21.36 Pvt. Francisco, John H .80 Pvt Ray, Evert P 20.42 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt. Hoop, Scott D .80 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E 33.64 Pvt. Habbick, George W 1.60 Pvt. Schwartz, Wm. .80 Pvt Jarvis, Chas. T .80 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N. .80 Pvt Keanes, James N. .80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E... ..33.64 Pvt Line, Jno. M. 17.59 Pvt. Ward, William R .80 Pvt Whalen, Edwin F 350 COMPANY C— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. White, Thomas R...S27.46 Pvt. Shiel, Daniel J 7.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Ninie Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Du* Cpl. Bailey. Frank C .22.74 Pvt. Breechwr.ld, Philip 2.40 Cpl. Dillicn, Samuel II 27.4G Pvt C&lt; stcllo, Michael F 13.30 Cpl. Sydow. Emil 27.46 Pvt. Collins. Bernard P 3.58 Cpl. Miller, Wm. E. 27.46 Pvt DeRivieres, Francis L... 4.80 Cpl.' Burket, Harry B 2.40 Pvt Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Wag. Clayberg, I liner .27.46 Pvt. Denske, Fred .80 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Hawkins, Elgin C 8.58 Art Freeman, Nathan W 27.46 Pvt. henry, William 2.40 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E 27.46 Pvt Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Howell, Harry It. .....22.74 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F. 2.40 Pvt. Keliher, John F. 4.80 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Long, Wilber W 5.75 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.80 Fvt. Mitchell, Edward F 2.40 Pvt Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Norton, Ernest II 11.41 Fvt Wahlstrom, Albin F 2.40 Pvt. Paul, Henry C. 2.40 Pvt. Zurubsky, James ..' 7.64 COMPANY D— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D...S 4.80 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 Cpl. Aberr.athy, Fred B. 26.71 Pvt Jansen Nels P 23.91 Cpl. Christensen, Pvt. Juul, John M J 30.52 Christian A 36.18 Pvt Jones, Lewis C .80 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Pvt. Lr ntisbury, Harry 1.60 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L. 3.20 Pvt. ' Lundell, Ernest 4.80 Mus. Howell, Edward 3.20 Pvt Nelson, Chas. M 8.00 Pvt. Allwein, John C. 1.60 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G. J 8.00 Pvt. Anderson, Edward 4.00 Pvt Pool. John E . 4.80 Pvt Anderson, Andrew 3.20 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S I 4.80 Pvt Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.8J Pvt. Sutton, Frank E. 6.40 COMPANY E— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt Siddell, Bert E S13.01 Pvt Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Pvt Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred .80 Pvt. Hays, John S : 28.12 Pvt Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt Lewi n, Samuel C. .80 Pvt Van Epps, Bert L. .80 COMPANY F— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Uilbarn, Cb.ude A S36.69 Pvt. Olson, Chris .80 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank . Name Amt. Due Pvt. Baughman. Chas. 2.40 Pvt. Olsen Lars P 36.69 Pvt. Brunker, Frank . 1.60 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Hon, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius ...36.69 Pvt Hcudek, Charles .. 1.60 Fvt Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Hudec, Win. 3.20 Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Karges, John 36.69 Pvt Kment, Joe 1.60 Pvt Saare, Alfred H. .80 Pvt Knott, Fred .80 Pvt. Sramek. Anton . 1.60 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt Underhill, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J. 1.60 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M .80 Pvt. Nicholson, James T 1.60 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J . 350 COMPANY G — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burnett, Hamilton H $29.72 Pvt. Forsman, Oscar 29.72 Cpl. Larson, Felix G 29.72 Pvt Fuller, Guy W 1.60 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S ...29.72 Pvt Howard Edward 29.72 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Jones, Frank 27.72 Pvt Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt Knapp, Willie R 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Larson, Axel W .29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt Meade, Frank .29.72 Pvt Bowerman, Wm. F 4.80 Pvt. Morton, Frank H 29.72 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William 4.00 Pvt. Conner, Clement T 29.72 Pvt. Fickard, Harry M 29.72 Pvt Durham, Miller L. 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A 29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac __, .80 COMPANY H— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt Headwell, Axel $31.09 Pvt Robinson, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N 6-55 Pvt Robinson, Andrew M. — 3.20 Pvt. Keever, Oscar W._ 13.16 Pvt. Thomas, James T 3.20 Pvt. Leichty, John 6.55 Pvt Matson, Albert 5.60 Pvt. WiUiams, Edgar T. 31.09 COMPANY I— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Derienger, George $36.61 Pvt. Brown, Frank H 4.00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry D. S..37.56 Pvt Carroll, John W 4.00 Cpl. Dickenson, John W 12.07 Pvt Center, Albert 4.80 Cpl. Felts, William B 6.40 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R 9.24 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M 4X0 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander 350 Cpl. Meyer, Otto 4.00 Pvt. Fairchild, Homer 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">RI£IORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Ra-.ik Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Brett Zir.a H 22.45 Pvt. Guthercole, Fr^d A 4.00 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 1.63 Pvt. Hutchinson, /. lbert L... 1.60 Pvt. Hanks. Harry E 1.60 Pvt Jones Lloyd O 4.00 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Marqwadt, Fred W 1.60 Pvt Primer, Archibald G 5.60 Pvt. Miller, Fred S 954 Fvt. Ro.erts, James W 9.24 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F 954 Pvt. Selby, Arthur L. 9.24 Pvt. Padol, Adam .... .80 Pvt. Staaky, Cyrus 37X6 Pvt Perry, Chrs. E 11.12 Pvt. StoI.e, John G 4.00 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W 23.40 Pvt Swan, Richard B .80 Pvt. Aitktn, George F 37.56 Pvt. Vandyke. Jchn T 6.40 Pvt. Baird, Francis H 4.8J Pvt Vandyke, Sherman 6.40 Pvt. Bersley, Wm. G. 31.59 Pvt. Warrington, Albert J... 2.4J COMPANY K— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 1st. Sgt. Jaccbson, Carl L $34.29 Pvt. McCftulley, \V:n. G 1.60 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N 34.29 Pvt. Mines, James S 1.60 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H .80 Pvt. Painter, Vvra C 2.40 Pvt. Colitld, Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Porteriie-ld, James A 34.29 Pvt Gray, Lyman 3.20 Pvt. Rea.don 1 atrick J 2.40 Pvt. Grcss, Lenry C ..14.47 Pvt Roff, John L 29X7 Pvt Hightower Harry A.—- 2.40 Pvt. Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kennedy, George H 7.20 Fvt Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Pvt Rankright, Clinton D. .. 27.68 . Pvt. Ihcmpson, Janie« B 3.20 Pvt. Kruger, Wm. .80 Pvt. VanSicklo, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. Mathews, Stanley 30X2 Pvt. Williams, 'wm M 1.60 COMPANY L— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name . Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Brown, Cleveland W..1S 750 Pvt. Jor.es, Jcseph B 4.80 Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J 4.00 Pvt Kelley, Rooert S 6.40 Cpl. Lowe. Walter 8.00 Pvt McCell Jchn 14.40 Cpl. Taftj Charles C 21.01 Pvt McCoimick, Lenj. D 8.00 Wag. Stockton, Andrew 32.34 Pvt Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman 6.40 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H 5.60 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt Eradshaw, Thomas H 5.60 Pvt. Lee, Justivin E-. 1.60 Pvt Burns, James E 350 Pvt. Lehmus, L^wis A 21.01 Pvt Ci.isolm, Ralph O 5.60 Pvt. Mardock, John E 1.60 Pvt Foster, Louie C 32.34 Pvt. luardock, John E 1.60 Pvt Redfield, Cyrus R 4.80 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. hundus, Frank 32.34 - Fvt Athos, Andrew G 27.62 Pvt. Sherry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Black, Wm. 2.40 Pvt Swans^n, Nels 32.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Fox, Ernest S 24.79 Pvt Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Grove, George W. 5.60 Pvt. Walker, Chas. 27.62 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E. .. 6.40 COMPANY M— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dne Pvt. Foster, John E... $ 4.00 Pvt Heisler, Robert D .80 Sgt. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt. Hensel, Wm. A 2.40 Cpl. Alsen, John C 35.38 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris .—35.38 Mus. Porter, Lester E ...16.50 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H. 17.44 Pvt. Bennett, Niles 21.22 Pvt Maddan, Chas 35.38 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E 11.78 Pvt. Brewick, Andrew T 3.20 Pvt. Ratekin. Janson L .80 Pvt. Cantello, John 10.84 Pvt Timmons, Alfred D 34.44 Pvt. Carigan, Robert J 35.38 Pvt Wiesman, Jacob 2.40 Pvt. Custard, Marshall 1.60 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A 13X0 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Pvt. Alley, Franc 2.40 Pvt Foster, Frederick W 17.44 Pvt. Beardsely, Wm. S .80 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John D 13.60 Pvt. Griggs, Bert '. 2.40 TROOP K— THIRD CAVALRY Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter ... 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred . 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger, Claude G— 2.40 It is recommended that this list be given a circulation in the news - papers of the State with a view to locating such of - these men as possible. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>