<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  COMPETITION IN CEREALS.</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE l'v.\ I.K&lt;ITV &lt;&gt;h Nl'liKASKA. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Von mi: XXIV. AmcLE V. COMPETITION IN CEREALS. My K. C. Montuombsy. Iii-ikihi tkii May S. 1912. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA 0. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD THt KO»T&gt; Of IHf limimny) RABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President. Lincoln HONOKAHLK CHARLES H. AMtERSON Lincoln. HONORABLE GEORGE I (M l'LAN HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORK. Valley DKA.BLK VICTOR G. LYKORD, Kails City. '1U.NURABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. H . ex offlcio. E A Bl'RNETT Li J. S. DALES. M. Ph., Financial St THE WORKING STAFF KMtAD Wn.uv Ph. D., .4 : I Botany. J. Alway. Ph. D., Agricultural Chemutry. L. W. Chase, B. Sc. M i ring. C. W. Pvmui, B. 8c.. Farm Mmnmptment and Agricultura. • H. R. 8mith. fH. Gaik. M. D. C Animal Fa) H. FluMn.iv. M. S A Lawkeme tiki .neb, B. Ic, Entomology. * E. G. Montgomery. A. I my. T. A. KiEBMUArii.il B tal Agi Bbwix H. Barboik, l'n . i ' G. R. Chatbubn. A. M.. // B. A. Emebson, B. St.. Hoi O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engm- G. A. Lovela.nd, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Sntdeb, M. 8.. Supcrint&lt; r, Plai rW. Bvbk, B. 8c., Aaoeiate in Soils and Crop*. North Platte; As- Agriculturist. OJfce Dry Land A&lt;in&lt; ultur. . ' • Agri - culture. M. H. Swenk, A. M.. A*t&lt; Geobce K. K. Link, 8. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. R. 8. Tbvmbuix. A. M.. Assistant in Agri&lt; ultural Vh-mittry. Ebwin Hoft, B. Sc. Assistant in Agronomy iCropt). P. B. Babkkb, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy {Soil*). Ellis Rail, B. Sc.. Assistant in Animal Husbandry C. B. Lot, B. Sc. Assistant in Animal Husbandry. L. B. Stirdevant. A. M.. M. D.. Assistant in Animal Pathology R. P. Howard. B. S(. ix Ai;r.. Assistant in Hortf t V. V. Westgate. A. M.. Attittant in Horticulr James Cowan. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. ValenUne Fritz K*orr. B. Sc. Superintend' nt Experimental Substation. Mitchell. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">COMPETITION IN CEREALS. B1 i:. i,. MONTGOMERY. Betition ■ *&gt; .1 factor in inodifyiag the character of plant ions. In means &lt;&gt;f destroy iii«r m- hindering those whicli MM ■i til li&gt; survive under tin- particular environment, ;i recognized as one of importance since I&gt;arwin |&gt;oiiited &gt;ffective workings. V\ liile tlius recogmiaed as a naun-al means of maintaining the and strength of native vegetation, it has not km H i ans i&gt;f maintaining the yield ami vfcjaff of our ■ -11 1 ru|is. Oar common cereals have km cultivated for 1 1 saml \ears with practicall.v no attention to selection mIimi: until in &lt;|iiile rtient times. If anv change has taken iheie has acea a slow im|&gt;rovement so far as we ai"e aide t&lt;&gt; jmtgT ag the limited information at hantl. It is paaaMc that ilie i-ustoni of placing in the soil seeds for two or three nian.v plants as are really necessary to occupy the land suited in a continuous natural selection of the strongest and most productive. Ethe fall of I'.miT. a series of small winter wheat plats was at the Nebraska K.\|K-riment Station for the purpose of riag dat: the amount of natural eliniination of plants takes |.la«e under various nites of planting, and also to nine to what decree plants coining from undeveloped or seeds inijrht Ik' eliminated when planted in competition plants from large, well-developed seeds. ■plan adopted was to plant seed of wheat at various dis namely, one fourth ineh. one half inch, one inch, and one e half inches apart. This was done with two varieties— IUI. m, Milt K XV STATION OF NEBRASKA. VOL. XXIV, ART. V. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Th&lt;- c &lt;mi|K'tition ami riit»-of planting pU thiii on 1 1 iiKxith ■ i where smooth and tx^mrded a' and on th&lt; Turkcx Kol aad l!i^ Pnuc. Then in i lion on plants Kniwiag from l;i mt-. well &lt;l&lt;-v •■!&lt; &gt;|miI ilcv&lt;-lo|M-(i seeds. ifs|&lt;iMi i\cl\ . nrdi at the twn \; iHmM For &lt; - x . 1 1 1 1 1 &gt; I &lt; - . well iIi-\iIo|iim| aped of Would Im- :i 1 1 i-l'NM l«-i] with Illiclrv rlo|M-&lt;l Mni ot I! tli&lt;- \iirious ratm fro m- foiirih inch n im-liiti. A rpripntml wriea m &gt;bn planted, usin^ |ioorl\ • l&lt; - rgloped Turki\ !£•-•! in roaipetitioa with well developed Fniinc Tlifst- scries were dnplimted ami alternated with check l&gt;lats. iIktc 1m-i h&lt;x !m; |thits all told. The cx|M'riinciit was repeated with winter when in IMt, P.MII. ami I'M 1 . aad with two I ti«*»* of oiitu in IMC anil 11M1. Hteg lar^c ami small sf»-&lt;ls in the hitter c awe. Imt all well developed. The winter wheat plata were colii|ilc1el\ winterkilled in l'.lllt. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 x l mi- ..t seeds plaited par plat ai mm* rate ••■ nrili inch apart; '&gt;•"•••. H8, and 111'. res|&gt;ertiveh . at Tli.- huiiiIm'i or plats in ■ series, including - 18, which ]-»-|»-;(f&lt;*«l iii;i&lt;Ii- M in all. The plat - &gt;f t rows ::i; inHwa laag and § indies apart. M the l'.HiT. i lie living plants in each case were ( i.-IoIm-i ml Hgaia at harvest time all wm ronnted. For • n all daia vm redwc»&gt;d in the following table to the ii inn plains planted e ami, tut il ililhi for Tin l.i II It'll mill I'iil i'lilni ulnnt siui irul of plant* iii niiimix ruii x nf planting. 1908. Number ,,f Number of n ?»m s Decree*, &gt;lantinsr plants. h»rvP«t P1 l &lt;&gt;ct ol&gt;e''to planted ( »-t. 22, IWi i££" X harvest -ii 77 12 half incl H t&gt; 100 -7 70 17 and liai\esi t i ii i4- lliere m an average deirea - tr.iin various ians4's. That some of this dec ioim|m-i ition i&gt; shown In the fail that alaiui twiie re losi under thick plantin-: as thin. rii'i i in- i \pcrimeii! was coin inued. hut under unfaYoralde : ~ The fall and w inter proved t&lt;&gt; lie vel \ toy, so the low i Ii was rather small, and w inlerkilliny was lieavv. ita show that for evcr\ IM seeds planted there were 71 plants heceinlM-r 2. II at harvest time, and an average de &gt;.- of :::: plants from fall to hancst. A^ain tlie gn |.|iru\iin:lti'lv 32 liv of. inches. Elm 66 17 h inch U» «&lt;&gt; 21 rae « i i~ 2 lmi Sibils planted iIutc \\:is an av^rajte of S."&gt;.r&gt; live mil •'&gt;&gt;."_' |&gt;liiiiis ctnr i&lt;&gt; ni.itiiritv. ltd w ct-n 1 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 R'Hihinril ilntu ft&gt;r Titrkrii I!,;! uml Big I nt. si irrirul nf pltintx nt PCTM I'.KHI •er of Numb. plai Distant • of planting -■ .-d- One and one-ha • imi .", | imi 14 100 71 li«i :il Averairf li«l 71 II In IMt lli.' « uih-i- « ln*:i i |.l.. in. I n&gt;. ui-i-il \ &gt;,i i, - ,,i . planted in ihc - inaniii-r. jjavc data xiniilai tn thai ■eoared with winter \v as allow ii in Taldi , nliim *l ilm ■ Numl Distance of planting harre-*. : M P|mt .cut !••-■-■■■ iiini i.»n \\;i&gt; n.ii recorded Tin i • i&gt;f 7.!.." per .••ill M im:ui\ phmts li.irv r»li-«| I. and &lt;&gt;nl\ 14 |mt ml witli tli«- ilii.k.si |.l;mtinu&gt; Tin* t'X|MMMiiifiii \\;is i .nit iiiiiiil iii 1911. with ili&lt;- f« • 1 1 • • EMS 100 -h KNi inch </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 i -hitu for tun mrietie* of u hint. ■I ni /limits, il i minus ruti'x nf jiJnnt mi/. I nniliiin il ihlhi for tWO null til x of outs, xin, of iihnitx ut nniniis rutrx nf /i/tint i&gt;i(j. l!&gt;lt. Number of Number of Decrease, f planting- spp.Is plants planting to planted harvested harvest 1 1 ;i 1 1 1 •&lt; ;i i -. iiom data cited tliai there is a icctcaaw at Bbmri 31) per &lt; cut in the iiiiiiiImt of plasta from ;&gt;);i nt milt to Imr There are nunn caaaea of this ieereaac, such as in^ mil in cidcnis of various kinds, hut after these are ac ■ ic.l for ii is &lt;vi«lciit that we still have a loss of plants thru competition in the thicker ptaatiafta. It seems natural to aaajaMM that the (plants eliininate&lt;l shoiihl Ik- those that from any cause are weak &lt;&gt;r slow in development. Plants from undeveloped me usiiall.v smaller in early jrrowtli. altho later the plants mav become rigorowa eaaagh. As mentioned early in the paper. in certain plats well develojx-d seeds were alternate*! with un - de\c|o|H-d mtiIs :it I hi* \arious rati-s. far the BOTfjaae of deter miniaf araether the more vigorous plants from the hups - Ian ting Number of Number of Decrease, seeds plants planting to planted harvested harvest . 100 74 '~ 26 WO 7A 27 HX) 75 25 ion a 1IHI 71 29 2tf 27 2n 71 :r!h inch 100 100 UK) mo mo 76 77 II I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 would lend ii&gt; fliiniii:ii&lt;- tin- U-ss rigoro— plant* from ttw \»«-v m*n\. Tnlilr «i is ;i suiiini;ir\ of il;it;i from l&gt; pl;il&gt; "t uiul.i - wImmi wit It nil nit.-s ..1 phinl in». .;,i plains two ll 'ain plain ami ■ ■at plants one-fourth imh apart. Ii is at thi^ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 . /(, .&lt;/ i o/ t-ompetitioH «/ two grmdea of teed. Numtier of Number of Number of Decrease, • teed Method* plants plants October to Oct. 22 harvested harrert planted Al- UK) 72 15 IB Alone l(Xl Competi- tion 100 Hii 25 oped Competi 100 79 Ill tion ■ 100 bV \H Vverage UNH ihat the f nt ire plat was sown from that one grade of : in Competition" means that undeveloped seeds of re alternated with well developed seeds of the other In mi i as&gt;- Van the two grades of sml of the same variety his would have been desirable, but two varieties were inter to separate plants from the two grades of seed at harvest I'.nili ytiiilis ut sectl showed tin- same decrease from OrtoU-r However, in i*nnipetitioB, wlirn the two grades were al- ni-il. plant* from the weJl-dereioped s«'&lt;il wkammt a markcil Htlrantafte. Kvidenth the initial advantage gaiacd l&gt;.\ the mure •us plant! IriHii large, phiinp s»h'(1 ewihM them to evavi • mi the li^s vigorous plains, when plante&lt;l in &lt;-rnnjK-ti tion. (H&gt; nous made in the field showed that earlv in the season when rapid ppmrth tii-st U-^ins. either with fall sown or spriti}; sown - if for an\ &gt;aus&lt;&gt; a plant is slow in startinjr. BBi it is (I befwa &lt;p' i&lt;k stnit inji idants. the latter will soon shade it and have advanlajjes in various ways, so that the slower plant i&gt; |ieriii;menih i-etai-di-d. whereas, a similar slow starting plant. nmoBfg other* &lt;&gt;f its kind, niav fully recmrar in time and at barred l«* as riKorona as any. ~i. w lit'ii I &gt; l:i 1 1 1 «-&lt; 1 alone. /. &lt;'.. cjich &lt;ji-;m1c in ■ plat to </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ■ill ill &lt; '• I) Ills 'iiihimtl ilnlii fur Turl.i ii h'nl mill llni I U r a- hi &lt;il . In $ki &lt;&lt;/&gt;//« til tarn. Number of N ™*T of Nu ™* rof Deenw, K.ndofeed Method' n^d- plan 19(|e |W8 arvest W'd. A &lt;*&lt;J a :u Well d. plump one MO 71 Undeveloi Undevelo|.&lt;-,| Con.; tion | i,'om|rf"ti - plump 100 -1 Averatff 71 41 tion | plump 100 -1 Averafff 71 41 Tllf il;ll;l for l!Mi'' ,, [||»- in I Ih j &lt;I;i lii for 1 'hi'.i "••'inlii inns under which grown und ievere winterkill • -&lt; • till it ions under whiih ;im\ii .iihI srxcir winterkil ftmitm «&gt;n- »•■ ■rvereh winterkillt&gt;d thai little ooin| ftmitm «&gt;n- »•■ &gt;i\.'ItI\ w inlii-killctl llial lilllf cuii take | • I ; 1 1 -&lt; • in tin- s|iiinp i:ic&gt;\\ih. Inn again th&lt; of Hiirvivinj: |ihinls ni w i i li l In &lt;l in • . mi | ..-: i 1 1 ■ .i elimination among plants from poofh &lt; l&lt; -\ ■ - ill &lt; &lt; &gt;lll | M'T it i&lt; &gt;t 1 . Ill 1910, S\\i«li»h S. (Mack) vm &gt;&lt;&gt;\\ n in competition, a I term • ■liiuiiiiit inn among plants from jtonrh deve (black) toe sow n in competition, alterna and* -it various nittt* fnun one finiitli to t» In- aad s ill \;l|-iniis r;ilcs fnmi one fniill Ii to l« In » ,iim lag liiiyc s&gt;-&lt;'&lt;| and ■mall leed alone ;it the rarioiiM r^tew 18 illJT I;iiyc si-ol ;ili«l sniilll seed .iIiiik ill 'li« \;il ■■'- tei IS in all. &lt;lllll XIIKlll si I l/.v .,/ I nt nirinux rnh s uml in /.''/". — ■ 5sss "US "— " v mh^r / Numtxrof KindofBeed M.thod* '^^11^1 plant* Kind of seed •eeds lown han . ( Small seed Alone Iimi BJ 40 Small wed Alone Ml ■ M Larg«Med Alone UN) K&gt; Small aeed Competition !'«■ 32 Larfre seed Competition UNI 74 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 • -(I in c |k-t i I ion did not show idvantage ;is compared with small seed than when the .mil small were sown alone For smur reason, in almost -. with lioih wheat anil oats two varieties in eoni|*'titioii n a greater namber of plants at harvest ami a fri than \\ Inii either varieti was sown alone. Comhimei data for Turing /&gt;'&lt;&lt;/ ami Big Fran of competition on tico grades of seed. inn. Number of Number of seeds plants planted harvested Method Kind of seed . -loped Alone 100 «♦&gt; I. ft 1 4 i u I O4\ M . plump. Alone 10(1 69 31 Competition 1UI 72 ■ . plump Competition 100 77 23 In 1911 there was no marked effect as ■ result of eompetitkm, thai more |ilants were harvested where the two kinds 11 ' nuihiniil 'lulu fur tiro riiriitifn of outx to - of competition "// tiro frmttt of seed. 1911. Number of Number of nXa^a^' Method seeds plants p ."~ B planted harvested harwS Kind of seed Small teed Alone 100 75 28 UMwed Alone 100 77 23 Small seed Competition 100 76 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ''of' the weaker plants are dead or produ. ine only ■ verv small &gt; i-l.t </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Kik .".. Photograph showing relative size of large and small plants at harvest, from plat sown at rate of 16 pecks Kherson oats per acre. When the plants are about 8 inches high, the strongest begin to grow rapidly while the weakest plants either die or make slender growth, producing only a few seeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 T;ilil&lt;- 11 is a siiiniiiaiv of tin- data regarding the Dumb |iI:imis surviving at rariooa ratea ■•( plaatiaft for foai rll. \ilnihii uj /limits Inn i i still fin fltHI i, f loo x&lt; nls /ihintiil Hi iiuiinix rwtt I Tin- i-&lt;-siilis iinliiiiic iIkii . i Ixin i two-thirda a* duiii plaa Is |&gt;laiilr&lt;l. ;is an average &lt;&gt;t all I f. The imiiiiImt sur\ i\ in^. « Iii-ii- the (ilanliii'j i* ilin acr « -« -ii t ftcatcr thai ihat tac plaatiag is rli i&lt;-k . ii the tliiik planiini: is apparently •!■ i of competition aiming tae plai rut \~. \ timber &lt;&lt;/ ftmrnta Inn 10(1 xtnlx jilnnliil ill nil intis. In v/c ■ / (&lt;/ tiri, ij ni ■ As an avi'i-ip- for four years when the small or uudevelu|*ed seed an- atmrjM alont-. M plants wmt harvcaM ' &gt; each l«i am * .!*»r of Winter Winter Winter XxmrmM •end- wheat, wheat, ,„,„• wheat. ,ui?' A * er »«e planted 190* 1J*i» 19HI lid I liM1 folr One mnd one- half or two One-half inch P fourth h Average. lixi 77 91 74 H«i 70 J4 &gt;\y H«' ■ 1(10 .11 ■ MB ■ Jl 71 77 t Number Winter Winter ,. W •eed Method of seeds wheat, wheat, VJ:f ' wheat planted 1W* 1WI9 IS&gt;1U 1911 la " Small or un developed . Alone UMl 65 M 6(1 66 Lar^e, plump Alone UK) 72 43 65 06 77 Small or un- Corape- developed tition 100 tU :«i 6K Tl Large, plump Compe- tition 100 7W 60 74 77 "1 Average W 41 67 71 77 Average 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 - .iimI ti.'i plants fr tin- large, well-developed aeed. This - thai there warn ronajdrrable difference in the original ■ -. i-il. When planted in competition, there r |mti ■cniiiac of snr\ ivors in l&gt;otli ease* a fart Bated I The nninlH-r of rorvivon from large teei in ei&gt;ni|M'tition. ru T"J. it It more than from the small seed, while planted alone the advantage wae only •;.-&gt; la M an iwraji Since the total ledtU— in the ihhiiImt of plants ■ .ii an average, 35 per rent, the adwantafe of lai-yi - ill in iliis respect is not hwpe. Ir seems that there are - inaii.\ weaklings snsiept il&gt;le to the etl'eet of eoni|H't it ion if plant* from lar^e aeed as amony: those from smaU EFFECT OF COMPETITION" OX YIELD. ■'Ml. ;;immI data were se.ureil on tlie relativ*- yield of the ii uraih- nt siiil when planted alone and in eoni]K-tition. ■ 13. Relation of i/rath of Mad to i/itlii wftan aJBax competition, mi paait &lt;&gt;f pUU i» r fM /ilmitx. l!&gt;lt. Yield per 100 plants There was an advantage of abo«1 Id |mm- cent iu vield whaii the two gradw* were planted alone, lmt when planted in e*n&gt; petition plants from small aeed were at a marked disadvai the difference Immh^ aboni i'.'i per eeat. By icCerriag to TaMe 11'. it is apparent that the iecTCMC in yield is jrreiiter tlian the de.rease in nninlH-r of plants, indicating a very rapid elimina lion of those plants having an inherited initial disadvantage in Kind of seed Method Winter wheat Oats Rr undeveloped Alone plump Alone r undeveloped . Competition plump Competition drama 219 236 187 234 drama 117 129 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 It lias Ihm-ii iiii'in iiuicil (Inn mil' inwttHii i»f growing tW( linn- limes ;h I n ; 1 1 1 \ phi lit s on the H lit H 1 — ri U&gt; full.\ «••-«- 1 1 1 »_\ 1 In- lami |M'iiiiiis nt ;i large mbouiI of riimi«*ti&lt;M ■ liii^ l''iiH|iii-iii icms li\ mam Experiutesi Ntatkma n thai .1 \ .iikii inn i&gt;( Iriiin ilnif to i-i^ln |Miks per u* ii&gt;: winit-r w In-ill iii;i\ Iijim- little or u&lt;&gt; rtfort or jieM. !■ • 1 1 J • - In lllf ;lliilil\ ill I III' |.|;|||| In nmkl- ■ Illll ;nljllSlllli III to ■ ■■lulu urn*, ilni- |&gt;i'ii&lt;liirin^ UMLxiuiUDi \ \f\&lt;{&gt; under quite ng. Table li iiffortlw .in excel If o I ■•\.iin|ilc u( ili&lt; 4 plutiag in v iilil ;inil m/.i- ut [iliiiu. ■ 1 I SlimrillH fihml Win 1 10 nm 'I'm 1 1 in or. I'JII O-i ■ mi tin- i-tli-ii of r;iti- ni |il;mi iiiL 1 &lt;&gt;u Htttoliny n| iiafn under mliiiniis im iiiililislii'il in Rn I let ill 11:'. "t this Snnum lu-ii- ii-|»-:ili-il EFFECT OF RATE &lt;&gt;F PLANTING ON SIZK Or I 1910-11 1911 Number ■ Numberof Antual YJ( , M Ni planted pl&gt;- P-r hanrested plant htlTMM jgj (.'rams . i 144 m 57« Hi 1 IfJ 1 21' 79 m 217 I M m </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ii typical Kherson oat plains from plat sown at rate of Ifi I'lants ■ !&lt; ties high. At the right art' about nl,alil&gt; will not »urvlve until harvest, or. if th produce mon than ■ in FiK. I are shown the • the unaller plants at harvest time. ks Number ™ , Number S ™' Total yi , , °' Number of tillers ™! number \Jf' rt SS3" P'— o7S^ «"»'•" Pfl. Plants ---- a^ TaKI.K 1.". Shiiilinil (if h h&lt; rxini mils. l!&gt;l)7. I -—of stems" - t Plant. ™;;r ~» per &lt;A( r* CButh II 105 Ml 5:18 ."&gt; 12 160,797 'J* 4 .W&gt; M 7 4J !tls :&gt;!Mi 1.80 »92,2«9 1,406,825 414 tt 613 1075 M! 7."&gt; 938,748 1 ,K«i,255 49- II 7«t I LtM 1, 2&lt;K),til7 1,646,255 44 ■&gt;4:i 1 106 3S - 1,290,970 1,784,081 5o o 44 1042 1210 MB 15 1, &lt;52,994 W.4 14 Ki7li liiil 1 OB 2,1 111 1!MI&gt;. iiiiinls well- Hi, lili- nil llll-t-c lilies of so'ilili^. «ilh tile 'nlli-W i 1 1 ii I'esulls. I'iiiimIs were nillile oil (111 | li h ;| tc |il;ll-. Roth H .Hi- liivell. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Tabu Hi Peck ,-in.ber Total sown exam- of number Numher of til, P* T ined P la ' „,„ of tillers acre on area Tin- Ml |il;ini&gt; lillfii-d abundantl.i when nvi rwj iliin. |&gt;i - " 4 32 229 K&gt;4- -1!&lt; I 57 311,72k 1,421 4 21- l(tt* 7«i 296.752 1,412,977 ;*2 4-&gt; li 1 -&lt;9 582,615 1,6*1,144 ■ H7 1310 -&lt;23 1 S 8H2.929 16 :J2 1180 17H2 »9 l,ia»i,27. ; 16 :12 &gt; 2^ 1593 :(»&gt;'&gt; l,ti71,iil.'i {,188,471 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I. Ill' Jlllllf' I ' " 1 1111*1 * 4 " 1 * &lt; 1 * " * 1 lIlI'Mllv the rate af plaatiaaj was toeraMed, nry few developing - &gt;&lt;\- more pet acre was used. ■ally m&gt; lillcrs developed when li! or M pecka was its have Ims-ii obtained with earn pisata. Kxperimeiit Station liulletin '■•!. page IS.) It is iiinj; thai, whatever the rate of Mediae there waa a g ii-inlem \ for the tliin seedinga to tiller euottijli to l&gt;ring tund up t final. The normal staml s«-«miis to ht alnmt sterna pei acic COMI'KTI I ION OK VAKIKTIKS. lilt of the «'X|K'fiinellt. some ilala were seelllcii show \ tit-it of one variety on another when in competition. lu of winter wheat, the following table shows that in i. inie was sow n alone under the conditioM of \|niiiiieiii . it yielded most. Itnl when sown in cowpetitioa l'nrke\ Ucd the latter was most product ive. 1380 183H 3232 1190 ll-l tion 2f.76 »mf Coni[)Pti- 4TJH 1712 :«fi6 S26 788 tion 257ti In 1911, Tiirkex Bed sown alone yielded more than Hij: Frame 1.x l&gt; per ei-nt. l&gt;iir when in lawpttltloa Turkey Red yielded prartioalh twice as —eh. A practical example of the result of competition under tield conditions is afforde&lt;l by a lor of Rig Frame wheat which has Imi-ii ;rrown continttnllv in a certain «-\pet iini-nt for 12 \t the atglaalaj there ni ■&gt; slijrht TaMJE 17. Competition of rinirlirx thod Number of seeds planted Number of plant* harvested Total yield 11HI* lilll me i9ii 1908 I'M 1 \lone llfSTt! 4.t2M 2Sn 4:i2u 1429 2*Hi 17&gt;M MM I. nun l dram. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Miliiiixiuic of Tuikcv lii-d. Inn the percentage of Tnrkc.v Util li.is jiki-i-hmhI. mini in 1911 practical h '.hi per • -« * 1 1 ■ of the phil Wiic nf this varicn . Bui &lt;&gt;;iis in HUH, whoever tin- black aaia lUarton \\;is nti alone ii &lt; ml \ icldiil iln- white lull when sown iii &lt;-t &gt;iii |m-i i t i«nj llic while reiuim-d tin - \ if hi. In I'.Ml Minilar iCMllta I ired. T M'l I 1 v ' "in /m mi a ilium mill in mi. Yi&lt; lil in i iihil mi" n»ii i 1!M" . t r of plants nut Urai Oartnn N i:«; 121 146 Swedish Select whr m lit; lit: in 1 111 ii" lm Swedish Select white, 141' 111' 106 1S1 I I II IT i&gt; .1 HXplannl imi in i In- estrh liali &lt;&gt;f lllf l\Mi Ml \Mlirlii&gt; Tin blfll'k iii tin' .mmI Make little |tn»*"th in I" a i'|-:il \M-«k&gt;. whili- tin- whiir ckii&gt; iLii.w i - : 1 1 &gt; i 4 1 1 \ in ll i W Inn niiilmi-. bath v;niiliis mii- jiImpiii ill' - ■ iluii ili&lt;- Mil ninw \\i\i habit ul iln- R-hit&lt; vv* it mii initial ftdvaatajrc in num - ■'■•••■ i n baa aJvaya been (fr»»*n rather thin. ~" tin- plant* from &lt;omi|h-i iiion to ■ large extent. Siitunil - thru i-oiii|H-tit ion baa nut bee*, in rilm in order to secure data mi tlif effect* &lt;&gt;I ioin|M-t ii ion in corn a nerien nf |&gt;Imis started in 19(15. nainy IIh^ih- Vellon I •rut ruin and plaatiaaj 1 '! anal I amiaa met liiil Sm.i that I r k 1 in. in. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">&lt;&lt;&gt;mpetilum in Cereals 21 planted coatiaaooalj at the same rate. MM insults for three JWM l»nu*ka Mullet in 1 111. In T.tll. after six rear* coatiMKO* aclectiea, the following results were secured. rl!i. ) i&lt; lilx i&gt;f corn from need grown muler different &lt;■ f ///■ ix yews (1905-1911 ). nrninyeil unonlinij Yield 1911 when planted at three rates Rate of planting umler tWhei-f tin- coru was plauted thin in 1911, namely one grain r hill, the seed from thick planting did iiot show as large raataf" as ia caseti where the planting was three or live sialks par hill. In the latter catte the increased \ ield amounted to 7 •T I bushels per acre. Sl'MMARY AND OONCU'SIONS. tWhilf i lit- cx|«'i-iiii»'iits hav« i not been continued lonp enough justify Una I roin-hiaions. vet the data arc so concordant that • following concliiRiorm seem justified : C\^ iln- rate of planting is increased, the paMHtRfi "f nts Mnrhrtag until harveBt gradually decreases. The total deeTCMB in the experiments described in the preceding pages amounted to .!4 per cent, and the relative survival of the thinnest stand i- inches i and thickest stand I [ inchi averaged TI and ."&gt;»&gt; per cent respectively. There are one-third more survivors in the thinnest stand. •J. \\ hfii liirjre. plump seed are planted in competition with small or j&gt;oorh developed Reeds, the decrease in the number of plants from the large, plump seed is 28, and that in those from the small or shrunken seed 38 per cent, while those from the Knas been | rown per hill . . ts per hill : lull One plant Three plants Five plants per hill per hill per hill BuaheU Bushel* Hushela 26 6 39 8 % 5 27.3 43.7 44.6 29.3 4H.1 45. ti 38.5 41.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 aune yiinl.-^ (.ImukmI :iIi&gt;mc ieonaaal '■&gt;'&lt; par aaart ami 411 |hm respect ivelv. The plants from all graftal *li&lt;&gt;w a marked iltvrease due t&lt;&gt; various causes in addition to coaapetition, bat when tin - tpjaaai an- planted in miii|M*tii ion the atraMBT plants haw advantage in the Dumber of sm-viv Khen two varieties are planted in competition, on. s \cr\ a|&gt;i to ha\i' an advantage, which, if continoed. in tinif I'MiiKc it in |ir;i&lt;'ti&lt;all\ replace tin- other. It ap il&gt;o ili.ii tin- one yielding besi aJoae will not alwi ■ suivivinj; nnder competition. 4. Nature seeora in aan of eliminating tin- »«-ak i iiiiiIit oar preaent »v»te I ■ ereala) uraetker tbe.i from Brpe ar small weda, Simc this i-liminaiion h;is U&lt; n taraaam, ii awa wa\ leeai thai •■ artificial method ol m In fauning mill o mild in &lt;■&lt;■■ \n \\ wince nar nu-thod of t ti i • k allo«&gt; natiiii- to eliminate oik plants i afftitini: the vicld. Ei Aeairabilit.i of Mepnratinj; pure strains i» emphat f.nt that whfti h-ft in wa petition the varietj »&gt;i \ ii-liliT whi'ti |&gt;lai'«-il alum- \uu\ not alwaya doui tl tlicr liaml. a leaa aradactive type nit 1m- bea v&lt;- competition. E'rai lii -a I irsnlls have U-cn sr. nrcil with ran bj under n.in|M-l it i\t- loiidiiioiis. tin- gaia in \ if Id aftci amounting to ahaarf Si pe? eeot. 7. W'lu-rc two varit'tifs have In-«-ii fWWB tagvther in the l»etition |&gt;lats (the aaaia of caih \arii-t\ being alternated), the niixtnii- of tht- two \ miii . idil iIkiii either variet, a..,,,,. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>