<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00035.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00035.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE VETERINARIAN</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">• </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER v, Gover Stock S, or t iiilin 1 s. of Lincoln. Xchr.. January I, l!il~&gt; roor John II. .Moivhead. ami the ? nitiirv Hoard : transmit my second annual report z December .!!. 1014. L. C. EEOIN, (KIM TV STATE VKTKIMNARIAN </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Introduction. Kie State Wt&lt; riiuir\ Depart mi alth of li\&gt;- stock liv iri \ i 1 1 tr &gt;■; IV SIIVIML r IV tow Item have been intro «.&lt;•&lt;! live stork. The to protect the S'ebr tot or physical pxa state In s|ii;^ \ BWolils. vlnilVi lie. a peculiar Ki| n;i r;t 1 1 i-i- aiiioiu . In tracing tfa S t'llllllll tllili mi: Phi tin' state of Wvii No iloulit. other i introduced in a ainni to what extent. This State should Mini mouth disease that pi eiitfal. eastern and 01 The prompt action We our State Li\ e Si promulgating rules that they ei EVilera! Government at South Omal s disinfecting all stock eara in tin lost important part in preventing t nee into this State. ■v rattle is of the most extreme imp&lt; velocity of its apread and the dange I vailing orgaiiigiiiK tlmt i of live stix-k annually t has been pro\ en on Mii|&gt;;&gt;f&lt;l in I r&lt; Mippoaetl to I As in tin- diseases thai prevai </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 specially of dairy and thoroughbred ill is test will be seen and accepted only apidly as the test is accepted, just that provided more sanitan proper attention. the most relial le test in existence at well as this State, hut • H its adoption in this State. If th - ivill mean uun-li additional testing a&gt; the &gt;c ijrreatly reduced. The reason is time and trouhle that must lie _ Wl The regulation of the Nebraska requiring all reartors to be Hranded jaw. has been a move in the pi his knowing that this animal had i!t its deathly I low to the swine growen tention lias been &gt;ri\eii towards U» 1 eradication by the Nebraska Live 8 ir State employes. Tile Board dee! Iple of men ill the field, to educate the method of vaccination and importai \l rating vaccination, over the State, farmers. Dr. J. ('. Bowman of t the Government force in the rthern half of &lt;iasre and all ii M-incipally looked after the sanitary end No work was done along this line until th&lt; N'o doubt, but the last two years' work will stimulate i&gt;t tw xt two years, additional. 11 tile 11 &gt;\e the value of the work that has benefit anti-hog cholera serum has given over rted to by many of our live - ra-dermal test is being eapwinwted |M&gt;8Kihle for a rt-iii'tiir to be mM Omaha, \\;i&gt; appointed to give ''•* </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Mate is impossible. However, potent serum used pi has proven its efficiency. Tin- statistical report tliat the Nebraska Live Stock Sanita Hoard hopes to have in the next two year •rt results, will enable them to be in a position t&lt;&gt; giv&lt; a public some very valuable information (Handera has been found in thirt Glanders lias been found in thirty inulp&gt;. the past year. All of these an mules, the past year. All of these animals were appraise/ killed. Two-thirds of their appraised value was paid bJ killed. Two-thirds of their appraised to the owner. This disease dot tu tin- owner. This disease does no1 &gt;e&lt; n particular Ketioa of the State. The particular section of tin- State T tered throughout the Mate. Tin- reim IW such animals, undoubtedly has been o such animals, undioulitedly ha information thai gave us a eiue in !in information thai gave US a Km- the past two .wars, we haw- not si- upon any premise. Mullein testing of all horses and sanitation has. undoubtedly, been re« report. Cattle si-aliies iii tile western pa report. Cattle scabies in tin- wi reduced to the miniin-om. Kitrht yean \ in quarantine and at the prenent t in quarantine and at remain in quarantine, with a few ncatt remain in quarantine, with a w Animal Industry must be given Animal Industry must eation of this disease. I'lifortunatly. cation of this disease. I nfortunatly. tile &lt; pelled to withdraw all their force o pelled to withdraw all their foi hraska plains, and send then east to fiirht t hraska plains, and send them east to disease. We hope the &lt; ioveninieiit wil I of men. to assist in the complete erad The Nebraska live Stock Sanits dii|&gt;loyes in the field the past sprinj. inspeetora, in supervising the dipping of men. to assist in the complete cradi The Nebraska Live Stock Sanita \ employes in the field the past sprii X cattle. The Board experts to continue its cooperation 10 evei manner possible with the Government until this mm eradicated. Anthrax made its appearance on twn occasions was discovered by Dr. Edttingfield of l'laiuview. Nebraska Dr. McKini of Norfolk. Nebraska. Ms </seg>
            <seg id="p007">&gt;■ f I Nebraska. Tin- seeoad ease was discovered tn exist near Benson, Nebraska. Through pasture the disease abated near without vaccination, but the outbreak near ntrolled by vaccination and also sanitation. ■t- of black leer throughout The State, have Department. The (ioverninent vaccine has it upon each call, from the State Agricultural ami under this method, the disease has difficulty. re poisoning has aKo been reported from p.cially the past fall. The usual advice -tuck from the corn stalks or to make a when it would 'be due to molds, ete., or and mowed away report, you will note that we imported 147 stallions. W jacks. 6,013 cattle. 1&amp;R •1 We exported HU44 horses, 1,OM mules, «\!»ti&gt; cattle, 1,836 lioyis and "&gt;♦►:? sheep, made upon this Department is constantly ,-,.. daring the i&gt;ast year, two additional the pay roll by the Nebraska Live Stock n spite of this, we have managed to our appropriation. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AN'NTAL REPORT in INTERSTATE SHIPMENT OF LIVESTOCK report, show tin Imports Horn Mule Exports Mule stal Jai-l ('••in s FINANCIAL REPORT reuloMK &lt; 1 u !•! n -_r Hu- y«*ar 1914 Total ii ittu i H i- of i-ati li- tcstei Nil s S'nmber of cattle shipp* N'nniiiei- nr reactors found Diiiry c;ittle nhipped from VV Niinilier of reactorx Found \,U \ Tiic record* mi file in this Stalin Jar las Ciitt!.- Hogi Folio wini XuiiiIht killed at I Total number killei Dairy rattle imported fr I Vumher of reactors found </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 2 slowly down the mountain Bide, i-n slowly bnt rarely very nation as well •u it r;i n s\\ lilt hare of the disease. How- ii-r that the cattle of this State arc not as general- other states. The reasons for this new State in the dairy industry tution possible has been pot forth the different State Veterinarians as toek Sanitary Hoard, since its exist- ealtliy. tuberculin tested dairy and State we no doubt have been imposed upou era. At this time. 1 wish to mention place lasi February. Three hundred il into tiie northwest section of this Genoa Junction, Wis. A quarantine st following revealed seventy- ,n!y one of the many attempts, by dit'f. X.-hraska law. fice. I gave much thought as ootrolkng this disease. I soon real - v given, not only to the dairyman only way I could accomplish nows the efficiency and value of the i: proving its accuracy, we must be lenient who do not know or realize the necessity iiiry herds of this country, in order to elimin :,e test. h mm into all channels ii tiiis subject that moM &gt; very •ontaffioua ;iml infectious lilom affeeted. owing to s made umWr proper conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 I have often times placed myself in puss. - dairy eattle and wondered it' 1 would permit a vet make a test on such herd, if I were not aware of tli li»ease to tlie human family. I believe that eve makes a tuberculin test should place himself in this i sitiiui so that it would stimulate him to try ami ex dairyman more fully, the reason why sin-h tests shoiil rinana I v I pla We must remember the dairy this business to make :i laii'-ia other man conducting his usines*. whatever it may time, we cannot wonder why he so seriously objects to hi herd tested and abide l&gt;v he --on In my opinioi al aaed that an obligation M\s .i'-tion or so more for n appropriate an indemnity n tiiat are condemned. I do not presume that it homes in this country, wl infected milk consumed Arc we to allow this condit way in which the people :ls a \\ seriousness of this disease.' I do believe that it the way that I have in mind to the lesions in an animal that ha disease. Again, there an- tit few State, who realize the unsanitary method in which the portion of milk is handled. The most gratifying work that I have d charge of this department, is the motion pictures tl taken pertaining to this subject. I feel quite tare that th&lt; tit t results obtained from money spent was andoubt v idoi line of work. I am in a position to see the results that hav come from showing Mich pictures in different towns over tli I^Th t •* a lid i i* I k nt* w t li a t 1 whs t * * ivmih i n in t In** • 1 i (•ring the price the dairyman is pt danger of tubercular u a living man t&lt;&gt; estinu </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Y 1 V A w ii tr that a ii l ii i xpenel \v;in |nv\ i-lltll &lt; &gt;iii- year too y would continue along educational to state that I do not feel that we wi the line of tontrollisg and eradicatin the sentiment and co-operation of tli write and talk until there will he noth inir to this siilijeet. Hut seeing is l)elie\ contend that the people must lie show iiis evil or they will not join the fi Tuberculin Testing of Cattle. &gt; be encouraged, (iovernmeut and Statt reliable in !»', of aH .-mscs. When w« •ulin is not always used in the most scientific yinjr to know the hijrh percent of accuracy iri\ iiiL' an animal a thorough physical exam - g test U beiaf realized by all veterinarians. ii &gt;• preliminary temperatures and five post temperatures reveal the condition f jecting the toberenlio and the five post tcm - ry two hours, covers a period of time suffi- t em pen tare to ■ defree that would war animal. ipe and cK-sire that time would; afford me ■&gt; on the experiments with the intradernial which would satisfy me as to its accuracy ave usc-d this test on •"&gt;&lt;¥) cattle in conjunc- liar thermal test and in most eases the results owing to the lack of similarity in certain e Kseoarsging but later 1 discovered that it was relative to the technie of inakintr this nilar results. I sent a circular letter from this department, veterinarians in this State use the intrad^rmal i with the thermal, in order to gain information n making such test. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 If this test proves to radical .mi tested a* It Wl on the part of the veterinarian aa well as the expenai It was my desire t&lt;&gt; bav iiitraclerina .ist year at the time \v iHtion Meeting but ow tiiat time we were unable to State Veterinary M 11 ir tn tin' inelemeney ot w fiml a suitable place to can f ltauli- pla&lt; sf na&gt;- existed in ' ent time. Tin- only way that I \ \\ unify the owners of such porting all suspicious cases that hi and tested, provided that a te*l was ileeint mine if the suspected animals were affet-ted witl \[ .1 iii- t 1 1 1 1 1 'S *&lt;ll^l)l(*lolls t'Jlscs 1 1 1 1 \* t • I) I* t*n 1***1 Hil'T cm \\" [1 many hundred additional eatl having Mich test math II I ICilauderM an infect ioiu i\ !i to be Iran &gt; an annual a A&gt; .\ «»ii will m&gt;t.- !i We roiisidiT till' li State. In looking over |&gt;&lt;i&gt;t iip&lt; more pxteiiKive in tliU i!i.- appropriation that baa know thai they "ill In- rehnhwrs Buy- Mispieioua f *f« report ■id two-thirds of the appr i eertainly feel very much ind State for their valuable ro-op&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">l:: hi ( t.iiiii-i ti&lt; hi iind I'l-.-iciici'd hi New inn (ii Clamlcrs in Ortobar, 1911, he Fmcf &lt;n ■ Wteriiiai-y Siirm-on Win. </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">15 «• Reactor </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 ISllfSS s I i \v xatioi i\ }■ By I I Tot a From A i i Myvotic Lymphangitis or diseased In my opinion, the genera] public do not realize the danger It has been proven by many able tentinies a man was affected with this disease een improperly diagnosed and was being ■r iliso;iM\ In conversing with many people t. 1 have found that there are only a few disease is dangerous to the human family. iserting ■ photograph of a veterinarian who I am also inserting a photograph of a realtor. This animal had ulcers on the sep- indurated subinaxillary glands. hiring the past \&lt;;\r 47 samples of blood have been sent nt and forwarded to Washington for the com- Thirty-five samples reacted to the test and mules were immediately appraised and (Is of their appraised value which was paid to y 1st. 1914, to April 1st, 1914. the following num- destroyed and paid for out of the $30,000 i. Minium 1913-1914. Iward Miller Dwatur 1 Dr. U M. Walker Deeatur h;i&lt; (-"lowers 1 Dr. K. ('.. Pieman iMcGrew •&gt; 1 1st. 1!&gt;14. to -Inly 1st. 1914. the following num - rere deatrsjvd and paid for out of the $30,000 or the hienniuin 1013-1914. mini: to •&gt;-_ &gt; T42.T."&gt;. )wnors Name Address 8 t °ro&gt;^" R™""^! </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Owners Name Address No D+ Amount 8troy-»d Receiv Amount carried forward \pril 14, 191 4 1 John Berrigan Ewing Neligh By Dr. McXare Men. :{0. 1914 W. S. lusher Newport Norfolk Minatar.- McGrew ) By Dr. MrKim limn 10. l»1 • S. C. Shaul By I)r Pieman XI r. Hurnap HarrisburK McGrew Bj Dr. I'inman Erom July 1st, 1!H4. to October 1st, 191-1 F hones were destroyed and paid for priation for the biennium 1913-1914 Amk Owner's Nanin Addr. No. I st roved K Amount carried forward Minatar McGrew By Dr. B. Q. Pieman Sept. 1, 1914 Ross Goethe Lttchfleld Lincoln LttchfleM lii!K*'llll July 29, 1914IS. A. Shaul tBy Dr. F. H. Davis 4 Ross Goethe Bv Dr F H Davis </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 By I n ( &gt; \ I I o, 1 Rtroyed Received 14 Standard Oil Co. Lincoln ', 1 13 1 14 Stewart Ley master Litchneld ... 1 i By Dr. F. H. Davis Lincoln A. ('. Remau - schneider Codv l Ian. 1. 1914. to Oct. 1, 1!M4 .,,, 1&gt;t. 1!&gt;14, td December -llsx, 1914, the following wen destroyed ami paid for out of the $30,000 the luenniiun 1913-19(14 Owner's Nmne Address No. De- Amount stroyed | Received ried forward 12^21 Geo. Ii;itt Lincoln 1 &gt;r K H. Davis Lincoln I. Hums B. Co. Omaha. Dr C. C. Hall Omaha. Neb. 1 Neb. Robs i. Litchneld . 1 83. Dr. John Boyd Mason City. .lacob i Lincoln 1 Dr M I Kelley Lincoln Name Address *«• D* m0 . unt . &lt;;ibson Reynolds _ 1 V Bostrom Lincoln I CMhaoa Reynolds 3 | 300.00 F. H. Davis l.iinoln \V. Carrineer Lincoln :) Dr. U C. Kigin Lincoln Bv Dr. L. C. Kigin Lincoln By Dr. F. L. Reed Cody ■U.I. Hums B. Co. Omaha. Neb. 1 83.33 By Dr C. c Hall Omaha. Neb. • IIS. Leymt l.itchtield 1 X.66 By I&gt;r. John Bogrd Mason City. liy Dr lolin Boyd Mason City. '14 C Anderson Stromsburg . 1 73.3^ By Dr. M. L). Strong Stronisburg .. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 1 ■ Foot and Mouth Disease ■The most contagious disease known that affects can s. ether ruminants and swine and occasionally the him The I'nited States lias sever experienced Nek ■ leriou break of this disease as the past year. Five previous out have visited this country '.iiit were controlled and held liounds of a small territory, in comparison with the 1!&gt;14 outhiva The live stock growera of Xebraska should feel moi irratefiil to the work of our Live Stock Sanitary Hoard immediate action in pawing rules and regulations eontrollii shipments into this state from free territory as well as | rigid (|uarantine asrainst any shipment i-arrv the infection into the midst of tin- stock trowing indust of Nebraska. We must not forget to expi i-nt nihvays operating in tli tate tor tion and assistance in preventing this dis. - n gaining trance. When the Nebraska Live Stuck Sanitary Boan order that all stock ears within th di-infected. as well as all utv railroad companies immediately pi icction, to comply with such denial The South Omaha itoek yards eompi ter of appreciation to the Nebraska Live 8 if appreciation to the Xilira^kii Live for their commendable work, which heir roamfiwlahlr work, which i-cm.1v South Omaha, X Smith Omaha, Mr. -Tas. II. Balk, Prett. Live Stock Sanitary Boai Mr. Jas. H. Balk, 1'ivsY. Livo Stock Buitary Board. Kxcliansrc Bailding. Exchange Building Rulla : r Mr. Rulla : It srivcs in.- considfi-alili- pleasure to with a set of Resolutions unaniniouslv adopted at the A Meeting of our Kxchange held jreaterdaj This should mean considerable to you. for it came froi people with the heartiest of good will. Untold losses would ha\ occurred to the Xebraska stockmen had the foot and mouth di </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 s .VIIKKKA ■V1IKKKA ( IT K.I \ May w Ma Inv lireil to til within our state. This one case will in- the liiiirlit sputs lit' your a&lt;l miiiist ration of the Signed Secretary-Traffic Manager. Board adopted by tlif South Omaha The South Omaha market and the State of ar escaped the hoof and mouth disease, and. A great deal of credit for this is due Owum in .1. II. Bulla. State Veterinarian L. ('. Kiarin. nliers of tlie Nebraska Live Btoek Sanitary rompt action and their very effii-ieut work in intine regulations which made a irreat saving iidustrv in the State of Nebraska, therefore SOI.VKD, That the South Omaha Lixe Stock Bi - ll meeting assembled, do hereby extend a vote of •loliii II. Moivhead. Chairiiian .1. II. Bulla, L. &lt;'. Kiirin. and the other neafcan of the Stork Sanitary Hoard, for their very efficient at a t'opy of these resolutions be spread upon v furnished to eaeh of tin- above mentioned iking its appearance in the states of Iowa, Kansas, the possibility of preventing its entrance ired very irrave at one time, hut owinsr to the in s plaeed by State offieials mi siii-h infei-ted ter - ites mentioned, they were abk to control its ill join and extend coiiirratulations to the offi meiiti d states for tlieir efficient work. ■ this state, fearing that the disease existed in their ation revealed, in most every ease, that the ani - \ebraska stockmen had the foot and mouth dis- A. F. STKYKKK. itive k» tin- Xebraakta State Kxchange, .lainiarv 8th. 1!&gt;1"&gt;. were s.'iit in to this department by different </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 ln-fii prevaleni in this State for a number of yean tion has hcfii paid to its occurrence until the foot an ease prevailed M extensively, at which that reports would be forthcoming if an animal of ■ ML'lis of sore ill oil 1 1) or feet The main difference in th w riooa wars- However, the two diseases ha .Vt Ow or two iiniinals of ;i herd showing ioi &lt;»ne or two animals of a herd Knowing sore mouth and feet wit ,Y out additional animals contracting same ii out additional animals contracting same is a ven g lie Is a Vd-\ tliai they are not affected with the eon&lt; that they are not affected uith the contagious foot and inout disease. Myeotk' Stomatitis is caused by i ■ttitis is caused nv a tuniri emit f 1 eaten, usually in the dry summer an \ muz/.le ! econie* dry. cracks open and b] form in the month and contain a broi muzzle eeoiiie* dry. crack* open and bleed* verv read v form in the mouth and contain a brownmh or \ and tin- saliva wliii-h drips From the :. also tlic Feet swell ami have i ten I. also the feet swell and have a tendency to anreai The teats lieci Tin- teats become reddened ami peel of -' . tin- sali\ a is \ ery clear and has a nee. when observed in sunlight. Ah a pearance. when observed in guiilig smacking sound in this disease mail. smacking sound in t which is characteristic of this particular It seems to In- very puzzling to inan.v which is eliaraeteri It seems to lie very puzzling t v and exposed animals an killed when sn mouth diaeaae. a* it is pos«,il&gt;!r for aniu mouth disease, as it i "••■i't nt when affected. Hut we must r treat nt when affected. Mm w ot this disease doe* not confer immunity roold apparently recovei boi eootii of this disease does in Ml rould apparently reeovei bat eontii feetion, similar to a ease of walking typh&lt; rtile l&gt;e.-( • reinfected throuajfa anothei i tllelllseh Cs. Considering tin !n^ of milk, wast,- Considering the loss of milk. \\ expense of nursing, as u, expense of iiiu-sinir. ; , N w ,.\\ as BBC j, ;m ii ll;l i I'm- breeding purposes, it is deemed advisal for breeding purposes, it is deemed adviaahle bv our areal B of Animal Industry to He the most profita uid re sari to sanitary measures in pletely eradicating this diaeai The foot and mouth disease, as p By eradicating this disea he foot and mouth disea » the luiniHii family through drinking </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE VKTKHINAKIAN 23 n in infected areas by property pasteuriz- . it leaves comparatively bo danger of the nan health. Hog Cholera. Sanitary Board tVlt the nrrraaitj of placm in tiiis stall- to lecture to aaaembled bodies of farm- ture tn assembled bodies of farro- tieular disease. &gt;ince they realized that the liest re sr disease, since they realized that the hest re- accomplished by education and demonstration, I) ar.oiiiplislied by education and demonstration. Dr. South Omaha was appointed to take charge of this ■South Omaha was appointed to tak&lt;- charge of th ver in t-hia report. Dr. Day lias given a Iragth tni-r over in this report, l&gt;r. Day lias fives a lengthy n this iHsiiiM . Therefore, 1 am depending upon h - . Therefore, I am depending upon his er this disease in every detail. However. 1 a tort sent me by Dr. 8. K. Coaford, Government I irire id' the i-o-operative beg cholera eradieatk orthern half of &lt;ia«;c and ail of -loliuson countie in this report tiiat on a out the 1st of May. 1!»1 n half of Gage and ail of Johnson counties report tiiat on a out the 1st of May. 1!»14 man was aatuffDed by our Board to a&gt;siM in mm was awuirned by our Board to a&gt;sUt in rack were principally to look after the clean-up of ties were principally to look after the clean-up &gt; tMiUKeg ami stork yards as well as to supervise U i'led. .'■&gt; and slock yards as veil as to Hiperviae san - opled. t inserted will speak for the good results o!itaiiie&lt; When we consider tin- extra work that vai M will speak for the good results obtained When \\c consider the extra work that Wai in - -wine irrowcis in this i|iiar - ini/e and educate the twine growera in this qoa ml educate tl ii. it pannot hf douhteil that vaccination ami Ban have eiiefited this section 1»X&gt;',. iiani/ation complete, it is evident this ro-operath &gt;ii that vaccination and aani- etion 1&lt;H»«; miization complete, it is evident this ro-operatire urk will prove the efficiency of anti-hog choler fieiency of anti-hog cholera will pro dininisteied under such aanitary prerantiom, (1 under li sanitary precautions Reports show tl at ■ i&lt;_'ht million dollars worth of swine died liow that eight million dollars worth of swine dice from this dreadful disease. Therefore, we sincere swine irrower* in this qoarantiaed area will s.'i\ dreadful disease. Therefore, we tin ■OWl rative body in charge of this which will lm a long ways towards preventing such an ontr wavs State, as above mentioned. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 DR. L. C. KKilX. Deputy Stan- Veterinarian Lincoln, N Beatrice, Nebr., Feb. 7. 1913 1!»1 Dear Doctor: I am in receipt of lettei from Acting Chief of Hi" I .nil iii receipt of lettei from Acting Chief of Biocl Division df the Bureau of Animal Industry, stating there ia •ion to furnishing your office with information eontaii Division of the Bureau of Animal Industry, statin in annual report i&gt;t' work done, result*, rt&lt;-.. in hog cholera con1 and eradication work, in Northern Gtage and Joknaon eoontie*. and eradication work, in Northern G-asre and John n be aaed in making up your annual report. You have ■ copy of my report n&gt; the Chief of Bureau be used in making up your annual report You have ■ eopy of my report to the Chief of Bureau mal Industry covering the work up to December 31, 1!U4. T mal Industry covering the work up to December 31, 1!U4. 'I report embodies practically all the information you d&gt; - report embodies practically all the information yi yon can use what yon nee fit of it. In order to assist you xnii can use \\ha1 vo mine readily the hogx (riven "serum alone.'" and herds mine readily tin with both "serum alone*' and "serum simultaneout with both "serum the following tabulation : Herds Treated With Serum Alone Hog No. Herds Trea U&lt;; 1.104 with hiyh t with norii Total IK 2,269 Herds Treated With Both Serum and Serum Simultaneo Treatment i rMMini siimilt 1 Total Numbers Treated 70 6.408 with high tempera 6.837 with normal tem|ieramr( 13.24 Vou will note that we treated onlv hoes ii That the entire loss in 13245 I \V; i That the loss o: simultaneously treated (normal h&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 1 high temperature hogs treated. t n herds treated with serum alone, i that these were the smallest herds, as a rule, and January 1st. 1!&gt;14. and the date we beau treatment 1«H4 thirty-four farms in this territory. Daring the remainder sixteen farms upon which the disease had v abated before we were notified, and no treatment wu vY ted during the year 37O herds, or tile :S70 herds vraa teeond treatment on the same t'arn: Department Of the eleven farms on which the tied, five had been eleaned and diaiafeeted ndw \&gt;v. -I. ('. Bowman. I beliere that infection which ■arance of disease i&gt; four of the five pj ined. was bronght on later. ip pea ran akes 4&lt;&gt;!i infected premises in this territory. One huu- M-ty ..; these have been cleaned ud disinferted under \ e farms have been cleaned up by the owners lisinfectans used, but the Live Stock - put a man on tin' job. as soon as weather eon - . to give supervision to the cleaning and dis- way of having a thorough job done. started work in cooperation with this Sta- May, 1014. It took about a month to eom - ritory along the border. Later it took some C. Bow he disinfection of the Railroad Stock Yards. at the Railway Stock Yards in this territory Below oiniujr. which it was thought necessary to clean and dis- They have all been cleaned and disinfected, with the ex- Hoair. (iraf. and Johnson on the Burlington. This was e Burlington, but duo to the muddy condition of ne yards at Hoag, at the time. And Graf, and Johnson being on i B. R. Division that had not been lined up to do the work. \nd Inter we were so busy that it was neglected. ■a had appeared and practically atat- ipproxinuit.lv 270 infected farms yet to be il&gt;le to give the farmer valuable ti </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Railway Stock Yards r. r. i. * v. i. n i q. Mu. I'iK x Hal lam \l)e Witt XI llOHRI Heatrict Brock. Talma xClatonia. ii &gt;t clea x Plymouth xKMis. xHeatrici Rockfor xFlllev. "li yards. Hur Beatrice Don xRockford Vir .xVirsinia. Levteton. Mayberry. Steinauer Note. An ' ■ x The mat before the name, si the weather is fax orahlr. A ivairmi chute and rards. and then- wuiiM he aii\ (ritjectin lointr this, him! it trill do ;i appearance of their utock \;n t" the farmers alone lines of \. ind (lisiiitcctioii of private stock yard* '-•cm seen and advtaed tluit their y»nU •at 1 i|iicsti(in if -h hiis been ac-eoni| \ of the l.i\c Stuck Kaniti att.'f w;is not issue. 1 until July 1st. 1!H4 Master. Mo. I'.-n-. li tile \irdtl \\;l&gt; &gt;,, (i f»\ OF Of U Ililr-W ;|&gt;|i Nothing in particular li;i I\C&gt;|HM-t I'll S. K. ( ■« &gt;sFi &gt;li'l </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 I \ 1 \ \ \ I ,\ \\\ r.\TK I.IVF II. .Mo i xliiliil.-il at tin' St;it&lt; nher. 1M14 Notice did you brinj tin- fairJ fa Wll Wllll e i &gt;;i rt i.-N D.-.-ii \ iii-i-i- mi iilonc tr.-iit- .■uiis treat- Tow TARY HOAIJD STIH'K SAN "&gt;4 rxhilii the Stat.- Fair. who &gt;«-iit in the ul exhibited at iii.l ?!• lit'ii.l at it •■\iiiiiiti-il. liv th were 111 the St;it.- Kiii Fair. -Ml wen Lini-iilii. Nebraska •&gt;.•]&gt; uiKWer tin 1 follow mir of tiu- Stiit.- Wt.rin- ic piirfMMM 1 is to ;i»ist in controlling it may orifnoate a&gt; a renul1 of trana- respoiinbility will be plae«1 on ;iny occur. :ing !i&lt;i'-l&lt; to your herd from the fair! t tit 1 iiildTf».-s of all partita n&gt; wham in tlir \"r raatka State Pair Grounds. Atkkem: State Fair. 241 ivhil.- :*&gt;!• \v&lt; iv reported sold </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 ,\ tit tin- iiuii u luivi' name .in it tin- fair, mi nit tlie llankti and return to t In- De-nut v State X Notice to Swine Growers In cud n:i tn or from tl State lions,.. I No re»|Ktlis K 1 of s\v llii lii&gt; iWte » after von iv i i\ in j our herd '. How ImiL' a did tin' other in within twi'h e iiioiitha '. I- within one mile of voiir tune witinii six iiioiitii» previnua to mi your premises When, if at all, have you u ■ us treatment in vour herd \\ Have vim received into \ The total uuuiWr vaccinated lief» Total vaccinated with serum alone, 1(12. T •inntiMl with tin- niiiuiltaneoiis method, 1*1. Ti Mitt. -d. 2&gt;7 &lt; Mi Sc|&gt;tciii!n-r 2"&gt;ih. ! i l.i nk notice* to xwiiie &lt;.T"« &gt; ill LilICO KitniL' the t wiiii* miirli low 1 1 1 &gt;_r iii t &lt; &gt; i - g i j .- 1 T i f;is tin- llog ni Pair from Al healthy up t« t Was I I l;is i here Iweii miv hits herd ' Wlnii did v&lt;&gt; or bogs) you received from the fa If i iii in u 1 1«-&lt; 1 . which method was used </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 r.\ I i I :\ I it \ 47 rej it*,- than tin- Nebraska State Fair? &gt;r answer tin- above questions same as I'clW ■County State us iii your herd within 15 days, after ify this iit'fic Deputy State Veterinarian By order of the IK LIVK STOCK SANITARY HOARD. ■e last notice* sent oat, w« reeeiTed 47 of ,is requested, although a number were re - ni delivered, owing probably to incorrect aiiL'e from September 28th to October 12th, who reported their hogs healthy, while 4 k. one report states that the hog got siek in mly one to get sick, and it died from pneu - )ii. Another report states that '2 hogs got i a Kvere &lt;-oiijrh and three days later, one ad eongfa but also states that all reeoTered. lima] siek when it arrived home, hail a bad i-dieiiie from the veterinarian, and the ani- rouble was caused by the animal get '(Hindu and sleeping in wet sand. No other tiler report showing sic-k hog states that ay*, was first in herd to get siek. no others nature nor eause of sickness, as the aui limed it did not have the cholera. Two vports. whether their hog&gt; were sick ed hog cholera within one mile of their ported that it was not. ports, thirty-eight reported that their hogs tnd Him- reported that their hogs were vac- 1 vacicnatiou with serum alone and six od. There wew 10 reported as buying </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 \ toga from any other x months, ami eleve ttn thi&gt; eountry by an iuiportatioi i ilnulit. the disease existed for n M \ From tin- original p kiv"&gt; not inuiiiuif, and 22 otl were liniininril. five reported that tlir Imgs wcif linn There were tliiri year 1S33. The find oiithr vi-ar in the St;itr of &lt; &gt;hio a in ii this country. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 tlit- rnited States ami it now prai-ti - worhl. Tlic .-(Mitral Inited States, a n states, is tin- part most largely af- i. owing to the large number of hogs Because of the scarcity of corn in the I'nited States, and the limit.-d transportation. «• hog indiistrv was slow to advance westward. alfalfa and other hog food, the swine tdnally gained a foothold as far west as the Along with it hog cholera has steadily and (I way westward, until now there is scarcely mi that does not have an occasional outbreak therefore absolutely necessary for Live Stock and State Officials to make rigid rules and ing tlie transportation of swine from one suffer enortnOtM losses from this dreadful di&gt; - lateil that the State of Nebraska lost W &lt; worth of Iiol's during the year VM'-i. there - .nut of money expended by the state in &lt;-oni - and educating the people as to the best iiieth- seciiis very insignificant in comparison with and the number of hogs that can be - ire pursued. Cause of the Disease. ised by a irerm or microbe that is prevalent when they are sick. The germ is so small iv the most powerful microscope now in use pwn mi any known media now in Me for j •oratory. We know it is a living organism of •. when we inject virus (the blood from a iii is called virus i into a pig that is wa - it will contract the disease. Hut when we wit from a sick pig to heat and boil it for a few ii in.jet-t it into a susceptible pijr. the animal . showing the germ has been killed by boiling. ,vii fact that heat is the greatest disinfectant in t iTet </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 i \ Disease ,\ ,v i u or a i \ Krld am! genus or microbes ill 1.,- killed. That is why infected bv boiling. '•hi-onic form atv usually sii ami then th.-v are immune Owing to tin- t'ai-t tiiiit hogs do not oaec ha\intr an attack of it. no ma they can be protected against an einating. Paasiag anti-hog eholera n protects or immnnes kin t from 2 to t&gt; weeks. When riroa o small iloscs. is passed tkroufth a h againat cholera for a lifetime. Km i&gt; I iinii-rrcimvnt (lix-ii^f an ttaek of it. and recovers, it \\i nog cholera is Dot caused in an duetion o &gt;u into tin- blood in tin- disease, and it "ill not prodi into the blood or system of ■ Imir t diseas.-. or is inmmin- against it. Th t.i ilu whiit w i ran tn pi iiitu our line's hy noi u ! g t'cir T i : !••-»- WVeks. .11 to the herd either Nature of the IloL r cholera i&gt; ;i con-tapi » the only anima i witl tlii- acute Mini chronic. T i|iiirkiy and severely. run« its irw i-oiintry very rapidly. It - . iio^ ■ttack'etl I siially fron ■^ ut' the disease. The ehronic form is j«i&gt;t ;i&gt; trul wore ilowly ami is not »&gt; extrei </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 liirl \ Ante-mortem Symptoms. ire characterized by a high da i. weakness and depression. Then Hour seven to t&lt;'ii days from the in into its system until it a] Yet, if the temperatnrc is taken, it will ,i Fever in :! or 4 days, which dries oweli and causes constipation. The ,\ days, when the constipation glTCS I t'ew days do not care to eat. they lie nd when driven up. start oft' witli a • L r ait. If a sick pig is ranght, it will emit . They appear very gaunt, have an ar Post-mortem Symptoms. nditions shown on the internal f tile disease. n order to hold a sick animal should he selected and it tile throat. Lay the which will often show in from the neck aloai lar vein xainine the skin Make an incisi ween the hind leffi hum's are the first . which will expose the organs to he examined, and passing liackward. iind ]&gt;ink in color. In large and small, which nd of the carcass ift. spongy pots appear, both uill blood vessels, allowing the blood next organ to lie examined, hut, as a rule, effect of the disease, in acute cases there &gt;n the outside, hut these are not always or melt is the next organ, lying .just of the stomach. This is a very the diagnosis of hoy; cholera. It is usually ted. dark in color, soft and easily hroken animal lias ■ very tad, d« </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 u n. Sometimes there appears la i mi the spleen, often the s|mt&gt; are bla Be tixue. This is a positive indicat le liver is an ornn that does fhance in this diwase and it is st-raci nei'tion. The large intenth in rhronic i-holera .ml ureas veil n vpll. SIIIhII Illci'l's 111 ilways aff lilS. Wllll arc in tl linn in t- in ii r;i 1 it urder ti in every animal, tin »j tin-.- of tl Hog Cholera Control In order for ln&gt;y:s to beeomi luti-ly licci-ssjirv that they gel tl \inis. ami where it arrows ami K' r ' 111 size fro ll-il. li-Mtlli-n ■ii\v exadittf neons mi-Hi Bin- kidneys ;iiriu&gt;si&gt; i»f number of them should In- found ii gVKtem. or into their blood, whicl tin- hoirs from coming in contact « •k. and by practicing utrici Fai _'i'i'in ii\\;iv from tlirm ani fill- 1 1 Wi'Jl si- IlnU'rVri' ll I t* r s &lt; ■ I t i * 1 1 111111 ■ ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">\TK VKTKR1XARIAN 35 • il. tin- si.-k 01 &gt; 'in.-, iinil the well ones given tin r vaeeinated with tin- aiinultaneon mil. I lii- taken and nil tboar showing fiven tlii- serum alone, as i &lt;mv those showing vrii tin- serum alone, as a cur rature of Ics* than lt&gt;4 should reeeiv HI. The Use of Serum i Use of Serum. in is usi'il for two purposes— to &lt;-ur vaeeinate those that are well. W'hil tor two Mirim- s tn nire d &lt;is ii fine it is recommended ••liiist ho^r eholera. Whin scrum alon Wlii-n Hern ill alum i-ii il becomes sick it will produce immunity ici-iiiiifs liek it will produce immunii In six weeks, called p&lt;issi\c imiiiiuiitx tin- wruni will pans n(( and th six weeks, called passive immunity rum will pass off and tin- L-eptible t&lt;&gt; eholera, but it is useful i &gt; chnlrra Hs.-llll 111 i rimiiii.-nilfd in riisi^ .if very vain very valiu tin for short |&gt;. -rinds while used fo rum alone is not followed by an Is Willie 1 owed by an.v n L'i'iiiis and can not .-aiisc the disr;i&gt;. Simultaneous Method. ltaneous Method. a. ■.■iiiation is tailed tin- aiiuultaneoi illed in.ji-i-t in&lt;r ■ ilosc of siriiiii and a iloa »f serum and a &lt;l . tli.- wruni at one ■■lid of tin- &lt;t ni ma iiiimal •r end. The virus has a tendency t a tendency to iul the serum prevent! it and the eon K animal pauses what is railed a r imal causes what is called a diiri'd is immunity and should last f&lt; &gt;i&gt; method, however, is that aboi .•inatcd eontraei a ease of eholera an ul.l last for aae of cholera and •n&gt;.&gt; scatter the genus on 1 1 1 * - premis nay spread the dia- When an animal imiir tarn ination. with the siniul- t' sernin alone in it the animal well again. As previously stated. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">I 36 I rv. I n K'4 \ I IV 1 1 1 1 1 Ik&gt; consider eg or above . for the pur| ■mil UK in i ruin. |-i-&lt; i ; ti n Wllil-ll is 111! till Kiitr sii-km lilt. -(I ll\ tin- i-oiitatcuui I'll II, c w vai'cin iluiii from f, MKM-eftsfullv UK tlii'in tu ;i | • of tlie ear. When \ ai-cina takeu in urtit-r to noi iuaeri t it' tiiis is dour, swelling am illtril H eland Double Method Iicit is another niftlnMl of \ii hisrlily for valuable hops and to mei ■ •(insists in iri \ in ir the Beruni first and tlu-i nerds Ik icrtrd. before using i tarn should In- taken and .-ill hogs showing i tM-trii ll(l«rs tllilt ill Keriini. How shown ■ rullMilrtvil \V llh'inli'd HH a |'l si k. they &gt;ln ■ to ru re a got* •s tip row it. W ■■riiiatfil mid « - iiiiiliiicni more expense. This is eal &lt;:i\i tin- srruin and virus liotli. '1 tin- necessity nt cati'hinjr the piga t\v twicr. I hit it i?&gt; by far the s;ii&lt;-&gt;t way. I iil&gt;j..'iii*i|i(^ fill* i 1 T ( ° " I • " 111 " I \ \ \ i \ t </seg>
            <seg id="p037">\TK VKTKKIXAKI.W 37 -•nun producer a derive of iiniiiiinit\ t them from the dangerous effects of the remembered that virus i&gt; the blood of pigi ngeroiis effects of the that virus i&gt; the blood of pigs, tins tin' germ that eaase hoa i;i. and eontaina the pjerwa that eaaae hoir nil contains nn&lt;- without •a alone without the mm it will give th» the sitiuii it will rive the ii irtiirc. it should be uaed with utmost cart liciiild In- used with utmost care mains after vaecination is completed. shouW ifter vaccination is completed, should . container and all. in order that it docs m outainer and all. in order that it does not i ■(• the premise*. Virus ia the liquid part i« &gt;•!■ the premise*. Vinis ia the liquid part of iir after the Fibrin has been restored. Serum Production. immune From either passing throngs, the n lias been removed Serum Production •j vaccination is used for the production o iL r i« pi-npi ■v'.y washed and cleaned, the ei .it. (I. rive ciil)ic eentimeten of virus to tin injected into the blood veaaels of the into tile Mood vessels of til ' win of tin- ear. This process pro amount of immunity an. I is eallei The blood i&gt; then drawn off unde defri ranated &lt;t id I strained througl lii|iiid part is railed anti-hog cholera aernn veiu i&gt;i' tin- ear. This protest pro &lt;m nt of immunity ainl is ealli then drawn ot't' under I'ri ranated and strained through a hit t is known as anti-hodiea, which pro tee tile disease. All serum producerx arc in&gt;\\ 1 3 Veterinarian license Xo. Pro !•&gt;« :i^e. All serum producers are now S. Veterinarian license Xo. Pro- cd to ship their serum interstate unless the.x requirements of the I*. 8. Dep't. of Atrri serum interstate unless thej • icc|iiir,- nt&gt; of the I'. S. Dep't. of Atrri- iiiiiiial Industry ami make the serum in ac nid icirulations made by the Bureau iatioiis provide that the scrum must pas is sent out. The Nebraska Live Stock Sani Aniinal Industry ami make the serum in a&gt;-- aiid regulations made by the Bureau. provide that the Reran must putf The Nebraska Live Stock Sani- i refrulation providing that all serum mad« ii providing that all serum made iducera secured their I . S. veterinary liceiis. liners secured their !'. S. veterinary lieeBM teste«l .it Siuiih Omaha ttock yards, under the supervision itli Omaha stock yards, under the supervisioi state Field Veterinarian, and approved 1»&gt; ►ay. state Field Veterinarian, and approved by been earired on for some time in eo-operatioi ska State Serum Laboratory, they having fur- and two assistants to do the actual work. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ii. Nt-a "i lltri- \\ s, Application ol Serum and Viru \\ twu hyp. \ v\ Bllir IVirks Ml] Illllt'llil IHOVei Kt i ii »r tlii&gt; work iicl&lt; S;init;ii-v I' Bnirv t id\ emor M n nirudation of the Jt is liis dutj ui [ iii. and especially j. mis iif controlling Ii Ktrurt Farmers ;i nut vac rum. Hi- tins In. ii \ itv till' fills Iliillli- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 \ \ \ x ■V Inilustry, win Tiii.-nt bv holding a Iu»k eholer* thy inly fair id by reaching lioir rhnlera rontrol very important iii tin- |&gt;n-\ -1'iitioii iihI other animal (license*. Farm Sanitation ■ very important matter ami ran only c most rigorous and tliorough proved tin tifficult that it cannot be pareti wit ■ (treat amount of good can all the corn robs and loose Mi ill kinds and burn it. If ■ little salt and burned &lt;■&lt;&gt;, h and the pig« allowed and dust in the drs of the shed. low ii all t w UK a&gt; well a t,i »ark, dust an irt from the feiic. 1 and dust as a o\ i d After removing tin ne kind and apply f lit Iseptlc SOllltlOll includin linir. A &gt;lis ■••mi nt l'» 1" &gt;lic acid, ordinary Used v to kill lice am skm spray pump, the larger Mini ■tronger th driven into the crack on is rough application am contact with all the gerotfl and kill then n applied for several hour lire posts around the \ai work itn.l Dr. Lintuer. represen- i&gt; also eo-operatin ver the state. In srhti ;!!•'• inti-i-i'^ti-il in nefitttni. After raking up ;ill tl mil properly &lt;li&gt;|)nsinir of i ut ion »i r;iii&gt;o!i&lt;- arid, oroinarj ,• owd. bill it rci|uircs a iniiri. iln not ii.-ivi- tlic stiviitrth or two ,ntirlc&gt; mentioned. Dip*. iff mill animal [&gt;a ra&gt;it&lt;-s o! all The antUrptii- Holntioi \\iisli -nIiciiiIc! lie applied to th« i-filin </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 ANNUAL REPORT \ ground outside and ,\ nod to sweeten the digest well, l.artrc hog lots should he plowed up. allowing t HWl .hi- to get into the loose dirt and disinfect it. A !l, Hiiarters tin i; ( ustriii-ti'd aw I low LMiant. A t M. \V1 V, Testing of Anti-Hog Cholera Serum In co-operation with Dr. -I II. Ga ■ who furnished a veterinarian an in Kf the tfstinj: under my dir that had : ecu produced veterinary licentw had 1 raa earied out. The testini 191-1 Fresh lime &gt;h&lt;&gt;u &gt;p should ■ I am ■■&gt;!&lt;• State Ki. I . I &gt;.-;• i i T \ S ■»&lt;i.n i-arieu out. i ne testing \v;is sti ■ 1'iiion St. i,-k V;ii-ils. South On iiber Lith, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 (1 by ten nrom companies ill were made, amounting; to half iralloiis ol serum. Two in the thirty-five tests, the pi?s were used as cheeks; sixtv-niue is cheeks; sixty-nine ml no scrum ; one wu &lt;ri\ t-n a dot k pijrs died ; one got did not die: the rature. Inn mistiiki- did not gel sick. the sci-iiiu tested khowei ake di«l not gi showed no ch - inii-s tiiHt produced it w 1 it were notified in fer for mIc any of tl ir offer for sale any of the serum that failed dard of test. i withheld from the mar t market was valued A;i^ enough of it tn vaeeii hundred pounds each. 1 u vaccinate 5.333 head it-li. Placing a valiu ( r shoats. it would amount to •f42.titi4. that iceinated with impotent serum •an lie iix-d m an example to - od potent - in ill Reran and it wm shoals \v ng 1 f N &gt; pound- would amount to wing \i-ry profitab Necrobacillosis of Pigs. ffeeting little piga. It a - nu.-li trouble, whifh i Bureau ... Animal ludustrv noiith. Their 1'ittlt is i-ut the skin sufficiently uecrophorua, which the tissue, jrivinir it the appear- kea on different ap- Hint of the nose, which au final \ -. ." In this condition thi with </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 affected, tin- destructive action of the bacilli &lt;•; tin- bone, i-auxini; p. iil'Iv ii( ■lUn aff trouble is tiKiiallv started in ami cutting « Ik i Tile tUsks HIM*. It Is Olllv I|)|»«TK. ( lii i-as r »in riii- in M asilecl ill i It Is liest til Hog Cholera Meeting Since tl IK. The boK ell Inriiiy: the past \ear. It is ,-st imatiil i vaccination condition i\ . hit that time. This h The improvement in the prodn ird of potency, ami obtaining leal to help the situation. Th xilla. an&lt;! rlir tm-liiii i H'-ll other while sll Their &gt;li;ir| TlVilt Illrll unfilled ami p Mav, I'M t iifftinyx ;it \\ I ■ ill .Mill! 1 III' i i-riiiii. our knowledge of </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 ijuite extensively, al olera situation. live experiment lias been eon- state, with i*e rum alone. After lation, the live Stock Banitarr ant 1 1 in- and one-half counties Morrill. Box Butte and the smith half of ow any virulent hog cholera virus to and only allow tin- use of scrum alone ittable owing to the faei that tin- typ. &lt;lv there wa a mild nature and the Board t to not import a virulent strain of virus whicl nt and destructive type of cholera that ifHtructiou of hojrs. than the type of The proposition and hope of eradieat- iiin alone method, was thought to lie tl nation in the North I'latte Valley a ith v pe oi disease existmir tiler ived valuable assistance and mutual operation with Air. ('has. S. Jones, an em i Jo\ eminent, who has taken a great interea t and rendered valuable assistance in carrying out an vaccinated eighty-one herds ilnrin r&gt; ;is to the ' est methods of i ncral plan of the eX| I rked out unite Mtixfartorilr, then being y objection whatever to tin- |&gt;lan. and we ii'-ii who diil not thoroughly undi-rstand who ilid not thoroughly understand l!'1"&gt;. there rii held at the opera house iTth. l!&gt;1."&gt;. there waa held at the opera house mliia in. •( tin-;, iii tin- afternoon and eve - writer nave a lull ami complete expla - tin- quarantine, and tin- objeel and ad- illg. in the afternoon and ev&lt; u "riter gave ■ full ami complete expla- in*, and the object and ad- UK it on. The object of eonrw was for the pur- i. Tin- object of coins.- was for the pnr- irating tin disi-asi- From the qnaraatined will In- able to do in a few years of per- y eradicating the disease from the quarantine* will lie able to do ill a few .Wars of per- \ .niil -iiii-essful hos fholera meetinc was </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 \ .it Imperial, Xeliraaka. in tiic •oiniiy court bouse. iiiuIit tin- c-liai ■ r. There iraa i pood attend* ■ounty i-ouri houite. under tin- chairmanship of Dr. Kr.-&lt;| II. ueixter. There wan a flood attendance, the crowd in;ir tin- rourt room, pood attention «■««, the court room, good attention tiderable interest tak«-n in the entii a distance of twenty ami twei tin ■i distance of twentv and twenty-five mile* in attei fore tin- meeting, a demonstration of 11 w livery barn, where a pig was vaecin iwry harn, where a pig «;i the proper method. A poat-morteiii &gt;;ii;ill |ii«r li!-iniL r lii into tn\\ 11 foi the proper method. A iMjut-niorteiii examiuation \\ and iliagnotua of itx ailment, th( the |&gt;ife niiylit Im ,! &lt; &gt; mind to *l&gt;ffted. After the meeting anil rei-eive«l ■■•i.-i, iiistructin ti.iii ih.' pip might lui- ..niiiiiii ,,S|, \ft ,111 ing inittruiiieutK, ' (i am! I iicir mii; \| r. liotli lniil&lt; s|&gt;iM-ia oing vaeciiiHtiiiK At tin i n:n ii I an Hllti-h&lt;&gt;u ILL' Illsllllll v'es am \ f«»rn m&gt; prexidfiit. and M r. ( '. \l Mi An intereiitil uurthousi .iiul under the mana^i esident. Mini M r. ( ituxtrator of Seward County. « I itur of Sew iuil ( crowd of In run r- gathered foi ly room aliout uue-hal F lull. T V II II 1 1 II ill Illl 1 1 lecture, (laying rlotte attention, ami (ting ijueHtionK. Mr. K. '/. Rui Twentieth Century farmer, whowan timi to itpeak, and be einphahizetl tli tiiin tu itpeak, and he einphasiz ;iim and the nereMity of preventin !n ( - as [MMaihle. The meeting wan mljourm 'inn iiinl the m-.i-N.sii\ ise Ms liotuiillle. erinary ln»N|iital of Dr. J. S. Andei umultaueuiia mei hod of \ ae&lt;- • liiiiiry hoapital of Dr. J. H \ simu'.taneoiiH nut hod of \ invitation was given for anv i»ers&lt;&gt;i striiiiients under m\ direction, one </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 1 i w I v. but ■ little more care in washing the i injection was inaiated upon. I "disinfecting" the skin at points of \ irufl was not med for the reason that of ■ hoe's skin can not be accomplished skin with an anti- I do advocate aad parts with a good, inserted, believing into the puncture employed uk and cleaning of th n before the needle i: in t i-Ti-ioii eettuu ell cleaned than when it is dry and un - t In- enough solution left on the aimal's iinetnre hole, the parts should be wiped and no aponge should be used to either iisiny: it. Dr. J. II. Gain, Animal Path - ni'iit Station, arrived in the afternoon are &lt;m the production of anti-hoe eeting was over inside, a demonstration of nise. An invitation was given to earn the proper methods of vaccination itomohile through a very severe wind to the farm house of Mr. I'. YV. Remeder, about Morrill. N'ebraska. There were t'ter the storm was over, about twenty men and Dg a i 1 1 » ir cholera meeting. The im&lt;I iii washing tin unoiis method \vn&gt; given on a pig under inv direetion. supper. Dr. Gain, Dr. Pigmui and my- tnrted about R oVloeh p. in. by myself, who gave ra iinil vaeoination. a&gt; &gt;|Minyv&gt; an- so easily infected and in- witli all kinds of germs. Their use in ■ 1 1 1 1 he (lisci)Mtiniii'(l. iieitintr in opera honor at Mitchell. Nf- I attendance, there being aboal wventj- learn of the work being done «ith hog rtnti ami post-nwrteni lesioni of hop in a li-i-tuiv by the writer. An explana- sf ut' serum in 1 1 i • - imniunization of hoga </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 I *&lt; Hi I I Dr. (Jain told them how he pro&lt; racki st;it. ■ Serum Plant and al ;it 12 o'clock, midnight, we forn i I, of Nebraska Xearly c\ ery |i neiit. Mr. &lt;• Brown of M During tin- even i fresh niriits \vi a 11 u tn 1 &gt;•' i- ol voca n of tin- !;u A very sue &gt;J l&gt;r. (iain and iii\M-iC the next day, -I Seott'a Bluff. NV raska. Mr. Wi re was a large and enthusiastic ;m i iiic-ii and niic « unian present to - tin- Rubjects of hog cholera, . ■ rum iiinl in receive instruction in vaccination, ■tt 's liliiff. : ,. M r . \\ 'li'iil linn an A Btllr RUOj ruin ami l&gt;r L ('. Kiifin. Dipiitv State \ ■ I iwinff to preiw ol nrji I &gt;r. 15. P. l);i\ is. Star. Veterinaria present and Fax orecl us h i rv ii Hea hog cholera in his state \\ often. At present he knows of none i tin vigorous manner in which l&gt;i\ Km D it does liH|i|&gt;rii to gel earired mti it docs liapi wonder ;it the (!iM'iis.- l&gt;ein|( i|ui&lt;-k Two diM-iiN.-.l | &gt;i &lt;r«s were exaniiu&lt;tl ludience to determine the nature h tlit- aiidieix the trouble, infection of necroliacillosii sen »ore mouth amonR little j &gt; i l;-&gt;. I 1 ;it deal of trouble by affecting uf the meeting ;m auti-hog rge iiiinilpi'i' nt' uignera who proiuis tin- trouble, infet-tioii of ueerolu s sore ii Mil it li ailions little niu • it deal of ti-i nlilc hv afffctiiiK lone of the nifctiii III anti-lii ife iiiiinliiT of Mil's Win will materially aid ami assist in eontn will materially aid mill awist in ■tt* \'allc\ . cholera from the I'lattt- Vallej . There was only a fair sued attends og cholera Hieeting held in the eit; ca, •linn- loth. Nn anitable hall \\ There was only e-ided to Imlil the meet ins out of door him! humid, (hilv a slight interest \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 ;it only ;i few rases of Iiojj cholera utility up t&lt;&gt; this time. A few men. ntiii-stfil to learn bow to vaccinate ntlv Ivantage of the opportunity to mte- rtem and post-mortem symp- rxplanation of serum ami virus. Farm sani- tin&lt;r a demonstration i f vaccination was given i where a sow and nine of her ruckling pigs, and i were vaccinated with tlie simultaneous method . The weight of the piga ranged from Fifteen ids. the shoal weighed about fifty ponnda ami the \nxs. weighed about two hundred fifty hoal weighed about fifty pounds ami weighed about two hundred fifty .\ i tc given trom one to one and one-half C. C. fifteen to twenty-five C. ('. of serum. The was vaccinated with two C. ('. of virus and \ ere (liven trnin one to one and one-half C. t twenty-five &lt;'. C of serum. &gt;vas vaccinated with two ('. ('. of virus ami y I '. C. of scriiin. the sow did not appear real vaccination. Had been a little off feed for ('. ( '. of neruni. the sow did not appeal Had been a little off feed for a iiperature was one hundred four degrees, b ature was one hundred four degrees id as she had not been exposed to cholera, not :iit!i exposed to cholera, aa hiirh temperature did not indicate she wi iture did not indicate she was ged to Mr. Castile and we agreed to expo Mr. Castile ami we agreed to expose ■nt outbreak of hog ebolen to te&gt;t their it itbrcak of hoi; eholera to test their im- weks from tlie time they were vaecinated, ■ ■Me for tin' animals to ' ecome norm a ne tliev were vaccinated, a] nun' normal ie piL's (rot sicl&lt; after vaccination, did not e\i sipw retrained her appetite, the milk in her after \ ar. -iiiation. did not e\ en tied her appi ,\ the iiiiIk III ip. in fact, no ill effeeta were noticed after the act, no ill effects were noticed after tli utire bunch of piys was given a very thorough re iMiiich oi piu-s was given a very thorouirh n where the cholera was very severe. Some here the rholera was verv severe. Some aced in a small pen that had been used for a u used for a pell lany pi pi had diet) with the cholera, Init none ami- sirk. In fact, not the lea- died with the cholera, luit none d pigN became sii-k. In fart, not the least liit Mi uf June "Ji'im!. a bog cholera Meeting was i&gt;ka. in the opera house, where, at '{:1"&gt; '-'Jin!, h hoft cholera meeting was crowd of farmer* who were interested in rais- ;iii address on hog cholera. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 ■nte-morteiii ami post-moi ttmetiona were given in the *yringes and other instr cut After tin- meeting in the a ■million was Riven i mi large svn ■n.-.-. All were iri \ »of Dr. 1'. L Cady. whei ■ with liuL r eholera \ i i tu hold autopsy in on It I &gt; It , I Inn. Uiisn 1 l;t 111 iiioikI m « ;in |&gt; il tu en ■affiliating. Utrl- tin- II liou to hold Mirh iNiiiniiialiiiiis </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 ilk on ■all park, No hiii- was only ,\ iVi \ /.. mi the w Illltil IV \ w •ounty. Tli liiorti-'ii 1 1 ■ ion t" ask i|ii(Ntioiis \va&gt; .\- rv iiicctiiiir. A iViiv a^kcil ami answered. \niinal Industry, who had been a&gt; - i — . 1-i ; i for the T". S. i Sovera- first time in (1 up and piT- i and |&gt;im ( 'iiimtv Farmers &lt; &gt;rsran- Mr. A K. An. V il ir.-i-.kii, in responw net-ting. Dr. .Foli ti </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 at «•. Tin- Doctor explained \\ in a 1 -"» - 1 n i 1 1 1 1 1 « ■ tall&lt; w An attempt wa&gt; niiiilc to hold a meeting at K i, through the invitation of the Farm !&gt;■ 1 1 .all. Tl to UlloU ■ until in lev to Ic It is alwavs \\ rrowil in atteiidaiu EOgalalla a meeting ■ (1 interested crowd was pr was &lt;ri\ en. question! vaccination and po»t-moii ip to tin- coiintiy was ma lioiis wiM'c examined ani damnation was ad \ &gt; ,v to hick of intere ii f.-u present to listen to Mr. Russell, M tlii- people xtiimi; interestei itllil We illlsWi jectn. Two t 'ill 1 1 mg distill seven Tliciv m about ud &gt;i;i!c |&gt;oMti them. The us. Ill I'OllspicllOUS |&gt;l;i If tins i&gt; done ami </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 the ptfhlie hall « mlan.-f. by aetual Fount Mr. Douthett of Ciishinir, l&gt;nt tlu It. Walliach in order to secure a was manifest. A regular which a demonstration of vaccination wo pigs. In one animal, cholera er pit: w«8 badly affected with worm ly affected with worms. i was advised For the eholeri or t In- cholera at ti'fi'i-tcil with worms i dose of Santonin. ■Icil with w • fins a (lose of Santonin 1 i;il I. ten grain* to each hundred with sweet ith swirt slop made of shorts. adi- of shorts eeting was held at tin- baseball park. .Madison. [ Wiis held at the baaebal] park. Madwm, E. '/.. Russell and myself, under tin- auspiei ■II and myself, under the auspices of the re' Association. Mr. Val Knska, Farm cliairmaii. Mr. Roaaell spoke i Association. Mr. Val Kiiska. Farm airman. M Russell spoke • per feeding as means of reducing, to ■ nil proper feeding as nieana of reducing. • of outbreak* of cholera. He bum gare treat i or eholera infeetion can he carried. ing meeting was held at Meadow Grove x lera inf eting was )■•-]&lt; I at Meadow Grov« apl.- trees. Planks were used t'.ir - rough invitation and under the aaspiees Mr. Val Koaka presided as ehaii rees. Planks were used for * n and under the auspices Mr. Val Kuska presided as chairman. Irest «ms given y Dr. Day, followed uldreaa was given y Dr. Day. follow. -.1 Dr. Lintner of the bureau of Animi &gt;r. Lintner of the bnreas of Animal In - ainl agreeably co-operated with dm in iihlv in this state I was held at the lloheiiiian Hall, Swan. theinian Hall. Swan- &gt;■ m. under the allspices of the ritiiens flu- citizens irhood. Mr. llendricba took special m- the meeting. The meeting was attended ng. The meeting was attended id twenty-five farmers, stockmen, bank - town who took a lively interest in uty-five farmers, stockmen, bank- ■ lively interest in own w iltcd in considerable good lit-inir done. A eil in considerable good being doni e aute-morten ami post-moi-teii lesions loulile, ftingie and simnltaneoos methods splained. Th«- lecture w;i- nii a pig and a post-mortem held on a </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Is KllilU ,\ Hog Cholera Day State Fa \\,, St \Yn An in\ il to do mi. I In first i... cholt-ra ;it the iv Drs. .Idliiis \ ■ sanitation mid pinphasi/.i Kanitatioii in i-oi ption if attendai h n j'itr to il&lt; hijrhly appreciati Sf|&gt;tciii' er 16! Limp. Nebraska, ii Ki.l. Mr. K. /.. Kn list rated vacciual KI(IL r rlldlcl-il ilii.V W h ilurini: ' </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 Nebraska Cattle Growers Convention. (irower* in-Ill a will attended ami ver Allianee. Xebranka, r»n June 18th an well attended sod very n June ImIi am \ \ ;i in was attended by h larjre number of cattli is attended l&gt;y a large Dumber of i-att i- stat trgc delegation of the Li\ Liv, nn!&gt; from South Omaha, ami repreaei • huaha. ami repi •&gt; ii- k YariU ;i!&gt;n attended. A long an the aaaoeiation w.i-, resd, ii Yards a!&gt;ii attended. A long am in w.i-. read, in their lirand Inapector. Mr. Talbot i v Dr. Dav Hih ilelivered to i Mr. Talbot in i'a ,\ \ erv County Fair Work. 'ni\ prmity Ex ten era day. one iiintv lairs during tin- fall, in connection wit An agreement was made in which tli rate with tin- Kxtensioi ,\ as f Animal Industry ii Dr. l.intmr and myself, as repi \aiiiliiatiiins IJeneva. Xelson. IVatrire ami Aulnir Nebraska State Fair. iska Live Stuck; Sanitary Boar lion. \ and Hit ISIdi.'.. on the Stat iska State Fair. Tli n during the entire tim u men, disscininatinir mis in regard to the tran tweeii tlif hours of 1 |( and 11 oVloek, Smith uintr of the In rnivcrsity, i&gt;r. Cond eaeh dmy on tin- subjei </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 .iimn in ttairy illll.s. -M\ v li&lt; Farmers Institute Work I "ni\ i isitv. I • IHVilll Of A I January 1st. 19 kinsoii. Stanton, W,&gt; K.tiriin « iff held at M ti tile produi tiolls llscil i At tin- Fjirn Hill i-ilt iiiion wci't- u&gt;iiiillv irivcii ' K..; Dourine. This disease lias om &lt;&gt;n September 2nd, I received i Dr. A. D ■ if hoK cholera, K cholera, unitary (1 the method of t Dr. I/. ( '. Kiirin &gt;lmu horn, .Mops,- I'.lu: \;i|iiiiiit. Krank'l St. K.lwiinl. At taken on the i&gt;n Chief of tin- Bureau of Animal liul </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 •hipped from the Selway \ the Donald Thompson ranch at ;&lt;&gt; reared they might be affected with •t blood from sonic of th. iiipleinriit-fixation tea Vl1 l1 "' Korean to detail me u expmeaeed JBK uivert,g.Uo«. My ,•,,„„,, ».. gwnted &gt;r .M m, in. L- t.. ♦!. . ■ • ... ■Murdoel. the vi,ii,ity of Heela. We ta ions and mares and sent same Resill iowi-.I five rcaeton and m\ Sanitary Board wan eall&lt; at tl tins meeting, fire rmutin tti n«ln*Bf (lurry. Thoinaa, Hooker Grant R Cherry. Thoiuaa, Hooker. Grai and six suspicion* animali irei i&gt;rs an six tmpirioilK animals \\,i; - "ii hand to maiataia this depar Iir any further action until tli eoniing legislature, at which tim ii hand tu maintain this i|,-i&gt;art ■" llli '" &lt;lllV| - "iiy further action until th,- re th. off It i-Mslatutv. fit whi.-h time rill be appropriated to parry .. »ymptona inanifested in tliis ,h y \\ yinptoms manifested in this ,li- r Ic Bymptoiui in many eaara tlia " val1 "' '" dwell upoa this paaw he six reactors we found was i M a !&lt;■ mx reaeton wr fonml whs in i owed a Hliarhi paralysia o nostril and the left hint! 1 inches longer than the other -1 that the Bureau will be in , position to furnish will enable this state to entirely nii; yea i Scabies in Cattle. &lt;; Mill It in cleaning up this disease the \\ -■el the possibility of being able to n- twehe counties in the northwestern </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 •turn (it tin' foot-ai Iv \ W, K, \i Pasteurization of Milk human lira ictii-i-il. tS.-ciny tin- eXJHtillg ■•uiiili! inns a&gt; mil-nil what .-ill mothers would s lit- of tin- dairy faring a- they ;uv k gome (food mother would not \\ riti Statistic nIhiu tli; (I and tilizr under wlmt unsanitan lulled before reaching lier ha </seg>
            <seg id="p057">IK VERKRIXARIAX Boy to Be a Soldier," pathetic soul' we have Boy in I'x a Soldier have given up Anu'rieai Mini lath captain to organize tenefit filthy mi ■ the day every veterinarian t( mistake I hav€ arc employ proper way 1/ .\ hvs properly .mid be tnberealiii effect tin- dkeMi would warrant thf all cow -I i\ t v ic-t reliable under the average workinj Raise Mv 1 &gt;iiln't Raise .M imtry in this horrible tizcus. regret to learn e eoald be fought iu niramst the invading. t resell oar infaata' rioMaehi ry would be the neuu ol saving zrow • 1 1 &gt; and make strong, healthy iilf &lt;&gt;f our American m i\ii.v iii whii-h rpRiilifi ean be aeeomplishecl iif &lt;-&lt;! tii-ii t i-&lt;l as tn the value of paatenriza- influencf would In- brought to bear opoa h ;i iiiuiii&lt;-i|&gt;iil paiitenrizing plant. an- M&gt; iniprartiej iting with the dif ii. if properly done ig a most importan 11' The destrui isteurizatiou, I a i. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 condition and that i&gt; ill IMlCV. Ko. I am inn \ he Bureau Milk hid on th .ml till id. pi \ « entv to thirty ininuti - ■ ion and that i&gt; the holding proems. I nd#r tl is bested to 1+"&gt; degw* !•'. and should ratiuv for 30 minutes and tlnn lie rapidh i'&lt;l in it \\ ■inn the bottoi &gt;t' water and ptv\ i igrfa tin- &lt; - i« f » of irdinarjr floal rate, and nor* iliiin 1-V&gt; ili-tfrt'fs I r&gt;s ami not n In- removed nay be held more uniformly y cown \ The punctured cap should -loiild be cox ifi-il with mm i "After the milk has been held as tooled as quickly unit ■« much .-in poHsil Tn avoid danger of breaking the bottle l&gt; temperature, this water should be warm warm water slowly with eold water. Ait in all i-Hscs In- held at the lowest availab "Tliis method way be employed tn milk or cream for ordinary purposes, h however, that paatetirizati l&lt;v • </seg>
            <seg id="p059">\ i old and used as soou ve to this itabjeet, I will refer iv tin- Bureau of Animal In- Financial Report. the financial conditions of this dt-- -J. 74-2.7 w v sllhniltt L. ('. KWirX. Dt'imtv Siat.- Veterinarian. l!H.-j ■mil January Int. 1914. to January s ami asHiHtants, stamp*, telephom total *1 7. :it &gt;&lt;&gt;.+&gt;. Mention to t h»- Faet that +4,1 ."»:4.71 w«» pai&lt; iv coll bv the !&gt;&gt;&gt;;inl </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>