<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00095.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0095.0004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Ninth Biennial Report Department of Labor State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">Novemeber 30, 1942</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">TWENTY-NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT Department of Labor State of Nebraska December 1, 1940 To November 30,1942, Incl. DWIGHT GRISWOLD, Governor 0. M. OLSEN, Commissioner of Labor Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">Letter of Transmittal Lincoln, Nebraska, December 24, 1942 To His Excellency, Dwight Griswold, Governor of Nebraska : Sir: In compliance with the provisions of Article IV, Sections 1 and 23 of the Constitution, and Section 84-705 Comoiled Statutes of Nebraska, I submit herewith the official biennial report of the State Department of Labor for the period starting December 1, 1940, the date of the last report of the preceding administration, and ending November 30, 1942, exclusive of the Division of Place - ment and Unemployment Insurance, which is required to report between January 1 and May 31. Respectfully submitted, 0. M. Olsen, Commissioner of Labor, </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Present Personnel and Rate of Compensation Name Title Monthly Salary 0. M. Olsen Commr. of Labor $200.00 (State Funds) * Alfred P. Smith Inspector 175.00 Holger N. Nelsen Inspector 175.00 Jerome R. Bigelow Inspector 150.00 Pearl Johnson Eathorne Principal Clerk 110.00 Mildred Taylor Junior Stenographer 80.00 *In addition to the $200.00 per month from state funds, the Commissioner receives $100.00 per month from federal funds as overall administrator of the Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance in the State Department of Labor. ADDITIONAL PERSONNEL EMPLOYED DURING THE BIENNIUM BUT NO LONGER WITH THE DEPARTMENT Name Title Period of Employment John Larsen Inspector 1-13-41 to 10-15-42 Ray E. Stacey Inspector 1-13-41 to 1-31-41 Niel Collins Inspector 2- 1-41 to 2-28-42 Harold Jespersen Inspector 9- 1-41 to 1-31-42 Ray L. Williams Inspector 9- 1-41 to 12-31-41 Jean Edgecomb Tempor. Steno. 8- 4-41 to 8-24-41 Ada Mac Mark Tempor. Steno. 6- 9-42 to 6-30-42 Marjorie Stewart Tempor. Steno. 10-13-42 to 11-15-42 Delores Masterson Principal Clerk 11-30-40 to 11- 1-42 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Appropriations and Expenditures SALARIES and WAGES: Unexpended balance of 1939-41 (7-1-39—6-30-41) appropriation for salaries and wages as of December 1, 1940 $ 5,605.48 Expended by the preceding administration for salaries and wages for month of December, 1940 790.00 Balance on hand January 1, 1941 $ 4,815.48 Appropriated for salaries and wages for 1941-1943 (July 1, 1941 through June 30, 1943) $20,800.00 Total available for salaries and wages from Janu - ary 1, 1941 to June 30, 1943-inclusive $25,615.48 Expended for salaries and wages from January 1, 1941 to November 30,1942 inclusive $18,749.11 Balance on hand December I,' 1942 for salaries and wages to June 30, 1943 inclusive $ 6,866.37 MAINTENANCE: —- Unexpended balance of 1939-41 (7-1-39—6-30-41) appropriation for maintenance as of Decem - ber 1, 1940 $ 1,104.20 Expended by the preceding administration for maintenance during month of December, 1940. $ 195.29 Balance on hand January 1,1941 $ 908.91 Appropriated for maintenance for 1941-1943 (July 1,1941 through June 30, 1943) $ 6,000.00 Total available for maintenance from January 1, 1941 to June 30, 1943 inclusive $ 6,908.91 Expended for maintenance (Equipment, Supplies and Traveling Expenses) January 1, 1941 to November 30,1942 inclusive $ 5,622.62 Balance on hand December 1, 1942 for mainten - ance (Equipment, Supplies and Traveling Ex - penses) to June 30,1943 inclusive $ 1,286.29 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">TOTAL BALANCE ON HAND DECEMBER 1, 1942 (For period ending June 30, 1943) Salaries and Wages $ 6,866.37 Maintenance (Equipment, Supplies and Traveling Expenses) .$ 1,286.29 Total •$ 8,152.66 FEES COLLECTED Private Employment Agencies, for 1941, fourteen licenses at $50.00 each $ 700.00 Private Employment Agencies, for 1942, thirteen licenses at $50.00 each $ 650.00 Female Labor Work Permits for hours between one o'clock a.m. and six o'clock a.m., from August 24, 1941, through December 31, 1941, 153 permits at $3.00 each $ 459.00 Female Labor Work Permits for emergency over - time hours from August 24, 1941, through December 31, 1941, 2 permits at $3.00 each... $ 6.00 Female Labor Work Permits for hours between one o'clock a.m. and six o'clock a.m., from January 1, 1942 to November 30, 1942, inclu - sive, 214 permits at $3.00 each $ 642.00 Female Labor Work Permits for emergency over - time hours from January 1, 1942 to Novem - ber 30, 1942, inclusive, 12 permits at $3.00 each $__36 ; 00 Total ¦$ 2,493.00 Note: The above mentioned Private Employment Agency fees and Female Labor permit fees are payable into the gen- \ eral fund and are neither used by nor available to the State Department of Labor. 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Personal Property Furniture and Equipment Inventory Number Article Description Condition 20- 19 Table Work-Mahog. fin.—3'x6'—2 drws. Fair 20- 3 Chair Swivel-Walnut-Arms-Leather seat Fair 20- 32 Chair Straight back-Walnut Fair 20- 33 Chair Straight back-Walnut Fair 20- 34 Chair Straight back-Walnut Fair 20- 35 Chair Straight back-Walnut Fair 20- 36 Chair Swivel-Walnut Fair 20- 37 Chair Swivel-Oak-Anns Fair 20- 39 Chair Steno.-Green leather seat and back Fair 20-223 Chair Swivel-Oak-Round-Back-Anns Fair 20- 7 Basket Wastepaper-Square-Metal Fair None Basket Wastepaper-Round-Metal-Unnumb. Fair None Basket Wastepaper-Round-Metal-Unnumb. Fair 20- 8 Fan Gilbert-Oscillating-16" Fair 20-220 Fan Gilbert-Oscillating-16" Fair 20-221 Fan Westinghouse-16" Fair 20-222 Fan Gilbert-Oscillating-16" Fair 20- 15 Desk Steno.-Walnut-2 ped.-6 legs Fair 20- 17 Desk Steno.-Walnut-2 ped.-8 legs Fair 20- 18 Desk Steno.-Walnut-2 ped.-8 legs Fair 20- 22 File Steel-Letter size-4 drawers Fair 20- 23 File Steel-1 sec-2 card size drawers Fair 20- 24 File Steel-1 sec-2 card size drawers Fair 20- 25 File Steel-1 sec-2 card size drawers Fair 20- 26 File Steel-1 sec-2 card size drawers Fair 20-216 File Steel-1 sec.-l legal size drawer Fair 20-217 File Steel-1 sec-1 legal size drawer Fair 20-218 File Steel-1 sec-1 legal size drawer Fair 20-219 File Steel-1 sec-1 legal size drawer Fair 20- 27 Cabinet Supply-Steel-3'x6'-2 doors Fair 20-213 Cabinet Supply-Steel-S'fxeVjj'-Z doors Fair 20-214 Cabinet Supply-Steel-3'x6V£'-2 doors Fair 7 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">PERSONAL PROPERTY—Continued Inventory j Number Article Description Condition 20- 29 Typew't'r Royal-# H-1708282-11" Fain 20-907 Typew't'r Royal-# 7-1709162 Fair| 20- 41 Bookcase 1 sec.-Oak-l glass door Fair 20- 42 Bookcase 1 sec.-Oak-l glass door Fair! 20- 43 Bookcase 1 sec.-Oak-l glass door Fair; 20- 44 Bookcase 1 sec.-Oak-l glass door Fair 5 20- 45 Bookcase 1 sec.-Oak-l glass door Fair 20-928 Bookcase Oak-1 section Fair 20-929 Bookcase Oak-1 section Fair 20-930 Bookcase Oak-1 section Fair 20-931 Bookcase Oak-1 section Fair 20- 49 Lamp Desk-Dir. Indirect-Fibre Shade Fair 20- 50 Lamp Desk-Dir. Indirect-Fibre Shade Fair I 20- 51 Hall Tree Oak Fairl 20-215 Cooler Water-20th Century-5 gal. jug Fair | None Auto. 1941 Plymouth Coach Fair! i 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Duties and Functions \, The duties and functions "of the Department are pre - scribed and outlined in Sections— 48-201 to 48-219 48-301 to 48-313 48-401 to 48-431 48-501 to 48-515 48-801 81-2901, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska. These sections include— Employment Regulations Child Labor Health and Safety Regulations Private Employment Agencies Race Discrimination Statistical information and industrial welfare. Employment Regulations: 48-202 to 48-219. Under this section of the statutes it is the duty of the Department to require employers in certain employments to provide seats for their women employees wherever and when - ever the use thereof will not interfere with their work; to enforce the limitation on hours which women may work per day or week in certain occupations and to issue permits for extra hours upon investigation and proof of jneed of such hours; to require compliance with the statute forbidding the employment of women in certain occupations between the hours of one a.m. and six a.m. except under working condi - tions approved by the Department and upon issuance of a permit therefor; to require the posting in all such places of employment of notices of the hours worked by such women employees and to make the necessary inspections for the enforcement of said law. 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">To administer and enforce the statute against the unauth - orized use of labels and trade-marks adopted by any workman or any association or union of working men to advertise goods manufactured by him or them and, to require the issuance by the employer of a service letter in certain cases to any em - ployee upon the termination of his employment. To enforce the law requiring the employer in certain occu - pations to permit his employees to leave the premises where employed during their lunch period. In the administration of this section during the period covered by this report, there have been issued 381 permits at $3.00 each, for which there has been collected and paid over to the State Treasurer a total of $1,143.00: (See Fees Col - lected, page 6 hereof.) Child Labor: 48-301 to 48-313. Under the Child Labor Law of the state it is unlawful for any child under the age of 14 years to be employed in certain occupations named in said law, or to be employed in any business service whatever during the hours when school is in session, nor may any child between the ages of 14 and 16 years be employed in said named occupations without the employer first securing an Age and Schooling Certificate from the superintendent of schools in such child's school district, or furnishing satisfactory proof to the Department that such child is over 16 years of age, nor may any such child be per - mitted to work more than 8 hours per day or 48 hours per week, nor between the hours of 8 p.m. and 6 a.m. The Department is charged with the duty of enforcing these provisions. During the period covered by this report 1,162 such Age and Schooling Certificates have been issued and filed with the Department for which certificates no fee is charged or charge - able. 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Since the out-break of the! present World War the United States Department of Labor has requested the State Labor Department to supervise the issuance of Certificates of Age through the school authorities to all minors over 16 years of age who are to be employed within the State on Government War Contracts under the Fair Labor Standards Act and the Walsh-Healey Public Contracts Act. Forms for such certifi - cates are prescribed by the United States Department of Labor and are furnished to the school authorities in blank by the State Labor Department. Of such certificates 1,866 have been issued during the period covered by this report. Health and Safety: 48-401 to 48-431. This statute covers a wide range of activities, including all the inspection work which the Department, with its lim - ited appropriation and personnel, is able to carry on. In fact, the Department has never been able to cover the field as fully as should have been done, or even to an extent approxi - mating full coverage. * Under this statute it is the duty of the Department to inspect and regulate sanitary conditions in places of employ - ment; require separate dressing rooms for men and women; to require protection for employees against dust and fumes in factory and workshops and the elimination of accident hazards on construction work and other kind of employment wherever possible. To adopt and enforce safety codes govern - ing the manner in which dangerous work shall be performed; regulating the installation and operation of dry cleaning equipment, electric equipment, elevators, steam boiler and other dangerous equipment, require adequate fire escapes at all places of employment and require employers in certain in - dustries to report to the Department all accidents to their em - ployees, fatal or otherwise. Private Employment Agencies: 48-501 to 48-515. This statute requires the licensing and supervision of pri - vate employment agencies, the most important part of such 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">supervision being an ever careful scrutiny of the fees charged by the agencies of their applicants for employment, which fees are limited by law to 10% of the first month's wages or salary of the employee. Many abuses of this law have been attempted from time to time, making constant policing of the act of utmost importance. Many attempts have been made by these private agencies to escape regulation of the fees which they may charge, among such attempts being suits to enjoin the Department from enforcement of the act, one of which suits was tried to the United States Supreme Court within the period covered by this report and in which suit the United States Supreme Court upheld the validity of the act. The most recent attempt to invalidate the act is a suit to enjoin the De - partment from enforcing the fee regulation which suit is now pending in the Supreme Court of Nebraska. License fees for such agencies are $50 per year. During the period covered by this report, 27 such licenses have been issued and fees in the aggregate sum of $1,350 collected and paid over to the State Treasurer. (See Fees Collected, page 6 hereof.) Race Discrimination: 48-801. This act merely declares the policy of this State with reference to race discrimination in collective bargaining and raises no administrative problem. Statistical Information and Industrial Welfare: 81-2901. Under this act the Department of Labor,in addition to the duties imposed upon the Commissioner by other sections of the statutes, is empowered to collect, systematize and re - port statistical details relating to all departments of labor deemed to be of value to the industrial interests of the State. This is an activity which, due to lack of funds and per - sonnel, has suffered more than any other activity in the De - partment. Yet, it is a most important one. A constant stream 12 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">of inquiries and requests flojw into the Department from all \ parts of Nebraska and from; other states for statistical data,, ' manufacturers directories'anil other information useful to and ;;¦ needed by those engaged in or interested in industrial pursuits and of a kind usually available in other states, but not avail- - able in Nebraska. Regrettably, due to its limited facilities, ' neither has the Department been able to gather and compile ; even a full and complete record of industrial accidents, their I location and causes, without which accident prevention work j has been greatly handicapped. Review of Activities Following is a summary of the activities of the Depart - ment and its inspection staff for the period covered by this report in addition to the routine duties of the office: Number of accident reports received 282 Number of towns visited 159 ; Number of inspections made 2,785 Number of investigations made 2,154 / Number jof interviews given 3,851 Number of miles traveled 17,786 Number jof employment agency licenses issued 27 Number jof dry cleaning establishment permits issued.. 263 ', Female llabor work permits issued 381 Child labor work certificates approved for minors und^r 16 , &#132; 1,162 Child labor work certificates approved for,, minors over! 16 1,866 j Citations^ for violations of female labor laws 3 Female labor permits revoked 2 Prosecutions for violations of female labor laws 4 . Convictions for violations of female labor laws 3 Dismissals 1 .:¦; Total fees collected $2,493.00 V 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Towns Visited for Inspections and Where Inspections Were Made Ainsworth David City Howells Albion Deshler Humboldt Alliance Dodge Humphrey Alma Edgar Imperial Arapahoe Elgin Kearney Arnold Elwood Kimball Ashland Emerson Laurel Atkinson Eustis Leigh Auburn Exeter Lexington Aurora Fairbury Lincoln Battle Creek Fairmont Loup City Bayard Falls City Lyons Beatrice Firth McCook Beaver City Fort Crook Madison Benkleman Fort Robinson Maywood Blair Franklin Mead Bloomfield Fremont Millard Blue Hill Fullerton Minatare Bridgeport Geneva Minden Broken Bow Genoa Mitchell Callaway Gering Morrill Cambridge Gibbon Nebraska City Central City Gordon Neligh Chadron Gothenburg Nelson Chappell Grand Island Newman Grove Chester Grant Nickerson Ciarkson Greeley Center Norfolk Clay Center Harrison North Bend Columbus Hartington North Platte Cozad Harvard Oakland Crawford Hastings Odessa Creighton Hay Springs Ogallala Crete Hebron Ohiowa Crofton Herman Omaha Culbertson Holdrege O'Neill Curtis Hooper Ord 14 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">TOWNS VISITED FOR INSPECTIONS AND WHERE INSPECTIONS WERE MADE—Continued Orleans Saint Edward Tecumseh Oshkosh Saint Paul Tekamah Oxford Sargent Tilden Palisade Schuyler Trenton Papillion Scottsbluff Valentine Pawnee City Scribner Wahoo Paxton Seward Wakefield Peru Sidney Walthill Pender South Sioux City Wauneta Pierce Spalding Wausa Plattsmouth Stanton Wayne Plainview Stratton Weeping Water Ponca Stromsburg West Point Ralston Superior Winside Randolph Sutherland Wisner Red Cloud Sutton Wymore Rushville Syracuse York Revision of Safety Codes Safety Code for Dry Cleaning and Dry Dyeing Establishments: On December 30, 1941, pursuant to the procedure and provisions outlined in the statutes, the Department adopted a revised safety code for dry cleaning and dry dyeing establish - ments to become effective on January 1,1942. This new dry cleaning safety code was adopted to meet the changing conditions in the field of dry cleaning with its new and improved equipment and new kinds of cleaning sol - vents, all designed to reduce the danger of fire and explosion, and injury and damage to person and property. 15 </seg>
         <seg id="p016">As a result of this new code every dry cleaning estab - lishment in Nebraska, approximately 275 in number, have been inspected and brought into conformity with the requirements of the code except four or five which are making the neces - sary changes in their building or equipment to meet these re - quirements and employment hazards in such establishments have been reduced to a minimum. Due to excessive fire and explosion hazards which could not be satisfactorily minimized in one plant, it was necessary to require it to discontinue operations. The adoption and enforcement of this new dry cleaning code was an important step forward in safety work and accident prevention in the State of Nebraska. Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, and Escalators: Following numerous and persistent requests for a modifi - cation and improvement of the Nebraska safety code for pas - senger and freight elevators, the Department on November 24, 1942, adopted a revised code for elevators, dumbwaiters, and escalators, and related equipment to become effective Jan - uary 1, 1943. This modified code became necessary due to the steadily increasing number of accidents resulting from the faulty installation, maintenance, and operation of elevator equipment. Several fatal accidents and a great number of non - fatal accidents having recently occurred. In adopting this re - vised code as well as other safety codes, representatives of both the employer and employee groups and of the general public were called in for advice and consultation to the end that a code might be adopted that would best serve the inter - ests of all interested groups and be effective in minimizing the accident hazards attendant upon the installation, maintenance, and operation of elevator equipment. Safety Code for Meat Packing Industries: The need of a special safety code for the meat packing industry is another form of code for which a demand is steadily growing. Codes already adopted having no special application to many types of equipment used in the slaughter- 16 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">ing and meat packing industry leaves such occupations with- R out adequate provisions for safe-guarding employees engaged in this hazardous work. Consideration is now being given to the formulation and adoption of a safety code for this industry. Recommendations There are a number of Nebraska Labor Laws which should be amended in several minor respects to facilitate the ' : enforcement thereof and to more equitably extend their cov - erage to types of employment not now covered by the law. For example, the child labor law contains provisions that minors between fourteen and sixteen years of age may not be employed in a mercantile institution or store without securing an employment certificate from the school authorw ties, which certificate must be approved by the Department! of Labor, but there is no prohibition against such children \ working in a restaurant next door or across the street or l&gt;&gt;_ elsewhere. Neither is there any prohibition against such child - ren working as messengers for a telegraph company or any other employer or kind of business not mentioned in the act and the Department frequently finds itself Nconfronted with the necessity of enforcing this law against certain kinds of em - ployers while others engaged in similar or comparable busi - ness where the employment hazards and moral influences are substantially the same are exempt from the operation of the law. Such inconsistencies should of course be remedied by legislative amendment. There should also be a slight amendment to the female labor law correcting a manifest error occurring at the last session of the legislature in which "manufacturing" plants that process "seasonable" agricultural products are given cer - tain privileges under the law not extended to other employers. The word "manufacturing" should be deleted and "seasonable" should be changed to "seasonal". Private Employment Agency Law: The Private Employment Agency law is at this writing the subject! of litigation now pending in the Nebraska Su- 17 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">preme Court, wherein several private employment agencies have joined in an action to restrain the Department of Labor from the enforcement of the fee provision of the act. Should this matter be decided by the Supreme Court within the time that bills may be presented to the legislature, then in the event there is a decision by the court adverse to the State, it may be desirable to introduce a proposed amendment to this par - ticular law. Section 48-412 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebarska should also be amended so as to provide equal protection against industrial hazards to all employees whether they be self employed, employed by another member of the family, or by any other person, firm, corporation or association. New Laws There has been a long felt need of a few additional enact - ments for the benefit and protection of the public under the Nebraska Labor Laws. For example, adequate provisions for steam boiler inspection is greatly needed including provisions for the appointment of a qualified steam boiler inspector. Many instances have come to the attention of the Department wherein steam boilers are installed and operated in rural school houses throughout the State and in many of the small towns throughout the State and in many places of employment, with - out any requirement for adequate boiler inspection or qualify - ing experience and examination of a suitable operator for such steam boiler and related equipment. There should also be at least a skeleton statute enacted providing for the appointment of a qualified and competent freight and passenger elevator inspector, giving to such in - spector certain authority and charging him with certain duties which can not be adequately provided through the adoption of an elevator code, to the end that there may be a further reduction of the too frequent accidents occurring as a result of elevator installation, maintenance, and operation. There is further an ever increasing demand for legisla - tion requiring employers to provide suitable equipment to pro- 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">tect their employees against the dangers of occupational lead poisoning in connection with trie use of newly developed spray painting and similar work, which protection can not be ade - quately provided by safety codes under the provisions of our present labor laws and should therefor be provided by statute. Consideration should also be given to the enactment of a small claims law or small wage collection law. Numerous and ever increasing requests come to the Department from persons having wage claims in small amounts against employers who are unwilling to pay and refuse to pay. The Department has no authority to enforce payment of such claims with the re - sult that these impoverished claimants are all too frequently made the victims of their employers' refusal to pay and their own inability to finance a suit for collection. Some provisions shoud be made whereby the Department would have author - ity to require the payment of such claims when they are in fact a just debt, and in the event litigation becomes neces - sary the costs thereof should be assessed against the employer when the proceedings result in a judgment against him, or to be paid by the Department in the event the suit is dismissed. Conclusion In conclusion it may be said that it has been and is the policy of the Department in the enforcement of the several State Labor Laws and Safety Codes, to secure voluntary com - pliance therewith whenever and wherever possible, believing that in so doing a greater and better service is rendered to the State than by instituting prosecution of first time viola - tors. The Department has on occasion been criticised for not proceeding against all who have committed a violation of any of the labor laws. It is considered that such a policy would be unwise and would only create opposition to the law and hamper enforcement, while voluntary cooperation gained through a tactful approach to enforcement problems has pro - ven to be an effective means of securing compliance. However, in second offense cases, or in cases where a violator cannot be persuaded to comply, the Department has 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">limMUiUxl ami will ooiiMmut to limUtuto protuiouUon whun all (lUici 1 mniiim prove Ui bn nf no nvull, T)ip Dujjiirtmonl h««, riitrliifr the lierlod oovared liy Mifa report, mnilu mi oiu'iiotit uii'ort to udmlnlHtfli 1 the luwh oom» mltUiil in lv ttii|&gt;ttrvl«l(in with duo ro^ni'd I'm' thu righto mill (ionvnnltuuwn ol' llumo nl'l'iuiUiil, liioludlnjr tlui publki tfenernlly, nnil Uml ))i)lli\v will, nf pdiii'hu, l»i wmllmiwd, 20 </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>