<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Growing Pigs in Summer</title>
               <date value="1918-06-15">1918-06-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">■ULLITIN NO. Ill Nun i ii I'l a i t* Hi noiAIHiN Id I I ktin N THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION or NEBRASKA \ mi i m|i SXX, Amu i i \ GROWING PIGS IN SUMMER HI mi Ml'MIMI&gt;*IA! «M'lt»MMl!N, Nl'NIM I'l *t\¥, Ml MNA«h/« W I /»( lull Hltl Hi ¥,. \. Ml N«.l I I, fill,,/, HiaiNIH I H I.IM'iil.N, NHMIMMM, I' N S </seg>
            <seg id="p002">4«k» 11*1, mrnmrn tmm or mum I Ml HHVINNINM IHMB MU «&gt; !!! ! !'!;i!l!!; I I WiMV V, 1 "";'" I ft ',-, III* • l»HHft MMI^H» fillrari; 1 /,! to:;::, / f TNI W0NNIM ITAPP btiwit. Hi, »i ll Hi luHhitii hi wmmm , U H H,.nni.li A M /u/WUHl Iii /.mil ihimuim il I'm.* nf i(|i-mii ► (hi miiIiUm .m tll.Ullnl Iimim lljfu. llj III. I miii! *«n. iillmt. ImMhI »UIm |(i|i.iil Mlflll l|l AmMiIiIIMI* Wf»IHM)(l'iH I' ' Ihnnfmi h»m nl »i ' »' I'MM*, »'« It, -lull' mini ,il i liniit I W j lit** M r \S A &gt; iHihnllimil I miiin-Hllllil W *V ,1*' "« I' m \mi\ h \&gt;» -H»'M( A M, iHliil/lW* ! ti«i* M f( &lt; i //(//■ u I I'MMii-'M M h 4 /«'»* Hiitl'iHi'if \ I ■&gt;-&gt;.,». A M ffw/««|«/i I hMM h M /'(//»! il,lmlii&gt;w,nl Uim*nn A M Iliniiiiiltiiiii I A |«»m*M, A, ¥i hlfjiitiittlmh 1 UniiVi/inti* \'ji \) I'liiiii l'iiilt«lti,h mnl I'lhHiihiih Hilt* V I' t\H,m M fc, kiil'iiiiitifiiihiii b*^ uni fin tiihthiiiHii Nj'Mli I'lxtu 4MM I )(**«, M P, &gt;)iihtiiiiiinl,,&lt;i I •imiihiihil liiliflillhm V hImihh. I mm A lli(fW r «i 'I *' kiih'iiiiliiulnil hh'ilmiiiilHl kuliilnllmi Vu&gt;M\ I /)DIH II hi iHfiiitnifl WmmIi h»|(&gt;. W j 4| VIM II H» 4llHfk\i in ImhUllUiHl I llfttiltln H H T'l*li I'll (» lumhih //i /'/,&lt;»/ l',iilhilnii¥ iiml I'liviiiihni* </seg>
            <seg id="p003">liNHWINh Mil* IN MlMMtN i%iiimiii i mi* Nil huh Ik mi Wl»H H» I" I" »tii|»' in m mil MiiiMiiiu ■ "if Illl llMHlll' -Hill |i||| .HIM |ll Mil" WftVi Hdl Will ■HHHH Hit 4 illlMlilll |ll Illll | I, MM HIM IIIMMMI|l|ll« Illl limllll* llf »MMHmI Hk|»i Urn III" III Ml "M HIM |llM&gt; lllll I|IM I III' -iiiiiiiiMi, mIIIi Ilii' UiiiiimM Him! I imkm I H»I||U iiim&gt; miinIjIm Him IiIIIIHI III ||m(mIII|||IM Kllll «II||IM MMUCHN llf mm III. II* M fvW llf ill* im mi n* »-m IIimI ImhI lii piiilll miiiI IIihI miihiiI hkhIii»I Ihm (!•■ Ill HIJIIMI Mil III Ml hH I* imiH* III Iiii im i IhiIImIIiim km liHtu nImimii IIihI Him ihIm him| itml nl MMlli» « In II M|llillM I'lM" HI'MW "'i 'ill'tll.i |IH Iiim |'l IhImI Im Hi' Miiimiiil uf mmiIii liil ,\ llulil I ill hill Ml Vmm njiiH lull i||iM|i MHlll* b llMHVf IHllllll UlVMM fMnl lull Mi«l|» M'lljl" A HI' llllllll I Ml Hill glVM* IIIMllllllll M"lll« Hi 'I IIIMllllllll fllfel I III IiihIII iiii Ilii- iiwiiiui' |ilu illlllliM Him mihiiiiihi |n im||h|I^ uimuI m«I wli'iii' Hih Illiml MlHlll I* It'll |l nun i-« mid Hi ll Hi Ml Inmlit'l Mini Him M'll'i "ii |iIm» *|f)llll iimi Hill |iuiiiii|h, |||||« MIMOIIM MM ttlrillltl |I»)»IHM' Mllll llMlllM It'll I III II HIlU Illl M»|.' . I. ,1 III Ml" 1 M|l|llii&lt;tllllMlt'U Him liillllWllltf iMnlllln I If full M H'l» Ijlfljl I ill Hill nl iilnilll | li.illllil nl nun il.Hl in i Hill |i»nii!i!« ut llit'ii whImIiI, Himv ■IiiimIiI mmIii mIuhiI III [iiillllil tlttllv Hill) mmI I *&gt;»» ifiiilliiU nl iiilll fn&gt; 'Mid Hill |imiiiii|m (if IIHlll III wt'lMllI MllllIlM IM) 'IhV« illl |IH»Ihh Him mmIH sunlit Iim Mhiilll ft'i liiilllllU, Him MI'Hlll full III mmi ll |HM Wlilllil In .llllllll Illl |llllll|l|», Mllll III" WlllIM ..I Hi. MHlll HllHVM TllM I H«l III Hi" mi ll mIihii ill lid If ii ni'iilliiiM iMljiill Hf kl fil lift |i mini" iimi Hill iiiiiiin . WNliflil ill Him my* |« in! iImiU, Himii Him hvmi MMI' |HM ■llUK ll MHlll Iiillllil III imlllill llMllv, Mllll MHl hIiIIIII JMlt liiMIIItU ill M ' Mill fUi' IIMI IHMIIIil- ill Illl IMMmi ||| Wl'llflll flllllllH IMl llNV» IIM MlfMlf* (INMlllI'M, Hit' UN I (I |M')' |l||f Wlllllll Im mIuhiI l»7 imimiU, Him mimIii mmImii hv mncIi |iltf »l»«Ml U77 liiniiiiU, iir A IiiiiIimIn, miiiI Him vmIiim nf Him M'Hh "^'i Him I'iml ml. lih .1 I" Mi (I M, •i/i.l-l Mini III i IHlllii. III. ImI.Ii Ilia i IH.lt Ml InlM III In . iiiim ili m|« hiiiI I « ll.lll.ll. Tll/»t. |,|ll*|llHl|..ll» ...IN llH«J;»l, /III II. run iriifi ii iim iiir ■Miiininf f mf ■ lil.i.l..! 111111.1111 \t&lt; llllllll 4 Mil" . Ill I ■•( </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I Nt 1 1 n litfi ■I. h Inimlm AuiiniUiinil Kgp, Slnliun, Iliilli * .. If I • -r I H Cl *•.'■*:&gt;* 5?i&lt; 'ii V *. »- I ■« « ji 8 a 8 % , i- SI Ii h w w B i, m-r-t - I Ii . »* *Lli Si 1 ««-S-S5 If : If i. Mi I* 5I1K « I PN&gt;. ' i IMP fl» I s &lt; H ** to 8S3&gt;I S }l « « » BiS'iq S 1$ « </seg>
            <seg id="p005">limn Inn I'm* IH Htiwnn i 5 nf Kim grain (mi wumil #7»W. It Uiu |ilg» win givuii mmiU .1 full i«i'»l, ttiiiitiiniiiiK in litii wtini ;i &lt;&gt; Mil ;i .i hiMiniU of w' win |lft' 10(1 ImmiimU ii( Hi.. II tvultflil dally, lli.oi llmv »||mi!i| gftlli iilmill .0 |HlUlld iwh dully Mlllj Wtf. alrtlMl KM I |»&lt;llllf|a (ll* |f lit III in'i 100 |muhm( 0 uh\wmi in weight, During 150 iluv* mi alfalfa imHiuru Kiu average i»ig •limilil gain «Ijm«i IHft |i&lt;iuiui», «mt about ftl J ihiuikIn or h liUlu uvur 0 ImimIiuU nf Mm, «iuj givti h niMCUin of iibmil #7 HI Hlmvu llu« mat nC Urn gi tun ralm If turn ii|i|ii'imi'litii| tliu |100 murk, hh in I'.H7, Hum tht* gruHt - • «i iir.iiii would In- from thu mudium mlion. ThuttrohU pur pig during tliu Muiiuiuir would Uu H|i|)roKiiimlu|y $5.40, &lt;lii.ll, itiul 12,'iH, Uu' lu'iiv ii-hi cHtion giving i !&gt;■ i- .i.-i proht. * II I'l-.H f'HNT li A in »s &lt;u c hiin i (i»ic\in it turn 4 mm ■ HMOS "»l I •»!!&gt; I 1)11 I'lliM t,\i\/,l\t, ON U.I U.I » I'tHll III For 70 liny* during tin- nummui' of 1U1H, 20 pigv wttrtt fud 1,8 poundv of corn daily pur 100 poundu of ilwir weight, whilu 20 Hiniiliir pigit wiTt' given thru a Hulf-fuudor h full ruiuni of corn, amounting to 3,74 pound* daily par 100 pound* of thuir weight, Doth loU of pig* grazed on alfalfa pasture, The average weight per pig at the beginning of the tart was -lit pound.-,, and at the clo«e mi pound* for the pigx fed a medium ration and 110 pound* for thoite fed a full ration. The pigs on the medium ration gained at the rate of ,RK pound each daily and ate 197 pounds of com for 100 pounds gain. Those on the full ration gained .95 pound each daily and ate 300 pounds of com for 100 pounds of gain. Con - sidering com worth $1.40 per bushel, the cost of grain to produce 100 pounds gain from the medium ration was $4.92 and from the full ration $7.50. Considering the gains on the pigs worth $15.00 per 100 pounds, the daily profit per pig from the medium ration was 5.8 cents and from the full ration 7.1 cents. A -i I'KIt MM IIATIOS OK &lt;-Olt.\ (OMI'XKI K WITH A I(ATIO\ OK i oll\ AMI TAKKAMK KKI.K-KKII KOIt IMOH c.HAZIM. ON AI.KAI.KA I'AKTl'KK** Two lots of 20 pigs each grazed on alfalfa pasture from June 20 to August 1, 1916, 42 days. One lot was fed a medium ration amounting to 1.83 pounds com daily per 100 pounds of the pigs' weight. The other lot was self-fed corn and •Table 1, l..t« HA and HI Tulil.- I. I. .in 71 and 73 and XI und v:i </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 165 6 v. ■ I e»«&gt;8 BQ S uc 85SS S M ■i « -«-S 8 5 5 8 ohjt:82!S g« M .§ 3 8S§8 S N X 8 ° |S3S8 3 M s p. g oh a$ss § w a s sws a- 6 8, a •Si : &gt;;.Er c :?jfl« B I !!2i4 i .EfiJatcc s E- ,■&lt; J 1 \z.i&lt;«J- r- J| g* I nicr&gt;8 n . . I w:a&gt;Mtj sn -^ J. *, O — &lt;*&gt;« — — N e » , - — = 11 = !5 ■ S 18 t " t -°r * 1 If ijLL_!!iiJ: I « I «H —— ' © • I III 3-. ■!&gt; n » </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Growing Piyv in Summer 7 tankage and ate 4.16 pounds of this feed daily per 100 pounds weight. Two other lots of 20 pigs each grazed on alfalfa pasture from July 18 to September 26, 1916, 70 days. These two lots were fed in the same manner as the former two lots, but the pigs which were self-fed corn and tankage ate 5.02 pounds daily per 100 pounds of their weight. The average weight of the pigs at the beginning of the tests was about 42 pounds and at the close from 61 to 115 pounds according to lot. The average daily gain of the pigs in the two lots fed the medium ration of corn was .53 pound and of those self-fed corn and tankage .87 pound ; or stated in terms of comparison, the pigs self-fed corn and tankage gained one-half faster than the pigs fed a medium com ration. On the other hand, the pigs on the medium corn ration made 100 pounds increase on 192 pounds corn, while those self-fed corn and tankage ate 294 pounds of corn and 10 pounds of tankage in producing 100 pounds of gain. The hogs self-fed corn and tankage ate one-half more grain in producing 100 pounds gain than the pigs fed a medium corn ration. With com worth $1.40 per bushel and tankage $100 per ton, the cost of grain for 100 pounds gain on the pigs fed the medium corn ration was $4.80, while in the other lot the cost of grain for 100 pounds was $7.85. If hogs were worth $15.00 per 100 pounds, then the profit on 100 pounds gain from the medium ration of corn would be $10.20, and from the self-fed ration of corn and tankage $7.15. The daily profit per pig would be 5.4 cents from the medium ration and 6.5 cents from the full ration. The main factor favoring a heavy grain ration for hogs grazing on alfalfa pasture is in the increased profit a pig gives in a given time or in the increased daily gain per pig. When prices are such that the pig fed a medium ration gives as great daily profits as the pig fed a full ration, then the evi - dence is very largely in favor of feeding the medium ration. It seems quite evident that the relative profit per pig fed a light, medium, or heavy ration during the summer depends largely on the relative price of hogs and corn, but also that a medium ration is likely to give quite satisfactory results. We have not considered the difference in the cost of the alfalfa eaten by pigs receiving different amounts of grain as this would be so small as to influence results very slightly. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 165 &lt; &lt;&gt;i:\ &lt; &lt;&gt;MI'\i;i |&gt; WITH Vim\ AND TAXKAUK KOK 1'KiS GRAJUXa OS AliFAM-'A I'ASTIRK* During the summer of 1914, a total of six lots of shotes with an average of 21 head each, or 126 shotes, grazed on alfalfa pasture for an average of 65 days and were fed a medium ration of corn amounting to 2.42 pounds daily per 100 pounds weight of the shotes. Six similar lots were kept under similar conditions but were fed a ration of 95 parts corn and 5 parts tankage, amounting to 2.37 pounds daily per 100 pounds of their weight. The pigs averaged about 60 pounds each when put into the pastures, and when taken out those fed corn averaged 108 pounds each and those fed corn and tankage 112 pounds each. The average daily gain of the pigs fed corn was .78 pound and of those fed corn and tankage .85 pound. The pigs fed corn ate 262 pounds of grain for 100 pounds of gain made, and those fed corn and tankage ate 240 pounds of the mixture for 100 pounds of gain. If we consider corn worth 56 cents per bushel, tankage $50.00 per ton, and hogs $6.25 per 100 pounds, the cost of grain per 100 pounds gain on the pigs fed corn was $2.62, and on those fed corn and tankage $2.58. The daily profit per pig fed corn was 2.8 cents and for those fed corn and tankage 3.1 cents. If we raise the prices to 84 cents per bushel for corn, $60.00 per ton for tankage, and $9.00 per 100 pounds for hogs, then the pigs fed corn gained 100 pounds at a cost of $3.93 for the com eaten, and those fed corn and tankage gained 100 pounds at a cost of $3.78 for the corn and tankage eaten. The daily profit per pig on those fed corn was 3.6 cents and on those fed corn and tankage 4.2 cents. If we raise the prices to $1.40 per bushel for corn, $100.00 per ton for tankage, and $15.00 per hundredweight for hogs, then the pigs fed corn would gain 100 pounds at a cost of $6.55 for the corn eaten and those fed corn and tankage at a cost of $6.60 for the corn and tankage eaten. The daily profit per pig on those fed corn would be 7 cents and on those fed corn and tankage 7.1 cents. Table </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Growing Pigs in Summer 9 t'OKX KhXF-FKD COMI'AltKI) WITH OOR.X AXD TAXKAGK SEI.F - FKD FOR I'IGS UKAZIXU OX ALFALFA PASTl'RK* Two lots of 20 pigs each grazed on alfalfa pasture from July 18 to September 26, 1916, 70 days. One of the lots was self-fed corn; the other lot self-fed corn and tankage. The pigs eating corn gained at the rate of .957 pound each daily and those getting corn and tankage gained at the rate of 1.03 pounds each daily. Of corn alone 300 pounds were required, and of corn and tankage 293 pounds, for 100 pounds gain. With corn worth $1.40 per bushel and tankage $100 per ton, the cost of corn to produce 100 pounds gain was $7.50 and of corn and tankage $7.57. SOAKIXU THK COKX The effect of soaking the corn from one feeding time until the next feeding time for the pigs when grazing on alfalfa pasture was demonstrated in the summer of 1913** when three lots of 23 pigs each were fed a medium ration of dry corn and three similar lots were fed a medium ration of soaked corn. The daily gain was the same from the pigs fed the two rations, and the corn eaten to produce 100 pounds of gain was practically the same. The outcome of the trial was a draw, excepting that soaking increased the labor. During the summer of 1915t, three lots of 20 to 25 shotes each, a total of 69 shotes, averaging about 38 pounds each, were turned into alfalfa pastures and fed a medium ration of dry shelled corn for an average of 87 days, while three similar lots of pigs were kept under similar conditions but fed corn that had been soaked since the previous feeding time. The average mean weight per pig fed dry corn was 58.9 pounds and of those fed soaked corn 59.4 pounds. The amount of grain fed daily per 100 pounds weight of pigs was the same for each lot, 2.23 pounds. The results were practically the same from dry corn as from soaked corn. In only one lot did soaked corn produce a faster or cheaper gain than dry corn. The average daily gain per pig fed dry corn was .48 pound, and of those fed soaked corn .47 pound. There were required 273 pounds dry corn or 276 pounds soaked corn to produce 100 pounds gain. The results would seem to give conclusive evidence that soaking corn under these conditions is not a commendable practice. ♦Table 1, lot* 80 and S3 hull. -tin 147. tTabl. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural E.vp. Station, Bulletin 165 10 30 N A ««e« n c-* &gt;r „, .2 « c j m 3C © frj N 9 "« •M "5 _ -* » e ■ CO g e i io»-w5 S 5 3 T! '! &lt; 5 c I Nionio — g § 8 ! MMX^. SO •M V. ■g » gD S I nwoo o of N O "5 — tO « -WIN C jtj © Cj ?) 3C O c en " 3 z N?:*-* x •M a ■' i j: «i:&gt;si fc.Jia* -«.Sf.Sf|£ 1 »f5i Qc, S &lt; of'? I uses oq •* N = TJ nCO ~ "I 1 1&amp;ei --jS «nS 5S25.SS ; N i iSitfli li WHS" *^ a, o^ a, ./ x q t8 O &gt; &gt; i. &gt;J2X JCtf Z&lt;K«JJ a* </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Growing Pigs in Summer 11 SHOUTS WITH COK.N The results* of two tests in which shorts were substituted for a part of the corn ration for pigs grazing on alfalfa pas - ture indicate that the shorts gave about the same result pound for pound as the corn. Therefore the advisability of feeding shorts to pigs grazing on alfalfa pasture will depend very largely on the relative prices of corn and shorts. THK VAIAK OK 1'ASTlKKt During the summer of 1916, three lots of 20 pigs each were fed corn and 60 per cent protein tankage in self-feeders while running in fields of alfalfa. Three similar lots of pigs were fed the same ration but were kept in a dry lots where there was no green feed. Two lots of pigs were on trial 56 days, two lots on trial 42 days, and two lots on trial 70 days. The average weight of the pigs in the various lots ranged from 37 to 47 pounds when the tests began and from 47 to 115 pounds when the tests ended. The pigs in the dry lots ate 4.18 pounds of tankage per 100 pounds of corn and tankage, while those on pasture ate 3.85 pounds of tankage for each 100 pounds of corn and tankage. The pigs on alfalfa gained at the rate of .87 pound per day, while those in the dry lots gained at the rate of .32 pound per day. The pigs in the dry lots ate 596 pounds of corn and 23 pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds gain, while those on alfalfa pasture ate 297 pounds of corn and 14 pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds gain. Access to alfalfa pasture reduced the grain eaten to produce 100 pounds of gain nearly one-half. Considering corn worth $1.40 per bushel or $50.00 per ton and tankage worth $100 per ton, the cost of corn and tankage for 100 pounds of gain in the alfalfa field was $8.12 as against $15.47 in the dry lot. Alfalfa pasture reduced the cost of gains nearly one-half. After August 1 the pigs of Lot 74, which had been in a dry lot and self-fed on corn and tankage, were taken from the dry lot to an alfalfa pasture. On August 15, 5 of the larger pigs were taken from the lot and the smaller 15 kept in the alfalfa field for 42 days, August 15 to September 26. They were self-fed corn and tankage. While in the dry lot ISuiletln 147. limited edition, pace 23: popular edition, page 12 tTable 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Siation, Bulletin 165 12 * .i ••&gt; ": = Ifc-B 133 -&amp;§ ssj£ 'sags *»« *NO | £5; i 3,^ I oiin^oo ££ N «■* ■S3 T 3£j« : laoqw IE s «jr S i &gt;• »ri &gt;1« ■5 iS 5S* ui-eo S5* i •7. K N »NlO C6 B -T - - Z " 2*1 -i-s X 2 ?^ ?' N»SI- 50 W «&gt; 3-5 »1 !C *^-s »:g, BC I- S«*jC OH *J! £ VS I a ■■» ; .si ! aw v. f*Si ?° 0? «t li: ;i !K*J si IKS is a« B** 1 §£s 1- E- ■ - i: - x m o&gt; tu&gt;::J § t * SP-S p- 2 - . a. q&gt; &amp;&gt; &amp; &amp; at m t5 j&lt; &lt;:&lt;:-&lt;-&lt;j hj </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Growing Pigs in Summer 13 on this ration the average daily gain per pig was .24 pound but in the alfalfa field on the same ration the average daily gain per pig was 1.35 pounds. In the dry lot these pigs ate 710 pounds of corn and tankage to produce 100 pounds gain, but in the alfalfa pasture they produced 100 pounds gain with 277 pounds corn and tankage. One lot of 10 pigs fed a full ration of 95 parts corn and 5 parts tankage in a dry lot in the summer of 1913 gave a daily gain of .43 pound each and required 514 pounds of com and 33 pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds gain. It seems quite evident that the feeding of tankage does not obviate the necessity of having pasture for growing pigs. OX ALFALFA I'ASTUIK During the summer of 1916, two lots of 20 spring pigs each were fed a full ration of corn 95 per cent and tankage 5 per cent twice daily, while two similar lots of pigs were fed com and tankage in self-feeders. All pigs were grazing on alfalfa pasture. Two lots were on this test 42 days, the other two lots 70 days. The average weight of the pigs by lots at the beginning of the tests ranged from 39 to 46 pounds and at the close of the test from 69 to 117 pounds. There was not much difference in the rate or economy of gain due to the hand feeding or the self-feeding. However, both hand-fed lots made faster gains and used less feed in making 100 pounds increase in weight than the corresponding lots that were self-fed. The average daily gain of the pigs hand-fed was .96 pound as against .87 pound of the pigs self - fed. The hand-fed pigs required 298 pounds of feed for 100 pounds gain, while the pigs self-fed received 304 pounds of feed for 100 pounds gain. The pigs being hand-fed received 4.52 pounds of tankage in each 100 pounds of com and tankage. One lot of the self - fed pigs ate 3.17 pounds and the other lot 3.41 pounds, or an average of 3.3 pounds of tankage in each 100 pounds of corn and tankage. The results of these two tests would not warrant one in drawing conclusions in favor of or against the self-feeder for feeding pigs under the conditions existing during these trials. •Table H \M&gt;-I I 1 MM. VS. sKI.I -I KKI&gt;I\(; Sl'l:i\(. I'KiK GRAZING </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 165 Table 5— Hand-feeding compared with self-feeding spring pigs grazing on alfalfa pasture, summer of 1916 Two other lots* of 15 pigs each were fed ground wheatt of poor quality and tankage while grazing on alfalfa pasture 42 days, from August 15 to September 26, 1916. One lot was hand-fed, the other lot self-fed. The average weight of the pigs at the beginning of the test was 69 pounds and at the close about 125 pounds. The hand-fed pigs were fed 5 pounds of tankage in each 100 pounds of corn and tankage. The self - fed lot ate 4.55 pounds of tankage in each 100 pounds of corn and tankage. The self-fed pigs gained 1.47 pounds each daily and ate 343 pounds of corn and tankage to produce 100 pounds of gain, while the hand-fed pigs gained 1.17 pounds daily and ate 341 pounds of corn and tankage to produce 100 pounds gain. We believe the difference in rate of gain is due to the self-fed pigs having eaten more than the hand-fed. The former ate 5 pounds each daily while the latter ate 4 pounds each daily. Self-feeding was advantageous chiefly because it Table 6. lot* M and 8fl tThU wheat waa of the 1115 crop and unlit for milling ptirpn June 20 July 18 August 15 August 1 September 26 September 26 42 days 70 days 42 days Lot No 72 78 82 83 88 89 Ration* (alfalfa C 95 C C 95 C W 95 W and T pasture) T 5 and T 5 and T 5 T T Hand-fed or self- fed H-F S-F H-F S-F H-F S-F No. pigs in lot 20 20 20 20 14 15 Av. first weight per pig, lbs 46.6 39.2 43.5 42.5 69.3 69.:) Av. last weight per pig, lbs 83.7 69.4 117 3 115.1 118.5 131.3 Av. gain per pig, lbs 37.1 30.2 73 8 72.6 49.2 62.0 Av. gain per pig dairy, lbs .88 .72 1.05 103 1.17 1.47 Lbs. grain for 100 j C 300 305 270 283 W 324 W 328 lbs. gain T 13 10 14 10 T 17 T 15 Total lbs. feed for 100 lbs. gain. . . 313 315 284 293 341 343 Lbs. grain per 100 lbs wt. of pig . . 4.23 4 16 3 73 5 02 4.25 5.04 The hand-fed pig* were iVil corn 95 purtx. tankauc .", part*. The aelf-fed pl(T» were fed corn and tiniUiiui- In Ml f -feeder*. •C. corn; T. tankage: W. wheat; H-K, hand-fed. 8-F, nelf-fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Growing Pigs in Summer 15 gave the pigs an opportunity to eat all they would. As ground wheat, like shorts, is eaten very slowly, the pigs apparently were being fed all they would eat, when in fact they were being fed only four-fifths of the amount they might have eaten had they been given more time for their meals. hand-kkkdim; ( omi'.akkd with mi.i -i i i mm. a poor qiality ok whkat and taxkauk to i'hjh UKAZ1NU OX M.I \l,l A PASTl UK* The results of this test are given not with the thought that they give very definite information but with the idea that this evidence added to other similar evidence may enable one to decide whether it is profitable to add tankage to a ration of wheat and alfalfa pasture, and that it may also add to our knowledge of the value of wheat of very poor quality when fed to pigs. TABLE 6 — Feeding a poor quality of ground wheat with and without tankage to spring pigs grazing on alfalfa pasture. Hand-feeding vs. self-feeding ground wheat. August 15 to September 26, 1916, 42 days In this test there were three lots of 15 pigs each. The pigs grazed on alfalfa pasture from August 15 to September 26, 1916, 42 days. One lot was self-fed ground wheat; an - other lot was hand-fed ground wheat 95 per cent and tankage 5 per cent, and a third lot was self-fed ground wheat and tankage. All wheat was of poor quality, shrunken and musty, and not fit for milling purposes. The plan was to give a full •Table «, Lot No 87 88 89 Ration* (alfalfa pasture) Gr. W Gr. W and T Gr. W and T 95' c and 5', Hand-fed or self-fed S-F H-F S-F No. pigs in lot 16 14 15 Av. first weight per pig, lbs 69.0 69.3 69.:} Av. last weight per pig, lbs 120.3 118.5 181.8 Av. gain per pig, lbs 51.3 49.2 62.0 A v. gain per pig daily, lbs 1.22 1.17 1.47 Lbs. grain for 100 lbs. gain 353 W 324 W 328 T 17 T 15 Total feed for 100 lbs. gain 868 341 343 Lbs. grain per 100 \h*. « t. of pig . 4.55 4.25 5.04 •(Jr. \V. ground whfiit; T. tunkm.'r; S-K, m-lf-fid: H-K, hand-fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 165 feed twice daily, but the amount of feed eaten indicates that the hand-fed pigs did not get all they might have eaten. The average weight of the pigs at the beginning of the test was 69 pounds and at the close 123 pounds. The pigs self-fed wheat gained at the rate of 1.22 pounds daily, those hand-fed wheat and tankage 1.17 pounds, and those self-fed wheat and tankage 1.47 pounds each daily. The pigs self-fed wheat ate 353 pounds of wheat for 100 pounds gain. Those hand-fed wheat and tankage ate 324 pounds of wheat and 17 pounds of tankage for 100 pounds gain. Those self-fed wheat and tankage ate 328 pounds of wheat and 15 pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds of gain. Tankage increased the rate of gain and slightly decreased the grain required to produce 100 pounds gain. Altho there was approximately the same amount of grain used by all lots in producing 100 pounds of gain, the rate of gain was much greater in the lots self-fed. The pigs being self-fed wheat and tankage gained 1.47 pounds each daily, while those being hand-fed the same ration gained 1.14 pounds each daily. This difference is readily explained by the differ - ence in the amount of feed eaten by the pigs of the two lots. The hand-fed pigs ate 4 pounds of grain per head daily while the self-fed pigs ate 5 pounds grain each daily. Pigs eat ground wheat slowly. It is presumed that the hand-fed pigs were not full fed, tho the herdsman thought he was giving them a full feed. The result of this test would indicate that self-feeding may have a distinct advantage over hand-feeding when there is a desire for fast gains and when the ration is of such nature that hogs do not eat a full feed quickly. [4-2--1R — 10M] </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>