<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Tractor Test 1924 and 1925</title>
               <date value="1926-02">1926-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 212 February. 1926 Nebraska Tractor Tests 1924 and 1925 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">TRACTOR ENGINE « Bore Total Mfer. £ and Rated MAKE Fuel Hours Rating Weight H Stroke r.p.m. Used Run Urn NAME Used Run &gt;. O 1 2 3 14 5 6 8 9 101 BEAK B" . ... 26-36 7,0001 4 i 4Jx6j 1,290 Stearns Gas 40 J«K JOHN DEERE O" 16-27 4,260 ! 2 ! 6$x7 800 Own Kero 32 101 BEAR B' 16-27 4,260 1 2 ! 6*x7 800 i Own Kero 32 103 OIL PILL "S" 30-60 17!500 2 | 9x11 470 ! Own Kero 3S 104 BEST "S -30" 25-30 9,065 4 : 4?x6J 850 Own Gas 36 105 BEST "A 60" 50-60 ; 20,000 4 i 65x81 650! Own Gas 84 1M HART-PARR 16-30 6,000 2 6}x7 750 Own Kero 38 12-24 | 4,675 1 2 5Jx6£ 800 ' Own Kero 32 Iff HART PARR IN MONARCH "D 6-60". . 40-60 16J80 6 4|x6 1,200! Beaver j Gas 38 1W CASE 18-32 6,680 4 4ix6 1,000 Own Kero 36 18-32 6,680 j 4 j 41x6 1,000; Own Kero 36 25-45 10,610 4 ! 5ix6J j 850; Own Kero 36 1 10 CASE IK OILPULL'L" 113 MONARCH "C* 114 HEIDER 20-35 7,948 15-25 5,510 25-35 10,340 15-27 6,200 2 6Hx8J 640 Own Kero I 41 2 5}|x7 755 Own Kero 40 4 4ix6 ! 1,200 Beaver Gaso 34 4 43x6| 900 Waukesha Kero 36 4 3fx5i 1,200 Waukesha Gaso 26 IIS SHAWNEE'30" 9,200 2 7Hx9} 640 Own Kero 41.5 4 3fx5 1,200 Own Kero 39 4 4|x7 825 Own Kero 40 1IC OIL PULL "R" 117 I H C FARMALL IIS THE MINNEAPOLIS 25-45 12,084 3,550 7,300 SUMMARY OF RESULTS OF NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS CONDUCTED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA-DEPART OF AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING-LINCOLN, NEBRASKA i BELT TESTS | ' i RATED LOAD— TW ) HOURS MAXIMUM LOAD— ONE HOI Varying RATED LOAD— TEN HOURS _j , Load — — Fuel ! Water Temp. °F. Fuel Water 1 T One Hour Slip of F 1 '__ i Draw Drivers Av. H. P. Av. H. P. R. P. M. Draw Bar Miles Av. Per Cent i Type Eng. Gals. Hours Gals. Eng. Gals. Hours! Gals. I — 1 Bar Pull per Eng. of Gear H. P. R.P.M. per per per Air Rad. H. P. r.p.m. per per per I A H. P. Lbs. Hour R.P.M. Point Face ! Lug Used Gals Hour Gal. Hour Hour Gal. Hour ! Highest Lowest Lugs Rim per Hour Draw Draw Bar Bar Pull H. P. Lbs. Slip of Drivers Miles Av. I Per Cent per Eng. Hour R.P.M. Point Face Lugs Rim RATED LOAD— TEN HOURS Type of Lug Gear Used Gals per Hour Highest Lowest 10 11 12 13 14 15 , 16 17 18 19 I 20 I 21 I : 24 25 26 I 27 28 29 I 30 I 31 32 33 34 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 24 I 25 — Tl I I I I j | | I I I I I I I I I I I I I _ i 36.53 1,293 4.533 8.06,0.179 75 180 55.56 1,295 8.426 i 6.59 0.00 1,399 i 1,286 27.79 2,835 1 3.68 1,285 \ 2.91 j Angle Interm 4.8*6 27.11 803 3.000 9.03 1.232 83 207 30.40 801 3.877 ! 7.84 2.791 838 I 800 16.75 1,786 i 3.52 783 1 6.56 —9.65 Spade High 2.710 60.74 472 5.599 10.85 7.305 67 208 70.16 474 8.593 8.16 12.21 505 469 32.72 4,847 ■ 2.53 473 8.55 — 4.22 Spade Interm 4.326 30.24 853 3.259 9.28 0.000 74 173 37.83 850 i 4.907 7 71 0.00 977 840 26.56 j 3,796 2.62 I 852 1.33 Interm. 3.397 60.00 651 7.814 7.68 0.000 87 196 72.51 653 11.360 6.38 0.00 ! 696 652 51.6117,654 2.53 649 1.45 Interm. 8.493 1,399 1,286 838 i 800 505 469 977 840 696 652 27.79 2,835 1 3.68 1,285; 2.91 Angle Interm 4.896 16.75 1,786 I 3.52 783 I 6.56 —9.65 Spade High 2.710 32.72 4,847 ; 2.53 473 8.55 —4.22 Spade ! Interm. 4.326 26.56 3,796 2.62 852 1.33 Interm. 3.397 51.61 ! 7,654 2.53 649 1.45 Interm. 8.493 16.79 2,097 3.00 740 7.86 —4.49 Spade High I 3.312 11.57 1,326 3.27 778 8.07 —5.85 Spade High \ 2.445 40.06 7,312 2.05 1,218 3.45 1 V-Cleat Interm 6.757 19.21 I 2,117 I 3.40 1,013 8.45 —1.24 i Spade High 3.460 26.09 , 2,966 3.30 856 6.69 —2.49 Spade High 4.531 i I I I _ L,_ L __ -_. ._J__ __ „„,. 30.33 751 3.320 9.13 1.464 90 194 37.03 751 4.596 8.06 2.29 783 751 16.79 2,097 3.00 740 7.85 j —4.49 Spade j High 3.312 24.24 804 2.567 9.44 1.499 81 192 26.97 799 3.142 8.58 2.25 836 I 797 11.57 1,326 3.27 778 8.07 j —5.85 Spade , High 2.445 60.21 1,200 6.709 8.98 0.163 78 192 70.74 1,202 9.372 7.59 0.00 1,313 1,176 40.06 7,312 i 2.05 1,218 3.45 V-Cleat Interm 6.757 32.08 1,000 3.080 10.42 0.681 78 192 36.73 1,002 3.982 9.23 1.20 1,065 990 19.2112,117 1 3.40 1,013 8.45 —1.24 Spade High 3.460 45.18 854 5.135 8.80 1.170 73 183 52.59 852 5.754 9.14 2.57 909 849 26.09 j 2,966 3.30 856 6.69 — 2.49 1 Spade High 4.531 783 751 836 I 797 1,313 1,176 1,065 990 909 849 1 , : I 1 ! I L_l— ! - ' ■ - - ■ ■ ■ - 35.59 I 642 I 3.154 ; 11.22 i 2.79 64 212 43.07 | 642 j 5.110 8.43 5.09 i 663.5 640 21.13 3,017 2.63 611 10.55 —4.93 Spade I Interm 3.5M 25.19 ' 754 2.314 10.88 3.765 60 220 30.52 754 3.625 8.42 4.90 745.5 750.5 16.01 2,315 2.59 741 11.43 —0.55 Spade I Interm 2.584 35.68 1,203 4.039 8.83 0.193 71 208 43.67 1,200 5.731 7.62 0 00 1,282 1,186 26.07 3,553 2.75 1,214 3.29 V-Cleati Intern 4.769 27.16 ! 904 3.567 7.62 0.515 67 I 181 30.00 906 4.608 6.51 1.161 957 891 17.06 2,461 2.60 909 10.59 1.19 Cone j Low 3.302 1 1 QE 1 TOO' O CO 1 O19 S OA A 17 V.r'loot Witwh 3 013 663.5 640 745.5 750.5 1,282 1,186 957 891 21.13 3,017 2.63 611 10.55 —4.93 16.01 2,315 2.59 741 11.43 —0.55 26.07 3,553 2.75 1,214 3.29 17.06 2,461 2.60 909 10.59 1.19 11.95 1,732 2.59 1,212 8.24 —4.17 27.42 3,824 2.69 543 8.47 I —5.88 9.35 1113.5 3.15 1,207 10.17 —5.71 18.33 3,118 2.21 839 7.75 —0.25 Spade | Interm 3.586 Spade ! Interm 2.584 V-Cleat Inte ml 4.769 Cone Low &lt; 3.302 V-Cleatj High 3.013 1 11.95 1,732 2.59 1,212 8.24 I —4.17 V-&lt;Jleat: High 3.013 i II I I I 45.55 546 4.270 10.67 i 5.620 | 95 217 50.57 541 5.371 9.42 6.220 J 567 543 27.42 3,824 2.69 543 8.47 J —5.88 Spade Interm 4.121 18.03 1,196 1.870 9.64 1.885 91 210 20.05 1,201 2.136 9.39 1.100 f 1,288 1,197 9.35 1113.5 3.15 1,207 10.17 —5.71 Angle Interm. 1.788 30.88 827 3.269 9.45 0.209 65 196 34.76 824 5.224 6.65 1.320 i 891 j 822 18.33 3,118 2.21 839 7.75 —0.25 Angle Low ; 2.944 567 543 1,288 1,197 891 822 Spade Interm 4.121 Angle Interm 1.788 Angle Low ; 2.944 I l__ I 1 I I i I I I I M I I I I | I ' ' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS r OF AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING LINCOLN, NEBRASKA DRAWBAR TESTS Varying Load One Hour R. P. M. RATED LOAD— TEN HOURS Slip of Drivers Draw Bar Draw Bar Miles per Av. Eng. Per Cent Type of Pull Lbs. H. P. Hour R.P.M. Point Lugs Face Rim Lug Highest Lowest 24 25 2fi 27 28 29 :iO :il ■42 Angle Spade Spade Spade Spade V-Cleat Spade Spade 3,017 2.63 -i.93 -0.55 S|mde Spade 2,315 2.59 V-Cleat Cone 3,553 2.75 1,214 2,461 2.60 9(19 10.59 1.19 1,732 2.59 1.212 V Cleat 8.24 -4.17 3,824 Spade Angle Angle 1113.5 3,118 1,399 1,286 27.79 2,835 3.68 1,285 2.911 838 800 16.75 I 1,786 3.52 783 6.56 ; —9.65 505 469 32.72 4,847 2.53 473 8.55 —4.22 977 840 26.56 3,796 2.62 852 1.33 696 652 51.61 7,654 2.53 649 1.45 783 751 16.79 2,097 3.00 740 : 7.85 —4.49 836 : 797 11.57 1,326 3.27 778 8.07 —5.85 1,313 1,176 40.06 ' 7,312 2.05 1,218 3.45 1,065 990 19.21 2,117 3.40 1,013 8.45 —1.24 909 849 26.09 2,966 3.30 856 6.69 —2.49 663.5 | 640 21.13 745.5 750.5 16.01 1,282 ! 1,186 26.07 957 891 17.06 1 11.95 567 i 543 27.42 1,288 1,197 9.35 891 822 18.33 611 10.55 741 ■ 11.43 214 3.29 2.69 543 8.47 ! —5.88 3.15 t 1,207 10.17 —5.71 2.21 839 7.75 I —0.25 SUMMARY OF RESULTS OF JONDUCTED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA-DEPAR BELT TESTS RATED LOAD— TW ) HOURS MAXIMUM LOAD— ONE HOI MAXIMUM LOAD— ONE HOI Fuel j Watwj Temp. °F. Pud Water; 1 Av. H. P. 7 Av. | H. P. i Eag Gab. Hour* Gals. Eng. Gals. Hours Gals, j . P «JMI. per per per Air Rad. H. P. r.p.m. per per per A Hour Gal. Hour | Hour Gal. Hour I i i i i I* II 12 1.1 14 16 16 17 18 19 20 21 : Li* 1J5W 4.633 8.06 0.179 I 75 I 180 55.56 I 1,295 8.426 6.59 | 0.00 I Ml MS 3.000 9.0S 1.232 83 I 207 30.40 801 3.877 7.84 2.791 EM 4« IM* 10.86 7.305 67 208 70.16 474 8.593 8.16 12.21 U4 H63 3.259 9.2fe 0.000 74 173 | 37.83 850 ! 4.907 ! 7.71 i 0.00 \M&gt; tfl 7.814 7.66 0.000 87 196 72.51 653 11.360 6.38 0.00 US 741 iJUO 9.13 1.464 90 194 37.03 751 4.596 8.06 2.29 j L*4 DM 2.567 9.44 1.499 81 192 26.97 799 3.142 8.58 2.25 | Ul IJM C7M 8.98 0.163 78 192 ! 70.74 1,202 9.372 7.59 0.00 l B \jm It** 10.42 0.681 78 192 36.73 1,002 3.982 9.23 1.20 B KM 6.136 8.80 1.170 73 183 52.59 852 5.754 j 9.14 2.57 ' — — — — =— =^ — ■TfC! 3.164 11^2 [2.79 { 64 212 I 43.07 I 642 5.110 I 8.43 5.09 &lt; Lli 764 2.314 10.88 3.765 60 220 j 30.52 I 754 3.625 8.42 4.90 Bk IJtt 4.039 8.83 0.193 71 208 43.67 1,200 5.731 ' 7.62 0.00 B M4 3.6C7 7.62 0.515 67 181 | 30.00 906 4.608 6.51 1.161 \M 64« 4^70 10.67 5.620 95 217 50.57 541 5.371 9.42 I 6.220 I B 1.IM 1.870 9.64 1.886 91 210 20.05 1,201 2.136 9.39 1.100 E Htn tM» 9.46 0^09 66 196 34.76 824 5.224 6.65 1.320 IN HOURS MAXIMUM LOAD Fuel | Water j Temp. °FJ Low Gear i Intermediate Gear High Gear 5ear Jsed D. B. Gals H. P. per Hours Hour p'r Gal Gab. I per \ Air Rad. Hour Draw Bar H. P. Draw Draw Draw Bar Miles Draw Bar Miles Draw Bar Miles Test Pull per Bar Pull per Bar Pull per iNo. Lbs. j Hour H. P. Lbs. Hour H. P. Lbs. Hour :j:i 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 fnterm. 4.896 5.49 ligh 2.710 6.18 nterm. 4.326 7.78 nterm. 3.397 j 7.82 nterm. 8.493 ! 6.08 .0635 1.040 4.759 0.000 0.000 61 165 47 198 60 185 79 181 77 175 31.55 22.53 40.57 30.20 61.33 6,805 3,277 8,350 7,563 12,360 1.74 2.58 1.82 1.50 1.86 44.64 4,863 40.10 6,016 33.21 4,823 61.27 9,155 3.44 2.50 2.58 2.51 41.28 21.15 40.58 32.02 60.22 £., I I/O 2,241 4,731 3,343 6,240 O. t — 3.54 3.22 3.59 3.62 10: 10: 10- 10; 3igh 3.312 I 5.07 High 2.445 i 4.73 nterm 6.757 5.93 High 3.460 5.65 Sigh 4.531 5.76 1.645 0.782 0.043 0.327 0.538 77 185 54 171 69 171 54 173 37 193 18.66 16.99 51.51 24.01 32.96 4,913 3,054 12,922 3,882 5,750 1.42 2.09 1.50 2.32 2.15 53.25 9,967 2.01 24.79 17.54 49.55 24.52 34.65 3,320 2,080 5,678 2,883 3,969 2.80 3.16 3.27 3.19 3.28 101 10' 10; 10! IK nterm I 3.586 5.89 n term 2.584 6.20 nte m 4.769 5.47 3.302 5.17 iigh 3.013 3.97 3.30 63 186 2.696 71 192 0.00 67 177 000 70 177 1.704 77 210 27.54 4,850 2.13 18.48 3,327 2.08 37.59 6,680 2.11 21.54 3,302 2.45 11.57 3,533 1.23 26.20 19.34 37.58 19.24 3,705 2,816 5,182 2,557 2.65 2.58 2.72 2.83 24.03 18.74 31.77 16.72 13.19 2,720 3.32 11 2,228 3.15 11: 2,593 4.59 Hi 1,993 3.15 11 1,969 2.51 11 3,696 3.46 11 867.5 4.505 11 3,040 2.86 11 nterm 4.121 6.65 nterm 1.788 5.23 aw 2.944 6.23 4.809 88 195 1.165 91.5 210 0.143 59 166 32.64 6,321 1.935 12.70 2,727 1.745 22.37 4,374 1.92 35.54 13.27 4,922 1,625 2.71 3.06 34.13 10.41 23.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests E. E. Brackett Enffineer-in-Charge of Tractor Tests O. W. Sjogren C. W. Smith Lew Wallace Board of Tractor Test Engineers This bulletin summarizes all reports of Nebraska official tractor tests for 1924 and 1925 (Nos. 101 to 118 inclusive). As in previous tests the tractors used were certified by the manufacturers as being regular stock model machines. It should be remembered that the tractors were in the hands of skilled operators during the tests and the results obtained are probably better than would be secured by the average operator. Tractors are credited only with the power delivered to the measuring apparatus, no allowances or corrections being made for atmospheric conditions, driver slip, belt losses, or other losses. Fuels were of ordinary kinds regularly sup - plied to the trade, no special or high test grades being used. Regular operating settings of the carburetor, spark, air heater, and governor are not considered adjustments. Copies of the original reports contain three pages each and are available at five cents per report from the Agricul - tural Engineering Department, Agricultural College, Uni - versity of Nebraska, Lincoln. The accompanying table is made up from data shown in the reports and the following extracts are also taken from these reports and from the specifications submitted with the applications for the tests: Test No. 101. BEAR " B " 25-35. Bear Tractor Inc., New York City. April 1 to 8, 1924. American Bosch " AT4 " magneto. Schebler "A" 13,4 inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Simplex centrifugal type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Dow metal pistons. Lynite (aluminum alloy) con - necting rods. Chassis: Tracklayer type; two tracks, both drivers; mul - tiple dry disc clutches. Gated Speeds: Low, 2.35 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.80 miles per hour; high, 6.15 miles per hour. Comments: Slot in governor plunger lengthened 3/32 inch. Point of one spark plug readjusted. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 212 Test No. 102. JOHN DEERE "D" 15-27. Waterloo Gasoline Engine Co., Waterloo, Iowa. April 11 to 17, 1924. Splitdorf Aero " 246C " magneto. Schebler " D " li/ 2 inch carburetor. Donaldson Simplex 2 inch oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; own make dry disc clutch; enclosed chain drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.45 miles per hour; high, 3.27 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 103. OIL PULL " S " 30-60. Advance Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., LaPorte, Indiana. September 6 to 13, 1924. American Bosch " DU4 " magneto. Secor-Higgins 2% inch carburetor. Own two stage air cleaner; centrifugal first stage, oil fibre second stage. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; own disc clutch; en - closed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate. 2.5 miles per hour ; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 104. BEST " S 30 " 25-30. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 22, 1924. American Bosch " ZR4 " magneto. Stromberg " MP3 " lVi inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Tracklayer type, two tracks both drivers; mul - tiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.75 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.63 miles per hour; high, 3.63 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 105. BEST " A 60 " 50-60. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 29, 1924. American Bosch " ZR4 Ed 18 " magneto. Stromberg " M4 " Special 1% inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests 5 Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Tracklayer type, two tracks, both drivers; mul - tiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1% miles per hour; intermediate, 2% miles per hour; high, 3% miles per hour. Comments : At the end of the test the vacuum tank leaked at the bottom seam. Exhaust valve on No. 1 cylinder would not hold compression. Test No. 106. HART-PARR 16-30. Hart-Parr Co., Charles City, Iowa. October 14 to 23, 1924. KW " T " magneto. Stromberg " MB3 " IV2 inch carbu - retor. United, whirling vane type dry air cleaner. Madison- Kipp lubricator. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted with crank - shaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: During the low speed maximum drawbar test the shift gear would not stay in mesh unless the shift lever was held in place by the operator. Adjustment of the end play of the clutch shaft was made in an unsuccessful attempt to correct the trouble. Test No. 107. HART-PARR 12-24. Hart-Parr Co., Charles City, Iowa. October 14 to 23, 1924. KW " T " magneto. Stromberg " MB3 " iy 2 inch carbu - retor. United, whirling vane type dry air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2^ miles per hour; high, 3V£ miles per hour. Comments : During the rated drawbar test one spark plug was cleaned (points had burned together) . Test No. 108. MONARCH " D6-60 " 40-60. Monarch Tractors, Inc., Watertown, Wisconsin. October 24 to Novem - ber 1, 1924. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">6 American Bosch " AT6 Ic " magneto. Stromberg " M4 " 1% inch carburetor. No air cleaner. Pharo oil type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Track layer type, two tracks; open chain drive; disc clutch; brake bands for steering control. Rated Speeds: Low, IV2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2Vfc miles per hour; high, 3Vfc miles per hour. Comments: Six cotter keys in track shoe pins broke off; two of them were replaced during the test. During the limber-up run the gear shift lock spring weakened and gears had to be locked in mesh when the drawbar tests were run. Te«t No. 109. CASE 18-32. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 11 to November 4, 1924. Bosch "AT4.IVC3" magneto. Kingston "L" 13/ 8 inch carburetor. Donaldson " Simplex " oil fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.46 miles per hour; high, 3.28 miles per hour. Comments: During the maximum drawbar test the clutch was adjusted once. Test No. 110. CASE 25-45. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 28 to November 9, 1924. Bosch " ZR4 " magneto. Kingston " L " 2 inch carburetor. Own make water type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Chassis: Four wheel type, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; expanding shoe type clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 3.2 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the right cylinder head gasket burned out and both gaskets were then </seg>
            <seg id="p011">7 Test No. 111. OIL PULL " M " 20-35. Advance-Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., LaPorte, Indiana. March 29 to April 15, 1925. American Bosch " DU4/2Ed.22 " magneto. Secor-Higgins 2Ys inch carburetor. Donaldson " Simplex " oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubri - cator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Te»t No. 112. OIL PULL "L" 15-25. Advance-Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., LaPorte, Indiana. March 29 to April 16, 1925. American Bosch " DU4/2Ed.22 " magneto. Secor-Higgins 1 13/16 inch carburetor. Donaldson " Simplex " oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Kmments: After the belt tests and before the drawbar were run, the first ring on the left cylinder was found stuck in its groove. This was corrected by cleaning. Test No. 113. MONARCH "C" 25-35. Monarch Trac- tors, Inc., Watertown, Wisconsin. April 16 to 24, 1925. Robert Bosch " DU4 " magneto. Stromberg " M4 " 1% inch carburetor. Bennett oiled fiber and centrifugal type air cleaner. Pharo oil type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Dow metal pistons. Duralumin connecting rods. Chassis: Tracklayer type, two tracks, both drivers; open chain drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 1.75 miles per hour ; intermediate, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour. Comments: Just after the rated load belt test, the fan belt was shortened. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 212 Te»t No 114. HEIDER 15-27. Rock Island Plow Co., Rock Island, Illinois. May 7 to 13, 1925. Dixie " 46 " magneto. Kingston " L " iy 2 inch carburetor. United, whirling vane type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical L-head, head not removable, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; friction drive. Rated Speeds: One to four miles per hour. Comments: During the belt run before any data were taken, the right pulley shaft bearing heated excessively. It was removed and balls found to be chipped, ball retainer bent and broken, and inner race broken. It appeared that the trouble was caused by a defective inner race. A new bearing was installed. The friction drive ring was found slightly burned (probably due to excessive slip when bearing failed) and was replaced by new ring. Test No. 115. SHAWNEE THIRTY (Road Maintainer). Shaw-Enochs Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 16 to 28, 1925. Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Zenith 1 inch carburetor. United, whirling vane type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head (Ricardo) removable, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Two drive wheels (by which machine is steered) in front carry engine and transmission. Two non-drivers in rear carry road working equipment and operator. Enclosed worm gear drive. Disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; high 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 116. OIL PULL " R " 25-45. Advance Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., LaPorte, Indiana. July 7 to 14, 1925. American Bosch " DU4/2 Ed22 magneto. Secor-Higgins 2% inch carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, removable head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.5 miles per hour ; high, 3 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests 9 Comments: After the limber-up run and before any of the data for this report were taken, a gasket was inserted under left bearing plate to provide more end clearance for the crankshaft. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING " FARMALL." International Harvester Company of America, Chicago, Illinois. September 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf " Aero " 937950 magneto. Ensign " 3DA600F " 1 inch carburetor. Pomona Model 118 oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 118. THE MINNEAPOLIS TYPE B 17-30. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. October 21 to November 12, 1925. American Bosch " ED21TC " magneto. Wheeler-Schebler " A " lVa inch carburetor. Donaldson " Simplex " oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Detroit lubricator. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Chasis: Four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.23 miles per hour; high, 2.84 miles per hour. Comments: It was necessary to drill eight holes before the left extension rim could be attached. After the limber - ing-up run and before any official data were taken the engine head was removed, the carbon cleaned out, and all valves ground. During the limbering-up run and the rated drawbar test, the fuel line clogged up, requiring stops for cleaning out. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>