<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00077.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1933-1934</title>
               <date value="1935-01-01">1935-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1933 - 1934 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1935 . i ' From: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. t To: His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. subject: Biennial Report of 1933 and 1934. El- l n compliance with requirements of Sections 1 to 5, Chap - ter 55, Article 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1929, the following Biennial Report for the calendar years 1933 and 1934 is respectfully submitted. The Nebraska National Guard occupies an enviable posi - tion in its standing in the National Guard of the United States and that steady improvement which has so richly rewarded the efforts of its personnel for years has never been more potent than during the period covered by this report. Each year training has material - ly improved in a logical and progressive manner, and notwithstand - ing the fact that many states allot much more money for use of the National Guard, I sincerely believe there is not a better organization in any State in the Union than has Nebraska at this time. 2. The community interest in our units and the assistance given by committees of Chambers of Commerce and by the citizenship as a whole has been most gratifying and most helpful and I feel that this support is well warranted for it has become known throughout the State that our training camps are absolutely clean and wholesome and the fear of young men acquiring any bad habits In the Nebraska National Guard is a thing of the past. 3. Annual armory inspections are made by officers of the United States Army detailed for that purpose. The results of our last armory inspection evidenced the closest conformity to prescribed schedules and found our organizations as a whole very satisfactory. 4. As previously reported, the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Nebraska National Guard have to con - tend is the rental of armories. It Is almost Impossible to rent suit- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL able buildings and we conduct a continual fight to hold the rentals down; on the other hand, the government is very insistent that we have armories that afford adequate protection to government proper - ty and that have ample space for armory drills and training. It Is realized that Nebraska is behind many of the other States that have State owned armories and the State is frequently criti - cised by inspectors on this account but, though constantly urged to do so, I have not been willing and am not now willing to submit an armory building program for your consideration, as well as that of the Legislature, until conditions generally speaking have become nearer normal. 5. The results of the Armory Drill Training and the Field Training for the period of this report have been very satisfactory. The reports of officers from the War Department assigned to make inspections indicate that the state of training of all, organizations has steadily improved and that our National Guard of today is better fitted to serve the State and Nation in the event of an emergency than ever before in its history. In connection with the armory drills it is gratifying to note that the attendance is better than it has ever been before and that many of our companies have enlisted to full strength authorized by the War Department and have a waiting list of those anxious to join. 6. The following is a list of the Tinted States Army Officers and Sergeants who are detailed by the War Department to the Stan - of Nebraska for instructional purposes, and in reporting the increased efficiency of our National Guard proper appreciation of all the ele - ments concerned therein would be lacking were not the regular army instructors on duty with our troops accorded due recognition for their line services to us. They have all given us the finest of cooper - ation, the most understanding and sympathetic aid in our problems and in general, every opportunity to make the most of their efficiency aud time. Major Ralph Hall. Inf., USA.. Lincoln, Nebraska Major Jack L. Meyer, QMC, USA., Lincoln. Nebraska Captain Harold H. Elarth, Inf., USA., Omaha. Nebraska Staff Sgt. Joel G. Gerard, Inf.. USA., Lincoln. Nebraska Sergeant Zack T. Scarborough. MC. USA.. Lincoln, Nebraska 7. . In conclusion I wish to express my appreciation to the officers and enlisted men of the National Guard who have, through their </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL hearty cooperation, assisted in bringing the Nebraska National Guard to the present high state of efficiency and the personnel thereof to al much higher standard. I also desire to extend my appreciation to tlie dozens of Chambers of Commerce and to the thousands of loyal citizens who have given us their moral support and thereby assisted ill making the Nebraska National Guard a bigger and better or - ganization. H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. FINANCIAL STATEMENT NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD . V-' -'■'■ ■■■'"'."■ E :: '7' Appropriation Hienniuin July 1. 1933, to July 1, 1935 $110,000.00 l-xpeiulitlires .Inly 1. 193:), to December 31, 1934 Office Salaries $10,935.00 Office Maintenance 2,275.15 Miscellaneous Nat'l Gd. Expense.. 2,796.55 Labor and Salary Caretaker — Rifle Range 8,100.08 Rifle Range Miscellaneous 5,587.37 Arsenal Expense 1,923.22 Armory Rental' 26,985.00 58,602.37 Balance ? 51.397.63 STKKNGTH BY COMPANY AND DETACHMENT AS OF DKt EMBER 31, 19-4 Eni. War. Officers Men Officers State Staff and State Detachment S 21 H5TH DIVISION Detachment, Hq. Stall" 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (19th Brigade Headquarters 4 134th Infantry- Headquarters 6 Med. Dept. Det 4 30 Regtl. Hq. Co 3 62 Service Co 4 98 1 Howitzer Co 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 1st Bn. 3 24 Company A 3 60 Company B 3 64 Company C 3 61 Company D 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 2nd Bn 3 21 Company E 3 63 Company F 3 64 Company G 3 64 Company H : 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co.. 3rd Bn 3 25 Company I 3 64 Company K 3 64 Company L 3 64 Company M 3 64 65 1081 1 110th Medical Regiment Headquarters 8 Service Co 4 66 1 130th Coll. Co 2 61 130th Amb. Co 2 47 166th Hosp. Co 6 63 110th Vet. Co 7 2 39 24 276 1 :55th Division Train Headquarters 1 Hq. Detachment 2 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL MedY Dept. Det 1 16 1.17th Mot. Tr. Co 2 43 138th Mot. Tr. Co 2 44 119th Mot. Rep. Sec 1 19 119th Wagon Co 3 49 120th Wagon Co 3 51 15 236 Grand Total 122 Officers .', . 2 Warrant Officers 1617 Enlisted Men ROSTER OF OFFICERS OK NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD STATE STAFF Paul. H. J. Brig. Gen., AGD, State Capitol, Lincoln O'Connell, Frank B., Major, AGD, State Capitol, Lincoln Clark, Clarence L., Capt., JAGD, 410 Richards Blk., Lincoln Stein. H. C, Major, QMC. State Capitol, Lincoln McConnaughey, W. E., Major, QMC, State Capitol, Lincoln Jurgensen, Walter H., Captain, QMC, 3636 F Street, Lincoln Yoder, Byron E., Capt., QMC, 535 No. 24th St., Lincoln Gillaspie. Trev. li.. Major, Ord. Dept., Post Office, Lincoln 35th DIVISION Detachment, Hq. Staff ■i ' Thornton, Thos. Q., Lt. Col., Inf. (G-l). 1408 W. O. W. Bldg., Omaha Poteet, Marcus L.. Lt. Col., QMC (G-4), 103 1st Nat'l Bank Bldg.. Lincoln Stout. Richard P., Lt. Col., JAGD, (Div. JA). 722 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Young, A. Farley. Capt., JAGD (Asst. to Dlv. JA) , Court House, Lincoln Ellis, Harry H.. Lt. Col., QMC, (Div. QM). Post Office, Holdrege Leftier, Delbert C, Capt.. QMC, (Asst. to Div. QM). 920 West Avenue, Holdrege </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (iDth Brigade Headquarters Thomas, Amos, Brig. Gen.. Inf., 824 Omaha Natl Bk. Bldg., Omaha Utterback, Wm. G., Major. Inf. (Ex. Off.), 706 Central Ave.. Nebraska City Dudley, Henry H., Capt., Inf. (Adj. I. State Capitol. Lincoln Crocker, Judd W., 1st Lt., Inf. (Aide), 424 Farnam Bldg., Omaha 134th Infantry Headquarters Douglas, Robert G., Colonel. Inf.. State Capitol. Lincoln McCormick, Clyde E., Lt. Col.. Inf. (Ex. Off . I , SOS So. 59th St.. Omaha Stoll, Fred H., Major. Inf. (P.&amp;T;), 609 Court St.. Beatrice Blodgett, M. A.. Capt.. Inf. (Supp. Off.), Omaha Collier, Harold L.. Capt.. Inf.. I Asst. I'.&amp;T.l. 4.'" No. Ifith St.. Beatrice Turner, Howard R„ Capt., Inf. (Adj.), 2025 Harwood St., Lincoln .Med. Dept. Det. Ensor, Rolland R., Major, MC. 1105 1st Natl Bank Bld«.. Omaha Attwood, Norman H., Capt., MC, 813 Med. Arts Bldg.. Omaha Klnyoun, Floyd H., Capt., MC, 1105 1st Natl Bank Bldg., Omaha Sands, Robert L., Capt., MC. 6109i£ Military Ave.. Omaha ■ ■'•'•' Headquarters Co. McGlll, Albert L., Capt.. Inf.. 1505 Olin Ave., Omaha Bradley, James A.. 2nd Lt., Inf., 214 N. W. Bell Bldg.. Omaha Service Co. Beckley, Harry A., Capt.. Inf.. 613 Grant Ave.. York Anderson, Raymond J., 1st Lt., Inf., Citizens Nat'l Bank, York Davis, James. W., 1st Lt., Inf., Middlebrook's Store, York Downer, Worth O., 2nd Lt., Inf., 610 Lincoln Ave., York McCall. George A.. War. Off. (Band), 120 W. 7th St.. York Howitzer Co. Allison, J. Ned, Capt., Inf., Gering Laughlin, Leslie J., 1st Lt., Inf., Gering Wood, Warren C, 2nd Lt., Inf., Courier Bldg., Gering </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. 1st Bn. Mlltonberger, Butler B., -Major, Inf., Post Office, North Platte Hq. Co.. 1st lln. Yager, Leslie, Jr., 1st Lt., Inf., 716 Central Ave., Nebraska City Pitzer, John M.. 2nd Lt.. Inf.. Nebraska City Co. A Thurman, Ray A.. Capt., Inf., Cleveland Store, Nebraska City Morton, Thos. S., 1st Lt., Inf., Court House, Nebraska City Wilson. Robt. R., 2nd Lt., Inf., 191S 1st Ave., Nebraska City po. B Myers, Merven F., Capt., Inf., Stone St., Falls City Smith, Leo L., 1st Lt., Inf., High School, Falls City Spencer, Harold J., 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 1713 Fulton St., Falls City I Co. C Coonley, Dean E., Capt. Inf., Court House, Beatrice Boatsnian, Alford C, 1st Lt., Inf., 422 No. 7th St., Beatrice scott. Harrison F., 2nd Lt., Inf., 709 No. 9th St., Beatrice i Co. I&gt; '■■■■'.•'■ Petersen. Fred C. Capt., Inf., Post Office, North Platte Wilson. Denver W., 1st Lt., Inf., 723 No. Jefferson St., No. Platte Godwin. Dale M., 2nd Lt., Inf., 108 W. 2nd St.. North Platte Hq. 2nd llll. Eby. Louis R.. Major. Inf.. Post Office, Hartington Hq. Co., *_nd Bn. Trout. John T.. 1st Lt.. Inf.. Armory. 12th &amp; Dodge Sts., Omaha Co. K Eatwell, Ora A., Capt., Inf., Post Office, Scottsbluff Runyon, Harold M., 1st Lt., Inf., Post Office, Scottsbluff Cooper, Basil A., 2nd Lt., Inf., 14 W 17th St., Scottsbluff </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Co. F Hardy, Lloyd R., Capt., Inf., Post Office, Hartington Stejskal, Julius, 1st Lt., Inf., Hartington Ready, George E., 2nd Lt., Inf., 500 Washington Ave., Hartington Co. G Riley, Ivan C, Capt., Inf., Hastings Nat'l Bank, Hastings Van Fleet, Robt. J., 1st Lt.. Inf., Fire Dept.. Hastings Lovell, Robt. A., 2nd Lt., Inf., 220 Lincoln Ave., Hastings Co. H Barratt, Edgar, Capt., Inf., 1st Nat'l Bank Bldg., Grand Island James, Percy F., 1st Lt., Inf., 317 No. Sycamore St.. Grand Island McElroy, Francis L., 2nd Lt., Inf.. G. I. Culvert &amp; Metal Works. Grand Island Hq. 3rd Bn. Grasborg, Bert C. Major, Inf., 1023 U. P. Bldg.. Omaha Hq. Co., 3rd Bn. Dier, Clifford L., 1st Lt., Inf., 2828 N St.. Lincoln Hervert, Fred G., 2nd Lt.. Inf., 1610 Sumner St., Lincoln Co. I Van Kirk, Rolla C, Capt., Inf., 802 1st Natl Bank Bid*:.. Lincoli Stewart, Clarence J., 1st Lt., Inf., 1127 Plum St., Lincoln Weyand, Foster H.. 2nd Lt.. Inf., 1512 N St.. Lincoln Co. K Peterson, Emil B., Capt.. Inf., 204 U. P. Bldg.. Omaha Gatz, Edwin C, 1st Lt., Inf., 3105 No. 59th St., Omaha Bach'man, Earl E.. 2nd Lt., Inf., 204 U. P. Bldg., Omaha Co. L Thomsen, Alfred, Capt., Inf., Rt. 8, Florence Sta., Omana Kelso, Earl H., 1st Lt., Inf., 1919 Emmet St., Omaha Roberts, Donald Ii, 2nd Lt., Inf., 3119 No. 55th St., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Co. M Ceesen, Edward J., Capt., inf.. 641 Seward St., Sewaid Jones. Erwin A., 1st Lt., Inf., Seward Hauck, Paul C. 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 509 So. Columbia, Seward llOlh Med. llegt. Headquarters Hilton. David C. Colonel, MC, 305 Richards Blk., Lincoln Bartholomew, P. H.. Lt. Col., MC, (Ex. Off.). State Capitol, Lincoln -•vans, J. North, Major. MC. (P.&amp;T.). Columbus Itrooks, Karl B., Major, MC, 939 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Bennett, John R.. Major, DC. 917 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Norden. Carl J., Major, VC, 227 No. 9th St., Lincoln Deppen. Earl N., Capt., MC.' (Adj.), 911 Sec. Mut. Bldg., Lincoln Service Co. Hall. Harry R.. Capt., MAC, 304 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Stearns. Harry A.. Capt.. MAC, Post Office, Lincoln Strickland, Henry H., Capt., MAC, 4332 L St.. Lincoln Neely, J. Marshall, 1st Lt., MC, 1927 South St., Lincoln Welch, Lyle A., War. Off. (Band). 1939 So. 10th St.. Lincoln 130lli Coll. Co. Evans. Carroll D.. Jr.. Capt., MC, Columbus Anderson. Ronald C, 1st Lt.. MC, 1319 8th St., Columbus 13-th Anil). Co. I Swansoh, Leonard A., Capt., MC. 412 No. Hastings Ave., Hastings Thomas, Dwight P., Capt., MAC, 510 E. 5th St., Hastings lii-ili Hosp. Co. Johnson. Rodney K.. Capt.. MC, Friend Wells, Francis A., Capt.. MC, 1010 Sharp Bldg., Lincoln Johnston, Leonard R., Capt., DC, 916 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Anderson, Jas. B., Capt., MC, 1119 Fed. Trust Bldg.. Lincoln Merideth. John A., Capt., MC, 914 Fed. Trust Bldg., Lincoln Barber, George H., 1st Lt., MAC, 2248 Sewell St., Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL HOth Vet. Co. Alford, S. W., Capt., VC, 1311 No. 37th St., Lincoln Skidmore, Louis V., 1st Lt., VC, 3859 Dudley St., Lincoln 33th Div. Qm. Tn. Headquarters Henninlger, Guy N., Major, QMC, Court House, Kearney Hq. Detach.' Browne, Wm. H., 1st Lt), QMC, 2701 Everett St., Lincoln Gish, Herb. D., 2nd Lt., QMC, 2020 South St., Lincoln Metl. Dept. Dot. Rose, Wallace E., Capt.. MC, 2218% Central Ave., Kearney 137th Mot. Tr. Co. Gillette. Edward. 1st Lt., QMC. 553 W. Ave., Holdrege 138th Mot. Tr. Co. Olson, Nels A., 1st Lt., QMC, 537% No. Broad St., Fremont Peterson, Vaughn, 2nd Lt., QMC, Hancock Street, Fremont 119th Mot. Rep. Sec. Yaklsh, Wesley H., 1st Lt., QMC, 1518 No. Clarkson St., Fremont 119th Wagon Co. .Bates, Merton O., Capt., QMC, Lexington Burnett, Oliver H., 1st Lt., QMC, 1001 Jackson St., Lexington Klffln, Monte R., 2nd Lt., QMC. Lexington 120th Wagon Co. Atkinson. Wm. J., Capt., QMC, 927 W. 28th St., Kearney Mattson, Herman G., 1st Lt., QMC, 107 E. 27th St., Kearney Beaver, George R., 2nd Lt., QMC, 2721 Ave. D, Kearney </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL - STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1933 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1933, to October 31, 1933. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 15, 1933 General Orders No. 2 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Tuesday, May 30, 1933, consecrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National Flag will, in accordance with par. 2, sub-par. 11, AR 260-10, be displayed on all armories and all sta - tions of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organizations in the observance of the day Commanding Officers of National Guard Organizations will place their respective commands at the disposal of local repre - sentatives of the Grand Army of the Republic. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 6, 1933 General Orders No. 3 1. Upon authority of the Chief, Militia Bureau, contained in letter M. B. 325.4 (Med)-Neb-ll, dated May 26, 1933. the Band Section, Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard,' stationed at Crete, Nebraska, will be mustered out. of State and Federal service June 16, 1933, by Major -W. E. McConnaughey. He will forward to this office final copies of Form 100 and all books and records of the section, together with the discharges of the en - listed personnel. 2. Warrant Officer Lumir C Havlicek and the enlisted personnel will be discharged June 16, 1933, in accordance with paragraph 8b, NGR 22. 3. All property pertaining td the Band Section will be transferred by the officer designated to muster-out this organization to Captain Harry R. Ball, Service Co., 110th Medical Regiment. 4. The Regimental Commander, 110th Medical Regiment, is authorized to reorganize the Band Section as a part of the Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, with station at Lincoln, Ne - braska. When the new section is ready for inspection for Federal </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL recognition application should be made to the Corps Area Commander through this office and Form No. 113-M.B. and a complete roster furnished. i By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: E H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 11, 1933 General Orders No. 4 1. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. i:;-l. file NGB-354.1 Nebr.-25, July 7, 1933, the State Staff and State Detachment, Detachment, Headquarters 69th Infantry Brigade (I offs.). Detachment, Headquarters 35th Division (1 off.), 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, and 110th Medical Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 7 to 21, 1933, inclusive, under command of Brigadier General Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty the above named organizations will return to their home stations. Attention is invited to par. 37, NGR 45. a. Company E, 134th Infantry, will be allowed sixteen days' pay and the Howitzer Company. 134th Infantry, will be allowed seventeen days' pay. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Lt. Col. H. C. Stein, QMC. Detachment, Headquarters 35th Division, and two enlisted men of the State Detachment will go into camp at the earliest pos - sible moment August 4, 1933, and will remain in camp August 22 and "- 3 1933 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment August 5. 1933, taking the first train available for that purpose: </seg>
            <seg id="p018">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL State Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, two Captains, QMC, and nineteen enlisted men; Service Detachment, Ser - vice Company, 134th Infantry, consisting or one Captain, S. O., one First Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detach - ment, 35th Division Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six enlisted men; and Service Detachment, Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, consistnig of one Captain, S. O., and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to Lt. Col. H. C Stein, August 5, 1933. The Com - manding Officer of the 110th Medical Regiment will designate one Captain, MC, to accompany the advance detachment of his regiment and will see that he is provided with the necessary medical equipment to establish a camp infirmary. This Captain will remain in camp with the rear detachment August 22, 1933. 4. Upon arrival in camp August 5. 1933, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134th Infantry, will establish mess for his Detachment, and the Commanding Officer, Service Detach - ment, 110th Medical Regiment, will immediately establish mess for the State Detachment, Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, and his Detachment. The officers In charge should see that at least one regular cook is included for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train and 110th Medi - cal Regiment will see that equipment necessary for establishing commissaries is forwarded with advance detachments. 5. A rear detachment consisting of one Major, QMC. and two Captains, QMC, of the State Staff, and nineteen enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 22, 1933, for the pur - pose of necessary detail incident to the departure or troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedule's, supplies, equip - ment, etc., will be handled by circular letters from this office. 7. The Camp Commander of the Nebraska National Guard will see that all officers are physically examined in accordance with para - graph 4, NGR 27. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp. 8. The following named officers, residing at places other than the headquarters or organization to which they belong, are authorized transportation in kind from their actual residence, which is shown opposite their names, to the annual field training of the Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL National Guard at Ashland, Nebraska, August 7 to 21 inclusive, and return to their home stations. Major Wm. G. Utterback, Hq. 69th Inf. Brig., Nebraska City Capt. Henry H. Dudley, Hq. 69th Inf. Brig., Lincoln Lt. Col. Clyde E. McCormick, Hq. 134th Inf., Omaha Major Fred H. Stoll, Hq. 134th Inf., Beatrice Major Harold C Capsey, Chaplain, 134th Inf., Wayne Capt. M. A. Blodgett, Hq. 134th Inf., North Platte Capt. Wm. H. Achenbach, Med. Dept. Det., 134th Inf., Nebraska City Major J. North Evans, Hq. 110th Med. Regt., Columbus 9. The travel directed is necessary ih the military service of the State. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant Geueral, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: II. C STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 12, 1933 General Orders. No. 5 1. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. 4 3-2. file NGB-354.1 Nebr.-25, July 7, 1933, Detachment, Headquarters 35th Division (5 officers), will go Into Camp of Instruction at Fort Riley, Kansas, August 13 to 27, 1933, inclusive, and upon completion of this tour of duty will return to their home stations. 2. The travel directed is necessary In the military service of the State. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Januaiy 1, 1934 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1934, to October 31, 1934. By order of the Governor: ; H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 15, 1934 General Orders No. 2 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Wednesday, May 30, 1934, consecrated to the brave; soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE' ADJUTANT GENERAL American Republic, the National Flag will, in accordance with para - graph 2, sub-paragraph 11, AR 260-10, be displayed on all armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organizations in the observance of the day, Commanding Officers of National Guard Organizations will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 18, 1934 General Orders No. 3 1. Pursuant to authority contained ln Training Authority No. 43-1, file NGB 354.1 Nebr.-25, July 14, 1934, the State Staff and State Detachment, 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, and 110th Medical Regiment will go Into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 6 to 20, 1934, Inclusive, under command of Brigadier General Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty the above named organizations will return to their home stations. Attention is invited to par. 37, NGR 45. a. Company E, 134th Infantry, will be allowed sixteen days' pay and the Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will be allowed seventeen days' pay. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C Stein, QMC, State Staff, and two enlisted men of the State Detachment will go into camp at the earliest possible moment August 3, 1934, and will remain in camp August 21 and 22, 1934. 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment August 4, 1934, taking tbe first train available for that purpose: State Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, one Major, Ordnance Department, one Captain, QMC (Commissary), and nineteen enlisted men; Service Detachment. Sen-Ice Company, 134th Infantry, consisting of one Captain, S. O., one First Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six enlisted men; and Service Detachment, Service Company, 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain, S. O., and ten enlisted men. They will form ah ad - vance detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and estab - lishing camp for the reception or troops and will report to Major H. C Stein August 4, 1934. The Commanding Officer or the 110th Medi - cal Regiment will designate one Captain, MC, to accompany the ad - vance detachment of his regiment and will see that he is provided with the necessary medical equipment to establish a camp infirmary. This Captain will remain in camp with the rear detachment August 21. 1934. 4. Upon arrival in camp, August 4, 1934, the Commanding Oriicer, Service Detachment, 134th Inrantry, will establish mess tor his Detachment, and the Commanding Otflcer, Service Detachment. 110th Medical Regiment, will immediately establish mess lor the State Detachment, Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, and his Detachment. The orficers in charge should see that at least one regular cook is included for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train and 110th Medical Regiment will see that equipment necessary for establishing com - missaries is forwarded with advance detachments. 5. A rear detachment consisting of one Major, QMC. one Major. Ordnance Department, and one Captain, QMC (Commissary), ot the State Staff, and nineteen enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 21, 1934, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the deptarture of troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., will be handled by circular letters from this oriice. 7. The Camp Commander or the Nebraska National Guard will see tha's, all officers are physically examined in accordance with para- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL graph 1. NCR 27. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp. 8. The following named officers, residing at places other than the headquarters or organization to which they belong, are authorized transportation in kind from their actual residence, which is shown opposite their names, to the annual field training or the Nebraska National Guard at Ashland, Nebraska, August 6 to 20, 1934, in - clusive, and return to their home stations. Lt. Col. Clyde E. McCormick, Hq. 134th Int., Omaha Major Fred H. Stoll, Hq. 134th Int., Beatrice Major Harold C Capsey, Chaplain, 134th Inf., Wayne Capt. M. A. Blodgett, Hq. 134th Inf., Omaha Capt. Harold L. Collier, Hq. 134th Int., Beatrice Capt. Wm. H. Achenbach, Med. Dept. Det., 134th Inf., Nebraska City Major J. North Evans, Hq. 110th Med. Regt., Columbus 9. The travel directed is necessary in the military service ot the State. By order or the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OF THE' ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 25. 1934 General Orders No. 4 1. Pursuant to the requirements of paragraph 3. NGR 75-11, dated June 30, 1927, the Annual Inventory of Property pertaining to the organizations of the Nebraska National Guard herein men - tioned will be made on the following dates: Co. F, 134th Inf. Hartington October 20, 1934 Hq. Co., 1st Bn., 134th Inf. Nebraska City October 22, 1934 Co. A, 134th Inf. Nebraska City October 23, 1934 Co. B, 134th Inf. Falls City October 24, 1934 110th Vet. Co., 110th Med. Regt. Lincoln October 26, 1934 Co. E, 134th InL Scottsbluff October 29. 1934 Howitzer Co., 134th Inf. Gering October 30, 1934 Co. D, 134th Inf. North Platte November 1, 1934 Co. C, 134th Inf. Beatrice November 5. 1934 138th Mot. Tr. Co., 35th Div. Tn. Fremont November 7, 1934 119th Mot. Rep.Sec, 35th Div. Tn. Fremont November 8. 1934 Hq. Det., 35th Div. Tn. Lincoln November 9. 1934 137th Mot. Tr. Co., 35th Div. Tn. Holdrege November 12. 1934 119th Wagon Co., 35th Div. Tn. Lexington Xovenibei 13, 1934 120th Wagon Co., 35th Div. Tn. Kearney November 14. 19.4 Med. Dept. Det., 35th Div. Tn. Kearney November 15, 1934 130th Coll. Co., 110th Med. Regt. Columbus November 16, 1934 Co. G, 134th Inf. Hastings November 19., 1934 130th Amb. Co. 110th Med. Regt. Hastings November 20, 1934 Co. H, 134th Inf. Grand Island November 21, 1934 Service Co., 134th InL York November 22, 1934 Co. M, 134th Inf. Seward November 23, 1934 166th Hosp. Co., 110th Med. Regt. Lincoln November 26, 1934 Hq. Co., 3rd Bn., 134th Inf. Lincoln November 27. 1934 Co. I, 134th Inf. Lincoln November 28, 1934 Service Co., 110th Med. Regt. Lincoln November 30, 1934 Co. L, 134th Inf. Omaha December 3, 1934 Regtl. Hq. Co., 134th Inf. Omaha December 4. 1934 Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., 134th Inf. Omaha December ... 1934 Co. K, 134th Inf. Omaha December 6. 1934 Med. Dept. Det., 134th Inf. Omaha December 7. 1934 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. All property will be arranged so that it may be counted with the least possible delay. Individual equipment records WD MB Form No. 30 will be posted to date and an abstract of items shown thereon will be made up so that same may be considered in the inventory. 3. Attention is -invited to the provisions of NGR 75-3, dated January 22, 1927, which requires that all property be kept in the armory. 4. Responsible Officer with Supply Sergeant and two (.2) assist - ants will be present to assist In the inventory on the date set. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">24 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 25, 1934 General Orders No. 5 1. The Commander-in-Chief announces with profound sorrow the death of Major Harold C Capsey, Chaplain, 134th Inlantry, Nebraska National Guard, October 19, 1934. 2. Harold C Capsey was born in London, England, August 4, 1884. He enlisted in the Regular Army at Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, June 19. 1918, with the grade or pri - vate. Served with the Medical Department Post Hospital. Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, until he was honorably discharged August 2, 1918, to accept commission. Appointed First Lieu - tenant Chaplain, August 3, 1918, Regular Army Training Camp, Fort Monroe, Virginia. Served with the 339 Field Artillery to ; and the 350 Infantry to discharge. Served overseas from August 23, 1918, to May 7, 1919. Honorably discharged May 9, 1919. Commissioned Captain Chaplain, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, S. O. No. 42, AGO — Nebraska, May 31, 1921. Commissioned Captain Chaplain, ORC, January 27, 1927. ' Commissioned Major Chaplain, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, S. O. No. 72, AGO — Nebraska, June 5, 1930. Commissioned Major Chaplain, ORC, August 5, 1930. 3. Major Capsey's service with the Nebraska National Guard will long be remembered as one of splendid example, uprightness, and decency. As was his work and mission in life to teach the law of both God and Man, so he lived and gave example to others. One of the most beautiful and im - pressive services held at our National Guard encampment the last few years Is a Memorial Service initiated and carried out at the suggestion of Major Capsey. This service Is by its nature a memorial to those members of the Nebraska Na- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">25 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL tional Guard who have been taken from this life auring the preceding year. 4. Coming to this country from a foreign land. Major Capsey had no hesitancy or doubt with regard to his future relations with these United States, as was demonstrated by his ready willingness to enlist and be a soldier of same. At the close ot the war when the National Guard was reorganized he immediately identified himselt with the National Guard ol this state, in order to continue his connections with the National Defense of this country, which in itself indicated his tuture devotion to the national welfare along patriotic lines. Major Capsey will long be remembered as an able and efficient officer of the Nebraska National Guard, the sympathy of which is extended to his entire family in this, their hour or sorrow. By order or the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 25, 1933 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment Fiscal Year 1933. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. 1. In accordance with instructions received from Headquarters, 7th Corps Area, it will be necessary to submit not later than March 1, 1933, requisitions covering supplies and equipment for your com - pany for the balance of the fiscal year 1933. 2. Requisitions received after the date set forth above can not be acted upon prior to Field Training 1933. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ' March 15, 1933 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Status of Members of the National Guard now Receiving Pensions, etc. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The following immediate action letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the Information and guidance of all con - cerned: . "1. Your attention is invited to the Inclosed extract from the Army Appropriation Act, H. R. 14199, Fiscal Year 1934. In accord - ance with the provisions therein, action must be taken on the fol - lowing points by June 30, 1933: a. All members of the National Guard of your state who come within the classes named — those drawing pen - sions, disability allowances, disability compensations, or retired pay must either — (1) be eliminated from the National Guard, or, (2) surrender such emoluments for the period of their services in the National Guard, during the fiscal year 1934. 2. The only exception to the above will be the case of the state adjutant general should he be drawing such emoluments. His federal recogntlon status may continue, but he cannot draw pay thereunder. 3. It will be necessary for the state adjutant general to initiate the necessary action to make effective the requirements of the law as shown in paragraphs 1 and 2 above. 4. Attention is invited to the fact that should any member of the National Guard, whose name appears on the Emergency Officers' Retired List and who does not draw compensation thereunder, desire to remain In the National Guard, there is nothing In the provisions of this Act that would forbid it. 5. It must be noted that under this law the state adjutant general is the only officer who can give up his pay in the National Guard and still continue to be federally recognized. 6. In view of the fact that some of the monies appropriated in this bill may be used as pay in the June 1933 field training camps, and pending further instructions, May 31, 1933, will be the dead line be - yond which no payments will be made to National Guard personnel unless the provisions of the bill referred to herein have been complied with. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7. Instructions as to certificates that will be lequired ou all vouchers for payment of National Guard personnel will be furnished at a later date. (Signed) George E. Leach. Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." 1 Incl. By direction of the Governor: ! H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March Ki. 19 33 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Replacement of Property Damaged or Destroyed by Fire: To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. Information called for in paragraphs two and three must reach this office not later than April 15, 1933. .-'■•■: ■'■■'I "1. Recent losses by fire of property issued to the National Guard have created a serious situation with which the Militia Bureau is confronted. In the great majority of such losses the - state has been relieved from accountability; but the replacement of such property has become a problem, In view of the fact that the free Issue source of supply Is being depleted rapidly, and ! because of the necessity for economy In National Guard and Army appropriations. '"•'..."'■ \ ' 2. In order to assist the Militia Bureau in the studies now being made, information is requested of the approximate value or </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL federal property in each armory, arsenal, hangar, warehouse, gun shed, stable, buildings, etc., in your stale, and the fire in - surance rate on property housed or stored in each such place. 3. It Is suggested that the information relative to insurance rates be obtained through contact by local commanding officers with reliable fire insurance agencies so that rates reported may be as accurate as can be reasonably expected. In this connec - tion rates tor each armory or arsenal should be listed separately. 4. It Is requested the above information be supplied not later than May 1, 1933. For the Chief, Militia Bureau: (Signed) W. H. Waldron, Colonel, M. B. Executive." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 17, 1933 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Claims for Checks. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Finance Officer, U. S. Army, Fort Omaha, Nebraska, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Supplementing the instructions contained in letter of this orfice dated April 4, 1932. in regard to lost or destroyed </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL government checks, you are advised that in the case or checks returned on account of Inability to locate payees. It Is also neces - sary that the payee write this office over his own signature re - questing the return of check. In the case of lost, stolen, destroyed or undelivered checks the payee should be furnished all the In - formation available in regard to the check, so that check may be readily identified when his letter reaches this office. (Signed) E. C Morton, Major, Finance Dept., Finance Off., U. S. Army." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. . - ''. .■''.■ STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 13. 1933 Circular Letter No. 5 - ■ ■■ • i Subject: Ammunition Allowances Calendar Year 1933. . I To: All Responsible Officers Concerned. I 1. The following allowances of caliber .30 ball ammunition for practice firing at home stations is authorized for the calendar year 1933: RIFLE COMPANIES: 100 rds. per man for qualification. 50 rds. per man for requalificatlon. This allowance is for all men in the Company armed with the Rifle who have qualified with the caliber .22. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL SERVICE, HOWITZER, HEADQUARTERS AND MACHINE GUN COMPANIES: 100 ids. per man for qualification. This allowance is only authorized for men armed with the Rifle who have not qualified as Marksmen or better and who have qualified with the caliber .22. DIVISION TRAIN UNITS: 100 rds. per man for qualification. This allowance is only authorized for men armed with the Rifle who have not qualified as Marksmen or better and who have qualified with the caliber .22. 2. It will be noted from the above that only in the Rifle Com - panies are the men who have previously qualified with the caliber .30 authorized to fire this year. 3. There will be no allowance of caliber .45 cartridges author - ized this year. 4. Requisitions based on the above allowances should be sub - mitted at the earliest practicable date. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, - •• The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 1, 1933 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Mother's Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization who may be separated from their mothers on May 8 the duty they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mother's Day. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 1. 1933 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Small Arms Practice. 1933. To: All Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. WHO WILL KIBE AND COURSES TO BE KIKEI). Subject to the amount of ammunition available, the provisions of Training Circular No. 1, MB 1933, and Nebraska Circular Letter No. 5. 1933. will govern small arms practice of all units in this State. 2. SMALL BORE AND PRELIMINARY PRACTICE. All prepara - tory exercises, all small bore firing and all preliminary firing with service ammunition will be completed at home stations. 3. RECORD PRACTICE. All record practice will be fired dur - ing the 1933 Annual Field Training period. 4. RECORDS AND REPORTS. Blank examination forms (for recording the state of progress in preliminary markmanship) . Indivi - dual Score Books and score cards are available. Score cards and Re - port of Individual Classification in Arms (Form AGO 110) must be submitted to cover small bore and preliminary firing. These reports will be In the bands of the regimental or similar unit commander not later than 5 P. M., August 7, 1933. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5. AMMUNITION, TARGETS AND SUPPLIES. a. Ammunition, targets and supplies will be furnished upon requisition by unit commanders direct to this office. All ammunition will be accounted for by filling out special ex - penditure forms (which will be furnished by this oriice) and by turning in any remaining on hand to the camp ordnance officer not later than noon August 8, 1933. li. Iu expending ammunition it must be borne in mind that the allowance per man for firing the preliminary course Is fixed by regulations and any expenditure for an amount greater than the number of rounds required based on the reports submitted will not be accepted. Bv direction of the Governor: — , H. J. PAUL. A The Adjutant General, Nebraska. 7- STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN y June 6, 1933 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Military Leave to Post Office Employees. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chier, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the Information and guidance of all concerned: "With reference to the granting of military leave to em - ployees of the Post Office Department, the following letter dated May 27, 1933, from the First Assistant Postmaster General, addressed to the Chief of the Militia Bureau, is quoted for your information and guidance: </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "In reply to your letter of April 11, 1933, file MB 230.571 Gen.-14, you are Informed the Department has de - cided to grant military leave with pay to employees who are members of the National Guard, and who are properly ex - cused for duty at the annual encampments on and subsequent to April 1, 1933." (Signed) George E. Leach. Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 7, 1933 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Enlisted Men of National Guard Enrolled in CCC To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. The following letter from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published Tor the information and guidance of all con - cerned : "The following radiogram W, D. date Ma&gt; 26, 19 33, is quoted for your information and guidance: "Enlisted men of the National Guard who have been enrolled In the Civilian Conservation Corps may be granted leaves of absence for the purpose of attending annual field training with their organizations. Under such conditions they forreit their Civilian Conservation Corps pay Tor the entire period or their absence and their transportation ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL penses to and from National Guard Camps will not be borne by the Government." By command of Major General HAGOOD: (Signed) J. O. STEGER, Colonel, A. G. D. Adjutant General." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 12, 1933 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Compensation, Retired Pay, etc. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter Irom the Chief. Militia Bureau, and in - closed form for waiver are published for the information and guid - ance of all concerned: "1. With reference to that part of the War Department Appropriations Act for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1934 (Public No. 441, 72nd Congress) prohibiting the payment of monies from such appropriations to any officer or enlisted man of the National Guard who may be drawing a pension, disability allowance, disability compensation, or retired pay, the follow - ing is an extract from a letter from the Administrator, Veterans' Administration, to the Chief of the Militia Bureau: "Your first question is as follows: 'May members of the National Guard who elect to surrender such emoluments as pen - sion, disability allowance, disability compensation, or retired </seg>
            <seg id="p038">36 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL i pay be reinstated and continue to draw the same,' should they subsequently be separated from the National Guard?' Neither the law, nor the form prepared pursuant thereto, would require a surrender of the basic right to the monetary benefit awarded to any person affected. It Is rather a temporary suspension of the right for the period in question. While it can not be said that a person would be reinstated and continue to draw the monetary benefits at the same rate upon separation from the service in the National Guard upon which the surrender is based, any person who signs the waiver would, at the termination of the period of service, be entitled to resumption or his award pro - vided that no change in basic entitlement or amount ot monetary benefit is indicated at that time. "As you probably know. Public No. 2. 73d Congress, 'An Act to maintain the credit of the United States Government", approved March 20, 1933. repeals the laws granting disability allowance and disability compensation, and will permit payment after July 1, 1933, only of pension and emergency officers' re - tired pay. The benefits payable under that law are based upon new principles and it. will be necessary to review all claims to determine entitlement under the new law and regulations issued pursuant thereto. "You further ask whether or not the Veterans' Administra - tion approves the form presented by you upon which a member, of the National Guard may surrender his right in order to eon- 1 Torm with the law quoted above. It appears that the form will be sufficient to meet the desired purposes. It is returned here - with, a copy having been retained for the files of the Veterans- Administration."- A copy of the form rererred to therein is furnished for your information and guidance. 2. These forms will be made out in triplicate, one being sent to the Chiet or the Militia Bureau, one to the Administrator, Veterans' Administration, and one retained by the State Adjutant General. Upon receipt or this Torm in the Veterans' Administra - tion, action will be taken by that otfice to discontinue further payments of the surrendered amounts. 3. All pay vouchers for the fiscal year 1934 should be cer - tified substantially as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "I certlty that no member ot the National Guard paid here - on is receiving a pension, disability allowance, disability com - pensation, or retired pay from the government of the United States." I • State authorities will take necessary measures to assure themselves that members of the National Guard whose names appear on pay rolls or pay vouchers are not drawing pensions, disability allowance, disability compensation, or retired pay from the government of the United States. 4. Officers or enlisted men drawing a pension, disability allowance, disability compensation, or retired pay may not retain their federal recognition in the National Guard without armory and field training pay, with the one exception of present Adju - tants General (that is of March 4, 1933, date of 1934 Appropria - tion Act), nor may such officers be transferred to. the National Guard Reserve. 5. Action by the Veterans' Administration in cancelling the award of a pension, disability allowance, disability compensa - tion, or retired pay, to a member of the National Guard prior to June 30, 1933, will make further action by the State authorities unnecessary. 6. Should a National Guard officer surrender his National Guard commission and later be denied continuation of any pen - sion, disability allowance, disability compensation, or retired pay he is now receiving, there would be _o objection on the part of the Militia Bureau to again extend tederal recognition to such orficer when qualified therefor. 7. Should there be any conflict Detwe.n the law laid down in the National Defense Act and the law in the recent Appro - priation Act, the latter, as the later law, will govern. 8.- Attention is invited to paragraph 6, red bordered letter. "March 14. 1933, which must be complied with. George E. Leach, 1 incl. Major General, (Form) Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: ■••7 H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 21, 1933 Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Athletic Program. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1.. The following Athletic Program, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this program his personal attention and will cooperate with the Camp Athletic Officer in all particulars to the end that the program may be most interesting, entertaining, instructive and beneficial to the enlisted men and officers. 3. PROGRAM a. FIELD MEET. Saturday. August 19, after 9:30 A. M., is reserved as Athletic Field Day. (1) All entries in athletic events scheduled for that period will be released trom all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared or troops prior to the above designated hour. (2) Track. All track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded Tor 1st, 2nd and 3rd in each event. b. SWIMMING ; (1) Swimming events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd and 3rd in each event. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (2) The swimming pool may be used only when life guards are present and on duty at the pool. c. BOXING (1) There will be competition In each weight division and a medal awarded to tbe winner in each weight. d. MASS ATHLETICS ( 1 ) All enlisted men not engaged In other regularly scheduled training between the hours of 1:30 P. M. and 3:00 P. M. daily, Monday, August 7, and Satur - days and Sundays excepted, will be assembled In their company streets at 1:15 P. M. and marched, under a permanently designated leader, to the athletic field and reported to the camp athletic officer for physical training, athletics, recreational games, sports and training for athletics. (2) The period from 1:15 P. M. to 2:00 P. M. will be devoted to mass athletics, group games and similar events. The remainder of the time allotted will be devoted to baseball, swimming, track and similar activities. 4. GENERAL PROVISIONS a. Each regimental and separate battalion commander will immediately upon arrival at camp appoint a regimental and battalion athletic officer who will immediately report to the camp athletic officer as his assistant in the super - vision of the recreational and athletic activities of the camp (Training Directve 1933). b. The commanding officer of each company or like unit will detail one noncommissioned officer or selected private to act as athletic representative of the unit. Individuals so detailed will report to the camp athletic officer as assistants from 1:00 P. M. to 3:30 P. M. on days when physical training is scheduled; also they will be made available from 9:00 A. M. to 10:00 A. M. for attendance at any conference or school scheduled by the camp athletic officer (Training Directive 1933, par. 6 o (3) ). </seg>
            <seg id="p042">40 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. All officers detailed as above and all others assigned as camp athletic Instructors will be under the orders of the camp athletic officer and will report to him for duty dur - ing the periods herein provided. d. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS HAVE ALL MEN WHO WILL BE ENTERED IN THE BOXING CONTESTS ACCURATELY WEIGHED AND IM - MEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER A LIST OF THEIR RESPECTIVE ENTRIES TOGETHER WITH A STATE - MENT OF THEIR ACCURATE WEIGHTS. e. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS PREPARE LISTS OF THEIR RESPECTIVE ORGANIZA - TIONS' ENTRIES IN THE FIELD. TRACK AND SWIM - MING EVENTS AND IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER SAID LISTS TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER. 5. GENERAL'S TROPHY a. Adjutant General Paul is again offering a cup to the com - pany showing the greatest activity and efficiency in athletics. b. Points will be awarded to the various companies upon the following basis: (1) Boxing Owing to the difficulty that has been experienced in arranging a card for the second evening of camp (Tuesday), It has been decided to award a greater number of points to the companies having entries in boxing bouts upon that evening. Therefore, upon the first Tuesday evening, 25 points will be awarded for each entry at the ringside in condition to box, and 15 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. Upon all other evenings points will be awarded as follows : J p </seg>
            <seg id="p043">I REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 10 points will be awarded for each entry appearing at the ringside In condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. An additional 15 points will be awarded to the winning entry in each bout. 25 points will be awarded to each entry who enters the semi-final. 50 points will be awarded to the champion in each weight division. ( 2 ) Swimming 50 points will be awarded for each 1st. 35 points 'will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (3) Track 50 points will be awarded for each 1st. 35 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Mass Athletics 350 points will be awarded to the company evidenc - ing the greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 250 points will be awarded to the company evi - dencing the second greatest activity and efficiency In mass athletics. 150 points will be awarded to the company evi - dencing the third greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 50 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the fourth greatest activity and efficiency In mass athletics. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 26. 1933 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1933. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau to submit unft and n 8 °b St r gth ° B "" eVeDlnS ° f June 30 ' »»»• therefore a unit and sub-unit commanders are requested to wire this office their strength Friday A. M.. June 30, in order thai we may com pi e same and forward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, that day. men tpa?aL;: i rouTd;rus 0 ed: te,eerara ' "^ «»«" "Co. A, three officers, sixty-three enlisted men. (Signed) Smith. Captain." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 5, 1933 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: |^-~^Re-ultli,_ from Amendment to the National De- To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL [The following letter from the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all con - cerned. It is essential that paragraph two be strictly complied with. "1. Pending publications of new Regulations and policies affecting the National Guard as a result of the Act approved June 15, 1933, amending the National Defense Act approved June 3, 1916 (H R 5645), the Adjutant General Is no longer issuing commissions in the Officers' Reserve Corps to officers, warrant officers and enlisted men or the National Guard. Action in- such cases should thererore be suspended until further notice. 2. Attention is invited to the difference in wording in the oath of enlistment for enlisted men as given In the new Act of June 15, 1933 and as given In MB Form No. 21. The words "and I do agree to accept from the United States and the State or such pay, rations, and clothing or other allow - ances as are or may be established by law"; are part of the oath of enlistment shown in MB Form 21, but are not In the oath prescribed in the new law. The words quoted are therefore no longer lawful and must be deleted before the applicant is j sworn in. (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, Nat'l Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 11, 1933 Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Infantry Drill Regulations. To : All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Inasmuch as Nebraska Circular Letter No. 23, 1932, has been compiled with, all organizations will revert back to the former train - ing regulations which will be used for now until camp, during camp and until further orders thereafter. By direction of the Governor: H J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July is. loss Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1933. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers. NNG. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1933, having been set. i. e., August 7 to 21, 1933, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section III, NGR 45. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non-compliance therewith will cause forrelture of pay of Company Officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to train schedules, transportation requests and bills of lading. 3. Company Commanders are authorized to purchase subsistence for enlisted men and will follow Instructions received from the USP&amp;DO thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained. 1. e.. no men on top of the cars or on platrorm, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders and men's personal appearance </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL and conduct correct. All orficers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The| Commanding Otficer will make a thorough inspection or the train before troops entrain at home station, and arter they detrain at camp, and report to the camp commander Immediately upon arrival any defects or faults round with railroads transporting troops. Each Coijipany and Detachment Commander upon arrival at detraining point will immediately report to Detraining Otficer with reference to bag - gage detail. I 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breehces, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise during tlie fifteen day training period. j 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Train - ing Regulations 50-SO and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag or foot looker. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue cloth - ing, i. e.. cotton breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment and cleaning materials. No saddles, saddle equipment, or harness will be brought to camp as there will be no animals this year. No target material or canvas cots will be brought to camp. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except cal. .22, long rifle, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO. All empty car - tridges (brass) ln packing boxes, aiming devices, arm racks and lockers sufficient for men in camp, rifles, bayonets and pistols for same and all other ordnance with which the individual and com - panies are equipped will also be brought to camp. The Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only sufficient ammunition to be used in the conduct of its fire on the range. 9. Kpecial Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer prop - erty, including lister bags, is to be carried. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e.. Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men attend - ing camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence will be turned In Immediate - ly upon arrival ln camp. 11. Transportation on equipment other than enumerated above, which becomes excess equipment, brought to camp will have to be paid for by the Unit Commander bringing or permitting same to be brought (M.B. file 554.4 Gen.-81, May 25, 1931. Subject: Transporta - tion of Equipment for Field Training.). 12. Messes. All Company Officers will mess with their organ - ization. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess Is one of the most Im - portant things toward contentment and good morale of an organiza - tion. The Commanding Officer, 134th Inrantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Trains, QMC, will establish Officers' messes for the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff and 69th Inf. Brig, and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 7, 1933. 13. Parking. The main road through camp and entrance there - to will be kept clear of traffic at all times. No cars will be left stand - ing or parked in the road. The cars of officers will be parked along the river bank against the dike in back of their respective areas. Cars of enlisted men will be parked In the corral area. Driving on or off the main highway through camp will not be permitted except at such places marked for such purpose. No motor transportation will be permitted in the enlisted men's camp area. Company or like or - ganization commanders may detail one private to take their (com - pany commander's) car to camp and return same to home station. Not more than three private automobiles, belonging to enlisted men. per company or like organization will be permitted in camp. Any private conveyance brought to camp other than set out above without special permission will be Immediately impounded and held during the field training period. Officers and enlisted men bringing auto - mobiles to camp will present State registration certificates at Camp Headquarters and have same registered on day of arrival. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ' ! 14. The attention of all Unit and Sub-unit Commanders is called to the necessity of knowing their men are physically fit before taking same to camp as the number of major operations In our camp must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 15. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will make sure that they are not bringing any venereal cases to camp and In case any are found on the physical examination tbat will be made on entering camp, same will be returned to their home station at their own ex - pense, without pay or allowances, as they will not be permitted In caimp; such men will aslo be required to refund both railroad fare ard subsistence expended on them in bringing them to camp. 16. No companies, detachments, or details will be permitted in camp in advance of the time ordered in, for the purpose of condi - tioning kitchens, putting up tentage, or doing other routine work unless same have been designated by order or otherwise by this office. 17. Motor Vehicles. The 137th Motor Transport Company, QMC, will leave at their home station five FWD trucks. All organizations having Government owned motor vehicles will, immediately after arrival at camp and unloading of their equipment, have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Officer, to be placed in the camp pool for the duration of camp. No Government owned Ford trucks will bebrought to camp this year. IS. Inasmuch as the area on which enlisted men's tents will he pitched has been raised since the last camp the pitching of said tents is absolutely forbidden. 19. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will read this letter to their command at every armory drill between the time of receipt of same and the time of entraining for camp. By direction of the Governor: •':'■'■ H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 14, 1933 Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment. 1933. (ROUND TRIP) To: Officer- Responsible for Same. 1. In accordance with par. 73-c. NGR 71. Government Transporta - tion Request No. WQ is inclosed herewith, to cover railroad trans - portation (tickets) for your Company and any field or staff orficers or the NNG residing at your station, to Ashland, Nebraska, and return, which should be completed in accordance with Check List "B" at - tached in duplicate. 2. The responsible orficer in this case is acting as transportation orflcer and as train quartermaster and any accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations will be charged against the re - sponsible otficer. 3. Arrangements have never been made to have the transporta - tion requests exchanged tor tickets on the train. It is therefore re - quested that they be exchanged with the local agent. Read carefully NGR 70 and 71. with changes. By direction of the Governor: H.'j. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C Stein. Lt. Col., QMC, | USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL •I Incls. 1, Original T/R 2, Check List "B ", in dup. 3, Post Card WD MB 36, in dup. I. Conductor's Reports as required. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 15, 1933 'Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment. 1933. Td: Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Government Bill ot Lading WQ Is Inclosed herewith for f i eight (not checkable baggage) Involved In movement of your Com - pmv to Ashland. Nebraska. Bill of Lading for the return movement will" be furnished while at camp. These Bills of Lading should be ompieted in accordance with Check List "C" attached in duplicate. 2. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable rate where lliere is no Government transportation available tor the purpose ot transporting baggage and equipment Irom the armory to the depot and return. 3. Company Commanders will detail sufficient personnel to handle baggage at the detraining point. •I. Bead carefully NGR 71 and 72 with changes. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Lt. Col., QMC. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. 4 Incls. 1, Original B/L with memos and S. O. 2, Check List "C", in dup. 3, Public Voucher 4, Property List, in trip. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">— ■ STATE-OF-N^BRASKAr— — ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT LINCOLN July 18, 1933 Circular Letter No. 18 | Subject: Train Schedule To and Return From Annual Encampment, 1933. Ashland, Nebraska. , To- All Company Commanders, Field and Staff Officers, NNG. „ h 7_.,,i« 2 1. In accordance with General Order No. 4, AGO Nebraska. July 11. 1933. the following train schedule * is prescribed for movement to camp: *&lt; "^ 7 ., Appiox. Bag. Schedule E Movements Organizations Location No . p a8S . Car g STS ESS tr— s L, «,« Ta m. „. ..I, I'M Fremont T P v, n _ton 4 5 1 Lv. Lexington UP Spec. 2:15 AM g CB&amp;Q 119 u Wag Co Le xington 4.5 1 and Igland up Spe( , 4 ... £ Ashland Co H &lt;* r - lslana AM Ar. Ashland Q Spec. 7:45 AM O cT-B F^W-ii^ — A ralls /? y Tn No. 119. 3:37 | No . 2 c A Nebr. City 55 1 #■ Nebr C&lt;ty 5:15 AM | MP HqColstBn 18 Lv . Omaha Tn No. 15, 9:00 AM Omaha Regtl Hq Co Omaha 50 i CB&amp;Q Co K rf i Ashland Co L o_ g?ff^r 18 Ar_Ash i and Ji 45_AM </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Movements Organizations Location jfoJpJSJJ I car Schedule Hq Co. 3d Bn Lincoln 18 1 Lv. Lincoln Q Spec. 11:00AM No. 3 Co I 55 8/7/33 CB&amp;Q 110 Vet Co 30 Ashland Hq Det 35 DT Ar. Ashland 11:35 AM W 120 Wag Co Kearney 45 1 Lv. Kearney Tn No. 36, 6:45 ij MD Det 35 DT 10 AM 8/7/33 g No. 4 Co G Hastings 55 1 Lv. Hastings Q Spec. 8:10 AM 2 CB&amp;Q Co C — Beatrice 55 1 Lv. Beatrice Tn No. 25, 8:43 AM Ashland 130 Coll Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. Columbus Tn No. 20, 8:00 g AM Ar. Ashland Q Spec. 11:35 AM g Co E Scottsbluff "~55 i Lv. Scottsbluff Tn No. 32, 9:11 H No. 5 (x) PM 8/6/33 &gt; CB&amp;Q Serv Co 134 Inf York 70 1 Lv. York Tn No. 42, 11:12 AM h Ashland 8/7/33 c Co M Seward 55 1 Lv. Seward Tn No. 42, 11:56 AM h Ar. Ashland Q Spec. 2:20 PM &gt; Co F Hartington 60 1 Lv. Hartington Bus G.30 AM H Interstate Truck 8/7/33 p Transit Lines I Ar. Camp 11:30 AM IS I 2J • &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p055">53 .. • . ■ , ~ No. Pass. Bag. Schedule Movements Organizations Location Approx. Car scneouie l 30 Amb;Co --*£* Z, M8/7/33 No. 7 Sen- Co 110 MR Lincoln 67 Lv. Lincoln ,7:00 AM 8/7/33 ...,_,» « _gs,s^ "": : § ____^ aaaaaaaaaaa-— — — a. _____-_—-————— ——"^——— — ""- ► _ (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Co. E (Scottsbluff). B a '-■.-.-■.. .g H . P </seg>
            <seg id="p056">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 2. Co. A and Hq. Co., 1st Bn., will load in on. bag - gage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and Med. Dept. Det. will load in one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Organizations shown therein will load in one bag - gage car. v Movement No. 4. 120th Wag. Co. and Med. Dept. Det.. 35th Div. Tn., will load In one baggage car. 2. TICKETS Government Transportation Requests on the carrier concerned will be exchanged for ROUND TRIP TICKETS at the local ticket office. Requests for berths will be exchanged with the Pullman con - ductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT Baggage cars will be set the day preceding the movement to permit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is necessary. Tourist car3 or coaches will be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner in ample time to permit carriers to leave at desig - nated time. 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, field desks, dispensaries, typewriter, etc., (par. 28, NGR 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bill of Lading. Excess baggage, con - sisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bill of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">55 5. The following train schedule is prescribed for the return movement: .!-„ Approx. Bag. Schedule Movements Organizations Location Nq _ pasg Car -cneauie , Mn o 7EE7 "Beatrice 55~ 1 Lv. Ashland Q Spec. 9:00 AM No- » L0 u 8/21/33 » CB&amp;Q Ar. Beatrice Tn. No. 89 12:15 W Dest. pM g _ M Seward 55 1 Ar. Seward Tn No. 39, 11:21 AM » Serv Co 134 Inf York 70 1 Ar. Rork Tn. No. 39, 12:10 PM H Serv Co lo4 int - r Island 55 ! Ar . Gr . Island Tn No. 39, 1:27 o 0 e PM * 3 ~„ r Hastings 55 1 Ar. Hastings Tn No. 5, 2:00 PM P° r Falls City 55 1 Ar. Falls Cy Tn No. 42-16, 4:18 K uo a PM H Scottsbluff 55 1 Ar. Scottsbluff Tn No. 31, 5:55 &gt; Co E &lt; x &gt; AM 8 / 22 /33 O No7~9 130 Coll Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. Ashland^ Q Spec. 10:00 AM | _, CB&amp;Q . Ar. Columbus UP Spec. 2:00 PM * UP 120 Wag Co. Kearney 45 1 Ar. Kearney, UP Spec. 4:30 PM q De8t&gt; n D 9Wag 3 Co PT Lexington \l 1 Ar. Lexington UP Spec. 5:30 PM § 119 Wag co No. Platte 55 1 Ar. No. Platte, UP Spec 7:00 PM W H 0 w co Gering 55 1 Ar. Gering UP No. 53, 11:15 AM &gt; (x) 8/22/33 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Movements Organizations Location Approx. Bag. Schedule No. Pass. Car No. 10 Co K Omaha 55 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 24, 11:10 CB&amp;Q Co L 55 1 AM 8/21/33 Omaha MD Det 134 Inf .25 # Regtl Hq Co 50 1 H Hq Co 2d Bn 18 Ar. Omaha 11:56 AM O ; ' ; W No. 11 Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln IS Lv. Ashland Epec 1:50 PM O CB&amp;Q Co I 55 1 8/21/33 " Dest. 110 Vet Co 30 . ►_ Hq Det 35 DT Ar. Lincoln 2:30 PM W Hq Co 1st Bn Nebr. City 18 1 Ar. Neb Cy Tn No 122, 5:20 PM H Co A 55 &gt;• No. 12 Co F Hartington 60 1 Lv. Camp, Bus 7:00 AM G Interstate Truck 8/21/33 S Transit .. --•"■. z Lines Ar. Hartington 12:: N H : , , , z </seg>
            <seg id="p059">57 _ . ,, i „-,,inn Approx. Bag. Schedule Movements Organizations Location N ' ' ass . C ar No. 13 1~ Am,, Co 35 » Motor 166 Hosp. Co bu » O l.L M MR°Sec Ari St 7:00 PM ' .\% lh M T^n Holdrege 44 Lv. Camp 4:00 PM. 8/20/33 137 MT Co Holdtege Ho , drege 2:00 pMr gyh/33 § (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). g ..a '": Z Z ... -._: </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 10. Med. Dept. Det. and Regtl. Hq. Co. will use one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co.. 2nd Bn.. will use one bag - gage car. s Movement No. 11. Hq. Co.. 1st Bn.. and Co. A will use one baggage car. Lincoln units will use one baggage car. IK-Jpin./ 031 * 1 Card ReP ° rt WD MB N °- 36 »W be mailed to the USP&amp;DO as-soon as possible after arrival at home station with any unused tickets and "Conductor's Report of Troops Carried" the JspJdo Zr? nd , Um ? PleS 0t Bi " ° f Ladl " g " ,ust b « «'ven to the USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to departure. By direction or the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C Stein, Lt. Col., QMC, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 20, 1935 Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Supplementary to Nebraska Circular Letter No. 15, 1933. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. braska 7n\r l7*\7£ * f aragraph 13 ' C1 ™'ar Letter No. 15. Ne - braska. July 13, 1933, owing to the fact that passenger cars per- </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL -;.■'•';'; mltted to be brought to camp thereunder are solely for the con - venience of the ones permitted to bring same, no reimbursement will be made for the transportation thereof. 2. Company Officers are required to travel with their com - ranles. Where permission is given to an enlisted man to bring his automobile to camp he will be required to transport same alone; this in order that too great a discrepancy will not occur in the railway and bus transportation of the military organizations. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 24, 1935 Circular Letter No. 20 . Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Annual Encampment, 1933. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 15, MB Circular No. 25, A-21, August 30, 1930, responsible officers for companies or detachments are authorized to purchase the necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40 cents per meal per man for the time involved in»" assembling, travel and arrival at camp. Balance of meals for the first day will be the Garrison Ration. 2. There is inclosed Check List "A" in duplicate, which goes Into detail and must be used In conjunction with purchase and set - tlement of the amount involved. 3. In accordance with the train schedule your company or de - tachment would be entitled to the following meals: </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL I Company August 7 . . ( I BUS I i ■ I J ! I I :" I ill ._ I I j : B — Breakfast D — Dinner " S — Suppe.- O — None GR — Garrison Ration M — Meal By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Lt. Col., QMC, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. Incls. 2. 1. Check List "A" in dup. ' . 2. Vouchers STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 27, 1933 Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills. F. Y. 1934. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "1. The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of Federal pay drills to be held during the fiscal year 1934, will be limited as follows: a. During the 1st and 2nd Quarters (July 1 to December 31, 1933 Inclusive) not to exceed 16 Federal pay drills. b. During the 3rd Quarter (January 1 to March 31, 1934, inclusive) not to exceed 8 Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the 16 drills not held in the 1st and 2nd quarters. c. During the 4th Quarter (April 1 to June 30, 1934 in - clusive) 12 Federal pay drills and no more, will be held. d. In no event will the number or drills ror which payment is made from Federal funds exceed eight (8) In any one month or thlrty-slx (36) during the fiscal year tor any organization ot the National Guard. 2. All drills held, whether for Federal pay or not, will be reported monthly on M. B. Form 100, wlfh notation made on the form showing the drills for which Federal pay is claimed. (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief. National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: • H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 22. 1933 Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Armory Drill Pay Rolls. , ( . To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">.;• REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The following letter from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. The following letter from the Chier of the National Guard Bureau is repeated for the information of all concerned: "NGB 240.91 Gen.-107 July 24. 1933 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1934. 1. The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of Federal pay drills to be held during the fiscal year 1934. will be limited as follows: a. During the 1st and 2nd Quarters (July 1 to Decem - ber 31, 1933, inclusive) not to exceed 16 Federal pay drills. b. During the 3rd Quarter (January 1 to March 31, 1934, inclusive) not to exceed 8 Federal pay drills in addi - tion to anyapart of the 16 drills not held in the 1st and 2nd Quarters. c. During the 4th Quarter (April 1 to June 30. 1934. inclusive) 12 Federal pay drills and no more, will be held. d. In no event will the number of drills for which pay - ment is made from Federal funds exceed eight ( 8 1 in any one month or thirty-six (36) during the fiscal year for any organizatlon of the National Guard. 2. All drills held, whether for federal pay or not. will be reported monthly on M. B. Form 100, with notation made on the form showing the drills tor which Federal pay is claimed." 2. Attention is invited to instructions in paragraph 2 of above quoted letter, as regarding number of drills to be shown on Form No. 100. Attention is also invited to letter rrom Chief. Mllltla Bureau to the Adjutants General of all States, subject: "Limitation of Armory Drills" dated October 10, 1927. (File MB-240.91), especially paragraph 3 which provides in part that "no matter how many assemblies may have been held, in the preparation of pay rolls only those assemblies lor which armory </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL drill pay is authorized should be entered on the pay-roll. It the number or assemblies held during a quarter exceeds the number tor which Federal armory drill pay has been authorized, only the particular assemblies for which such pay Is claimed may be entered upon the payroll." For the Commanding General: J. O. Steger, Colonel, A. G. D., Adjutant General." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 23, 1933 Ci rcular Letter No. 23 Subject: Changes Resulting from Amendment to the National De - tense Act. Tc : All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. . The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "I. In order to comply with the National Defense Act as amended by the Act of June 15, 1933, M. B. Form 62 (Applica - tions for federal recognition) should be changed, substituting "National Guard of the United States" for "Officers' Reserve Corps" in heading in paragraph 3, page 1, and paragraph 3 of indorsement top of page 4. - 2. "Militia Bureau" wherever it appears on the above men - tioned form, should be changed to "National Guard Bureau". </seg>
            <seg id="p066">64 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. a. Particular attention is called to paragraph 2 c and d of "Instructions" on back of oath. The signature on the oath must be the full name as shown in the body of the oath. b. Attention is called to the fact that the oath is a dual oath. Paragraph 4, same instructions, is modified as follows: 4 a Change "or", first line, to read "and". 4 b Deleted. 4 c The oath of office, being a dual oath, must be taken before some one authorized to administer oaths by laws of the United States and also by State laws. Any person who is author - ized by local municipal law to administer oaths in the State, Ter - ritory or District, may administer the oath inasmuch as Revised Statute 1758 (U. S. Code 5:18) empowers such officers to ad - minister the oath on behalf or the United States. '4. Attention is invited to the tact that an appointment In the National Guard ot the United States must have been re - ceived before the oath, which is the acceptance ot the appoint - ment, can be legally taken. Pending receipt or an appointment in the National Guard or the United States, the oath applies, as heretofore, only to acceptance ot State appointments in the Na - tional Guard. Appointments in the National Guard of the United States will be tendered in the near future by The Adjutant General to all National Guard officers federally recognized on June 15, 1933. ■ l ' For the Chief, National Guard Bureau: H. LaT. Cavenaugh, Colonel, N. G. B.. Assistant." ..,,,.-■■ ■ . . ■. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. -. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 25. 1933 Circular Letter No. 24 Slbject: Limitation of Armory Drills. Fiscal Year 1934. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. With reference to letter from this Bureau dated July 24. 1933, on the above subject, the following information is rurnished. 2. It is the intention that armory drill pay or all olficers will be on a corresponding basis to that outlined In letter from this Bureau above referred to. 3. In the case both or officers below the grade of major not belonging to organizations who receive armory drill pay at the rate of four-thirtieths of the monthly base pay of their grade (par. 9. NGR 58), and of orficers above the grade or captain, who receive armory drill pay at the rate of $500.00 per year, computed on the basis of one-twelfth annual pay per month (par. 8. NGR 58) tor the performance or the appropriate duties prescribed, payment should be on the basis indicated in the letter reterred to, namely, not to exceed two-thirds ot the amounts indicated in the regulations for the first and second quarters, nor tor the third quarter. Payment for the full amount authorized may be made for the fourth quarter of the fiscal year. 4. The provisions of the letter above referred to will not reduce the amount or administrative pay for officers entitled to receive same. W. H. Waldron, Colonel, N. G. B. For and in the absence of the Chief, National Guard Bureau." </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA - ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 26, 1933 Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Inventory and Inspecting Officers. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published for the information' and guidance of all concerned: "No federal funds having been allotted for Visits or Instruc - tion by Regular Army Instructors during the current fiscal year, and due to the shortage or lunds allotted for other travel of Regular Army personnel, it will not be possible to send Regular Army Officers to act on Inventory and Inspection reports, and it Is suggested that property placed on I. and I. be kept in the hands of organizations until inspectors become available. For the Commanding General: J. O. Steger, Colonel, A. G. D., Adjutant General." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 31, 1933 Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: National Guard ot the United States. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "As apparently there is some doubt as to procedure in the matter of appointments of, and acceptances thereof by officers in the National Guard of the United States, and also as to pro - cedure in regard to enlisted men, the following is published: 1. While the Act of June 15. 1933, amending the National Defense Act, established the National Guard of the United States, it is necessary that The Adjutant General promulgate the fact and enunciate the policies to govern. It will also be necessary, in some matters, for the Secretary of War to publish Regula - tions to govern, where the Act so prescribes. 2. Before any action can be taken by the states or by individuals, towards commissioning officers in the National Guard of the United States, the latter must first be tendered an ap - pointment by the President of the United States through The Adjutant General. No action can therefore be taken until the receipt of the appointment, the acceptance of which is evi - denced by the oath to be taken the date of which cannot ante - date the appointment. The issuing of commissions Is also a function of The Adjutant General and the state cannot legally appoint or commission officers in the National Guard of the United States. , . 3. The order establishing the National Guard of the United States will be Issued In the near future. It will probably be a blanket order, and in addition to the establishment of the Na - i tional Guard of the United States. It is expected to cover ap- </seg>
            <seg id="p070">68 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL pointments of officers In the National Guard of the United States. All officers appointed or promoted after the date of the blanket order, desiring appointment in the National Guard of the United States must apply for same in the space now pro - vided on M. B. Form 62 for application for appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps. After receipt of the order, enlisted men may be sworn into the National Guard of the United States by an officer designated for the purpose by the Corps Area Commander. The oath may - be administered by an officer of the Regular Army, Organized Reserve, or officer who has accepted appointment In the Na - tional Guard of the United States, but not by an officer who is a state National Guard officer only. The oath can be administered en masse, the individual enlisted man then signing the amended oath shown on the enlistment papers, to be then filed in the office of the State Adjutant General. 4. The Adjutant General has decided that a record in the Na - tional Guard Bureau or satisfactory physical examination taken within one year of acceptance of appointment is sufficient to comply with the law. As the National Guard Bureau has on file few records of physical examinations of National Guard Reserve officers, It was deemed advisable to direct that all National Guard Reserve officers be physically examined before appoint - ment, also that in their cases applications for appointments (M. B. Form 62), accompanied by M. B. Form 63 (report ot physical examination), must be received before appointments will be tendered them. The question as to whether or not a National Guard Reserve otficer will be tendered an appointment in the National Guard of the United States has not yet been decided. No physical examination of enlisted men is required by law for the induction Into the National Guard of the United States. The oath is sufficient. For the Chief, National Guard Bureau: H. LaT. Cavenaugh. Colonel, N. G. B.. Assistant." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 22, 1933 Circular Letter ■ No. 27 Subject: Training Circular No. 1, Militia Bureau, 1932. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, Is published for the information and guidance ot all concerned: "1. Training Circular No. 1, Militia Bureau, dated April 15. 1933. contains reterences to A. R. 775-10. 2. Until the receipt ot the new A. R. 775-10, now under preparation, A. R. 740-10, December 28, 1931, will govern. 3. Paragraph numbers ot Training Circular No. 1, Militia Bureau, with reterences to A. R. 775-10, and the applicable paragraphs or A. R. 740-10 are indicated below: Reterences References Tr. Cir. No. 1 in AR 775-10 in AR 740-10 15 20 11 18 22 13 21 " 24 ., 15 28 32 21 31 34 23 37a 27 26b 37c 28 27 George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 23, 19 33 Circular Letter No. 28 Subject: Ordnance Inspection. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual inspection of ordnance equipment in the hands of Nebraska National Guard will be made in accordance with the at - tached schedule. 2. The dates shown are approximate depending upon the condi - tion of the ordnance equipment and the character of modifications necessary. This may cause some slight alteration ot the schedule, in which case, organizations will be notified in advance by the inspector. 3. All organization commanders are directed to bring to the attention of the ordnance representative all matters of faulty weapons and equipment, cases where cleaning or repair has been difficult, and all other ordnance troubles encountered. It should be borne In mind by all organization commanders that it is the desire of the inspector to make these inspections helptul rather than criti - cal, so if you have any ordnance troubles ot whatsoever nature do not hesitate to call it to the attention or the inspecting officer. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. : Ord. Schedule </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL - NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Ordnance Inspection -Schedule 134th Infantry 1933 Omaha Co. L Dec. 4- 5 Co. K Hq. Co. Hq. Co. 2nd Bn. 7 Nebraska City Co. A Dec. 6 Hq. Co. 1st Bn. Falls City Co. B Dec. 6 Beatrice Co. C Dec. 7 Lincoln Co. I Dec. 8- 9 Hq. Co. 3rd Bn. Hq. Det., 35th Div. QM Tr. Seward Co. M Dec. 15 York Service Co. Dec. 16-17 Grand Island Co. H Dec. 18 Hastings Co. G Dec. 19 Holdrege 137th Motor Transport Co. Dec. 20 Lexington 119th Wagon Co. Dec. 20 North Platte Co. D Dec. 21 Kearney 120th Wagon Co. Dec. 22 Fremont 119th Motor Repair Section Dec. 23 138th Motor Transport Co. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 17, 1933 Circular Letter No. 29 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, Fiscal Year. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: Officers Below the Grade of Major Receiving Pay Under Par. 9, NGR 58, and orficers Above the Grade ot Captain Receiving Pay Under Par. 8, NGR 58. - The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "Paragraph 3 of Bureau letter dated August 22, 1933, on above subject is revoked and the following substituted therefor. 3. In the case both or orficers below the grade or major not belonging to organizations who receive armory drill pay at the rate ot four-thirtieths ot the monthly base pay ot their grade (par. 9, NGR 58), and of officers above the grade ot cap - tain, who receive armory drill pay at the rate ot $500.00 per year. computed on the basis of one-twelfth annual pay per month (par. 8, NGR 58) for the performance of the appropriate duties prescribed, payment should be made on a basis of 8 drills for each of the first three quarters and for 12 drills in the last quarter. During the quarter camp is held deduction will be made on the basis ot 2 drills from which it follows that all such officers will receive pay on a basis of but 34 drills for the fiscal year 1934. v W. H. Waldron, Colonel, N. G. B., For and in the, absence ot the Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 18, 1933 i .''■.... Circular Letter No. 30 Subject: Loss of Fire Arms. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information of all concerned. Every pre - caution must be taken to see that neither arms nor ammunition get out of possession of those charged with the safe-keeping of same. "1. The following letter from The Attorney General to the Secretary ot War is quoted tor your information: "The Division of Investigation of this Department has had under Investigation for violation of the National Motor Vehicle Theft Act the notorious Barrow Brothers, Clyde C. and Marvin (Buck) Barrow. These two brothers have engaged in many gun battles with law enforcement officers In Oklahoma, Iowa, and other Western States. They have killed a number of officers. In their battles with law enforcement officers the Barrow brothers were armed with Browning automatic rifles or machine guns, as well as with a large number ot .45 calibre Colt auto - matic pistols. On July 19, 1933, near Platte City, Missouri, the Barrow brothers were approached by a group ot orficers and in the ensuing gunfire Marvin (Buck) Barrow was wounded. He, however, was not apprehended at that time. The car in the possession ot the officers was disabled by fire from the machine guns in the possession ot the Barrow brothers. On the morning of July 24th, these brothers were again located by officers and Marvin Barrow was again wounded and was apprehended. He . died at Perry, Iowa, on July 29th. as a result of the wound re - ceived in the battle near Platte City, Missouri. At the time of Marvin Barrow's apprehension, the armament of these criminals was seized by the officers, the armament consisting of thirty - nine .45 calibre Colt automatic pistols and four Browning auto - matic rifles or machine guns, all of which were property of the United States, and appear to have been stolen from National Guard Armories. j. ■-•".:• « s&gt; et - e e'e t. * In a number ot other cases Involving violations or the laws or the United States, Investigated by the Division of Investiga - tion of this Department, it has been found that criminals were in possession of firearms which were the property of the United States and had been stolen from National Guard organizations. This is called to your attention. In view of the possibility that if your Department will suggest to the National Guard units of the several States the desirability of taking stringent precau- </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL tlons to prevent the larceny of firearms It may result in the criminal element In the United States finding it much more diffi - cult to secure lethal weapons to use in their criminal activities." 2. The necessary steps will be taken by your office to see that the provisions of NGR 75-3 are strictly complied with at [all times. 3. The excessive losses of arms and ammunition by theft during the past year make it obligatory upon this office to hold | states pecuniarily liable for any losses unless it can be fully es - tablished that all due care and precautions have been taken to prevent such thefts. E. A. Fry, Colonel, N. G. B., For and in the absence of the Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. i ■ , ■ STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 20. 1933 Circular Letter No. 31 Subject: Requisition for Coats, Serge and Breeches, Elastique. .'..■■--■ ,'i'.. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The new style woolen uniforms consisting of coats, serge, and breeches, elastique, will be available for issue in the very near future. So it is directed that you submit requisition for sizes re - quired using QMC form 51 for the amount necessary to equip your command at their present strength. 2. This office will only receive 1630 of these uniforms which </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL will no doubt necessitate some men not being fitted, but requisitions will be filled in the order of receipt of same. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. QMC No. 51 in dup. - STATE OF NEBRASKA ' ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 7, 1933 Circular Letter No. 32 Subject: West Point Preliminary Competitive Examination, 1933, for the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of one enlisted man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competi - tive examination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office, Wednesday, November 15, 1933, at 9:00 A. M. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an applicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date .of admission, July 2, 1934, have served as an enliseed man not less than one year, must be between tbe ages of 19 and 22 years and must not be less than 5 ft. 4 in. in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, therefore former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War De - partment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is .scheduled to be held beginning on March 6, 1934, and the appoint- </seg>
            <seg id="p078">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ment available on July 2, 1934, will be awarded to the qualified candidate ln the order of merit established at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously applicants have presented themselves to take this examination who were In no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an applicant should have had at least one year in college, in addition to a high school education. The examination will be written and will consist of an exhaustive examination in the following subjects: Elementary Algebra, to and including Quadratics, Plane Geometry, English Grammar, United States and General History and English Literature and Composition. 5. No State Funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. 6. The delayed reporting ot the Senior Instructor, who acts on the board, has necessitated the short notice given for this exam - ination. 7. A blank form to be used in making application to participate in the examination Is Inclosed. By direction ot the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. I net. (1) Appl. blank. Town Date In accordance with instructions contained in Circular Letter No. 32, AGO-Nebr., November 7, 1933, I request that I be authorized to participate in the West Point Preliminary Examination to be held at the Adjutant General's Otfice, State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska, No - vember 15, 1933. 1. NAME : (Last Name) (Middle (First) 2. RESIDENCE (Street Address) (City) (State) </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. DATE OF BIRTH: 4 (Day) (Month) (Year) (Place) 5. DATE OF ENLISTMENT: 6. SCHOOLS OR COLLEGES ATTENDED: From to GRADUATE — Yes or No From to GRADUATE — Yes or No From to GRADUATE — Yes or No From..... to GRADUATE — Yes or No (SIGNATURE) (Company) (Regt.) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 29, 1933 Circular Letter No. 33 Subject: Remarks on Form 100. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following information furnished by Captain H. H. Elarth, lnf-DOL, Instructor, Is published for the information of all con - cerned: "The F. O. US Army does not require any remarks on the armory pay rolls reference "Enl Str" In case of reenllstment of NCOs and Pfc. Such remarks are required only in case of Initial appointments. In order to have the remarks on Forms 100 coincide as far as possible with pay roll remarks lt is requested that company </seg>
            <seg id="p080">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL commanders be not required to show a remark "Enl Str — " In cases of reenllstment of NCOs and Pfc." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 12. 1933 Circular Letter No. 34 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. 1. Inclosed are WD MB Forms No. 67 to be used in making the annual Efficiency Reports for the year ending December 31, 1933. The reports are to be made In accordance with instructions contained in paragraphs 63 b (1) and d (1), NGR 20, dated November 12, 1931. 2. Reports are to be forwarded by the reporting otiicer to the next military superior within ten days or the close or the period covered in the report, exclusive of Sundays and holidays, and are to reach this office by the end of the month. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Ind: </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 18, 1933 Circular Letter No. 35 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books, 1933. To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1933, in accordance with the following Instructions: a. The account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under "Other Funds" and In accordance with paragraphs 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 of the instructions. (See also the model.) h. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, regardless whether receipts or expenditures. C. Certificates for receipts and itemized invoices for expendi - tures are required for all transactions from January 1, 1933. (1. In case the lull page of the account will not carry the year's transactions, cut off bottom of page above words "Total receipts and expenditures" and the top of the next page "In accordance with funds," etc., under the word "year" and above "month", and paste these pages together. e. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of December 31, 1933. f. Certificate must be submitted as a voucher showing the officers that messed with your company and the amounts paid. 2. From the audits in the past it is noted that responsible officers in some cases do not post their books when the transaction occurs. This practice must stop and every transaction should be actually posted on the date that it occurs. The canteen dividend for </seg>
            <seg id="p082">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1933 must be picked up under this year's business. In cases where the Council Book has been filled and the last certificate has not been signed it will be necessary to send in the old and the new book. How - ever, these books should bo used until they are completely filled and they are good for a period of from five to ten years. 3. These Council Books with vouchers will be sent immediately to Lieutenant Colonel H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska, who will audit and return same, making report to this office of any discrepancies found. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. ..,■■■•' . : i STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 26. 1933 Circular Letter No. 36 Subject: Melton Cloth Uniforms. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. In view ot the fact that the new serge and elastique uniform is being issued for dress purposes, the restriction that was placed on the wearing of the Melton Cloth Is rescinded and same may now be worn for armory drill. By' direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 28, 1933 Circular Letter No. 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Armory Drill Payrolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance ot all concerned: "1. The Chief of Finance has called attention to the follow - ing irregularities In the preparation of armory drill payrolls: "Attention Is called to the fact that armory drill pay - rolls forwarded to this office for submission to the Comp - troller General for decision as to the propriety of payment do not contain a certificate showing whether or not the I officer or enlisted man, as the case may be, was receiving a pension, disability allowance, disability compensation or retired pay from the Government of the United States. As this certificate is required by the Comptroller General be - fore a decision is rendered, it is requested that the matter be brought to the attention of the National Guard author - ities concerned In order that when armory drill payrolls are prepared notation may be made thereon, or a certificate attached thereto." 2. Attention is also invited to the fact that it has been necessary to return armory drill payrolls for correction on ac - count of the date of Federal recognition being Incorrectly stated. 3. Request is made that the attention of all concerned in the preparation of armory drill payrolls be invited to these irregularities in order that the necessary corrective steps may - lie taken. For the Chief. National Guard Bureau: E. J. O'Hara, Major, N. G. B.. Assistant." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 1, 1934 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: CWA Work. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. For your information you are advised that we have obtained fourteen men who are doing general work at the Ashland Rille Range. I am just informed that the Service Company at York has obtained men to build up their rifle range and clear off a lot on which they will drill. Inasmuch as the officials in charge are desirous of having work for the men employed by the CWA, it is suggested that company commanders take advantage of this opportunity to get any work done they may have to do. Make your request to your local com - mittee men. By direction ot the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 13. 1934 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Survey of Target Ranges. To: All Organization Commanders. 1. Due to the fact that the danger area of cartridge ball cal. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL .30 M-l has a range of approximately 5,500 yards (3 miles, 220 yards), or 2,050 yards greater than the cartridge ball cal. .30 M-1906 (the ammunition that we have been using), ana that the high velocity ammunition will be used in the future, It Is directed that you immediately make a survey of the range that you now have leased or have been using, furnishing the following information: a. A plat (which may be secured from your County Engineer) showing the exact location of your range with the sections and townships thereon, including public roads and buildings. b. Would it be practical to re-locate the range? c. With the present location of the range what Is the distance from the 200 yard firing point, along the line of fire, to the boundary of the range? (1. What is the nature of the terrain in rear of the target butts? e. ir the present range is not suitable, can a suitable range be secured in your vicinity? 2. This letter Is furnished to all organizations so that members of their command, who may use this ammunition, may be governed accordingly. If you have been using the Ashland range for pre - liminary practice make no report. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 14, 1934 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Annual Armory Inspection. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. At the annual armory inspection all officers having ordnance are directed to make available to Inspecting officers copies of reports of the Corps Area Ordnance Officer covering technical inspections of ordnance material. 2. Due to the shortage of funds for miscellaneous travel all officers detailed to make the annual armory inspections have been directed by the Corps Area Commander to take every possible ad - vantage to act on surveys and I &amp; I Reports submitted to them by - unit commanders. Since the time allowed Inspectors for conducting these inspections is necessarily very limited unit commanders are di - rected to take every step possible to facilitate the prompt handling of these reports In order to have all cases of this kind acted on It practicable. By direction ot the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 6. 1934 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment Fiscal Year 1934. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with instructions received rrom Headquarters 7 th Corps Area, it will be necessary to submit, not later than March 17, 1934, requisitions covering supplies and equipment for your com - pany for the balance of the fiscal year 1934. 2. Requisitions received after the date set forth above can not be acted upon prior to Field Training 1934. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT .:'.■.. LINCOLN ' March 21, 1934 Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Theft and Recovery of Small Arms. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter received from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, Is published for the Information and guidance of all concerned. In case of theft Immediate report must be made to this office giving the information called for In paragraph two of the following letter and It is necessary that each unit commander familiarize himself with the citations made. "1. In connection with paragraph 11, NGR 75-3, your attention Is Invited to Section II, Circular 6, War Department, February 27, 1934, Subject: "Report of theft and recovery of Small arms." 2. Hereafter in case of loss of fire arms by the National Guard of your State, it is requested that In addition to the re - port required by paragraph 11, NGR 75-3, a telegraphic report to this headquarters be made at once, giving name of weapon ." lost, the place of manufacture and the serial number. For tbe Commanding General: J. O. Steger, Colonel, A. G. D., Adjutant General." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 4, 1934 Circular Letter . No. 6 Subject: Requisition for Blank Forms and Publications, Form No. 22, NNG. (Ed. March 20, 1934.) To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. 1. Officers responsible for Requisition for Blank Forms and Publications will use the new form referred to above (supply in - closed) for future requisitions and destroy all forms of former editions now on hand. 2. The revision of this form became necessary ! on account of changes In form numbers, some of which are as follows: a. Report Individual Classification is now AGO Form No. 110. b. All QMC forms have been changed to the 4 00 series and Requisition for Clothing In Bulk, QMC 51, is discontinued for use of the National Guard. In the future requisitions for clothing will be submitted on QMC Form 400, but sizes of clothing must In all cases be shown and must conform to those given In AR 30-3050. Requisitions for medical property must show item number in accordance with Medical Supply Catalog, 1932. The column "On hand and due" on QMC Form 4 00 must in all cases be filled out. c. NNG Forms 19, 20, 21, 23 and 25 cover ten individuals to each of these forms and should be requisitioned accord - ingly. d. Under "Office Supplies" erasers, pencil and typewriter, and and thumb tacks will be issued annually (just prior to Field Training). Typewriter ribbons will be issued every other quarter. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. Requisition for Blank Forms must be submitted in accord - ance with note at bottom of the form and must not be confused with the pay roll period. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 6, 1934 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Increase in Armory Drill Pay Check. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following radiogram sent from the Chief or Finance to the Finance Orticer, Seventh Corps Area, Omaha, Nebraska, is quoted for the information and guidance of all concerned: "59 WAR W 130WD WASHINGTON DC 344P APRIL 3 1934 '■• v THE FINANCE OFFICER 7th CORPS AREA OMAHA NEBRASKA ACT OF MARCH TWENTY EIGHTH NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR PUBLIC NUMBER ONE FOUR ONE PROVIDES FOR DECREASE IN PERCENTAGE DEDUCTION OF FIVE PERCENT FEBRUARY FIRST NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR AND ANOTHER FIVE PERCENT DE - CREASE EFFECTIVE JULY FIRST NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR PERIOD FOR NATIONAL GUARD QUARTERLY PAY ROLLS COV - ERING THE MONTHS OF FEBRUARY NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR ALREADY PAID REQUEST ORGANIZATIONS THROUGH STATE ADJUTANT GENERAL TO SET UP COLUMN ON NEXT QUARTER - </seg>
            <seg id="p090">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL LY PAY ROLLS SHOWING FIVE PER CENT OVER DEDUCTED FOR FEBRUARY NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR SO THAT SAME MAY BE ADDED AND PAID NEXT QUARTER BY FINANCE OFFICER PERIOD FOR NATIONAL GUARD QUARTERLY PAYROLLS NOW IN OFFICE TO BE FIGURED AND PAID FOR QUARTER ENDING MARCH THIRTY FIRST NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR ONLY TEN PERCENT WILL BE DEDUCTED FOR FEBRUARY AND MARCH NINETEEN THIRTY FOUR PERIOD COLEMAN 544 P" By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 17. 1934 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Enlistment in the National Guard of the United States. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, Is published for the Information and guidance of all concerned. As understood by this office It Is necessary to administer the new oath subsequent to the passage of the new law in order that men may - qualify thereunder, this, notwithstanding the fact that the enlisted men have been enlisted In the National Guard of the United States and the State of Nebraska. "1. General Orders No. 3, War Department, April 4, 1934. provides for enlistment in the National Guard or the United States of all present enlisted men of the National Guard for the unexpired portion of their present enlistment. To accom - plish this a new enlistment form will not be used, it being only necessary tbat the oath on the original enlistment record on </seg>
            <seg id="p091">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL file in the organization be again administered by au officer authorized by the laws ot the state concerned to administer oaths or enlistment in the National Guard. After administer - ing the oath the officer will make a notation on the enlistment record over his signature ot the date on which this was done. U additional space is necessary is may be provided by pasting additional paper to the form under the Certificate of Inspection and Enlistment. 2. H-ieafter enlistments in the National Guard and in the National Guard of the United States will be simultaneous and one enlistment record will cover both. No change will be made in the disposition of this record. (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 24, 1934 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Oaths ol Office. To: All Officers and Warrant Officers, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, Is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "With reference to War Department General Orders No. 3 dated April 4, 1934, and letters of even date pertaining thereto. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL SSSF^JS lnVU f d , t0 the fact "&gt;" when regulations are pub - bv St. , " eSUlatlons wlU P~~ r »be that all oaths executed by Nationa Guard Officers in connection with their acceptance of an appointment In the National Guard of the United States be forwarded through the State Adjutant General, the Corps St oHT^ thG CWef ° f the NaUonal Guard Bur - u. the Chief of the Arm or Service, to The Adjutant General. Com - pliance with this provision is requested. (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Circular Letter April 25 ' 193 ** No. 10 Subject: National Guard of the United States: To: All Officers and Warrant Officers. NNG. nlshinf/ | U °T ln f le " er fr ° m the A &lt;» uta ~ General of the Army fur - nishingex racts from General Orders No. 3. War Department. Apr U cerned: PUb ' iShed for the '-formation and guidance of all con- Cener, 1 ,' n * tten *J° n ls invited &lt;° the following extracts from General Orders No. 3. War Department. April 4. 1934: «,„-_ " 6 ; ? y direction of the ITesident of the United States, each physically qualified commissioned officer of the Na- FeH- n Uard n0t ab ° Ve the grade of col ~ e1 ' "o is in a Federally recognized status on the date of this order and </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL who has not already been appointed in the National Guard of the United States, is hereby appointed in the National Guard of the United States in the same arm or service and in the same grade, provided there is an allotted unit of the active or Inactive National Guard to which he is or may be assigned to bring such unit to war strength. See para - graphs 11 and 15. "7. By direction of the President ot the United States each physically qualified warrant orflcer of the active Na - tional Guard who is in a Federally recognized status as such on the date of this order is hereby appointed a war - rant officer in the National Guard of the United States. "8. Each appointment "as provided In paragraphs 6 and 7 of this order (subject to the limitations imposed in those respective paragraphs) shall continue in force during the pleasure of the President of the United States for the time being, for the period during which the particular appointee's Federal recognition In his present grade and arm or service of the active or inactive National Guard shall continue in effect, and shall terminate upon the ter - mination of such recognition. "9. An appointment as provided In paragraphs 5, 6, and 7 of this order can be accepted only by the proper execution and proper forwarding of an oath of office on or before October 31, 1934. Unless the appointment is accept - ed by the proper execution and proper forwarding or the oath or office on or before October 31, 1934, the appoint - ment Is to be regarded as withdrawn as of November 1, 1934. In accepting present or tuture appointments, the oath of office will be taken before a notary public, a clerk or prothonotary of a court ot record of a State, Territory, or the District of Columbia, a deputy of such clerk or prothonotary, or a magistrate authorized by the law of the State, Territory, or District to administer oaths. The oath is as follows: 'I do solemnly swear that I will support and defend the Constitution of the United States and the constitution of the State ot against all enemies, foreign and domestic; that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the same; that I will obey the orders of the President of the United States and </seg>
            <seg id="p094">92 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL of the Governor of the State or ; that I make this obligation freely, without any mental reservation or purpose of evasion, and that I will well and faithfully discharge the duties of the office of in the National Guard of the United States and of the State of upon which I am about to enter, so help me God.' "10. Acceptance of an appointment to a commissioned grade in the National Guard of the United States will vacate any appointment now held in the Officers' Reserve Corps. "14. An officer appointed in the National Guard of the United States who now holds or, subsequently to Novem - ber 11, 1918, has held an appointment in the Otllcers' Re - serve Corps of the Army of the United States is hereby assigned the same serial number assigned to him while an officer of the Officers' Reserve Corps. "16. By direction of the President of the United States, any warrant officer or enlisted man of the National Guard now holding an appointment in any section of the Officers' Reserve Corps, is, if physically qualified, hereby - tendered appointment without further examination in the National Guard of the United States in the same grade and arm or service provided there is an allotted unit to which each may be assigned to bring such unit to war strength. Acceptance of appointment under the provisions of this paragraph will be evidenced by the proper execution and proper forwarding of an oath of office. Such oath of office shall be accompanied by report of physical examina - tion on proper form made within twelve months prior to the date of such oath." 2. It should be noted that the appointee under paragraph 6 of the General Order must have held federal recognition on April 4, 1934; and that his federally recognized status on April 4, 1934, governs his appointment in the National Guard of the United States. If the Officers' federal recognition in the National Guafd terminates on or after April 4, 1934, and prior to the acceptance by him of the appointment tendered by the General Order of April 4, 1934, the General Order has no effect with respect to him, and the question of appointment In the National Guard of the United States must be made the subject of separate action. It should be noted also that the appointments tendered by para- </seg>
            <seg id="p095">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL graphs 6 and 7 of the General Order can be accepted only by the proper execution and proper forwarding by the appointee of the Oath of Office on or before October 31, 1934. 3. In accepting appointments tendered in paragraphs 6 and 7 quoted above, the oath of office required by paragraph 9, also quoted above, will be executed on National Guard Bureau Form No. 337, and forwarded through appropriate National Guard channels to the State Adjutant General. Forms for the purpose may be secured from appropriate authorities of the National Guard. The oath of acceptance will be forwarded to the War Department from the State Adjutant General through the Corps Area Commander, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau and the Chief of Arm or Service. •i. When the completed oath of office Is received by the State Adjutant General it should be checked to ascertain that it has been properly administered, and then forwarded to the Corps Area Commander with the following information: a. Status of the individual to whom it pertains in feder - ally recognized National Guard on April 4, 1934, and whether or not federal recognition in the National Guard has been continuous since that date and up to and including date of acceptance. Any change in federally recognized status should be reported giving date. b. Status In federally recognized National Guard on date of forwarding the report. (Note: It is believed that In most cases these require - ments will be covered by a statement showing status on April 4, 1934, and that no change in status has occurred since that date). c. Present assignment in National Guard of United States showing unit. d. For appointments made under paragraph 16 of General Order report of physical examination should be inclosed as directed thereby. e. If acceptance of appointment tendered by paragraph 6 or 7 of the General Order Is forwarded by the Ste to </seg>
            <seg id="p096">94 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Adjutant General on or arter November 1, 1934, statement should be made as to date or receipt from the officer in or - der that determination may be made as to whether or not it was forwarded by the officer within the time limit set by paragraph 9 of the General Order. 5. When the oath of acceptance is received at Corps Area Headquarters the federally recognized status will be checked with the Report of Federal Recognition previously furnished the Corps Area Commander under paragraph 53 a, NGR 20, and the assignment status in the National Guard of the United States and serial number ot the officers referred to in paragraph 14 of General Orders No. 3 will be recorded. It will then be forwarded to the National Guard Bureau. 6. When oath of acceptance is received in the National Guard Bureau the report required In paragraph 4 will be checked, and in forwarding, any discrepancies found will be set forth or statement made that the report is correct. In addition, (for those acceptances not accompanied by a report of physical exam - ination) the forwarding statement of the National Guard Bureau will also Include: Date of latest physical examination and whether or not the individual concerned was reported as physically qualified on such examination. Satisfactory reports of physical examination less than one year old will be accepted. For those appointed to commissioned grades who have not held prior ap - pointments in the Orficers' Reserve Corps a copy or N. G. B. Form 62 will be attached, or statement made that copy has been furnished to The Adjutant General. For those appointed War - rant Officers a copy of N. G. B. Form 62 will be attached. 7. It is suggested that the Adjutant General of the State set a suspense date to about November 15, 1934, for any officer under his jurisdiction whose appointment In the National Guard of the United States is effected by the General Order. It proper - ly executed oath of office is not received in time, report to that effect should be forwarded through the channels prescribed for forwarding an acceptance, with recommendation regarding can - cellation In any such case where appointment was made under </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL paragraph 16, General Orders No. 3. This report should set forth the efforts made to secure acceptance and should contain a state - ment covering federally recognized National Guard status as re - quired by paragraph 4 of this letter. By order of the Secretary or War: (Signed) James F. McKlnley, Major General, The Adjutant General." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 27, 1934 Circular Letter No. 11 " ■ .' ** Subject: Mother's Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization who may be separated from their mothers on May 13 the duty they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mother's Day. By. direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 28. 1934 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Enlistment in the National Guard of the United States. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following letter from the Chier, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance or all concerned: "1. The following questions relative to enlistment in the National Guard or the United States for the unexpired portion of enlistment in the National Guard have been received in this office: "Decision is requested as to whether the individual enlisted man now a member of the National Guard is re - quired to sign again the oath of enlistment for the unex - pired portion of his present enlistment period. "Information is requested as to the 'appropriate change - required In the oath when it is readministered; can the fol - lowing be interpolated in the oath: 'I do hereby acknowledge, etc., for the unexpired period of my present enlistment', etc. If not please indicate what change is desired! "Decision is requested as to whether a mass adminis - tration of oath is satisfactory as by company or battalion. "Information is requested as to whether data on the new administration ot oath should be included also on the duplicate enlistment record now filed in the otflce or the State Adjutant General." </seg>
            <seg id="p099">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL -. The above questions are answered as follows: "1. Since these men are already in the National Guard, they are enlisted only In the National Guard or the United States for the unexpired period or their National Guard enlistment. In effect, therefore, it is an enlistment in the National Guard of the United States for a term less than a rull-term enlistment. The proviso in Section 69, National Defense Act as amended, authorizing this, reads as follows: 'Provided, That all enlisted men of the National Guard on the date of approval or this Act may, under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of War, be enlisted In grade, rating and branch in the National Guard or the United States for the remaining unexpired portions ot their enlistments in the National Guard." "2. It will be noted that under this proviso these enlistments are made 'under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary or War'. The regulations pre - scribed are contained in General Orders No. 3, War Depart - ment, April 4, 1934. Under paragraph 12 or this order, the oath prescribed (the statutory oath) 'Is taken' on enlist - ment in the National Guard or the United States for the re - maining portion of enlistments. When men are enlisted in the National Guard they sign an enlistment contract and subscribe to the oath. Therefore the enlistment in the Na - tional Guard or the United States or those now in the Na - tional Guard is accomplished by taking the oath, and the making or appropriate notation thereof in the current en - listment records. Subscription to the oath is unnecessary. This is in accord with the National Guard Bureau letter or April 7, 1934. "3. As to changing the oath, no objection is seen but would add to the change proposed to make it read, 'for the unexpired period or my present enlistment In the National Guard'. "4. No objection is seen to 'mass administration' or the oath. It would appear to be desirable and would facili - tate the making or record thereor. "5 As to whether the 'date on the administration or the new oath' should be entered on the duplicate enlistment </seg>
            <seg id="p100">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL record now on file In the office of the State Adjutant Gen - eral, it seems that appropriate notation should be made of the fact of the date pf this enlistment In the National Guard of the United States, if for nothing more than permanent record purposes. This action Is deemed essential in those states that do not require the original enlistment record to be forwarded to the State Adjutant General when an In - dividual Is separated from the service." (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." 2. With reference to par. 5, this state requires the original enlistment record to be forwarded to this office when an individual is separated from the service which will give a complete record on file of those having severed their connection. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 4. 1934 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Claims for Overdeduction of 5% on February 1934. Armory Drill Pay. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following extract of letter from the Finan.e Officer. U. { S. Army, Fort Omaha, Nebraska, together with copy of payroll con - sidered by him to be correct for repayment or the overdeduction of </seg>
            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL five per cent on account of the Act of March 28, 1934, Is submitted for the Information and guidance of all concerned: "1. The only Information available to this office with re - gard to the repayment of the overdeduction ot 5% on account of the Act of March 28, 1934, was contained in radiogram from the Chief of Finance, a copy of which was furnished to each Adjutant General concerned. 2. In the opinion of this office a proper method of prepar - ing the claims tor refund of the 5% is as follows: On the payrolls covering the period March 1 to May 31, 1934, the Armory Drill Attendance Record should show the pay drills held during the month of February 1934. The remarks after the name of each claimant must show any change in grade which occurred during the month of February 1934. If a member of the organization was discharged and re - enlisted during February, that fact together with the date of the old enlistment must be shown. In case of transfers, the claim should be made on roll of the organization with which carried during the month of February. Column 11 of the payroll should be headed "Drills attended In February 1934, overdeduction or 5% Act 3-28-34" and the number of drills or percentage of duty performed entered in that column opposite the name of each claimant. Officers claiming administrative pay must state in remarks the fact administrative pay was claimed and paid for Feb - ruary 1934. The voucher number, month and account on which the regu - lar pay for February 1934 was paid, must be shown. In the case of members paid on supplemental rolls, the voucher number, month and account of the supplemental roll must be shown. 3. Claims for men who have left the service should be submitted directly to the General Accounting Office. This office </seg>
            <seg id="p102">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL is prohibited by law from furnishing advice or information in regard to the presentation of such claims. ****** (Signed) H. G. Coykendall, Major, Finance Dept., Finance Officer, U. S. Army." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Inch Model payroll STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 7, 1934 Circular Letter ; ,"j" , No. 14 Subject: Ammunition Allowances Calendar Year 1934. To: All Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. Tlie allowance of caliber .30 ball ammunition for practice at home station authorized by National Guard Bureau for the calen - dar year 1934 is as follows: 134 INFANTRY: 100 rds. per man for qualification. 50 rds. per man for requallficatlon. - This allowance Is for all men in the Company armed with the Rifle who have qualified with the caliber .22. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35th DIVISION TRAIN: 100 rds. per man for qualification. This allowance is only authorized for men armed with the Rifle who have not qualified as Marksmen or better and who have qualified with the caliber .22. 2. The above allowances have had to be curtailed by this office due to the fact that our supply of M1906 ammunition Is limited, but It Is thought that the amount which has been shipped to each organi - zation is sufficient to take care of all preliminary firing at home station. 3. There is no allowance of caliber .45 ammunition authorized this year. By direction ot the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 8, 1934 Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Appointment of National Guard Enlisted Men as Reserve Officers. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The following policy approved April 16, 1934, with refer - ence to the question of appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps of warrant officers and enlisted men of the National Guard </seg>
            <seg id="p104">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL was announced in letter from The Adjutant General dated April 18, 1934 (210.1 ORC 11-21-34 Res. A.): "That it be the expressed policy or the War Department that all appointments of Enlisted Men and Warrant Officers of the National Guard to commissions in the Army of the United States be in the National Guard of the United States, and that no such applicants be commissioned in the Officers' Reserve Corps." For the Chief, National Guard Bureau: (Signed) H. J. Weiler, Lieut. Col., N. G. B., Assistant." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA &gt; ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 9. 1934 Circular Letter No. 1 6 Subject: Transfer to Inactive National Guard of the United States. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Section 77, National Defense Act as amended by the Act of June 15, 1933, provides that under such regulations as the Secretary of War may prescribe, upon termination of service in the active National Guard an officer of the National Guard of </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the United States may, if he makes application therefor, re - main in the National Guard of the United States in the same grade and branch of service. 2. Prior to the issuance of General Orders No. 3, War Department, April 4, 1934, transfers to the National Guard Re - serve, effective prior to that date, were accepted by the National Guard Bureau and appropriate MB Forms 3-c issued. In all cases where those forms have been issued, oaths of office from National Guard Reserve officers will be accepted and forwarded to The Adjutant General provided such officers are assigned to appropriate war vacancies and a statement to that effect is fur - nished by the adjutant general of the state. 3. In the future, officers who are to be retained to fill war vacancies should be transferred to the Inactive National Guard and not to the National Guard Reserve. Transfers to the In - active National Guard should be accompanied by an application from the otficer concerned to remain in the National Guard of the United States and a statement by the state adjutant general that there is a vacancy in an active or inactive allotted unit to which he may be assigned. If such application accompanies the state order transferring the officer, MB Form 3-b will be issued continuing his federal recognition in the Inactive National Guard instead or the former process of issuing MB Form 3-c. That form will hereafter be issued only to terminate the federal recognition ot a National Guard Officer. 4. The foregoing provisions will continue in effect until supplanted by the appropriate regulations. (Signed) E. A. Fry. Colonel, N. G. B., For and In the absence of the Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, \ Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 25, 1934 Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Athletic Program. \ . To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following Athletic Program, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this program his personal attention and will cooperate with the Camp Athletic Officer In all particulars to the end that the program may be most interesting, entertaining, instructive and beneficial to the enlisted men and officers. 3. PROGRAM a. FIELD MEET. Saturday, August 18, after 9:30 A. M., Is reserved as Athletic Field Day. (1) All entries in athletic events scheduled for that period will be released from all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared of troops prior to the above designated hour. (2) Track All track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event. b. SWIMMING (1) Swimming events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd in each event. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (2) The swimming pool may be used only when life guards are present and on duty at the pool. c. BOXING (1) There will be competition iu each weight division and a medal awarded to the winner in each weight. d. MASS ATHLETICS (1) All enlisted men not engaged in other regularly scheduled training between tbe hours of 1:15 P. M. and 3:00 P. M., daily, Monday, August 6, and Saturdays and Sundays excepted, will be assembled in their company streets at 1:15 P. M. and marched, under a permanently designated leader, to the athletic field and reported to the camp athletic officer for physical training, athletics, recreational games, sports and training for athletics. (2) The period from 1:15 P. M. to 2:00 P. M. will be devoted to mass athletics, group games and similar events. The remainder of the time allotted will be devoted to baseball, swimming, track and similar activities. 4. GENERAL PROVISIONS a. Each regimental and separate battalion commander will immediately upon arrival at camp appoint a regimental and battalion athletic officer who will immediately re - port to the camp athletic officer as his assistant in the supervision of the recreational and athletic activities of the camp (Training Directive 1934). b. The commanding officer of each company or like unit will detail one noncommissioned officer or selected pri - vate to act as athletic representative of the unit. In - dividuals so detailed will report to the camp athletic officer as assistants from 1:15 P. M. to 3:00 P. M. on days when physical training is scheduled; they will also report promptly at 9:00 A. M. for one hour's attendance at any conference or school scheduled by the camp athletic officer. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">106 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. All officers detailed as above and all others assigned as camp athletic instructors will be under the orders of the camp athletic officer and will report to him for duty during the periods herein provided. d. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS HAVE ALL MEN WHO WILL BE ENTERED IN THE BOXING CONTESTS ACCURATELY WEIGHED AND IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DE - LIVER TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER A LIST OF THEIR RESPECTIVE ENTRIES TOGETHER WITH A STATEMENT OF THEIR ACCURATE WEIGHTS. e. ALL UNIT AND SUB-UNIT COMMANDERS WILL PRIOR TO LEAVING THEIR RESPECTIVE HOME STATIONS PREPARE LISTS OF THEIR RESPECTIVE ORGANIZA - TIONS' ENTRIES IN THE FIELD, TRACK AND SWIM - MING EVENTS AND IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER SAID LISTS TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER. 5. GENERAL'S TROPHY a. Adjutant General Paul is again offering a cup to the com - pany showing the greatest activity an.l efficiency in athletics. b. Point- will be awarded to the various companies upon the following basis: (1) Boxing Owing to the difficulty that has been experienced in arranging a card for the second' evening of camp (Tuesday) , It has been decided to award a greater number of points to the companies having entries in the boxing bouts upon that evening. Therefore, upon the first Tuesday evening, 25 points will be awarded for each entry at the ringside in condition to box, and 15 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. Upon all other evenings points will be awarded as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 10 points will be awarded for each entry appearing at the ringside in condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. An additional 15 points will be awarded to the win - ning entry in each bout. 25 points will be awarded to each entry who enters the semi-final. 50 points will be awarded to the champion in each weight division. If a knock-out occurs, the winner will be entitled to credit for three rounds. ( 2 ) Swimming; 50 points will be awarded for each 1st. 35 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (3) Track 50 points will be awarded for each 1st. 35 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Kitten Ball 75 points will be awarded to the company rating first place. 50 points will be awarded to the company rating second place. 25 points will be awarded to the company rating third place. (5) Mass Athletics 350 points will be awarded to the company evi - dencing the greatest activity and efficiency In mass athletics. 250 points will be awarded to the company evi - dencing the second greatest activity and efficiency In mass athletics. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 150 points will be awarded to the company evi - dencing the third greatest activity and efficiency In mass athletics. . By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 8, 1934 Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Loss of Small Arms. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. Your attention is invited to NGR 75-3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 30, October 18, 1933, and Nebraska Circular Letter No. 5, March 21, 1934, i. e., that small arms in possession of National Guard units must be safeguarded at all times and required to be kept in accordance with regulations which provide that they must be locked in chests or racks furnished by the Ordnance Department, and in addition are to be kept in securely locked rooms and not on the drill floor. All keys must be properly safeguarded as provided for in regulations cited above. 2. For your information you are advised that just recently a unit commander was held responsible by the surveying officer for the loss of small arms by theft, for the reason that the regulations above referred to were not complied with. 3. In numerous instances automatic rifles, machine guns, et cetera, have been found in the hands of gangsters, bandits and des - peradoes and a check up shows them to have been stolen from armories in different sections of the country. As a safeguard against our weapons falling into the hands of these people you are directed </seg>
            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL to remove the parts of arms listed below from the arm Itself and to place same In a secure place separate from the arm or arms as indicated: a. RIFLE, Calibers .30 and ,22 Remove the BOLT b. AUTOMATIC RIFLE, Browning, Caliber .30 Remove the FIRING PIN c. PISTOLS, Caliber .45 Remove the recoil spring PLUG d. MACHINE GUNS, Browning, Caliber .30 Remove the BACK PLATE ASSEMBLY ■' t.E'YE E ■ ' . - - - 7 ' ■ 4. Your attention is invited to the fact that bolts are fitted In - dividually to rifle caliber .30 and that in each case where a bolt Is removed from its rifle it must be tagged with the number of that rifle. THESE BOLTS ARE NOT INTERCHANGEABLE. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, I .. Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 17, 1934 Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Care and Preservation of Clothing and Equipment. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The allotment of funds for the replacement of clothing and equip - ment has been received by this office and shows quite a material re- </seg>
            <seg id="p112">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL duction from what has been available In former years, the amount now being approximately $2.40 per man for articles or the uniform and approximately 40c per man for other Quartermaster supplies. So It will be absolutely necessary for all concerned to use the utmost care «n preserving equipment or all kinds now in their possession and in this connection attention is invited to the provisions of paragraph 10, NGR 75-3, which will be compiled with. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 23. 1934 Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1934. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1934, having been set. i. e., August 6 to 20, 1934, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section III, NGR 45. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non-compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay or Company orficers. .--.-. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to train schedules, transportation requests and bills of lading. 3. Company Commanders are authorized to purchase subsist - ence for enlisted men and will follow instructions received from th"te USP&amp;DO thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained, i. e.. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL no men on top of the cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders and men's personal appearance and conduct correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. Tlie Commanding Officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp, and report to the camp commander immediately upon ar - rival any defects or faults found with railroads transporting troops. Each Company and Detachment Commander upon arrival at detrain - ing point will immediately report to Detraining Officer with reference to baggage detail. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O.D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on. Issue legglns and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Training Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag or foot locker. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., cotton breeches and O.D. shirts. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment and cleaning materials. No saddles, saddle equipment, or harness will be brought to camp. No target material or canvas cots will be brought to camp. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except cal. .22 long rifle and initial allowance of cal. .30 ball cartridges, lot 1644 FA, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO. All empty cartridges ( brass ) in packing boxes, aiming devices, arm racks and lockers sufficient for men in camp, rifles, bayonets and pistols for same and all other ordnance with which the individual and companies are equipped will also be brought to camp. The Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only sufficient ammunition to be used In the conduct of its fire on the range. The Infantry regiment will bring. in all ot its .22 caliber rifles with magazines. </seg>
            <seg id="p114">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 9. Special Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer proper - ty, including lister bags, Is to be carried. 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned In Immediately upon arrival In camp. A list In quad - ruplicate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence will be turned in immediately upon ar - rival in camp. 11. Transportation on equipment other than enumerated above, which becomes excess equipment, brought to camp will have to be paid for by the Unit Commander bringing or permitting same to be brought (M.B. file 554.4 Gen-81, May 25, 1931, Subject: Transporta - tion of Equipment for Field Training.). 12. .Messes. All Company orficers will mess with their organiza - tion. Every effort sbould be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. The , Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, with the Commanding Officer, 35 th Division Trains, QMC, will establish Officers' messes for the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 6, 1934. 13. Private Transportation. Company or like organization com - manders may detail one private to take their (company commander's) car to camp and return same to home station; no reimbursement will be made for the transportation thereof. Not more than three private automobiles, belonging to enlisted men, per company or like organiza - tion will be permitted in camp. Any private conveyance brought to camp other than set out above without special permission will be Immediately Impounded and held during the field training period. Officers and enlisted men bringing automobiles to camp will present State registration certificates at Camp Headquarters and have same registered on day of arrival. Company officers are required to travel with their respective companies. Where permission Is given to an enlisted man to bring his automobile to camp he will be required to transport same alone. </seg>
            <seg id="p115">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 14. The attention of all Unit and Sub-unit Commanders is called to the necessity of knowing their men are physically fit before tak - ing same to camp as the number of major operations In our camp must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 15. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will make sure that they are not bringing any venereal cases to camp and in case any are found on the physical examination that will be made on entering camp, same will be returned to their home station at their own expense, without pay or allowances, as they will not be permitted in camp; such men will also be required to refund both railroad fare and sub - sistence expended on them in bringing them to camp. 16. No companies, detachments, or details will be permitted in camp In advance of the time ordered In, for the purpose of condition - ing kitchens, putting up tentage, or doing other routine work unless same have been designated by order or otherwise by this office. 17. .-Motor Vehicles. All Government motor transportation, in - cluding Fords more recently issued, will be brought to camp. All or - ganizations having Government owned motor vehicles will, Imme - diately after arrival at camp and unloading of their equipment, have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Officer, to be placed in the camp pool for the duration of camp. I, 18. Miscellaneous, it will be noted tbat tent poles, the ends of which have been painted red, are to be used only on the concrete tent floors. 19. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will read this letter to their command at every armory drill between the time of. receipt of same and the time of entraining for camp. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p116">STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Circular Letter . ™* 25 ' 1934 No. 21 M Subject: Train Schedule To and Return From Annual Encampment, 1934, Ashland, Nebraska. H To: All Company Commanders, Field and Staff O. 'fleers, NNG. § 1. In accordance with General Order No. 3, AGO Nebraska, July 18, 1934, the following train schedule Is prescribed for movement to camp: *Q Approx. Bag. K Movements Organizations Location No. PaBB. Car Schedule M How Co Gering 55 1 Lv. Gering Tn No. 15, 4:00 PM &gt; No. 1 U) 8/5/34 g UP Co D No. Platte 55 1 Lv. No. Platte, Spec. 12:45 AM _. Fremont 8/6/34 _ g CB&amp;Q 119 Wag Co Lexington 45 1 Lv. Lexington, Spec. 2:15 AM g Ashland Co H Gr. Island 55 1 Lv. Grand Island, Spec. 4:15 AM h 130 Coll Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. Columbus, Spec. 5:45 AM Ar. Ashland. Spec. 8:05 AM H ' co~B Falls City 55~ 1 Lv. Falls Cy Tn No. 19, 3:28 | No. 2 AM 8/6/34 a MP Co A Nebr. City 55 1 Lv. Nebr. City 5:13 AM &gt; Omaha Hq Co 1st Bn 18 CB&amp;Q Regtl Hq Co Omaha 50 1 Lv. Omaha Tn No. 15, 9:00 AM Ashland Co K 55 1 Co L _ 55 1 MD Det 134 Inf 25 Hq Co 2d Bn 18 Ar. Ashland 9:45 AM </seg>
            <seg id="p117">Approx. t»ag. Movements Organizations Location No. Pass. Car Schedule Co 0 Beatrice 55 1 Lv. Beatrice Tn No. 24, 8:15 No. 3 AM 8/6/34 CB&amp;Q Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln 18 1 Lv. Lincoln, Spec. 10:00 AM Ashland Co I 55 ... S HO Vet Co 30 Ar. Ashland 10:35 AM n Co~E '. Scottsbluff 55 1 Lv. Scottsbluff Tn No. 32, 5:15 g No.. 4 (x) PM 8/5/34 . % CB&amp;Q 120 Wag Co Kearney 45 1 Lv. Kearney, Spec. 2:00 AM CB&amp;Q MD Det 35 DT 10 8/6/34 Ashland Co G Hastings 55 1 Lv. Hastings. Spec. 3:25 AM Serv Co 134 Inf York 70 1 Lv. York, Spec. 5:10 AM » Co M Seward 55 1 Lv. Seward, Spec. 5:55 AM j£j Ar. Ashland, Spec. 7:45 AM cT~F '- Hartington 66 F" Lv. Hartington Bus 6:30 AM d Interstate - ruck A 8/6/34 -, Transit Ar - Camu 11:3 ° AM £ Lines § 130 Amb Co Hastings 35 Lv. Hastings 7:00 AM 8/6/34 H No 6 Ar - Camp 3:0 ° PM O "via Serv Co 110 MR Lincoln 67 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 8/6/34 | Gov't 166 Hosp Co 60 Ar. Camp 10:00 AM | Motor 138 MT Co Fremont 44 Lv. Fremont 5:00 AM 8/6/34 Vehicles 119 MR Sec 15 Ar. Camp 9:00 AM £ 137 MT Co Holdrege 44 Lv. Holdrege 3:00 AM 8/6/34 f Ar. Camp 5:00 PM SS&amp;SD Lincoln 20 Lv. Lincoln 7:00 AM 8/4/34 I Ar. Camp 10:00 AM (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). </seg>
            <seg id="p118">i REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 2. Co. A and Hq. Co., 1st Bn., will load In one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and Med. Dept. Det. will load In one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Lincoln contingents will load in one baggage car. 2. TICKETS ..' Government Transportation Requests on the carrier concerned will be exchanged for ROUND TRIP TICKETS at the local ticket of - fice. Requests for berths will be exchanged with the Pullman con - ductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT „_. FaTT T WlU be SCt the day ~ eced ' S the movement to permit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is necessary. Tourist cars or coaches will be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner In ample time to permit carriers to leave at designated 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls hand baggage, field desks, dispensaries, typewriters, etc.. (par " 8 ' S?v «' K EaCh PleCC WU1 be marked ° r tag sed with name of owner' Checkable baggage will not be included on Bill or Lading Excess baggage consisting of property other than checkable baggage ' will be handled In baggage cars but Is paid for by ,the Government on ?ZT_r_, T ° f C ° VerlnE SUCh '"-Omenta ZZZ from each station, at freight rates. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">117 5. The following train schedule is prescribed for, the return movement: Approx. iJag- Movements Organizations Location No. Pass. Car Schedule , cTc Beatrice 55 1 Lv. Ashland Q Spec. 9:00 AM *?°vl Ar. Beatrice Tn No. 89, 12:08 # CB&amp;Q p M H De8t - Co M gcward 55 1 Ar. Seward Tn. No. 39, 11:41 g AM fO Sen Co 134 Inf York 70 1 Ar. York, Tn No. 39, 12:26 PM H Co H Or. Island 55 1 Ar. Gr Island Tn No. 39, 1:46 Q PM *J Co G Hastings 55 1 Ar. Hastings Tn No 5,1:10 PM H 120 Wag Co Kearney 45 1 Ar. Kearney, Spec. 2:40 PM g Sh-JTstBn- Nebr City - 18 1 Ar. Nebr Cy Tn No. 122, 12:35 &gt; Co A 55 PM U Co B Falls Cy 55 1 Ar. Falls Cy Tn No. 42-16, 4:18 g PM ►} ro E Scottsbluff 55 1 Ar. Scottsbluff Tn No. 31, 6:25 &gt; (x) (A) AM 8/21/34 g 130 Coll Co Columbus 55 1 Lv. Ashland Q Spec. 10:00 AM 0 No 8 8/20/34 M SZ'JL - Ar. Columbus UP Spec. 12:30 Z PM " Fremont Lexington 45 1 Ar. Lexington UP Spec. 4:00 PM g D?t Co D No Platte 55 1 Ar. No Platte UP Spec. 5:30 PM P How Co Gering 55 1 Ar Gering UP No. 53, 11:10 AM (x) 1 8/21/34 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">Approx. Bag. Movements Organizations Location No. Pass. Car Schedule Co K Omaha 55 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 24, 10:30 No. 9 Co L 55 1 AM 8/20/34 CB&amp;Q MD Det 134 Inf 25 Omaha Regtl Hq Co 50 1 n '.•,,,,... M Hq Co 2d Bn 18 Ar. Omaha 11:20 AM W No 10 Hq Co 3d Bn Lincoln 18 ~~ Lv. Ashland Tn No. 7, 2:19 PM &gt;o CB&amp;Q Co I 55 1 8/20/34 g D est7 110 Vet Co 30 Ar. Lincoln 3:00 PM £ J7~ 11 Co F Hartington 66 1 Lv. Camp, Bus 7:00 AM O Interstate truck 8/20/34 «* Transit H Llne8 Ar. Hartington 12:00 N W ~~- 130 Amb Co Hastings 35~ Lv. Camp 7:00 AM 8/20/34 No 12 Ar. Hastings 3:00 PM &gt; Via Serv Co 110 MR Lincoln ' 67 Lv. Camp 1:00 PM e^ Gov't 166 Hosp Co 60 Ar. Lincoln 4:00 PM G Motor 138 MT Co Fremont 44 Lv. Camp 3:00 PM £ Vehicles 119 MR Sec 15 Ar. Fremont 7:00 PM v. 137 MT Co Holdrege 44 Lv. Camp 4:00 PM 8/19/34 H Ar. Holdrege 2:00 PM 8/20/34 0 SS&amp;SD Lincoln 20 Lv. Camp 7:00 AM 8/21/34 M Ar. Lincoln 10:00 AM 2 (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). (A) Day S coaches from Ashland to Lincoln. F </seg>
            <seg id="p121">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 7. Hq. Co., 1st Bn. and Co. A will use one baggage car. Movement No. D. Med. Dept. Det. and Regtl. Hq. Co. will use one bag - gage car Co. K and Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., will use one bag - gage car. Movement No. 10. Lincoln contingents will load in one baggage car. 6. Postal Card Report WD MB No. 36 will be mailed to the USP&amp;DO as soon as possible after arrival at home station, with any unused tickets and "Conductor's Report of Troops Carried". 7. Two in. ■mo ran. In in copies of Bill of Lad ing must be given to Ihe USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to departure. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Major, QMC, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 26, 1934 Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Annual Encampment, 1934. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG 1. In accordance with par. 15, MB Circular No. 25, A-21, August 30, 1930, responsible officers for companies or detachments are authorized to purchase the necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40 cents per meal per man for the time involved in </seg>
            <seg id="p122">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL assembling, travel and arrival at camp. Balance of meals for the first day will be the Garrison Ration. 2. There is inclosed Check List "A" in duplicate, which goes into detail and must be used in conjunction with purchase and settle - ment of the amount involved. 3. In accordance with the train schedule your company or de - tachment would be entitled to the following meals: August 6 Company B j D S B — Breakfast D — Dinner S — Supper O — None GR — Garrison Ration M — Meal By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. Ncbiaska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Major, QMC. USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. Incls. 2: 1. Check List "A" in dup. 2. Vouchers </seg>
            <seg id="p123">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 27. 1934 Circular Letter No. 23 . Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1934 To: Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ is inclosed herewith for freight (not checkable baggage) involved in movement of your Com - pany to Ashland, Nebraska. Bill of Lading for the return movement will be furnished while at camp. These Bills of Lading should be completed In accordance with Check List "C" attached In duplicate. 2. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable rate where there is no government transportation available for the purpose of transporting baggage and equipment from the armory to the depot and return. 3. Company Commanders will detail sufficient personnel to handle baggage at the detraining point. 4. Read carefully NGR 71 and 72 with changes. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. 4 incls: 1 . Original B/L with memos and S. O. 2. Check List "C", in dup. 3. Public Voucher 4. Property List, in trip. </seg>
            <seg id="p124">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN I ; July 28, 1934 Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Government Transportation Requests. Annual Encampment. 1934. (ROUND TRIP) To: Officers Responsible for Same. i. In accordance with par. 73-c, NGR 71. Government Trans - portation Request No. WQ is inclosed herewith, to cover railroad transportation (tickets) for your Company and any field or staff officers of the NNG residing at your station, to Ashland, Nebraska. and return, which should be completed in accordance with Check List "B" attached in duplicate. 2. The responsible officer in this case is acting as transporta - tion officer and as train quartermaster and any accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations will be charged against the responsible orflcer. 3. Arrangements have never been made to have the transporta - tion requests exchanged for tickets on the train. It is therefore re - quested that they be exchanged with the local agent. Read carefully NGR 70 and 71, with changes. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major. QMC. USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p125">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4 incls.: 1. Original T/R 2. Check List "B", in dup. . 3. Post Card WD MB 36, in dup. 4. Conductor's Reports as required. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ;,■'... .... j - i July 31, 1934 Circular Letter No. 25 ■■&lt;:■'■■ &gt; Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, Fiscal Year 1935. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, Is published for the information and guidance or all concerned: "The Secretary or War directs that you be informed that the number or drills to be held during the Fiscal Year 1935, will be limited as follows: (a) During the 1st and 2nd Quarters (July 1 to December 31, 1934, incl.), not to exceed 24 Federal pay drills. (b) During the 3rd Quarter (January 1 to March 31, 1935, incl.), not to exceed 12 Federal pay drills in addition to any part ot the 24 drills not held In the 1st and 2nd Quarters. ' •'-■'■■ . ' ' ■ - ■:■■'.'.,'■'! (c) During the 4th Quarter (April 1 to June 30, 1935. incl.)', not to exceed 12 Federal pay drills in addition to any part ot the 36 drills not held during the 1st. 2nd and 3rd Quarters. .,...-',' E (d) In no event will the number ol drills for which pay - ment is made from Federal funds exceed eight (8) In </seg>
            <seg id="p126">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year for any organization of the National Guard. (Signed) E. A. Fry, Colonel, N. G. B., For and in the absence of the Chief, National Guard Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, .''■'. Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 24. 1934 Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: West Point Preliminary Competitive Examination, 1934. for the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of one enlisted man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive examination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's orfice, Wednesday, Novem - ber 8, 1934, at 9:00 A. M. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an applicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1935, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years and must not be less than 5 ft. 4 in.j in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and can not be waived or modified, but It Is not essential that the service be con - tinuous, therefore former service In the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibUity. </seg>
            <seg id="p127">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War De - partment to report for the regular entrance examination, which Is scheduled to be held about March 5, 1935, and the appointment avail - able on July 1, 1935, will be awarded to the qualified candidate In the order of merit established at the examination, which is competi - tive among all National Guard Candidates. 4. Previously applicants have presented themselves to take this examination who were In no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an appli - cant should have had at least one year In college, in addition to a high school education. The examination will be written and will consist of an exhaustive examination in the following subjects: Ele - mentary Algebra, to and including Quadratics, Plane Geometry, Eng - lish Grammar, United States and General History and English Litera - ture and Composition. 5. No state funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. 6. A blank form to be used in making application to participate in the examination is inclosed. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. (1) Appl. blank. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 26, 1934 Circular Letter No. 27 Subject: Issue of Military Publications. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p128">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The following letter from the Chier, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Due to the reduction in available funds for printing and binding, fiscal year 1933, the provisions of Militia Bureau Circular No. 16 A-12, 1931, are suspended and future distribu - tions will be made as indicated herein. 2. For new training publications the distribution is to be approximately one for each oHlcer and one for each unit file down to and to include company, troop, battery and detach - ment for the arm concerned. In the case or publications now In print replacement requisitions can only be filled from stock now on hand. Publications already ordered by the Militia Bureau on the basis ot the old distribution will be distributed accord - ingly. 3. The distribution of Army Regulations will be reduced In the case of State Staffs from ten to five copies, in the case of Division Headquarters from twenty-live to ten copies and in tho case of Brigade Headquarters from five to two copies. 4. The distribution ot War Department General Orders is discontinued, except those affecting the National Guard. 5. The issue ot the Army List and Directory is discon - tinued. Copies desired may be obtained from The Superin - tendent of Documents, Government Printing Office, Washington. D. C, at a cost of $1.50 per year or at 40c per copy from funds other than Federal. (Signed) George E. Leach, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p129">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 15, 1934 Circular Letter No. 2S Subject: Drill Pay Notations on Form No. 100, F. Y. 1935. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. The following letter from the Chier, National Guard Bureau, is published lor the information and guidance of all concerned: "Paragraph 2, National Guard Bureau letter of July 24. 193;;. on subject: Limitation or Armory Drills, F. Y. 1934 re - quiring that "All drills held, whether for Federal pay or not. will be reported monthly on M. B. Form 100. with notation made on the form showing the drills for which Federal pay Is claimed", is rescinded as Federal funds will be available to pay for forty - eight drills held during the fiscal year 1935. For the Chief. National Guard Bureau: (Signed) W. R. Smedburg, Jr., Colonel, NGB., Assistant." By direction of tlie Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN • December 8, 1934 Circular Letter No. 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p130">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENErAl Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment, Fiscal Y'ear 1935. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with Instructions received from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area December 5, 1934, It will be necessary to submit, not later than February 1, 1935, requisitions covering supplies and equipment for your company for the balance of the fiscal year 1935. 2. Requisitions received after the date set forth above can not be acted upon prior to Field Training 1935. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 10, 1934 Circular Letter No. 30 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. 1. Inclosed are WD MB Forms No. 67 to be used in making the annual Efficiency Reports for the year ending December 31, 1934. </seg>
            <seg id="p131">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The reports are to be made in accordance with instructions contained In paragraphs 63 b (1) and d (1), NGR 20, dated November 12, 1931. 2. Reports are to be forwarded by the reporting officer to the next military superior within ten days of the close of the period covered In the report, exclusive of Sundays and holidays, and are to reach this office by the end of the month. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. ' i ' -■■'■ '-••'- ' </seg>
            <seg id="p132">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who partici - pated in the service of the Spanish-American War in the First, Second and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volun - teer Cavalry: COMPANY A — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name A nit . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Pvt. Gelvin, Robert N $3.20 Pvt. Allen, Roller C .3.20 Pvt. Kremer, Cochron A 4.00 Pvt. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 Pvt. Sommers, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Morgenstern, Henry A 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W 3.20 Pvt. Shively, Bion 3.20 Pvt. Wompler, Elmer B 3.20 Pvt. Freeman, Charlie O... 3.20 COMPANY B — FTBST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Garinger. Albert $0.80 Pvt. Killhom, Perry A 4.00 Pvt. Black, John 4.00 Pvt. Ke.ssekuie. Herbert L. 4.00 Pvt. Grainger, Louis 1 1.60 COMPANY (' — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Johnson. Hans $3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 Pvt. Campbell, Roy G 3.20 COMPANY l&gt; — FIRST REGIMENT Bank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alley, John S $4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 COMPANY K — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F....... 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt, Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Moffet, Jesse C 3 20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W. .. 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pv]t. Bays, Wm 80 Pvt. Thomas. Harry H 3.20 COMPANY F — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher, Josehp P.. .$3. 20 Pvt. Gilbert. Alvin W 3.20 Cpl. Sims. Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E '.'. 3^20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua .... 3^20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E. 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston .... 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3^20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 COMPANY G— FIRST REGIMENT . Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John $3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C ..,'. 3.20 Pvt. Dowis. Jonathan E 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P '.-.'.. S^O Pvt. Underwood, Henry C. 3.20 COMPANY H — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H $3.20 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Robblns, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W '.. 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S... 4.00 Pvt. Sutton, Roy O..... 1.60 Pvt. Mansker, James F.. 3.20 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Wlnagel, Anthony J... 2.40 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L'.j 3.20 COMPANY I — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Hotsel, Leon V $4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J 4.00 Pvt. Berndtson, John E 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY K — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. DeLong, Herbert B $3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L... 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Pvt. Schmelder, Wm. G 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N 3.20 COMPANY L — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Downs, James W $3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H... 3.20 COMPANY M — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin A 3.20 _t,s. Rucker, Winifred L... 3.2. Pvt Jack, Cecil B 3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due P. M. Brown, Robert S $4.00 Mes. Murnhouse, F. Edd 4.00 COMPANY A — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H...$3.20 Art. Devlnney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Palne, Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T... 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David A....... 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Pvt. Williams, AUred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles .... 3.20 COMPANY B — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Whltmer, James K $3.20 Pvt. Mlnnlch, Herbert J 3.20 Wag. Crow, Wallace H 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Frank- A 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Art. Grossett, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Briggs, Ernest G. Pvt. Wilson, Eli A 3.20 (Died in service) 3.20 COMPANY C — SECOND REGIMENT Bank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles. George $3.20 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 Pvt. Klme, David 1.60 J Pvt. Lee. Ira E 3.20 Pvt. McLaln, Clarence E 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R... 3.20 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester .... 1.60 Pvt. Church, John H...J. 1.60 COSU'ANY D — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Nanus Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M. 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 COMPANY E — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due | Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 : Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W... 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W. 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E.. 3.20 Pvt. | Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COJIPANY F — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton, George $3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY G — SECOND REGIMENT Bank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2ndLt. Hodgins, Eli .....$3.20 Pvt. Hugh. Harry 80 Cpl. Hays, Robert A 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S 80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. McFarlaUd. Sm'l F..... .80 Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V..... .80 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H 80 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L 80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 3.20 Pvt. Fisher, Leo 80 Pvt. Quimby, Luclen E 80 Pvt. Galney, John H .80 Pvt. Ritter, David 80 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr... 3.20 Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D 80 COMPANY H — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Borland, John A $4.00 Pvt. Johnston, George H... 4.00 Art. Nlell, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvah 4.00 Pvt. Bowers/ Henry H 4.00 Pvt. Meitner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 4.00 Pvt. Davis, Harry E 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Serensen, Ole C 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry 0 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 4.00 COMPANY 1 — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Anil. Due QM Sgt. Rainey, Jacob A... $4.00 Pvt. Schuelke, Herman A... 4.0" Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore .. 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. I Walker, Joseph H 4. On Pvt. Penland, John W 80 Pvt. Way, Rueben D 4.00 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 7 COMPANY K — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Anil. Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T...$3.20 Pvt. West, Charles 3.20 Cpl. Hill. John T 3.20 COMPANY L — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Jack. Charles H $2.40 Pvt. Clarenden, Alvln T 4.00 i . . .... </seg>
            <seg id="p137">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Sage, John M 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, Wm. C 80 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Pvt. Powell, Joseph A 3.20 Pvt. Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Cottrell, Eugene W 3.20 Pvt. Wilson. Thomas B 1.60 COMPANY M — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Alfreds. Frank H $5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm 5.60 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W. 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncan C 5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 FIELD STAFF AND BAND — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, Roy D.$9.60 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L. 12.00 RB Mus. Parkhurst, Harry 3.20 COMPANY A — THIRD REGIMENT Bunk Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Brldenthal, C. W. $32.55 Pvt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 Pvt. Horahan, Chas 5.60 Cpl. Stelnbach, George ....12.72 Pvt. Hinckley, John S 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Mathew 1.60 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J 1.60 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Pvt. Koontz, Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N. 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 Pvt. O'Leary, John J 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Pace, Perle R. 2.40 Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Art. Ball. Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Schneider, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Allen, Thomas 4.80 Pvt. Smith, John J 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 Pvt. Taylor, James J 2.40 Pvt. Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Trombly, Pvt. Collins, John H 1.60 Warden. A. F 18.39 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr... 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY II — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. McGrew, Frank .......... .80 Pvt. Bradford, George H... .80 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W...33.64 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas 80 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Custer, Ellsha 80 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Francisco, John H 80 Pvt. Place, John F 21.36 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Ray, Evert P 20.42 Pvt. Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Roop, Scott D 80 Pvt. Habbick, George W 1.60 Pvt. Schwartz, Wm. 80 Pvt. Jarvls, Chas. T 80 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N 80 Pvt. Keanes, James N 80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E 33.64 Pvt. Line, Jno. M 17.59 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 Pvt. Whalen, Edwin F 3.20 COMPANY C — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Sue 1st Sgt. White, Thomas R..$27.46 Pvt. Shlel, Daniel J 7.64 Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip .... 2.40 Cpl. Dilllon, Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Costello, Michael F 13.30 Cpl. Sydow, Emll 27.46 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P 8.58 Cpl. Miller, Wm. E 27.46 Pvt. DeRivleres, Francis L. 4.80 Cpl. Burket, Harry B 2.40 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Pvt. Henske, Fred 80 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Hawkins, Elgin C 8.58 Art. Freeman, Nathan W... 27.46 Pvt. Henry, William 2.4 0 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E 27.46 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Howell, Harry H 22.74 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F 2.4 0 Pvt. Keliher, John F 4.80 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Long, Wilber W 5.75 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.80 Pvt. Mitchell, Edward F 2.40 Pet. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Norton, Ernest H 11.41 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albln F... 2.40 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Pvt. Zurubsky, James 7.64 COMPANY D — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D..$ 4.80 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B 26.74 Pvt. Jansen, Nels P 23.91 Cpl. Christensen, Pvt. Juul, John M 30.52 Christian A. 36.18 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C 80 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry .... 1.60 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 4.80 Mus. Howell, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M.. 8.00 Pvt. Allweln, John C 1.60 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G 8.00 Pvt. Anderson, Edward .... 4.00 Pvt. Pool, John E 4.80 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew .... 3.20 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S 4.80 Pvt. Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Roble, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Sutton, Frank E. 6.40 COMPANY E — THIRD REGLMENT Bank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Siddell, Bert E $13.01 Pvt. Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Pvt. Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Lewin. Samuel C 80 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L 80 COJIPANY F — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A...$36.69 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P 36.69 Pvt. Baughman, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Head, Charles ...36.69 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Karges, John 36.69 Pvt. Kment, Joe 1.60 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H 80 Pvt. Knott, Fred 80 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Underhlll, i Charles ....36.69 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 Pvt. Nicholson, James T 1.60 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J 3.20 Pvt. Olson. Chris .80 COMPANY G — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burnett, Hamilton H $29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac 80 Cpl. Larson, Felix G 29.72 Pvt. Forsman, Oscar 29.72 Cpl. Collins, Wllke S 29.72 j Pvt. Fuller, Guy W 1.60 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Howard, Edward 29.72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt. Jones, Frank 27.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p140">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Knapp, Willie R 29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt. Larson, Axel W 29.72 Pvt. Bowerman, Wm. F 4.80 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William .... 4.00 Pvt. Conner, Clement T.....29.72 Pvt. Plckard, Harry M 29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A 29.72 COMPANY H — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name . Amt. Due Rank Name Ami. Due Pvt. Headwell, Axel $31.09 Pvt. Williams. Edgar T 31.09 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N 6.55 Pvt. Robinson. Edward .... 3.20 Pvt. Keever, Oscar W 13.16 Pvt. Thomas, James T 3.20 Pvt. Leichty, John 6.55 Pvt. Matson, Albert 5.60 COMPANY I— THIRD REGIMENT Hank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Derlenger, George ....$36.61 Pvt. Carroll, John W 4.00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry D. S. 37. 56 Pvt. Center, Albert 4.80 Cpl. Dickenson, John W 12.07 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R.. 9.24 Cpl. Felts, William B 6.40 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander 3.20 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M 4.00 Pvt. Fairchild, Homer 1.60 Cpl. Meyer, Otto 4.00 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A 4.00 Wag. Brett, Zine H 22.45 Pvt. Hackler, David D 1.60 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L 4.00 Pvt. Hanks. Harry E 1.60 Pvt. Jones, Lloyd 0 4.00 Pvt. Potter. Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Miller, Fred S 9.24 Pvt. Palmer, Archibald G... 5.60 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F... 9.24 Pvt. Roberts. James W 9.24 Pvt. Padol, Adam 80 Pvt. Selby, Arthur 1 9.24 Pvt. Perry, Chas. E 11.12 Pvt. Starky. Cyrus :!7.56 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W...23.40 Pvt. Stohe, John G 4.00 Pvt. Aitken, George F 37.56 Pvt. Swan, Richard B 80 Pvt. Baird, Francis H 4.80 Pvt. Vandyke, John T 6.40 Pvt. Bersley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Vandyke, Sherman .... 6.40 Pvt. Brown. Frank H 4.00 Pvt. Warrington, Albert J. 2.40 COMPANY K — THIRD REGIMENT ; Hank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. Jacobson, Carl L...$34.29 Pvt. Mines, James S 1.60 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N... 34.29 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H 80 Pvt. Porterfield, James A.. .34. 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Bunk Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Colield, Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Reardon, Patrick J 2.40 Pvt. Gray, Lyman 3.20 Pvt. Roff, John L 29.57 Pvt. Hightower, Harry A... 2.40 Pvt. Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kennedy, George H 7.20 Pvt. Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Pvt. Kankright, Clinton D. 27.68 Pvt. Thompson, James B... 3.20 Pvt. Kruger, Wm 80 Pvt. VanSickle, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. Mathews, Stanley 30.52 Pvt. Williams, Wm. M 1.60 Pvt. McCaulley. Wm. G 1.60 COMPANY Is — THIRD REGIMENT i Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. I Brown, Cleveland W..$7.20 Pvt. Jones, Joseph B 4.80 Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J. .... 4.00 Pvt. Kelley, Robert S 6.40 Cpl. Lowe, Walter 8.00 Pvt. McColl, John 14.40 Cpl. Tart, Charles C 21.01 Pvt. McCormlck, Benj. D... 8.00 Wag. Stockton, Andrew 32.34 Pvt. Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman 6.40 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H... 5.60 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt. Bradshaw, Thomas H.. 5.60 Pvt. Lee, Justivin E 1.60 Pvt. Burns, James E 3.20 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A 21.01 Pvt. Chlsolm, Ralph 0 5.60 Pvt. Mardock, John E 1.60 Pvt. Redfield, Cyrus R 4.80 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Rundus, Frank 32.34 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. Sherry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Athos, Andrew G 27.62 Pvt. Swanson, Nels 32.34 Pvt. Black, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Fox, Ernest S 24.79 Pvt. Walker, Chas 27.62 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Mus. Woerhlde, Charles E... 6.40 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 COMPANY M — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Foster, John E $ 4.00 Pvt. Helsler, Robert D 80 Sgt. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt. Hensel, Wm. A 2.40 Cpl. Alsen, John C 35.38 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris ....35.38 Pvt. Bennett, NUes 21.22 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H 17.44 Pvt. Blegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Maddan, Chas 35.38 Pvt. Brewick, Andrew T 3.20 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E 11.78 Pvt. Cantello, John 10.84 Pvt. Ratekln, Janson L 80 Pvt. Carigan, Robert J 35.38 Pvt. Tlmmons, Alfred D 34.44 Pvt. Custard, Marshall 1.60 Pvt. Wiesman, Jacob 2.40 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A.. .13. 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p142">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Foster, Frederick W...17.44 Pvt. Alley, Franc 2.40 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Beardsley, Wm. S 80 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 Pvt. Johnson, John D 13.60 TROOP K — THIRD CAVALRY , Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. McLaughlin. Walter..$ 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger Claude G. 2.40 It is recommended that this list be given a circulation in the newspapers of the State with a view to locating such of these men as possible. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>