<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home AT GRAND ISLAND For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home A I GRAND ISLAND For the Bicnnium Ending November 30, 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">REPORT. Eo the Honorable John H Micke. rnor, ami the Board f Public Lands and Buildin. utlemen : — I have the honor to submit the following report be biennium ending Novemlx I am glad to be ai i»&gt;rt that there will be but few de - 1 the funds in which there are deficiencies are I • minended larger appropriations for. The improve - r which appropriations were made consist of an addi - to the brick hospital, fire proof coal house, iron roof to boil - ei house, and a rn. The folio* rovements were made from the cash fund: uhouse : brick root house in which we store 1,500 addition of f&gt; stalls to horse barn; frame store ft. : also a i with the others mill iine. The cost of this cottage did not come li fund proper, but was built by money bequeathed for that pi: ud donations by two (2) of the In the all buildings, (excepting the main build ;nted. pi &gt;r ealcimined. The main building painted with mineral paint over the soft brick on out- B calcimined and er- ings on part kWith this you will find estimate for coming biennium. I have refull ,f the home, and ask for no more an the iiureasc. and ] warrant me in doing. On . e had a membership of 464 ; on Xovem - '•. 1906 we had 507 making a net gain of 43 members. We have on file the applications of 20 women whom we can - account of no room, and 5 men whose applications n approved, but not yet reported. In addition to this have had a great many letters from old comrades making in - quiries as to admission of th &gt; and wives, but. when they learn that women cannot be admitted for want of room, say that thev will starve it out together. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I do think that additional room should be provided or that law of admission be changed. I call attention to the re- port of the surgeon as to need of additional room in hospital. Two years ago I urged that an appropriation of twenty-five thou- sand ($25,000) dollars be made for a new building here to re- the present crowded condition and to provide for the fu- ture. I shall again urge this appropriation. Thanking the governor and the board for courtesies shown, and the officers and members of the home for efficient help and cheerful compliance of the rules, I am Respectfully W. S. ASKWITH. Commandant NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME. GRAND ISLAND. NEBRASKA .ESTIMATED EXPENSES FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM. Salaries. Two yrs. Commandant |] .1)0.00 $3,0&lt;i' Adjutant 1.000.00 2,00 Surgeon 1,200.00 2,4C Matron 500.00 1,00 Total $8,400.00 EMPLOYEES. Bookkeeper Head engineer 900.00 Night engineer 1.200.00 Farm manager 540.00 1."- Stenographer 180.00 ■•"&gt;.00 Major 240.00 50.00 Orderly Sgt. 1 -n.00 360.00 rter Master Sgt. o.OO 240.00 ■ Com ii, 120.00 240.00 180.00 360.00 (.•tier 7 mo. at $15 105.00 210.00 Florist 240.00 480.00 florist 120.00 240.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">322 ■her 1 -i'.OO 0.00 ■:t watchman 10.00 1 Mian :.4&lt;).iM) l.i - Niirht fireman 540.00 1,08 Miki.OO 0.00 farm hands and dairyman 1,800.00 3.600.00 dryman 1,200.00 • launch 0.00 UundreM 600.00 ...in bail. 1,800.00 420.00 84(M)(i lital 36O.O0 720.00 it a I 360.00 Ti'o.imi t table ■ !"i each per month . 1,440.00 dish w month 720.00 1,440.00 Hos] ward IS B0.00 ;.ital nurses 1,800.00 3.600.00 niatn&gt;n ai - e janit&lt; ich lawn keeper 7 i $15 105.00 21&lt; 7 mo. at $15 105 210.00 55 ■ *:U.l- ■ I all others noi - r5.000.00 Furniture and bedding 2,500.00 Transportat- 400.00 Libn :!( 1000 1.01 500.00 'a kelp 4i" Total maintenance and clothing 180.100.00 lJurial expens. | l&gt;.i fuel and engine oils 17.500.00 team plant 1 .!&gt;■ i)rugs and instrunn pita] aj&gt;pli ;: I aintiriir and repairs </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Stock and implement! I. 1 " 3,0 Klectric lights and repairs ~&gt;&lt; I would recommend appropriation! for an addition to brick I would recommend appropriation* fur an addition to brick ital similar to addition built within the past t\\ this •■ the women '■ side; also for extension on the kitchen ital similar to addition built within the past tv this •■ the women*! side; also for extension on the kitchen dining room to make room for the patients at table: als. uining room to make room for the patients at table: als. and niakiiiL' quarters for the hospital help. raising root' and making quarters for the hospital help. Total Total • house 1,0 1,0 r permanent sidewalks to replace the wooden on that are now worn out Pot permanent sidewalks to replace the wooden im that are now worn out metal eeilings for the main building, 17,000 sq ft. 1.4' ,in additional building ■_'•"&gt;. 'MlO.OO I eeilinga for the main building, 17, Odd For (400 ft 2* inch cotton tire how For hose cart for :«M&gt; ft. hose Col. W. 8. Askwith. Command;! I have the honor to submit to you the tenth biennial re of my office for the two years commencing the first day of De- ■&gt;er. 1W4. and ending the 30th day of November. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">324 pan} JO A.lUrtl -dm i uoi.«ud I -!«H : 5 ■ . 5 : ; • f ' SB '. ~'\ . '. '. . '. • «■ — — I- I- I- — C -f • • ■• l- f*. . - -c « — - ' • -*Q9fi»3 — ' - - ■■:-ga: ;:: - i. . . . ; • : § . tai . 3 : • • : | » te 3? 13 ii §J S * "O a ■ a -a a S ■ - = • - - i i. 3 1 1"! I -pasd«i * 333SSS r: U(H1S[J(I(UI| 61 i«a T ■ ■- ■ X '. '.~ '. . . '. •papu — 1 - c r c. c * 1 -r ;i-Ktr- 'OSTOar - r^&gt;M — *i — *T TJ «» I I«5O X c ■": I- »-■; 1- aoii -vudojddv 5355 = 5 ;5S;SS?SS5= . ' : = S,^; — 71 I- — . p-^ssa SI 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">punj COfil JO A.MI..I uoiiBiadojd r I papuadx^ f: — c -f • - — — [«lo X § 5 § 5 '- g 1 §§§ &lt;;(Hi[ UOll -Budojddy x : 5 i '7 ! ■; -r ri 9061 painijdojd -d« ADU.»l.)lJd(J ■4 &lt; ■ojrtdc jofiKit - : : if : i : : i I : J a 1 : : 1 • j| : • 5-3 :2 — t« a. . c c 3.5 S * :J 8gj| 1 ■ 111 111 Sao •— i c c .= O i- r. C </seg>
            <seg id="p008">326 Cash receipts and disbursements from December 1. 1904, to ember 30, 1906. 1904 Dec. 1, Balance cash on hand *l.i'75.94 Dec. 1, Warrant* in adjustment of deficiency vchrs. 251.49 RECEIPTS. IKM Dec. 6, Bee Hive Grocery lard ... $ 13.40 r. 14, Warrant for labor performed by farm em - ployees, acct. new commissary building Dec. 14, Surplus pay roll 12.93 Dec. 14. S. H. Roush for lard 2.45 Dec. 14, H. M. Gilbert. glo\- .35 Dec. 20, Effects of Geo. Craig, deceased 1905 Jan. 1. Sale of hide 4.56 Jan. 1, G. N. Anderton, meat trying! 1.00 Jan. 1. Sale of hide 5.18 5.18 Jan. 1, E. Wilson, gloves Jan. 1, E. Wilson, gloves .25 .25 Jan. 3, S. H. Roush, meat frying 4.55 Jan. 3, S. H. Roush, meat fryinjrs 4.55 Jan. 3, M. Williams, meat frying 2.40 Jan. 7, Surplus Dec. pay roll 19.14 Jan. 3, M. "Williams, meat fryin^s 2.40 Jan. 7, Surplus Dec. pay roll 19.14 Jan. 8, Effects of Jas. Slavon, deceased 2.85 Jan. 8, Effects of Jas. Slavon, deceased 2.85 r. 9. Warrant for labor performed by farm em - ployees acct. commissary building 4.50 Jan. 9. Warrant for labor performed by farm em - ployees acct. commissary building 4.50 Jan. 10, G. N. Anderton, meat fryings 1.75 Jan. 10, G. N. Anderton, meat fryings 1.75 Jan. 10, Effects of deceased members _ 31.10 Jan. 10, Effects of deceased members _ 31.10 Jan. 13, Jonas P. Sacrison, member of Home 24.00 Jan. 13, Jonas P. Sacrison, member of Home 24.00 Jan. 13, Sale of effects of deceased members 12.25 Jan. 13, Sale of effects of deceased members 12.25 Jan. 17, S. C. West, iron post .20 Jan. 17, S. C. West, iron post .20 Jan. 18, Sale of steers 1,022.45 Jan. 18, Sale of steers 1,022.45 Jan. 19, Sale of 21 cows and heifers 514.85 Jan. 19, Sale of 21 cows and heifers 514.85 Jan. 20, Earl Wilson, gloves and tobaci .60 Jan. 20, Earl Wilson, gloves and tobaci • .60 Jan. 21, Sale of hogs and cow 329.42 Jan. 21, Sale of hogs and cow 329.42 Jan. 25, Effects of Jas. T. Northrop Dec 25.32 Jan. 25, Effects of Jas. T. Northrop Dei 25.32 Feb. 1, Sale of hides 8.75 Feb. 1, Sale of bides 8.75 Feb. 1, Sale of meat fryings and lard 5.62 Feb. 1, Sale of meat fryings and lard 5.62 Feb. 4, Sale of hides 5.55 Feb. 4, Sale of hides 5.55 Feb. 6. Sale of meat fryings </seg>
            <seg id="p009">327 Feb. 11, Sale of fryings Feb. 15, Surplus Jan. pay roll Feb. 15, Sale of fryings 3.10 Feb. 16, Sale of meat fryings -80 Feb. 18, Sale of meat fryings 150 Feb. 18, Sale of meat frying Feb. 22. Sale of hide 4.90 Mch 1. Sale of lard 4.17 Mch. 1, Sale of lard .Mch. 1. Sale of lard 26.85 Mch. 1. Sale of lard 26.85 Mch 3, D. B. Cook, deceased 70.30 Mch. 3, D. B. Cook, deceased 70.30 Mch. 9, Sale of meat fryings 2.00 Mch. 9, Sale of meat fryings 2.00 Mch. 9, Sale of meat fryings Mch. 9. Sale of meat fryings Mch. 11. Sale of meat fryings Mch. 11. Sale of meat fryings Mch. 13, Sale of hide Mch. 13, Sale of hide Mch. 14, Surplus pay roll Feb. 3.12 Mch. 14, Surplus pay roll Feb. 3.12 rch. 14, Warrant for labor performed by home car - penter acct. new com. 10.50 Mch. 14. Warrant for labor performed by home car - penter acct. new com. 10.50 rch. 14. Warrant for cash pd. acct. new commis - sary bldg. 24.r&gt;8 Mch. 14. Warrant for cash pd. acct. new commis - sary bldy. 24.r&gt;8 Mch. 15, Sale of tea lead .56 Mch. 15, Sale of tea lead .56 Mch. 1"). Sale of meat fryings 2.35 Mch. 1"). Sale of meat fryings Mch. 90, Sale of meat fryings 3.60 Mch. 24. Sale of alfalfa 2.30 .Mch. 25, Sale of 1 old horse "Bill" 15.00 Mch. 28, Aiisoii Carey, deceased 10.46 Mch. 2&lt;t, Meat frying! .10 Mch. 30, Meat frying 2.15 Mch. 31. Meat fryings .90 Apr. 4. Meat fryings .30 Apr. 5. Sale of hide 4.97 Apr. 5. Sale of 2 ok) cows 60.00 Apr. 5, Sale of 2 eowi 93.19 Apr 6. 51 fat hogs 567.40 Apr. 6, 6 crippled hogs 39.60 Apr. 6, Mrs. Grabach, deceased 70.85 Apr. 8, 8 bbl. lime 12.00 Apr. 10, To correct error frt. bill .18 Apr. 12, Sale of rags 4.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">328 2.00 Apr. 12, Old crates 36.00 Apr. 13, J. P. Sackrison, as agreed Apr. 14. (' A Perkins, as agreed Apr. 17, Meat fryings 2.30 185.00 Apr. 21, 5 cows Apr. 28, Sale of hide 3.65 May 1, Effects of L. Warren, deceased May 5, Sale of lard 42.40 May 13, Sale of lard 3.29 May 8, Surplus Apr. pay roll May 17, Sale of hide 17.4* l\7:&gt; May 22, Sale of meat fryings May 22, Effects of L. Warren, deceased May 23, Effects of D. W. David, deceased June 6, Home store 2.00 15.00 Ene 7, Home store ne 8, Home store ne 9, Home 5.00 5.00 5.00 June 9, Sale of r. tallow June 10, Home store 2.70 :,.(io June 12. Home store 5.00 Jane 12. Sale of 1560 lt&gt; hay June 13. Home store :..(mi June 13. Sale of meat fryings June 13, Surplus May pay roll June 14. Home store 3.06 10.00 June 14, Home store 1.75 June 14. Sale of meat fryinjrs June 14. Sale of lard June 1"). Home store June 16, Home store Jane 16. Sale of lard tiune 17, Home store 5.00 7.00 21.36 5.00 2.1". Jane 17, Sale of meat fryinjrs Jane 17, Home store 10.00 7.86 June 19, Effects. David Dunkle, deceased June 19, Sale of meat fryings 30 June 19, Sale of lard June 20, Home store 24.06 June 20. Sale of r. tallow </seg>
            <seg id="p011">June 21, Home store 5.00 June 22, Home store June 23. Home store June 26, Home store HUMi June 2(&gt;. Ad.jt. Bowen for hat 1.25 June 27. Home June 30, Home sto'-e July 1, Home store 5.00 July 3, Home store July 6. Home store 15.00 July 8. Sale of meat fryinga July 8. W. L. Lindley for shoes 2.00 July 10. Surplus June pay roll July 10, Home store July 12, o. I). Rhodes, deceased .July 12, X. X. R agreed 36.00 July 12. J. If. Sackrison as agreed 36.00 July 13. Home I July 13. ('. A. Perkins as agreed July 15, Home stoiv July 17, Sale of r. tallow 1.30 July 18, Home store 15.00 July 19, Sale of old mattress L.65 July 20, Home store 20.00 July 2."",. Home store 20100 July 27. Home store July 29, L. Stanter. deceased July 31, Sale of meat frying! July 31, Error, bill of Donald &amp; Porter .86 July 31, Home store 30.00 Aug. 2. Home store 15.00 •*ii£. 3. Sale of r. tallow 1.00 Aug. 9, Sale of old mattr. -^ 1.00 Aug. 9. Surplus July pay roll 17.74 .Aug. 10, Sale of meat fryingrs 3.35 Aug. 11. Home store 55.00 Aupr. 17, Home store 40.00 ,\up. 19, Home store 25.00 Aug. 24. Effects of J. E. Kirkpatrick Aug. 25. Effects of Paytun Sheets, deceased </seg>
            <seg id="p012">330 Home stun- 25.00 Aug. 2(i. Ho«M store li &gt;.&lt;»&lt;) Aug. 29, (J. I Canning Co.. on acct. error 8.61 Aug. 31, Home store 1, Home store 5.00 2, Home store 5.00 • 4. H re 5JM) Home store 5.00 Home 5.00 11. Surplus Aug. pay roll 211.44 13, Home store 30.00 14. Home store 15.00 lti. Home store 15.00 le of tallow 1.40 21, Home store 20.00 23. Effects of C. \Y. Jorgensea 3.29 Home store 15.00 Home store 10.00 W. E. Round for lard 3.75 . Home store 10.00 S.pt. 27. Dow Fire Escape Co., for amt. pd. for 2.000 brick 14.00 27, Dow Fire Escape Co., for 8 sacks cement t. 27. Dow Fire Escape Co.. for unloading and haul- ng material .{.."/) Sept. 27. Home store 30.00 2. Sale of lard 3.37 4. Sale of male pig 10.00 5. Home store 15.00 Dow Fire Escape Co., for drayajre hs agreed 1.00 5. Effects of J. Peter Sackison :*6.00 7. Home store 20.ini 9, Sale of tea lead .80 9. Surplus Sept. pay roll 11, Home store 50.00 12. Sale of male pig 12.50 Oct. 12. N. X. Rice as agreement 36.00 A. Perkins as agreement 45.00 Oct. IS, Sale of lard 330 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">331 Oct. 17. Sale of male pig 15.00 20, Home store 33.00 Oet. 21, Home store 50.00 Oct. 23. Home store 5.00 Oct. 24. Sale of meat fryings 1.00 Oct. 24, Effects, F. L. Stanton. deceased 1.00 Oct. 24, Sale of lard 1.02 24, Home store 24, Home store 10.00 Oet 26, Sale of lard 3.38 &lt; 'it. 26. Mrs. Askwith for outing flannel .10 Oct. 26, Sale of hide 4.20 Oet 30, Sale of hid.- 4.00 31, Home store Nov. 1, Sale of lard Nov. 2. Home store 20.00 Nov. 2, II. S. Askwith for shoes .75 Nov. 3, Sale of lard Nov. 4. Effects of E. VanBuren 15.00 Nov. 4. Home store 15.00 Nov. 4, Effects of J. Finney 3.45 Nov. 9, Home store 25.00 Nov. 9. Surplus Oct. pay roll 4.60 Nov. 10, Home store 15.00 Nov. 11, Home store 10.00 Nov. 14. Home store 14.0(1 Not. 15, Effects of Mrs. A. Prime, deceased .57 Nov. 15, Home store 5.00 Nov. 16. Home store 8.00 Nov. 17, Home store 5.00 Nov. 18. Home store 9.00 Nov. 20, Home store 6.00 Nov. 22. Sale of r. tallow 2.00 Nov. 23. Sale of lard 6.50 Nov. 25. Home store 28.00 Nov. 25, Sale of lard 3.20 Dec. 1, Home store 25.00 Dec. 5, Home store 20.00 Dec. 7, Sale of r. tallow 1.65 Dec. 7, Home store 11. (Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p014">332 8, Wm. Anthony for medicine .50 Home stor. 10.00 Dec. 9, Sale of lard 2.10 12, .Meat fry ings 12. Surplus Nov. pay roll 12, D. A Anderton for medicine 12, Dan Kuwoldt for male pip 15.00 1L\ Hmne store 43.00 12. Sale of male pig 12, Home store 30.00 12. Home store 2(1.00 6.00 20, Home store V Smith, deceased ile of meat fryings __ 1.0(1 23. Ho): 25.00 Sale of lard 3.30 - M. Kimis for 1 month 14.00 26.00 28. Hume store 30, Home store 15.00 5. Effects of N. Kyllaberg 146.90 1906 .Ian. ."&gt;. Home store 20.00 6. Sale of lard 7.06 le of tallow 4.17 Jan. 6. Home store l."&gt;.oo 10. Sale of meat fryinps Surplus Dec. pay roll 10.87 10, Home store 30.00 11. II. Walker as agreement 40.00 Jan. 11. Home store 25.00 Jan. 12. N. X. Rice as agreed 36.00 - Howe as agreement 36.00 Jan. 12, Sale of drugs .2.-) Jan. 12, Effects of P. Kelly, deceased 13. Effects of G. K. Bullock, deceased 7.19 Jan. 13, C. A. Perkins as agreement 45.00 Jan. 13, Sale of lard 5.50 Jan. 13, Home store 35.00 Jan. 16. Home store 35 OH Jan. 18, Hoi </seg>
            <seg id="p015">333 »J Hi) . _ i '. oiilc oi j h rci Jan. 20, Sale of lard 6.50 Jan. 20. Home store Jan. 22. Effects of G. X. Booth, deceased Jan. 22, Home store 20.00 Jan. 24, Sale of rags 1.00 Jan. 24, Effi '. Parkhurst, de. Jan. 25, S. Howe as per agreement Jan. 25, Home store Jan. 27, Home store Jan. 27, Sale of lard Jan. 29, Home stun Jan. 30, Sale of r. tallow 2.00 Jan. 30, Sale of lard Jan. 31, Home store 15.00 Jan. 31, Sale of bran sacks Feb. 2, Home rtore 15.00 Feb. 3, Home store 10.00 Feb. "). Sale of lard Feb. -I. Sale old iron and rags Feb. 5, Sale of hides Sale of 1 hide 7.20 Feb. 5, Home rtore 10.00 5, Sale of effects of deceased meml»-&gt;-N 19.70 Feb. 6, Sale of effects of i members Feb. 6, Sale of effects of H mbera Feb. 7, Home store 10.00 Sale of lard Feb. 9. Sale of meat fr 2.40 Feb. 10, Home store ]2. Sale of meat frying! Feb. 12, Sale of meat frying! ].2f&gt; Feb. 12, Sale of meat flyings Feb. 12, Home store 15.00 Feb. 12, Sale of lard 17.33 Feb. 12, Sale of lard 3.75 Feb. 14, Sale of hide . 7.20 Feb. 15, Sale of meat fry ings 1.80 Feb. 16. Sale of old cow Feb 17, Home store 35 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">334 rl for 1 ireek hoard 3.50 If*. Home 81 : lard • 3.7.") 7.20 of \ Rice. d( 5.00 hide 6.30 : lard 3.75 ■ton lard 3.75 ■ 2.10 • Home 6.40 Home 1.87 10, Hum.- rtore le of lard 3.75 M.-h. 12. Sale of drugs 3.00 1153 I lar.1 12. Surplus pay roll 7.57 Amt. left by B. H. 1'erkins. Dane by P. L. Sayeni 1.67 of J. F. Kirkpatrick 5.50 Je of meat frying! 2.10 Home le of lard 28.43 M.li lard 11.40 Ifeh. 17. Home store 20.00 Mch 17. Sale of hide 6.40 lard le of hide le of r. tallow R. Bond 44.60 6.04 ■ Some ki </seg>
            <seg id="p017">335 Mch. -~i . \i. A. Anderton for mediciin- Blch l'&gt;. Home store .Mch. 30. Home rtore Mch. 31. Sale of hide Apr. 2. Home store Apr. 3, Sale of hide ami tallow Apr. 3, Sale of lard 3.75 Apr. 4. Home rtore 15.00 Apr. 7. Sale of hide Apr. 7. Home store 10.00 Apr. 9, Surplus Mch. pay roll 14.0:5 Apr. 9, Home stun- 15.00 Apr. ft. Sale of hide Apr. It. Sal .it fryings Apr. 10, Home 20.00 Apr. 10. Sale of meat trying* 1.00 ■ Apr. 10. \V. F. Fonts as per a I 12.00 Apr. 11. Ilouie store Apr. 12. Home - Apr. 13, Sale of hide Apr. 13, Sale of tallow 2.55 Apr. 13, S. Howe ;is per agreemeni 40..~&gt;n 13, Horn.- store Apr. 14. C. A. Perkins as agreement 45.00 Apr. 14. Hanson F&lt; greement 15.00 Apr. 14. Effects of 1 members 3.00 Apr. 16, Sale of meat frying Apr. lti. Home store Apr. 17. Sale of lard 11.32 Apr. 17. Sale oi 14.o'»i Apr. 1&lt;. Home store 10.00 Apr. 18, Sal' it frying! Apr 18, Effects of J. White Apr. l!i. Home store 15.00 Apr. 19, Sale of lard Apr 20, Home s Apr. 24. Sale of hide Apr. 24. Sale of bull Apr. L'"&gt;. lion Apr 26, N </seg>
            <seg id="p018">336 Ipr. 26, Home store pr. 26. Sale of hide pr. 28, Sale of hide pr. 28. Home store pr. 30, Sale of hide pr. 30, Home store ay 3, Sale of hide&gt; ay 3, Home store 10.00 6.75 3.95 20.00 6.40 10.00 10.38 20.00 Eay 5, Sale of hi. ay 8, Home stor ay 8, Home store 6.10 20.00 10.00 May 10, Sale of meat fryings 4:. May 11, Home Bi 25.00 Eay 12, Sale of meat fry ay 12, Sale of hide .85 6.30 12, Home store May 14, Sale of hide 20.00 5.67 Way 14, Dussell &amp; Son for dru 5.50 14, Surplus Apr. pay roll 3.83 May 14, Sale of hide 1.50 16, Sale of meat fryings .40 Pay 16. Home store ay 18, Sale of hide 30.00 7.20 !y 18, Sale of tallow y 18, Home store y 18, Sale of tallow y 21, Home store y 22, Sale of hide y 22, Home store y 24, Sale of h y 24, Home store y 25, Home store le 1, Home store le 1, Sale of hide 3.60 20.00 2.25 15.00 6.00 15.00 1.1.00 15.00 7.20 June 1. O. S. Kirschke for board June 1. Sale of meat fryings June 1. S. Howe as agreed June 1, Sale of scrap brass 27.05 1.00 16.10 3.50 June 1, Sale of hide 6.60 1. Home store </seg>
            <seg id="p019">June 1, Sale oj 4. Sale of hide 6.80 Jane 4. Sale of r. tallow June 5. Home Jon, ..plus Mj roll 3.00 30.00 June 9, Borne store 25.00 June 12, Sale of r. tallow 12, Home store 10.00 June 14. Home store Jane 15. B. II. Church as agreed 40.00 r Ralph If. I'iper foi his own use as member of the home 4."&gt;0.00 lti. Home store 10.00 June 19. Home store 15.00 June 21, Home store 15.00 Jont Mut .85 June 23, II' v 10.00 June 26, Home store 10.00 : . deceased 157.00 June 30, Home store 30.00 Juh \ Bar] 6.00 July 3, Home store 10.00 July 6, Effects R. 1.00 July 7. Home store 30.00 July 9. Sale of meat fryings 2.35 July 10, Home store 20.00 July 10, Sale of meat fryings July 10, Home store 25.00 July 11. Surplus June pay roll 2.50 July 12, B. F. Riley as agreed 6.00 July 12, Home store 45.00 July 14, Home store 30.00 July 14, C. A. Perkins as agreed 45.00 July 16, R. R. Piper, to apply on cottage for self 50.00 July 16, Home store 15.00 July 17, Sale of meat fryings .85 July 18, Home store 20.D0 Julv 24, Home store 30 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">338 July 26, Home More 15.00 Ju). 15 July ! r. tallow - W K 17.50 ■ 15.00 July 31, !!■■ 10.00 15.00 10.64 roll Aug. 10, at trying! - Hume - I-).!'11 11. H&lt;&gt;: B. &lt;'arr as Aug. 13. -' fans le of hide and r. tallow 14. Sa; 3 1- 14. Hi 10.00 17. II 15.00 21, Hi B of lard Home Home 5.00 Home .50 - R. R. I ige 7.15 v Home 29, Sale of meat frying! Aug. 29, Home store 10.00 Aug. 30, Sale of meat fryings .98 Aug. 31, Sale of meat fryings .98 1. Sale of 1330 lt» hogs at 5c 66.50 1. Sale of 270 tt&gt; crippled stag 5.40 1. Home store 15.00 Sept. 3, Sale of lard 3.10 3, Home store 10.00 5, Home store 10.00 Sept. 6, Sale of r. tallow 2.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">M jl '1 f"-i i- 339 i.ll' ie nA 1 II .!_ Kt. 8. Surplus Augusi pay rolj 11. II. 1.60 13, Home stow KB H. Church 17. Sale of lard C\ - £\ lard Sept 1". Home Kle of meat byii 19, Home Kt :21 Am. Toba« r r. tallow 1-70 I lard Home - n t\,-\ 27, Hoi 1 . t 29, Am. Tob. Co. on aceomri I, Home 2, Home store 4. Sale of meat frying! ;: Sale of meat frying! 8, Sale of lard 13.68 Sale of meat frying! 100 Sale &lt;&gt;f lard !)0 ° 10, W. P. Foui reed 21.00 10, Surplus September pay roll 10, Home store 11, Home store 550 ° 11, J. True on account sale of cow 18.00 12. C. A. Perkins as agreed 12. B. T. Riley as agreed 6.00 Pet. 12. Sale of 148 lb lard 1332 12, Sale of 47 lb lard 4.23 Oct. 12, Donald &amp; Porter Co.. overcharge 1.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">340 W. E. \ 13. Home store tuieider as ;._ W. H. Lindsev for 1 male pig 16, It. lard Sale of 50 Hi lard 4.50 17. It. lard 4.50 Effects of Ira Brown, dece; 30.00 Sale of meat fr. old trunk 1.00 fryings •r, deceased \in. Tobi 'iint Hum.- 1.00 Hon 20.00 Sale of meat fr 1.54 I \Y. Eva: 32.21 Effec L. Battles, deceased It) lard 36.00 Sale 150 tt&gt; lard 13.50 Sale of r. tallow 2.00 Home store 30.00 Home store 25.00 26. Hilda J. Young. 3.65 A. A. Eastman as agreed 6.00 L. W. Chopin as agreed 5.00 male pig B. ML Gilbert 15.00 29, F. Erntmeyer for male pig 15.00 Sale 50 lb lard 4.50 30, Home store 25.00 31, Sale of meat fryings .50 31. Sale of meat fryings 1.20 2, Sale of meat fr 1.05 Nov. 2, Home store 30.(10 Nov. 3, Home store 15.00 3, Effects of W. T. BiUiter 9.40 3, Sale of lard 3, Sale of lard 4.50 .20 r. 5, Sale of meat frying* 1.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">I ' N IJ 7, Sale of lard 9.00 Nov. 8, Home store 15.00 9, Sale of lard 4.50 9, Sale of meat frying! 10, Surplus Oct. pay roll 10, Home store 15.00 12. Sale of hi-l. 12, Sale of r. tallow 3.70 13, Home store I 15, Sale of hid.- 15 Home store !!». Sale of meat fryings 19, Home store 30.00 le of r. tallow 9.60 21, Ho 15.00 C. Wills for tel.charges 22, Fred Dyer for 19 2 Home 24. Sale of raga 2.00 -1 .[. Himn for condemned mattreM I meat frying* 1.40 . Home store 15.00 Home $12.!)47.4»; The following June ami November. 19 amount of d&lt; vouchers returned to us by the state audi- tor to be paid out of the cash fund. DISBURSEMENTS. 1904. •Tune 1. IT. P. Lawrey. spinach and sweet potatoes $ 2.7-~&gt; June 1. G. R. Guenther, sharpening two mowers 1.75 . I une L R. Portable Oven Co., for thermometer June 2. Louis Pollock, egtrs and butter June 7. Edith Burgess, onions June 7, E. J. Graves, lump jaw cure June 11, J. Guendell, polish 14. H Schuff, for potatoes 11.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">342 14, J. R. 1 3.50 June 17. M. D. (iraver, strawberri&lt;-- 9.50 June 17. M. D. strawberries 3.90 June 18. B. &amp; M. R. R. frt. on Billings, laundry work Jim. ah Siniih. I'D &lt;iays laundry work 16.00 1, G. I. 1. pty barrel P. R. R.. frt. (»n pat-kin- lis Veit. 3 lard cans and bbl. : G. I. 1. empty barrel ndell. empty liarrel ■ r. empty barrel _ Louis Veit, empty barrel '. G. I. L A mpty barrel T. Gilbert, turnips 5.75 8, B. &amp; If. R. R Co., frt. on pulp 2 cars 8, B. &amp; If. R. R. Co., frt. on pipe 21. .In: ndell, 2 empty bUa. 1.50 21. \V. A. Bobtw, empty bbl. 21, G. I. I. empty bbl. 21. Julius (Tiieixlell. brandy and port wine for mince meat 1.50 1, Eli A. Barnes, notarial work 3.00 1. Frank Doty, labor 5.00 1. J. Hilleke. labor 7.00 - dernian Co.. burial acct 3.00 F. Terwilliger, labor 10.75 7. B. &amp; M. R. R.. demurrage 15.00 1!». Hart Gun Co., turning rod .40 G. I. Plumbing Co.. material 2.15 J. EL Postal, iriiiiire glasses L75 14. J. J. Taylor, labor 1.00 14. Michael Conoff. labor 1.00 1"). Jno. H. Wright, labor 6.00 16, Frank Doty, labor 16. Frank Doty, labor 4.00 21. Col. Askwith. expenses Lincoln state business 6.40 Villis, labor 12.25 21. C. F. Terwilliger, labor 5.50 21. Wm. Gabriel labor 3 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">343 — . a . . * . au j Dec. 21, Sarah Smith, laundry work I &gt;.'c 21. A. R. Wolcott, labor 1905 Jan. 1, P. Sorensen, hauling head stones 3.00 Jan. 1, Sarah E. Randall, stamps sent Arbuckles Bros., premium spoons Jan. 3, Dr. Garfield. veterinary service 5.00 •Jan. 7. C. F. Terwillii; 10.50 Jan. 9. I. Smith, labor 17.00 Jan. 9, J. H. Wright, labor 6.00 Jan. 10, M. G. Priest, cleaning LOO •Ian. 10, Thos. Hoot, janitor service 10.00 Jan. 16. Sarah Smith, laundry work 13.50 Jan. 16, M. G. Priest, repair ga LOO Jan. 17. C. B. &amp; Q. R. R.. frt. on coal 12.80 Jan. 17. Win. Davis, labor on iee 4.05 Jan. 17, Fred Davis, labor on ice 4.50 Jan. 17. W. Nelson, labor on ice 2.70 Jan. 17. L W. Grant, labor on iee Jan. 17, Leroy Arthalony. labor on ice .75 Jan. 17, Steph. Lowell, labor on ice 6.01) Jan. 17, J. W. Eby. labor on iee Jan. 18. Win. Schroder, labor on i&lt;-.- 6.60 Jan. 18, A. Oraps. labor on iee 6.60 Jan. 18. F. Schroder, labor on ice Jan. IS. J. J. Dwyer, labor on ice Jan. 10. J. J. Taylor, labor on ice 6.60 Jan. 20, Win. Roller, labor on ice Jan. 20. T. Fallenberg. labor on ice 3.00 Jan. 23. Lederman Bros., material 3.72 Jan. 23. W. H. Harrison, bldg. material 42.15 Jan. 23, W. H. Harrison, bldg. material 164.00 Jan. 24. G. I. L. &amp; C Co., empty bbl. 75 Jan. 24. G. H. Eager, threshing oat&lt; 8.00 Jan. 24. Mrs. J. A. Gabriel, laundry work 4.7"» Jan. 25. G. G. Vreeland. exp. for meals for men haul - ing saw-dust •I a »I fir^Hnpt fcMni t h Ifliindrv work 1 (H) •Is n C 1 ho (r T-iinbr Co Huilflincr nifltorifll n^ </seg>
            <seg id="p026">344 t lan. abor on iee l.oU Jan ■' on ice 150 Jan. 26. Rnbert Lietch. labor on ioe 1. Wni. Koller. labor on ice 1. J. J. Taylor, labor 1, «J. J. Dwyer, labor LA Waddick, labor 1, A. ■ '«• 1. Jno. Grabach. labor on it-t 1. Bert Bishop, la uibor on iee 2.7" 1. A. Waddick. labor on iee 1. A "-"I' Feb. 1, Wm Gabriel, labor on iee 1.50 1.13 1. J. .T Dwyer, labor hauling coal 10.12 1. ifidlM i. unloading coal 1. Mi( 1. J. J. Tayl. 1.50 1. J. J. Tay]. 1.50 reb. 1. 1' eb. 1. C. B. &amp; Q R R . frt. on indse 1. I'. - . drayage :rt. on mdse R. R . denmrr; R. R .. ilfiiiurr, 1, J. E. K ik ami &lt;-haii laundry work p eh. 2. El]' laundry work ! W. Thomas, for m bu. 10 T. E. Hibbi busiir m 27.7" Mrs .1 A Gabriel, laundry work Feb R. H. demurragre 7 pars pty bhls 1.50 13. Ell' laundrj- work •1 M ■ laundry work 5.00 Villis. la 1 r hSQ 16. Th&lt; janitor 17. Jno H. Wriirht. labor fi.00 17. P. - W jj [ ,.j a | </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SOLDI KI wS -raith. labor 11.00 K. Terwilliger, labor 11.50 Feb. 21, Mrs II s. Norton, laundry work Feb. 21, W. H. Harrison, bldg. material 21, Kvaline Noble, laundry work K.-ii. 21, Mrs .1. A. Gabriel, laundry work rch. 1, J. 6. Briniger. 5 fa horn p( 4'. Mch. 1. C. P. K 1. .31 Mch. 1, Michael Connof, la or Mch. 1, Jno. Fisher, labor Mch P. R \l.. frt. on pipe 4.03 tch. *&gt;. (Hi. Askwith. expensea to Lin busi: Meh. b. J. ( I M«-h Meh. 7. C P. Terwilliger, labor 11.50 Mch. 7 h. labor Mch. 7. I". P. R. B 5.46 Mch. 11. J. W. Kb. planter 1.75 Mch. 14. J. M. Totten, laundry work Mch. 14. Mrs. Moore, laundry work Mch. 14. Th . janitor service 15. .(. II. Wright, labor Mch. !•"&gt;. C. P.. i Q. R. R., frt. on mdse Mch. lti. Lerennan Mch. Ki. R. II. McAUis Mch E. Lykke. wagon boa I. Pint' rch. L'n. Col. Askwith A'ljt Lin - 12.~&gt; l * Mch. 21, &lt;\ P. Terwilliger. labor Mch. 21. Bert Wingi crial r.-h. 22. J. W. Bowen. Adjt. H B. far .,ln business Mch P. K. I: rror tch. 13. G. W. Avery, labor pr. 4, C. P. Terwil pr. 8. Win Ha1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">346 J. .M. Totten. extra laundry work 5.00 Apr. 12, Thus. Boot, janitor service 5.00 Apr. 12. Stella Klinge. labor L29 J. H. Wrigkt, labor 6.00 .\pr. 17. E. H. Baker, :? load* sand l.'.d Apr. 18, Isaac Smith, labor 31.00 Apr 21. Gt Apr. 21. &lt;;.-,, 1; 5.40 ikwith, exp. Lincoln. State bus; .May 8. J. H. Moroney, janitor work 5.00 Mav 9, J. H Wrijrht. labor 6.00 C. Willis, labor 14J0 Willis, labor 3.50 F. Terwilliger, labor 27.50 nan A: Co., furniture 94.75 I*. R. I; re &lt;»n dniL's .15 Lmbr. Co., building material 190.51 Lmbr. Co.. building material !&gt;4.41 .May 26, H. S. Askwith. service boat painter 20.00 .^la.v lard can* June 1. Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae H 8 95.56 2 Donald &amp; Porter Co.. for ndae II. 8. June 2. Dnlan Fruit Co., for mdse. II. S 10.25 3, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdae. II s. .").10 n Buriress fur 4 boxes strawberries 24 June !». Donald &amp;. Porter Co., for mdse. H. S. 10.40 June Id. Donald &amp; Potter Co.. for mdse. II S 3.40 June 12. Dolan Fruit Co., for mdse. H. S. 21.60 June 12. D'.'.an Fruit &lt; 10.77 12. Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse H s 6.85 June 13. E. A. Edv r berries 1.75 1.7.". June 13. John Moroney for extra work janitor 5.00 14. Dolan Fruit Co.. for mdse. H. S 4.25 June 14, E. A. Edwards for 2 crates berries 3.50 June 14. S. Edwards for 48 boxes berries 3.00 June 16. J. H. Wripht for labor 6.00 17. Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdse 9.80 June 20. Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdse. 2.25 Dolan Fruit Co.. for mlac 4")&lt;i June 26. Donald &amp; Porter Co.. for mdae </seg>
            <seg id="p029">June 28, Dolan Fni June 30, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae. 11 9 July 3, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdae. H. 8. July 3, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdi 15.17 July 3, Dolan Fruit Co., for nnl.se H. 8 July 5, Dolau Fruit Co., for mdse. H. - 5.10 July 5, Donald &amp; Porter Co., fur mdae. II. S. July 7, Donald &amp; Porter Co, for nidse. H. S. July 7, Dolan Fruit Co., for indse. H. 8. July 8, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae July 10, Dolan Fruit Co., for i July 10, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdae 41). 18 July 10, J. Moroney. for janitor work July 10, E. Weinier. for waiting table July 11, J. II. Wrighi for work in commissary July 11, Dolan Fruit Co., for radae ) 17.J"&gt; July 11, H. B. Groff for show etm H S 4.00 July 12, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae. 4.50 July 11, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdsc July 11, Louis Schmidt for 1500 bricks 11.35 July 12, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdae. July 13, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdafl July 14. X. C. Foy, nijrr.. home store July 14, X. ('. Foy for ledger, counter book . i uly 14, Lederinan Bros., for candy tray^ July 14. Dolan Fruit Co., for ind.se. II S 1.00 July 14. Donald &amp; Porter Co.. for bkbm 8.60 July 17. Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdse. July 1."). Dolan Fruit Co., for i July 17, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdae July li). Donald &amp; Porter Co.. for mdae. July ID, Dolan Fruit Co.. for indse II. S 10.90 July IS. Dolan Fruit Co., indse. H. - July 25, Dolan Fruit Co.. for nidse. H. S. July 25, Dolan Fruit Co., for indse. H. S. July 28, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. H. 9 July 28, Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdse. H. S. July 29. Nebr. Merc. Co.. for n 3.60 July 31, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdae. II 8 13.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">348 Aug. 1. C P. Birk for harness 28.75 1. Waltei toed sable rent . for mdse. 16.10 1. Dolan Fruit Co., lor nidse. H S 3.40 J. \V. Bowen for i .75 Ian Fn- 1.45 12.60 15.95 Aug. 7. Donald &amp; Pot . Dolan Frail Co., for mdv 7, Dolan Fru for mdaa. : &amp; 1W 4.&lt;i."&gt; 22.25 1U. Donald i: Porter I 22.25 in Moroney for lab": 5.00 in Moroncy f&lt;-r Labot 5.00 •in H. Wright for labor 5.00 ha H. Wright for labor 5.00 * Ian Fruit ('&gt;&gt;.. for mdv 11.85 15.00 for mds.- l(i.24 ior mds.- in 24 uald A Porter Co., for nidsc 1.75 uald t Porter Co., for radse. 1 T."&gt; Donal.l A: I •!.(•() Donald A ! 3.00 Aup .in Fruit &lt; 1.50 ug .in Fruit ( 1.50 17. Donald &amp; l'or for mdae 11.75 17. Donald &amp; Por for mdac 11.75 Ian Fruit Co.. for n Ian Fruit Co., for n an Fruit Co., for n an Fruit Co., for n Porter Co., for mdae. Porter Co.. for mdae. 2 Dolan Fruit Co.. for ndae. 2^0 2 Dolaa Fruit Co M for ndae. 2.50 Dolan Fruit Co.. for mdv 12.65 an Fruit &lt; 12.65 Donald i: Porter Co., for mdae. 7.13 Donald i: for mdae. 7.13 I. Fruit Co., for mdae. 1.80 I. Fruit Co.. for BMfae. 1.80 11, 'Mji 11 hews for .80 11, 'Mall hews for .80 Dolan Fruit Co., for :5.7&lt;i Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae 20.70 30, Dolan Fruit Co., for mdafl 6.50 31, Home store for fruii if.7' &gt; 31, Donald A Porter Co., for in. Is.- 12.15 31. Donald &amp; Pon for mdse. ■ Ian Fruit Co., for mdse 12.12 1. H 3.30 Dolan Fruit I M 11.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">349 I. Edward Weimer for labor Donald &amp; IW for mdae. 8, Donald ft Porter Co., for n Ini Moroney for labor 12. John II. Wright for labor 12. Edward Weimer for labor Sept. 12 Dolan Pruil 12. Donald &amp; Porter Co., for mdae. 1.26 Srpt. 13, Home store, for fruit Sept. 17. Donald ft Porter Co., for n Sept. 18, Dolan Fruit Co.. for mdse 4.06 &gt;&lt;p\. 18, Dolan Fruit Co., for 2.70 19, K. Wilson, for 1-2 peek measure 19, Donald ft Porter Co., for mdae. 7.0() 21, Dolan Fruit Co.. 22, W. 11. Harrison for bldg. material 171. :&gt;0 Sept 22. Wolbach I for 3 p s 1.2."&gt; F. Terwilliger for :! days labor 3.00 I, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. • Dohui Fruit Co. for mils.-. 6.34 Sept 25, Frank Doty for labor 4.."&gt;0 Sepi 25, Odell Peterson for labor 4.50 S.-pt. 27. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 4.7^ 28. Dolan Fruit Co. for i 28, llollis .Johnson for 1 basket grapea Sept. 29, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 11.90 1 Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 17.57 30, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 2.50 Kept. 30, II. C. Foy for mdse. H. S. \ C. Foy as ni£rr. home store 15.00 6. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 1.10 Donald i Porter Co. for mdse. 28.53 6. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 3.40 6. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 13.21 7. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 9, Fred Marti for mdse. 5.00 9. G. Ditzel for labor 2.33 Oct. 10, H. J. Wright for labor 5.00 10. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 39.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">350 12, Donald A: Fort* 1.41 1.60 ■ 16. John Moroney for ;aboi 1.17 17. Frank Doty for lal Donald «.v I 51 ling for labor 1"&gt;" 11.5(1 r labor Smith for labor 3.50 .1 J. Binin for lal^ 4.00 nof for labor 4.00 fl 24. Bank 'lall for f;i DBgtOD widow 1.16 L'4. Dolan 1 42.00 Donald dc Ton redit S. \ C Poj for for home store .75 Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 1.48 Dolan Fniit To. for mds,- 7.70 Dolan Fruit Co. for m - 7.75 an Frui ; 1.00 1. N r. hoflM store 15.00 3. J. H. Hall for labor 12.00 3. Martins for nidse. home store 1.85 3. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdsr- Ian Fruit Co. for n 8, Dolan Fruit Co. for n 8.60 8, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. . 5.15 I ward Weimer for labor Ditzel for janitor work 5.00 10. John W. Wright for work commissary 5.00 10. Donald &amp; Porter for mdse. 11.70 10, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdst 8.25 13. L inidt for 20.000 brick 140.00 14. Fred Marti for labor 4.25 15. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 8.55 15. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 2.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">23, M. Connof for labor 11.im» Nov. 2:5. Udell I for Labor Nov. 25, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 10.12 Nov. 25, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 12.15 1. Odell I for labor ll.&lt;&gt;&lt;» IK for labor 4.00 I)..- 1. M Connof for labor C. Wills for labor K Terwilliger for labor 14. («) 1. J. J. Bunn for labor 1, J. J. Bunn for labor 7. \ (' Foy, mgr. b&lt; 15.00 ■ Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. Dolan Frail Dolan Fruit Co. for n Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S. !'.■(•. 9, Donald A Port H. S. Donald &amp; Port 1.77 9, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mete. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 10.11 Donald ft Port 11. Clam Pahl for labor 4.00 \V. Whitney for 10 days labor 1.67 11. Ed. Wt'iiiicr for extra work 5.00 Mtz.-l for 20 days labor P. Terwilliger for labor Dec. 12. J W. Wrierht for work eommii Dec. 12, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 15.18 Dec. 14. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 3.30 14. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. Dolan Fru r mdse. 20, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 5.00 Dec. 20. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 22. C. C. Wills for labor 12.50 per for labor 8.50 Dec. 21. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 4.50 Dec. 23. M. Connof for 2 days work 2.00 Dec. 25, Upperman &amp; Leiser for driving wagon 52.00 re. 25,Wm. Kelley for building material for home store and greenhouse 170.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">352 i'orter for I 17.!l&lt;&gt; Donald :er for nidse. 4.4O Donald &amp; Porter Co. for iikIm an Fruit Co. far Mdae. - H. J. Voss for Hi 1!' clip] 2.40 re 15.no ar cuttings Jan. 5, Dolan Fru for md.se Jan. 5, H. J Voss for 100 A. O. D. cigars Donald &amp; 1'orter Co. for mdse Donald &amp; Porter Co. for inds. 4.0."&gt; Dolan Fruit Co. for i 17. ."&gt;1 \V II ! r building material •Ian 98.35 .Ian 10. 'hal for labor 5.00 Jan. 10. E. Bunn for labor " 5.00 Jan. 10. Dolan Fru; Jan. 11. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. .60 Jan. 12. Donald &amp; Port for mdw 4.15 Jan. 12. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 6.45 fan. 13, i- material l!&gt;- ,lan 15, J. H Wright for labor 5.00 Dolan Fruit Co. for i Jan. 17. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 9.90 Jan. 17, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse 16.25 Jan. 18, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 2.00 Jan ut H. S. Jan. 18, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse 2.17 Jan Porter Co. for mdse. Jan. 20. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 4.35 Jan. 22. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 8.40 Jan. 22, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 1.85 Jan. 24. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 12.50 Jan. 24, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 3.14 Jan. 24, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 3.75 Jan. 24, G. I. Plumbing Co.. radiator spec. 68.00 Jan. 24, Lederman Bros, for brush .60 Jan. 25, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 1.75 Jan. 25, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. .55 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">353 Jan. 27, Dolau Frail r mdse. Jan. 27, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. Jan. 29, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. Jan. 29, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for m.lse Feb. 1, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdae. 2.90 Feb. 1, Dolan Fruit Co. tor m.lse. Feb. 5, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 9.00 Feb. 7. Douald &amp; Porte. Co. for in - Feb. 7, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 16.45 Feb. 8, Donald &amp; Porter Co for mdse. Feb. 10, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse Feb. 12, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 1.75 Feb. 13. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse Feb. 13, Dolan Fruit Co. for n " 6.50 Feb. 14, Martins for combs, home 1.00 Feb. 14, E. Bunn for labor 2.50 Feb. 14, Clans Phal for labor Feb. 15, Adrian Gillet forj. mo. serv. mgr. home store Feb. 15, J. W. Wright for labor 5.00 Feb. 16, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 24.7o Feb. 17, E. Corbin for mdse. Feb. 17, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 10.50 Feb. 19, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 1.60 Feb. 20, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 10.75 Feb. 20, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. Feb. 28, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 3.00 1 eb. 28, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 2.00 Mch. 1, N. C. Foy mpr. 1-2 mo. home store 7.50 Mch. 2, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 15.41 Mch. ■"), Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 3.00 Mch. 7. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 14.21 Mch. 7. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 11.35 Mch. 7. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 1.25 Mch. 9, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 1.50 Mch. 12. W. H. Warner for labor 2.00 Mch 12, Claus Pahl for labor 5.00 Meh. 13, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 24.50 Mch. 13, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 15.00 Mch. 13, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 3.25 Mch. 16, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p036">354 19, Donald A: Porter &lt; o. tor i Is 6.15 Meh. 20, Dolan Fruit Co. for mds. 12.80 Mch. 1'2. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 4.7") Meh. 23, B. &amp; M. K. R. for 3 days demurrage Mch. 24. Dolau Fruit Co. for mds. 5.50 Mch. 27. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. 10.75 Meh Ian Fruit Co. for mdse. 4.75 Mch. 2!». Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse Mch. 31, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 27.55 Mch. 31, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 8.30 Apr. 1, N ('. Foy mgr. home store 15.00 Apr. 3, Dolan Fruit Co. for mds. 10.83 Apr. 3. Donald A: Porter Co. for m 19.61 Apr. 6, Donal.l A; Porter Co. for inds. 18.70 Apr. 7. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. 8.63 Apr. 7. H. J. Yoss foi 4.00 Apr. 9, \Y. U. \Yarner for labor 2.50 Apr. 9, Claus Phal for labor 1.33 r labor 5.00 J. AY. Wrighi for labor 5.00 ■laid &amp; Porter Co. for nids.- 16.25 Apr 11. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse Apr. 16. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse Ian Fruit Co. for m&lt; N.- Apr. 16, R. H. McAllister for pocket knives 1.95 Apr. 17. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdw. Apr an Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S 6.60 Apr 18. Geo. Boh for cigar clippings 2.70 Apr. 21. R. H McAllister, mdse. home store 5.85 Apr. 21, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. H. S 19.92 Apr 21, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse H. S. 3.91 Apr. 24. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. 8 9.00 Apr. 24, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse H B 23.50 Apr. 26, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S 4.50 Apr. 30, N. C. Foy for mdse. home store 1.43 May 2, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S. 3.62 May 3, Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse. home store 41.10 May 4, Paul Fraun for 2 cows and 1 calf 303.80 May 5. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. B 15.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">' 9 \ A \J 1 ■ J \ \ i^' \ 1 i ' \ I A t I h I I /ill,, I I I k \ 1 I / 1 |j \ I J I . May 8, Donald &amp;, Pori 4.40 May 9, Dolan Fruit Co. for May 10, N. p. home store May 11, Dolan Fruit Co. for nulse. II. S. May 11, Dolan Fruit Co. lor md* May 12, Donald &amp; Por - 30.02 May 14, Dolan Frui B - 5.00 May 15. 151.21 May 15, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdae. H. 8 16, J. W. Wright for labor May 17, Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse hoi: 17. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdae. II. S. 17, Donald &amp; I :{.4O May 19. Donald &amp; Port May 1!&gt;. Dolan Frail II S May 111. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdae. II. 8 4.00 21, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. II. s 4.00 May 22, J. W. Bowen for :; match safes II &gt; Dolan Fruit Co. for nnlsr B. 8. May 23, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S 6.00 May 23, C. H. Tullj «r hill May 24. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. B June 1, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. II S. June 1. M. D. Graver for bern&gt;- 8.10 June 1. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse II S 10.25 June 1. Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse H 8 1.60 June 1, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S 6.1"&gt; 1. O. Kirschke as per bill June 1. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. S. 2.50 June 2. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. H. 9 11.50 June 2. Donald Porter Co. for mdse. H. S. 19.60 June 4. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse 2.50 June ."&gt;. X. C Foy. m?r. home stor. 15.00 June 6. Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. H. - 2.00 June 7. Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. H. 9 2.25 June 9. Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse. home store 13.55 June 9. Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store 3.25 June 9, Voss for cigars home store 3.30 June 11, J. H. Wright for work in commissary 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">356 «J une IX, Dolan r ni. June 13, Dolan Fruit Co. nidse. home - i.7"&gt; June 15, Dolan Fru home store 14. 4&lt;&gt; June 15, Bee Hive i for l)ernes L' 1". June 15, Bee Hive I M 2.15 June 16, C. F. 1 i&gt;r building store roon June 16, C. F. 1 or building store room June 16, Donald &amp; Tor; 45.20 June 16, Donald &amp; Porter Co. nidse. h 45.20 June 16, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. hoi lu.L'4 June 16, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. hoi lu.L'4 June 19, Dolan Fruit &lt; 2.40 June 19, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. L J.4&lt;&gt; June 19, Bee Hive Grocery for berries l!.l.~&gt; June 19. Bee Hive Grocery for berries l'.l."&gt; June 21. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdae homi 1.7"&gt; June 21, Dolan Fru 1.7"&gt; June 22. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store June 22. Dolan Fruit Co. for nidse. hone store June 23, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store June 23, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store June 23, Douald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store June 23, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store June 26, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home - 4.1") June 26, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home - 4.1") une 26, W. S. Ask with. &lt;■ of draft une 29, Dolan Fruit ( home 4.00 une 30, \Y. S. Askwith. eomd'1 cxcliai -heck une 30, N. C. Foy. bu 15.00 uly 2, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store 2 ."&gt;() uly 3, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store !t .."&gt;0 June 26, W. S. Askwith. &lt;• rror on exekan| of draft June 29, Dolan Fruit ( home 4.00 June 30, W. S. Askwith. eomd'1 exeliai lieck June 30, N. C Foy. nu 15.00 July 5, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse hom« store 7.70 July 7. Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse. home store 2ti.4n July 8, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse home si 13.55 July 9, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. h&gt; 12.55 July 9, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse h re 1.50 July 10, Hayden Bros, for combs, home store .85 July 10, R. H. McAllister for knives home store 1.20 July 11, Dolan Fruit Co mdse. home store 12.75 July 11, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store July 12. Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store 5.30 July 14. I. H. Wricrht for work in commissary 5.00 July 14, Frank Doty for labor 10.00 July 14. Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse. home store 27.90 July 14, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 2.00 July 16. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store 2.00 July 16. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 5.00 July 18, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 15.12 July 19, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 6.90 July 21, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. ?? 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">July l'4, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home Jnly 25. Dolan Frail home store 1.70 To cover balance due on h" &gt;0.00 drawn on stock and implement fund with only a balance of $99.04 left in fund July 26, Dolan Fruit Co., mdae home store July 27, G. I. Fruit Co. for tomatOM July 27, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store July 27. Donald &amp; I'orter Co., mdse. home •tore 15.00 July 28, Dolan Fruit Co.,- mdae. home store July 28, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store July 30, Dolan Fruil rtore July 31, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 1, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 1. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 1.7."&gt; Aug. 2, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 3, X. C Foy. manager home store mo. July 15.00 Aug. 3. Frank Doty for labor 12.50 3, Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse. h&lt; 2.00 Aug. 4. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 6. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 6, E. Pepper for extra work, waiter 5.00 Aug. 7, Dolan Fruit Co., mdae. home store Aug. 7. Chffo. Lmbr. Co. for building J 74 Aug. 8. J. H. Wright for labor eondnr 5.00 Aug. B, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 1.40 9, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home st ■■•■• 2.20 Aug. 9. Bee Hive Grocery for apples hon Aug. 10, Donald &amp; Porter Co. mdse. home b1 4 40 Aug. 11, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store 1.30 Aug. 11. Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home store Aug. 14, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store Aug. 15, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 1.50 Aug. 16. Ed Baker for sand 5.00 17. Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home ston- 30.47 Aug. 22, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store Auer. 22. Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse. home store Aug. 22, Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home .A.iiS' 2 T)olflri n^niif* C^o m/i^p li'iTTif* storp -4- tl' ) </seg>
            <seg id="p040">358 Aug. 23, Dolan Fruit &lt; •■■ home sture 4.70 Aug. 23, A. W. Buchheit for drop .25 Aug. 23, Bee Hive Grocery for apples home store .45 Aug. 24, A. O. Debrick for labor new eottage 81.45 Aug. 24, Dolan Fruit Co., nulse. home .75 Aug. 24. Dolan Fru home store 1.60 Aug. 25, Donald &amp; Porter Co., nitlse home store Aug. 25. L. Schmidt for material 44.25 Aug. 25, H. r painting 9.00 .*ug. 28, Dolan Fruit Co., mdae. home store 8.70 Aug. 29, Dolan Fru home store 4.65 30, Donald &amp; Por lug shot 2.95 1, Donald &amp; Porter, mdse. home store •Ian Fru home store 2.65 . ■ i L r 15.00 3. K. II. .McAllister for hardware 17.75 3. Otto Kirschke for material 14.55 Ian Fri. rtore 8.80 Sept. 6, Dolan Fruit Co. for md.se. ho: M..'5O 8, Donald &amp; Port • 13.28 6. Dolan Fruit &lt; home 4.15 10. I. W. Wright for work in commissary 5.00 10. Dolan Fru 2.66 11. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 3.60 11. Bee H for apples home store .85 11. Hugh MeVay for grading Sept. 13. Dolan Fru .-.. 7 00 Dolan Fruit I ,. g.45 Dnlan Fri, J.JJO 17. Donald &amp; Port 5.20 17. Dolan Fruit C 2.00 •nald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home store pt. 18, Dolan Fruit Co. mdse. home store 14.75 nald &amp; Port home store 19. Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home 4.15 for mdse. home store 9.00 Sept. 21. Dolan Fru home stole :{.5O Sept. 21, Chgo. Lmbr. Co. for building material 603.15 21. Chgo. Lmbr. Co. for building material 38.75 &lt;4o 91 C R 1^ rv\ </seg>
            <seg id="p041">otjjl. ~«*, JL/UlaH r FUJI v^U l ( 'i llHl&gt;e. li'mi* Sept. 22, Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home store ■ for mdse. home store i, H. S. Askwith for labor painting 36.00 F. Terwilli&lt;rer for labor 241.00 24. Dolan Fruit Co., nidse. home store 1.10 24, Dolan Fruit Co. for \ .60 t. 25, Dolan Fruit Co.. rndse. home - 3.25 : 26, H. J. Voss for cigars home store MO 26, Alleman &amp; Starr for ledger 26, W. H. Harrison for material . 27, Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse. home stun- 10.60 28, Dolan Fruit &lt; 4.10 1, Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse. home store 2. N. C. Foy, manager home store mo. Sept 3, Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home Dolan Fruit Co., nidse. home store 5, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store 9, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store 9, Donald &amp; Porter Co.. nidse hoi 6.15 11. I. H. Wright for work in commissary 5.00 11. Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. home store 1.70 13, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 15. Dolan Fruil store 16.33 15, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store .90 16, M. Connof for 8 1-2 days labor 8.50 16, J. J. Bunn for labor 3.00 17. H. J. Crocket for labor 1.00 17. -I J. Bunn for labor 1.00 17. J. Lesehinsky for 100 postal cards 17, Donald k Porter Co. for mdse. home 81 18, Mrs. H. Murry for procuring ■ 18, P. Binkley for labor 2.00 19, Donald &amp; Porter ( o.. for mdse. home store ■r for apples home Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store \skwith. 10 days painting Martins, for combs home store 23. Alleman &amp; Starr fo 24 \f jvO^*sgi* to i* flitolcs Iiotiip st 01* a </seg>
            <seg id="p042">360 Dolan Fruit Co. for rudse. home store 8.50 Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 6.00 Dolan Frui: Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. hon 30. W. EL Harrison for material 31. Bee Hi ry for apples horn. 1. If. J. Henderson for bananas hon 1, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. hon Iov. 1. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store 17.50 X. C. Foy, manager home store ni 15.00 _'. X. C. Foy, manager home rtore i 15.00 iimidt f' 4n.(Mi - midt for 5.000 brick- 4&lt;umi . Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. lion r, Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. hoi 7. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. home store 7. Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdae. home store Nov. 10, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store ov 10, Dolan Fruit Co., mdse. home store 10, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse. ho ov. 10, Donald &amp; Porter Co. for mdse h 10. Bee Hive Grocery for apples homi ov. 10. Bee Hive Grocery for apples home store 10, Bee Hive Grocery for apples home store ■eery for appl&lt; - Ian Fruit Co. for mdse. home store _' 56 ■ Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store _' 56 16, K Bunn for labor in commissary ov 16. E. Bunn for labor in commissary J. H. Wright for laboi ssary 2.10 ov ltl. J H. Wright for labor o rj 2.10 16. Bee Hive Grocery for ap| &gt;re 3.00 ov. 16. Bee Hive Grocery for apples }ii&gt;inc sioro 3.00 nald &amp; Porter Co.. mdse. home store til. 4^ ov 17. Donald &amp; Porter Co., mdse. honi. til. 4^ ov. 17. Dolan Fruit Co.. mdse. home store 21. Donald &amp; Porter Co.. mdse. horn 21. Dolan Fruit Co. for mdse. home store 21.00 i, G. G. Vreeland for meals to farm haixN driving hoprs to town 1 .'&gt;" \Y II Harrison for material 40~&gt; Ian Fruit Co. for mdse. home store !o. for mdse. home stor. 14.05 26. N. C. Foy. manager home store for mdse. 40. M 1905 rpt. 15. To cover amount of error in voucher on steam plant fund July 26. 190"&gt; 8.61 Total . $10.!t: VOUCHERS IN HANDS OF STATE AIDITOR. UNADJUSTED he following fm Maintenance and elothing </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Employes' wa^es . 43.25 Library Total di 111,2 Bal;i ih on hand 1.61 Total $12.94 ESTIMATED VALUATION OF PROPERTY ON HAND NO\ , bead work hoi $ 7i Two driving hoi 15 Je driving hors.- 1 One old man nieklini One pony Thirty-fivi- cnws. rs. in feed I UK) 1,050.00 Sixty-seven milch eows @$30.00 2.010.00 Thirty-three 1 and 2 year old steers and b Thirty-one ipring ealves at $15.00 47.").(Mi Twenty-three rammer ealves 1- thorough breed ft One two-year-old heifer One yearling heifer Two bull ealves - 1.00 K yearling hull 100.00 r.ol.l bull 12 'thirteen brood sow- L'- boar hondred sh&lt; carria&lt;;ks and wagoxs. platform spring wagon One double top carriage sinjrle bnggy W.OO One carryall 25.00 One wagon One coal wagon Ono pfli r trii One set of bob sleigh </seg>
            <seg id="p044">362 One ;&gt;low $ 40.00 15.00 Three stirring plows 10.00 Two harrows 20.00 B*vo cultivators ae dis 15.00 One roller 10.00 One breaking plow One hay rack 5.00 5.00 100.00 150.00 (hie lawn m One horse mower One feed cooker One potato digger ■anon spreader HARNESS AND ROBES. Four sets double harness _ Cine set light harnes&gt; One b e harness $ 40.00 sets single harness (old Three pairs leather fly nets 6.00 4.00 One pair leather fly nets One single fly net 3.00 Twelve halt &gt; wolf r i new robes 3.00 4.00 30.00 5.00 Two horse blankets HAY STACKER. AND TOOLS $ 30.00 Two hay stackers hay rakes (old) 10.00 10.00 One hay rake Three mowers One hay sweep 45.00 25.00 Two stack covers Ten pitch forks 10.00 One hay knife 50 MISCELLANEOUS TOOLS. One potato scoop Two beet forks Two potato forks </seg>
            <seg id="p045">long handle shovels Three short handle shovels 'l\V(p spada LOO hole digger 1.00 ( nal scoops 1.00 Three picks .75 One ax -50 hammers 1.25 Four monkey wrenches 1.00 Four pr. pinchers 100 One rasp, hoof knife, iron maul crowbars, log chains, two sets pulleys and rope ICE TOOLS. ice saws, one marker, eight prs. tongs, four ice bars 14.00 t pike poles, one ice hand-saw, and one ax 3.00 Total fODUCTS RAISED ON HOME FARM FOR TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906. —1905— —1906— Beef, lbs 2.180 $ 124.78 lbs 24,300 $ 1,280.90 Pork, lbs. 15.265 1,240.32 lbs. 6,410 497.41 Milk, gals 26,074 3,1 - &gt;42 2,9! Alfalfa hay. tons 400 1,200.00 tons 450 2.250.00 Prairie hay. tons 35 175.00 tons Corn, bu. bu. 1,650 495.00 Sweet corn, bu. 120.00 Pie plant, bu 28 18.20 bu. Onions, bu _ 32% 24.19 bu. 16 Lettuce, bu. 10y 2 6.50 bu. 5.31 Asparagus, bu. .... 2.25 bu. 15 15.00 Radishes, bu. 10 7.50 bu. 17 12.75 Spinach, bu. 12 i Greens, bu. bu. Green beans, bu. 23 Vj; 11.75 bu. 37 18.50 Cabbages (early) doz. doz 40.50 Cab. (late) doz. 151 113.25 doz 2912-3 175.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">i COM MISS KKPORT 364 75 18.75 Turnips, bu 100 25.00 bu. Tom. (ripe) bu. 40% 30.38 bu 49y 2 37.13 Tom. (green) bu. bu. 86 34.40 Pickles, bbls. 4 60.00 rn. doz. 1,500 90.00 doz 951 57.06 305 183.00 Potatoes, bu 43 17.20 bu. VKUIV'VWJ M ers sold 676 169.00 200 10.00 8 .40 bu. 36 10.80 7.50 doz. 15 1,022.45 883.04 862.04 s &amp; heifers.. Fat hogs 507.68 6 cripld. hoi. 39.60 3 male pips Old hoi Old 37.50 15.00 3 12.00 Lard 219.29 37.70 Rough tallov Green hides 154.38 Total Total 9,62 Total value of prod &lt;l and used for the $19,275.27 two years Balance on hand N inn Produce 2,945.00 STATI'S OF MEMBERSHIP OF THE HOME FROM DECEMBER 1 19"4, TO NOVEMBER 10, 1* NTMBER OF MEMBERS DECEMBER 1. I&lt;tn4 Men 276 Women '•■2 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Women Total Total present and absent 4t&gt;4 Number admitted from Dec. 1, 1!)H4. to Nov. -10. 1905 Men Women Total 'vumlicr discharged from Dec. 1. 1904, to N l!Hir&gt; Men Women 14 Total Number of deaths from Dec 1. 1904, to Nov. 30, !!•&gt;■ Men Women Total regate loss 90 Net frain 19 M'MBER OF MEMBERS NOVEMBER 30, 1905 Women Total 381 Absent — Men 63 Women 39 Total ln2 Total present and absent Number admitted from Dee. 1. 1905, to Nov. 30, 1906: Men 87 Women </seg>
            <seg id="p048">366 Nuji. 41 14 1 1 i &gt;• &gt; Xui 1905, to \&lt;&gt;\ 30, !'""■ g ;il 24 -■aiii 24 NCMBKR OF MEMBERS NOVEMBE KBBR OF MEMHERS NOVKMBBH 30, 297 11!) 119 Total Total 41 ti 41 ti Men 27 27 Total tal 9] !H Total present and absent 507 .")( 17 rily average present from I). 1. 1904 to November : ■ i Daily average present fr naber 1. l!i(&gt;4 to November : ■ i rly average present and absent from December 1. 1 !»«&gt;4 Daily average present and absent from December 1. 1904 r 30, !!»""• 4»^ rily i &gt;^nt from December 1, 1905 to Novem - ber 30, 1906 Daily a' it from December 1, 1905 to Xovem - ber 30. :iti4 rily aver: M-nt and absent from December 1, l!»0f&gt; to November 30. 1906 Daily average present and absent from December 1. 1906 mber 30. 1906 -t of daily rations for year ending November 1905 1.1792 cost of clothing for men for one year ending No - vejnber 30. 1905 -S15.99 Avera of daily rations for year endinp November 30. 1905 $.1792 cost of clothing for men for one year ending No Average cost of clothing for women for year ending No </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Hpita tor year end 1!" rif daily rations for year ending \( ft' clothing for n em - ber 30. 1906 $15.29 -1 of clothing t'i&gt;r w iber 30, 1906 r capita loofi DEATHS — MEN \\MR. AOE. COMPANY &amp; REGIMENT. DATE :. Edmoivl if. 63 D. 102 Til. Inf. I L904 Cronk, Henry 7n B Tnf. Dee. 7. 1904 Crair ; 7 Ta. Tnf. Dec 10. 1904 •".4 TT. 7 Ohio Cav. Dee. 21, 1004 Northrop, James T. Sm1v.ii. James (alia 67 B. 40 N. Y. Inf Jan. 5, 1905 McKiiinev. Barney Bnrnell. Gilbert 62 12 T". S. Inf. Jan 26, 1905 Driscall, Charles 81 B. 211 Pa. Inf Feb. 3, 1905 Cook, Daniel 1). B5 C. Cass Co. Mo. Inf. Feb. 21, 1905 Walton. Andrew D. 66 H. 67 111. Inf Feb. 23, 1905 Junes. Ellis W. 76 E. 5 Mo. Inf. Mch. 10, 81 K. 6 Mich. Inf. Mch. 10. -fonl, William 76 C. 2 Ind. Inf. Apr. 17, Warren. Louis 7s K. 47 Mass. Inf. Apr. 24. Snelling, Elliott R 78 H. 17 Ind. Inf May 1, David. David W. 66 D. 51 111. Inf May 21, 1905 Dnnkle, David 72 H. 13 la. Inf June 10, Kirkpatrick. James E. 67 M. 10 111. Cav. June 13, 1905 Rhoades, Oliver D. 83 E. 2 111. Cav Juae 25, 1905 eer, David C 33 Mass. Inf. July 14, 1905 Stanter. Louis 76 B. 154 111. Inf July 16, 1905 Hughes, Joseph R. 65 F. 13 Ind. Inf July 19, 1905 Noble, Cherriek J. 61 E. 191 Pa. Inf Aug. 7, 1905 Burnett. Elliott R. 79 A. 29, Mich. Inf. Aug. 13, 1905 to, Peyton 55 E. 133 111. Inf Aug. 23, 1905 Jorgi hristian X. 67 G. 39 U. S. C Aug. 29, 1905 T^nir&gt;Wpr T miis f»^ I* 1 2^ Ta. Tnf nt 11 IQO^i </seg>
            <seg id="p050">368 til M. 8 111. Inf. Sept 16, 1905 71 B. 9 111. Inf. Sept. 27. 1905 Durkee. Miles F 71 B. Inf. ..Oct. 1« 1905 YanBnrc! Finney. Jan Billings, Abnnn •k. Jnli Tucker. Jairn-s I* Wolf, Qeorge \Y. Nils Bullock. Kelley, Patrick Booth. Qeorgi 1'arkhurst. .1 Nathaniel N C'runie, John Desmar, Henry E. Rich, Francis M Kirby. John X. .rt. 147 111. Inf. 1905 75 K. 78 N. Y. Inf. Oct. 27, 1905 L 12 la. Inf. .Nov. 30, 1905 71 B. 1 Wis. Cav. I 1905 74 E. 39 la. Inf Dec. 28, 1905 58 A. 8 la. Inf. Dec. 29, 1905 77 E. 44 IU. Inf. I 1905 68 110-2 Regt. Yet.R.C. Jan. 7. 1906 70 E. 90 111. Inf Jan. 9, 1906 75 D. 23 .Mass. Inf. Jan. 13, 1906 79 D. 91 111. Inf Jan. 24, 1906 77 N. Y. Int. Feb. 10, 1906 2 Neb. Cav. Feb. 26, 1906 67 M 6 N. Y. Cav. Men. 12, 1906 66 K. 120 111. Inf. Mch. 13. 1906 65 B. 118 111. Inf Mch. 16. 1906 IJ ( ihn ond. Richard andall, Alonzo ill, Edwin J. 'endlh. Frederick 'hite. Jar 64 K. 4.") HI. Inf. Mch. 18, 1906 67 B. 4."&gt; Wis. Inf. Mch. 20, 1906 77 E. 1 Mich. Art. Mch. 28, 1906 9 \. Y. Cav. Mch. 28, 1906 62 1. 139 111. Inf Mch. 29, 1906 75 B. 117 IU. Inf Mch. 30, 1906 Connelly, John I". S. N. Lds. Mch. 31, 1906 May 2, 1906 7:5 D. 86 N. Y. Inf. May 2."&gt;. 1906 Mullarkey. Jam yuiglt-y. William L. Fobs, Ransom 72 B. 34 IU. Vet. Inf. June 30, 1906 Fears, James 14 I. S. Q Inf. July 7. 1906 William H. r, George T. B. Wa Battles, Otis L. lers. Thorn: Brown. Oscar F 62 A. 156 111. Inf July 24. 1906 22 Ind. Inf Aug. 18, 1906 73 D. 104 111. Inf Sept. 8, 1906 73 F. 3 R. I. Cav. Oct. 8, 1906 66 G. 97 N. Y. hit 12, 1906 74 E. 1 Miss. M. B. Oct. 12. 1906 72 F. 194 N. Y. Vol. W. Inf Oct. 18, 1906 l'i' A i \ T &lt;iV-i f\j%+ Oft 1 0fW? </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DEATHS WOMEN. .NAME. m. \TE. iluss. i Henrietta B. Jan ■on, Martha J. Mch. 14 [nghram, .Margaret Mch. 18, 1 Grabaoh, Mai tin Mch. 31, 1 Um 65 May 14 Bel). Amanda M. Juh Elizabeth 75 Aug. utrick, Mary Aug. 1!». 1 Galligan, Virginia B. Mch. 4. 1 :iger, Eunice May 10, isan A. Ma; Olive 69 .June 20, 1 Randall, Sophia Auir. 4. 1 Mary E. 71 Aug. 20, 1906 r, Zela 67 Oct lilda J. 04 Oct. 14. nan, Sophia M. 74 Oct i deaths this biennium, men 65, wunien 17. I deaths last biennium, men 55, women 16 K owing increase in deaths, men 10, women 1 age, men 68. age, women 62. Respectfully submitted J. W. BO WEN. Adjutant. Col. W. S. Askwith, Commandant: Dear Sir : — Herewith I submit my report for the biennium end- ing November 30, 1 There has been since the report of November 30, 1904 deaths — 65 men and 17 women — 63 died at the home and 19 away on furlough; but 2 more deaths at the home this biennium than during the prior one, yet the total membership is 43 more now than two years ago. With each passing year all are be&lt; fijnjg more and more enfeebled. The addition to the west hospital was not completed until the 2nth of March, the present year. At that date we commenced tising it, although before its acceptance from the contractor by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, because of the extreme '-* </seg>
            <seg id="p052">370 of the b I will say that the work - -hiji in that part of tin- building is the beat in the brick &gt;ital. Tl help, relieving the _■ that tl us room f" 1 b. Twen - ihiin are n&lt; During tl. n there have &gt;-k ;iiul invalid members admitted, who had to Jl the available :s taken, ;ll sicken from among the more healthy meml I Another add liould be immediately built to m &lt;&gt;rdf i the ameagem the veterans and their wives. IB for 1 -adly needed and a larger dining MB also. With the other addition this must come, for with greater number of patiei required, and oni for their accommodation. The roof over the dining d kit' raised I :ories and the room acquired t up int" lor help, then the rooms now occupied then i and family as formerly plan - d. but long si n up to old ladies and the help. An appropriation should be made for building porches the whole length of the south front of the ■ ;&gt;ital. It would shade from the heat of the summer sun the south rooms, making rhem much more comfortable for the sick. The convalescents and feeble could gather on them and take out door air and ex - ercise a great portion of the time in pleasant weather. The present small porch in hot and pleasant weather is nearly al - ways crowded. In the autumn of 1903. by order of the state architect all the toilets were changed to automatic flushing bowls. They have all proven very unsatisfactory, failing to work, keeping the hos - pital in an unsanitary condition — the absent minded and feeble unable or Hush each time with a bucket water. I recommend their removal, to be replaced with "full" flushing toilets and porcelain lined iron tanks. There will be needed for drugs and instruments for the next Hennium a $3,000 appropriation. K Thanking yon for jroor cordial support, id hoping that the | in their wisdom </seg>
            <seg id="p053">SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, GRAND ISLAND 371 Id magnanimity by their generosity and gratitude toward the ed veterans and their helpmates of lang syne, may, as you and and all do, who are associated in caring for the "old soldiers," I the exigencies above outlined and by a liberal appropriation ovide for these n&lt; s, I am Very truly yours, H. L. RANDALL, Surgeon. Burkett, Nebr., November 30, 1906. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>