<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD SEPTEMBER 1, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE 8TATE BANKING BOARD SEPTEMBER 1, 1916 1916 ■• By E. ROYSE, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">DEPARTMENT OF BANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD HON. JOHN H. MOREHEAD Governor, President HON. W. H. SMITH Auditor of Public Accounts HON. WILLIS E. REED...- Attorney General E. ROYSE." _.._ _ - _ - Secretary JOSEPH V. JOHNSON Clerk MAUDE HOGE - - Assistant Clerk ANNA GASS __ Assistant Clerk TILLIE C. EPPENS Stenographer EXAMINERS S. M. PATTERSON M. C. WILDE E. E. EMMETT S. A. LAPP E. N. VAN HORNE T. R. RILEY A. D. TOUZALIN JOHN BOATSMAN J. H. DONNELLY </seg>
            <seg id="p004">State of Nebraska, Department of Banking, Lincoln, September 1, 1916. To the Honorables John H. Morehead, Governor; William H. Smith, Auditor of Public Accounts ; Willis E. Reed, Attor- ney General, Members of the State Banking Board, Gentlemen : I beg to hand you herewith the Twenty-fourth Annual Report of the Department of Banking, showing the condition of the building and loan associations of the State of Nebraska at the close of the fiscal year June 30, 1916, compiled from annual reports of these associations, which contains tabulated statements, detailed reports, with other information and com - ments, so that the true condition of these associations may be known and comparisons made with reports submitted in previous years to your honorable body. I am pleased to report the steady growth and expansion of these associations, the resources having increased $6,256,976.55, and to supplement this statement with the in - formation that as a rule these institutions are capably man - aged, and deserve the confidence of the people of their com - munities. However, as in my previous report, I must voice my conclusion that there is an over optimism, and not that degree of prudence in loaning, as is clearly demonstrated by the amount of loans in foreclosure and subject to foreclosure, which approximates a total of $1,000,000.00, with an addi - tional $1,000,000.00 or more in other real estate and real estate sold on contract, making a grand total of over $2,000,000.00. I called your attention to this matter in the report of 1915, but again desire to emphasize the significance of this item as a part of the general summary given. I would not feel that my duty had been fully done did I not call attention to the apparent excessive rate of interest charged borrowers as shown from year to year in the statistics of these associations, and pursuant to this policy I am directing your special attention to the rate of dividends declared on running stock and on full paid or matured stock, and the rate of interest charged borrowers during the year, to which must be added premiums charged borrowers. The average per cent of dividends declared on running stock is seven and seven-tenths per cent, full paid or matured stock is six per cent; the rate of interest charged </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 5 borrowers averaged eight and two-tenths per cent, together with the additional two and five-tenths per cent premium, making a total average of ten and seven-tenths per cent paid by borrowing members during the year. While it is true that the borrowing member receives some benefit by way of reduction of his rate in the dividends paid or credited on the amount he has paid in on his stock, yet the fact remains and is clearly apparent that in many building and loan associations he is penalized by a too high rate of interest. I am of the opinion that the time is not far distant when legislative interference will be necessary in the adjustment of this matter in the fixing by legal enactment, or the conferring of authority upon some body, to fix a maximum and lower rate of interest, especially on full paid and matured stock. The Department can not see any justice in the home builder (in whose interests these associations are supposed to be created) being taxed to pay a higher rate of interest to that portion of the investing public which seeks the advantage of the high rates of interest now prevalent paid by these asso - ciations. These are the two prominent items in this report to which I feel it my duty to direct your attention, viz: The indiscreet loaning made manifest by the number of mort - gages in foreclosure and subject to foreclosure, and the rates paid by borrowers, as shown heretofore. It must be clear to anyone conversant with the financial conditions as they now exist, that a period of falling prices and lower price levels will mean serious results for building and loan associations that do not trim their sails for what will eventually come as a sequel to present over optimism. Very respectfully, E. ROYSE, Secretary State Banking Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SUMMARY Of the condition of the SEVENTY-TWO BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916. ASSETS First mortgage loans _ _ _.....-._ $ 42,467,383.51 Loans in process of foreclosure - 258,499.74 Loans on stock or pass book security _ _ _ 464,626.70 Office and other real estate _.._ _ _ 860.857.33 Real estate sold on contract „ 257,944.84 State and municipal securities _ _ 292,032.28 Cash _ _ - 2,819,014.78 Delinquent interest, fines, etc _ 149,984.37 Furniture and fixtures _ _ 32,548.84 Taxes paid 15,756.17 Other assets _ 23,443.64 Tax certificates 2,972.37 Certificates of deposit _ _ 282,782.51 Total * 47,917,847.06 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _...$ 43,133.413.54 Paid-up stock and dividends. _ 2,094,884.84 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1,001,341.03 Reserve fund _ _ 1,117,012.05 Undivided profits. _ _. 466,434.12 Unearned premium 47.90 Other liabilities _ 57,629.15 57,629.15 Matured stock _ 40,514.45 Bills payable 7,570.00 Total ..._.. - _.$ 47,817,847.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 7 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ $ 2,206,285.05 Dues (running stock) 12,032,654.18 Stock loan payments...- 685.956.24 Paid-up stock _ _ _ _ 3,942,523.80 Mortgage payments 7,055,492.39 Stock loan payments 685,956.24 Real estate sales _ _ _ 172,982.67 Interest _ 2338,128.43 Premium _ _ _ 109,755.34 Fines _ _. 12,829.18 Rents _ _ _ _ 15,191.52 Membership and transfer fees...,. _ _ 55,066.00 Rents and office building receipts _ 29,970.62 Other receipts in detail _ 543,358.05 Tax certificates _ _ _ 3,482.19 Certificates of deposit...- _ _ _ 25l',8O5.50 Incomplete loans _ _ 247,604.11 Bills payable _.._ _ _ 23,095.00 TotaL $ 30,226,200.27 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans — _ $ 12,288,321.37 Stock loans ..._ -.._ - 654,537.88 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 8,987,471.86 Withdrawals, paidup stock -.... 2,490,399.19 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock-.... 634,346.92 2,490,399.19 Salaries .._ — - - 234,289.86 Commissions _ - 38,917.17 Other expense - - - 172,141.38 Real estate account 530,440.62 Cash on hand- _.._ - 2,841,221.52 Other disbursements in detail 450,206.05 530,440.62 Tax certificates 6,086.88 Matured stock.... _ „ 202,095.78 Certificates of deposit 376,690.01 Bills payable -. 25,069.77 Incomplete loans _ - - - 293,964.01 Total $ 30,226,200.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of associations. — _ _ 53 Permanent, 14 Serial 5 Combination Number of series issued since organization. 622 Number of shares issued since organization _ _... 2,338,787.67 Number of shares outstanding last report 891,333.79 Shares issued since last report _ _ 267,979.82 Total — - - _ 1,159,313.61 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 151,966.98 Number of shares in force this date 1,007,346.63 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. _ 7736 Number of shares in force this date. Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-pay - ment of dues _ 3009 Average running time of stock matured during the year.... 114% months Number of borrowing stockholders _. 30106 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 64821 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2593 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 3784 Par value of each share of stock _ 51 of $100; 21 of $200 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 62,609.65 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 81.509.14 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid.... 165,938.91 Number and amount of mortgages subject to fore - closure . _ number, 585 688,175.96 Number and amount of mortgages in process of fore - closure ..._ _.._ .number, 234 258,499.74 Amount of loans on improved real estate 41,196,069.28 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ _ 75,442,876.51 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 157,737.23 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _.._ _ 398,920.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security. — _ _ 52,996,005.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security.— _ 39,755,046.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms _ 1.6O5.6O0.0O Appraised value of land not including improvements 3,057,554.80 Value of improvements _ 807,855.00 3,057,554.80 807,855.00 Amount of fire insurance thereon 384,795.00 Amount of tornado insurance thereon — _... 245,585.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 177,174.61 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 25,376.50 177,174.61 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year- Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 1,834,523.05 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year _ _ - - 666,789.22 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dur - ing year.... _ _ _ 7.7% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ — _ _ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 6% 8.2% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year -._ 2.5% </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">STATEMENT Of total number of associations, number of shares in force, and total assets, from 1892, the first year that authentic reports were made, down to the present time. Number of I Number of Year Association. Shares in Total Assets Force 1892 71 45,012.5 $ 2,902,557.67 1893 84 61,964.1 3,653,096.83 1894 86 71,231.5 3,888,001.31 1895 81 70,615 3,929,778.27 1896 73 64,891.75 3,771,833.53 1897 _. 68 67,597.5 3,554,788.08 1897 _. 68 1898 _ _ 64 79,973 3,428,728.11 1899 _ _ 60 89,492 3,332,781.67 1900 60 105,625 3,697,356.06 1901 59 119,985 4,314,744.86 1902. _ _ 58 130,083 4,758,293.97 1903 _ _ 59 153,434 5,343,429.38 1903 _ _ 59 1904 _ 60 174,022 6,217,350.40 1905 „... 59 196,030 7,269,297.48 1906 _.._ 61 220,648 8,961,788.11 1907 66 315,372 ; 11,422,890.86 1908 68 372,826.77 13,415,822.89 1908 68 1909 70 438,054.19 17,094,771.57 1910 _ 70 512,344.71 21,327,766.83 1911 69 602,159.94 24,885,285.15 1912. 68 668,122.85 28,946,108.63 1913 _ 70 740,925.29 32,746,726.24 m4.!Z""Z!"ZZZ 72 816;671.*25 37,138!413.21 1915 71 891,333.79 41,660,870.53 1916 * I 72 1,007,346.63 47,917,847.08 Madison Building and Savings Association, Madison, liquidated and quit business during the year, and two associations were organized and chartered: Midwest Savings and Loan Association, Lincoln, and the Protective Savings and Loan Association, Ord. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATEMENTS Showing the condition of each of the seventy-two Build - ing and Loan Associations in the State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 12 STATEMENT of the condition of the ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA On the 30th, day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President — - _ _...P. A. Krause Vice President _ T. F. Martin Secretary F. A. Doten Treasurer _ . - _ F. S. Thompson Attorney _.._ - - - O. M. Needham DIRECTORS P. A. Krause F. F. Willott T. F. Martin G. K. Pittenger F. A. Doten H. P. Bull W. S. Price R. T. Flotree W. B. Martin F. S. Thompson C. A. Bull ASSETS First mortgage loans $120,300.00 Loans on stock or pus book security- lolaOO.00 Other real estate 1,553.80 Cash _.. _ 4.700.82 Delinquent Interest, lines, etc_ '7S5.00 Furnltnre and fixtures - 1L87 Tax sale certificates _ - ________________ 553.38 Total Z. I1XK 7(M 07 LIABILITIES Kunnlng stock and dividends |122,2S1.10 Paid-up stock and dividends fl.S75.00 Reserve fund 4,95o!oo Undivided prnfltg- S13.27 Uncollected interest and flues. l.Z 7S5!eo Total $138,704.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 13 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report- _ _ 9 2,274.28 Dues (running stock) _________ 22.353.tl Mortgage payments „ _ 'Jl.700.00 Stock loan payments— _ 1,000.00 Interest _ ______ 10.S78.71 Premium „ „ 1.827.3O Fines - ___________________ 431.10 Rents _ .16.00 Membership and transfer fees. " 201.50 Costs returned _ 87.20 Tax sale certificates ...___...__ _____ _ 523.04 Total | 80,^32.72 DISBIRSKMENTS Mortgage loans. $ 17,600.00 Stock loans 3.100.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends Withdrawals, paid-up stock 24.S43.2O 7.100.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 814.10 Salaries 1. 139.96 Other ex|&gt;ense _ „ 70.50 Real estate account _ 1.553.80 Cash on hand „ 4.700.42 Tnx sale certificates 410.55 Total.. * flO.?32.72 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association „ __ _ _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organisation. 12,441 Number of shares outstanding last report 4481 Shares issued since last report 841 Total - _ 5.122 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 565 Number of shares in force this date 4.SS7 Average running time of stock matured during the year 124 month* Number of borrowing stockholders _ , _ 14fl Number of non-borrowing stockholders 320 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year JO Plan of premium - _ _ Fixed payable monthly Par value of each share of stock $ loo.no Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 785.80 Par value of each share of stock 788.80 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 8 (1,400.00 .^Ullll»*"r nun niuuiiiii wi munBo^cn «■ i" iwirviiwjir — ..i^v. o *&gt;.n*l.\M» Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ _ 118,400.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - - _ -.. 237.450.00 Amount of leans on nnimproved real estate _ _ 2,100.00 Appraised value of nnimproved real estate upon which loans have been made , 5,000.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 124,820.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collsteral security _ 123.520.00 Amount credited fo reserve fund during year 000.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 9.1W5.7y Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 814.10 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year... 8.79% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured ajid full paid stock during year. _ - _ 7 and f¥jk Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ye«,r 7.2% Bate per cent of premium! charged borrowers during year. 1.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President.. _ _ _ ...R. M. Hampton Vice President A. D. Rodgers Secretary _ _ _ _ _ Geo. E. Davis Geo. E. Davis Treasurer _ _ R. M. Hampton DIRECTORS R. M. Hampton F. W. Irish A. D. Rodgers F .W. Harris John McDonald Geo. E. Davis Charles E. Wills Mrs. W. E. Rousey Jerry Rowan ASSETS First mortgage loans — $238.4410.00 Loans in process of foreclosure 4, 201X00 Loans on stock or pass book security litVMXOfi Cash 10.10ft.27 1.640.00 Cash Delinquent interest, fines, etc I 4!oftl!56 Furniture and fixtures '325:00 Tales paid __ __ 1.5B7121 Insurance 82.45 82.45 District court 122.00 Miscellaneous 114.96 Miscellaneous Total $258,732.44 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 96,734.32 Paid-up stock and dividends 147|fl81.00 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 4!ol(L46 Reserve fond • 3!&lt;J39.10 Other liabilities ~~.~..'.~. I 4!o8l'.a&gt; Tot«l $258,732.44 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 15 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 4.811.06 Dues i running stock). 16,893.16 Paid-up stock , _ _ 5O.7S6.0O Mortgage payments 16,876.10 Stock loan payments 9MKIM Interest 20.919.26 Fines 307.96 Taxes 2S6.96 Miscellaneous _ _ k"i.SO Total _ $112,023.31 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ 4O.7S5.M Stock loans. , 1.050.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends R.273.50 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 39,4«1.1O Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 10.459.86 Salaries - 1.188.30 Other expense 112.06 Cash on hand 10.109.27 112.06 Cash on hand- Taxes .- _ _ 317.06 Court costs — -._— . g^ 20 Miscellaneous _ _ — - - 200.75 Total _ $112,023.31 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - - - — -. Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization 4.S54.74 Number of shares outstanding last report 2.270.53 Shares issued since last report __ 767.27 Shares issued since last report 9 - Total -_- 3.037.80 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. 263.42 Number of shares In force this date 2,774.38 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 72 Number of sbarea subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 64 Average running time of stock matured during the year 114 months Number of borrowing stockholders 166 Number of non-borrowing stockholders .'... 53 .&gt;IIII1IM-| Ul IH«l-IPUII"tTlllR -i &gt;■■ n ii. .|.i- i - UD Number of loans made for building purposes dnring year 16 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year 17 Par value of each share of stock _ $ 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 2.842.00 17 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 2,602.00 Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid _. 4.081.56 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 9 8.800.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 3 4.20o!oo Amount of loans on Improved real estate 240660.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been r.inde - 375.400.00 Amount of fire Insurnnce in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _. 337.355.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 38.350.00 Amount credited t-o reserve fund during year Wifi.58 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _. S. 475.11 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock dnring year 10,450.86 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year 8% Kate per rent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock stock during year , — f"!t Bate per cent of interest charged borrower* dnring year 9.96% </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SOUTHEASTERN NEBRASKA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AUBURN NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _.._ „._ _ Wm. B. Smith Vice President. _ R. E. Harmon Secretary _ _ J. M. Gillan Treasurer.... _ _ _ _ B. C. Howe Attorney „ _.._ _ Edgar Ferneau Edgar Ferneau DIRECTORS B. C. Howe E. M. Kerns J. M. Gillan R. E. Harmon R. M. Gillan Wm. B. Smith AS8ETS First mortgage loans _ $193,040.00 Loans on itock or pass book security __ l!73o!oo Other real estate „ — _ _. 13' I C1°4O Real estate sold on contract——. _ r» oils 7u Cash _ 9^221.88 Delinquent interest, lines, etc ,., 3!d32!60 Furniture and fixtures _ '2»!oo Taxes Dald —— _ _.......„.... ....._... w ?_ 327.24 Xotal ™. $228,426.67 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends- $54 453.44 Paid-up stock and dividend* 182,100.00 182,100.00 Reserve fund _ ___ 5,'»7.'81 Undivided profits 5,927i72 Unearned premium 47.90 47.90 Tol $228,426.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band laat report _ S 13.947.44 Dues (running stock) 16,458.80 Paid-up stock _ _ _ 59.M0.00 Mortgage payments- x .isn'nii Stock loan payments 201X00 Real estate sales on contract 1,132.23 ._•»■ Interest, premium and lines 12.MM.44 Rents _ 442.54 Membership and transfer feet ' 225.00 Foreclosure account ..,,, ,, ,..., j 3^g 54 1.30B.54 Insurance and twx^t ____,__. .__----__-_-__..«_-. 113.17 Total _ tl32 T_ft 1ft __ — » — — — — — ■ "" —_»»_»»——■———■■■■—■» ■ ■■——■■*■_»■■■__■——■ ' 1 " ■•* 1 ■■ ■■ ■■■»-■■■*■-———*■■■■ Y""*! 4 *** *V DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans * 61.sno.00 Stock loans - 645.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. — 14.99l!86 Withdrawals! paid-up stock 27.80&amp;00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-op stock 7,tB7.VJ Salaries 2,227.40 Commissions - 408.00 {)tber cxpcnsf ...- hi hi h ■■ ■ 908 50 Real estate account , 5.216.58 Cash on hand 9.221.86 Insurance and taxes. _ 22J50 Furniture — ______________________ 85.00 Foreclosure account 1,379.40 Total $132,329.16 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of snares issued since organization 20,161 Number of shares outstanding last report- 4,247 Shares Issued since last report 1,886 Total in. i ■ in. - Hi.. 5 R33 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 662 ».?M Number of shares In foree this date 5,171 Average running time of stock matured during the year. .Class "A" 84 Mo.; "B" 144 Mo. Numberof borrowing stockholders — - 189 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 337 Number of loans made for building purposes during year ■ 8 Number of loaus made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year. 44 Plan of premium.— - Monthly Par value of each share of stork - $ 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 3.632.60 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 9 10.510.00 10.510.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 191,040.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made , , . 414.3N6.O0 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 2,600.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loana hare been made -— - — — — — — 7,375.0(1 Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 232.650.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association 225,000.00 as collateral security 225,000.00 ount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 68.39 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund dnrlng year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2,542.83 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 7.627.97 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 5% 7,627.97 5% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year J% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 6% 6% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrower* during year 1.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p018">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 18 STATEMENT of the condition of the AURORA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA, -NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - B. A. Munson Vice President - - _...W. E. Reber Secretary...- _ _ Jas. Schoonover Treasurer - — W. E. Lounsbury Attorney _ - - _ J. H. Grosvenor DIRECTORS W. E. Lounsbury J. A. Isama'n Jas. Schoonover W. E. Reber B. A. Munson Jos. Johnson N. J. Ronin W. E. Reber H. E. Newton E. C. Rhinehart ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 78.iXIO.0O Loans In process of foreclosure M9!lO Loans on stock or pass book security — 1.055.00 Real estate _ . __„„—«_. 1.233.92 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc 1,088.80 Furniture and fixtures _ 170.20 Taxes paid- 39.00 Total- - - $ 83.2115. S2 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ 58.334.87 Paid-up stock _ Reserve fund . . 23.700.00 388.94 Undivided profits - _ 40.W Matured stock - 300.00 Overdraft 531.35 Total f 83.298.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 19 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report—....™. „ „««_«„„—_-„ $ 4.078.90 Dues I running stock) t. _ ! 10,967.50 Paid-up stock 1.100.00 Mortgage payments 10,881.82 Stock loan payments 860.00 Interest o,756.M 1,100.00 Fines _ 116.90 Rents , 80.00 Membership and transfer feel 81.50 Insurance and taxes repaid 26.86 26.86 Settlement of foreclosure cases 3,480.31 Cash account overdrawn _ 531.35 Total————— $ 38,949.43 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - — a 5,500.00 Stock loans —........_— .......... _ . 2,025.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 4.677.99 Withdrawals, paid-up stocli 13,060.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 1,806.06 Salaries _— 740.00 4.677.99 Other expense 114.08 Real estate account 46.48 Insurance and taxes paid .„_„—..—.. _.._.__........-__..._.. 61.85 Matured stock _ 10.800.00 ■Court costs, foreclosure cases _— — . _ , 69.00 Xotal _ _ f 3S.Mft.43 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of series Issued since organization 27 Number of shares issued since organization 5,474 Number of shares outstanding last report 2 '^°}4 Shares issued since last report - - 189 Total _ - 2.499% Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 525% Number of shares in force this date 1,974 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent....—. 323 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 262 Average running time of stock matured during the year 124% months Number of borrowing stockholders 54 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 118 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year 3 Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 1,331.50 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 1,226.50 3 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1.088.60 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No 19 24,000.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure _No. 1 1.100.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate "S .900.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate npon which loans hare been made - - 167,360.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate None Amount of lira Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 90.100.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and aaslgned to the association 90,100.00 as collateral security 90,100.00 Amount credited to reserve ftind during year lHH.vfl Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year l.OfiO.50 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4.680.06 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 1.866.03 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock (lu rlnjr vpbt M , _......., ... i i inn 9Pfp te per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 81% *r. Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - _ _..JI. H. Norcross Vice President.— D. G. McGaffey Secretary - C. F. Gale Treasurer. — - _ _ Louie Graf Attorneys Rinaker and Kidd DIRECTORS A. H. Kidd H. H. Norcross T. J. Chidester E. L. Hevelone A. H. Phelps ASSETS First mortgage loans *W!»6.725.00 Loans in process of foreclosure — 15.550.00 Loans on stock or pass book security- 678.00 Heal estate, office _ _$ 6.0(10.00 Other real estate 18.130.23 24.130.23 Real estate sold on contract Il,~&gt;u2.85 C ag h __ 240,182.54 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc „ fl.27fl.50 Furniture and fixtures _ 1,175.90 Taxes paid, tax sale certificates- ►72.70 Other assets — 1.620.17 Total $1,296,716.79 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - $865,K4it.l7 Paid-up stock and dividends 347,O75.(.O Due shareholders on Incomplete loans.- _ _ l!t.!tl"J.63 Reserve fund - - l. r i.06fi.4« Undivided profits — - - 50.797.91 Other liabilities - 15.82 Tottl $1,298,71«.7» </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ $213,002.47 Dues (running slock) 341.358.67 Paid-up stock 97.050.00 Mortgage payments 123.873.16 Heal estate sales , :t.808.S5 Real estate sales on contract 1.4M1.65 Interest _ 9.1,204.11 Fines _ - - 354.03 Rents 263.00 Memltership aud transfer fees. - 4,444.74 Rents and office building receipts 362.00 Ma.ua Tax sale certificates _ .1(10.70 Incomplete loans _________ i.920.11 IjOun dues __ 909.00 Abstract fees 2,418.2ft Fire loss Insurance - 1,459.10 Bills receivable _ 900.00 Miscellaneous receipts ..._ - ii.OOK.86 Total _ t8V8.41. r &gt;.fi0 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - - _ $367,171.13 Stock loans — 75.00 Withdrawal., running stock and dividends. _ 171,274.42 Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ 7T.MU0 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock- 17,519.34 Salaries _ 8.SW.61 Commissions _______~_ 2,243.15 Other expense S.T9.39 Real estate account- _ - - 2.250.36 Cash on hand 2J0.182.M Fire loss account _ _ — 1.02fl69 Office building 1,061.-0- Traveling expense _ - 1.521.60 Collection and exchange 3.MM.5O Pottage and telephone 4-6.75 Miscellaneous 3.244.71 TotaL — _ $898,415.00 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association- _ _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization 103.829^4 Number tif shares outstanding last report 37,012% Shares Issued since last report 16,398 Tot : i| , 53,410^ Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 8.01OV Number of shares In force this date _ _ _ — 4o.39»H Average running time of stock matured during the year lit Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ . ft-9 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 2,949 Number of loans made for building purposes during year. 106 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year ________________ 183 Par value of each share of stock _ $ 100.00 Amount of dues owning by borrowing stockholders 3.442.S5 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 6.279.50' Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 17 22.100.00 C,-79.ofr Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure — No. 13 lSJtM.M Amount of loans on Improved real estate 1.011.975.01 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 2,O73.59fcOT&gt; nunt of loans on unimproved real estate — 300.00 2,073..m0f' Amount of loans on unimproved real estate- Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have t&gt;*-**ii .undo -_. •*- **+ ,_ i ,,._■■■■■■■■ t .!■■■_■■ ■■■ ■■■■■■■■ XfflOO.fjO ..mount of fire "insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1,236,560.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1,185,375.0^ Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ t.OWMC Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year- 1.054.:* Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 56.80*1.01 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 100&lt;,2.2O Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock 8% during year 1 *%- Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year... 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _...C. P. Fall Vice President _ _ Ernst Schaekel Secretary _ E. F. Kimmerly Treasurer. _ _ F. B. Sheldon Attorney _ _ - _.._ F. B. Sheldon DIRECTORS C. P. Fall C. A. Janssen H. E. Sackett ASSET8 First mortgage loans $37O.484.&lt;52 Loans In process of foreclosure 16.380.77 Loans on stock or pass hook security 79.00 Other real estate 23,702.47 Heal estate sold on contract 2,328.00 Cash ,. 6B.8U.fB Delinquent Interest, lines, etc 2.138..'i2 Fnrniture and fixtures 796.75 Taxes paid , _ 708.03 Other assets 5.25 Total M82.452.68 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $278,520.07 Paid-up stock and dividends 183.125.00 Reserve fund 5.266.14 T/mllvlded profits 15,300.48 Other liabilities H9.00 Total-..- _ $482.462.'» </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ $ 44.511.51 Dues (running slock) _ &gt;«i,l'.to.N4 Paid -up stock _ 64.750.00 Mortgage payments _ S5.16S.76 Stock loan payments S75.0O Real estate sales _ — 5.248.41 Interest - 36.INI6.25 Membership and transfer feel _ 519.50 Loan fees _ _ T.TO.iKi Taxes repaid _ _ , M ( 1.763.78 Foreclosure account- _™—™_— . 7.1*oi.iu Added reserve fund - _ 75.35 Other receipts _ 6.70 $3.77.280.90 Total nisnritsKMEXTS Mortgage loans — - _ * S-S.35S.fiO Stock loans - 429.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends- S.-..VVJ.T 1 - Withdrawals, paid-up stock 4O.finfi.00 Wlthdrawals. dividend on paid-up stock 9,511.28 Salaries - ~ 3.!lO0.O0 (nniniissions ,, , .._ „. L 1.1 10.00 Other expense — . 1.653.2*5 Iieal estate account. _ _ _ 1 1.TIMI fash on hand _ - - - 65.S31.ftS Furniture - ~ - 108.75 Taxes paid _ '. 2.472.4! Traveling expense ..._ .. . —•—•——• -- 370. Sti Foreclosure account - - ~ 2O.SO0.2."&gt; Reserve fund — - -. - - 1.R05.14 Loss not charged off _ 52.C2 Total - - *337,260.!&gt;9 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ - - — Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 34. MS Number of shares outstanding last report _ _13.63O.8O Shares issned since last report - _ 2.444J50 16.0T5.SO Total - 16.«7V;O Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 1.35fl.l&gt;5 Number of shares in force this date — _ 14.716.^5 Average running time of stock matured during the year — 114 months 14.716.^5 Number of borrowing stockholders 345 Number of non-borrowing stockholders . 989 Number of loans made for building purposes during year __ 13 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 36 Par value of each share of stock $ lm.oo Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2.136.52 ::« Nnmber and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 17 20.400.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. H 16.3SO.77 Amount of loans on improved real estate 370.234.82 Vnprnised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - -- 813,435.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _ 250.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate npon which loans have been made 600.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 439.830.f« Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 344.030.iiO Amount credited to reserve fund during year.- _ _ 1.565.35 Amount of losses charged to. reserve fund during year — 1.805.14 Amount of dividends paid on matured and patd-np stock during year 9.511.28 Amount of losses charged to. reserve fund during year — 9.511.28 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 18.986.S1 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year average - - .._ 7^4% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dnrinsr yesr „......, ...— , - &amp;%&gt; e per cent of interest charged borrowers during year »«%■ tr. Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dnring ye»r_. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - .Philip Graff Vice President - J. E. Lang Vice President Secretary. - M. F. Eickmann Treasurer - Carl Sonderegger Attorneys _ Rinaker and Kidd Attorneys. DIRECTORS J. E. Lang Carl Sonderegger Philip Graff John Huttenmaier Henry T. Jurgens ASSET8 Flr»t mortgage Irani $147,300.1)0 Cash 33,195.(S2 Delinquent Interest, lines, etc 1.44K.56 33,195.(S2 Furniture and fixtures ! 49T.7O Taxes paid — '^S-fJ Certificate* of depoiit" — 50,330.44 Total $233,152.86 LIABILITIES Running atock and dlrldenda $ 59,7».nO Paid-up stock and dividends 196.500.00 Beaerre fond «00.00 Undivided profits : 6,318.89 Total $233,152.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 25 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report....-——— _ * 19.621.BS Dues (running stock) 38.219.S0 Paid-up stock - _ 114,150.00 Mortgage payments _ 12,777.51 Interest — 10.7SS.48 Fines 108.50 Membership and transfer fees_ _ 838.00 Loan fees - 435.00 Total S196.738.S2 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans , , , f 5fl.277.51 Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ 14.934.25 Withdrawals, paid-up stock :. 34.52S.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid op stock.- _ _ 4.658.12 Mortgage loans - — 4.858.12 Salaries 1.525.00 Com missions | ___...__ 75.00 Other expense - 911.21 Cash on band 33,195.83 Tax sale certificates _ 300.87 Certificates of deposit - - _ 50,338.44 Total I196.738.S2 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation — 6,787 Number of shares outstanding last report 3.358*4 Shares issued since last report 2.124 $ Total __„ ■ ■ ■ 5,483^4 Shareswithdrawn. matured or cancelled since last report- 748H Number of shares in force this date 4.738 Total Average running time of stock matured during the year 120 months Number of borrowing stockholders 127 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 109 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 8 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 48 Par value of each share of stock f 100.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 337.50 -i« Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders— . Amount of Interest premium, and fines do* and unpaid 1.462.55 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 5 5.99000 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 146.200.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made 320.200.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 1,100.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan* have been made 3,000.00 Amount of fire" insurance In force and assigned to the association aa collateral security _ 211.425.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the associa - tion as collateral security __- 17 JJ_I S _2 Amount of dividends declnrcil . n running stock during year 2.661.87 Amount credited to reserve fond during year .__ ___ 375.(10 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and foil paid stock during year _ . . ■ •% Hate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President.— „ E. R. Stewart Vice President F. W. Arndt Secretary. _ John Schmahling Treasurer C. A. Schmidt Attorney. - - _ Clark O'Hanlon DIRECTORS F. W. Arndt J. E. Carver Julius Mueller Clark O'Hanlon C. A. Schmidt E. B. Stewart John Schmahling ASSETS First mortgage loan* S 80,250.&lt;iO Loans on stock or pass book security l.SWMiO Cash 2,642.(J0 Total i $ 04,192.00 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 75,212.53 Paid-up stock and dividends 10.100.iX) Reserve fund 2,K).'&gt;..'j8 .uaVM rndivided profits. _ 3.384.00 Bills payable. &lt;_\500.fi0 Total S fM.192.'J9 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report , f 1,285.33 Dues (running stock) 17,258.24 Paid-up stock 6,450.00 Mortgage payments 9.275.00 I nterest — _.._ 8,191.94 Fines 100.55 Membership and transfer fees 217.89 Money borrowed 3.500.00 Total f 44.278.75 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan« f 20.300.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 12.974.54 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 5.350.00 5.350.00 Salaries 245.00 Other expense 133.03 Cash on hand 2,642.09 Money borrowed paid 2.000.00 Interest - - .-—-.—.—— .....—_ 034.00 Total $ 44,278.75 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report 2419 Shares Issued since last report _ 235 Total 2.«54 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 332 Number of shares in force this date — . 2,322 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ _ 188 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of due* 198 .132 Average running time of stock matured during the year 9 years Number of borrowing stockholders. _ 9S Number of non-borrowing stockholders 134 Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 1.423.60 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 1.061.60 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1.411.16 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 3 2.500.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate. — .... 90.250.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - -....- - _. 150,375.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 109.450.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 95 700.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ."W3.5O Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year- 5.337.70 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year — 8% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year *% </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ENTERPRISE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President.. _ W. H. Faling Vice President _ _.._ _ Ji. H. Rankin Secretary _ _ D. L. Tallmadge Treasurer _ James Kelly Attorney _ _ _ _...B. F. Butler DIRECTORS J. M. Hollingsworth A. D. Bellamy D. L. Neiswanger W. H. Faling J. W. Hammond H. E. Day C. M. Brown R. H. Rankin A. E. Thorndike ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 17.80X00 Cash , t i 4*908.96 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc ' 40.86 Tottl * 22,749.00 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ _ I 20.0O7.M Reserve fund _ ' 90.29 Undivided profits _ ___■_«____ 1,»23°.31 Total $ 22.749.no </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 29 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 757. SI Dues (running stock) _ _... Mlt-M Mnrtjiaite payments — 2,400.60 Stoik loan payments .. 516.21 Interest 1,321.38 Fine* 11.80 Meiuliersnip and transfer fees 13.00 Bills receivable _ 2.450.00 Total $ 17.323.U0 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* $ 7.200.00 Stock loans _ 155.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 712 88 Salaries . _..._ 2O1.00 Commissions 15.30 Other expense __ _. __._.. 19.68 Cash on hand _ 4,906.95 Bills payable 4,110.00 Total f 17.323.00 SUPPLEMENTAL REI"ORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation- _ 2,559 Number of shares outstanding last report &lt;B0 Shares Issued since last report 506 Total _ 1,125 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 320 Number of shares in force this date 805 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 13 Number of borrowing stockholders 30 20 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 62 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 9 Par value of each share of stock $ 100.1(0 Total amount of dues delinquent it this date 53.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 53!o0 Amounr of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid 40.fi Amount of loans on improved real estate 17.H0RU0 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been niHiU' 34,250.00 Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _MMM Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 20,650.00 Amount credited to reserve fund daring year 50.26 20,650.00 Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 8% </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CENTRAL CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CENTRAL CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _.._ E. E. Ross Secretary _ F. K. Sprafrue Treasurer.— _ _...J. W. Vieregg Attorney „ E. E. Ross DIRECTORS E. E. Ross R. Tooley J. W. Vieregg F. K. Sprague ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 24.WO.IIO Cash 4.413.39 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc 212.S0 Total $ 29.476.19 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends- — _—_ — $ 28,013.73 Reserve fund __ 1,0(27.00 Undivided profits _ 222.08 Unpaid Interest and fines 212.SO Tot«l _ _ $ 20. 476.lt&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report f 8M.34 Dues (running stock) „ .v.c.l.i.i Mortgage payments l.TOO.iifl Interest 2.319.1W ., — f 868.34 2.319.W Fines * 1'11_.*.'...... 79.W Membership and transfer fees ZZZ Z_l 72^50 Unearned dividends H2.X, Ulicai litfU u 1 V HiyiHiB, , I||M mam ma ._ -»■■■■■■- ml ,.___,,,„ ■ »^ -i^ * Borrowed money _ 1,400.00 Total— $ 12,411. n DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans I l.SOO.IK' Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 4,«S8.0'.i Salaries 73.00 Commissions !J _....'. 8.50 Other expense , , Sfl.23 Cash on hand ____3_ 4.41S..T!' Borrowed money repaid 1.400.1 Hi Interest paid oo borrowed money 20:!0 Total _ - I 12,411.44 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization 1.SS.J Number of share* outstanding at last report 813 ..SKi Shares issued since last report IIS Total _ 914 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 71 Number of shares in force this date 855 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 117 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues &lt;U Number of borrowing stockholders 24 Number of non-borrowing stockholders ' 7S Nuinbrr of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year- _ ~ 1 Par value of each share of stock.. _ $ lOO.(K) Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 1.04.1.H0 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 120.M) Amount of interest premiums and fines due and unpaid 212. SO Numl&gt;er and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure _.No. 1 2.uod.ini Amount of loans on improved real estate 24.850.*O Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 53.40(&gt;.oo Amount of Are Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ; 29.5OO.(»i Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■.•s.-wo ,w, Amount credited to reserve fund during year- 110. '52 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2,433. (10 llD/a Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 1'*' Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year. 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President E. W. Orr Vice President C. D. Ellis Secretary J. L. Campbell Treasurer : J. L. Campbell DIRECTORS N. W. Johnson H. B. Campbell J. L. Campbell J. W. Whitlam George S. Ward George A. Allen ASSETS Fir«t mortgage loans , $ 54.725.IK) Other real estate _ 500.00 Real estate sold on contract - - 525.00 Cash ___...__. ft.515.Wi Delinquent Interest, fines, etc - 1,249.00 Taxes and Insurance paid _ 126.25 Total - - * 62.64(M)t LIABILITIES Banning stock and dlTidends - — _ * 5M5H.23 Paid-up stock and dividends. 500.no Reserve fund - iI9?-9° Undivided profits ' Z. — 11 2,281/il Total * 62.64O.M </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 33 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _. - I 1,507.14 Due* (running stock) .. 13.102. (HI Mortgage payments.. _ l.YKiO.iio Real estate sales — 280.U0 Interest 4,118.'.il Premium ________—— 811.26 Fines _ - 44.NI Membership and transfer fees _ — 34.(10 Insurance and taxes repaid _ 30.40 Sundries _ _ _ .... - _ _____ 64.32 Total — $ 35,8(13.57 DISKURSKMEXTS Mort Knite loans _ _ ♦ J.67 5.(10 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. — HJ..i!t.:i3 Withdrawals] paid-up stock. _ - - _ 3 "X!M!1! Withdrawals! dividend on paid-up stock — _ _ - SS-JS Salaries 1 - — - _____ __ ***■&lt;£ Commissions" —" — — 15-rS 133.14 Other expense- Other expense - — i-V'AA Real estate Recount - — — - — «il?,5 Cash on hand - 5 - s i,'-_? Taxes and insurance — 62. u f MM -■: Total.. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Permanent Plan of association. i:im Xutnlier of shares outstanding last report. ll!&gt; Shares issued since last report.. 1.419 _ * . i.ii:f Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report... 307 1.112 Number of shares In force this date.. \*n XniWr of shares on which dues are delinquent - ■■ ... -•■ »» Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues _,„_» J" Number or snares sunjeci to c-ui-iikiiuu i»i u^..-i™.-»- »• — _ _„_,„_ Average running time of stock matured during the year 73 montnt Average running time nt xiik-k uuiurm uu.,.. R .-&lt;; ..»- ,_= Number of borrowing stockholders -- 12 ■ Number of non-borrowing stockholders .. — . - — Number of loans made for building purposes during ~W— . ... ._ Number of loans made for purchasfiig of homesteads or payment of 1 :\umner oi iuuum w«nr mi t»m .--«.«« «. — - liomestead-mortgases during year _ - \innti.iv Plan of premium _ — - — - — ■ — — . kkii.i * 100.O1 Tut -J- rf «_^.1-&gt;. « t-rt _ __. • iX&amp; M Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders..-.-.-^--.. _ .oS&gt;o Amount of interest, premiums and fines due »nO" n P«' d - «„ ii lA'Sono Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 14 S"3!Js« \mount of loans on improved real estate -- r—r »»,_-i. ■&gt; Appraised value of improved real est_te upon which loans h»ye 10esBOno been made - . __g__— "" 300.00 1.3K7.(lO 1.240.C0 lO.AtlO.fH) 300.00 5?^_«d Of «lS?V'.nV_l?r-^- re_l e^.U upon "Which loan."..-* 60t&gt;.'« _jjszr &lt;rft i— i!* » •— • — * — «*— * *» — ' — — "— * «6.84O.0O AmX^'t^r&amp;Sttri^** -_■»--« «» »» i^-iTiiii es.3«o.uo » "•'_•'__' '—*'—t-?z-^ ' -BS \mount credHed to reserve lnnd during year..^.. 114 77 Amonnt of dividends declared on running stock during year . 4.1U.77 23t&lt;.(0 Vmoun ot dividends paVd on matured and paid-up stock duHng year WM Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7 «, Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock __^ R«t^ n pCT*r#nt%f"t-tere-t"eh_n^'"Sorrower» during year - - 8* 7', </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COLUMBUS LAND, LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President. J. H. Galley Vice President _ _...G. W. Viergutz Secretary...- _ Henry Hockenberger Treasurer.— _ _ E. H. Chambers DIRECTORS Theo. Moersen C. C. Hardy E. P. Dassell G. W. Viergutz T. C. Hogan L. F. Gottschalk J. H. Galley Henry Hockenberger C. H. Chambers ASSETS First mortgage loans. — $434,400.00 Loans in process of foreclosure _ _ 3,158.0m Loans on stock or pass book security 10,200.00 Other real estate _ _ 2,251.(12 Cash 42,785.13 Delinquent Interest, lines, etc - 3.44S.75 TotaL - $4«V.242.DU LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ $380,515.43 Paid-up stock and dividends- _ - 138,700.'H&gt; Reserve fund - - « 6,505.*&gt;-'l Undivided profits 522.1 1 Total _ $496,242."K) </seg>
            <seg id="p035">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 35 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band f 18,506.80 Due* (running stock) 121,706.19 Paid-up stock SA.SftO.'K) Mortgage payments 108,300.00 Stock loan payments 16.100.00 Real estate sales.. 2,678.10 2,878.10 ami trmmtr sales „ £,010. lu Interest 36.197.04 i uitfreoi JO,1VI .*« Fines _ _ _... 1,048.1:7 Rents _ _ 264.M Membership and transfer fees. 433.50 Mortgage foreclosure 1.873.55 433 JO Mortgage foreclosure. Total _ $346,680.99 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. _ $108,200.00 Stock loans 10,100.00 Withdrawals, running Btock and dividends 125.886.77 42.100. CO Withdrawals, paid-up stock 42.100.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 8,517.Sr&gt; Salaries 2,652.53 Other expense. 388.58 Real estate account _ 2,968.17 Cash on hand 42,786.13 Mortgage foreclosure - 5.031.55 388 JIS Mortgage foreclosure, expense 50.(10 Interest refunded 9.91 Total. *.-Ufi.tW.I W SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - _ — Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 28.831 Number of shares outstanding last report 10.337 Shares issued since last report _ 2,414 Total . _ 12.7M Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — 2.250 Number of snares' In force this date 10.501 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent -.. Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of due* 3IT7 Average running lime of stork matured during the year 98 months Number of borrowing stockholders. _.._ - - — S'jg Number of non- borrowing stockholders. — _ - 4JS Number of loans made for building purposes during year _.. 18 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 13 Par value of each share of stock $ "JJ-JJ) Total amount of does delinquent at this date — .&gt;.2M.iK Amount of due« owing by borrowing stockholders 5,2tH.&lt;« 13 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid.. 3,448.75 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 33 .KI.7O0.U0 aftJOO.IA Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosnre....No. 1 UW Amount of loans on improved real estate. _ 424.600.«&gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana have been made _ - -- 921.110.nit nnnt of loans on unimproved real estate — 9.800.(10 921.110.Oi) Amount of loans on unimproved real estate- Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - - - 27.200.(10 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 391.810.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association „,„ as collateral security...- - - 351.2flO.00 391.810.00 Amount of money loaned on unimproved farms. - 2.(100.(10 Appraised value of land not Including Improvements s.ono.no snno.no Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2.209.30 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 50.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 24.317.71 Amount of dividends paid on paid-up stock during year — 8JH7.S5 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year TA&lt;% Rate per cent of dividends paid and full paid stock during year 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.8 r ;i </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE WILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Henry Ragatz Vice President - W. A. Boettcher Secretary _ J. C. Echols Treasurer G. B. Speice Attorney Louis Lightner DIRECTORS Henry Ragatz G. B. Speice W. A. Boettcher Louis Lightner J. C. Echols ASSETS First mortgage loan* M2K.55O.0O 4.175.UI 3.4O0.M 4&amp;MO.4O 6,ine.&lt;;o I.niiiis mi stock or pan book security Other real estate...'. Cash Delinquent interest, fine*, et Taxes paid- _ uai.Tj *4S6.274.'J2 Total LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend*. Paid-up stock and dividends..... Keserve fund - $203,401.08 273.850.00 s.yas.'is 65.46 I'll divided profit k *4H«,274.92 Total. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on baud last report _ _ _ _ $ IMU.U Dues ( ruunlnK stork )_ _ ?. — _ _ 61.3Ki.r2 Paid-up stock _..._ _ 10H.llTin.nii Mortgage payments , 72. 150.00 Stock loan payi lents _ 3,13O.(i0 I nterest -___ 2H.263.-T&gt; Fines 316.30 Rents — — — ............. „_. 72.00 Membership and transfer fees. , 3i«.i») Interest on deposit 88.26 Taies paid. _ _ _ 83.20 Total _ $288,261. CS DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. f 84,550.1)0 Stock loans 2,975.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 60.041.77 Withdrawals, paid-up Mock _ 74.fiOO.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 15.012.S4 Salaries 2,817.24 Other expense. _ - 728.30 Real estate account 3.47254 Cash on hand — 43.8SO.4O Interest returned 63.00 3.472.S4 Interest returned.. Taxes paid 120.50 Total - *288.261.«S SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shores issued since organization „ 28.70O&gt;4 Number of shares outstanding last report —11.1MU 3119H „ Mjm Shares issued shire last report Totnl Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 2.415 Numlier of shares In force this date 11.850 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 1.6S6 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Average running time of stock matured during the year 108 months Numlier of borrowing stockholder* — — S66 Nnmber of non-borrowing stockholders. Number of loans made for building purposes during year 12 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestend-morUcages during year - 48 value of each share of stock -- * lno.ini M Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dnes delinquent at this date _ — 16.470. It) Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — lfi.47O.4fi Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid H.WKftll Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 46 4f...TOO.&lt;IO Amount of loans on improved real estate 421.050.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans bare been made - 87fl.ftiP.cX&gt; Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _ 7,500.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare been made _ - - 19.625.00 Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security. - - -■■ 413,4S0.&lt;10 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — 359.140.lrt as collateral security.. Amount of money loaned ou improved farms - 2.001) .00 Appraised value of land not Including Improvements....- - 5.000.(10 Value of Improvements - - J'222'12 Amount of lire insurance thereon _ 1.000.(10 Amount of tornado insurance thereon..... — . l.OOO.jio Amount credited to reserve fund during year_ _ _ - — 1.3fi2..V"i Amount of dividends declared on running atock during year 12.Wft.no Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 15.in-J.st Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock 7H% during year — •* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ _ Geo. H. Hastings Vice President — _ F. J. Rademacher Secretary and Treasurer _ — W. S. Collett Attorney. _ _ Geo. H. Hastings DIRECTORS Geo. H. Hastings W. K. Hopkins F. J. Rademacher Ed M. Parker L. H. Dennison L. E. Pugh V. J. Shebl W. S. Collett B. G. Miller ASSETS First mortgage loan* „ _ $125,780.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ 2,87B.0O Cash 2,706.75 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc _ „._ _ 333is2 Delinquent dues 28l!oo Tax sale certificates _ 71&amp;G5 Insurance accounts 131.&lt;W 131.W Total ___.- _ _ $132,866. r&lt;2 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $130,833.12 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 108.11 Reserve fund l,012.:M Undivided profits ' 3.U5 Total—— $132,855.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 39 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand list report $ 2,458.83 Due* (running stock) 21,019 M Mortgage payment* 24,150.00 Stock loan payment* 3.875.(10 Interest 7,185.43 Fines . 189.31 Membership and transfer fees 138J50 Delinquent does and lnt»-»«t 875.7" Tax sale certificates and Insurance 839.81 Total. * 80,510.11 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loana $ 29.900.00 Stock loans _ 4.840.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 14.941.0) Salaries 480.00 Other expense 2S&amp;35 Cash on hand ______________________ 2,758.75 Tsx sale certificates and Insurance 1,541.32 Certificates of Indebtedness, matured stock 3,500.00 Incomplete loans . 2.243.00 Total ...._._........._.. $ 80,510.11 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Number of series issued since organisation 14 Number of shares Issued since organisation 7,b82 Number of shares outstanding last report 3,418 Shares Issued since last report , 317 Total _ _ „ 3,733 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Ml Number of shares' in force this date 3,392 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 181 Number of borrowing stockholders 1&lt;)8 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 118 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 17 Par value of each share of stock $ 10O.UI Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 281.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 281. (in Amount of Interest and fines due and unpaid 333.52 IT 333.52 Amount of loans on Improved real estae _ 12S,780.(i0 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loana have been made ..._.__ 230,775.00 Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security- _ _ - 148.900.1/0 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security- _ 127.95000 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 180.00 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 194.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 7.001.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 5.8% Bate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 0% </seg>
            <seg id="p040">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 40 STATEMENT of the condition of the DAVID CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION DAVID CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - W. F. Delaney Vice President _ „ _ S. J. Hyatt Secretary _ _ G. A. Bryant Treasurer _ _ _..John Eberly Attorney - R. C. Roper DIRECTORS W. F. Delaney S. J. Hyatt C. F. Clark B. J. Sheldon Charles D. Ammon H. F. Anderson John Eberly G. A. Bryant J. B. Hookstra G. A. Bryant ASSETS Flr»t mortgage loan*. $ 19.M9.S7 Cash &amp;10 Furniture and fixtures. 75.00 Total - ~ „ _ y 19,532.97 LIABILITIES Running Mock and dividends _ Paid-up stock and dividends $ 1D.M0.50 7.822.44 Reserve fund ~ _ 250 (10 Undivided profits ." _ „ _..... 72M Other liabilities _ _ _ .- 827.11 827.11 Total | 19.532.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SECRETAEY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report- — $ 141.85 Due* (running stock) — 6,993.38 Paid-up stock - 7,179.84 Mortgage payments _ 2.94O.00 Interest _ - l,15O.r4) Loan fees _ ................. _„ 131.00 Bills payable 2,000.(10 Checks outstanding 727.11 Total - - $ 21,272.08 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ - - _ f 11.814.S7 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends...- 3,417.35 Withdrawals, paid-up stock l.^.i'O Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 291."iO Salaries _ -~ 26.00 Commissions 10.00 Other expense 181 .07 Cash on band - 8.10 Bills payable _ _ 3,000.00 IntprPRt * Daid out (JO** ri'&gt; Total - f 21,272.09 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association...- _ — Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation. 1.177% Number of shares outstanding last report _ _ —713* Shares issued since last report -358H Total - - - - 1.07(14 Shares issued since last report — Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 111% Number of shares in force this date — _ !*;■_• _. Number of borrowing stockholders 22 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 95 V. Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year. 10 Plan ' of premium — - - - 80c per share Par value of each share of stock. $ loo.fo Amount of loans on Improved real estate. 19.249.S7 Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made , ... _ 32.53.VJO Amount of loans oh nnimproved real estate - — - 200.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan's hive been made - 800.00 Amount of lire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security -.. — — 18,130.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security- as collateral security _ - - - 18,130.00 Amount credtied to reserve fund during year — 100.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Mfl.Ki Amount of dividend* paid on matured and paid-up stock during year - 289.24 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year—: 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p042">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 42 STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Jane, 1916 OFFICERS President— — _A. V. Pease Vice President _ _ _ .E. L. Simpkins Secretary _ E. W. Wunder Treasurer. H. H. McLucas Attorney. _ _ _...E. W. Wunder DIRECTORS A. V. Pease H. H. Toat J. A. Axtell E. L. Simpkins J. H. Bond S. H. Diller F. L. Rain J. C. Lien H.H. McLuceas AS8ETS Flr»t mortgage loans $ 60,400.00 Loans on stock or pat* book security 73800 Cash Cash 1,707.67 Other assets 44.70 44.70 ToUl $ ae,8M.«7 LIABILITIES Running atock and dlTldcndi $ SS.SM..S5 Pald-op atock and dividends 5V7fl8J)O Reaerre fund 1,500.00 Undivided profits 1 ' 22JB Total $ tt.8M.C7 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 43 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 3,588.33 Doe* (running stock) 22.065.04 Paid-op stock . 3,86&amp;58 3.658.58 Mortgage payments '. ____ IT.ZZIZ 14.000.00 Stock loan payments.. I __ '392^00 Interest Z — I — 1 Z ______ I__T.ZZ 4,395.:iS Fines and rit«/*nnnt« 13.84 4,396.3s r lun luu ,u»ii»mii — , -m _ _ f 13.*S4 Membership and transfer fees 344.00 Loan due* „ 113!(O Total $ 48,500. lit DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans t 18,750.00 Stock loans _ _ 350.00 350.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 26.31S.4S Withdrawals, paid-up stock 1.550.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock— _ 251.17 1.550.00 251.17 Salaries Z ~ 3OOifl6 Commissions _. 1 171.25 Other expense 163.32 163.32 Cash on hand '. _____ __________ 1.7O7.&amp;7 TotaL _ $ 48.5flO.19 SUPPLEMENTAL BEPOHT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares Issued since organisation ....... 2,701 Number of shares outstanding last report 1,480 Ul BliVrW vUlolAUUlUK *__•_■ iTrtfVr 1 ■ ,..„,.., lnll | Shares Issued since last report 348 Total 1,826 1 OlBl __ l.QZU Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 328 Number of shares In force this date 1.498 Average running time of stock matured during the year ., 77 months rti-s Number of borrowing stockholders 58 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 81 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 5 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 13 oi nouiesieau-uiorigagTO uunug year ■ ■ ■ ______ u Par value of each share of stock. f 100.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid 598.75 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 8 5,350.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 80.400.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ! 103.000.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association collateral security • 72,150.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 59,480.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year. 75.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3,709.50 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 312.23 Rate per cent of dividend* declared on running stock during year 7% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock daring year _. 6% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrower! during year 8.4% «"r </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRFIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRFIELD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President C. L. Lewis Vice President _ - Wm. Ashby Secretary _ - — F. Ana wait Treasurer. F. Ana wait DIRECTORS C. L. Lewis J. E. Spatz Wm. Ashby Wm. Hoevet F. Anawalt Walter Hogue ASSETS First mortgage lo«us _ f 5O.65O.UO Real estate - _ 410 77 Real estate sold on contract _ 5Oo!u6 Cagb m m^ 4K0 in Taxes paid and Insurance _ 157JB TotaL f 52,l»8.:i7 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ 32,742.&lt;C Paid-op stock _ ; _ _ 15]eno!(iu Reserve fond l. uo.no l. uo.no I'ndlvided profits _ _ _ _ _ ~__ 2 300 79 Other Hal. little* 5.13 5.13 Total i V* i'w "it </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 45 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ _ $ 1,585. »t Duos (running stork) 4,42M.6«i Paid-up stock — __ _ SJWlW Mortgage payments ■ t!'."7"!iirl Rp«1 estate Rales. _ SXiTT Interest _ _ „ 4.'JW\AZ Premium 12.43 Fines — _ — _ MM Rentx _ _ 11.(3 Meml&gt;ersh!p and transfer fees _ _ _ 12.25 Tuxes anil insurance _ iW.Vi Bills payable „ ____ NOO.'IO Recording fees, etc. _ _ _ _ 32.13 Total. t 19.42S0!) DISnt-RSKMEXTS Mortgage loans..._ _ _ f 44fln.no Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 2.480.10 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 7.7O0.(j0 Withdrawn!*, dividend on paid-up stock. 1J4M1 Salaries :m.no Other expense „ 18.11 Real estate account „ _ 1.222.74 Cash on hand „ 4W&gt;.15 Interest _ _ 130. IS Bills payable „ 1.200.10 Taxes and insurance „ „ _ _ _ 204.05 Recording fees, etc _ 39.!»5 Total $ 19.42S.M SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of snare* issued since organization 2..'iO5 Number of shares outstanding last report _ .W8 Shares issued since last report TO Total _ _ l.f&gt;17 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 131 Number of shares in force this date f**fi Number of shares on which does are delinquent 22« Number of sbareR subject to cancellation for non-payment of dnes 101 Average running time of stock matured during the year 93 months Number of borrowing stockholders _ i3 Number of non-horrowing stockholders. — 47 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ 10 Par value of each share of stock _. * 100.00 Total amonnt of dues delinquent at this date..._ 2..V&lt;7.r I rt Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders „ 2..V7.ol 10 Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid — 1.0R2J1S Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 12 9.750.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate ."VYfiriO.no Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans bare been made. 117.9fl0.fi0 Amount of Ore insurance in force and assigned to the association as as collateral security - _ - 72.255.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 72.2S5.00 Amonnt credited to reserve fund during year 220.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2,5ft4.!&gt;6 220. flO amount or nivinenns neciareu on running rioc*k uunufc jvnr *,.**i..'n Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-np stock during year 1.140.S1 Rate her cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year •% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock r~. during year _ - &lt;Wi e per cenj of interest charged borrowers during year - 9% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FALLS CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President. _ — _ J. H. Hutchings Vice President _ R. R. Rule Secretary W. L. Redwood Treasurer _ _ _ _ P. B. Weaver Attorney. R. C. James DIRECTORS J. H. Hutchings P. B. Weaver R. R. Rule W. L. Redwood W. A. Greenwald ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 56.615.UO Loans In process of foreclosure _ 2,300.&lt;i0 Loans on stock or pass book security 293.00 Real estate 2 14S 75 Cash _ 2ioi5!so Real estate 2,015.80 Delinquent interest, fines, eta _ 232.80 Total _ f 83.602..!.-. LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend! S 52.982.N9 nuuuiuK nuti iuu uitiusuuk- , , ,,... „ «y o£,voa£.ntr Paid-up stock and dlTidends 9,15O.K) ruu-up him iuu mnagmii .._ w.ioti.'iu Due shareholder* on incomplete loans 10.73 BaatrTe fund 1 l,104!w Dndlrided profits 121.18 Delinquent interest „_ _ 232.s*i ToUL_. f «,flO2.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 47 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report $ 1.535.10 Due« (running stock) 12,597.25 Paid-up atock 4.800.00 4.800.00 Mortgage payments 8,800.00 Stock loan payments 950.(10 Interest ..._...... 5,791.98 Flnea - _ ! 28.14 Rents , 00.00 Membership and tranafer (tea 82.00 Withdrawal 129.75 Taxes and insurance premiums repaid 268.20 Loan fee and expense 51.70 Total * 33,080-18 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loana $ 7,444.00 Stock loans 358.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. 15,868.38 Withdrawala, pald-np stock 3.800.(0 Withdrawals, dividends on paid-up atock 528.51 3.800.(10 Salaries 420.00 Commissions . 44.00 Other expense 197..T4 Real estate account . 2,145.73 Cash on hand_ . 2,015.80 Delinquent taxes and Insurance premiums paid 262.42 Total - f 33.080.18 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of asinM**Ht1" n i — - .,,,., Permanent Number of shares Issued since organisation 3,272^4 Number of ahares outstanding laat report 1.719 H Shares issued since last report 514 Total . - 2,233*4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since laat report 374 Number of shares In force thia date 1.859U Number of shares on wblcb dues are delinquent 1S7'4 Number of ahares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 51 Total Number of shares on which dues are delinquent... Number of borrowing stockholders ...___ — Number of non-borrowing stockholders — — 83 52 Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year 7 Par value of each share of stock— S 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at tbla date 1.078.10 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 88P.50 Amount of interest, premiums and fines dues and unpaid 232.80 232.80 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 9 2.3O0.H) Amount of loana on Improved real estate 58.560.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loana have 112.920.00 been made 112.920.00 aunt of loana on unimproved real estate — 385.00 Amount of loana on unimproved real estate- Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loana have been made 910.00 Amount of Are Insurance In force and assigned to the association aa collateral security ________ — _ Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association 70.700.00 its collateral security 89,350.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year . . 277.15 Amount of dividends declared on running atock during year . 4,550.97 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 528.51 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid atock 528.51 during year . 8% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year _ 9.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President .'. Frank Hammond Vice President Frank Fowler Secretary Arthur Truesdell Treasurer Chas. B. Veazie Attorney _ Geo. L. Loomis DIRECTORS Fred Bader Frank Hanlon Fred H. Richards Frank Hammond Arthur Truesdell Chas. B. Veazie Jas. A. Donahue Frank Fowler Geo. L. Loomis ASSETS First mortgage loans. f228.noo.00 Delluiiuent. interest, flues, etc— _ _ 1.6SK.W Furniture and fixtures ITn.OO Other assets - 82&amp;S1 Total-.. f23o. 702.1 i LIABILITIES Runuiug slock and dividends _ _ $197,607.29 Paid-up stock and dividends.- 24.011 10 Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ 1.1X16.80 Reserve fund — _ _ 4,250.011 I'ndiTided profits-. Other liabilities 516.S5 2.68O.S8 Total ,. $280,782.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 49 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RKCEIPT8 Cash on hand last report _ _ $ 1.197.77 Dues &lt; running stock) _ ....„...— 45.117.40 85.117.40 Paid-up stock _ , 5,900.on Mortgage paymentH .,_ 31 ,70i&gt;. tn* Stock loan payments 1.740.110 Interest _ _ 14.8b7.hs Fines , 118..13 Membership and transfer fees - _ 182.00 Other receipts „ 15 Mfl itft Overdraft ..'-'. _ 2.880. S.S 182.00 Overdraft Total »l.*).3S0.71 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ _ _ $ 4!&gt;.noo.i:n Stork loans _ _ 1.740.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dlrldendi MJR.4M Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ : R.275.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 1.4.18.7!) Salaries _ _ 1.050.00 Other expense ~. 1?5.C? Other disbursements _ _ - 25.512.(10 Interest _ 111.KI Stock matured and redeemed _ _ - 24.T.VJ.47 Total. |13!).K0.71 Srrri.EMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial and Permanent Number of series issued since organisation _ „ 46 NumlHT of shares issued since organization _ _ 10,186% Number of shares outstanding last report 2.2SW4 Shares Issued since last report 782&lt;4 Total _ _ _. -. 3.0BOH Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 4M&gt;% Number of shares In force this date _ 2.561V. Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Serial Stock 1l \veraire running time of stock matured dnring t-he year 119 months Number of borrowing stockholders — 184 Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ _. 108 Number of loans made for building purposes dnring year. 17 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ -... 29 Par value of each share o* stock - * 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Serial Stock B4.S0 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 84. SO 84.SO Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1.658.WI Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 8 6.500.'O 1.8W.*0 Amount of loans on improved real estate 228.000.011 \nnralsed value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 342,600.00 Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - 23!).4.1O.m Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - - 19fi.3no.OO Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ TnO.CO Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 12.215.23 litf.Wio.oo Amount of dividends nald on matured and paid-up stock during year 1.436.7!) Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - — _ 5* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year — 7.2% -,"r </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President.- _..- - - T. L. Mathews Vice President - .Ross L. Hammond Secretary. - D. D. Rowe Treasurer _ J T Mav Attorney - - W. J. Courtright DIRECTORS T. L. Mathews Ross L. Hammond E. R. Gurney W. J. Courtright Paul Colson J. T. May Chas. H. Hawley Dan V. Stephens D. D. Rowe ASSETS First mortgage loam $1,708,908.81 Loam Id proceM of foreclosure 5,348.57 Loans on stock or pass book security 3.365.00 Real estate - 24,386. U 3.365.00 Real estate , Real estate sold on contract 4.914.02 Cash , , _ 67.620.07 L1IO i .—. OJ.TkdU.UI Delinquent Interest, lines, etc 5.OSO.U7 Total $1314,o02.t« LIABILITIES Running- stock and dWldends , tl.US.flO6.il Paid-up stock and dlTldends 556,100.00 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 1,100.00 Reserve fond , , 37,000.00 KeserTe iudq ai,uuu.uu Undlrlded profits for July dividend 56,733.00 Interest to corer delinquency 5,060.!rf ToUl HJKUJBK.(X </seg>
            <seg id="p051">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C»«h on hand last report $ 83,120.35 Dues (running stock) 39l[39l!l.1 Paid-up stock 189JO0.00 Mortgage payments.... _ _ 251,'l77.'l2 Stock loan payments . _ __ _, Ml 14 401.06 Real estate sales __ 28!296JV» Interest , , .... "_ _ 139,8Os!37 Fines _. KT^ "W Rents 4s0.no 4w.no Membership and transfer fee* 1 Rao ffi Other receipts , 17,533.00 17'.333i00 Total *i,oee.488.m DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans | 466.492.00 Stock loans. 10.OClO.OI) Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 373.564.M) Withdrawals, paid-up stock 99,700.00 99.700.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up —•'-•- 2!)!si3..V( Salaries B.«73.0"&gt; Commissions „ " 3!4R5!rt2 Other expense „ . 3.289.A0 Real estate account - " 33i936.17 Cash on hand ;._ 87.8.0.07 \ asn on nan a __„ n7.fKU.ui Foreclosure , „_______ 6.501). 1(1 Postage, rent, printing and fees. _ 2.115.02 Examiner's salary and traveling expense 2409!!&gt;ft Incomplete loans. _ „ 4,875.00 Dividend on installment stock 80,297.37 Total V1.096.488.C1 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association . Permanent Number of shares Issued since organisation 103.023 Number of shares of outstanding last report 41,014 Shares Issued since last report 12.147 Total 53,161 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 7.714 Number of shares In force this date 45.447 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 1.260 Average running time of stock matured during the year 96 months Number of borrowing stockholders 1.548 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 2,052 Number of loans made for building purposes during year.. 187 Number of loans msde for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year ,. 312 Par value of each share of stock. .._ $ 100.00 f 100.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 21,072.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 5,080.97 5,080.97 Number and amount ofmortgages subject to foreclosure No. 14 12,600.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure 6 5,348.57 Amount of loans on improved real estate 1,708,906.81 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made : 8,691.774.51 Amount of lire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ - 2,006,112.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security -. 1.906,570.(10 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 9,812.07 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 3.812.07 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 80.297.37 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 29.313.5f) Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8", 1.906.570.(10 80.297.37 29.313.5!) 8", Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year 6ft Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p052">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE ■I STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - - Chas. G. Ryan Vice President _ —.Richard Goehring Secretary - - C. W. Brininger Assistant Secretary John A. Ferguson Treasurer _ S. N. Wolbach Attorney _ _ - - James H. Woolley DIRECTORS R. J. Barr C. B. Norris L. T. Geer R. R. Horth August Kruse Guy L. Harrison ASSETS First mortgage loans _ _ _ JS97.2OD00 Loans In process of foreclosure 2.29&amp;30 Loans on stork or pass book security — _ 2n.3m.O0 Ke»l estate, office- _ 12,000.(10 Cash - _ 10.610.2~&gt; Delinquent interest, flues, etc 844.45 Taxes paid _ _ - 0115.4:; Settlement, balance accounts - _ 3.971.00 Total.. *ft56,7»U3 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend*. *786,N94.SO Paid-up stock and dividends . 128.fl72.GO 129.«72.0O Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ B.OOO.ilO Reserve fund ——_ — - .....__~__. . , 33,750.00 Undivided profits _ 530.4:; Interest paid In advance _ _ M2.no Total 1808,790.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 53 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on linixl last report _ _ _ __ f 9.B46.07 Ones (ruiiniiiv stock I _ 251.714.45 I 'aid-up stork . _ _ _ 14.44XU4r Mortgage payments „ _ _ 100.2*21.(17 Stock loan payments.. :i MM) Interest — 65.7«7.2&lt;p s.ow.irr Fines _ 48o'o.-&gt; Membership and transfer fee*. Membership Mini transfer feed 8.5!) Rent and office building receipts _ _ 420.00 420.no Miscellaneous _ Settlement lialaure amounts _ .■».»» 8.402.78 I lecrees of foreclosure 3.508.00 Tax sale redefine VI7.O7 Total *4.V.t.ini.'Hj nismi SI ME NTS Mortisaire toau Il!&gt;7 &lt;if»&gt; 00 stock loans _... i'mnm Stock loan Withdrawals, running Mock and divtd. 111! 77.B7O.TO Withdrawals. pald-vp stock 59.600.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stuck m.us Salaries 6.75O.0O Other expense 541 JB Heal estate iimrani 477.18 Cash on hand i0.mn.2r, Tax sales purriiaseil !X!lM6 Certificates of indehtednf 32,554.90 Matured shares paid. .Vi.H00.IIO Dividends on paid-up stock. 6.283. 'JO Total fKM'.IIV.'Xt ar ppl em ex I AL nEPORT Plan of association Serial and Permanent Xnniher of series issued since organization Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares outfttflnfftnK hist report... Shares issued since last report 44 ™ 6.4OB Total 31.M9 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report - 'in tvr ___ _.* _i i_ m *_i.. I.. . r ' _ *i-'»» Nuinber of shares in force this date_ °4'718 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent ______ lss 1S.» Average r 1 1 1 1 1 1 i 1 1 ir lime of slock matured during the year ...7...Seriaf 318 weeks Number of borrowing stockholders. .'. 7 1( j Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ _, i o^j Number of loans made for building purposes during year "7,fil Kl Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year.. -:) Par Talue of each share of stock. _ _______ $ 100 00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Serial 71*7*00 7(r7.OO Amount of dues owing hy borrowing stockholders Serial 327*00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid M4 +5 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure !.''*Xo! 1 ] 4MJ0 •127.00 1.4W.50 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 2J_O.-0 Amount of loans on improved real estate ____" MK'.nboluo Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans bare been made 1 707 7v&gt;(io Amount of loans on unimproved real estate. ' 1 ftoo.00 1.7«7.7W).OO Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ „ _ prt Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 1 009 i_n 00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 857.6no.00 eta ' 1'iiiiiri n 1 o-ri 11 1 1, t - »—._.......■■ ..i.. ...—...—, ■■■... 1 ....... . .... SOT On(P IH7 Amount of money loaned on Improved farms. _. _ _______ flO0O(MT Appraised value of land not Including Improvements .."! {&gt;onoi&gt;o Value of Improvements - __ iionoloft Amount of flre Insurance thereon - „ „_ AOO.Oo Amount credited to reserve fund daring year „ _ _ 2 050 00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock daring year. _ 4RO7Tt r»o 4».nrn.r»o Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-op stock during year *\:.^7 •*** Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year " c&gt; d" r TO A t _t *__■» dant *\t i\\'\-\ i\ £*t\ i\ a notH #-n m- ft* »__r1 -ni*l # H 11 n — ! J _.____. Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ _ a*y Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during -«'- 1.1% </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Geo. I. Parker Vice President _ _ J. G. Beste Secretary - F. O. Robinson Treasurer. _ W. S. Weston DIRECTORS Geo. I. Parker Geo. F. Scoville J. G. Beste H. D. Spork W. S. Weston ASSETS First mortgage loans t 96,950.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 1,300.00 C a ,h _ _ 1.300.17 Delinquent interest, dues 33.46 Total * 86.58S.K2 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends » 78,996.20 Paid-up stock and dMdends 7.106.45 7.105.45 Dne shareholders on incomplete loans Z — — 000.00 Reserve fond 1,375.00 Undivided profits 27.22 Dues in advance 477.75 T»U1 » 88,583.«2 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 55 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 208.04 Due* (running stock) 17.974.50 Paid-up stock — 7,000.00 7,000.00 Mortgage payments 7,900.00 Stock loan payments - — 727.96 Interest 7,861.57 Fines 18.80 Membership and transfer fees 206.90 Other receipts ~ 31.87 Money borrowed - - — 4,125.00 Total $ 44,077.5- DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans f 20.550.00 Stock loans _. _ _ _ 1,427.98 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 1,454.54 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 7,600.00 Withdrawals, dividends on paid-up stock 481.44 Salaries 500.00 Other expense. 114.94 Cash on hand 1,300.17 Other disbursements — — — 31.87 Matured stock _ - — _ - 6.500.00 Bills payable and interest 6,116.82 Total $ 46,077.58 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial and Permanent Number of series Issued since organisation __-__—__ 21 Number of shares Issued since organisation-- 4295 4295 Number of shares .outstanding last report 1904 Shares issued since last report 481 Total I 2388 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report , 185 Number of shares In force this date 2200 4gl Number of shares on which dues are delinquent __________ 15 Average running time of stock matured during the year 90 months 15 Number of borrowing stockholders 96 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 146 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 10 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of 1W homestead mortgages during year S Par value of each share of stock , , , s. 100.00 Total amount of dnes delinquent at this date 15.75 3 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders— — 15.75 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _..__ 17.70 Amount of loans on improved real estate , 86,900.00 15.75 17.70 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 175,000.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security—..— 102,800.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association a* collateral security 87.300.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 250.00 250.00 Amount creuitea 10 reserve runa during year .-._—.— ————.. _du.uu Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 6,786.15 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 547.18 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year... 11% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock during year . 9% Bate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HASTINGS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HASTINGS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ _ _ F. L. Pease Vice President _ Wm. M. Lowman Secretary J. O. Rohrer Treasurer J. O. Rohrer Attorney - John Snider DIRECTORS Henry Siekmann Wm. M. Lowman F. L. Pease Geo. H. Pratt H. B. Cornelius Ezra Langevin H. C. Haverly ASSETS First inortfraice loani* _ _ *1!*7. 306.00 Loans in process of foreclosure _ 2.412.66 Loans on stock or pass book security 20,075.00 Cash 6.397.54 Furniture and fixtures ~ 175.00 Taxes paid .. _ _ 62.75 Total _ 9226,428.94 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. Running stock and dividends - *216.268.24 Reserve fund _ 6.205.55 fl.205.55 Undivided profits- — _ 3.955.15 Total—... _ - _ _... I226.42H.M </seg>
            <seg id="p057">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report S 3,511.09 Dues (runtng »tock) _ 40,796.35 Mortgage payments.. _ — _ 44.71fl.OO Stock loan payments. 9 0D0 00 Interest - 15!ot»!77 il.OBO.OU Interest Fines - _ _ _ 145.44 Membership and transfer fees— 92.25 Attorney's fees. _ _.. 100.75 Total *114.340.85 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - * 60.425.00 stock loans 13,:tH5.0u •&lt; 60.425.00 Stock loans Withdrawals, running stock and dividends- _ 15.188.62 Withdrawals, matured stocks- _ — 17.067.16 Salaries - — 1.2S6.0O Other expense _ 201.49 Cash on hand....—— - —— — ......— 6.397.54 Rebates, etc., - — _ 187.09 Taxes paid — - ... 62.75 Rent _ - 1MX00 Total - - - 1114.340.65 SrPPLEMEXTAI. REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 17.955 Number of shares outstanding last report — „ 6,744 Shares Issued since last report- _ 1,500 Total _ — 8,340 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 746 Number of -shares in force this date 7,594 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 80 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of does — — 44 Average running time of stock matured during the year 134 months Number of borowlng stockholders _ 212 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 304 Number of loans made for building purposes and purchasing of home - steads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 58 Par value of each share of stock. $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 220.00 .--1 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders...- _ — 160.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 210.00 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 1 iTiO.oo Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. No. 2... 2.412.65 Amount of loans on improved real estate. 197,306.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made 368,500.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ — 214,400.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security. - _ - 202.600.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ 719 .10 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 12.9wt.8O MMtfcM Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 6.9% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President. _ Samuel Hinkle Vice President _ _ ;. Arch Adams Secretary _ V. F. Hofmann Treasurer Treasurer _ _ _ F. B. Young Attorney _ _ _ _ F. B. Sidles F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS W. F. Ackerman Arch Adams V. F. Hofmann Fred Kroahler F. B. Young Samuel Hinkle C. F. Ballard Geo. W. Anderson E. E. Anderson ASSETS Flrit mortgage lo«n» _ S228.fifiO.00 Loans on stock or pasa book aecnrlty _ 5,170.00 Delinquent Interest, fine*, etc - 1.M7.75 Other assets— ~. — - 1,831-36 Total , .., „ _ (236,600.11 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $159,379.46 Paid-up stock and dividends - — 70.700.00 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 1,088.07 Reserve fund ,, 2,787.75 Other liabilities — _ 11.20 Treasurer _ 2.785.M Total *2S«,«W.ll </seg>
            <seg id="p059">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 59 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ $ 13,967.04 Does (running stock) 37,075.00 Paid-up stock 13.700.00 Mortgage payments 36,000.00 36,000.00 Stock loan paymenta.......* 1,146.00 Interest _ _ 20.118.0S Fines , , 156_0 Membership and transfer feet 1,177.00 Other receipts , 573.50 Overdrafts _ 2,787.75 2.787.75 Total — - - _ |1_7,_».24 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans „_ f 71,300.00 Stock loans " 2JS20l00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 19,023.17 Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ _ 43.000.00 Dividend on paid-up stock 4.232.10 4.232.10 Salariea ' 1,540.00 Commissions „ ____ .„„ 1,033.00 Other expenses — _ _ 408.18 Other disbursements 1.544.73 Dividends credited — 12,500.00 406.18 Dividends credited.. Total __ — $157,288.24 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association .... Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization _.._.__ 5,401 Number of shares outstanding last report. 2,787 Shares lasned since last report 1^13 Total 4.050 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 519 Number of shares In force this dale , , 3531 51!i Number of shares In force this date- Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 158 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues— 5 Average running time of stork matured during year 120 months Number of borrowing stockholders 201 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 382 Number of loana made for building purposes during year 22 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year.. 39 Par value of each share of stork $ 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date .... 14.92 :w Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 14.02 1.647.75 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1,647.75 Amount of loans on improved real estate 228,360.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ... 342,800.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 200.00 Appralaed value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 500.00 Amount of Bre Insurance In force and assigned to the association a* collateral security 230,000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association aa collateral security 230,000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 908.40 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 10.50 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 14.884.19 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 5,232.50 Bate per cent of dividends declared on running stocks during year— *% 14.884.19 &lt;Kh Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock V*e during year •% Rale of per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 9.90% </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOOPER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ ...._ John F. Heine Vice President _ B. Monnich Secretary Geo. W. Heine Treasurer.... — _ Jacob Sanders Attorney _ Wm. Meyer DIRECTORS H. J. Vlasak R. L. Schwat B. Monnich Wm. Meyer Joe Stipsky A. M. Tillman Geo. W. Heine Jacob Kusch John F. Heine Jacob Sanders ASSETS FirRt mortgage luan* _ _ t 17.500.UO Cash „ ~ 570.47 Furniture and fixture*. _ - 40.00 Other assets, account _ _ 72.20 Total $ 18.18E.S7 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends I 17.411.41 Reserve Pn nA , — 7T1.2C Total $ 18,182.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 61 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _.._ _ $ 72.38 Dues (running stock)— _ - 2,663.00 Mortgage payments 1,400.00 interest ZZ.....'.'.' i.3M:M Fines _ _ _ 43.9D Membership and transfer fees _ 18.00 Total $ 5,501.57 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. - 3,100.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. 7O&amp;5O Salaries - 100.00 Other expense 22 .80 Cash on hand 570.47 Bills payable - — l.OOaoo Total ♦ 5,501.57 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 1,0*5 Number of shares outstanding last report - 197 Shares Issued since last report — — 34 Total .. — - — 231 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since laat report '.' ■»" Number of shares in force this date - — 222 Average running I line of stock matured during year 130 months Number of borrowing stockholders 16 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 48 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year ,_—._» Par value nf each share of stoc ♦ 200.00 Par value nf each share of stc Amount of loans on Improved real estate - 17.500.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made *. r- 33,530.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 18.275.00 Amount at tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association us collateral security..- 1S.275.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year JK-9 0 , Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year- 1&gt;2 I^?? Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year f"S^ Bate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year - 7.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President. _ _ _ L. S. Hackett Vice President _ _ _ Otto Kotouc Secretary _ _ H. E. Boyd Treasurer _ _ Irvin Shirley DIRECTORS F. R. Butterfield N. C. Campbell B. Stramer H. E. Boyd J. B. Davis Irvin Shirley E. S. Cope L. S. Hackett Otto Kotouc ASSETS First mortgage loans _ _... S 43,851. OB Loana In process of foreclosure * 200.00 Loans on slock or pass book security 2,561.45 200.00 Otter real estate _ __ _ 1.000.00 Cash _ _ 1,084.47 Total ., _ $ 49,107.57 LIABILITIES Banning; stock and dividends. Running stock and dividends S 35.162.15 Paid-up stock and dividend* 13.268.61 13.268.61 Reserve fund.. , _ 653.67 Undivided profits 23.14 Total— $ 49,107.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 63 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report S 88.99 Dues (running stock) 13.S06.89 Mortgage payments 17.S80.00 17.S9O.0O Stock loan payment! 3,525.90 Real estate sales. 1.35O.00 Interest 5,607.88 Membership and transfer fee* 60.05 Total I 41.710.81 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans f 8,371.«5 Stock loans ~ _ 3,796.45 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 8,087.50 Withdrawals, paid-up stock „ 17,860.00 Salaries , 900.00 Other expense 166.11 8,087.50 Cash on hand 1,084.47 Interest paid on pald-np stocks 734.43 Total $ 41,710.61 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Number of series Issued since organisation 23 Number of shares issued since organisation 4.221 Number of shares outstanding last report 1,407% Shares issued since last report 247 Total 1.854% Share*?' withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 436 ty Number of shares in force this date 1,218 Average running time of stock matured during year 310 weeks Shares, withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. Number of borrowing stockholders — 62 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — : 67 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 10 Par value of each share of stock . . f 100.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders....- 1.227.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 615.50 10 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure, No. 1 200.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 43.071.66 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made — —.—-—. _—~ ~— — — -— —— — — — ... 88,150.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 780.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made... _„.. — — — — - — • 1,610.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association collateral security — — - 56,400.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security i S4 -2£S°, Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2 £ri£ Amount creaiteo to reserve runa nunng year 'r'^SX Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 150.00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 4,016.78 Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the KEARNEY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KEARNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President S. A. D. Henline Vice President _ John W. Patterson Secretary and Treasurer...- „ Willard F. Bailey Attorney John N. Dryden DIRECTORS S. A. D. Henline John N. Dryden N. P. McDonald John W. Patterson Willard F. Bailey Gilbert E. Haase J. E. Plank J. E. Plank ASSETS Fir«t mortgage lo«n» t 35,l(io.no Cash — - 15.ti&lt;13.02 Other assets.. - - 184.27 Total.. « 5O.XK7.29 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ _. $ 31.fttS.4O 1'nid-up stock and dividends _... 18.a».00 Reserve fond _ _...".."". ... 242.35 Tndivided profit*... Other liabilities iHfl.71 86.83 Total t 50.887.2* </seg>
            <seg id="p065">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 65 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 Caih ou band last report _ _ _. $ 2,005.63 Due*, (running stock)..... __ 17,ll&gt;a64 Paid -up stock 12.425.00 Mortgage payments . „„.«____ 2,600.00 Interest 2.741.33 Fines „ _ _ 7.80 Loan fee surplus , 42.48 Total _ $ ?&lt;J.SKa.88 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loaus. _ _. $ 13,7(10.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividend* _ _. 1.7M.M Withdrawals, paid-up stock 4,850.00 Withdrawals, dividend un paid-up dork 722.02 &lt; illusions _ 1(3.67 Other expenses * 1 "* t _'T Cash ou band l."&gt;,(103.O2 Total - _ t 36.a22.8ti SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 2,163 Shares issued since last report 7S0 % Number of shares outstanding last report — 1250% Total 2,001 2,163 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 317 Nuiulier of shares in force this date. 1.684 Numlier of sbnres which dues are delinquent — 250 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues.... 100 NuuiImt of borrowing stockholders. 33 .Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 118 Xuuit&gt;er of loans made for building purposes during year * 2 Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year — Par value of each share of stock - - ♦ WO.oo Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 1JSII0JM Amount &lt;f dues owing by borrowing stockholders — 350.0J Amount of Interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 37(1.00 Niimlier aud amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 2 2,. r i(»).0O Amount of loans ou Improved real estate - — 35,100.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ - 7O.4«"jO.0O Amount of flre insurance in force aud assigned to the association as collateral security _ — — 35.100.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 32,l&lt;l0.(10 Amount credited to resrve fund during year _ J!?"2P Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.604.S» Mnoiint of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 722.02 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... 7.«6% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dnriiiu vear _ - - °% during year _ _ - ,,22' Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year K.OVfe </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT • of the condition of the LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - - - J. B. Felber Vice President _ C. F. Furley Secretary and Treasurer _ Guy Wilson Attorney - E. P. Voter DIRECTORS J. B. Felber C. E. Nevin Guy Wilson C. F. Furley C. C. Sackett W. T. Graham E. P. Voter AS8BTS First mortgage loans _ - $ 36,850.00 Ca»h _ _ _ 808.56 Delinquent Interest, line*, etc 174.10 Total - - $ KJBUJtt LIABILITIES Banning stock and divldeuds - - * 30,572.08 Reserve fund r. _ 820.36 Undivided pHULT _ - 1.370.21 Bills payable .._„..'.'..' 5,070.00 Total - '. — ♦ 37,832.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">SECRETAKY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 67 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 2,947.16 Due. (running stock) 10.13475 Mortgage payment* 1 2,644.24 2,644.24 I nterest and premium __. __ 3,256.84 Fines . ' s.9o Membership and transfer fees 90.75 Bills payable 6.670.00 Total f 25.752.63 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans- f 16,750.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dlTidends 806.63 Withdrawals, paid-op stock _ 5,610.04 Salaries _ 100.00 Other expenses. ............_. ........................... __. 77.41 Caah on hand-. 808.56 808.55 Bills payable 1,600.00 Total f 2S.75Z.63 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ __. - Serial Number of series issued since organisation , 14 Number of shares Issued since organization 1,943 Number of shares outstanding last report _ 88ft Shares Issued since last report _ 396 Total 1,226 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 130 Number of snares In force this date — - 1,075 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent-. 31 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues — 15 Average running time of stock matured during year *- months Number of borrowing stockholders — 3D Number of non-borrowing stockholders 70 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 7 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year • Par value of t_eb share of stock — V !•*).*• **ar Taiue oi t-acn snare oi siuck * — w mww.ww Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 139.50 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders .........._ 139.50 Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due snd unpaid ,, 174.10 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 1 1,500.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 36,850.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been mm( l e _ ; 82,100.00 Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral vwnrity . 48,928.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association 44,926 00 as collateral * a^w-i^y , , , , , 44,925.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 141.79 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 2,824.44 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year •% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year — 4V4% </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN . ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Homer K. Burket Vice President John Gibson Secretary M. W. Folsom Treasurer T. N. Burket Manager of Agencies E. P. Leonard Auditor J. A. Piper DIRECTORS Homer K. Burket John Gibson M. W. Folsom N. T. Burket E. P. Leonard ASSETS First mortgage loans f "J.172.749.89 Loans In process of foreclosure _ 87,960.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ _ _ 7.630.00 Other real estate- - — _ HO, 445.48 Real estate sold on contract _ 51.253.87 Cash - 173,170.20 Office building, furniture and fixtures 17.820.16 Total - - $3,f»1.019.46 LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends. _ $2. 101, 4*1.42 Paid-up stock 1,201.254.24 Reserve fund - - 10T,TOC2T Undivided profits to pay July 1»16 dividends : 140,571.53 Total _ _ BJi&amp;l,019.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 69 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report $292 190 56 Dne« (running stock) __ _ .-. _ 790.2(»t.68 790.2(»t.68 Paid-up stock _ "__ 256,653.49 MortgHge payments 734.WJ5.73 8took loan pay menu _._„.. 5,5M0.0O Rent estate sales. 20905.82 5,590.00 Interest „ 288,*8H_.4_ Real estate.. __ _ 87.23-167 Fines and transfer fee* _ _ 1.0-3.76 Rents of real estate — _ I.IMBU Rents and ofllce building receipts 480.00 480.00 Reserve fund _!....'.'_ 30.025!3» Bills receivable _ _ 100.110 Total _ _ _ $2,48-. 424.81) DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans „__ $1,113,384.79 Stock loans _ _ :i.s.~xi.m Undivided profit a, dividends credited to running stock 143.266.00 Withdrawal*, running stock and dividends 6SS.791.42 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 167.94K2K Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 67,618.46 Undivided profits, reserve fund _ _ -6,000.00 Salaries _ _ yi.ftfi flff Commissions - _ — : 8,681.00 Other expense ' 7.8KN.72 Real estate account 73,566.90 Cash on hand _ _ 173.17O.2tt Taxes on office building ... — . .. 310.06 Reserve fuud _ 1,810.00 Office building and furniture 147.50 Real estate sold „ _ "j:&gt; MU- Total - ~ _ _ _ $2,4*42,424.80 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization j. 289.048 Number of shares outstanding last report V3.-48 Shares Issued since last report JUM Total - - - — - 109,512 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report - 16.410 Number of shares in force this date 93.102 Average runutng time of stock matured during year 117 months Xuniner of borrowing stockholders...- 2.784 Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ 4.916 Number of loans made for building purposes during year _ 366 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of nomestend mortgages during year 426 value of each share of stock $ 100.00 4-J.i Par value of each share of stock Amount of Interest and fines due and unpaid _ 11.!I64.N!) Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 35 31.800.00 11.H64.N!) Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 35.. Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure, No. 49-... 67,950.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ -. 3,172.749.69 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 8,733.110.00 Amouut of fire and tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 5,li*o.~Titt.fl0 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 20.025.3U Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 1,810.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 14.1,256.09 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during IT7.filS.4V, year - - (T7.ills.4t; Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7% Rate per ceut of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during vear _ _ .._...... 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8*4% </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AMERICAN SAVING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President... „ _ W. A. Selleck Vice President _.._ E. W. Brown Secretary _ _ E. F. Snavely Treasurer E. F. Snavely Attorneys .....Burkett, Wilson A Brown DIRECTORS W. A. Selleck E. F. Snavely C. J. Olson E. W. Brown L. C. Oberlies J. H. McClay John T. Dorgan ASSETS First mortgage loans ......._...__.. — 9241,085.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 175.00 Cash 21.185.35 Delinquent Interest, flue*, etc - 660.40 Taxes paid ........ _......~~....... ™. _ 772.00 Total $2*13,817. 76 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends f 88.588.52 Paid-up stock and dividends „ _.... lfl7.0S5.00 167.06S.00 Doe shareholders on Incomplete loans 5,394.19 Reserve fund _ ,, , 1,657.24 Undivided. pronts..._ 78.43 General fund _ . 1.043.37 79.43 General fund — Total $263,817.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 71 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report " g so8O7_ Doe- (running stock) 1 * ai!517» Paid-up stock! ' _ XWOM 66.100.00 Mortgage payments _________________ 51, '900.00 Stock loan payments 50.00 Real estate sales ._"______I..__ _ Z_ 137.77 Interest „ _ IS oiVvi Furniture and fixtures __________________ 167 04 Interest due . 150 m 152.80 Reserve R2OJM Membership and transfer fees __________ 1, 429^46 Taxes _ '3OO.S8 Undivided profits 3 ioi' - *o Total _ $200,503.87 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $126.138 31 Stock loans _ LM— 9 Mortgage loans.. 125.00 Withdrawals, ruuuing stock and dividends _ .. . _ .. 58,134 05 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 30.3O5.U0 30,305.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock _ _\379.59 Salaries _ 580.00 580.00 Interest due_ .... _______ 550!_0 Undivided profits Cash on hand.. „_ ____ 6.446.1M 21.185.35 Taxes .............. 1,046.29 General fund 3,308.14 Total _ _ 1280,503 87 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plau of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation. 17,411.05 Number of shares outstanding last report 4.618.60 Shares issued since last report ... .3.122 Total 7,740.60 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 840.05 Number of shares in force this date 7,100.55 Number of borrowing stockholders 143 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 455 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 9 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of 27 homestead mortgages during year _____...._.....___...__.......... 27 Par value of each share of stock ♦ 100.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 660.40 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 4 4.700.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 229,775.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana have been made — 559,700.00 11.260.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate ADDraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — — 29,550.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 280.58B.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security. — 171,186.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year S2J5 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4.815.98 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 11,984.93 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock 6"r during year — —-■ J* e Der cent of interest charged borrowera during year 7.2% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 72 STATEMENT of the condition of the LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ E. W. Brown Vice President .H. H. Wilson Secretary _ _ _ E. F. Snavely Treasurer _ Frank Parks Attorney _ E. W. Brown DIRECTORS E. W. Brown Chas. Olson Frank Parks H. H. Wilson E. C. Hurd E. F. Snavely L. C. Oberlies ASSETS First mort(t»(te loans _ *."&gt;S3,j50.00 Loans In process of foreclosure _ _ lli.nn.fln Loans on stork or pass hook security 1.255.00 Other real estate, _ 2tt.129.37 Heal estate sold on contract _ 1&gt;&lt;.386.26 Cash on hand - — . - 2.793.36 Delinquent interest, lines, etc _ 10.520.17 Furnlture and fixtures (lfil.30 Taxes paid 1.847.38 other assets „ _ _ _ 1.987.16 Bank certificate of deposit _ _ 2!&gt;..TO0.00 Bonds - 1O.062.72 Total. _ 'x70n.7ilo.56 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends 1320,588.42 Paid-up stock and dividends 356.670.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 10.006.50 Reserve fund _ _ K.304.83 t'ndlvided profits _ 11.88 Overdraft _ - _ __ 10.213.93 10.213.93 Total _ I705.PJS.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band Imwt report - _ _ $ 3H.651.90 Dues &lt; running stock) _ 166.800.90 Paid-up stock _ S5.725.O0 Mortgage payments. _ 145,136.73 Stock loan payments — ............ 711.00 Real estate sales account - _ _ 12,216.07 Contract - - - — - 4.303.37 Interest _ 47.963.39 Taxes - 2,126.22 Fines 25.60 Abstract fees - - _ 1.130.00 2.126.22 Abstract fee MemlMTship fees - - 2.679.10 Expense __ 6,233.10 Other receipts in detail. 7,622.21 Furniture aud fixtures „_ _ 1.100.00 Reserve - - 3,212.01) Certificate 'of &lt;le|H&gt;8it - 10.nOO.UO Overdraft _ _ &lt; - 7,430.87 Total »544.(I67.28 Total D18BIKSEMENTS Mortgage loans l212.K2.Min 1,466.00 116.230.02 Stock loans Withdrawals, running stock aud dtvideu la Withdrawals, paid-up stock 91.400.U0 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 29,771.74 4.798.00 Salaries Fees 308.25 Commissions 876.93 700.(10 Abstracts 16,812.14 Other expense 18.835.St Real estate account Real estate contract 13.998.«l 3.804.98 Other disbursement Delinquent Interest 3.205.40 2,626.55 Taxes Furniture and fixturei 745.03 16.500.00 Certificates of deposit. Bonds 10,062.72 *544.067.20 Total. AL REPORT _ Permanent SUPPLEMENT Plan of association Number of shares issued since organization 43,316.99 Number of shares outstanding last report- - 1S.TJ1.4S 15.721.45 Shares issued since last report - 8,784.25 Total - - — 24,505.70 Total Stares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report o™ 9 !? 19,597.70 Number of shares in force this date_ - _ Wfim.TO N'unilwr of borrowiiiK stockholders — **■ Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-horroing stockhoiders Number of loans made for building purposes during year...... 38 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year ~JS value of each share of stock » 100.00 l(il Par value of each share of stock.. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - 315J-JS Amount of interest, premiums and fines due aud unpaid .JM5H 0 , Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 88. 128.250.00 100.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. No. 12 19,000.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 433.XOO.OO Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loan* have been 816.700.00 ■^j e _ - 816. 700.00 mount of loans on unimproved real estate .... . 1,500.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans haTe ,™,w, been made 3,000.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 676.010.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force aud assigned to the association ,««„» as collateral security ,\',t!;™ as collateral mrvui hj iitinn Amount credited to reserve fund during year . oS'Suwi 28.8SO.0S Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year- 2s.S5li.0R Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during mm** year - - --- . . . .- — ' ■ a&gt;&gt;771 oL* Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year..- Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock tm e per ceui ui iimuriiu» |pmu vu u»«iu»™ .».,,, kH . a — . — during year — — — - Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9* </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President L. C. Oberlies Vice President _ _ John T. Dorgan Secretary and Treasurer _ _ _ E. F. Snavely Attorney _ _ _ _ _ E. W. Brown DIRECTORS i L. C. Oberlies W. A. Selleck John T. Dorgan E. W. Brown J. H. McClay ASSETS First mortgage loans _ $275,7*1.23 Loans in process of foreclosure *. 6.3OO.0O Loans on stock or pass book security _ _ 1.185.00 Other real estate 40.70ft.57 1.185.00 Other real estate.. Real estate sold on contract _ _ 11.539.83 Cash _ 11.168.99 Delinquent interest, lines, etc Furniture and fixtures lo.sS0.14 300.00 Bank certificate of deposit _ _ _ _ _ .~i.oon.flO Taxes paid _ 1,815.86 Bills receivable _ 731.00 Bonds 5.026.87 Office lease _ 1.375.00 Total _ _... $371,746.48 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends.. - - _ $227,643.10 Paid-up stock and dividends 136.310.00 Reserve fund _ _ _ 8,721.87 Undivided profits. 71.51 Total. $371,746.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 75 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 43.03S.M Dnea (running stock) _ „ ab.H6S.85 Paid-up stock 2,850.00 2,660.00 Mortgage payments 70,725.00 Stock loan payments _ 380.00 Real estate sales _ 9,888.11 Interest ! 28.10S.40 Taxes , 254.40 Reserve ,. 1,108.17 General fund 237.06 Undivided profits 6.195.24 Delinquent interest 2,994.98 Real estate on contract 2.'.t^.li4 Total _ _ *237,454.45 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans f 6,644.23 Stock loans ■ _ 150.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 114.284.42 Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ 43,515.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 14.658.70 Salaries _ „ _ 3.725.00 Reserve 278.84 General fund— U.576.M Real estate account 17.126JS7 Real estate contract — 3,616.87 Cash on hand - 11,168.99 U.576.M Rents 631.00 S. D. bonds 5,026.00 Bank certificate of deposit _ 5.000.110 631.00 Bank certificate of deposit Taxes 1,753.16 Furniture "and fixtures — 300.00 Tota l _ _ _ $237,454.45 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report ft.864.75 Shares issued since last report 132.50 Total __ 9,987.25 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 2.017.15 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Number of shares' in force this date — _ 7,970.10 Number of borrowing stockholders 32S Number of non-borrowing stockholders . 456 Par value of each share of stock t 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid .. 9,509.27 Par value of each share of stock- 9.609.27 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 82 95,600.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 4 6,300.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate. — 281,034.23 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ * 86 -ZS 0 .- 00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate- - 1,000.00 Appraised vnlue of unimproved real estate upon which loans have 6,000.00 knpn Tt\ ft {1 Q ■ ■■■&gt; I iiiii ■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ ■■! I Amount of fire "insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 406,800.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association „-„„-„ as collateral security 19 ?-JS?*? Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1,108.37 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 23,195.45 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during ,.„,»„, 14,010.26 vear h.uiu.jo Rate per cent of "dividends declared on running stock during year 6% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year — __ ..._„.._ - &lt;■ • Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ Albert W. Miller Vice President _ _ W. B. Ryons Secretary.— _ _...Loyd A. Winship Treasurer _ _ „ L. J. Dunn Attorney John M. Stewart DIRECTORS Albert W. Miller W. B. Ryons Loyd A. Winship L. J. Dunn John M. Stewart ASSETS First mortgage loans - _ _ $605,800.00 Loans In process of foreclosure _.. 3,11)0.00 Loans on stock or pass book security. _ _ 2,502.95 Other real estate _. 1MMJ] Real estate sold on contract - _ _ _.. 3,911.24 Certldcates of deposit _ - 78.316.00 Cash 22,296.36 Delinquent interest, fines, etc a.cM5.52 Interest due on certificate of deposit _ — ~m.*s Furniture and fixtures _ 1.ST3.31 Taxes paid - ~ 1 2,111.8$ Other assets. _ _ _ 8,673.75 Total - , $740,527.56 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ $242,243.03 Paid-up stock and dividends. :....- _ _ _ 408,025.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 80.884.27 Reserve fund 8,060.00 Undivided profits 7,545.26 Total- $746,527.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 77 HECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C»gb on band last report f 14,592.78 I)ue« (running stock! 142,578.81 Paid-up stock. „ 193,900.00 Mortgage payments 176,825.00* Stork loan payments _ 14,777.00 Real estate sales __ 10,456.14 Interest 47,233.44 Fine* 341.40 Rents _ _ _ 287.76 -•87.76 Bills receivable _ _ _ _ 125.00 Certificates of deposit _ 43,884.58 Tax certificates and insurance 2,051.66 Totals _ _ $646,853.08 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans.- ...—....... (254,660.38 Stork loans.—. 12,027.95 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. 112.417.06 Withdrawing', paid up stock _ 133.275.00 Withdrawals, dtvldeud on paid-up stock _ 22.459.65 Salaries _ — 4.7OO.OO Commissions _ 47.58 Other expenses. _ 5,508.74 Bills receivable 50.00 Real estate account _ - - 17.229.73 Cash on band — 22,296.38 Certificates of deposit 55,019.33 Tax certificates and insurance advanced _ 2.!*SS.80 Rent 940.00 Furniture and fixtures- _ 262.30 Totals — *64S,SM.66 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation _ 42.403.95 Number of shares outstanding last report- 15,522.75 Shares issued since last report _ _ 7.087 Total - 22.819.75 Shares withdrawn, matured or' cancelled since last report 3,417.75 7.OB7 3,417.75 Number of shares in force this date. _ 19.202 Number of borrowing stockholders. _ - - 557 Niiinlier of non-borrowing stockholders 1.786 Number of loans made for building purposes during year .— 103 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 106 Par value of each share of stock - I 100.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid- 3,776.00 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 11 16,200.00 3.T76.OO Number and ninount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. No. 2 .'{.100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate. 603,800.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana have Iwen made - 1.133.600.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 1,800.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - 3,800.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 610,885.00 Amount of tornado lnsuarnce in force and assigned to the association (s collateral security - - - - - 522,570.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2.&lt;K"K.0t&gt; Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 12.W4.17 12.SI4.17 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock daring y elr 22,458.05 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock •ft during year _ 8% Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIDELITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ W. A. Forsyth Vice President _ Fred D. Mason Secretary _ W. J. Hill Treasurer _ _ _ _...H. B. Treat Attorney Fred D. Mason DIRECTORS W. A. Forsyth H. B. Treat Thos. H. Mauck Fred D. Mason J. G. Harnung W. J. Hill Chas. E. Bardwell ASSETS Flr»t mortgage loans. $120,400.00 Other real estate _ _ - 10,711.68 Heal estate sold on contract — - - 700.00 Cash _._. _ 7.339.20 Delinquent interpst. fines, etc. Furniture and fixtures...-'. - — - iSS'S? Other assets- 885.71 Total $141,417.5 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ «|.l 91 " Paid-up atock and UlUmU _T - W.4BMP Dne shareholders on incomplete loans- — — 38G.9O Reserve tnnd__ -&gt;______-______ 1.18400 Undivided profit*- ____ - - - 3.222.50 Tottl - ._ - $141,417.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C*»b on band l«»t report — f 2.P99.39 viiu uu uhiiu ibbl gvyvi ■mini i. ■»■ — —.„..—.„..._....-.._...-„. .__.._ _„„. y A,rtnr.oo Dues (running *t&lt;M*k) ,,,. „ „ 29,535.97 Pald-np stock 29,856.81 Mortgage payments 16,630.88 Interest , 8,631.86 Rents . - - - 300.00 Membership and transfer fees S8.00 Other receipts —. f.l I.LIj Total... * 88,568057 DISBURSEMENTS Mori-gage loans _ _ $ 3JS.736.86 Withdrawals, running stock snd dividends _ 26,S4«.48 12,880.00 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 12,880.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stocks 3.885.54 Salaries 1,020.00 Commissions - 51.50 Other expense 1,303.99 Cash on hand 7.339.20 51JS0 Cash on hand Total - $ 88,563 57 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 8,012 Number of shares outstanding last report _ 4,165% Shares issued since last report 1088 Total 5,231* Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled alnce last report _ 664 Number of shares in force this date — 4.565H Number of shares on which do** are delinquent _ 341 Number of borrowing stockholders 60 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 348 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 8 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year . 8 Par value of each share of stock - I 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 1,029.00 9 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders ....... _ l.rtin.OO Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid .'. (Wn.98 Number and amount of mortgages Ruhject to foreclosure. No.5 11.300.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ _ — 120,400.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 210,225.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 127.000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - _ 75.450.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ Ill 00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3,990.28 75.450.00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 4.278.59 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year S% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year .". - ~ JJJ Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p080">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 80 STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ Wm. Seelenfreund Vice President Frank E. Gillen Secretary _ _ F. B. Sidles Treasurer Fred Whittemore Attorney _ _ _ _ _ F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS H. E. Sidles F. B. Sidles Wm. Seelenfreund Frank E. Gillen Fred Whittemore ASSETS Flmt mortgage loan* _ $421,770.00 Loans in process of foreclosure _..„... 12,300.00 Loan* on stock or pass book security 1. 100.00 Other real estate— __ 1,053.38 Cash - — Si.i:a..V) Pur nit u re and fixtures _ _ a r&lt;m.tl2 Taxes paid 718.53 Total - $519,660.04 LIABILITIES Running stock «nd dividends _ $262,976.49 Paid-up stock and dividends _ 252,550.00 Reserve fund - 3,8f»9.31 Undivided profits 283.24 Total - $619,(169.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 81 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report Dues (running stock) _ * 74.553.78 i_t_w7.&lt;i Paid-up stork.. S8.75O.00 Mortgage payments 73.925.00 Stock loan payments. sj"ji'&lt;i, Heal estate sales _________________ __ 177146 In""** - 37:iH4&gt;l Pines _ _ __ 18S8B Memfiership and transfer fee* 1 41050 Taxes „ _ 635 11 635.11 Total „ $384,223 dtl DISBURSEMENTS Total „ $384,223 99 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ $128,100.00 Mortgage loans _. $128,100.00 Stock loans..... _ 45001* Stock loans..._ _ „ _ '4.^/00 Withdrawals, running stork and dividends ri.-l.,'.,. 430.00 Withdrawals, running stork and dividends _______ MJMJ. Withdrawals, paid-up stork _ Withdrawals, dividend on pald-np stock Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ _ __ " 85 525 00 85.525.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock _ 15181 40 15.161.40 Salaries , — .:. tUMKXOO Salaries tUMM.OO Commissions _ j 41050 Commissions 1.410.50 Other expenses _ _ 93015 Other expenses _ _ _____________ 930.15 Real estate aeeoount - _ o g_4g4 Real estate arcrount 2.824.84 Cash on hand _ ____ sjjri-hii Cash on hand. S2.132.5O Furniture and fixtures... „ 2HK7 Furniture and fixtures. Taxes — IjBjj Total ........... _9&amp;i 99? 00 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association... l'lan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 37 844 Number of shares outstanding last report -$13 41914 Shares issued since last report " • Vkw'2 Total _ jt ]m]:1 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report __ _... 2^3562 Total 2.35614 Number of shares In force this date _ _____ 14 745% Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _____ ' 8eS m Number of borrowing stockholders nt \uinl&gt;er of non-borrowing stockholders 1,235 Number of loans made for building purposes during TTlr Number of loans made for purchasing of homestead or payment of homestead mortjritKes during year nouiextenu nioriKMK'eK iiiirin_ yenr 50 Par value of each share of stock $ 100 00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ 10X51 45 Par value of each share of stock... 10.ft51.45 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders.. Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 10 96145 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid. _____ 4!3U6!96 4,305.96 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 6 12.30o!oo Amount of loans on improved real estate !.„ 430920*00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans nave been made _ 749.095.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate ________________ 3 150.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made.... M..-000 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association aa collateral security _ 491,050.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 574.055.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year. Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1459 31 Amount of dividends declared on running stork during year.. • 15,088'si 15.088.81 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year jij jjj Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% M Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year „__ „. 5&lt;?t Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year ". ". »% </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ H. T. Wilson Vice President _ _ „ _..J. Y. M. Swigart Secretary _ Frank Mills Treasurer.— _ _ _ _ _ E. E. Butler Attorney — J. A. Brown DIRECTORS H. T. Wilson Frank Mills G3orge Hager J. A. Brown E. E. Butler J. Y. M. Swigart R. E. Harrington ASSETS First mortgage loam _ f 39,800.00 Cash .. _ 461.87 Delinquent interest, fines, etc... _ 310.60 Furniture and fixtures - 111.35 111.35 Total ( 40,683.82 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends | 10.021.90 Paid-up stock and dividends- 30,290.00 Reserve fund _ - 107.85 Undivided profits _ _ 304.07 304.07 Total f 40,683.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 83 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report f 1.180.78 Dues (running stock) _ 6,842.74 6.842.74 Paid-up stock ., — -». _, / 20,020.00 Interest _ / — ' 2,476.06 Membership and transfer fees _ j 750.96 Total I 31.270.56 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* _ $ 16.251.28 Withdrawals, running stock and dividend* 2.237.56 Withdrawals^ paid-up stock -_ 9,800.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock. _ _ _ 1,283.96 313.50 Salaries _ _ 313.50 Commissions - , _~___— »_«~~_ 664.49 Other expense 80.00 Other expense vrner expense ,. - /nt.\*i Cash on hand ...- ..... .... - — ,.. 461.87 Other disbursements - 177.91 Total _ - - —. * 31,270.56 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association- Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 1908.5 Number of shares outstanding last report 1047.5 Shares issued since last report 861 Total 1908.5 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 231 Number of shares In force this date 1677.5 Number of borrowing stockholders _ ____.- — 52 Number of non-borrowing stockholders i 161 Number of loans made for building purposes during year- Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 14 Par value of each share of stock- ♦ 100.00 14 far value oi encn snare or stock.. ♦ ±w.w Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 310.60 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 1 1.2(&lt;t.OO .Number and amount or moriKasjes sunjeci 10 mrwimun:, i^u. i.~~_ i.-i«M«r Amount of loans on improved real estate...- 39,800.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made 108,885.00 been made _ juo.ooo.uu Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 51.190.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association * as collateral security _ - 51.190.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year — - 9O.K2 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 533.03 90.82 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year- Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during \'c;i f ...„_„_.««__-.__■- —.....— 1,2S3.h6 Rate per cent of "dividends declared on running stock during year.... 8?» Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock M during year ■ ■■ 6% Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MIDWEST SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ _ Julius Reusch Vice President _ _ Henry P. Wekesser Secretary _ _.._ _ _.._ _.._ _ J. J. Stroh Treasurer...- _ _ Nicholas Ress Attorney _ _ _ F. A. Boehmer DIRECTORS Julius Reusch Nicholas Ress Mathias Wagner Henry P. Wekesser J. J. Stroh F. A. Boehmer Adolph Lei Adolph Lebsack, Jr. ASSETS First mortgage loans „ _ $ 31,175.00 C»»b _ 5.283.49 Total ♦ 36,438.49 LIABILITIES Rnnning stock and dividend* _ $ 2,543.10 Paid up stock and dividends _ _ _ _.. 31i.liOO.OO Doe to shareholders on incomplete loans 1.322.00 Undivided profits - 510.89 Prepaid stock _ _ _ 62.50 Total * 36,438.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 85 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1816 RECEIPTS Dne», (running stock) f 2,088.10 Paid-up stock 38.500.00 38.S0O.0O Mortgage payments. 100.00 Interest 549.SS Membership and transfer fees 28.00 Prepaid stock 82.50 Total t 41,925.49 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ $ 29.953.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ 145.00 Withdrawals, pald-np stock '. '„ 6.5Ooloo Commissions „__„ 25.00 25.00 Cash on hand. - « 5,263.49 Orher disbursement* ' 38.00 Total ~ - _ f 41,925.49 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization 1114*4 Shares issued since last report . 1114*4 Total _ — 1114*4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 136 Number of shares in force this date. — — 978*4 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent ft Number of borrowing stockholders _ 22 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 54 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Par Talue of each share of stock — $ 100.00 7 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 54.60 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 48.60 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid -.. 21.35 Amount of loans on improved real estate — 31.175.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made T — 66,250.00 Amount of fire insurance in ' force and assigned to the association as collateral security _... M.02S.0O Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security _ _ 31.206.00 Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers dnrlng year. 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p086">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 86 STATEMENT of the condition of the McCOOK CO-OPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION McCOOK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ _ _ _ John E. Kelley Vice President - _.._ _ J. A. Wilcox Secretary _ _ _ _...F. A. Pennell Treasurer _ _ _ L. Thorgrimson DIRECTORS John E. Kelley J. A. Wilcox H. P. Waite F. M. Kimmel C. J. O'Brien L. W. McConnell W. B. Mills C. L. Fahnestock M. Lawritson ASSETS First mortgage loans »193,0B5.0O Loans in process of foreclosure _ j.iti.'i.SN Loans on stock or pass book security- j.muou Other real estate. _... Cash 1W4.37 13.326.88 Delinquent Interest 22.50 Taxes paid 515.87 Delinquent assessments _ 15.00 Expenses paid 199.50 Interest paid on matured stock . 5.83 Total $212,430.81 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ (190.288.58 Reserve fnnd „ 6.924.76 Undivided profits _ _ 6,178.47 Advance dues . „ 39.00 Total _ _.'. $212,430.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 87 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cub on band laat report _ ._ .___ s 9,366.81 Doe* (running «tock) 38.433.30 38.433.50 Mortgage payments 46.750.00 Stock loan payments 5,80.00 4fi.TSO.00 Real estate sales 1,087.54 I merest _ ,._ 18.108.2S Premium ........_ 1,029.70 1.029.70 Fines , 90.14 Rents from real estate 170.00 Membership and transfer fees. 81.86 Ta_ sale redemptions 668.14 Recelred In loans and foreclosures __ 329.30 81.SS Received In loans and foreclosures. Total $120. 739. S3 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. S 46.700.00 Stock loans _ - „ „. 2.815.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends., 40.537.40 Withdrawals, paid-up atock — __ 16.200.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 5.83 Salaries 540.00 Other expenses.. ; 122.99 Real estate account, expenses paid 103.82 Cash on band 13.326.88 Tax sale certificates _ 563.58 Expense In loans in foreclosures. - 24.35 Total - - fl20.73U.83 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of series Issued since organisation. 57 Number of shares outstanding last report - .2987 Shares Issued since last report 810V4 Total - — 3.HO3U Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 58914 Number of shares in force this dste _ 3214 Number of shares on which dues are delinqnent- 15 Average running time of stock matured during year 123 months Xumher of borrowing stockholders v 173 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 284 Number of loans made for building purposes daring year. Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year.... 20 Par value of each share of stock _ _ $ 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 15.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 15.00 2(1 Amount of Interest due and unpaid 22.80 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 1 2.235.88 Amount of loans on Improved resl estste _ 193,005.00 Appraised value of Improved real estste upon which loans have been made — - 389,650.00 Amount of fire and tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 427,820.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 885.10 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 18,092.07 427,820.00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-op stock during 5.83 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running atock during year— 8% Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock /likplnfr woir __ ___■ T'Ki u, u r nigi, y -Ei .»»_&gt;----—-■*-«--»*—********—-■»**--""-—*-**--***"■■■ ■■■■*»■»*-■_■ 'i "" ■_»■■■■■■■«■*■ * /p Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 9% Rate per cent of premium* charged borrowers during year 5% 5% </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President „ C. S. Snyder Vice President _ — — Jacob Henderson Secretary A. E. Ward Treasurer _ J. L. Grant Attorney M. B. Foster DIRECTORS Fred H. Davis J. L. Grant C. S. Snyder Jacob Henderson F. M. Yaezel D. Q. Nicholson ASSET? First mortgage loans _... * 03.28.VJ0 Loans in process of foreclosure _ 1,000.&lt;K&gt; Loans on stock or pass hook sennit jr 250.00 Cash _ MMJi Delinquent interest, fines, etc _. _ 196.48 Furniture and fixtures. _ 371.50 Taxes paid _ 1S6.4.", Other assets 8.18 Total _ $102,243.33 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 57.114.61 Paid-up stock and dividends „ 42.000.00 Reserve fund _ 1.348.!tt I'ndivirted profits _ - 1,179.77 Total - _ $1Q2.243.:53 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 89 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report - f 1.383.60 Does (running stock) 12.536.18 Paid-up stocks _ 15,400.00 Mortgage payments 14.21)0.00 Stock loan payments _ 100.00 I nterest * 7,357.91 Fines _ _ _. 168J56 Tax certificate redeemed 1 1 7.8ft Refund on certificate 100.00 Profits forfeited certificate- - _ 4.53 Total f 51,370.00 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans....- - _ * 30,657.68 Stock loans..— 150.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 6.208.68 Withdrawals, paid-up stock - 4.100.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 2.18S.44 Salaries 605.00 Commissions — . — 45.00 Other expense _ 300.30 Cash on hand - - 6.M6.82 Tax sale certificates and subsequent taxes. 73.10 Collection charges _ 7.67 Total - - - * 51.370.00 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Nnmlwr of shares issued since organisation XiinilHT of share* issued Dim* organization 3.17H4 Number of shares outstanding last report _..1OB5*4 Shares Issued since last report - 326^ Total - M2214 Share* withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report M$ NuuiInt of shares in force this date - - UtH Number of shares on which dnes are delinquent Ml Average running time of stock matured during the ye«r - -... 117 months Mtt Number of borrowing stockholders _ 58 Number of non-borrowing stockholders. 101 Number of loans made for building purposes during year » Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages (Turing year 17 Par value of each shnre of stock.. - — ♦ 200.110 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 126.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 126.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid - V.H1.4M Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 l.oui.im Numlier and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure.. ..No. 1 l.OOO.'IO Amount of loans on Improved real estate.., — ■ 94.283.!&lt;0 Appraised value of improved real estate upou which loans have „.-„,„» been ma die. - li 0,040.00 94.2S3.!&gt;0 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as __„ collateral security — -.._ -- '■*'• ■*"' ■"&gt;&lt; Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security a8&gt; ££-!5 Amount credited to reserve fund during year iZ5'22 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year HZtt! 175.00 Amount or amaenas aeciarea on running block uuriug j«r ' °' Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 218^y Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur- St'V 1»« year ..................... ■■■-■-■■-■■■■■■■■■■■■~-~-~-r~r =^—- = - •* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year »&lt;?&lt;• </seg>
            <seg id="p090">TWENTY-FOUETH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 90 STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - - Henry Fastenau Vice President _ - - _.._ J. W. Butt Secretary Wm. H. Pitzer Treasurer...- _ _ _ _.._ _...H. F. Meyer Attorney Wm. H. Pitzer DIRECTORS F. M. Cook W. W. Metz H. D. Thiele George Bader E. G. Mueller H. F. Meyer E. H. Buhlman John H. Petring William H. Pitzer ASSETS First mortgage loan* _ I106.OOB.OO Loans on stock or pass book security- 6J0RO0 Other real estate 2,«11.8« Real estate sold on contract _ _ _ 1402.39 Cash _ _ _ 17',805.74 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc '. 1,'888'OC Furniture and fixtures 100.00 100.00 Taxes paid __ 142!« Total $196,417.41 LIABILITIES Runatac stock and dlrldends $137,086.78 Paid-up stock and dlridenda 51,000.00 51,000.00 BMerre fond 4,58«.03 UndiTlded profits _ _ 3.703.90 Paid on fiMiTTi***! ■■— ■ ■ i 33.70 33.70 Total __ $1»6,417.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 91 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Ciil on hand la»t report | 11,928.24 Does, (running stock) _ ™ 30.0fM3.59 Paid-up stock. _ ...!."!.... 22.SSO.00 22.560.00 Mortgage payment* - _ _ 18.645.00 Stock loan payment* 8,700.87 Interest 14.00B.flS Rent! 287.00 Membership and transfer fee* _ 156.25 County warrants redeemed _ 4.04&amp;58 4,O46.5fl Taxes repaid' 288.32 Real estate contract* 33.70 Total Z 1108,717.18 • DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans t 24.285.00 8tock loan* _ 9.045.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividend* 27,690.71 Withdrawals, paid-up stock 20,280.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock. ...... ■ 3,027.80 »,0*fi.0O n KIinriWIIB UlTlQCuQ Oil DK1U-UU BlUCK .— .. O.UCI.OU SaUrles 1.32aOO Other expense „. ™.._™..™. _ _ ....« 110.50 Real estate ■eeoii'ntl— 1,115.47 Cash on hand 17,805.74 County -«»~Wt« Z , 4.048.56 Taxea and Insurance — 20.41 Total $108,717.1» SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of share* issued since organization 8.808K Number of shares outstanding last report 2JSJ9 Shares Issued since last report 872V4 •Total _ - Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report— Numlier of shares in force this date. - - 3.224V4 Total Average running time of stock matured during year IS* months Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholder* W Number of loans made for building purposes during year 8 Number of loan* made for purchasing of homesteads or payment 00 of homesteads mortgages during year 60 value of each share of stock • 200.00 Par value of each share of stock Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1.886.02 Amount of loans on improved real estate 168,066.00 1.885.02 Amount of loans on improved real estate. ADDrataed value of Improved real estate upon which loan* have been made- -...- 288JOO.0O Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 288,600.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association M collateral security — 140,500.00 as collateral security • 1 *&gt;-2 oo i£ Amount credited to reeerve fund during year _ ™J? Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year, depreciation.... 203.22 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year S'SjrJS Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 3,027.80 Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year , f} Bate per cent of interest charged borrower* during y«ar 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p092">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 92 STATEMENT of the condition of the NUCKOLLS COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ - _ _ Geo. Lyon, Jr. Vice President W. C. McHenry Secretary C. R. Imler Treasurer. Henry Fox, Jr. Attorneys .. Cole and Brown DIRECTORS Geo. Lyon, Jr. E. D. Brown H. E. Goodrich J. B. Goodrich Thos. Graham F. E. Bottomfield W. W. Hawley H. G. Smith W. A. McHenrj W. A. McHenry ASSETS First mortgage loam _ $ 80,945.00 Loans on stock or pass book security -•- 5fi0.00 ('■Kb - 2,548.81 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc 83.W Taxes paid 82.41 Expense* - 25.00 Interest paid _ _ _ 145.21 Total - % 84,390.07 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - _ I 84.34aO8 Paid-up stock and dividends _ - 4.114.45 Reserve fund _ 1.203.00 1'udivlded profits" - 2.614.56 full paid Mock - - - 12.110.00 12.110.00 Total - * 84,380.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 93 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C»»h on hand last report. _.. | 775.83 Does, (running stock) — _ 2S.33t.70 Paid-up stock _ 0,605.00 Mortgage payments _ — 12,662.96 Stock loau payments 314.50 Tax sales redeemed - 146.69 Iirterest and flues _ __ 6,081.82 Membership and transfer fees _ 134.75 Premium 9.86 Total- _. $ 52,0B6.(« DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - * 21,497.67 Stork loans _ - - — 286.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. _ — 7,325.31 Withdrawals! paid-up stock - - 5,635.00 S-t In rips * 325 00 ■r*n fl h on hand 2 54M 81 Wit hdrawals, matured stock — _ 13.S41..T7 Interest pnid 472.44 Tax sale certificates.,. _ - 125.43 Total — » 52,088.08 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - — Permanent Number of shares issued since organlxatiou 3,221.45 Number of shares outstanding last report _ 1.8N6.4O Shares issued since last report 514.05 Total - 2.2CO.45 Total - 2.2CO.45 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled Blnee last report 349.35 Number of shares' in force this date 1.851.10 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _. 138 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 9 Average running time of stock matured during year _ 126 months Number of borrowing stockholders accounts 98 126 months Number of non-borrowing stockholders accounts - 106 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year ,~.jl Par value of each share of stock. I I 0 *- 0 " Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 267.00 Amount of dues owlug by borrowing stockholders — .... 262.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid. rS*-J5 Number and amount of of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No.l anSSJi'n? 267.00 -.'BL'HI Amount of loans on Improved real estate *■■ Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have 201,120.00 Amount" of"nre insurance in ""force and assigned to the association Amount oi nre iu»ui»i»x m lu.vc «..« -— .» .- — ioujki a -oII-iIithI securitv — — — ••** ivi,ia.w Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association ount or nirnaiio »«»"«' ■■■ •"■■r "«« —o.* ■■• .„„ as collateral security ... _- - lfl £nn£SR as collateral iKrvuriij' — -.-.-- o nS* ni\ Amount of money loaned on Improved farms _ wt.VnJK Appraised value^of land not Including Improvenien,, _ 20.000.00 Value of Improvements - St to 2S7.72 Amount credited to reserve fund during year .....^ Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year.j.....^...^--. \mount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during 4.7S8.67 472.44 Rate e ner cent "oFdwidradiT d«clar«* Ml wmSSk stock during year. Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock K", «-, "- I **70 Rate "per cent of inteie»t"chirged borrowers during year 8% </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President. Chas. Letheby Vice President — C. J. Peterson Secretary and Treasurer _ E. H. Gerhart Running stock and dividends _ _ S 19.010.05 Paid op stock and dividends 2,350.50 Dne shareholders on Incomplete loans 5.500.00 Reserve fnnd.._ __ 808.86 Undivided profits - _....1.........._........... 2,060.25 Total * 29.54&amp;5S L H. Gerhart A. L. Doty O. O. Buck idw. W. Lyon Chas. Letheby C. J. Peterson AB8BT8 first mortgage loans f 29,100.00 •ash '. 19.25 telinqaent Interest, fines, etc 256.80 'axes and paid expenses — 172.50 Total f 2S.M8JSS </seg>
            <seg id="p095">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C«sh on hand last report « i«ian wm,.'" 1 :^ itock) — —————— ■■ ' 4.473.00 £•1*1"^ «"* =:::zr:zzzizzzzz SSSm Mortgage payments 290000 Interest IBM 7a Interest . &lt; *»&lt; 70 Premium "~ 5em mSS' nm ♦O 2 -'* -pidcb IM ai &gt;fii n.«-,.. __ fin ivt 80.80 sundries zzzz__z..z:_zzz:z:z:zzzzzzz:zr .Hub Incomplete loans- .7....Z.1.IZ.~"....'.T. S.SOaoo Total ........... • 17 81170 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. _ % 13 000 00 Withdrawals, running stock aud dividends..- 3,'7«3.1S * 13.000.00 Salaries '150.00 Other expenses- _ , 22 80 Cash on hand 18.28 1H.25 Sundries 256.80 TotaL _— _ 17 S11 70 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Number of series Issued since organization- 22 Nmber of shares issued since organisation.. 1,239 Number of shares outstanding last report SOS 8hares issued since last report . 65 Total 373 85 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. 33 Number of shares in force this date 340 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 37 Number of borrowing stockholders. 24 Number of non-borrowing stookholders 30 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 10 Par value of each share of stock f 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 98.00 Amount of does owing by borrowing stockholders. — 83.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _. 158.80 Amount of loans on improved real estate _. 29,100.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have tieen made 81,680.00 Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 2S..VW.(JH Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 31.500.20 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ..._.. ._..._....________ 100.40 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.672.70 31.500.20 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-op stock during year L"35.05 Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 10% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and foil paid stock during year . 10% Rate per cent charged borrowers during year — _. 8% Rate per cent of premiums charged during year 1- |; '- </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _...H. A. Pasewalk Vice President- _ _ J. C. Stitt Secretary and Treasurer. C. B. Durland Attorneys Mapes and McFarland DIRECTORS H. A. Pasewalk W. J. Stafford A. Bucholz I. M. Macy J. Welsh S. G. Dean G. B. Christoph Burt Mapes J. C. Stitt ASSETS First murtKRire loans _ - W4X.550.0O Loans In process of foreclosure - 4.N00.O0 Loans on stock or pass book security 2.305.00 Real estate, office. _ 4 SMI. Other real estate _ 5351.61 5,851.61 Real estate sold on contract - - l.OSO.OO State and municipal securities - 4.(100.00 Cash _ _ _ _ 1(1.(126.62 Delinquent interest. Ones, etc_ — 4,782.90 Furniture and fixtures - 300.00 Taxes paid and disbursements account - 259.51 Total $481,955.64 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends 1277.308.67 Paid-up stock _ ZZZZZZZZZ 176.124.00 Due shareholders on incomplete ioana _ — i'Ji^VP Reserve fund - - 7,078.81 Undivided r^«"»- - — 4 '£? 1- f? Net earnings " 14.291.51 Total $481,055.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 97 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand lust report _ _ _ f 13.331.20 Kues (running stock) _ _ 82,913.00 Paid-up stock _ lM.66ft.00 Mortgagp payments 84.375.01) Stock loan payments 4.476.89 Real estate sales. _ 3.196.00 Interest _ 36.682.57 Disbursements and taxes _ 950.28 pines 322.36 Uents 103.85 Suspense _ .. 4,370^0 Bank certificate. _ 2.000.00 Surplus _ _ _ 1.425.00 I'roflt and loss _ 1.529.74 Total _ $394,362.72 DI8BURSKMENTS Mortgage" loans - ♦193.S50.00 Stock loans - 5,040.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ 85.437.22 Withdrawals, paid-up si,.,k wt.2H.tjO Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 9.337.87 Salaries '. 2,250.00 Suspense 1.624. «O Other expense... 2.682.27 Real estate account - 7.JW.O8 Oash on hand - — 10.026.62 Taxes ' _ 1.184.43 Stnte hank certificate - 6,000.00 Surplus — - 21.48 Total - $394,5fi2.72 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plmi of association '. - - Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report — — 6,839 Shares Issued since last report _ - - 3,819 Total 10.60) Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 2,003 Number of shares in force this date 8.657 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 705 Number of shares subject ti&gt;- cancellation for non-payment of dues 44 Average running time of stock matured during the year 124 months ,\lfninf running iiure *n on.. « ........... «- * --- Number of h-IIWlH stockholders 3BT Number of non-borrowing stockholders. _ ...- - 712 Number of btnns made for building purposes and purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year ..vJSS Par value of each share of stock - ♦ 2X-%! Total amount of dues delinquent at this date...... - t'isS 0 , \mount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 3 \fi5°A' Amount of interest, premiums and fines due nnd unpaid— ilSS? Nnmlier and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 6 _._ °'_I5- 0 i l Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure, No. 4— «i - 2_vi5 inut s,ino.on 4,800.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - .-— 452,560.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans bare ■«_. «„,«, irailKMl vmne ui iui|mu.™ ic_. ™_.« „,..,.. KlSMOrt, been made ,. - , - . . --- 800.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate iTV"-"; — v — Appraised value of nnimproved real estate upon which loans n«Te been made... - . . . ...„._ - — Amount of flre insurance' "in i "force and assigned to the association 512.230.00 Amornit^of tornado insurance In fore* and assigned to the association as collateral security — -— ilVnno 1.410.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year - —- * J?*_S Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year ~.nRftor Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year.. -■---••■- 26.050.97 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock daring 21.45 9,337.87 Rate'per cent'of dividends' deciared on running stock during : TefJ-" Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full pilcl rtock 10% «% Rate "per" cent' of interest: "charged borrowers during year 10 % </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ELKHORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President H. J. Cole Vice President F. E. Davenport Secretary T. E. Odiorne Treasurer _.._ H. J. Cole DIRECTORS H. J. Cole H. Deogner H. T. Donner F. E. Davenport C. E. Doughty T. E. Odiorne ASSETS First mortgage loans _ f 50,060.00 Cash - 2.506.52 Delinquent interest, lines, etc _ .". 292.97 Taxes paid 88.15 Total. * 52,949.64 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. - $ 16,641.60 Paid-up stock and dividends _ — : 33400.00 Reserve fund _ 1,800.00 Undivided profits - 1.108.04 Xotal - ♦ K.MB.S4 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 99 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING ' JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS r»Kh on hand last report _ - * 1,231.22 Dues, I running stock) - 9,473.14 Paid-up stock _ _ 12.700.00 Mortgage payment* 12.5Oi.flN Interest _ _ _ _ 3,728.48 Other receipts in detail, taxes paid 31.00 Total - ' $ 38,667.92 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ 19.150.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ _ 8,O16!87 Withdrawals, paid-up stock - _ 7,700.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 1,800.21 Salaries _ _ _ 18O.00 Commissions ~ - ~ 20.00 Other expense.- _ „ 292.32 Cash on hand _ 2.508.52 Total _ _ I 3U.667.32 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent N'umher of shares issued since organization 4.086 Number of shares outstanding last report- 887 Shares issued since last report Shares i.-Mie&lt;l since last report _ _ 3OH4 Total - - - - WpM Shares withdrawn, matured or cancrlled since last report 19B s Number of shares in force this date 76fl Number of borrowing stockholders _ 51 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - _ 63 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 10 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortcages during year _ ~w»n5 Par vale of each share of stock - * 200.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 292.97 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 2 1,000.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate...- riO.OGO.On Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made .: - 103.000.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association „„„„ as collateral security _ - 62,000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - " kS !J-!!!UI Amount credited to reserve fund during year - 200.00 auiuuui *:ic*iii«-\» m icwi »c auuu uutm* .,*«• — - Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year £££; AUIIIUlll »J1 IIIIIUCUUI «T-V»O»TTU Ull 1UUM11I0&amp; Blwi B uui»u B ?~— ■ • " -■- - Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 1,773^ Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock ll'-r during year — - J* e ner cent of interest charged borrowers during year ■ &lt;• Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORTH LOUP BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH LOUP, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ Geo. E. Johnson Vice President _ _ _ _ E. A. Hutchins Secretary and Treasurer _ _ E. J. Babcock Attorney — - — _ _ E. J. Babcock DIRECTORS E. J. Babcock E, A. Hutchins Geo. S. Mayo S. L. Clement Geo. E. Johnson H. E. Davis A. T. Jones ASSETS First mortgage loans _ f 21,835.00 Loans on stock or pass book security - 80.00 i --wi. _ _ 474 04 Delinquent interest, lines, etc _ — 145.39 Total - * 22.534.63 LIABILITIES? Running stock and dividends _ - ( 18,604.52 Paid-up stock and dividends _ _ 2.500.00 Doe shareholders on incomplete loans. _ 170.00 Reserve fund 568.22 indlvlded profits collected 548.30 Undivided profits earned but not collected. 125.88 Interest due on matured stock but unpaid. 19.71 T0U1 * 22.534.8S </seg>
            <seg id="p101">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 101 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 383.36 Dues (running stock) _ _ _ 1.T09.50 Mortgage payments - 1 .9B6.O» Interest _ 2,027.72 Fines - 55.15 Membership and transfer fees _ _ 34.70 Total - * 6.206.51 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans — _ - t 550.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 182.61 Withdrawals, interest on paid-np stock- 241.20 Salaries .". — 233.97 Other expense _ _ 26.86 ■ f\ otf r if a utrUBC--- _- ... —»—„»»«■....»««...»«. - ...,.,., . .. , . . ■ i . ., ■ ■-. i ., —*i. Cash on hand - - — - 474.04 Matured stock _ 3.920.79 Total. _ _ - - * 6.206.51 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association...- - - - Permanent Number of shares issued since organization - 156SH Number of shares outstanding last report -495 Shares Issued since last report. - 152 Total - - - 84T .15: Total . Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 76»4 Numl&gt;er of shares In force this date 570H Number of shares on which dues are delinquent- 46 Average running time of stock matured during the year — 11 years m Number of borrowing stockholders - - J5 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 34 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year- 2 Ptr value of each share of stock - I 100.00 Total amount of dues dellnpuent at this date. "&gt;.'*• Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders ln "iJ Amount of Interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid 145.59 Number and'amount of mortgages subject to forecloaure. No. 3 1.550.00 1.560.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate — 21.835.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have _,.„„„ been made - — - - 3 ' -I™-™} been made - - ■ "' ■"■**'-"" Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 200.00 Appraise value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare been made ■■■■--• JUU.iw Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■■•■■•■ 25,475.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association m ~ as collateral security - ' S"S2 Amount credited to reserve fund during year - JsS Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year l.OSi 3S Amount of Interest paid on matured and paid-up stock duriug year— 818.24 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 8% Rate ner cent paid on matured and full paid stock during year i r Hate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - Thos. C. Patterson Vice President Victor von Goetz Secretary Samuel Goozee Treasurer _ Frank E. Bullard Attorneys Wilcox and Halligan DIRECTORS Ira L. Bare Geo. W. Finn Milton J. Forbes Joseph L. Larson Wm. R. Maloney Frank T. Redmond Thos. C. Patterson Victor von Goetz Claudia 0. Weinga Claudia 0. Weingand ASSETS First mortgage loans. _ $760,600.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 10,000.00 Heal estate, office 29,354.81 Real estate sold on contract _ _ 1,834.7© Cash 19.828.82 Delinquent interest, fines, etc „ 512.30 Furniture and fixtures _ .t 1,017.37 Total- _ 1829.148.00 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. $343,848.08 Pald-np stock and dividends- .._ 438,900.00 Reserve fond _ 16,800.00 Undivided profits _ _____ 32,054.57 Advance interest _ _ * 44.40 Total _ _ _. _ (829.148.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 103 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand, last report _ f 19.131. IB Dues I running stock) _ _ _ 100.631.00 Paid-up stock 142.000.00 Mortgage payments _ 8O.38A.15 Stock loan payments - - — 3,678.39 Beat estate sale* - 1.558.01 Interest .. -. ~ - - W.I 14.90 Fines - - - _ 6R5.10 Membership and transfer fees , 457.00 Rents and office building receipts • 1.306.51 Foreclosure account _ — _ 283.37 Total - »413,183.51» DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. - - J23S.1DO.OO Stock loans - - - 7.400.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends — _ 34.S03.46 Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ _ Sfi.3O0.0O Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 23.915.80 Salaries ..-_ 2.275.00 Other expenses - - - Porwlosiirp account — - «...«...- « 92*7*5 Cash on hand. - - 1!i.k2R.K2 Office building..''".! - 85.00 T.,.| 1413 183 59 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of series Issued since organisation _ 17. all matured Number of shares Issued since organisation _ ... 26.401 Number of shares outstanding last report »,13»H Shares issued since last report -...- -3,125% Total - _ . . : • ■- - I 2 - 2 * 5 Total _ _ 12.28.1 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report ,ivlJS$ Number of shares in force this date _ 10.09?% Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 22H4 Averaee running time of stock matured during the year 124 months Average running time of stock matured during the year. Number of borrowing stockholders 464 r.T'.i Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 579 Number of loans made for building purposes during ye«r 66 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year ~,wv5i Par value of each share of stock $, 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at thia date...... 2?? 0 " Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders... 351.00 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 512.30 Amount of loans on improved real estate - - 766.000.00 A™pr«"sed value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made - - - - ~ """ ' ' Wnn Amount of loans on unimproved real e»tate — — 800.00 Apprised vain" of unimproved real estate upon which loans h.ve Amount of flre insuriince in "force and assigned to the association „„,-_„ Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the ..sedation a» collateral secnrity _ -- - 0SX1K RMe pVr cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8&lt;fr Rate of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock" Rate U p I er' g cent a of iiitereLt charged^^ borrowers during y«» r - - 7 - 2 * </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Thomas A. Fry Vice President _ R. S. Wilcox Secretary J. R. Brandt Treasurer _ ......G. E. Haverstick x i coaui ci \J. *^« uarci obit-n Attorney Edgar M. Morsman, Jr. DIRECTORS O. D. Kiplinger Bartholomew Julien William G. Ure Thomas F. Godfrey Byron R. Hastings Thomas J. Fitzmorris ASSETS First mortgage loans — _ fl.fi66.T5O.0U Loads io process of foreclosure—. „ _ _ — ._ 549.04 Loans on stock or pass book security _ 16.258.30 Other real estate _ _ 2.407.38 Keal estate sold on contract— 5,520.86 State and municipal securities _ — 13.749.87 Cash _ - 55.810.84 Delinquent interest, fines, etc Ml Taxes paid _ • _ 39.32 Total - - - - - f 1,161,690.28 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends I 808,674.40 Paid-up stock and dividends 279.263.37 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 51,276.13 Reserve fund _ 17,172.67 Undivided profits _ 5,303.89 Total ■ . 11,161.880.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 105 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 28,807.68 Dues l running stock) . 345.W2.39 345.Wi.3a Paid-op stock 84.517.86 Mortgage payments 185.750.00 Stock loan payments _ 40.910.61 Real estate sales contract - 832.07 Interest 64,171.71 Rents 43.00 Membership and transfer fees 1,817.40 Rent and office building. 400.00 Delinquent interest 852.91 43.00 Foreclosure 6,307.84 Miscellaneous 858.90 Total _ S 760.812.37 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - _ _ _ $ 337 .957. 4S Withdrawals, running stock and dividends . ."_ __.. L 208,070.16 Withdrawals, paid-up stock- , 78,748.64 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock - _ 15,496.08 3,357.85 Salaries Bonds IM 13,749:87 Other expense _ _ _ 1,888.24 Real estate account ...- __.._"._IT. _ 2,527.72 Cash on band- __________________ _ 55.810.84 Delinquent interest - - 1,07^.47 Foreclosure account _ ~ _____ 6.&amp;46. 9ft Miscellaneous _ 1 175.88 Total - $ 780.812.37 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ _ Numlier of shares issued since organisation _ 25.081% Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report 8.762 Total 33,823*4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 4.126% Numl&gt;er of shares in force this date _. -MW* Number of shares in force this date numiter oi snares in lorce mis uuie -jj.wi-h Number of borrowing stockholders - '-"'" Number of non-borrowing stockholders. 1,076 Number of loans made for building purposes during year — — 93 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year - — ~ — 83 Par value of each share of stock _ f i] 0 !* Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 603.64 603.64 Amount or interest, premiums ana nues uiw miu uiiiraiu «"■».«-« Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 8 18.S46.61 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 549.04 Amount of loar.s on improved real estate.. — — 1,088,750.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 2,M».»75.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1.419.795.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 1,277.225.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year - .5iSI^ Amount of dividends declared on running stocii during year 40.087.14 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock' during year 15.496.0R j^ £j j I I I j | | Q \j \ i j y M * • » B I " I d I • u, |1| \J 11 111*1 1 II i \ ' • • ■ i ■ * * ■ m —v * • ■• • * p^ . — ■ f ■ ■ •* ™ v ™ Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock durini; year.... •% Rate per cent ot dividends paid on matured and. full paid stock during year - _ ~ - ■■■-■;• : _* Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring year ; 6.6% </seg>
            <seg id="p106">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 106 STATEMENT of the condition of the OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - John F. Flack Vice President R. A. McEachron Secretary E. N. Bovell Treasurer Geo. C. Flack Attorney _.. .F. F. Wiles DIRECTORS John F. Flack Geo. C. Flack R. A. McEachron E. N. Bovell Robt. Dempster ASSETS First mortgage loans — _ - 13,934.471.00 Loans in process of foreclosure — 30.432.01 Loans on stock or pass book »ecurit.v _ 'J3.W3.00 I lr)it&gt;r r*»nl pfltflte _» — ................ 17 *2ft 83 pool Astntp Kolrt on contract „„ ftfi (t55 42 State and municipal securities 71.imio.47 C a8n _ _ 804,143.43 Delinquent interest, fines, etc _ 28.749.38 Total - *4,6Ki,2tt4.54 LIABILITIES Bpnulng stock and dividends $2,082,857.58 Paid-up stock and dlvidend*^ - 2.364.206.42 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans - 50.244.47 Reserve fund _ 17 S'!j&amp;I! Tndivided profits .'. 3,160.32 Total »4,a82,264.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 107 KECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report- _ _ $ 28WKW.11 linen c running stock I Ms! 457^33 Paid-up stock __._.... 812J2.V92 Mortgage payments M&amp;3M.72 Stock loan payments —____„ Real estate sales njmn 1&amp;;O2.M Interest — _.._ ."_......." 2Ift.t55.01 Premium _ 102.2fll.fi2 Kllic-i 2,013.20 Membership and transfer fees— _ 4i571.40 Real estate r.nitnictx 23.046.20 Foreclosures _ 2O,%21 .91 Lotin fees and expense MM.13 State and municipal securities _ !» HT.1t Total $2,901,101.62 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ _ »1,O66.3«4..T5 Stock loans ttMUM Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ _. ♦55.647.flR Withdrawals, irnld up stock _ 38K.3OO 54 Wlthdrawnls. dividend nn paid-up stock _. 116.7SS.36 Salaries _ , j _ H.Wtff Commissions _ 17.SS.VW Other expense ... _ 14.374.11 Real eats** «"cnnnt 6.H04.61 Cash on hand _ 501.143.4.1 Real estate contract 1.3R6.08 Foreclosure account _ 7.1 10.7 Profit and loss H41.OI State and municipal securities. _ 147.sw.17 Mileage and expense 1.376.14 Ccintliiireiit fund 00.42 Total «2.S01. 101.62 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since nrKHliiaitinn .V1.4«7 35-600 Numlier of ahnres issued since lost report — - 20.1.18% Totnl "(XeffiS 4&lt;C)-60O Share* withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 9,768 3-5 snares H II IMiniH 11. imiiurt-u nr ramTiini "iiiit mwi i*-|i*&gt;ii ir.iw -&gt;-ti Number of shares in force this date _ 80.S57 125-000 Average running time of stock matured during the year _ 108 Months Number of borrowing stockholders - 3.677 Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ 5,426 Number of loans made for building purposes during yenr 427 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year _ .'. 462 Talue of each share of stock _ f 200.00 4&lt;;-j Par vnlue of each share of stock Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2S. 740.38 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 34 32.300.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 78 30.432.01 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 3,934.471.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ - 7,470.542.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ - - 4.81R.4fln.OO Amount of money loaned on Improved farms - 4.1 700.00 Appraised value of land not including Improvements 90.400.00 4.61S.400.0O Amount credited to reserve fund during year...- NVON8.56 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund dnrlng year — 7.030.96 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 16S.3ii2.2O 7.030.96 AU1UUUI Ul lUBIKfl ' lllllk'n l\l ICBtnv iMii-i 'lining ,,rn» Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year. Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 121..VO.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year — - tffr Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year f&gt;". Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 2 4-10% </seg>
            <seg id="p108">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 108 STATEMENT of the condition of the OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - - G. W. Loomis Vice President - W. S. Wright Secretary and Treasurer _ _ _ W. R. Adair Assistant Secretary J. T. Helgreen Assistant Secretary A. A. Allwine Attorney - F. H. Gains DIRECTORS G. W. Loomis W. S. Wright Joseph Barker R. J. Dinning W. R. Adair John H. Butler Charles E. Black E. A. Parmelee Millard M. Robertson ASSKTS First mortgage lotn« - _ - $8,031,075.00 Loans in process of foreclosure 5.M1&amp;29- *8,631,675.00 Loans in process of foreclosure. LimiiN mi stork or pass haat security 101,118.27 -fcSIU.OOO.00 Real estate, office.. 42iio.000.00 ntknr r*Hll estate - . 12 1**9 49 1 1**9 40 Real estate sold on contract — _ _ 32,271.80 "ivmii Delinquent interest, fines, etc - Furniture and fixtures 628.00 Furniture and fixture* &amp;!&amp;no l"ith*»r nftRPtS ........ "'"ITi JV&gt; Contract sale Douglas block _ 21.000.00 Certificates of deposit 81.389.59 Total _! tO 486 996 25 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $8,233,197.76 Paid-up stock and dividends 688,'tl7!33 Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ 342,836.06 688/U7.33 Reoerre fund 208,085.11 Undivided profit* 15.960.00 Total ♦9.486.SW6.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 109 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 273,2X7.97 Dnet (running stock) _ 2.6R5.H18.94 Paid-up stock _ : 156,230.00 Mortgage payments - 837,185.00 Stock loan payments _ 203,250.46 Real estate sales - ............... 7.073.86 Interest - - _ 457.71S.83 Rents and office building receipts 2O.7ft0.Ol I truncates of deposit 14O.!»64.26 I neomplete loan ledger St.tttM.35 Foreclosure - _ 7H&gt;.65 Miscellaneous - 4.311.43 Total _ *4,933.175.5« DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - - »2,05».332.48 Stock loans — 22«.7(i3.47 Withdrawals, running stork and dividends _ 1.844.51 1.8a 84,850.00 Withdrawals, paid-up stock Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stuck 34.712.38 Salaries 2S.«.V&gt;.07 Commissions - - - — 131.50 Other expense : h.40».0k Real estate account ~ 1O.G19.30 Casb on band _ _ - 39S.14ii.vj MrCague building mortgage 4O.imo&lt;&gt; Office building expense 16.2M.8O Foreclosure ..._ _ - MW Certificate* of Jspoatt -., _. 192..T63.8B Furniture mill fixture* 108.00 Total _ - $4,933,175.56 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permnne»t Number of shares Issued since organisation i 237.997 1 Number of shares outstanding last report — lOlJU Shares Issued since last report — 27.963% Total 129.NB6?; Sbares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _. 12.757 s . Number of shares in force thin date 117.138 Number of borrowing stockholders 4.8S1 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — — 10,796 Number of loans made for building purposes during year - _ 320 'Number of loans nuiile for pur&lt;-lini&gt;ii|r of homesteads or payment of homestead inortifufres dnrtnir year - •"•:».'! Par value of each share of stock-.' _ $ 200.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid - 5.R80.64 Amount or interest, premiums auu uiiew uue auu uiipaiu .i.nnii.m Number and Hiniiniit rf mortiiHires subject to foreclosure _No. 21 21.918.85 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 3 5.50K2H Amount of loans on improved real estate „ 8,543.657.77 Appraised value of improved real estate upon whicb loans have been made 1T.451 .275.(10 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate - 88,017.23 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 222.700.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 10.566.207.35 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 7.934.28?&gt;.OO as collateral security n».vi..;f&gt;i.*p.r Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 21 flift.SO 1.581.39 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year _ — 1. 581.39 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 373.19ft.54 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 37.U9.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid atock 6T, during year _ _ 6% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrower* during year 6.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President ., Geo. F. Gilmore Secretary and Treasurer Paul W. Kuhns Attorney William Baird DIRECTORS Geo. F. Gilmore Paul W. Kuhns William Baird Randall K. Brown E. A. Benson A. W. Bowman Charles C. George Robert Dempster John F. Flack J. C. Robinson C. M. Wilhelm Byron R. Hastings J. A. Sunderland H. A. Thompson A. P. Tukey A. P. Tukey ASSETS First mortgage loans. *ii.i43.na&gt;.on Loans in process of foreclosure _ 42.001.13 Loans on stock or pass book security - ll"..t4C.4."&gt; Real estate office ... - $ 81 OOfMJO Other real estate _ MJM.43 Other real estate, new office - _ V*).M*tMi 261 .■•.Ifl.42 Real estate sold on contract MCMM Rtate anil municipal securities. 183.292.3A Cash - 7OT, 14hTiK Delinquent Interest, flues, etc S1.MS..TO Certificales of deposit .'. _ 3T,9tuJM Total - _ __ _ »12.XiO.:.'N.-i.7N LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ ta.Xti flM.Th Paid-up stock and dividends _ 2.4S7.fln.M Due shareholders on incomplete loans .T."&gt;2. rt)2.6n Reserve fund _ _ 320 (OMXI Undivided profits _ _ 4.Y2m!nn Rent*, new office. 2.260.40 Total _ _ $12,550,285.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 111 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING On the 30th day of June, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 50fl.t45.7(&gt; Due* (running stock) 4,021, -tTT.fil Paid-up stock TJl.MW.0li Mortgage payments 2,274,744.05 Stock loan payments lKt.4fl6.S0 Heal estate sales Interest _ _ ZZ1Z™!! 656|57s!l6 Foreclosure account _ _______ BO.742.86 Keal estate account _ _ _ Js.43s.08 Rents from office building 3,475.00 Membership and transfer fees i'i.SMt.80 3.475.00 Membership and transfer fees. Rents, Daridge block (new office) :I..MO.4O Warrants, bonds and certificates of deposit 29,956.66 Profits from insurance department _ _,_5U.0O Profit and loss- _ 215.87 2.25U.00 Profit and loss. Total _.- _- I8.530.4o0.22 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ _ _ _ *3,7M, »4h.bi Stock loans _ - ar7. 363.64 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 2,941,783.96 Withdrawals, paid-up stock ..._ - _. 412.649.40 2,941.783.98 Withdrawals, paid-up stock Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock ~ _ 119,000.85 Salaries _ _ _ .-i_.597.50 Foreclosure account „ tt4, 258.63 General expense _ _ 14..2K.4O Real estate account...- _ - - _ 34.076.19 Cash on hand 7O5.44f.5S Real estate sold on contract.. _ l«,7O4.84 Taxes and expense of office building _ — 2.AMt.41 Warrants, bonds and certificates of deposit 51,044.59 Interest on warrants _ _ 425.Hit I&gt;avidge block (new office) purchase - _ KiooiJO.uo Davidge block (new office) interest.... _ 1.250.(10 Reserve fund - _ 5.484.82 Profit and loss— * 125.00 Total 18.530,550.2 - 8UPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent 16.530,550.2- Number of shares Issued since organisation 908,987 Number of shares outstanding last report _ .283,510 Shares issued since last report _ 81,8*0 Totnl - 365.350 Shares withdrawn, matured or rancelled since last report 3S.3S2 Number of shares In force this date - 326,998 Number of borrowing utockholders 5.567 Number of non-borrowing stockholder Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ — 17,243 Number of loans made for building purpose* during year 230 J.to Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 216 Par value of each share of stock - $ 100.00 Amount of interest, due and unpaid _ 31.542.50 Number and amount of mortgages miujeet to foreclosure No. 21 3!i. 720.00 .NUIlloer mill Mimiuiil t»l iiiun^niirii nuujni iw lumiunuir .-»tr. «« sv.imi.iju Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 29 42,901.13 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - 9,599,660.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been 'made ■ — 21.311.374.00 made Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 1S,064,000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ».S26,5O0.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms _. 1,544.300.00 ADDraised value of land not including improvements _ 2,848.834.80 as collateral security 2,848.834.80 Value of Improvements - 494.470.00 Amount of fire insurance thereon 170,395.00 Amount of tornado insurance thereon 152.535.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 60,184.82 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 5.484.82 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _... 417,746.88 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during 119,060.85 year ltate per (fnt of dividends declared on running stock during year ..Jan. 1, 0% ; July 1, 5% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - Itn.,1, •%; July 1, 6% Hate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring year Farm rate — — •% City rate ......7.7. .'...." ".._._ 6.6% </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President W. D. Lincoln Vice President N. A. Spiesberger Secretary A. D. Touzalin Assistant Secretary A. A. Tenopir Treasurer. _ L. D. Spalding Attorney Thomas D. Crane DIRECTORS W. D. Lincoln A. D. Touzalin J. J. McMahon Thomas D. Crane Charles F. Kuncl John C. Wharton L. D. Spalding C. D. Hutchinson J. P. Leary J. P. Leary ASSETS First luortp&amp;gp loans _ _... _ $ 396.280.00 Loans in process of foreclosure 4.1flO.fln I. onus on stock or pass book security 7,802.67 Other re«l estate..— - _ _ 10f)!W&gt;.!&gt;7 rath 21.fi33.2H Delinquent interest. Ones, etc _ HUS Furniture and fixtures 2.&lt;K)©.75 Taxes paid 4ts^7 Total _ $ 443.WS3.53 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ _. $ 325.337.30 Paid-op stock and dividends _ MJSOOn Reserve fund , __ 1,753.57 Undivided profits - _ 23.92 Incomplete loans - 26 71W.74 23.92 Incomplete loans Total - $ 443,863.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 113 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _ | 12 208. Dues (running stock)™ 212,S!&gt;4]r&gt;3 Paid-up stork 3.V40O.00 Paid-up stock 35*400*00 Mortgage payments : MJBXiM Stork loan payments — .._ „ ______ 7,133.37 Stock loan payments , 7,133.37 Real estate sales _ _ _ _ 4,444.93 Real estate sales _ _ 4.444.93 Interest _ _ 2S.S3O.O2 Interest _. 530.02 Premium commission account.. 1fl3*flT&gt; Premium commission account.. lS3.flii Fines _ _ 4;t .".»; Fines - _ 4;t .".»; Rents „ W0 00 Rents _ W0.00 Delinquent interest _ _____ _______ 2.447.83 Delinquent interest _ _ _ 2.447.63 Expenses _ 1.00B.H7 Expenses _ i.mp»i.!t7 Insurance receipt* _ 44.94 Insurance receipts _ 44.94 Incomplete loans 15t.519.65 Total $ 5flR.S16.oo DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ I53.!iflo.nn Stock loans...- - B.644.51 Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ 1M&gt;_WJ3 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ 11 . 730.no Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock M—Ltf li.73n.no Salaries - _ - 2.1.W.0II Bent _ - 2.iSO.oo Other expense _ - .-. 1 M— K ' Heal estate account _ fl.17fi.4rt Cash on Mud — - 21.633.2Ti Taxes paid _ - — 4ii;.B7 Reserve - ifH.O.t Delinquent interest ~ - - - 1.26R.03 Incomplete loans _.... 134.t90.62 Total - ♦ 5OS.si6.oo SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - -. - Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 48.98214 Number of shares outstanding last report _» .9.404 Shares Issued slace last report...— 3.499 Total — 12.903 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report I.fil24 Number of shares in force this date 11.290% Number of borrowing stockholders _ 263 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 843 Number of loans made for building purposes during year- - 38 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 48 Par value of each share of stock - $ 100.00 4x Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 915.22 Number and amount of mortgages in process foreclosure 4. 100.00 915.22 Number and amount of mortgages in process foreclosure. Amount of loans on improved real estate - _ 400.38000 AtH&gt;ralsed value of improved real estate on which loans have been made - 8B6.760.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security .... 460.100.00 Amount of tornado insnrance In force and assigned to the association is collateral security — — 33S.wo.on Amount credited to reserve fund during year - 870.28 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year_ 204.03 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 11.3S3.00 ll.3S3.Mt Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 6.023.40 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock 6'', H II pinflf v^—ti* — *•***•••- ■■■■■■■ -■■_ ■ ■■!■■■■■■■ w/x 1 Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year....- 7.2&lt;£ 6"r </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COMMERCIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ „ Patrick J. Sheehy Vice President W. P. Adkins Secretary ....Jas. J. Fitzgerald Treasurer „ _ F. W. Thomas Attorney A. H. Murdock DIRECTORS Patrick J. Sheehy W. P. Adkins W. J. Coad E. C. Kohansl Frank Koutsky L. F. Etter E. C. Kohansky T. J. Quinlan Jas. J. Fitzgerald ASSETS First mortgage loans. Sl.m2.4W.no Loans on stork or pass book security _ _ 10,438.50 Other real estate — _ !i.77!U3 Real estate sold on contract _ 2!48."&gt;1» cash ___ m'jxnM Delinquent Interest _ _ _ tW3!lO Total _ „ SI. 125.41)0.90 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ C61.V2.1.TO Paid-up stock and dividends 23B.i(Ki.OD Due shareholders on incomplete loans „ 12.12V 9fl Reserve fond ■ 20.000.00 Undivided profits _ ~2,1SS.1S Total S1.125.1OB.9(&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p115">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 115 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash mi hand last re|Hirt _ $ 38,001.58 Dues {running stock) 904.224.57 Paid-up stock _ — — _ 44.tno.OT) Mortgage payments _ I7_!215loo Stock loan payments _o!4H3!_l Real estate sales 2.030.75 I nterest 7ft'ifl7 tr Loan expense _ _ 1,M_!_ Expense _ ______ 'xm.im Real estate on contract - 2.256.12 Cash exchange _ HUB S. _! Mortgage foreclosures _ I._H ■ Interest ninl e;irnin_* ' 79.99 OrtinVntes of deposit _____ 23.()&lt;io!oo Total _ ,. f 735.920.35 DISBIRSEMEXTS Mortgage loans — $ 6S.7.V&gt;.OO Mortgage loans — $ 6X.7.Vi.no Nt4M*K lUUlln MLttflfft skk-k i, ,in.- __ 1&amp;33K.50 Withdrawals, running stock «nd dividend* „ 31_..t_O.l.s WithtirnwalH, running «t»M*k «ml dividem!* „ 312..TJO.1S Withdrawals, pit id - up hUm-Ic — — «■ 31,&lt;Vi&lt;VoO Withdrawals, pniil-up stock 31.ti5O.O0 Interest and earnings _ _ HUB Interest and earnings _ _ 121.25 Loan expense _ _ „ 1 54 j in Loan expense _ _ „ 1 54J 44) Salaries „ „ 1 w m ) ( k &gt; Incomplete loans .. _ ______ 15_6.\V.3O Other expense ..._ - _ - _____ 5i»4tU4 Real estate account - — 1J45UB Cash on band _ _ _ ___ «K373!&lt;i2 Cash exchange _ _____ 48448.41 Cash ....._.... ___________ *'V(kvhm» Mortgage foreclosures _ _ ' 4i!oo Delinquent interest . 50'or. I'ndivlfled profits 521.22 521.22 Real estate on contract _ 7.00 Total _ _ $ 735.920.35 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ , _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization _ 45.5.5Vi Nnmlii-r of shares outstanding last report 18..W3 Shares issued since last report 3,955V Total _ 22.548V4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report X27414 Total \-JTH\ Number of shares In force this date __ 19!_73*i Number of borrowing stockholders " 861 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1,402 Number of loans made for building purposes during year.. Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year „ 140 Par value of each share of stock _ $ 200.00 1411 Amount of Interest, due and unpaid S.T.T10 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ •_ 1.08_ 40000 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been ni'xlf - 2.085,075.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _ 6,125.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ _ 15..soo.ou Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral security 1,445.400.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security as collateral security . 1.062.!&gt;50.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms _ 5,000.00 5.000.00 Appraised value of land not including improvements 8.000.00 Value of Improvements ........ ,„ 1/jOOOO Amount of lire insurance thereon _ llsoo.oo Amount of tornado Insurance thereon 1,300.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year...- 4.500.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year.- 45.9-4.30 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 12.190.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ' 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year ,„, 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ T_% </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PRUDENTIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the SOth day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President W. C. Bullard Vice President Chas. R. Sherman Secretary _ _ D. H. Christie Treasurer _ _ _ D. D. Miller Attorneys Smyth, Smith and Schall DIRECTORS W. C. Bullard D. D. Miller T. E. Wood C. R. Sherman E. A. Blum D. H. Christie W. W. Mace ASSETS First mortgage loans „ f 276.315.00 Loans In process of foreclosure 2.7S6.00 $ 276.315.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ 1.KIO.0O Cash _ _ _ 8.419.26 Furniture and fixtures.. _ 657.60 Due from various persona 141.00 Total _._ * 290,118.86 LIABILITIES Running Mock and dividends $ 281.28S.24 Due shareholders on Incomplete loan* 6.118.74 Reserve fund — — _~- - 1,809.00 Undivided profits JZZ1JZIZIZ!1__ZZZ1IIZZZ1!Z!!Z!!1._1Z!11.!!_. 80S.B8 Other llabilltes, loan feel _ 102.30 102.30 Total $ 290,118.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 117 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C«»h on band last report _ f 4.967.32 Dues ( running stock) _ 93,493.20 Interest - ~ 14,675.00 Stork loan payments — ~ 250.00 Membership and transfer few _ 328.35 Miscellaneous ~ ......... 5,285.72 Total $ 118,809.59 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ __ $ 57,449.68 Stock lonnx _ _ r 200.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividend* _ 4O.17ti.14 Salaries - - 1.560.00 Other expense „ — - SM.4S &lt; H*h M Imml S.419.26 Other disbursements in detail, rent 504.00 Fees 277.50 Miscellaneous _ 5,122.59 Total ..- — * 118.998.5U SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association — _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 12,552 Number of shares outstanding laat report 6,827 Shares issued since last report _ 2.470 Total 9.297 L',470 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 683 Number of share* in force this date _ — 8.604 Number of borrowing stockholders . 250 Xuinher of noii-horrowiiiK stockholders — 525 Par value of each share of stock I lflo.00 BOB Par value of each share of stock- Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 2.200.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 1 -',786.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 276,315.00 Aminiiseil vnliie of improved real extate upon which loans have been made __ ... 552.B30.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ _ - 290.000.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association •a collateral security - 260.000.00 Amount" credited to reserve fund during year R37.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 11.864. TO Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during; year — 6% 6&lt;1 Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Samuel Rees Vice President H. M. Beall Secretary — Irving G. Baright Treasurer Irving G. Baright DIRECTORS Samuel Rees E. C. Hodder Irving G. Baright H. M. Beall H. C. Getscher ASSETS First niortKliKe loans f 12n.'&gt;03.15 Loans In process of foreclosure _ x]918!ob I. nans on stork or pass hook security _.. l]465\00 Other real estate _ _ _. _ lltiouro Real estate sold on contract - 616!58 Cash _««..-—.— — - _ 16.H34 47 Delinquent Interest, lines, etc _ _ _ l.(K4!&lt;M Furniture and fixtures....- _ _ 63l!(X&gt; Other assets - - - _ 2S7.25 Expenses !)6S.«2 Total -., _ _ $ 1X5,496.10 ■» LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend* $ n8.348.n6 Paiil-up stock and dividends 4(V0to!3O Doe shareholders on incomplete loan* _ _ 4.iii'4.4i; Reserve rand - *727!86 Undivided profits 5. 631.77 Miscellaneous - 47 J6 Total f 155,498.1(1 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">SECRETARY. OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 119 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING On the 30th day of June, 1916 RECEIPTS C»»h on hand last report _ f 5,829.61 Dues (running steck) — 58,243.42 Paid-up stork 20,096.00 Mortgage payments _ 19,582.00 Brock loan payment* — - _ _ 3.101.80 Interest _ __ 10,116.15 Premium loan fees _ __ ' 54.10 Flnea, delinquent Interest _ 022.23 Rents paid on contract.. - 8.42 Court costs v— — — — ,, 61.00 Miscellaneous _ » 15.76 Total f 118,629.49 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans 9 34,898.00 Stock loans - - - 2,!M1.80 Withdrawals rnumug stuck and dividends „ 48.S46.15 Withdrawals paid-up stock S.570.00 Withdrawals dividend on psid-up stock 2.142.90 Salaries - ,, t&gt;02.75 Commissions 14.86 Other expense 1,533.87 Real estate account 30.00 Cash on hand lfi !*34.47 Delinquent interest 1.295.06 Kurnlture anil nxiuren - 376.00 30.00 Furniture and n\iint &gt; Court pfMitfl .............. .__.._.. 21800 \l 1 Cl '**! ] H 11*^4 111 *. 'J^l fU F 1 Total - - $ 118.629.4» SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report 4,437 Shares Issued since last report 1,711 Total „ 6.148 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 1,927 XuuiIht of shares in force this elate N'uuilwt of shares in force this elate - 4,221 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of does.... 19 1» Number of borrowing stockholders — - 115 Nuuilier of iiou-borruwliiK stockholders - 414 Number of loans made for building purposes during year. 13 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year — — 36 Par value of each snare of stock - - - f MO.OO Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid — 1,084.08 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 1 1.000.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 1.U1S.00 Amount at loans on improved real estate - 133.511.15 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been Amount of lire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 169,075.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral necurHy - 158,100.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farm* I 0 !*-*? \ppreJ»ed value of land not including improvements 6,400.00 Value of improvements - 1.000.00 411.08 \iwnint crtHHted to reserve fund durinir year _ 411,00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4.645.00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 2,042.95 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock daring year . - ** lute per cent of interest charged borrowers during year.. 66 cents per 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENf of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President J. C. Michelsen Vice President Wm. E. Davis Secretary _ H. Earl Cox Treasurer _ -Perry Wheeler Attorney A. C. Pancoast DIRECTORS F. A. Cressey W. S. Shafer Richard De Young Claude R. Orchard A. F. Stryker C. L. Talbot ASSETS First mortgage loans _ $ 9I.1W.18 Cash _ 5,822.13 Furniture and fixtures- 199.00 Total - - * 90,215.31 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ f 44.5M.83 Ptid-up stock and dividends.—!.. . 18.080.00 Reserve fund K4JS6 Undivided profits 2.89S.93 Total f 86.215.S1 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 121 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 BECKIPT8 Cash on lHind last report- _ a fl.302.B4 Dues (running stock).. ....... __.__ 19,309.74 Paid-up stock _ 7.950.00 Mortgage payments , 12.002.39 Interest .— _ 5.108.26 Furniture and fixtures — __..__ 75.00 Total - — _ f 51,707.93 DISUIHSKMENTS Mortfaa* loans $ 14.178 25 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 15,857.54 Withdrawals paid-up stock 10.700.00 MiTI L':l;rt* l&lt; Jills 10.700.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock - _ 1,167.60 Salaries 505.35 Other exjtense — - _- - 997.42 Cash on hand '. 3,8-2!l3 !ID7.41&gt; Cash on hand Dividends credited _ _ 2,418.07 interest _ - 36.67 Furniture and fixtures. ._._...„ 27.00 Xotal - _ $ 51,707.93 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ _ _ _ _ Permanent Number of series issued since organization 1 Plan of association.. 1 Number of shares issued since organization 4.60844 Number of shares outstanding last report _,1S7 Shares Issued since last report- - 539^ Total — — _ -.726% 2.1S7 Shares Issued since last report- Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 490 Number of shares in force this date 2,236% Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 220 Number of borrowing stockholders— 63 «a N'uiul#r of non-borrowin« stockholders.... 133 Number of loans made for building purposes during year T Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ 3 value of each share of stock _ $ 100.00 3 Par Talue of each share of stock. Amount of does owing by borrowing stockholders 601.49 Amount of loans on improved real estate- _____ 60,194.18 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made — 142 SdO.OO Amount nt tire iiiKiirHiii-e in force and axsigned to the association as collateral security — '.Nl.mio.ii! Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security— 7\__r&gt;.00 Amount credited to reserve fond during year 1SO.73 7\-_r..oo Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2.41S.O7 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-op stock daring year 1,167.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 6% Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year .._.—...— — , ,.., 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8% </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PROTECTIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ORD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President M. B. Goodenow Vice President Geo. R. Gard Secretary Joseph P. Barta Treasurer _ _ - Joseph P. Barta Attorney - - Claude A. Davis DIRECTORS M. B. Goodenow A. J. Firkins Geo. R. Gard C. A. Hager Claude A. Davis Joseph P. Barta ASSET* First mortgage loans _ t 9.050.00 C*ib 'J.OOe.M Total * 12.659.28 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 3,744.ft5 Paid-up stock and dividends 7.452.56 7.452.55 Doe shareholders on Incomplete loana 1,434.00 Reserve fund Daufra fnlld __ ___ — — ...... X7 IHm a • t. &amp; uu *• «....".^".."..». - ..... .... . .. .....—. ....— ......... ................................ •#■■ I Undivided profits - _ - 22.2U 22.211 Total % 12.tViil.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 123 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Dues (running stock) _ _ _. $ :t,715.8O Paid-up stock , 7.550.00 I merest 115.25 Membership and transfer fees 135.UU Loud fees - — — 60.00 Total - — _ * ll.r&gt;76.05 UISBIUSEMEXTS Mortgage loans — — _ t 8,216.00 Withdrawals. paM-sp stock _ 15O.00 Other expense - 200.79 Cash on hand 3.(X».2« Total * 11.S76.06 SriTI.KMKXTAL REPOUT Plan of association..... _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued since organization _ nwi'i Number of shares outstanding last report - 1.1I00V4 Total _ - - — I'""-, Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report lVfc Number of shares in force this date _ 1.0B8 Number of borrowing stockholders „ _ 8 Number of non-borrowing stockholders -- - 60 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 5 Par value of each share of stock.. - $ 100.00 5 Par value of each share of stock..... far value or eacn snare oi siock- ♦ «".w Amount of loans on improved real estate _... 9.IS50.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been "made _ _ _ __ 22.0110.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 10,500.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - 10.jflO.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year -— 5.47 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year— 20.15 1O.J0O.0O Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 52.56 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - — *v» Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year »% </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PAWNEE CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President J. H. Shepherd Vice President J. F. Wilson Secretary .._ R. W. Story Treasurer _ _ G. E. Becker DIRECTORS J. H. Shepherd A. S. Story G. E. Becker J. C. Waddell J. F. Wilson R. W. Story G. A. Sawyer M. L. Van Horne H. L. Flory ASSETS FlrM mortgage loans % 16,080.00 Cart 158.80 Delinquent Interest, flues, etc, - 110.37 Total — $ 16.299.17 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend* __ f 15.S39.74 Reserve fund . 806.00 I'ndivlded profits 138.83 Advance payment of Interest- 15.00 Total « 14.2W.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 125 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report- _ I 10.88 Due* (running stock) _ _ 3.198.40 Mortgage payments — - - - - 980.00 Interest - - 1,084.28 Fine* - 8.72 Membership and transfer feel _ 45.08 $ 5,276.28 Total — DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loam I 3,200.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends- _ 804.58 Withdrawals, paid-up stock - - Hfi w* 1 •' •'■* rttvicipnrt on nairt-np and matured stock- - 316.60 Interest paid on matured stock— 87.51 Commission- - - - 20.00 Exchange on draft — - .10 Cash on band . 158.80 Bank examiner'* fee — - _ 15.00 Publishing annual statement - — 5.00 Total - » 5,276.28 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization-. 700 Number of shares outstanding last report - 145 Shares issued since last report — ~ 45 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since iast report 16 Number of shares In force this date - 174 Number «t shares on which dues are delinquent...- - _ 3 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues.... 3 Average running: time of stock matured during the year- 114 1-6 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders ■ 30 Number of loanB made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year »m«nS Par value of each share of stock ♦ SS'v\ Total amount of dues delinquent at this date jSJ'2? Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders ??J?- Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid ~. — - 110.3. Number and amount of mortgage* subject to foreclosure No. 1 MO.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate. -. — — - lB.imi.uu Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been 3403000 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association _-.„.„ as collateral security —=— _e.i~o.0(&gt; Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association «..-_«„ ■ ■ AAllatA-Ml -ponritv - - - — — ■■ .O.4.XMHI as collateral security - «2 Amount credited to reserve fund during year .—.. » .i»i Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year — 1 '°J*_2 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 18j8B Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— B% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock 18.86 M T~r Rate 'per'^ent of "interest charged borrowers during year 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _E. P. Lute Vice President R. A. Bates Secretary...- T. M. Patterson Treasurer F. T. Ramge Attorney J. M. Leyda DIRECTORS E. W. Cook H. F. Goos E. P. Lutz F. T. Ramge T. J. Yanda R. A. Bates J. M. Leyda C. A. Johnson T. M. Patterson ASSETS First mortgage loans. _ $ 206.S46.67 Loans on stock or pise boor securitj _ _.. r&gt;,471.11 Other real estate „ _ _ .. - fl.M5.9a' Real estate sold on contract L',553.00 Cash 10.6SS.73 Delinquent Interest, flues, etc _ _ „ 143.88 T.ital $ £t!,Wlt.l2 LIABILITIES Running stock and diTidends $ 173.616.30 Paid-up stock and dividends- _ _ - 54.7(».0n Reserve fond _ 31.000.00 Undivided profits _ 1.122.82 Total _ $ 232..VK1.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 127 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report. Cash on band last report $ 1JW7 22 Does (running stock) _ _ - . _______ 39,427!oTi 39.427.ar Paid-up stock — _ _ 32.100.00 Mortgage payments — _ 1S..T37.*: Stock loan payments , 1.757.00 Interest _ _ 15,*-8.33 pines &amp;L63 Rents - - 300.00 Membership and transfer fees- 26.50 Taxes repaid by stockholders 115.18 115.18 Bills payable __ 4.6Wioo Total _ f 121.7D2.6S DISBrHSEMEXTS Mortgage loans : $ 5ii.0W.0O 8took loans ..._ - 2.24o!oo Withdrawals, runnlug stock and dlvideuds. _ _ 3l|2U5.6D Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ - _ 7.30o!oo Wiiuiimwals, dividend on paid up stock _ 2,544/ Salaries — - 1 1K{ Oil Commissions . _ 85.00 Other expense _ 138.77 Real estate account _ _ 5.538.40 Cash on hand - - - 10,688.73 Matured stock and interest- - 555.50 Bill* payable and interest - - _ 4.642,95 Total * 121,792.68 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Serial NumlMT of series Issued since organisation 6.') Xiiinlifr of shares issued slwe organization - - 10,422 Numlier of shares outstanding last report _ 3,358% N 1 1 1 ■ 1 1 &gt;f r of shares issued siuce organisation Shares issued since last report.... _ 867 Total - - - ■ 1,225V- Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 65* Number of shares in force this date...- _ — 3.568% Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 4S Average running time of stock matured during the year. 11 years Number wf borrowing stockholders. _ 204 Number of non-borrowing stockholders.... 327 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 17 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year.. - _ 12 Par value of each share of stock - f 200.00 Total amount of &lt;lu**s d«*ltmiuent at this date _ 50.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 41.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 87.63 Amount of loans on improved real estate. — — 206,846.67 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - — 364.O0O.0ci Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ - 221.600.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 107.700.00 ount of money loaned on improved farms - - 2,8no.0(&gt; 107.700.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms... ' ■•■•d nut including Improvements...- 4,320.00 Value of Improvements 500.00 Amount of fire insurance thereon — - - 400.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 743.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 10.7IM.7O Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 2.M4.73 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— 9H% 2.%44.73 Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock d. . _» i _. ~ ii_a m ____* _ _«__ — _ . . . _ __^_ ftC£» Urill^ jfVWt !■■■■ ».,—-■■■■--■ w ««i,... M rt.t*.Hiw"-»""'"— ■■».w.. M ..t.ii**«*..i l i^..» \r n Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 8% 6", </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President D. B. Smith Vice President _.. .F. G. Egenberger Secretary C. G. Fricke Treasurer - - C. A. Marshall Attorney A. L. Tidd DIRECTORS D. B. Smith F. G. Egenberger Wm. Hassler H. M. Soennischsen C. A. Marshall Harry Barthold Wm. Holly F. E. Schlater C. G. Fricke ASSETS First mortgage loans - * 186.171.74 Loans on stock or paR» liook security - 1L',9S5.00 Real estate sold on contract i52tt.Ol Delinquent interest, flues, etc _ 1.029.13 Taxes paid and advanced _ 1.9&amp;.12 Rent and repair - 281.49 ToUl - ~ - » 2O».:t*2.7» LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - $ 158,006.06 Paid-up stock and dividends _ ■ s *'i? ) S 0 Rewrve fund — ' - » ■ 10.fl04.54 1'ndivided uroflta i.nOl.z4 558.90 Casb Tot,! S HM.'MtW </seg>
            <seg id="p129">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 129 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS rash on band last report Hues Manning stock) * 2,562.72 31,586.00 Mortgage payments ... Stork loan payments Real estate contracts.. Interest 3UC7.25 TJMuM 1.1181.56 14.147.17 Fines 31.54 Membership and transfer fees... Cash overdrawn. 161.25 .-i58.!HJ Total * 8S.S51.45 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans Stock loans t 60.325.00 3.1M0.00 23,230.0(1 1,300.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends Salaries — Other expense 229.11 Insurance and taxes paid and advanced Rent and repair 418.2!l ir.9.0.-. Total * 88.iS51.4S SITPI.KMKXTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Number of series issued since organization Number "f shares issued since organization 11,234 Number of shares outstanding last report 2,514 Shares Issued since last report ."&gt;43 Total 3.OR7 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Number of shares in force tbts date. 2«0M Number of. shares on wblch dues are delinquent 14 Average rnniiine tip"* rf stock matured during yenr in Numlier of borrowing stockholders. :tl:i Number of non-borrowing stockholders. m Number of lonns nmile for building purposes during year 13 Par value of each share of stock $ 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 247. 0U 715.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amount of Interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 1,029.13 188.171.74 Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - - 340.500.00 Amount of flre Insurance In force and assigned to the association as i-nlhitiTiil security 196,450.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in fon-e and assigned to tbe association as collateral security "0.14O.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.3D1.76 Amount of dividends paid on matured stock during year 7.724.00 Kate |er cent i f dividends dednreil on running stock during year.... 4, Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid Mock (hiring year 6. and s- , 10&lt;7r Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year M </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION SEWARD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ John Zimmerer Vice President J. F. Geesen Secretary _ H. A. Graff Treasurer _.._ W. E. Langworthy Attorney J. J. Thomas DIRECTORS M. C. Miller H. D. Landis J. M. Calder H. F. Goehner Roy R. Schick J. V. Willis ASSETS First mortgage loans- - _ f 148,375.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 8,680.00 Canh _ l.:'.4!t.lMi Delinquent interest, fines, etc 1.e3ft.33 Furniture and fixtures - _ _ _ _ 235.00 Certificates _ _ _ _ _ 827.64 Office supplies - — .29.55 Insurance unpaid 21.70 Total _ * 181.155.18 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ 136.210.52 Reserve fund _ - - - 4.7.W.8O Advance dues 1,106.50 Advance Interest _ 78.36 * 161.155.18 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p131">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 131 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RKCBIPT8 Cash on band last report &gt; 1,788.84 Doe* (running stock) _. 82,331.12 Mortgage ana stock loan payments. '.- 15,212.17 I nterest - 12,266.23 Insurance repaid — — _.—......-.„-..-. 43.5B Fines - . 151.60 Membership and transfer fees : 186.45 Tax redeemed _ 153.42 Profit and loss Kern _™ -__ m ,11 Total - - ( 92.136.49 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage and stock loans _ $ 29,860.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. 59,291.45 Salaries 806.00 Other expense — - 132.87 Cash on hand-.- ~ — 1.349.96 Insurance •• ™ _...-__«--. , { , , 30.00 •Tg j sale certificates. - — ..— — — 067.21 132.87 Tax sale certificates. Total _ — * 92.136.49 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association 8eT^ Number of series Issued since organization SO XuiiiImt of shares issued since organisation 9.998^4 Number of shares outstanding last report 2.292U Shares issued alnce last report 743 Total — - 3 -9?W Number of shares outstanding last report. Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 7O4U Number of shares In force this date 2.331 N'umber of shares In force this date.. Number of shares on which due* are delinquent 128% Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues S Average running time of stock matured during the year 314 weeks Number rt borrowing stockholders ™ Number of non-borrowing stockholders — — — *lf NunV&gt;er of loans made for building purposes during year — 4 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year "■ — — » Par value of each share of stock — _ • 222-S Total amount of dues delinquent at this date , SS"S Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders. _ '•25IIs Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _. — . .sS-Jx Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 8 .-rSHMS Amount of loans on Improved real estate ■• •■— •• lJO.J7a.wi Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been ioof)o Ammlnt e of "loans on unimproved real estate. rrT~;~ i= 12.000.80 Appraised valne of unimproved real estate upon which loons have l«" made _ - - - - ■ - - *'"""" Amount of Br* insurance "ta force' and assigned to the association as collateral security — _ -■ -•• -■-• .■_- 162.465.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - — .-■- — wiS Amount credited to reserve fund during year va'Xn Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year — — — — ??;S, Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— 7.71% !&gt;..„ ,*.. «.-t rrf int»re«t i-hnrupri borrowers during year....- 7.8% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION SIDNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President H. T. Doran Vice President _...J. R. Williams Secretary and Treasurer Robt. A. Barlow DIRECTORS H. T. Doran A. Granneman L. Neubauer J. R. Williams L. Jessen Lena Jessen H. Schroeder M. Lancaster Robt. A. Barlow ASSETS First mortgage loan*....- f 31.100.00 Cash 718.86 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc „ _ "40.00 Furniture and 'fixtures _ ~~ „. „ 160.55 Expense 20.00 Total _ f 3*.'.J4SI.OO LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends Running stock and dividends f 29.282.87 Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ _ 1.000.00 1.000.00 Reserve fund -._ 855.31 undivided profits 1.025.19 Suspended stock _. 85.83 Total _ - -... I 32.248.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOAKD 133 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _ _ _ .... $ 1,285.16 Dues (running stock) - 6!lOl.flO Mortgage payments „. 500.00 Interest — — — — . 2.14946 Membership aud transfer fees..- - — 2.75 Total _ _ f 10.088.07 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans — _ $ 0.400.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ _____ 2J86/22 Salaries _ ______________ IO0I60 Other expense' 33ioo Cash on hand 718185 Total „ 9 10.038.07 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association „ „ Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report 4GO Shores issued since last report _ „ 41 Number of shares outstanding last report... 41 Total „ _ _ ""* 401 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since iast report.. ___ 55 Number of shares In force this date 436 Average running time of stock matured during the year "... 126 months Number of borrowing stockholders..- ______ 17 Number of non-borrowing stockholders. „ 28 Number of loans made for building purposes during year. 3 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year 3 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid $ 249.80 3 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure _ No. 1 2.000.00 Amount of loans on improved real -estate 31.100.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ _ _ 83.000.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 41 00000 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 19.000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ~~ 10&amp;40 Amount of dividends declared, on running stock daring year 2,552.12 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year— 9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid ' stock during year _ .. &amp;% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p134">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 134 STATEMENT of the condition of the CITIZENS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVING ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ _ _ „ W. S. Young Vice President Vice President. .W. P. Long. Secretary _ J. T. Robbins J. T. Robbing Treasurer J. T. Robbins DIRECTORS W. J. Elliott W. S. Young W. P. Long J. T. Robbins F. S. Southand H. C. Devoe J. M. Silver John E. Eyre W. A. Myers A88ETS First mortgage loans- _ S 30,000.00 Loans on stock or paca book security ; 1,800.00 Other real estate 2,063.97 Real estate sold on contract 2,300.00 Cash 3.931.80 Furniture and fixture* 50.00 Total ., | 60,336.77 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends f 34,043.93 Paid-up stock and dividends __.____.__—_ 24,700.00 24,700.00 Reserve fund : 1,781.84 Total f 00.53S.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 135 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report...— ........ _ - _ S 8,876.19 Dues (running stock) ...... _ 7.X.NK 15 7,888.15 Paid-up stock _ _ 1,700.00 Mortgage payments 12,000.00 Stock loan payment* 001.20 1,700.00 Mortgage payments Stock loan payments Interest 4,649.90 Herts „ 82.TO Total 1 * 38,796.19 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loana _ — _ $ 1,200.00 Stock loans _ 2,201.20 Withdrawals, running xtoek and dividend* _ _ 12,004.57 Withilriiwiils. paid up stock- _ _ 5,(100.00 Withdrawals, dividends on paid-up stork 1, •!("&gt;. 25 Salaries 625.00 Other expense 390.0S Real estate account _ — 2.U03.97 Cash on hand ..._ „ _ .1,931.80 Profit and loss, First National Bank 8,498.37 Total - - * 35,798.19 SUPPLEMENTAL. REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report- _ l,!flsl Shares Issued since last report - 109 Total - 1,390 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 2M Number of shares in force this date - - 1,126. Number of borrowing stockholders. _ _ 41 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 86 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year. — Par ralue of each share of stock.... — i 100.00 Amouut of loans on Improved real estate. -.-- 50.000.00 2 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been 88.000.00 made - 85.000.00 ount of loans on unimproved real estate - — 1,500.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate.. Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan* hav« been made 2,500.00 Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 56,600.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - - 50,600.00 Amonnt of losses charged to reserve fund during year ..........__._.. 1,208.10 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1,941.36 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 1,696.25 1,208.10 Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock during year _ ., . ■ t% Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8.9% 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year *% </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TECUMSEH BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President... P. A. Brundage Vice President _...E. C. Hedrick Secretary _ J. B. Douglas Treasurer _ _ Harry Phelps DIRECTORS P. A. Brundage J. B. Douglas C. W. Graff G. W. Hassett E. C. Hedrick Harry Phelps R. F. Reynolds C. M. Shaw W. M. Sherman ASSETS First mortgage loans &lt; 1155SOOO Loans on stock or pass book security .."'. 2,785.00 L'.TtU-i (HI Other real estate - Cash fi.281.63 8,076. 4« Delinquent Interest, line*, «tr. ' sioSs Furniture and fixtures. 12*7.95 Total — _ _ 1 131,711.72 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. $ 113,430.39 Paid-up stock and dividends .... ... ..- n'suoon Reserve fund 2.5«.» T'ndivided profits Advance dues 4,274.94 122.00 Advance interest ___ 42' 70 Total ___ _ $ 131,711.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 137 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report Dues (running stock) - $ 2.134.06 36,667.00 Paid-up stock 2.200.00 Mortgage payments 44.UfiO.00 Stork loan payments S.770.00 Interest 10,911.32 Fines 469.36 Rents bkm Membership and transfer fees. 408.96 Total * 106.736.61 DISBURSE MEXTS Mortgage loan* I 30,050.00 NtiM-k loan*. 3.61O.0M Withdrawals. runuiiiL' stin-k and dividend 37,264. Withdrawals, paid-up stork. 1,700.1 «) Witliilrnwals. dividend on paM-sjp stink .niu.ow 638.49 Salaries 1,120.00 Commissions 26.00 Other expense 247.01 Real estate account _— Cash on hand 4.370.63 6.076.46 Matured stock and dividends 20.HW.00 Loss on settlement of doubtful loans. «33.29 Total * 106.736.61 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Number of series issued since organization _ 39 Number of shares issued since organization 8.046 Number of shares outstanding last report. 3,105 Shares Issued since last report-. Total , 3,827 Hhares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 837 Number of shares in force this date - - _ _ _.. 2.988 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent '250 Average running time of stork matured during the year 73 months Number of borrowing stockholders Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ 143 Number of non-borrow stockholders — _ 148 14S Par value of each share of stock _ $ 100.66 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ - 4S4.O0 4S4.00 Amount of does owing by borrowing stockholders 45700 Amount of Interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 277]96 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 7 R.32TV00 Numher ana amount or mortgages subject to foreclosure no. 7 R.32TV00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 115.550.00 S.32r&gt;00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 240 195.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 154,000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association us collateral security : - 121,005.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 483.51 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year - !&gt;33.;M&gt; Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3,939.23 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during; year 638.49 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year— 8.39% Rate .per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year — - - 6% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8.47# </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TRENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President „ _ _ O. E. Reynolds Vice President C. L. Allen Secretary — _ _.._ _ J. R. Greenhalgh J. R. Greenhalgh Treasurer — _ A. E. Reynolds DIRECTORS J. F. Ratcliffe J. C. Hurst A. T. McCoy O. W. DeWald R. H. Pember ASSETS flrwt mortgafe loan* | 10,750.00 5«.h _........ :.::.:...z • s^a •Mml | 14.028L8J LIABILITIES Ranntng ttock tnd dlrlitenda , * 1147200 UndlTided profit* * JjSS 2.55A83 TotH I M ,&lt;B8£5 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 139 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report $ 1.S89.61 Dues (running stock) 4.010.00 Mortgage payments 1,900.00 Interest „ 1,113.15 Membership and transfer fees T.00 Total S 8.81».7ft DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* f 1,400.00 Withumwalx. runnliiK Htwk and dividend* _ _ M_| Withdrawals, paid-up stock 3,000.00 Salaries _— 180.00 Other expense „ _... 1000 Cash on hand-— 3,276.83 10.00 Cash on hand Total _ _ | 8,810.7ft SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of aeries issued since organization 12 Number of shares outstanding last report 308% Shares issued since last report TO Total 378^4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — ______ 48 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report- — Number of shares in force this date 390^ ATerage running time of stock matured during the rear 70 monttis 3-H4 Number of borrowing stockholders .. 30 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — M Number of loans made for building purposes during year Par Talue of each share of stock $ 100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 9,900.00 2 Amount of loans on improved real estate-. Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made 17.000.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate . . 800.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 1,230.00 Amount of flre insurance In force and assigned to the association as as collateral security 18,000.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 10,000.00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 870.00 Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock *7r during year — * 8% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p140">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 140 STATEMENT of the condition of the FIRST BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION UNIVERSITY PLACE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ A. L. Johnson Vice President _ E. D. Currier Secretary G. E. Currier Treasurer _ B. H. Schaberg Attorney _ W. R. Gaylord DIRECTORS A. L. Johnson E. D. Currier G. E. Currier B. H. Schaberg W. R. Gaylord W. G. Bishop S. H. Chism C. H. Roper R. R. Smith ASSETS First mortgage loans _ ; 38.850.00 Cash _ — - 7 ifijj ii Total 4 46.039. 34 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends.. _ _ j 10.493 99 Paid-up Mock and dividends _ _ :•„-, &lt;■&gt;&gt;&lt;■&gt; 3.1 000.00 Reaerve fund 1 . 40Z0G Other liabilities, prepaid stock — __!__ 143I3O Total ™ « _ 1 id n«n Qi </seg>
            <seg id="p141">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ _. f 6,714.21 Does, (running stock) 14,878.61 Paid-up stock _ _ _ r.i.ljO.oo Morttrnife uuvineuts— ......._... „ 81)0000 Interest Membership and transfer fees 178.00 Abstract aud filing fees _ — _ 119.10 Prepaid stock _ — .- — 290.36 Xotal - - I 5::, 884.55 DISBURSE MENTS Mortgage loans. I 29.1)17.86 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends. MMJB Withdrawals! paid-up stock- _ KTflMb Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock — 2,010.37 ("mil missions }^*® Other expenses — 352.31 2,010.37 Other expenses Cash on hand - - 7,189.34 Withdrawals, prepaid stock -.. 231.23 Total * 52.884.55 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Permanent Numl&gt;er of shares issued since organization — — 1,670 Number of shares outstanding last report...- — - ir.'7 Shares issued since last report - 30»&gt;to Total 1 ' 32 ££ Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cani-elleU since last report. - 221 Number of shares in force this date - - ldM l$L Number of shares on which dues are delinquent — _ 96 Nuintwr of borrowlun stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders— — — 102 Number of loans made for building purposes during year - — J Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year _ .nn, 1 ,?. Par value of each share of stock _ - ♦ i™M!! Total amount of dues delinquent at this date . oij.w Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders *(•'* Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid... -2p" Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 1 7TO.0O Amount of loans on improved real estate _ ~ *«,uoo.wj Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have 22.fc-iO.0O been made. Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 800.00 \ppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made. - ; ■■■ :: l.WUMIO 800.1)0 Mnount of flre "'insurance in force and assigned to the association ,.„„„ us collateral securiry - -— 4ri'&lt;»u«i us collateral seciiriry Amount of tornado insurance in iforce and assigned to the association as collateral security... -,i-l! 2! 54.7.TO.OO Value of improvements. Amount credited to reserve fund during year 3?Jii Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year...— ____ Amount of dividends paid on matured aud paid-up stock during 54.V88 1,530.28 v€ar - 1.UOU..SO Rate per cent of divi(ien(is declared on running stock during year- 8% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dnrine year - - - ■ ■ — ™° Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year, clasi A, 7.2% IMS class B -&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President...- _ H. W. Hoenig Vice President..- _ _ - _ John M. Tucker Secretary _ _ J. T. Keeley Treasurer _ F. A. Cumbow Attorney...- F. M. Walcott DIRECTORS L. L. Bivens W. T. Kincaid Chas. Lewis W. S. Barker E. C. Davenport ASSETS Fimt mortgage loans....- _ $140,290.00 Loans In process of foreclosure _ f. 200.. 00 Cash _ _ 4.982.22 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc. _- 1M.20 l',i xpjj paid - 1N5.(B Other assets, insurance premium 56.10 Total $146,874.61 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ $110,065.05 Reserve fund_ - - 2,248.90 1.060.66 Undivided profits, interest 1.06O.66 Valentine State Bank — _ __ _ 6,000.00 Matured stock r 27,300.00 6,000.00 Total - - »146,874.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 143 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash ou banil Inirt report _ f 4,241.19 Does (running stock) _ 19,927.50 Mortgage payments . ■ 8,S62.5» 8,S62.5» Stock loan payments 70ft00 Interest _. 12,813.03 Premium, insurance 41.56 Fines 149.06 41.55 Membership and transfer fees Valentine State Bank 57.00 10,100.00 Tftt«t . t _„„ 9 54,891.91 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _._ _ f 29.900.00 Stock loans. _ 100.0b Withdrawals, running stock and dlridends 819.75 Salaries -.._ _ _ _ «».&lt;X&gt; Other expense 250.67 Discount _ ,„ , . 537.83 Cash on band _ _ _...„. 4,9i&gt;2.2"J Insurance premium 56.70 Ta»fK - _ 1».O9 Matured stock paid 12,809.59 Interest _ — _ _ 534.08 Valentine State Bank . _ _ _ .'. 4,100.00 Total — « 54,891.»1 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of series Issued since organisation 32 Number of shares Issued since organization 3,809 Number of shares outstanding last report _ 1517H Shares Issued since last report 209 Total :. 17L'6ti Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled slDce last report... ' !US H Numl)er of ahareii in fon-e this date _ _ _... 1,5-6 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. ______„ 93 Nunil'cr of share* in fon-e this date. M Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 41 Average running time of stock matured during year _ 10 yrs. 4 mo. Number of borrowing stockholders - r. 122 Number of non-borrowing stockholders. _ _ 106 10 yrs. 4 mo. Number of loans made for building purposes during year 23 Par value of each share of stock _ $ 200.00 » Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 484.00 Amount of dues owing borrowing stockholders _ _ 415.00 Amount of Interest, premium, and fines due and unpaid 191.20 Number and amount of mortgages, subject to foreclosure. No. 10. 7.400.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure, No. 1 1,200.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate. - _ _ 14O.2SO.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made. . ,, , ™________ 277,705.00 Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security _ S16.7UO.0O Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - _ — _... 50,100.00 uo v viia i*ri a* f« i u i 1 1 % i . . .... ...._.._..._, .„--.——-„ uv, rnif.wi Amount credited to reserve fund during year _. +S0.30 Amount of Iix-m's charwil to reserve fund duriim year 26.16 Amount of dividend* declared on rnnnlng stock during year.... 9,518.97 Rate per cent of dividends declared on funning stock during year.... 9% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 9 6-10% </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WAIIOO -AUTIAL LOAN AND WILDING ASSOCIATION WAHOO, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President Ben D. Rupp Vice President. J. L. Winter Secretary _ H. M. St.r'Uon Treasurer. ...C. Fred Tornblom Attorney G. H. Simpson DIRECTORS G. H. Simpson R. F. McCreery M. A. Phelps L. J. Kudrna F. J. Kirchman Jas. O'Donnell ASSL'TS First mortgage loans. Loan* "ii stork or pass book security Cash lK»linquent interest, fines, et&lt; Furniture and fixtures Taxes paid Other assets. Total.. LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends. Due shareholders on incomplete loans Keserve fund I ■Hl.lll 4.635.00 Total $148,777.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 145 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS C«8h on hand last report _ f 528.59 Dues (running stock) 24,018.50 Mortgnge payments - 3,965.00 Interest .._____.. , _ _ 8,422.15 Premium - _ - 2. 382.66 KiiKM _ _ 21.36 Membership and transfer fees. 156.75 Taxes _ 86.06 Personal accounts...- 83.70 Total _ 9 39.675.75 DISBURSE MENTS Mortgage loans $ 27,100.00 Stock loans - 1.500.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 3,182.37 Salaries _ 600.00 Other expense __ 119.20 Cash on handT....... .7.7. ... 7.7. -.. B.K84.4."&gt; Interest 96.80 Xaxes 179.05 insurance 13.88 Total- _ $ 39.675.73 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Serial Niimlier of writ's laaaad since organization _ 45 Numlwr of shares issued Rlnce organisation. — - 11,192 Number of shares outstanding last report. _ .3.792 Shares issued since last report- - 544 Total _ _ - 4.338 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 323 Shares withdrawn, mattired or cancelled since last report. Number of shares In force this date - - 4,013 Number of snares on which dues are delinquent 68 Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues 9 Average running time of stock matured during year 129 months Nuiutier of borrowing stockholders - - 110 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 166 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of '.&gt; homestead mortgages during year - IS Plan of premium, per share per month.— - — 15 Par value of each share of stock I 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at thi» date - _ 1R4.0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ — ■ 151.50 Amount of interest, premiums and lines doe and unpaid _ 290.47 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 1 700.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - 139.450.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made...... _ - 237,250.00 Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to the association ■■ collateral security - Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association 142.525.50 as collateral security - - - 113.050.00 ii &gt; uvm lain bi ocvu iiij .—- — — • ...... » &lt;&gt; iiA Amount credited to reserve fund during year — - - 5*5.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year M3S-9 Rate per cent of dividend declared on running stock during year 7 \2 &gt; Rate Der cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ B% 5*5.00 Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during tbe year, per </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATIO N WILBER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President.. Jos. Cerny Vice President _ _ _ _...V. J. Kohout Secretary B. V. Kohout Treasurer „ _ \ J. J. Novak Attorney j. F. Spirk DIRECTORS Anton Sagl Alois Borecky Win. Bohacek H. Binger Ed. H. Houser J. A. Sasek H. A. Greer Anton Shimonek Charles Pospisil ASSETS First mortpape loans ~ $ 86,T00.OO Loans on stork or pass book security 2,150.00 Ch _ m 4«43 Other assets, arrear dues 33.00 Total. $ 87,929.43 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends * 84,72«.8B Reserve fond ""' : 1.622.00 Undivided pronts.".".'.".."..-." , 1.J20.0* Advance dues.. ._ZZZ— Z — Z_ Z. 1 J5S5 Advance interest — "-SO Ui l xotal - * 87,8*8.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p147">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 147 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report — _ f 528.57 Dues (running stock) 31.803.50 Morten ire pa yinenta — - 34 015.0(1 Stock loan payments IKJU.00 Interest ...... 5,258.10 Premium - 32. ly Fines — - 53.M Membership and transfer fees- 160.00 Tntal S 62 786 90 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans- 2T.40O.0p iifofir Innnq — 1.1U0.00 Withdrawals', runuiug stock and dividends- - — 33,863.48 Salaries _. „ _ 305.50 Other expense - 71-49 Cash on hand - — 4fi.43 — I 02.786.90 XoUl _ SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association- - 1 Number of series Issued since organization 21 Number of shares outstanding last report _ UjSU Shares issued since lase report- — 332 T o tnl - 1,481 Total — _.__._ M»l Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. 288J4 Number of shares in force this date 1&gt;11B 3 ■ Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 59 Average running time of stock matured during the year- .6 months as Number of borrowing stockholders — 88 Number of non-borrowing stockholders. ™ 4 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of INUIUUtJr Ol IUBUB "Hut W» i&gt;u&gt;t-"»°.'&gt;* v» uv— «.«»«.«» ~. ,.— v homestead mortgages during year ' Par value of each share of stock * "L'-J" rar vaiue ui wil-h snare wi «,.w». * - - Total amount of dues delinquent at this date VStlX Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders low Amount; or uues o»iub wj uv»fu«»u ft o^^v-u^.^.o -- - — Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid o. T /«S Amount of loans on improved real estate — •- S5.iW.oo Appraised Talue of improved real estate upon which loan* have .„.««„„ been made - -■• ~~~ iJ0,4fi&gt;.wi Amount of fire 'insurance in'Torce and assigned to the association ,-,,„__ as collateral security - ■■ . ~~ — MJWMUWi as collateral securiLjr —-; — Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association „,„»„„ as collateral security - -—- imom Amount of money loaned on improved farms - t'SSVnn Appraised value of land not including improvements i-JCwm Value of improvements — ....—.-. - Sm'oo a „,..,, i, t i-roiiitod to reserve fund during year _ ™-~ Amount credited to reserve fund during year- Amount Creaiiea IO reserve iuuu uurius jm ; itailale Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year — — "»* Rate per cent of dividends declared on running atock daring year— **'%% Rate per cent at Interest charged borrowers during y««r •* </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - Tliomas A. Evans Vice President _..- John J. Carter Secretary William L. Sprague Treasurer .Milton C. Wingert DIRECTORS T. A. Evans J. E. Ayer J. E. Hoye D. V. Mc'Kee S. M. Nelson W. S. Warren E. E. Brittin J. J. Carter J. W. Cunningham ASSETS First mortgage loans * ra,200.00 Lonus on stock or pass book »ecurity - - — 1,300.00 Ultimo u»l Diuv» «• |iu«o uvvm n *.u...j - i^ CggQ _ _ „.„ 1.06 Delinquent interest, flues, etc 378.56 Tott] _ * 74,880.21 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - * 6 1"SIS"$J Reserve fund — 'StSvS 215.00 Undivided profits 216.00 Aflvnnre nflvmpnts „ - - J.101..W Advance payments- Auranre pijmcui. — - - - oiivwm Matiured stock 8,00000 ToU] _ _ _ f 74,880.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p149">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 149 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report — ,. f 66-58 Dues (running stock) .■ 12,706.22 Mortgage payments 1.G0U0O Interest 4,720.71 l'rt'iuiuni — &gt;w— — ..... - i ii 833. 06 Fines lfil.86 Membership and transfer fees ............ ,,,, SH.75 Xotil f 19,630.16 DlSBUUSl :mknts Mortgage loans I 10,100.00 Stwk loans_ 1,1UUOO Withdrawals, running stock and dividends- 7,630.30 Salaries - 410.00 Other expense 49.70 Cash on hand ', — — 1.68 Interest on withdrawals 215.72 Interest on advance payments 112.78 1.68 Interest on advance payment Total f l»,«20U6 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT PUn of association Serial and Permanent Number of series issued since organization 12 Number of shares issued since organisation 5,150. Number of shares outstanding last report 1702 Shares issued since last report 34H Total 2,000 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report M&gt; Number of shares in force this date 1,781 Number of shares on which dnes are delinquent 54 NuhiUt of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 44 Average running time of stock matured during the year 114 months Number of borrowing stockholders 68 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 96 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 3 Number of loaux made for building purposes during year 7 Plan of premium. .._ Fixed Par value of each share of stock f 100.00 Total amount of dnes delinquent at this date 207.00 Amount of &lt;luen owing by borrowing stockholders— 207.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 17L55 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 5 3,400.00 17L55 Amount of loans on improved real estate 73,200.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 150,000.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 96,605.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1044*80.00 Amount credited to reserve fnnd during year 188.53 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4,134.51 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 6.6% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year U% </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WYMORE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WYMORE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President _ J. A. Reuling Vice President _ _ _ A. T. Sherman Secretary „ _ G. T. Stephenson Treasurer » _ W. A. Dawson Attorney - E. N. Kauffman DIRECTORS J. A. Reulinjr W. A. Dawson C. N. Miller A. T. Sherman M. J. Moran G. T. Stephenson D. A. Lasher ASSETS First mortgage loans _ $ 7fl.siin.nn Oagh - - .'1,5*17.76 Delinquent Interest, flues, etc , 185.00 Furniture and fixtures 216.00 Taxes paid - 45.0T&gt; Insurance. ....... .....___.__..__.» — 34.35 Personal accounts - - 18.90 Total — - ♦ 83.807.06 LIABILITIES Running Hock and dividends. „ * 26.423.71 Paid-up stock and dividends 53.000.00 Reserve fund - 8)10.00 Undivided profits'! _ - : - 1.5H3.35 Tortl $ 83.S07.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p151">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 151 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Caiih on hand last report $ 1.S33.61 Hues i run ni ml' stock) 15.171.81 • !'ii Id up slock 2S.MD.0li Mortgage payment* 6\85oloo Ut.il estate »alcs _ 1.607.45 Interest e.LViO.rifi Membership ami transfer feet- 547.75 Total. $ samo.is DISBII SI MEXTS Mortgage loans _ _ $ 33.2.1O.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends _ _ 10.Sil.32 Withdrawals, paid-up stock _ _ Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock 5,200.01 1 2.S77.5K Salaries _ _ 650.00 Other expense r.H.ir, Real estate accouut _ .. 1.607.45 Cash on hand _ 3.507.76 Furniture and fixtures _ _ 16.00 Insurance - _ 31.15 Surplus '. _ 2S5.OO Miscellaneous _ _ _ 133.27 Total _ I 68,070.18 srrri.EMENTAL report Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 2429 Number of shares outstanding last report 1227 Shares Issued since last report- _ 726 Total - 1JK3 IM Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 116 Number of shares In force thU date _ 1.S37 IM Number of shares In force this date.. Numl&gt;er of shares on which does are delinquent 108 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues.... 57 Nnmjier of borrowing stockholders _ 107 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 138 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 14 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 25 Par value of each share of stock $ 101. 00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - 750.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 400.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1SR.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - - 79,800.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been mnde 136.48S.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ _ 500.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made...- - 1.500.00 been made.. Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 07.000.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 84.675.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 283.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2,107.96 2.KT7.96 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 2.263.36 ■»nt of dividends declared on running stock during year 10% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ T7r Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year.. 9.ft% </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - Geo. W. Shreck Vice President _ Chas. A. McCloud Secretary _ ~ Hattie S. Reed Treasurer - Geo. H. Holdeman Attorney W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS W. L. White Geo. W. Shreck Geo. H. Holdeman Chas. A. McCloud W. W. Wyckoff Hattie S. Reed Harris M. Childs Wade H. Read ASSETS Flr»t mortgage loans - $124,000.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ 3,000.00 Other real estate - .1.283.97 Canh 5.SO4.10 Delinquent Interest, lines, etc. SMI Furniture and fixtures 256.38 Taxes paid 7.88 Other asset*, note 250.00 Total _ $138,921.16 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. I132.819.8D Reserve fund 6,090.84 Undivided profits . 1.43 Total »1S8,921.1« </seg>
            <seg id="p153">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 153 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report...- | 1,486.10 Dues (running stock)...-. — 54,779.40 Mortgage and stock loan payments - 62,800.00 Real estate sales _ 800.00 Interest and premium. _ _ 11,116.04 Fines _ _ 1,108.25 Membership and transfer fees - 460.00 Total - $132,550.85 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage and stock loans .. ,.._„.„ 41,300 AlUriKOKv ttUU Slv't-Jfc. I Ua ||i^ , I,,, , ,■■■■■■■■ , 1 1 ■■! ■ i ■■■ Ajy Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 84,238.96 Salaries - - 780.00 Other expense— — 344.38 Keal estate account.. - — —. - - 23.38 Cash on hand _ 5,864.10 23.38 Cash on hand.. Total—— $132,550.85 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ - Serial and Permanent Number of series issued since organisation 48 Number of shares issued since organisation 28,918 Number of shares outstanding last report _ _ .5208 Shares issued since last report. 1160 Total - 6,368 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 1,574 1,574 Number of shares In force this date 4,79* Numl&gt;er of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 50 Average running time of stock matured during year 85 months Number of borrowing stockholders — - 119 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 400 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 6 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 24 Par value of each share of stock f 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ - _ 308.40 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 258.84 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 226.40 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 2 Amount of loans on Improved real estate — 123.400.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate.. Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made. _ _ - 24O '999-99 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 600.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hJiTS been made- 1,500.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - — 126\n00.00 as collateral security Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 12 ? &gt; 2£?-2? Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year. 9 ' o3? 120,000.00 Amount or dividends deciarea on running siock &lt;iuriug jwr. »."^" Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... 8% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p154">TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 154 STATEMENT of the condition of the WORKINGMEN'S SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1916 OFFICERS President - - C. A. McCloud Vice President _ - -N. A. Dean Secretary W. W. Wyckoff Teasurer - Geo. H. Holdeman Secretary Attorney - W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS C. A. McCloud N. A. Dean W. W. Wyckoff Geo. H. Holdeman ASSETS First mortgage loans * l 8 -:£0-&lt;» Loans on itock or pass book security 300.00 l-ash ' 915-42 Tot«I_ - * 17,415.42 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends- * 18 'ii2'nn nuDUIHB »lWf:» auu umuruuD- -r — »r*w\iwi Doe shareholders on incomplete loans ISJ.SS uuc Buareuviucra uu 1111 ,'ui|fittic ivhuci - -- r Reserve fund 4 *' £ jvescrvc iuuu — — ...—.■ - — — - ■■- — ••— TJndrrtded profits. «"■* $ 17,415.42 Totml. </seg>
            <seg id="p155">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 155 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1916 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report f 3.0G1.47 Due» (running stock) 6.33G.00 Mortgage payments _ 4.800.00 Interest ~ 1,223.50 Premium - - 68.00 Fines - 1O.20 Membership and transfer fees 21.75 Total I 15,510.01 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans. _ :.._ - * 3.900.00 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 9,884.34 Withdrawals! paid-up stock...- 464.00 Withdrawals, dividend on paid-up stock - 138.00 Other expense - - - - - 4.00 Cash on hand - 915.42 Interest on stock withdrawn _ 208.25 Total - * 15,510.01 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association — - Perm " ne »t Number of shares issued since organisation - - ~~- 1.939 Number of shares outstanding last report 886 VI eUffllCB vuioiuuuiu^ i«o» »-t*~.. Shares Issued since last report...- - - »1 Total — ._..._. — '— - - - . " .« 8hii«^iFhSiiiw¥."'in«toiped~or''c«nceUed since iast report m Number of shares In force this date - JJ» Average running time of stock matured during the year 77H month* Number of borrowing stockholders - 28 :&gt;umuer oi uurruwiug blwiuulmcio — — — Number of non-borrowing stockholders •■■ - - *&lt; Number of loans made for purchasing of homestead! or payment of homestead mortgages during year * Plan of premium. 2 per cent on face of loan ,„&lt;»&lt;*» Par value of each share of stock - ♦ .-■""{■JJJ far value o* eacn suarc oi mwi ▼ t »iJi« Amount of loans on improved real estate _ - io.jw.wi Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have have been made r - 7 15,«oo.oo Amount of lire insurance In force and assigned to the association as 2310000 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association mn/m as collateral security- ' A8» *«*...■.» *,~..1itnH tn w£*narvn film! ilupltlff V«»H T — — «"' w Amount credited to reesrve fund during year — liwvX Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during year — - 1 'Viw Rste per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.- (V4% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year. -gr-— ,.„ nf ..{.„ ti.k. n»r »nt nf Interest chanced borrowers during year 2% on face or loan Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year- </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>