<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Corn Supplements and Substitutes for Fattening Lambs</title>
               <date value="1926-02">1926-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">February, 1926 Bulletin 211 Corn Supplements and Substitutes for Fattening Lambs 1SY H. D. FOX THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT. DIRECTOR artment uf Animal Husbandry </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY OF EXPERIMENT NO. 1 OCTOBER 14, 1924, TO JANUARY 22, 1925 PART I. ADDING LINSEED MEAL AND CORN SILAGE TO A RATION OF SHELLED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY Where 0.17 pound of linseed meal was added to a daily ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay, the lambs made considerably larger gains. These lambs did not seem to get off feed so easily as did those lambs which were not fed linseed meal, and they consumed considerably less corn and hay in producing 100 pounds of gain. The lambs fed linseed meal made a somewhat higher dressed yield, made cheaper gains and returned a larger profit per head than did those lambs which were not fed linseed meal. Where corn silage was added to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay, the gains made were slightly larger and less corn and hay were consumed in producing 100 pounds of gain on the lambs. The silage - fed lambs made a somewhat higher dressed yield, a trifle cheaper gain, and returned slightly more profit per head than did the lambs which were not fed silage. The lambs which were fed a ration of corn, linseed meal, corn silage, and alfalfa hay made the largest and cheapest gains that were made in any of the four lots in this group. They also made the highest dressed yield and returned the greatest profit per head. It seemed that the feeding of the linseed meal was particularly beneficial when silage was also fed. PART 2. FEEDING TANKAGE AND BARLEY The lambs which were fed tankage in addition to shelled corn and alfalfa hay ate a trifle more corn and made somewhat larger gains than did those lambs which were fed only corn and alfalfa hay. Th£ dressing yield was somewhat less for the tankage-fed lambs, but the cost of 100 pounds gain was 10 cents more. However, they made slightly more profit per head, due chiefly to the larger gains which they made. The lambs fed barley consumed more feed, and made somewhat larger and cheaper gains than did those fed corn. Due to the larger and more efficient gains, the lambs fed barley returned 23 cents more profit per head than did the corn-fed lambs. However, the corn-fed lambs made a slightly higher average dressed yield than the barley-fed lambs. Where barley was fed during the first half of the feeding period and corn during the latter half, the lambs made somewhat larger gains than did the lambs in the lots where only barley or corn was fed. Their gains were also cheaper, the dressing yield higher, and the profit per head greater. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY OF EXPERIMENT NO. 2 FEBRUARY 10, 1925, TO APRIL 10, 1925 PART I. FEEDING LINSEED MEAL AND ALFALFA MOLASSES MEAL WITH SHELLED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY The lambs fed 0.15 pound of linseed meal per head per day ate considerably more corn than did those lambs which were fed only corn and alfalfa hay. They appeared to have keener appetites and did not get off feed so easily as did those lambs which were not fed linseed meal. The gains which these lambs made were materially larger, and somewhat cheaper. They also made a higher dressed yield, sold for 50 cents more per hundred pounds, and returned 58 cents more per head than the lambs fed only corn and alfalfa hay. Where approximately one-half pound of alfalfa molasses meal was added to a ration of shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay, the lambs consumed a larger amount of feed, and as a result, considerably larger gains were made. The gains made by these lambs were cheaper, the dressed yield higher, the selling price was 10 cents more per hundred pounds, and the average loss per head considerably less than for the lambs which were fed a ration of shelled corn, linseed meal. and alfalfa hay. The lambs which were fed corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa molasses meal did not make as large or as economical gains as did the lambs which were fed corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal and alfalfa hay. These two lots of lambs made the same dressed yield; but due to considerably more expensive gains and also to the fact that they were valued on the market at 20 cents less per hundred pounds, the lambs that received no alfalfa hay returned a larger average loss per head than the lambs which were fed alfalfa hay. PART 2. FEEDING SHELLED, CRACKED AND GROUND EAR CORN WITH ALFALFA MOLASSES MEAL When fed in conjunction with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal, cracked corn produced better results than did shelled corn. The lambs fed the cracked corn made materially larger gains, and the amount of feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain on these lambs was considerably smaller. These lambs showed more finish and produced a higher dressed yield. The cost of gain was less for these lambs, and as they were valued at 35 cents more per hundred pounds the loss per head was much less than for the lambs fed shelled corn. The lambs fed ground ear corn made materially smaller gains than did those fed cracked corn. The corn required to produce 100 pounds of gain on these lambs was considerably larger, the cost of gain was higher and the selling price 10 cents less per 100 pounds. When fed in conjunction with alfalfa molasses meal, ground ear corn furnishes more bulk than is desirable for fattening lambs. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Corn Supplements and Substitutes for Fattening Lambs Experiment No. 1 October 14, 1924, to January 22, 1925 BY H. D. FOX OBJECTS 1. To determine if it was advantageous to feed linseed meal in conjunction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay. 2. To find out if corn silage could be fed to advantage in conjunction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay. 3. To find out if it was advantageous to feed both linseed meal and corn silage in conjunction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay. 4. To find out if tankage could be fed to advantage in con - junction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay. 5. To compare barley and corn as feeds for fattening lambs. 6. To get data concerning the advisability of feeding barley during the first part of the feeding period and corn during the latter part, both being fed in conjunction with alfalfa hay. PLAN Seven lots of 30 lambs each were fattened for market on different rations. They were purchased on the Omaha mar - ket during the first week of October. In dividing these lambs into lots, special care was exercised in order to make the lots uniform in respect to conformation, quality, weight, condition, sex, and wool type. The following rations were fed: Lot 1. Shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2. Shelled corn, linseed meal, alfalfa hay. Lot 3. Shelled corn, corn silage, alfalfa hay. Lot 4. Shelled corn, linseed meal, corn silage, alfalfa hay. Lot 5. Shelled corn, tankage, alfalfa hay. Lot 6. Barley and alfalfa hay. Lot 7. Shelled corn, barley, alfalfa hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 EQUIPMENT The experimental feeding plant in which this test was conducted consisted of an open shed 20 feet deep, which was divided into 10-foot sections opening into small open lots on the south. These lots, including the space under the shed, were about 70 feet long. Flat-bottomed grain troughs, which were placed in the open lots, were used. Hay racks with tight bottoms and vertical slats 4 inches apart were pro - vided. Water was provided in galvanized tubs. WEIGHTS The lambs were weighed individually on 3 consecutive days at the beginning, and again at the close of the experi - ment; an average of these 3 weights was taken as the initial and final weights, respectively. The lambs were also weighed in groups at the end of each 28-day period to ascertain the progress they were making. The weights were taken in the morning after the lambs had finished eating. Each lamb was identified by means of an ear tag number. METHOD OF FEEDING The corn, linseed meal, barley, and silage were fed in troughs in the yards, but the hay was fed in racks which were located under the shed. The concentrated feeds were mixed together when fed. The silage was fed first and the grain feeds were spread over it. The tankage was fed mixed with the corn during the first four weeks of the test, but during the remainder of the test it was placed in a small trough which was located under the shed. It was thought that when the tankage was fed in the trough with the corn, it might cause a decrease in the consumption of corn. The lambs did not seem to relish the tankage very much at first, but after a time they seemed to have a desire to eat more of it. However, the total amount consumed during the test was quite small. The lambs in Lot 7 were fed barley and alfalfa hay during the first half of the feeding period, and corn and alfalfa hay during the latter half of the period. The change from barley to corn was made very gradually. Two weeks were required to complete this change. The lambs in each of the lots were started on approximately one-fifth of a pound of concentrates per head, per day. The quantity was grad - ually increased until they were practically on a full feed at the end of four weeks. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Fattening Lambs DESCRIPTION OF LAMBS The lambs were of choice quality and were quite low set, blocky, and uniform in size and appearance. Most of them were dark faces and of medium wool type. . They were bred in Wyoming and the majority of them were apparently the produce of Hampshire rams on Western ewes. The average weight per head at the beginning of the test was about 59 pounds. The purchase price on the market was $13.00 per hundred pounds; but when they were started on the experi - ment a few days later, the total cost was $13.30 per hundred pounds. This includes the cost plus freight, commission, and the feed which they ate from the time they were purchased \on the market until they were weighed into the experiment. FEEDS The corn used was No. 3 yellow which tested 15.0 per cent moisture. The barley used was of good quality and tested 13.5 per cent moisture. The linseed meal was old-process, pea size. The tankage was Meat Meal Digester, containing 60 per cent protein. The corn silage was made from corn estimated to yield 40 bushels of corn per acre and 9 tons of silage. The alfalfa hay was of fairly good quality. PRICES OF FEEDS In making the financial calculations, the prices used for the various feeds represent average market prices in the state during the time the experiment was in progress. The prices of feeds are as follows: shelled corn $1.12 per bushel, barley 84 cents per bushel, linseed meal $50 per ton, tankage $65 per ton, corn silage $7 per ton, alfalfa hay $15 per ton. HART 1— ADDING LINSEED MEAL AND CORN SILAGE TO A RATION OF SHELLED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY By comparing the results obtained in Lots 1 and 2, it will be noted that where 0.17 pound of linseed meal was added to a daily ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay, the lambs made more rapid gains. This was undoubtedly due to the fact that they ate considerably more corn and a trifle more hay in addition to the 0.17 pound of linseed meal. The lambs fed linseed meal did not seem to get off feed so easily </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 as did those which were not fed linseed meal. Where linseed meal was fed, considerably less corn and hay were consumed in producing 100 pounds of gain. In this connection, it will be noted that 54 pounds of linseed meal replaced 78 pounds of corn and 77 pounds of alfalfa hay. The lambs fed linseed meal made a somewhat higher dressed yield, and at prevailing prices of feeds made cheaper gains and returned a larger profit per head than the lambs which were not fed linseed meal. The replacement value of the linseed meal in pro - ducing gains on the lambs was about $80 per ton. TABLE 1. — Adding linseed meal and corn silage to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot Lot 4 Shelled c Shelled corn Shelled corn Linseed Rations Shelled corn Linseed Corn silage meal Alfalfa hay meal Alfalfa hay Com silage Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Number of lambs per lot 30 30 3C Average initial weight per head, Its 58.66 59.40 59.16 59.18 Average final weight per head, 16» 82.66 90.20 85.16 91.38 Average gain per head, H&gt;« 24.00 30.80 26.00 32.2i Average daily gain per head. U&gt;« . .240 .308 .260 JBI The results of adding corn silage to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay are shown in Lots 1 and 3. Where the silage was fed the gains made were somewhat larger and the daily consumption of corn was also greater. However, in producing 100 pounds of gain on the lambs, less corn and less hay were consumed where the silage was fed. It will Average daily ration. Ibt. per hrad: Shelled corn Linseed meal _ ~.. Corn silase .™™......... ........ — t Alfalfa hay 1.16 M| __■_■ .__.. I 1.22 .w 1.25 .18 .7.1 .75 Feed required per 100 pounds fcain. D&gt;».: Shelled corn _ Linseed meal Corn silage _ - Alfalfa hay I 483 405 i _ 54 _ S96 319 i j- 469 268 298 | 388 M 217 233 Averaue dressing percentage Cost of feed per 100 pounds sain Value per cwt. at market ] Profit per lamb I 50.21 50.63 $12.64 tll.85 17.50 17.50 2.S0 2.90 50.84 $12.56 17.50 2.43 50.96 SU.62 17.50 3.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Fattening Lambs 9 be noted that 268 pounds of silage replaced 14 pounds of corn and 98 pounds of alfalfa hay. The silage-fed lambs made a somewhat higher average dressed yield, a trifle cheaper gain, and returned slightly more profit per head. The replacement value of the silage was $7.60 per ton, so that with the prevailing prices of feed there was a slight advantage in feeding the silage. The results obtained in Lot 4, where both linseed meal and corn silage were fed with corn and alfalfa hay, show that feeding of the linseed meal was particularly beneficial when silage was also fed. The lambs fed this ration made the largest and cheapest gains of any of the four lots in this group. They also made the highest dressed yield and returned the greatest profit per head. The replacement value of the linseed meal in this lot was $85 per ton, while that of the corn silage was $9 per ton. PART 2. — FEEDING TANKAGE AND BARLEY The data in Table 2 show that where tankage was fed to the lambs the rate of gain was increased and the con- Table 2. — Feeding tankage and barley Lotl Lot 5 Lot 6 Lot 7 Shelled corn i Barley Rations Shelled corn Tankage ! Barley Corn Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Number of lambs per lot 30 30 30 30 Average initial weight per head, 16s 58.66 59.13 58.59 59.30 Average final weight per head, lbs 82.66 85.23 84.89 87.10 Average gain per head. !6s 24.00 26.10 26.30 27.80 Average daily gain per head, 16s .240 .261 .263 .278 Average daily ration. 168. per head: Shelled corn ' 1.16 1.21 ! .75 Barley 1.43 .56 Tankage j — .06 ' , • Alfalfa hay | .95 .96 .94 .99 Feed required per 100 pounds gain, 16s.; Shelled corn 48S 463 268 Shelled corn Barley _ ! 645 201 Tankage — I 23 i Alfalfa hay - 396 J67 357 355 Average dressing percentage I 50.21 50.04 49.96 50.47 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain- $12.64 $12.74 $12.21 $11.54 Value per cwt. at market— 17.50 17.50 17.50 17.50 Profit per lamb 2.30 , 2.39 2.53 2.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 sumption of corn was also somewhat greater. It was several days after the tankage was first fed the lambs before they ate an appreciable amount of it. At first the tankage was mixed with the corn when fed, but later it was placed in a small trough under the shed and kept before the lambs at all times. They visited the trough quite regularly and appeared to relish a small amount of the tankage. Based on the cost of making gains on the lambs the replace - ment value of the tankage was $55 per ton. The dressing yield was somewhat less for the tankage-fed lambs. But notwithstanding that the gains on these lambs cost 10 cents more per hundred pounds, they returned slightly more profit due to the larger gains which they made. By comparing the results in Lots 1 and 6, a conception may be obtained of the comparative feeding value of the corn and barley. Here it will be noted that the lambs fed barley consumed more feed, and made somewhat larger and cheaper gains than did those fed corn. Due to the larger and more efficient gains, the lambs fed barley returned 23 cents more profit per head than did the corn-fed lambs. However, the corn-fed lambs made a slightly higher average dressed yield. Based on the results of this test, the barley at 84 cents per bushel was a more efficient feed than corn at $1.12 per bushel. The lambs in Lot 7, which were fed barley during the first part of the feeding period and corn during the latter part, made more rapid gains than did the lambs in the lots where only barley or corn was fed. These lambs made the cheapest gains of any of the four lots reported in Table 2. They also made the highest dressed yield and returned the largest profit per head. PART 3— PACKING HOUSE DATA As a result of the co-operation of the Dressed Mutton Department of Swift &amp; Company, we were able to get the dressed yield, the percentage of fat, and the grading of the carcasses of the lambs in each of the lots. In addition to the above facts, they also furnished a brief description of the carcasses in each of the lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Fattening Lambs 11 Table 3. — Packing house data Brief description of the carcasses of each lot: Lot 1. — Good kidney, good color, choice. Lot 2. — Heavy kidney, good color, choice. Lot 3. — Average kidney, poor color, just fair kind. Lot 4. — One condemned, cystitis trouble, heavy kidney, good color. Lot 5. — One bruised, good kidney, good quality. Lot 6. — Fair kidney, fair color. Lot 7. — Heavy kidney, good color, choice. Lot 1 Lot 2 Lots Lot 4 I Lots Lot 6 Lot 7 : I | I Rations L Corn : Barley Corn Corn 1 Linseed Corn Barley Corn Corn Linseed Silage meal Tank- Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa meal Alfalfa Silage age hay hay hay Alfalfa hay Alfalfa Alfalfa LJ"^J 1 -\ - | j AveraKe dressing percentage.. 50.21 50.63 50.84 50.96 50.04 49.96 50.47 r i Average percentage of fat 2.1 2.4 2J» 2.1 2.0 2.1 2.» Grading of carcasses : Special Good Medium Heavy _ I ' 5 6 9 4 9 8 6 21 18 18 17 14 20 20 1 ' ! 1 1 2 5 2 8 2 i 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 1 ?( I ■^ 9 -^ * '- ~ 4. -C = *S B o 4 i - "fi C 3 «s 5 -; A &gt; i I 5 ~ S X — s .2 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 • ttua , 00 ... &gt; - - &gt;* «5 c ? r 1°9 c^ "i °? : : ; — ** T &lt;x ? c^ cs ! o ? t "! L ° r 1 u ? 0( ? ♦- * ' — F*3 o» t» t-&gt; * oc © : : :irii-i © i&gt; co * "rHe^eo^c^ 9 1 !:&gt; iiooon ve : : :to ih iq hhooth J g mu« i NN i» * • •* •» — _: # OS OS O CD [m : : !iH rH CO *nf ff.aoff.tf^ •:s - iooocc&lt;N :t- : : &gt; n oi h- ci w cc w u: x h l: 3^*m o6 -^ «o : V : : i «o ci oi t^co'^t^o^c-i — | H •»»" is ! i ;g s. * * rtrt0 °^ 15 ■^ I S g _ °^°. a ! nmcxe ! o i i «o In •• enBjoMeMNolS*^ ■Jo Ec"« "5&lt;»^ » i i« ig £ &gt;» „ rtrHOOjJ ■». P.IO _Z1 &lt;Se!&lt; »£•* «U ' ' ' xxscq w isc irt 1 * « tp t»»ieO!«o«a* i,. &lt;t Jo E*8« looseo ao : u: : i-i n i-i to hhooh S-St g Lls 1 w : !ww r _!___ * "^ " I S?g o g " n cecooco ifl : : :ho « i« r-r — r ~. t~ ~ ~ z -- S • hho« os : ; ; m e to oo «nn«t-ifir&lt;n« o ri: l-x:i « : : :ea ri u hiiooh * J e .^_ 5 -.^ ' : _ . 1st c5«S oo ... h a. «"2 J " oo^o o !»h : :oo ta cc ouMcoioiOoao ffl*i "8 a ■* e i«&gt;™ =1 : T : i °*. °". &lt;". nannSionoo: a * Jg 9* _&gt;e'S; side ' io ii&gt; I ios r-i o t-^M ' 'nnvun n ~» ■Jo b* a to ai eo o : to i »H r-i us h^ooh lid 1 0^ I £E* 2 ~. a . O . . . . «! V •a ~* : «e «o o •* « : : i : «c ■* 1-1 on«««o«^o _, * - ~ t- IcocDOCj * ! : ; :h &lt;o :i xc *i^-i: -i-:: r lili s : i i I ; : i i i i N M ilTT j 4 i \ 4 I I i ' ■ J : i it i ! I 1 I ii ;* it 1 1 I if J| i TSa i SSjs 2 e ° : : : : : i oft g »»!-2« + j a B i » i iiHIiiiiililiaf! </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experiment No. 2 February 10, 1925, to April 10, 1925 BY H. D. FOX OBJECTS 1. To get data 'concerning the feeding of linseed meal in conjunction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay. 2. To get data concerning the adding of alfalfa molasses meal to a ration of shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay. 3. To find out if it is advisable to omit the alfalfa hay from a ration of shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa molasses meal. 4. To compare cracked and shelled -corn when fed in con - junction with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal. 5. To compare ground ear corn with both cracked and shelled corn when fed in conjunction with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal. PLAN The lambs used in this test were purchased on the Omaha market during the first week of February. From the 130 head purchased, 126 were selected and were divided into 6 lots of 21 lambs each. When this division was made, special effort was exercised in order to make the lots as nearly alike as possible in conformation, quality, weight, condition, sex, and wool type. The following rations were fed: Lot 1. Shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2. Shelled corn, linseed meal, alfalfa hay. Lot 3. Shelled corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal, alfalfa hay. Lot 4. Shelled corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal. Lot 5. Cracked corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal. Lot 6. Ground ear corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal. EQUIPMENT This experiment was conducted in the same feeding plant as was Experiment No. 1. The same equipment was used for both tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 WEIGHTS The manner and time of weighing were the same as in Experiment No. 1. METHOD OF FEEDING The corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa molasses meal were mixed together just before feeding and were placed in grain troughs which were located under the open shed which faced the south. However, in those lots where no alfalfa molasses meal was fed, the corn and linseed meal were fed in grain troughs which were in the yards and hay was fed in the racks which were located under the shed. The lambs that were fed alfalfa molasses meal were practically self -fed from the start, as feed was kept before them at all times. The lambs which were not fed molasses meal received a somewhat limited amount of concentrates at first, but they were gradually increased, as rapidly as it was deemed advisable, until they were on full feed. All lambs were fed twice daily. DESCRIPTION OF LAMBS Most of the lambs were white faces, medium wool type Wyomings, and graded as good feeders. They were fairly uniform in size and general appearance. The average weight at the beginning of the test was approximately 63 pounds. The cost on the market was $17.50 per hundred pounds, but when they were started on the experiment it was $17.80 per hundred pounds. FEEDS The corn used was No. 3 Yellow. The linseed meal was old-process, pea size, and the alfalfa hay was of good quality. The alfalfa molasses meal was composed of 30 per cent cane molasses and 70 per cent ground alfalfa hay. A number of samples of this feed were taken during the time the experi - ment was in progress and each sample was analyzed by the Department of Agricultural Chemistry. The following is an average analysis of the samples as reported by Dr. M. J. Blish, Chairman of the Department of Agricultural Chemistry : ANALYSIS OF ALFALFA MOLASSES MEAL Nitrogen Water Ash Fat Fiber Protein free extract Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 19.9 7.6 1.0 21.0 10.3 40.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Fattening Lambs 15 PRICES OF FEEDS In making the financial calculations, the prices used for the various feeds represent average market prices in the state during the time the experiment was in progress. The prices of feed are as follows: shelled corn, $1.12 per bushel; cracked corn, $1.18 per bushel; ground ear corn, $1.18 per 70 pounds; linseed meal, $50 per ton; alfalfa molasses meal, $28 per ton ; alfalfa hay, $15 per ton. PART 1.— FEEDING LINSEED MEAL AND ALFALFA MOLASSES MEAL WITH SHELLED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY The data in Table 5 show that the addition of linseed meal to a corn and alfalfa hay ration proved to be very beneficial. (Lots 1 and 2.) The rate of gain was increased materially, Table 5. — Feeding linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal with shelled corn and alfalfa hay Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Shelled Corn Shelled Corn Linseed Shelled Corn Shelled Corn Linseed meal Linseed Alfalfa hay meal Alfalfa meal Rations Alfalfa hay molasses Alfalfa meal molasses Alfalfa hay meal Number of lambs per lot. _. I 21 21 21 21 Average initial weight per head, lbs 63.60 62.97 63.51 6S.32 Average final weight per head. lbs 81.90 85.17 90.93 87.44 Average gain per head, lbs _ 18.30 22.20 2"!42 24^12 Average daily gain per head. lbs.. .305 .370 .457 .40: _ ! .305 .370 .457 .402 Average daily ration, lbs. per head: Shelled corn _ 1.26 1.40 1.55 1.49 Linseed meal ! .15 .18 .18 Alfalfa molasses meal _„ .52 .82 Alfalfa hay _ .83 .80 .42 Feed required per 100 pounds gain, Ibt. : Shelled corn 414 S77 340 371 Linseed meal I 40 38 44 Alfalfa molasses meal I i 113 205 Alfalfa hay 270 217 91 I Average dressing percentage..- 46.5 47.3 48.0 48.0 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain $10.29 $10.17 $10.01 $11.38 U» IWW 1«T1 JVU JWUIHIS K«lll *1V.£V (L'Mi »1U.U1 #11.00 Value per cwt. at market 14.00 14.50 14.60 14.40 Loss per lamb __ _ 2.85 2.27 1.92 2.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 Iich no doubt was due to the fact that these lambs con - ned considerably more corn in addition to the 0.15 pound linseed meal. In comparing the amounts of feed required produce 100 pounds of gain on the lambs in these lots, it 1 be noted that 40 pounds of linseed meal replaced 37 inds of shelled corn and 53 pounds of alfalfa hay. The lbs fed linseed meal made a higher dressed yield, made aper gains, sold for 50 cents more per hundred pounds, 1 returned 58 cents more per head than the lambs fed y corn and alfalfa hay. By comparing the results shown in Lots 2 and 3, some idea may be obtained of the value of adding alfalfa molasses meal to a ration of shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay. The lambs fed the alfalfa molasses meal made considerably larger gains, which were probably due to the fact that they consumed a larger amount of feed. These lambs were prac - tically self-fed from the start, and did not seem to get off feed so easily as did those lambs that received no alfalfa molasses meal. The results of this test indicate that a mixed bulky ration is safer and more likely to produce larger and more efficient gains on lambs that are self-fed than one not so bulky. The dressed yield was higher for the lambs fed alfalfa molasses meal, the cost of gain less, the selling price 10 cents more per hundred pounds and the average loss per head considerably less. The lambs in Lot 4, which were fed corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal, but no alfalfa hay, did not make as large or as efficient gains as did the lambs in Lot 3 where alfalfa hay was fed". The writer does not believe this dif - ference was due entirely to the rations, as the lambs in the former lot did not seem to be quite as " good doers," appar - ently not being as thrifty, as a whole, as the lambs in Lot 3 or as those in Lot 5. As a matter of fact, the largest gains were made by the lambs in Lot 5, which were fed exactly the same ration as those in Lot 4, except that the corn was cracked instead of being fed in the shelled form as it was in Lot 4. The lambs in Lot 4 made the same dressed yield as those in Lot 3. However, due to considerably more expensive gains and also to the fact that they were valued on the market at 20 cents less per hundred pounds, they made a larger average loss per head. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Fattening Lambs 17 PART 2.— FEEDING SHELLED, CRACKED AND GROUND EAR CORN WITH ALFALFA MOLASSES MEAL A comparison of the value of cracked and shelled corn, when fed in conjunction with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal, may be made by studying the results in Lots 4 and 5. (Table 6.) These results show up very much in favor of the cracked corn. The gains made were much larger, due, no doubt, to the greater consumption of feed in this lot. The amounts of feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain on the lambs are considerably smaller where the cracked corn was fed. These lambs showed more finish. This was borne out by the higher dressed yield which they made. The cost of the gain was considerably less for the lambs fed cracked corn, and as they were valued at 35 cents more per hundred pounds the loss per head was much less than for the lambs fed shelled corn. As has been previously mentioned, the lambs in Lot 4 did not seem to be quite as thrifty as those in Lots 3 or 5, and the writer is inclined to feel that the unfavorable showing which these lambs made was not due entirely to the dif - ferences in rations. It does appear, however, based on the Table 6. — Feeding shelled, cracked and ground ear corn vnth alfalfa molasses meal Ration: Number of lambs per lot... Average initial weight per head. (ha. Average final weight per head, Ibt... Average sain per head, lbs Average daily &lt;tain per head. lbs.. * Reduced to a shelled corn basis Average dnily ration, Iba.: it (i : Shelled corn Cracked corn Ground ear corn Linseed meal Linseed meal Linseed meal Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa molasses meal molasses meal . molasses meal I 21 w IVi.3&gt; I 87.44 24.12 .402 6S.11 92.09 28.98 .483 21 62.75 87.47 24.72 .412 m Corn - Linseed meal _ Alfalfa molasses meal 1.49 .18 .82 .nn .18 XI .1H .74 r eed required per 100 pounds Rain. lb». : Corn Linseed meal .. . .......... ) Alfalfa molasses meal 371 44 205 34r&gt; 38 186 405* 89 180 Average dressing percentage. Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain Value per cwt. at market Loss per lamb. .„„..„„. 48.0 til. 38 14.40 2.56 48.6 $10.82 14.75 1.96 48.0 $12.03 14.65 2.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 results of this test, that there are some advantages from feeding cracked corn. This is probably a more important consideration where the corn is mixed and fed with other bulky feeds than where it is the only concentrate fed. Where shelled corn was fed, the lambs seemed to pick it out from the mixture, so that the mixture which they ate would vary more in composition than where the cracked corn was fed. A uniform bulky ration seems to be ideal where it is desirable to feed for a short period and also where self-feeding is practiced. The results in Lots 5 and 6 present a comparison of the value of cracked and ground ear corn, when fed in conjunc - tion with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal. These results are considerably in favor of the cracked corn. The gains made were materially larger, but the consumption of grain was practically the same for the two lots. Where ground ear corn was fed, the corn required per hundred pounds gain was considerably larger, due principally to the small gains made by these lambs. The cost of gain was much higher ; and as the selling price was 10 cents less, these lambs made a greater average loss per head than those fed the cracked corn. The lambs did not eat a large amount of the ground cob, and as a result it was found necessary to clean out the troughs regularly. When fed in conjunction with alfalfa molasses meal, the ground ear corn furnishes more bulk than is desirable for fattening lambs. PART 3.— PACKING HOUSE DATA As a result of the courtesy and co-operation of the Dressed Mutton Department of Swift &amp; Company, it was possible for us to get the following facts concerning the desirability of the lambs in the various lots from the packers' viewpoint : </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Fattening Lambs 19 Table 7. — Packing House Data Lotl Lot 21 Lots Lot 4 Lota Lot 6 Shelled corn Shelled | Cracked ; Ground Shelled I Linseed corn i corn ear corn Shelled corn meal Linseed Linseed Linseed corn Linseed Alfalfa meal meal meal Alfalfa meal molasses Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa hay Alfalfa meal molasses molasses molasses Ration; hay ' Alfalfa meal meal meal hay Average dressing percentage 46.5 47.S 48.0 48.0 48.6 48.0 2.4 2.3 1.8 l.» Average percentage of fat 2.0 Grading of carcasse 6 6 2 4 3 Special S 6 6 2 4 3 Good _ 14 12 14 16 16 18 Good _ 14 Medium _.. 4 2 3 ■1 Heavy - 1 Brief comment on the carcasses of each lot: Lot 1. — Fair kidney. These poor color and poorest of the group. Lot 2. — Good kidney. Lot 3. — Good kidney. Lot 4. — Good kidney. Lot 5. — Good kidney. Lot 6. — Good kidney. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 i J= = O 6 a :-. 1 a co : : I oi&gt;MH : :eu)H : ;co © t-t-eneftoaust-coos . t- ■» r- •» : t- us *_ : !o «* &lt;-;osi-iwt";co'*«e&lt;i'«»; J&lt; »«c ; ;ocooo ;£* g hhooh » ■ »» I tes B s s I i* a ? 'IP &lt; OH ; no i — v -jz ~. zc — -r-Tj-^r- - oocd : no c i t T 1 "1 cy ? u 3^**! G ! u 5i(i£2i; «■* ii-ioo i-in ' - **coeQc&lt;i5is'S ■*O:»H^* iH HH00H C«-&lt;fc« B • 5 I "s US : iOONfl HMtlL'; CO o* t-i : i 'not-' as J- »O1N i CO H«W iHO 0*0005rHOOSOiCa;'a3.SS - Ln *•-! M "S o : ius iot-r-or- oo c ««- a; - N1ON i f CO 00 C^ i I- ri = - "-* r- V ?■ ;-: fia -- = 1 § if ; |« ill | i z i I = ifiil ill ['ft sign I ! fills ij ; smiiii^ i HiiHHiiiStfi&amp;iiis; i S I e2 &amp;*c3 u ! _ ! ' [-3 3"S =■1 ! «:«• t» ••• &lt; * : 3&lt;&lt; s»»»rtoMO&gt;eiiiT£ afi r&gt;» ■-■ c*n to fm ta ,^^ * ™ * iH : coot- as : :ooc«&gt;h|ooc r- w ■* &gt;* «o « ih I k &amp;t- [ i : : : . r Q. = •• ■ M i i-t |l&gt; © H»«O.^ONI&gt;t-- CO : IO Ii-J GO NNHMC»Orih;Nn Oi : t* JO t&gt; i—ci * "^-^r-irHc4 **" PS :H H* »— ,-ii-lOOrH Uj I I i - X - -1 &lt;oi ieooooo si : iojjoso Noot-oiwoOHic'l'Ss j_,"^* : "cq»ho6 'j co : : i in dco " "w^ncw "Sec ,ss!S|i I j J i I i jiJ j { Yd I j I j I MM* ,C i i ! ! i ! m" i S C 511: I"*** *,;!§?! i£m&amp; io&lt;!fe i 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Fattening Lambs 21 DISCUSSION A considerable amount of alfalfa molasses meal has been utilized in recent years, by lamb feeders in Nebraska and other states. The amount fed has varied materially, some feeders favoring a heavy allowance of this feed, while others have felt that a relatively small amount would give better results. This feed probably has been more popular and used to a greater extent by the larger feeders who purchase the majority of the feeds fed, than it has by those who feed a relatively small number of lambs or by those feeders who produce most of the feeds fed. It has been used extensively by feeders who make a practice of short feeding their lambs and more especially by those who use self-feeders. This feed is well suited to be used in this way, as it can be mixed with the grain feeds to form a bulky ration, which seems to be essential for best results where lambs are self-fed. The composition of this feed varies considerably, but the majority of it has been compounded so that it contains from 20 to 50 per cent of molasses and from 50 to 80 per cent of ground alfalfa hay. There is an abundance of this meal produced annually in Nebraska in an attempt to utilize to a better advantage a portion of the surplus alfalfa hay crop, since the manufactured product enjoys a somewhat lower freight rate than the hay, and furthermore, the hay is somewhat more completely utilized by lambs when fed in the form of alfalfa molasses meal. As yet. there has not been a sufficient amount of experi - mental work done at the Nebraska Station to give any definite information regarding the percentage of molasses which is likely to give best results. A similar statement may also be made as to whether cane or beet molasses can be expected to give better results. These are some of the prob - lems which we hope to make further investigations on in the near future. The feeding of alfalfa molasses meal probably will be most profitable when the following conditions exist: 1. When hay must be purchased, and particularly in a section where leguminous hay is scarce and high in price. 2. When it is desired to feed lambs for a short period, and especially where self-feeding is practiced. 3. When hay and corn are relatively high in price. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 211 22 When the following conditions exist, the feeding of alfalfa molasses meal is not likely to be so profitable: 1. When the feeds fed are produced on the farm, and particularly the hay. 2. When an abundance of cheap legume hay is readily available and where the corn is not so plentiful. Under such conditions relatively long feeding periods, with the extensive use of hay, often gives the largest net returns. 3. When hay and corn are relatively low in price. Based on the results of this and other experiments con - ducted at the Nebraska station, the writer feels confident that a considerable percentage of the death losses in feed lots is due either directly or indirectly to overfeeding on con - centrated feeds. It seems that one of the most critical times of the feeding period is when the lambs are started on feed. At this time some of the lambs have a tendency to gorge themselves if given all the feed they will eat; and where allowed to eat all the concentrated grain feeds they wish, losses frequently occur. Our results indicate that if a mixed bulky ration is fed at this time, there is little danger of a lamb eating enough to cause any very serious digestive troubles. As the lambs get accustomed to their new ration, the amount of grain in the mixture may be increased grad - ually and the amount of roughage decreased. It should be borne in mind that the majority of western lambs which have been brought directly from the range have had little to eat except relatively dry grass and their mother's milk. It seems logical, therefore, to expect some digestive disturbances if these lambs are allowed to gorge themselves on very con - centrated feeds which they have not been accustomd to eating. An attempt should be made so far as practical to feed, for a few days, feeds that are similar to those which the lambs are accustomed to eating. Some prairie or other dry hay can be fed to advantage at this time. The aim should be to make a gradual change in their ration. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Value of Corn Supplements and Substitutes The feeding efficiency of a corn supplement or a substitute depends primarily upon the follow - ing factors : 1. The relative prices of the supplements and substitutes as compared with the corn and the hay composing the basal ration. 2. The gains produced where .the supplements or substitutes are fed, as compared with those made where only corn and hay are fed. 3. Amounts of feed required to produce a given gain on the lambs when different combinations of feed are used. 4. Comparative selling prices of the finished lambs in the various lots. By keeping the above suggestions in mind, the feeder can use to advantage the facts given in this bulletin, in determining the combination of feed that is most likely to give best results with the existing prices of feed in his locality. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>