<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School AT KEARNEY, NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">OF THE S UPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School AT Kearney, Nebraska FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">&lt; &gt;FFICER* H. D. Schaff Ass't Superintendent. George T. Day Stenographer and Bookkeeper C. V. D. Bast en Physician. Ministers of Kearney ( haplains. K. E. Dillon .Manager Family A A. L. Moon Manager Family "B" T. A. Batcher Manager Family K. A. Case Manager Family "D" M. W. Perry Manager Family "¥.' </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Emtlemen : It gives me great pleasure to present for your con - •ation the Thirteenth Biennial Report of this school for biennium, ending November thirtieth, 1906. During the biennium just closed we have labored hard to improve our school along all lines, and we feel that, in a meas - ure, we have succeeded in placing it on a higher plane, in get - ting some few people to see the work that is being done from a correct standpoint. The sole object in maintaining a school of this nature ii make men, and equip them for independent citizenship. To take the unfortunate boy, who has not had a fair chance far in life, and who for some reason, is called a delinquent, a dependent, an incorrigible, a mendicant or criminal, and by anyway possible, instill new and correct ideas into him and send him out prepared to meet the realities of life as a man. The success of such a school must be measured only by the work of this kind it has accomplished; not how cheaply it has been maintained, nor how much revenue it has earned, but how many good, all round, competent, and useful citizens it has made &gt;f the "bad boys" with which it has been furnished. Eiourse, strict business principles, and economic rules should served in carrying on the business, but the succes - ; of the work done depends on the quality of manhood 1 out, and should be measured by that standard. It has been with this idea in view that we have worked during the time we have had charge of this school, and the results will have to be measured by the lives of the young men and boys whom we have sent out from our school, to take their places in the citizenship of the world. I take this opportunity oj" publicly thanking the governor of this great state, for the interest he has taken in our work and the support he has driven during all the time we have had charge of this school. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">270 Pthe Board of Public Lands and Buildings for their unqual - co-operation and assistance. To the officers, teachers, and employes of our school, for their efficient and faithful services. To the State Superintendent of Public Instruction, the faculty oi the University of Nebraska, and State Normal Schools, The teacher's bureaus, the courts, the probation officers, the charity organizations, the woman's clubs, the press of the state, the military department, the ministers, the W. C. T. U. organiza - tions, and to all the other people and influences that have so ably assisted in elevating the standard of our work. Very truly yours, B. D. HAYWARD. Superintendent. HOW THE WORK IS DONE P&gt;rder that you may understand something of our plan of I will give you a short synopsis of what is done. When a boy is received at our school, he is registered, ex - amined, had the rules explained to him and tWe object of the school, and what we expect to do for him and what we expect of him. He is then assigned to the family to which he is best suited. Flie family manager and his wife then get acquainted with i, have him bathe, change his clothes, and assign him a place the family. He then goes to the principal of schools, where he is exam - ined as to his school work, and assigned to the proper grade. Ethen starts to school, attending one half day, each day doing some kind of work during the other. In due time placed on a detail for some trade which he may choose e think him best adapted. We do not inquire into his past life, or the causes that brought him here. We prefer not to know them, so that we may not have any prejudices to overcome, and may be able to take him for what he is. Yet many times we have to listen to all of his shortcomings from his friends, neighbors and often his parents. We endeavor to find whatever good thert is in him and it usually predominates, and cultivate those qualities; restraining at all times the evil. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">271 Pus the work goes on day after day encouraging, restrain - leading, guiding, drilling, training, doing all we can to in - proper ideas and have him be governed by them. SOME HINDRANCES TO OUR WORK. A wrong idea of our school by the public generally. Lack of proper information by the courts who commit boys to our school. Ignorance of parents and friends as to the time necessary for the completion of our work. P continual annoyance from some parents and friends for parole of boys before they are ready. Attempts made by some lawyers, for a consideration, to have boys released on a technicality, whether they are deserving or THE COTTAGE OR FAMILY PLAN. Our school is conducted on what is called the family or cot- The boys are classified as to size, age and temperament, into families of about forty each, and these are placed in charge of a man and his wife who are to be a father and mother to them as best they can. Each family has a cottage, and lives separately from the rest and do not mingle with them any more than you do with your neighbor. Each family has its own tables in the dining room, au&lt;l its own play-grounds. When school is dismissed or their work is finished, they go to their several homes the same as all boys should do. In fact they are as distinct and separate from each other as can be made. LOCATION. ri state of Nebraska owes a debt of gratitude to the man located this school, for it is the universal opinion of the people who visit here, that not a more sightly, healthful, im - posing location could have been found in the state. The school is located 2 1-2 miles west from the city of Kear - ney on the main line of the great Union Pacific railroad. t buildings are on a high elevation overlooking the fertile valley with its fields of alfalfa and other crops for which &gt;ted. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">272 Rq the buildings may be seen the Platte river for a dis - of twenty miles winding its way like a silver cord pre - f a landscape beyond description. THE BUILDINGS. The buildings consist of one administration building, five fam - ily buildings or cottages, one industrial building, besides the "use, root house, boiler house, barns, etc. The family buildings, administration and industrial buildings, are made of brick, and are located around a square that is for the campus, these buildings are about one hundred and fifty apart, all facing south. There are wide cement walks all around the campus, and 1 ing to each building. EDUCATIONAL. In our educational work we endeavor to give our boys a good common school education at least. We have a graded school system so that a boy may be placed at once into the grade where he can do the best work. Our course of study does not conform strictly to that of the public schools, but is arranged to give the boys those subjects that we think more essential and will best equip him in the short time he is with us. The average time a boy is with us is about two years, and the work he gets here will, in many instances, be all that he will ever get in school. We have a principal of schools and a corps of good competent teachers and under our compulsory attendance we are able to accomplish good work. We are proud of our schools. LIBRARY We have a well selected and equipped library of fifteen hun - ored volumes and are adding to it each year. The books are all numbered and indexed and are issued by the librarian, by the card system the same as the city libraries. INDUSTRIAL WORK In our work here we pay particular attention to industrial training, believing that the trained hand is as necessary as the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">273 CARPENTER DEPAKTMl. In our earpenter departm* with a bench and -■■ them. ii.-iii. and keep them in shape for work, and is held personally unnble for them. From this department is done all tin i for the various bnildinga and much of the new b A hoy learna to do just siu-h work as he will ha }ip works at h TAILORING DKI'AKTMEXT. I our tailoring department all boys clothing, under . pillow-cases, table cloths, towels and everything in this sed by the institution are made. All the repairing s and nearly all the &lt;-iti/&lt; which are fnraii paroled, are made in this shop. SHOE-MAKING DEPARTMENT. In this department all the d* made and repaired side the harness, ball*, suspend) of the institution. LAUNDRY DEPARTMENT. ■ Laundry is one of our strong departments, not only use - d nerrssary. but very practical, and i trade in their a are in demand and well remunerai M A ( ■ H I N E R V DE HA RTMENT. tepartment boyi are taught to be plumbers, stea 1 lechanies, electrician*, engineers, blacksmiths, firemen, and general usefulness. A large number is ai i_ r tor an opening in this department. KITCHEN AND DIMNP, I ■ ind bakir lone for ist it ut ion : boys are taught to lie practical cooks and bak - id to manage and care for dining-room work. PRINTING DEPARTMENT I printing department is one of which we are very proud, well equipped with type, presses, and machinery and we ad to say with boys of ability. From this department are our monthly magazine "The Courier", which the ex - onal magazines issued in </seg>
            <seg id="p008">274 Knited and a Meekly paper called the Iixlnst rijil I Tinea. Both of these papers are practically edited ami bed by the tx I ring the past year we have not been alile he kin«l led 1&lt;&gt; luanagy this department and when - without a foreman tlie boys took full charge both, ntorial. and mechanical work. The last tin ir uagazine lire wholly the work of the boys. In addi - to this, all the printing for our schools and other depart &gt; of the institution is done from this ofti DAIRY DEPARTMENT Purinp the pat materially improved our Dairy I by adding a number of registered HoLrtein-Frieman .■ nn separator and chnrn and make mo - butter n» CEMENT STONE We have added a new industry of late in the nature of a nt bloc) machine and arc now able to manufacture jill i toi' bu]ldiuL r s mf* anv other imp' OTHER TRADES Eintiiijr. decorating:, paper-hanirini:. brick and stone la - taught during the summer and fall by haviner the t in making all the repairs in these various lit The results from our work in the various industrial depart - r« very gratifying : many boys are placed in thes. ho do not know their ability and in a short time ■ ver that they are able to do something and many be. rt workmen. It is a preat stimulant for educational work i learns the need of an education to make the beat of industrial work. It is also a great aid in discipline, for .reat trouble in governing is solved by furnishing the pupils with interesting and instructive work. Bhave applications for all the boys we can get ready from ' our departments at remunerative wages, and many of »ys are making a marked success in the trades learned i school. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">275 HORTICILTIKE Our campus and greenhouse afford a great opportunity • iiir hoys to study th iiid nurturing of plants. [1 Miig and interesting work and adds materially to i education. MILITARY. B! military instruction a boy n ■ i|iiitt' complete. We five well organized military companies, officered by ■ full officers: these companies are drilled regularly in military s and the manual of arms. During the summer months we battalion drill once a week. During the | ■ ?• the neral of th' loaned us some Springfield rifles, i has aided us very much in our military work. I are arranging to set apart one day eaeh year, which own as "military day" on which our various companies told their competitive drill and he thoroughly insp ■ military department of our Sti ATHLETICS. We have no regularly prescribed course in physical cult boys have their athletic ;dl. football, baskethall. ikating. and various other sports known only to a boy. They have an opportunity to exercise themselves in doinur the on the farm, and the other work incident to i 11 «jt up such an institution. We find work of this kind a sfactory substitute for regular physical training, and an not be excelled as a muscle developer. Eeach year, usually on the Fourth of July, we observe | On this day a fierce contest is waged in all field s| are given to the winners of each class: an institution kept of the winners and the records made each year and p ambition of the contestants to break the previous re&lt;- ■Id Day has become a part of the institution and is ] as the great event of the year. Ere have erected a gymnasium which is forty by sixty feet, as soon as we can have it equipped, we will be able to carry our work regardless of the weather. Ering the las' &lt;nir baseball and football teams phi mber of games with the surrounding High school \, the State Normal and Kearney Military Academy t&lt; made a very creditai' </seg>
            <seg id="p010">276 MCA I. DEF'ARTMENT W, .ihlishin- net musical department i and pi. it instn, It ia nrst class band here for th a t)n\ ! play well he is ready fur parole play in some other band, so that this department is musical instruction rather thai: about thirty \ popular and is making a very creditable showing. CHICKEN DEPARTMENT ta well equipped chicken department capable I f about five hundred hens. We also have a large ■arge of this department □ over to two hoys, who ■ 1 it during the ily. AGRICULTURE. B. I) Hay ward: I. ith have tl in- of handing yoii nial Report of the Agricultural and Horticultural tution. W. that the agricultural and horticultural world t" • profitable feal l&gt;eriod in the h culture — the the young lneii of to-day who follow the pursuits of the farm, large opportunities knowledge and the modern methods of fanning, and if carried out intelligently will give him md profitable returns. The farm drudgery is ?rad - ually but surely passing. ;. &lt;-al machinery is being in - ■ •essfulh I country hon^ becoming I | home. Th of the farm life is rapidly disappearing. The rural hone jming more inviting and beautiful each ing year, the architect, the landscape gardener, and the hole asp- ry life is being changed by the the coining of the electric rail- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">277 I by the interest being taken in the building of good roads, • and more comfortable vehicles, and by the rural free de- The new burning we predict will be intensive rather extensive. Kay of our modern houses on the farm are being lighted by &gt;r in other ways, just as modern : supplied with . piped wherever needed. Tl Dginfl pumps th&gt; Inirns the butter, and crushes the corn to meal. Libraries, al instruments, and trained vo to be found in unity. This life thus approaches the true ideal. Thus knowing of the prospective prosperity and ideal h ■ und in the future agricultural and horticultural I. we have daring the biennial period put forth ffort t" it id instruct those young men and tx e la- I in this department of the school. In the ini. for tlie results obtained, we ha\ reason to be ha]' ■nd the In. Minted for the A number of them have developed it workmen in the different bi liis depart! Bms been our aim to teach, not only, how to plow well, but e for the plow after usingr it: so has been n the use and care of all farm implements and machi en1 of the farm and its work In acres, the farm was neither increased nor diminished dm period. Hut for the best interests of the school, the S id purchase, at least, one half section of farm land ai. pasture land. The farm now .• About 'In acres are occupied by buildings, campus, drives, canal (with ponds and corrals, - - are planted to alfalfa - in pasture. f&gt; acres berries and fruit trees. HO acres was planted in bronp md alfalfa last spring, and the remain - are cultivated I farm in sreneral is in l; edition, beintr free from is weeds and neglected corners. The fences, shells, corrals, arns and the greneral equipment belonging thereto are in or fair shape. I account of a portion of the farm bein» hilly, the soil has e thin and the productive qualities depleted. This por - eeds fertilizine. which we expect to do as far as possible r the next three months We are short on grazing land, and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">278 the roughest 1 land was planted to bra I, with a 1 alfalfa 'I ill need to be fenced in Enproductive in a wet, or even an average ■ nut of it Laying in the fora of a basin. This The farm i r the biennial period have ■ ■ nes. In fa ral might be reeorded with b pride in behalf of the farm hoys and the manageme: ', a tract of about 20 acres in corn pro - rong per acre. This corn was of the Iowa Silver and was drilled in during the second week in May. as grown on alfalfa ground broken during the month of rn was hoed twice by the little boys, cult 1 The same year ti.iMMi bu. of potato ted fron .ring the grown :i of 1906 ire received no rainfall, r than enough to "'lay the dust" several times, for eighty - v Believing in the merits of "dry farming.'" we titivate until the 23d of July. Corn and potatoes cultivated In times. We were fa, •d yield- the corn made seventy bushel - while a part of the potatoes yielded at the rate of 150 bd. per * THE GARDEN Kng the dry period the garden was cultivated weekly, if all kinds urn in enormous quantities, and choicest varieties. A table following will show the quan - - here h ;&gt;lendid opportunity for acquiri ?h and practical drill in gardening. E greenhouse work never goes begging for apprentice ilmost daily. This branch of the department s an unusual! opportunity for thorough discipline, cal training and character building. The apprentice is t. and intensely so. to be exacting, prompt and business - le must learn: little things here cannot be neglected. Here </seg>
            <seg id="p013">279 he learn to and the care o germination, traus - ung, and everything connected with greenhouse work plant in B turned out o\ ■ 1 plants. These wen ■table, flowering, border and i.' plants. ■our campus work we lut\ i neither pains nor hard, ing work to make the floral display, with the eampm rronndings in general, interesting, attractive and beai. I the year of 1905, 114 1 - acres of fanning land was n 00 per acre: and ''&gt;-0 it cres of pasture land for - ear 114'j acres were ren1 and $1 aid fur pasture land. Prom the above report it can be ■ i that it would be a good busmen proposition for the wn mure land. The farm implements and machin - well as all are kept in Rood repair and under roof. CATTLE. The schuul is slaughtering its own cattle. This has been found g tod business as well as insuring the best quality of i herd is kept up by purchasing good young feed, to time and by fattening old and unsatisfactory milch cows. herd id' milch cuws has been built up until it now mm. about 40 head, including eight thorough-bred Ilolsteins. '. cattle on hand, including calves. 90. The products of the dairy will be reported elsewhere in this report. HOG9. I i re slaughtered per week to furnish the dem. •huul. The herd is of Jersey-Duroe breed. The surplus larketed from time to time. Total number on hand, inclu ages. 14'i HORSES. Rng this period we lost (died) one carriage horse and one It will be necessary to purchase two farm teams •r to carry on the farm work as it should be. One team of young farm horses was purchased during the period. All the bbor e team excepted) are old. Several teams are ■ worn out and should be replaced soon. The need of a L r team will soon be imperative. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">280 Kur farm h;r Id and well-worn that 1 ii the thing of the past It will require, very I ' &gt;n to the h utire h; r remodeled. The stalls irrow that iiiently sprain and injure tl ■ lying down and getting op. Farm horses, t In r : rivers, two; ponies, tw ■ FOl.IXnVIMI TABLE EXHIBITS THE FARM AND GARDEN PRODI' THE YEARS ltO6 AND 1906. 1906 • I 1"&gt; - 4+n 153 105 bushels 4ii 4n s.l Mil I lti.lKMI 22") bushels 4&lt;i 150 Rhubarb, bushels 60 210 190 160 Da, niadr tdr the halt' 12 :ldi ton* i 30 100 - 24£ l'7^ 12 ushels 200 ich, bushels 14 l^ Cauliflower, heads bushels bushels 1 ,( '&lt; M &gt; ."&gt;ll </seg>
            <seg id="p015">281 •40 10 200 mber pieklea, barrels 4 &gt;li. loads i rmelons, loads [melons, load* loads Strawberries, quarts 200 radish, bushels In 4 . beads Oats, bushels ishels The following produce was sold: Potatoes, 2,157 bu. : &lt;&gt;• ■ u.: iweel potatoes. li"&gt; bu. ; i; alfalf; tomatoes, 305 bu.; sweel eorn, 250 bu.: cabbage, 187' The balance was consumed by the imtitui pting the amountfl uM hand at present. In &lt;&gt;ur floral display on the campus, we had arra' ped tin- following different bulbs, floral, bedding, ami bor- plants: :ii|issin a Aehvraiitheutri Asters Poppies &lt; alendulas Asters ]'&lt;&gt;i&gt;|' : i.lissin ;i Achyrantheum May variety &lt; 'alendu I'yrethnini ■i i May variety I anthiro l'yrethnnn I'hvsalis I'liysalis Altemanthim Galardia (double) &lt; Jalardia I Kelway I Sweet ]'. lia ratum Lobelia ratuni Galardia (double) &lt; Jalardia I Kelway I Swirl P( Sweet William Stokesia Sweet William onette Mignonette SI ok. Morning Glory Seal' ■ks Sealii ■ks i mums Morning Glory Hollyhocks Hollyhocks uias IVtimias &lt; ieraniuins Phlox Marigold (Legion of Honor) Verbenas Daisv i Shasta i Sultaiitias • urtiunis Bsis l.ancaolata Trieaphylla Beans ( 'andytuft ( 'elosia ( annas ( rladiolas Marigold (Eldor Tritoma Pfit Zinnias </seg>
            <seg id="p016">282 In the growing, arrangement and care of these plants the much ini all have been pleased and the &gt;er-by and the traveling public have admired them. I am. Yours Vi ally, H. 1) SCHAFF, Assi Supt. HEALTH AND SANITATION. We are profoundly thankful for a great i if healtl: have enjoyed during the biennial. There I end no tioas di~ a fact we have had little sickne- : the minor troubles incident to child! and youth and a few c from at hi' We believe that eleanl for healthy eondit and we wage war againai dirt and filth in ly. We thoroughly cleansed and disinfected every portion of the in - stitution and keep this work up regularly. Wherever paper waiii- could be dispensed with it has been done and | and kalv ibstttnted, so that we are reasonably free from vermin of all ki: PHYSICIANS REPORT. B. D. Hayward. Supt. State Industrial School. Kearney. N'ebraska : Dear Sir: I have the honor to submit herewith my repoa 1 hysician to the State Industrial School for the past two y Owing to tl lentious care bestowed upon the physical well being of the bo\ If and Mrs. Hayward and others hem in charge, they have health about normal. They are a testimony to the value of outdoor work and play, whole - id and regular mode of life. From Nov. :&lt;0. 1904. to Nov. SO, 1906, I have in. xclusive of visits to pa - ts in the Kearney Public Hospital. Have made 1 animations, and have given out 9SC riptions. The are as follov Rinp worn 8 si bite 4 Indigestion 21 Biliousness and diseases of the liver 11 Malaria 9 throat 122 Congestion of chest and Inn- 9 r 18 ■ Ids. laprippe 40 Insomnia 1 Bl. 39 Iw 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">283 p, colic, diarrhoi Itch 16 Boils, abcesses, felons 74 1 ( 'onstipation Skin ilis. iry - thenia, acne, impeti: - 'smii, intertrigo lti Rheumatism, luml Headache II lip* and mouth I Gum boils 6 Stomatitis I s on hands, arms and B Enuresis s Worms 5 Hemorrhoids •&gt; Neuralgia 5 Asthma 1 se of heart I Enlarged and swollen md eyeli glands lti Peritonitis 1 General debility 5 INJURIES. Injuries of I arms. ■Is and fingers ,i 4 Burns 6 Sprains Amputation of finger 1 Dislocations I Ral of finger and toe - 8 Teeth extracted Bruises Warts Condylomats 2 Epididymitis 4 1 Balano Posthitis 1 Klist does not include many re throat, b . cuts aiul l)ruist's. which have a|i])lit'd to .Mrs. IIa\ ief. I beL p leave to thank you and Mrs. I lay ward for h - and unvarying courtesy, and to subscribe myself, Very respectfully yours. ('. V I). BASTEN. MORAL AXD RELIGIOUS INSTRUCTION. We have no resident chaplain at the institution, but rel i .. strvices are held every Sabbath afternoon at 2:30 o'clock, ducted by the ministers of the different churches in the cit Kearney. These ministers alternate in their work and assi^ much in carrying on the religious work of the institution. Our Sabbath school is held every Sunday morning from 1 E clock, and is conducted by the superintendent and assistant •intendent and grade manager and is made a regular part of the work of the institution. Cystitis f bladder 17 Toothache Re-dreaung &lt;&gt;t' wounds </seg>
            <seg id="p018">284 DISCIPLINE. Tli' &gt;f all training is discipline, whether it I the mind, bod; I- In our work we endeavor to ent - rain the evil. We encourage a boy to do r&gt; way ire can and make it as difficult a.s po - r&gt;r him to do wrong. We prefer to reward him for doing •r than to punish him for misbehavior. We keep pn the oat for ■ t, rather than for the bad. V in opportunity to suppress the wrong, however yet w&lt; in the old maxim. "The way to get rid of a riee is to put a virtue in i' To bring about the required discipline rt to all the ways and means known. All a ••■ated alike and we must apply the remedy thai m for the particular case Doses to be repeated a&gt; oft. - ssary REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS the biennium the following material improves) lar 4&lt;&gt;v and twelve feel high, and double-decked It is built of cement hi - • p of the cellar we have a building of the same &lt;|i liich is to be equipped for a gymnasium. have removed the kalsomine from all the dormitoi and play rooms, and many of the employee ■ painted the walls. w hard wood floors have been laid in the dorm i to - and halls. ■ library has been repaired by a new steel ceiling, and the haviuL' been painted, and decorated. A sew local intercommunicating telephone system has died connecting the various buildings with the offii K -bower baths have been constructed in the basement administration building for the use of the boys, which &gt;s in a measure the "Old Swimming Pool.'" which was fur - ns by the canal. have laid about twenty thousand square feet of cement walk, five feet wide all around the campus, and connect - the various buildings. ■ r-hauled and repaired our pumping-station and puttiiiL' new pipes and points in many of them. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">285 We have ii and improved our dairy herd and our I We have added new I it department*. Sag to tin 1 increased attendance to mir school, we to repair ;i large room in the third story &lt;&gt;f the admin uilding, (or u ehapel. B added over two hundred volumes of the lat. library. We have luiilt a large brick oven in our bak baking four hundred loaves of bn oe time. Bad our buildings and out buildings, departments, fan hing in general are kepi in as good repair as lierever an improvement can be made in any Hue. \ ii afford, we always try to make it. OIK NEEDS. r buildings are all in fair condition and will only J repairs including a larirc Dumbei 1 ceiling Bciur in. ittendanee, ami the probable inc g the next biennium. it is absolute), lary that we at least one new family cottage, which will cost, from I and to fifteen thousand doll, t boilers and engine have been patched up ami rep e last four years. Four of the hoi; old. The examiners now say that tw&lt; new boilers, and engine, will have to be put in next year These will ; ust five thousand dollars. Band should have a small well-equipped hospital, would cosi about fifteen hundred dolla E-h of the old steam line, running to the various bail' ecuine s&lt;&gt; rotten that it should be replaced by new pipe ■ another win ■nf tlie buildings should be painted outside and in e biennium. &lt; &gt;ur gymnasium should be equipped. ■ i one hundred more jruns for military purj need new black-boards for all of our schoolrooms. a complete new outfit of harness. ■ three new farm teams and one driving team to re - ■ and ha </seg>
            <seg id="p020">286 It that our school n mplish the best results up a strum; and substantial farm department, which will •ially aid in reducing the cost of maintenance, a section of land should be purchased, by the State, for its use. Imdred and twenty acres of farm land and hundred and twent\ &gt;f pasture land, in addition it we ha Kit has paid five dol - •e rent for farm land: this year we had to pag •s per acre and the outlook for D4 r is that we to pay seven dollars per acre for it. This does n&lt;H M if it can lie avoided. Tfc f rentinjr le uncertainty of &lt;rettin&lt;r it at any price makes it opinion, for the • purch; more land. Ire were thus equipped we could place this department un - ■tion of the state agricultural school and accomplish results along the line of scientific farming. To purchase mount of land would require an expenditure of twenty to i-five thousand dollars. Kuld recommend that iphy and typewriting should trht in our school so that many boys could equip them - with the- accomplishments: this could he done lall cost, the of which would be for the pur ■writ&gt; POPULATION E'lishment of ta 1 there have !■• hundred and twenty-six boys At Um of this biennium. the attendan one hundred and ty-one. and during the two years we have received one hun - and seventy-iiin. There have been one hundred i iroled durinpr this time, tearing the number of !it on Not. 30th. 1906, two hundred and fourteen. E explanation of the tables which follow, I will say that all mitted to our school are under its jurisdiction until arrive at the ape of twenty-one years. As soon as t k we have outlined for them, they are paroled re looked after by the school. The terms. "Boys pre - in actual attendance and those paroled </seg>
            <seg id="p021">287 ■".\ s iii attendance November '-W. 1!&gt;(&gt;4 of boys received from November 30, 1906 179 paroled diirinir the biennium .f boys preseni November 'inth. 1906 214 AGES OF BOYS PRESENT AND ON PAROLE. 5 No. 15 years of age Xo. 15 yean &lt;&gt;f age 50 t; 6 No. lti years of ai:&gt;- Mo. lti years of ai:&gt;- 56 No. In years of age 6 6 No. 1&lt; years of ai:e No. 17 years of ;ii:'- No 11 years of age 9 1 yean of aw No. 1- 96 No. 1- No. 1 14 No. 12 years of a«re "_'■"&gt; .' yet \o. ] ;i No 13 yean of age -"' No. 2n years of a*_'&gt;- No "Jn years of age No 14 years of age 4 years &lt;&gt;f jilt-- 50 BiL'e of hoys preaeni and on parole 15.25 years. II HS FROM WHICH BOYS PRESENT AND ON PAROLE WERE RECEIVED AND THE Xl'MBER FROM EACH Antelope Antelope Howard I Howard - son 7 Adams 4 Adami 4 son 7 Box Butte •') \in\ Butte •"&gt; Johnson :{ Johnson I Hurt 4 Hurt 4 Kimball I Kiinhail 3 Brown Brown - •) l\nox 2 l\ 1 1 1 1 x 2 BuflFalo Buffalo IV Lancaster .~&gt;4 Lancaster 54 i Lincoln 1:1 Lincoln -'■n 7 i ( 'nit' - Madison 7 &lt; li \ "' ■) Merriek L 1 Merrick ime 2 line 2 Nance | .Vance | ( ;isv .") Nemalia 7 Veinaha 7 ( Jherry 5 N'nckolla 4 ( "herrv 5 Nuckolls 4 Cmning 1 Otoe 7 Otoe 6 Pawnee "&gt; Pawnee ") as .•las Pierce 1 Pieree 1 ,n ."&gt; [Matte | I'liit Denel -2 Deoel 2 I'olk | Polk | ."&gt; Phelps 1 Phel 1 :&gt; 1 l Richardson 1 Richardson 1 7 7 Saline •_' Saline •_&gt; Fnrnas 1 Fiirn;is 1 Seward ti Sewmrd I Frontifr 1 Fn&gt;iitifr 1 Sarpy | Sarpy | Fillmore 8 Fillinore 8 Sheridan | Sheridan | 1 1 ScottS Blllff 1 Scotta Bluff l 14 14 Sioux 1 Sioux 1 • Jrant 1 • Jrant 1 Thayer Thayer ITarlan S Harlan S Thiirston i Thiirston l Hamilton 3 Hamilton 3 Valley 2 Valley Tlolt 4 ter i Webster i Hall B Wayne l Wayne l 171 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">288 OR WHICH BOYS. PRESENT AND PAROLED. \\ COMMITTED 88 6 Mendicity n.v 41 ary » It H' NATIONALITY OF BOYS. PRESENT AND PAROLED IS [ndiarm 1 a - 1 1 h ■&gt; 1 Swede Irish 1 4 German FINANCIAL STATEMENT In order to make clear the statement of "Appropriations and which follows, it will be necessary to give an tory explanation of the manner in which the amounts ppropriations are derivi Rthis biennial period began December 1st, 1904 and the i "priatioi not available until April. 1905. there were al months that we were using funds of the 1903 appropria- On Augusi 31. I'Mtn. however ihis appropriation la; - then remaining in all the funds reverted to bowing the balances in the various [and iennial period, to which are added the apjtroprations for 1905; from these totals, are deducted the which have lapsed on 31, 1905. The remain - imounts which have been actually at •sal during this period, and are used in the statement as ipriatioi Balance. Appr. Lapsed Net Appr K&gt;. 1904. 1905. Total. Aug. 31, '05. Available ' sal- E -;.■;.,-;:_■'■■ 58 $20.7' igea 17,000.00 21,524.35 4.49 21,51 1 15,000.00 17.140.21 16.04 17,124.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">289 Board, dining- room, etc. 7.986.28 24,000.00 31,986.28 4.20 31,982.08 Clothing, bed- ding, etc S50.99 8,000.00 8,850.99 8.64 8.84: Library books 1,659.78 4,000.00 5,659.78 563.34 5,096.44 Equipping trade 713.05 1,600.00 2.313.05 510.36 1,802.69 Permanent and gen. repairs 173.92 8,000.00 8.173.92 68.87 8,11 &lt; APPROPRIATION'S AND EXPENDITURES. FINDS FROM DEC 1 1904 TO NOV. 30, 1906. era' salaries: Appropriation $20.71 Expended 17.150.88 Balance 3,6] Employes' wages: A ppropriatidn *- 1,5] Expended L7,0 Balance 4.484.40 Fuel, electric lights, etc Appropriation $17,124.17 Expended 15,39 Balance 1,729.80 Board, dining-room and kitchen ex.: Appropriation $31,982.08 Expended 28,768.88 Balance Clothing, bedding, furniture: Appropriation $ 8,84 Expended 8,837.83 ■o t .9 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">290 Prom the cash receipt* are paid all the expenses of the farm I ling rents, machinery, wag rriapes. horses, seed and • f the stock, blaeksmitliing, and all &gt;neral ex - s of the farm. These claims are vouchered. sworn to, and it taken for them, the same as any other claim and nr&lt; e in this office. On the first of each month ,an itemized nent of the cash receipts and expenditures is made to the -loner of Public Lands and Buildings. following is a statement of the receipts and expenditures ■ he biennium : Balance on hand November 30. 1!KI4 | 1.769.28 pts from Dec. 1. '04 to May 31. '05 $1,737.33 from June 1, '05 to Nov. 30, '05 1.346.17 pts from Dec 1. "06 to May 31, &lt;" 8,195.40 Receipts from June 1. '06 to Nov. 30, "06 1,992.90 8.271.80 $10,041.08 .library books, periodical- Appropriation Expended M Balance 1H Equipping trade departments: Pppropriation spended Balance 'ermanent and peneral repai Appropriation [•ended Balance otal funds available for the biennium $115^4 otal expenditures durinp the biennium 100 Balance 14,64414 CASH ACCOUNT. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">291 Disbursements from Dec. 1, 1904 to May 31, 1905 $1,045.48 rursements from June 1, 1905 to Not. 30, 1905 2,378.70 rsbursements from Dec. 1, 1905 to May 31, 1906 2,196.12 Disbursements from June 1, 1906 to NOv 30 1906 Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1906 2,191.10 ■STATISTICAL FORM FOR STATE INSTITUTION ARED IN ACCORDANCE WITH A RESOLUTION OF THE NATIONAL CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION, ADOPTED MAY 15. 1906. NAME OF INSTITUTION. STATE INDUSTRIAL SCI I' FOR BOY POPULATION. Number of inmates present at beginning of biennium year. Not. 80. '04 171 Bived during biennium Nov. 30. 1904 — Nov. . '06 179 Number discharged during biennium Number at end of the biennium. Nov. 80, 'Otj 214 K average attendance (i. e. number of inmates tually present during biennium) 198 Bxe number of officers and employes during bien - um 33 EXPENDITURES Current expenses: salaries and Wgm $34,186.34 I Clothing 8,837.83 Subsistence 44,163.25 4. Ordinary repairs 6,472.67 5. Office, domestic and outdoor expenses 4,938.37 $98,598.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">292 Extraordinary expenses 1. New buildings, et, $ 2,000.00 2. Permanent improvements to existing building Total $ 2,000.00 $100,598.46 Notes on current expenses 1. Salaries and wages should include salaries of trustees or directors, if any. Clothing includes shoes and also materials for clothing and shoes if they are manufactured in the institution. 4. Ordinary repairs include all of those which simply main - tain the buildings in condition without adding to them. Any repairs which are of the nature of additions should be classed with "permanent improvements." EThis item includes everything not otherwise provided for, furniture, bedding, laundry supplies, engineer's supplies, ;e, freight, library, etc. Executive head (superintendent, warden or other title) THE ESTIMATE OF EXPENSES OF THE STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR BOYS FOR THE BIENNIUM COM - MENCING APRIL I; 1907 AND ENDING APRIL 1, 1909. Officers' sal a r Appr. '&lt;■ Salary of superintendent $3,600.00 tlary assistant superintendent 2.200.00 lary book-keeper, stenographer and steward 1.600.00 Salary physician 1.200.00 Salary chaplain and probation officer- 1.600.00 Employes wages Six family man;. $10,000.00 All other employes including foreman of each trade department and extra teachers 20,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, KEARNEY 293 Maintenance: Board, dining-room expenses and kitchen supplies $30,000 Fuel, electric lights, water supplies, boiler house expense 17,000.00 Clothing, bedding, and furniture 12,000.00 Equipping trade departments 2,000.00 library books, periodicals and papers, ■ekool books and stationery, medi - cines, oils and dr&lt; supplies, telephone, telegraph, p and office supplies, fugitives, freight and express, incidental and trav - eling expenv music and amusements $6,000.00 $67,000.00 Permanent and general repairs Repairs t&lt;&gt; old building ■is.iK30.00 One new family building 12.000.00 Two new boilers, one engine and dynamo 5,000.00 $25,000.00 Farm and pasture land : riree hundred and twenty acres bot - tom farm land. riree hundred and twenty acres pas - ture land _ $25,000.00 LECTURES AND ENTERTAINMENTS We have had a number of very fine lectures and entertain- ments during this biennium. which have been very much ap- preciated by us all. The following is a partial list : Lawrence Bruner, professor of entomology, subj., birds and insects. Dr. George Everett Condra, professor of geography and eco- nomic geography. Subj. geography of Nebraska. Ervin H. Barbour, professor of geology. Snbj. natural re- sources. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">294 T. L. Bolton, jii f psychology. General address. Kl H. Grunimann. professor of Germanic languages. Subj il trainii Bf. Burnett, dean of the state agricultural school. Subj ilture. ville .7. Pee, superintendent of university buildings. General talk to l&gt; Mia Jeane Dolen. Piano recital N. K. Griggs. Sutij MWf and story or "hash." is Lindley Subj. call of the birds. P»r \V. A. Clark, professor of pedagogy, in state normal. Subj I ihVations for success. ■rnor John H. Mick ieral adviee to 1 look. Illustrated lecture. Abraham Lincoln Pt. J. L. McBrien and Rev L. P. Ludden. (ieneral talks to boys. Dr. Holmes of Philadelphia. Subj. athletics rtnce and Miss Strochan. Scottish song and story ey orchestra. ss Anna Caldwell, superintendent of kindergarten at state normal. Subj. story telling. Band concert* by the Osceola, and Wisner military bands ••ption to governor and staff during encampment. •■rtainment by school for blind &gt;-r mission days by W. C. T. U. of Kearney. One session of state association of charities and corrections -trial session of the State Federation of Womans" Clubs Musical entertainment by Miss Dorsey. reader; Miss Knutzen, s Haase, pianist, and Miss Ware, vocalist. Prof. E. H. Parisho, president of Central Nebraska College. Subj. temperance. PAROLE SYSTEM Een boys are sent to our school they are committed until are twenty-one years of age, or until they are discharged iing to law. Bis does not mean that boys are to remain here until they ne of age; we have a system of parole by which a boy is ed to go out from here, after he has complied with the rules of the institution and attained a reasonable proficiency in the work assigned him. After he is turned over to the State </seg>
            <seg id="p029">295 for training and preparation for citizenship, it is necessary that the State do this work as thoroughly as it can in the tin &gt;■ require a boy to have a good, fair education, and in order to do this, it is necessary that he apply himself diligently 1&lt; work at school. We also require that he learn, reasonably well, the trade that he undertakes, so that he will be able to follow it when he goes out from the school. lie must also man Irportment and satisfy us that his conduct will be hould be after he is paroled. Eie time it takes to do this work depends entirely on th&gt; the boy puts forth and the interest he takes in it. We throw whole responsibility on him, and he can make the time long ter a boy is ready for parole we make another requirement of the parents or guardian; we require that they make a &gt;■' ing that they are capable and willing to look after and care for the boy, furnish him a home and have something for him to do. If we are satisfied with the showing made, after examin - ation we parole the boy for four months. We require a r&lt; from the boy. and the parent or guardian, every two weeks If the boy continues to do what he should, the parole is extei on and on, until he becomes of age. In case he violates this I arole and fails to do as he should, he is returned to the institu - tion. If the showing made by the parent or guardian dots not warrant our paroling the boy to them, we find a place for him, ourselves. B greatest trouble in paroling a boy to his parents is in put - m back in the same place and under the same inflm ? had before being sent here. If the parent could not ? him when he was twelve or fifteen years old, he surely do it when the boy is eighteen and nineteen years of age. We meet with more success when boys are placed in communities and under new influences. It is a very difficult thing for a boy to go back among his old associates and friends, and not take up the old habits; he may do it for a while, but in time if the associations are continued, he is very liable to be af - fected by them. No one knows this better than the boy, and quite often we have requests from the boys to be allowed to change their locations on that account. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">296 !"he first three months after a boy is paroled usually deter - le which way he is going. During that time he begins to act I think independently, and it is then that he needs a wise nsel, close attention and the assistance of those who are Tested in his welfare. It is necessary that he have something io to be kept busy, and that he observes the proper rules of duct and that his associations be such that they may lead in the right way. rVe try to have people in each community to take an interest our boys and assist them along these lines; to report the gress the boys are making, together with any wrong things they may be doing. If we find a boy is trying to do right, wa ■anst him in every way we can, even if he fails many times. do not expect our boys to be perfect. The commun judge them by a much higher standard than they do the a - of the community. This of course, is unfair; but they do and we cannot change their judgment. What we do expect of our boys, however, is that they do the best they can, and form habits that will be useful to them and to the communii which they live. After taring given them a fair trial, and they persist in going wrong, we return them to our school for further instruction. After a boy is paroled, it is only as a last reaort that we return him to the school. Pir experience with the boys we have paroled during the we have had charge of this institution, is indeed very en - aging and satisfactory. Out of the whole number paroled, only a very few have been returned. Some are not doing as well as they should and we are working with them, but tho jrreat majority of them are conducting themselves in an exem - plar}' manner, are industrious, and are trying to do the they can. In the matter of looking after our parole boys, our number has grown so large that I find it impossible to do all the work that should be done to keep them going properly, and find it will be necessary to have some assistance. In the estimate for appropriation for chaplain I have asked for eight hundred dollars per year for chaplain and probation officers, which will afford us the necessary assistance in this line. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">297 Ei are soliciting the aid of all good people in the state in work, which we think is the greatest work in the state: that of making good citizens. All that our boys want is one to care for them and an opportunity to work, and will do the rest. CONCLUSION. Ei the foregoing report we have been as concise as we could yet make it intelligible. During the time I have had charge he institution, I have given the management my personal ntion in all departments. I have tried to conduct the busi - on business principles. We have been as economical as consistency with &lt;rood manage - ment would allow. During the biennium our attendance has increased and prices of all supplies have so materially advanced, that we find our appropriation, together with the surplus left from the preceding bienniuni, will be expended and we may have a small deficiency, which we are trying very hard to r\ E airing our estimates for the next biennium. we have servative as possible, and have only asked for what is ely necessary. We have taken into consideration the products and receipts from our .farm, and in case that fund should not be used in our support, the general maintenance ap - propriation should be increased by that amount. rVe have combined work wherever and whenever we c that our present force is as small as good and safe ma' ment will warrant. Wherever a change or improvement could be made in any department, that would be aorc economical, without lowering the standard, we have done it. I am very glad to see the increased interest all over our coun - try in the matter of dealing with our delinquent and dependent jouth. Since the enactment of the juvenile court law. the ad - vancement in our own state has been very marked. I know of do law that has been enacted that could measure with it in importance. Pts corrective and preventative influences are far reaching and not be measured. The great number of children who have come directly under its workings are only a handful when com - pared with those who have been restrained from wrong and influenced for the right by its indirect influences. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">298 Pinee it has been in operation, there are better hornet ?nts, betr iiool. better Mndueted Inisiuess - r munieij&gt;al ncnt. and a genera] awakening &lt;&gt;f le in the method fcbng with children. g cannot realize the wonderful change that has l)een bnmirht n our larger cities, by the well organized and conducted irts, probation officers, and the many pood people, e •Misting in this work. 1 believe that Omaha leads the in the advancement made in the time they have king Ii law. needs several changes which its friends should we ade by the incoming legislature. The arbitrary reb &gt;y at sixteen years of age should be remedied so that there KNM option in the matter: if he is fit to be rel so. but if not to keep him until he is ready. Children :een years of age are in more danger than those at and it requires more care in handling them. Ball this work we have had but one object in mind and that do all we could for the betterment of the boys under our and to manage the affairs and business in a careful and rvative manner. We submit our acts for your consider- Respectfully submitted. B. D. HAYWARD. Superintendent </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>