<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Nebraska Farm Kitchen</title>
               <date value="1928-06">1928-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 226 June, 1928 The Nebraska Farm Kitchen GRETA GRAY Department of Home Economics THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Nebraska farm kitchens, on the whole, are far from satis - factory. Most of them are poorly lighted, poorly equipped, and badly arranged. They are inferior to town and city kitchens. There is need for raising rural housing standards and for more attention from architects and builders to the lighting of the kitchen and to work arrangements. There is need also for the education of housewives m household man - agement. Investigations with regard to desirable specifica - tions for equipment, storage space, and kitchen arrangement should prove profitable. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen The labor of the housewife is a very valuable contribution to the home and to the nation. Because each homemaker works alone m her own house, little attention has been paid to the conditions under which she works. It is known, how- : ever, that m many cases conditions obtain which, m a factory, would be considered intolerable. The kitchen is the chief workshop of the rural Nebraska home and the object of this study has been |to discover how it compares with generally accepted kitchen! standards, so that persons interested m home betterment may! know what are its commonest and its most serious deficiencies, and those which may be easily corrected. A good kitchen is well built and easily kept clean; it is well lighted and| ventilated ; it has modern equipment m good condition ; it is arranged, m so far as is possible, to eliminate fatigue and annoyance m doing the work ; and it is attractive. Such standards as the above are often expressed m the form of a score card. I A kitchen score card is used by the Nebraska State Extension! Specialist m Home Management as a means toward bringing about kitchen improvement. On this score card the women m the home management extension classes score their own. kitchens after the extension specialist has discussed the matter with them. Information m regard to the Nebraska rural kitchen was sought thru the analysis of these kitchen scores. The scores of 371 kitchens secured m 1924-25 are the principal source of the data presented here. The score card used at that time was revised m 1926 to secure more detailed information as to plumbing. 1 ; Some of the data used m this study were taken from 483! kitchen scores secured on this revised score card m 1926-27.! Seven per cent of the kitchens scored m 1924-25 are small - town kitchens, j Sixty-five per cent are m eastern and central Nebraska, and £5 per cent are m the western part of the state. Sixteen per cent of the kitchens scored m 1926-27 are m small towns. | Seventy-five per cent are m the eastern part of the state, and 25 per cent are m the western part. Tables 1 to 5 inclusive show how the kitchens of the earlier series were scored as to the various items on the score card. Table 4 includes also data secured from the revised score card. The most significant facts brought out m these tables are summarized m [Tables 7 and 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 Table 1. — Distribution of kitchens according to scores for natural light, artificial light, and screening, and according to possession of window board and transom. Kitchen croup . . Eastern and Western All Tnwn Farm central farm farm Pit rrvt' Per rrntl Per cent ' Percent [Percent Not scored 8.8 8 9 7 ■ From (I to 49 per Natural cent of perfect light score 11 8 12 12 12 \ From 50 to 99 per cent of perfect score 25 29 24 24 22 .. Perfect score 56 55 56 55 59 Xot scored 8 8 8 9 7 From 0 to 49 per cent of perfect Artificial sc '"'i- 13 ■*&gt; 14 13 15 From 50 to 99 per cent of perfect score 31 29 31 32 28 Perfect score 48 58 47 46 50 Not scored 8 8 ' 8 9 7 From 0 to 69 per cent of perfect Screening score 9 0 10 9 11 From 70 to 99 per cent of perfect score 15 8 15 16 15 Perfect score 68 84 67 66 67 Status as Xot scor&lt;&gt;d 8 8 8 9 17 Wdand W " ithout &lt;* ith " , 52 3S 53 52 55 transom — —' ~~ \ With one or both.... 1 40 , 54 39 -39 I 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen Table 2.— -Distribution of kitchens according to scores for attractiveness and sanitation of ceiling, walls, and floor. j : ! - Kitchen croup j j I „ i Eastern and Western '. All | Town | Farm | central farm farm : i i i i i ii? i i I Per cent Per cent | Per cent | Percent Percent Not scored | 16 17 16 18 14 \ -J - , Less than 20 per cent of perfect Attrac- score • 9 0 10 11 7 tiveness '— — — of ceiling 40 per cent of floor S i Perfect SCore 8 0 8 7 10 J60 per cent of | perfect score 11 8 1 12 12 12 80 per cent of perfect score 11 21 10 8 13 ! . _ Perfect score 45 54 44 44 44 ■ ; I _ I Not scored 16 I 17 16 18 14 Less than 20 per [ cent of perfect I Sanitation ' score 3 . j ° 3 5 0 of ceiling, : j ■ — i walls, and ;40 per cent of floor ■ perfect score 5 0 6 5 7 60 per cent of 1 perfect, score 12 ■ 0 12 12 12 I , I - i — 80 per cent of . j perfect score 11 25 10 7 15 i " j — 'Perfect score I 53 58 53 53 52 ! ! I </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 Table 3. — Distribution of kitchens according to scores for work surface and storage space, and according to posses - sion of stoves. Kitchen (troup I Eastern and I Western All Town Farm I central farm I farm ' I I i I ' ' I Percent Per cent Pre cent Percent I Per cent Not scored 22 25 ' 21 22 19 From 0 to 20 per cent of perfect score 2 4 2 2 3 Work 40 f 01 " ct&gt;nl " f surface perfect score 4 __0 4 4 4 60 per cent of perfect score _.___._ 0 12 0__ 18 &gt;80 per cent of perfect score 7 8 7 8 4 Perfect score 54 63 54 55 52 Not scored 22 25 21 22 19 From 0 to 20 per cent of perfect score 4 4 3 3 5 40 per cent of Storage perfect score 4 0 5 5 5 space I [ 60 per cent of perfect score 10 8 11 10 11 80 per cent of perfect score 16 13 ' 17 17 17 Perfect score _44 50 43 43 43 Not scored 22 25 21 _23 19 With 1 not good 7 8 8 6 9 Status as With 1 good stove to stoves or better 20 38 19 18 i 20 With 2 good stoves ! 51 ' 29 52 53 | 52 I I ' i </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen Table 4. — Distribution of kitchens according to equipment for supply of hot and cold water, and for the disposal of waste water.* Kitchen .roup i j I i i \ 1 I Eastern and Western All Town Farm central farm farm I 1 1 I \Pcrcent Percent Percent Percent Percent ■ _l , , . No plumbing but plumbing may have stove (1) 36 4 38 33 50 reservoir (2)j 32 ] 25 34 32 39 Stove reservoir but . no plumbing (2) 25 10 27 25 35 ; Sink (2) 1 1 1 1 1_ Sink, but 5ink and stQve J j ] no water reS ervoir (2) 12 5 14 14 11 under ■ ; r , r Pressure Sink and pump (2)) 2)3 2 ] 2)1 r i i i i Sink, stove reser- [ I voir, and I pump . (2)| 13 8 I 14 13 19 Sink, and cold water under pressure (2) 3 14 1 1 1_ I : : i r i Sink,, and Sink, cold water I water under pressure, i under and reservoir (2) 8 j 7 8 8 11 . pressure I Sink, and hot and cold -water, under pressure, ( 1 ) 12 29 11 10 12 * or better (2) 22 33 20 23 | 11 . Miscel- "~" I I — laneous (2)1-5 3 5 5 \ 6 Bucket (2)) .... I .... 14 [ 15 | 13 place°for Ground (2)1 -.■ I .... 27 23 41 waste Cesspool (2)| .... 49 53 1 30 water I I Septic tank (2) 11 | 9 | 15 * The figures in columns with subhead (1) were obtained from the kitchens scored in 1924-25; the figures in columns with subhead (2) were obtained from the kitchens scored in 1926-27. i ■-' </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 Table 5. — Distribution of kitchens according to possession of refrigerator and kitchen stool, and according to scores for arrangement. Kitchen croup j j i I Eastern and I Western All Town Farm ' central farm ■ farm I I 'It' I Pt-r cent Per cenl ] Per cent \ Percent I Per cent Status as No&lt; statt)(1 21 25 21 23 .' 17 friserator with „ ut 43 gl '' 44 ' 36 ' 60 With 36 54 35 41 23 Not stated 2 1^ _ 26 21 23 15 Status as to stool jWithout 47 29 40 44 59 With 32 45 30 33 26 Not scored 0 1) 0 0 0 From 0 to 24 per I cent of perfect 1 score 2 0 2 1 3__ From 25 to 49 per cent of perfect Arrange- scorc 2 0 2 1 3 ment — i J [From 50 to 74 per cent of perfect score 23 17 23 26 17 I i From 75 to 09 per cent of perfect score ' 29 17 31 28 38 II' 1 Perfect score 44 66 42 44 41 _! ' I ' I The comparison given in Table 4 of the two series of kitchen groups, that is, those scored in 1924-25 and those scored in 1926-27, as to the percentage with no plumbing, shows that there are fewer kitchens with no plumb - ing in the second series than in the first. The percentage of western farm kitchens without plumbing is considerably larger in the 1924-25 series than it is in the 1926-27 series. The percentage of eastern and central farm kitchens with no plumbing is about the same in the two series. There is </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen a far larger percentage of town kitchens without plumbing in the latter series than in the first. The number of town kitchens in the 1924-25 series is small and these kitchens may constitute a superior sample. A comparison of the two series of kitchen groups as to the percentage with sink and hot and cold water under pressure shows in every group, with the exception of western farm kitchens, a larger proportion of kitchens with this much plumbing in the later series than in the first. These observations suggest that western farm kitchens were improved between 1924 and 1927 by the introduction of some plumbing into those kitchens which had none in 1924. They suggest also that farm kitchens in eastern Nebraska were improved in these years by putting into those which already had some plumbing additional equipment to give them a sink and hot and cold water under pressure. According to assessors' reports compiled by the State and Federal Division of Agriculture, modern conveniences in Nebraska farm homes have increased considerably since 1920. The assessors' figures show that in 1920 water was piped into the house on 5 per cent of the farms; in 1924 on 8 per cent; and in 1926 on 13 per cent. The fact that 45 per cent of the farms which supplied the data for this study had water piped into the house in 1926, while the assessors' reports give only 13 per cent with this convenience at that time, indicates that the farm homes reached by the extension home management specialist are much superior to Nebraska .farm homes as a whole. In the two years from 1924 to 1926, according to the asses - sors' reports, water was piped into 5 per cent of the Nebraska farm homes. In a similar period, according to the data in this study, some plumbing was put into 4 per cent of the Nebraska farm kitchens which previously had none, and be - sides this a sink with hot and cold water under pressure was installed in 9 per cent of the Nebraska farm kitchens which previously had no plumbing or had something less modern than a sink with hot and cold water under pressure. The greater increase indicated by this study is probably due to three circumstances : first, these kitchens are superior to Nebraska farm kitchens as a whole; second, the data in the two series are not from the same counties; and third, commercial agencies have given plumbing demonstrations in certain districts. The increase in the percentage of kitchens having a sink and hot and cold water under pressure is in the group designated eastern and central farm kitchens. The kitchens in this group which were scored in 1924-25 are in Dakota, Dawson, Gass, Phelps, Clay, and Fillmore counties, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 and those which were scored in 1926-27 are in Washington, Saunders, Douglas, Lancaster, Otoe, and Johnson counties. The counties in the first group with the exception of Dakota and Cass are farther west, were settled later, have less rainfall, and have less wealth per square mile than those in the second group. In Dakota and Cass counties in 1924-25, 16 per cent of the farm kitchens scored had a sink and hot and cold water under pressure. This is 7 per cent less than the proportion of eastern kitchens which had this convenience in 1926-27, whereas in the whole group of eastern and central farm kitchens 9 per cent less had this equipment in 1924-25 than in 1926-27. One company which sells plumbing supplies has been using a truck to exhibit different methods of install - ing water under pressure. Another has given demonstrations of building septic tanks. These companies have given their demonstrations in eastern Nebraska following the work of the state specialist in home management. Their work in 1924 - 25 and in 1925-26 may have stimulated improvements in plumbing in near-by counties in which the state specialist worked in 1926-27. In Table 6 are given the total scores for the different kitchen groups. Fig. 1 is a plot of the total scores of three kitchen groups: town kitchens, eastern and central farm I 1 35 I I I I I I , 1 | I *° i , : I "•• U^rrl * ,o M lit ; 5 , 1 I ' onz^rd i i |^0-^9 30-&gt;.9(AO--^.9|30-^9) &lt; 5O-O9|^0-79|80-a0|90-l00( scoots ' TOW/. KITCHEAS tASTEQAl tcitiTVAs. Mp/*. KlTCHf/MS ViST.Q/M Mf)/A KITCM6/.S Fie. 1.— Distribution of the total scores of town kitchens, of central and eastern farm kitchens, and of western farm kitchens. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen kitchens, and western farm kitchens. It is apparent that the town kitchens are the best and the western farm kitchens the poorest. Table 7 gives the rank of these three kitchen groups as to each of the items on the score card. In determining these ranks corrections were made for the kitchens which were not scored as to the items in Tables 1, 2, 3, and 5. In each case it was assumed that had these kitchens been given ratings on the item in question these scores would have been distributed as were those actually given. Town kitchens rank first ex - cept as to two items, first, natural light, and second, two good stoves. In farm kitchens it is usual to find a coal stove which serves to heat the kitchen as well as for cooking. It is, there - fore, desirable that for summer use there should be a second stove which will not heat the kitchen as much as does a coal range. In towns the kitchen is frequently heated by a furnace, and gas or electricity is available for cooking; therefore, a second stove is not essential for comfort. Table 6. — Distribution of kitchens according to total score. j- Kitchen group •' i '■ i ~ Eastern and I Western All I Town Farm I central farm l farm I I I i- I i I i, Per centi Per cent Per cenl Percent \Percent Score from 20 to 29„ 10 1- 1 13 Score from 30 to 39 5 14 5 4 6 Score from 40 to 49 11 0 12 10 14 ' ; i ' Score from 50 to 59 18 4 19 17 22 Score from 60 to 69 21 4 22 26 14 Score from 70 to 79 16 8 17 17 18 Score from 80 to 89 16 38 15 15 14 Score from 90 to 100 12 42 9 10 9 . </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 Table 7.— Rank of kitchens as to highest score * in individual items scored and as to the total score. I Kitchen croup I I I I I Eastern and I Western ! Town | central farm ! farm I I ' I I ! Natural Mght ; 3 2 I 1 Artificial light : 13 2 Screening 1 2 ', Window board and transom 12 3 i ) Attractiveness 12 3 Sanitation 1 ' 2 3 Work surface 1 2 3 Storage space 12 3 f One good 13 2 Stoves ' I Two good ' 3 12 f(l) | 1 2 3 Plumbing * { I (2) : 12 3 Refrigerator 12 3 Stool ' 1 2 3 i i Arrangement ' 12 3 Total score I 12 3 • Plumbing rank based on percentaf.es with no plunibint, as well as on percentaECS with sink and hot and cold water under pressure. ill is the rank according; to the scores ol the 1924-25 kitchens; (2) is that according to the scores for the l_26-_. kitchens. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Nebraska Farm Kitchen The number of town kitchens among those scored in 1924 - 25 is small and the difference between the percentage of those with no plumbing and the percentage of town kitchens scored in 1926-27 with no plumbing as shown in Table 4 suggests that the town kitchens in the first series may be a superior group. Nevertheless, even in the later series the superiority of town kitchens to farm kitchens as to plumbing is still so marked that there can be little doubt that the ranks as given in Table 7 are, on the whole, correct. Eastern and central farm kitchens are superior to western farm kitchens in all respects except, natural and artificial light. The western farm houses have fewer large trees about them, they are newer, and consequently the rooms are smaller and have lower ceilings. These facts account for their superiority as to lighting. Altho the differences between farm kitchens in the two areas are slight with regard to some points, the inferiority of the western kitchens is evident, and shows clearly in Table 6, which gives the total scores of all the kitchens. The low rank of the western farm kitchens may be attrib - uted to the comparatively late development of the western part of the state and the consequent lack of money for home improvements. They excel the others in lighting because of the later style in which they are built. Table 8 shows the percentages of farm kitchens having per - fect scores for the items on the score card. The percentages with perfect scores given in Tables 1, 2, 3, and 5 were cor - rected for the kitchens unscored as to each item given in these tables. In preparing Table 8 the assumption was made that had there been no missing scores, the proportion of perfect scores to the total number in each case would have been un - changed. The items are listed in order, beginning with the one in regard to which the largest percentage of kitchens have a perfect score. It may be noted that plumbing is in the next to the last place on the list, whether its rank is based on the 1924-25 data or on the 1926-27 data. There is an interval of 18 to 27 points between plumbing and the next item. The second largest interval between items is 7 points. The Nebraska farm kitchen is, on the whole, far from satisfactory. Some of its faults are due to the architect or builder who provides a poorly lighted and -poorly ventilated room, and in many cases, one with doors, windows, sink, and flue so located that the housewife cannot arrange her equip - ment to the best advantage. The lack of adequate equipment and of satisfactory wall and floor finishes is due in part to economic conditions and in part to individual preferences as to the way in which money and time shall be spent. Some </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 226 of the faults of the Nebraska farm kitchen may be corrected by the housewife herself with little or no expense, if she is familiar with the principles of lighting and of kitchen arrangement.* Even tho with information now available present practice may improve, further investigations as to definite requirements for equipment, for storage space, and for kitchen arrangement are necessary in order that we may have the knowledge essential to providing the housewife with a workshop which will measure up to good factory standards. Table 8. — Percentages of farm kitchens having a perfect score for items listed, these percentages taken from Tables 1 to 6 inclusive and each one corrected for the items unscored in certain kitchens. I Item ' Perfect score I i Per cent 1 Screening 73 Work surface 68 Two good stoves 60 I Sanitation of walls and floors 63 Natural light 61 Storage space 54 Attractiveness of walls and floors 52 Artificial light 51 Refrigerator of some kind 44 Arrangement 42 Transom or window board 42 Stool of some kind 38 Equipment for water supply and waste disposal! (2) 20 (1) i 11 Total score I 9 • Gray. Greta. Convenient Kitchens. Farmers' Bulletin No. 1513. U. S. Department of Agriculture. 1926. t (1) is the score according to the 1924-25 kitchens and (2) is that according to the 1926-27 kitchens. [6M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>