<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills</title>
               <date value="1919-05">1919-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 171 May, 1919 Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills REPORT OF EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATION VALENTINE. NEBRASKA BULLETIN NO. 2 JAMES COWAN. Superintendent E. A. BURNETT. Director AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (Till: UEGEKTS OF THE UNIVERSITY Honorable E. P. Drown, President, Davey. Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln. Honorable Frank D. Judson, Omaha. Honorable John R. Webster, Omaha. Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Honorable II aery D. Landis, Seward THE STATION OFFICEB8 Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Director. W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service. J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. C. A. Lewis, B. Sc., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF P. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. I. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. Kiesselbach, A M., Agronomy. H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. I.. Van Es, M. P., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene. H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Animal Pathology. J. II. I randsen, M. S- A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FiLLEY, A*. M., Rural Economics. V.. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. (I, A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. F. E. Mussehl, B. SC, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. .Tames Cowan, M.E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation Mitchell. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. 'L. I. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depan rr.ent of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills By James Cowan The variety of crops that can be grown profitably in the Sand Hills, of northern Nebraska is limited, but fortunately the crops are of the kind that fit best into the economic requirements of this section. The leading export is live stock, while the leading agricultural products are hay and grain, which, with the summer grass provided by the extensive ranges, make up the bulk of raw material out of which the live stock is produced. Potatoes and to a limited extent beans have been profitable, especially for the smaller land holders and settlers struggling for a foothold. The raising of garden truck also has been car - ried on profitably, especially in the vicinity of the towns along the railroads, where markets are within reasonable distances. Commercial fruit growing, which, in common with truck raising, is generally carried on in the valleys, is still a very limited in - dustry, tho several orchards in the vicinity of Valentine produce profitable crops in favorable years. Thus it will be seen that the range of experiments that are likely to be of practical value in this section is limited. Recog - nizing this, and also the necessity that experiments to be of help in surti a section must be simple and practical and follow closely the needs and requirements of the farming population, nearly all of the work undertaken in recent years has been suggested by questions put to the Superintendent of the Substation. Hay and Fodder Crops For winter feed perhaps the greatest of all needs in the Sand Hills section is more and better roughage. Hitherto this has been almost entirely provided by native hay cut in the wet, and dry valleys or meadows. Some of the grasses forming this native or wild hay crop are good and nutritious, but considerable improve - ment can be made by substituting such grasses as redtop and timothy, which can be done by scattering the seed in early spring and leaving it to obtain a covering either by natural means, or by disking lightly or by other means helping it to take root. The greatest improvement of winter fodder is produced when some variety of clover is grown in place of the coarser and less nutritious grasses. Experiments have been conducted in the past few years to determine the relative value of different varieties of clover, alfalfa, and sweet clover, as well as the best methods </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 171 4 of seeding and handling such crops. The results of these experi - ments will be published in the near future. Much work has been done here with grain sorghums and with trying out various fodder plants, such as varieties of cane, millets and sudan grass. No work of this kind has been done during the last biennium, as there are scarcely any questions asked regarding such crops. The reason lies probably in the in - creased confidence that is placed in such crops as alfalfa, sweet clover and corn. Corn It is now very generally realized in the Sand Hills that corn must not be of a large variety, but rather small and medium, and also that the variety must be acclimated before a satisfactory crop can be raised. This Substation has tested out a large num - ber of varieties of corn advertised as having special value in the Sand Hills, viz. early maturing ability and drouth resistance, but no variety has been found much, if any, superior to the varieties in common cultivation here. Small Grains Small grains are increasing in importance in the Sand Hills. This is especially true of winter wheats, while the growing of winter rye has been greatly stimulated in the last two years. Conditions at the Substation do not favor the raising of any crop of small grain in bulk, but some experiments with winter wheat and rye have been carried out. As the growing of wheat is almost exclusively confined to what are known as hard lands, of which there is a considerable area within the Sand Hills section, and as there is no land of that quality on the Substation, the work done with wheat here is relatively unimportant. Much information relative to wheat growing on such land is obtainable from the North Platte Sub - station, where the growing of wheat has formed one of the sub - jects of extended study. Forty acres of winter rye were seeded on the lighter class oi : cultivated land at this Substation last fall. Some of the land was disked after corn and some plowed. The seeding extended over six weeks which elapsed between the time the first seed was put in and the last sowing was made. The amount of seed was varied from half a bushel to two bushels to the acre. The results of the different methods of handling the soil, dates of seeding and rates of seeding will be studied. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills 5 Experiments With Potatoes Five years of work in testing out varieties of potatoes hav - ug demonstrated that the variety known as Irish Cobbler was the argest yielder, as it stood first in three out of five years, while io other variety was first more than once, work during the past wo years was confined to various tests with the common potato f the section, the Early Ohio, and the Irish Cobbler. Tests were lade as to the value of treating sound seed picked from among eed known to be infected, as to the protection which treatment ave when the crop was grown on land on which diseased potatoes .ad previously been raised, and also to observe the merits of reatment of potatoes planted on land presumably free from .isease as compared with seed from the same bin that had not een so treated. Records of these experiments show that in all ases treatment serves its purpose, and that it pays for material nd labor involved. Experiments were also conducted with various depths of lanting potatoes. The results indicate that consideration should e given the nature of the soil and particularly to that of the ubsoil when considering the depth of planting. With a thin pper soil and damp subsoil, especially, it has been found that oubling the depth of planting reduces the crop by more than alf. It was also found that mulching a subirrigated crop of otatoes with litter had the effect of reducing the yield more lan 20 per cent, while potatoes on the dry, light upland soils mlched to a depth of 4 to 6 inches with litter yielded 27 per cent lore than when left unmulched. The value of mulching potatoes when growing for seed was emonstrated in previous experiments carried out at this Sub- ation. Experiments With Beans Half an acre was planted to varieties of beans last year, heae included the large and the small navy, the pinto and one r two other Mexican varieties, along with several others, and lese were planted on both subirrigated and dry lands. On sub - •rigated land the large navy yielded best, followed by the small avy and pinto. On the dry land, tho given careful cultivation, ttle success was obtained. This was partially due to the peculi - rity of the season, the early spring being cold and wet, while le early summer was exceptionally warm and dry. Beans be - lg a crop that require late planting, and this lateness being ided to by the lateness of the planting season, very little grow- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 171 6 ing weather for this crop was obtained before it began to suffer from heat and drouth. Consequently the dry weather began to affect the crop just at flowering time, and as a result few pods were formed. Under these conditions the pintos and small navy beans did best, but the crop in all cases might be set down as a failure. Following a somewhat similar experience the previous year, it would appear that beans are not a very reliable crop on light land, and not to be relied on under such conditions of drouth as cause failure of such a crop as corn. Garden Truck Much disappointment having resulted in this and other lo - calities thruout the Sand Hills section on account of total or partial failure following attempts to raise garden truck on light sandy soil, even when aided by water from a garden hose, numer - ous experiments were conducted here in effort to find out just what benefit could be obtained from mulching with old hay, stable litter, etc. The season was favorable for such experiments, as the mulching in all cases was done after the plants were well grown and protection thereby given just as the dry weather was well commenced. Without giving details here, it may be stated that under this system small crops were grown of nearly every kind of vegetable, where without mulching all attempts to grow such vegetables were failures. While there is increased work involved in raising vegetables by mulching, this is not so excessive as might be supposed, as the mulching does away with the cultivations that are necessary after each wetting given the ground, either by rain or hose. Crops such as tomatoes were kept back and the ripening of the fruit delayed by mulching. In no case was the benefit derived so noticeable as in the case oi potato mulching. This is probably due to the ability of the potatr to form the growth of the tubers at the level best suited for theii development which in mulching will be found close to the surface of the soil and under the mulch, where most moisture is usual 1\ to be found during the growing season. A common cause of fail - ure in raising garden truck is that too much is undertaken at the beginning of the season, and also that the early work is not followed up by persistent watering and cultivation until the croj is secured. On dry land it is useless to plant more garden stuft than can be well soaked twice a week by application of watei when rain fails. Too frequent light sprinklings which are not fol, lowed up by cultivations are also the cause of much failure. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills 7 Orchard Work Ore-hard work on dry land at this Substation has been an entire failure. Nearly every species of orchard tree, advertised or recommended for hardiness and drouth resistance, has been tried out here without success. Some species have grown well for a year or two, especially the hardier varieties of plums and apples, but no fruit has been produced, and the condition of the few trees that survive is such as to give color to the belief that they never will be of value. No attempt has been made to grow an orchard on the bottom subirrigated land, but observation of attempts made on such ground by farmers has failed to discover satisfactory results, altho the work in some of the cases was carried out under expert direction. The few orchards that can be called even moderately suc - cessful, so far as observed in this section, are situated on land where the level of the water providing subirrigation remains, or can be made to remain, practically the same during the fruiting season. Needless to say, such situations are far from common, and frequently when found, some other desirable feature, such as the right kind of exposure or shelter, i* lacking. Tree Culture Growing trees in quantity, such as is needed for groves and windbreaks, has proved to be one of the hardest anl most ex - pensive operations undertaken at this Substation, and one offer - ing but small satisfaction. These remarks apply to tree growing on dry sandy land only, for it is a comparatively easy matter to grow a grove of poplars or cottonwoods on subirrigated land that is not too wet. As in the case of the fruit trees, there are many kinds of deciduous trees that do well for the first year or two. Poplars and eottonwoods make fast growth for a year or two, but after that it seems that all efforts to save them are in vain. The same is true in a degree of nearly all deciduous trees planted here. 'Some varieties, such as honey locust, elm and box elder, live longer than the poplars and cottonwoods. Bull pines raised from seed collected in the vicinity of the Substation have done better than any other variety of tree, but it is questionable whether they will be long-lived, as it is found that a small percentage of them die nearly every season, and that, too, in cases where the individuals have previously appeared healthy. The probable cause of trouble with both deciduous </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 171 8 trees and conifers is due to the shallow rooting habit induced by both the shallow soil and the circumstance that during the growing season the moisture is found near the surface where the roots incline to seek it. In the case of deciduous trees the situa - tion is made worse by the ravages of borers which attack every species grown here. Mulching has been tried and trees that after planting would succumb are often kept alive for a time by this protection, but this practice is not advisable on a large scale, and besides it in - duces the shallow rooting habit, which is so undesirable. Experi cnce here has proved that at least on dry sandy uplands tht amount of successful tree growing is likely to be limited to the quantity of water at the disposal of the grower for that purpose as well as to the time and means at hand for its application. Good Dairy Stock in Demand The dairy herd at this Substation is improving in quality and some good butterfat producers are beginning to show up (trade animals of the second crossing are showing up well ii comparison with purebreds, especially when descended fron grade cows of good milking quality. Quite a number of pure bred males have been distributed from this herd over the country and the demand now exceeds the supply. The result of this dis tribution has begun to show in improved dairy stock, especially on the smaller holdings. Prices obtainable for males are not large, but it is satisfac tory to know that this blood is being distributed in a section tha has large dairying possibilities, and also that smaller farmer and settlers are awaking to the desirability of better dairy stock. The Substation with its herd of dairy cows is giving considei able impetus to this movement. 15-15-19— 3.M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>