<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00051.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00051.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Secretary of State of the State of Nebraska for Nineteen Months Ending June 30, 1922</title>
               <date value="1922-07-01">1922-07-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR NINETEEN MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1922 DARIUS M. AMSBERRY, Secretary of SUM TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">1 Office of Secretary of Lincoln, Nebraska July 1, 1922 To the Honorable, The Governor, Samuel R. McKelvie, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. My dear Governor: Conforming; to the statutes of the Commonwealth, I have the honor to present herewith, my report as Secretary of State for the State of Nebraska, for the nineteen months ending June 30, 1922. This report contains an exhibit of the affairs of the office and the method of conducting the same during the term now closing. It further sets forth the amount of moneys expended by this de - partment, a classified statement of all moneys received by the office as fees, a statement of the necessary expenditures for operation of the office, salaries, etc., a statement of the number of corporations incor - porating, qualifying, withdrawing or dissolving, the registration and renewal of brands, issuing and cancelling notary public commissions, and the granting of charters to chattel loan organizations under the provisions of Chapter 204. Session Laws of 1915. In the interests of economy, we have abridged the report as much as possible, eliminating several features that have heretofore been embodied, which would increase the cost of publishing and are in themselves, not of vital public interest. Respectfully submitted, DARIUS M. AMSBERRY, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">2 siuaa REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE SECRETARIES OF STATE TKRR1TOR1AI, 1. Thomas B. Cuming, August 23, 1854, to March 12, 1858 &gt;. J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6. 1861. 3. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861, to Feb. 21, 1867. STATE 4. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871 5. Wm. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 12, 1873. Acting Crovernor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873 6. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. 7. Bruno Tzschuck. from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879 8. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879. to Jan. 4, 1883. 9. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1883, to Jan. 6, 1887 t. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889. Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by the death of James Laird. 11. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891 Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by r tion of Gilbert L. Laws. tjohn C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891. to Jan. 3. 1895. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895, to Jan. 7, 1897 I William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 3, 1901 George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907, to Jan. 5, 1911. Addison Wait, from Jan. 5, 1911, to Jan. 7, 1915. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 7, 1915, to Jan. 9, 1919. 20. Darius M. Amsberry, from Jan. 9, 1919, to. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">3 STATK OFFICERS Dl'RIMi IHENXUM McKelvie, Samuel R., Governor Lincoln Barrows, P. A., Lieutenant Governor Lincoln Amsberry, Darius M.. Secretary of State Broken Bow Marsh. (Jeo. W., Auditor of Public Accounts. Lincoln Cropsey, D. B., Treasurer Fairbury Matzen, John, Supt. of Public Instruction Fremont Davis, Clarence A., Attorney General Holdrege Swanson, Dan, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings Fremont Browne, Thome A., Railway Commissioner Lincoln Cook. Harry L.. Railway Commissioner- Lincoln I MTEI) STATES SKXATOKS Hitchcock, Gilbert M Omaha 1917-23 Norris, George W McCook 1919-25 CONGRESSMEN Falls City First District Reavis, C. F Jefferis, A. W _... Evans, Robert E McLaughlin. M. O Andrews, W. E. ....... Omaha Second District Dakota City Third District York Fourth District Hastings Fifth District Kinkaid, Moses P O'Neill _ Sixth District A Special Election to be held the date of the Primary Election was called by the Governor to fill the vacancies caused by the death of the Honorable Moses P. Kinkaid in the Sixth Congressional District and the resignation of the Honorable C. F. Reavis in the First Congression- al District ADMINISTRATIVE HOARDS Of Which the Secretary of State is a Member Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Educational Lands and Funds Board of Canvassers Board of Pardons and Paroles Depository Bonds Board OFFICE FORCE OF DKF ARTMEXT OF STATE Darius M. Amsberry, Secretary Broken Bow William L. Gaston, Deputy _ Broken Bow Frances H. Sturmer, Bookkeeper _ Beatrice Ruey B. Beach, Corporation Clerk Lincoln Myrtle C. Bonner, Recorder _ Red Cloud Charlotte R. Littlefleld, Correspondence Clerk Lincoln Sue Zuver. Stenographer and Copyist _ ! Lincoln Taylor, H. G.. Railway Commissioner _ _ _ -.Central City </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF ST ATI 4 CORPORATION DEPARTMENT The table below sets forth the number of articles amendments to articles of incorporation, appointinen solutions, etc., handled during the past nineteen nion \ it ! Domestic ('or|M&gt;ratioii: red Total number of domestic corporations register* Number domestic corporations incorporated din-ins past nir months Number domestic corporation Number domestic corpor Foreign Corporation Total number foreign corpor Number qualifying during past nineti-f Number amendments to appointments fiU Number foreign corporal io ns, w NwProflt Coi-|&gt;oralion Total numbiT Number filed duri Number filing dis: Number amending Grand total of all cor Traile Mark* ami Trade Nam Total number of Trail M rks Number of Trade Marl I Trade N Stm-k Brands This department is chargec of brands used for the puip provided. The year 1922 is the year in which all renewed. This renewal conies but once in five year renewed. This renewal comes I the business for the past ninenen men t hi is as foil the business for the past nlaeteen months is as iollov Brands issued Aartag past nineteen months Brands issued during pa*t Bil Number of Brands renewed during past nineteen mo Number of Brands renewed dinir Total number of Brands now registered in this office Total number of Brand ffl« now KXI'KXDITl ItKS KXl'KXDITlltKS December 1, 1920. to July 1. tttS: Salaries Maintenance Compiling and Printing Soldiers' K&lt; Registering Brands 1,074 Initiative and Referendum </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 5 KIXAM'IAI STATKMKXT incorporation, corpora- ion of brands, certi- loan licenses under Laws of 1915, etc. The fol - moneys received during the 11 Money ll.-i.-n.-.l $ 34.480.20 4,818.35 151,117.75 27,109.00 4,673.07 M 1.559.00 3.242.00 1015 840.00 J27.30 $228,166.67 olSdAXI/ATION OK PRO&lt;JRKSHIVK I'AltTY Party, was organized and office on January 3, 1922. lis party agains SI'KCIAI, SK.SSIOX OK THK I.KCJISLATl KK called by Governor S. R. ng appropriations. The total re - r which $1.951. 6« applied to this January 24, 1922, and ad- ISKKKI IMH M office petitions request- i Senate File 305 — bills House Rolls !!•:'.. til red to the people at the passed by th? legislature of 1 next General Election which will be helc .1 T Ml. ich eacli bill is to be submitted, is A- 1 as follow leld November 7, 1922. The hfse petitions, together with </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STAT Bill Number Ballot Title Number Number of Sipnatui •&gt; 310-31 H. R. 15 :; H. R. 6 314-31 H. R. ti 3K-31 i LOAN AGBNCIKi House Roll No. 44. of 1915, provides for the licensing of loan a or loan agencies and is d small quantities upoi given by the coiaj filed annually on Marc companies operated di i under tne secon M \i l J eoples Loan Compi Provident Loan Bw Omaha Loan Comps Rex Loan Company Farmers Loan A: In\ rnese compar ana reports oi • \: uox l.oan company Guarantee Loan Comp </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OP STATE 7 itOAKD OK PARDONS A XI) PAROLKS number of applicants heard by the m the penitentiary, Reformatory for nd jails where convicts under peni- January 1, 1921, to July 1, 1922. Financial Statement of Funds for M January 1, 1921 to July 1, 1922 aintaining the Probation Office from $8,639.44 1,212.60 Extra Help and Reporting Maintenanc 850.73 Total $13,702.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE This board is composed of the Governor, Secretary of State and Attorney General. The board holds meetings monthly, the second Tuesday, to hear the cases of those who have been sentenced under the Indeterminate Sentence Law. During the eighteen months of the operation of this law of the four hundred and ninety-five cases heard by the board, two hundred and nine were paroled, of which only twenty-six violated their parole and had to be returned to the penitentiary. The only outstanding bad case of the violators is that of Fred Brown, who has been returned with a life sentence. It is because of the mistake made in paroling him that the law is generally criticised by the public. The question is: Should the law be condemned simply because one of the four hundred and ninety-five people heard failed to make good and that the other four hundred ar given a chance for their freedom? ninety-four been your son or mini cause Fred Brown failed to make have a chance? d ninety-tour should not have been Had one of the four hundred and ', would we have insisted that bi good that the innocent should nc I regard the law very highly, t lit it needs some amend D. M. AMSBERRV Secretary Board of Pardons and Respectfully </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>