<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">nebraska State Board of Health Published quarterly at the office of the Secretary of the Board, Lin - coln, Nebraska. Entered as second class matter, January 15, 1917, at the Post-office, Lincoln, Nebraska, under the act of July 16th, 1894. VOLUME 4 JULY, 1917 NUMBER 2 This Bulletin will be sent free to any person within the State upon request. HEALTH DEPARTMENT, CONSISTING OF BOARD OF HEALTH KEITH NEVILLE, Governor. WILLIS E. REED, Atty. General. W. H. CLEMMONS, Supt. Pub. Instr. SECRETARIES TO BOARD OF HEALTH. C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., Falls City. H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Seward L. STARK, M. D., Hartington E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Llncoli HEALTH INSPECTOR. DR. J. D. CASE. STATE BOARD OF HEALTH BACTERIOLOGICAL LABORATORY. DR. WILD, Director. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Fourth Annual Bulletin Work of the Board of Health Every county, state and village in the state organized for health work, statutes changed four years ago placing responsi - bility on County Board of Commissioners, in the event they had not formerly organized under the statutes. The law now makes them the Board in fact and places the responsibility on them. 1st. Adoption of rules and regulations governing the quaran - tine of contagious diseases and sustaining a health inspector in enforcing same. 2d. Establishment of Bacteriological and Pathological La- oratory. 3d. Promulgation of rules and regulations governing the same, making it possible for all parts of the state to have drinking water and ice analyzed and microscopical examinations made free. 4th. Gathering and compiling statistics of births, deaths, marriages and divorces, and providing that every child born in the state during the past eight years has his or her record on file in the office of the State Board of Health. 5th. The establishment of a Quarterly Health Bulletin for the dissemination of vital statistics on all state health matters. 6th. The organization of the annual conference of state and local health officers and the organizing of the state along health lines. 7th. The representation of Nebraska at all the national and international health associations held in this country during the past eight years. 8th. The establishment of reciprocal relations of Nebraska with more states than any other state in the Union; and placing its certificates on a par with any and all other states. 9th. Priority in the effort to place certified ice and drinking water on all intra- and inter-state passenger trains. The above work has been accomplished with the appropria- </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska State Board of Health. 3 tion of ten to eleven thousand dollars for the biennial, or it has taken five legislatures to have appropriated for the present Board the sum of $50,600.00. NEW RULE ADOPTED BY STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Be It Resolved by the State Board of Health of the State of Ne- braska that : No water samples shall be examined or analyzed by the State Bacteriological laboratory except when such samples shall have been properly forwarded by local health officers to said labora - tory and such water samples thus forwarded shall be promptly and correctly examined and analyzed in succession as received by the State Bacteriological Laboratory and a full, correct and complete analysis thereof shall be delivered by said State Bac - teriological Laboratory to the State Board of Health through its Board of Secretaries who are hereby authorized to take such steps as they may determine to be proper to either correct such impure water condition if such condition is found to exist or to condemn the source or supply of such water, and report same to State Board of Health for approval. Approved this day of October, 1916. JOHN H. MOREHEAD. Governor, Chairman. WILLIS E. REED, Attorney General. A. 0. THOMAS, Superintendent of Public Instruction. State Board of Health of the State of Nebraska. The above and foregoing rule is this 16th day of September, 1916, recommended for adoption in accordance with the provisions of Article 13, Chapter 27, Revised Statutes of Nebraska 1913. C. T. BURCHARD. President H. B. CUMMINS, Vice President. E. ARTHUR CARR, Secretary. LUCIAN STARK, Treasurer. Board of Secretaries to State Board of Health. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Fourth Annual Bulletin ABSTRACT OF LAWS GOVERNING NEBRASKA BOARD Board. — The State Board of Health consists of the gov - ernor, attorney general and superintendent of public instruction. The governor appoints four secretaries, who hold office for a term of four years, two of whom shall be regulars, one a home - opath and one an eclectic. The secretaries are in reality the Board of Health. The method adopted is to get around the con - stitution, which forbids the creation of more boards. Board Members.— C. T. Burchard, M. D., President, Falls City ; Lucien Stark, M. D., Hartington ; Herschel B. Cummins, M. D. (1920), Seward; E. Arthur Carr, M. D., Secretary, Lincoln. Examinations. — The board holds examinations at the State House, Lincoln, in May and November of each year, and in Aug - ust and February also when there is a sufficient demand. Feet. — Examinations or reciprocal fee, $25.00 ; for gi luates of Nebraska colleges, $10.00; endorsement of reciprocal creden - tials of applicants leaving state, $2.00. Application for License. — Each applicant must present evi - dence of good moral character to the Board, as well as his di - ploma, together with an affidavit that he is the lawful possessor of and the person named in said diploma, and that he has at - tended the full course of study required for the degree. After due investigation has shcfwn that the credentials are satisfactory, applicant is then required to submit to an examination, in the English laguage. in all the branches generally required by repu - table medical colleges for the degree of doctor of medicine. Ex - aminations on practice and therapeutics are conducted by the member or members of the Board of Secretaries who are of the same school of practice as the applicant. Certificates must be filed with the county clerk of the county in which the applicant resides. Temporary licenses are not granted. Students having satisfactory preliminary education and who have successfully completed the first two years of study in a recognized medical college will be permitted to take examinations in anatomy, physiology, physiological chemistry, chemistry, ma - teria medica and pharmacology on payment of the required fee, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska State Board of Health 5 these credits to be accepted toward the examination for license after the student has secured his diploma. No re-examination will be required in such subjects in which the student has been found proficient. College Standard. — To be in good standing a medical college must require for admission an approved high school diploma or an equivalent preliminary examination in all the common branches and in Latin and the higher mathematics, which re - quirements shall be regularly published in all the advertisements and in catalogues issued by said school. The medical school must also require as a requisite for granting the degree of M. D. attendance on four courses of lecturers of at least six months each, no two courses to be held within one year, and must have a full faculty of capable professors in all the- different branches of medical education and require clinical instruction in the last two years of the course in medicine and surgery of not less than four hours per week. States With Which Nebraska Reciprocate!. — Reciprocal rela- tions, on the basis of an examination only, have been established with Arkansas, Colorado, Illinois, Louisiana, Mississippi, New Jersey, North Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Vermont, Virginia and Wiconsin, and on the basis either of an examination or of a diploma from a reputable medical college without an examination provided the diploma and the license were issued prior to Aug - ust 1, 1903, with the District of Columbia, Georgia, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, Mis - souri, Nevada, New Hampshire, Ohio, Oklahoma, Utah and West Virginia. An applicant who has previously failed at an exami - nation conducted by the Nebraska Board is eligible for reciprocal registration only in certain instances. A certificate issued in an - other state on the basis of reciprocity is not acceptable for re - ciprocal registration in Nebraska. No certificate will be granted on reciprocity where the applicant has not resided and been in reputable practice in the state endorsing him for at least one year immediately preceding the endorsement. Definition of Act. — Any person shall be regarded as prac- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Fourth Annual Bulletin 6 ticing medicine who shall operate or confess to heal or prescribe for, or otherwise treat any physical or mental ailment of another. Act effective Aug. 1, 1903. LAW IS GOOD. Medical circles in Nebraska are much pleased with the deci - sion of the Supreme Court affirming the District Court of Sheridan county denying an injunction to one, Patterson against the State Board of Health. Patterson sought to practice dentistry without a permit or license. He also attacked the constitutionality of the act applying to both medical and dentistry practitioners. The case was tried in the District Court, briefed and argued in the Supreme Court by Deputy Attorney General Dexter T. Barrett. REPORT OF DR. CUMMINS TO STATE BOARD OF HEALTH. Proposed Correlation of Federal, State and Local Health Authori - ties and Other Sanitary Agencies for the Protection of Health in Time of War. While the bulk of existing health laws are for the protection of the civil propulation, the enforcement of some of them has a bearing also on the health of military forces, especially in war times, and all of them must be utilized to their fullest extent by the country when waging war. This will require proper cor - relation of all health activities. These activities as affecting the present situation and requiring the attention of federal, state and local health authorities are as follows : 1. Furnishing information regarding disease prevalence and endemic localities for the benefit of military operations and the civil population. 2. Sanitation of ports and places within the United States in co-operation with state and local health authorities to prevent danger to the health of military forces or of the civil population. 3. Laboratory examinations for diagnostic and public health purposes in stationary and traveling laboratories. 4. Supervision of manufacture of viruses, serums, toxins, and analogous products, and their preparation when necssary. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska State Board of Health 7 5. Control of epidemics and prevention of the interstate spread of disease along lines of travel. 6. Sanitary supervision of establishments manufacturing war materials. 7. Sanitary supervision of refugees and medical relief when necessary of dependents of those in the service of the country. Information Regarding Disease Prevention. Presumably the furnishing of information to military authori - ties regarding disease prevalence and endemic centers must be of benefit in relation to mobilization and establishment of concentra - tion camps. This can be done by means of adequate co-operation between federal, state and local authorities. A reciprocal ar - rangement is also important whereby military authorities will be required to report confidentially the incidence of communicable diseases among their forces. Sanitation of Ports and Places Adjacent to Military Areas. Undoubtedly a large amount of other data relating to sanita - tion are in the hands of federal, state and local health authorities, - which would be of service to military authorities. These health authorities should also be able to sanitate areas adjoining mobliza - tion camps and military reservations; by this means lessening the danger of insanitary conditions which might adversely af - fect not only the military but the civil populations. Work of this character would necessarily be intensive, and require con - siderable forces for its performance. Logically, such forces should become available through proper correlation of federal, state and local agencies. By law and precedent the Public Health Service stands ready to co-operate with and aid any state in which a public health emergency exists. All other states should be able to join the United States Public Health Service in such co-operation in a particular state to meet a national emergency. Not only could adjacent areas be sanitated, but special ex - perts should be in reserve for assignment to aid medical health authorities in meeting emergencies arising out of increased traffic conditions or epidemics. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Fourth Annual Bulletin Laboratory Examinations for Diagnostic and Public Health Purposes. A number of stationary and traveling laboratories of the Service are located in different parts of the country. These are equipped for routine examinations and research purposes. Un - doubtedly this number could be greatly enlarged by state and local laboratories which could be counted on to share in meet - ing any emergency. Supervision and Manufacture of Biologic Products. Under law all commercial establishments manufacturing viruses, serums, toxins and analogous products used in the treat - ment and prevention of diseases of man must hold licenses issued by the Treasury Department. Their supervision therefore is now maintained by the Public Health Service and can be extended as necessary. While large quantities of these products are re - quired in military operations, especially tetanus antitoxin, anti - typhoid vaccine, and vaccine virus, the facilities of commercial manufacturers are believed to be adequate to meet every need; their output could be supplemented if necessary by official labora - tories. Control of Epidemics and the Spread of Communicable Diseases Along Lines of Travel. The movements of large bodies of men will expose them along lines of travel to communicable diseases prevailing among the civil population. Soldiers and sailors may in turn dissem - inate such diseases. Provisions must accordingly be made not only for the care of perons detained and en route, suffering from communicable diseases, but the eradication of the infection from conveyances must be provided for. This will necessitate an in - spection service and the establishment of communicable disease hospital facilities at appropriate points. The Snitary Supervision of Establishments Manufacturing War Materials. To obtain the maximum continuous output of war material over a protracted period, the sanitary supervision of manufactur- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska State Board of Health 9 ing plants and the health of workers is necessary. The following is an enumeration of the activities required : 1. Sanitary supervision of premises, buildings and pro - cesses of industrial plants engaged in supplying war materials to the federal government. 2. Medical supervision of workers in industrial plants. 3. Instruction in personal hygiene, by personal contact with workers, so as to obtain their full cooperation in the general sani - tary measures designed for their protection. 4. Special studies to improve and increase efficiency, and to safeguard the health of workers. While due attention to factory sanitation will exercise a beneficial effect, the most marked results will be obtained from community sanitation in industrial centers actively engaged in the production of war materials. Such conditions as defective water supply, crowded and insanitary housing conditions, sur - face privies, inadequate facilities for garbage and waste removal, and the like must be done away with. This is the object constantly before health authorities. Plan of Correlation. In order to bring about correlation in times such as this, it has been suggested that a sanitary reserve force should be formed. This would require congressional action along somewhat the fol - lowing line: "For the purpose of securing a reserve for duty in the Pub - lic Health Service in time of national emergency, there shall be organized, under the direction of the Secretary of the Treas - ury, under such rules and regulations as the President shall pre - scribe, a reserve of the Public Health Service. The President alone shall be authorized to appoint and commission as officers in the said reserve such citizens as, upon examination prescribed by the President, shall be found physically, mentally, and morally qualified to hold such commissions, and said commissions shall be in force for a period of five years, unless sooner tennniated in the discretion of the President, but commission in said reserve </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Fourth Annual Bulletin shall not exempt the holder thereof from military or naval service." Resolutions Adopted by the Conference of State and Territorial Health Officials at the Session Held on Monday Evening, April 30, 1917. We, the Executive Health Officials of the several states and territories, in conference assembled, do hereby Resolve, that under conditions incident to a state of war, the public health personnel, resources and organizations of the several states and territories should be placed at the disposal of the Federal Government. Whereas, the Federal Public Health Service has hitherto been the natural point of contact between the Federal Govern - ment and the several states and territories in all matters per - taining to public health, and the aforesaid Service is thoroughly familiar with the manner of administration of public health measures by state and local boards and departments of health, be it therefore Resolved, that it is the opinion of the Executive Health Officials of the several states and territories in conference as - sembled, that the Federal Public Health Service, under condi - tions incident to a state of war, should be the agency of the Federal Government through which correlation, supervision, and direction of the various state and local health agencies should be exercised, and be it further Resolved, that aside from the hygienic and medical care of the actual military and naval forces, all sanitary and hygienic activities incident to a state of war which require a national policy, should be correlated, supervised, and directed by the United States Public Health Service. Whereas, the present personnel and organization of the Federal Public Health Service is entirely inadequate, be it there - fore Resolved, that it is the opinion of the Executive Health Officials of the several states and territories, in conference as- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska State Board of Health 11 sembled, that a National Sanitary Reserve Corps should be created as an auxiliary to the Federal Public Health Service. We, the Executive Health Officials of the several states and territories, in conference assembled, do hereby unequivocally endorse the following resolution: Joint Resolution To establish a Reserve of the Public Health Service. Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, that for the purpose of securing a reserve for duty in the Public Health Service in time of national emergency, there shall be organized, under the direction of the Secretary of the Treasury, under such rules and regulations as the President shall prescribe, a Reserve of the Public Health Service. The President alone shall be au - thorized to appoint and commission as officers in the said Re - serve such citizens as, upon examination prescribed by the Presi - dent, shall be found physically, mentally, and morally qualified to hold such commissions, and said commissions hall be in force for a period of five years, unless sooner terminated in the dis - cretion of the President, but commission in said Reserve shall not exempt the holder thereof from military or naval service. Said officers shall consist of Sanitarians, Passed Assistant Sani - tarians, and Assistant Sanitarians; and when ordered to active duty in the service of the United States, shall receive the pay, allowances, and leaves of absence of Surgeons, Passed Assistant Surgeons, and Assistant Surgeons, respectively, provided that the Secretary of the Treasury may appoint for duty with said re - serve employees in such number as the public interest may re - quire and the funds appropriated may permit. That for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this act the sum of $ be appropriated out of any money in the United States Treasury not otherwise appropriated. Resolved; in the opinion of the executive officials of the health departments of the various states and territories, the state departments of health of the respective states and territories </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Fourth Annual Bulletin should assist the federal authorities in the following sanitary activities during the period of the war. First. The sanitation of military and naval camps and camp sites. Second. The exercise of police powers in relation to the sanitation of the environment of military and naval camps. Third. The provisions, when required, of public health laboratory facilities for the diagnosis and sanitary surveillance of infectious disease occurring among the troops. Fourth. The provisions as far as possible, when required, of hospital accommodations for the care of cases of communicable disease occurring among the troops. Fifth. The protection of military and naval camps from the introduction of communicable diseases, (including tuberculosis and venereal disease), from the civilian population. Sixth. The sanitation of intrastate transportation facilities. Seventh. The investigation and exclusion from military and naval camps of disease carriers. Eighth. The immediate reporting to the Public Health Ser - vice of epidemic foci of various infectious diseases, (especially poliomyelitis, epidemic cerebro-spinal meningitis, smallpox, ty - phus, typhoid, and paratyphoid fevers and bacillary dysentery), developing in any of the states or territories. Ninth. The sanitary supervision of refugees and interned aliens. Tenth. The sanitary supervision of the sources of the water, milk, and food supplies of the combatant forces. Eleventh. The sanitary supervision of soldiers suffering from pulmonary tuberculosis, or those rejected from the army and naval forces because of this disease. Twelfth. The sanitary supervision of migratory laborers and of industrial camps. Resolved; that the Surgeon General of the United States Public Health Service be requested to definitely formulate and advise the executive health officials of the various states and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska State Board of Health 13 territories of the lines of activity in which the United States Public Health Service is able to extend aid to the state and local health officials of the country in case of necessity during the war : Resolved ; that in the opinion of the executive health officers of the various states and territories, the United States Public Health Service should establish and promulgate standards as to potency with reference to all biological products, vaccines, and sera, not only with relation to diphtheria and tetanus anti-toxin, but also especially with relation to anti-meningococcus and pneu - monia sera, and vaccines for typhoid, para-typhoid fever and bacillary dysentery. The preceding resolutions and proposed rules and regu - lations adopted by the Conference of State and Territorial Boards of Health and United States Department of Public Health will undoubtedly be enacted and become the rules and regulations governing state departments of health. As to the provisions in Nebraska for their enforcement compared with that of Other states will say that the appropriation for the successful carrying out of the same would be entirely inadequate, but our state is fortunate in having laws that if thorotighly understood and prop - erly executed will furnish us with means for their successful enforcement. The laws in this state impose upon the authorities of counties, towns and villages the duties of protecting the people from dis - eases arising from unsanitary conditions and from contagious, infectious and epidemic diseases and they are held responsible for the same and on their failure to perform this function the state department of health can step in and take charge and perform these duties and collect the expenses necessary for the completion of the work from the municipality. Almost every county in the state now has a County Health Officer. All cities, towns and villages with but few exceptions have local boards of health and local health officers, and where a local health officer has not been appointed and they have failed to organize a local board of health, the County Commissioners or Supervisors are held' responsible and compelled to perform that </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Fourth Annual Bulletin function. The same law pertains to towns and incorporated vil - lages,—thus it will be seen that every part of the state has means of enforcing these rules and regulations. Aside from the statutory provisions above referred to the State Hoard of Health has the power to formulate rules and regu - lations governing Public Health and Sanitation. The State Board of Health in this state have formulated and issued rules and regulations which are now in the hands of every health officer in the state which I believe pretty thoroughly covers the require - ments and they will need but very little revision or extension, iind with the co-operation of the Federal Department of Health all necessary measures can be enforced. Special rules and regulations should be issued covering the areas adjoining mobilization and military camps, also those of industrial camps. Probably one of the greatest menances to the people will be the spreading of disease by migratory laborers, — especially that of typhus fever and the infection of our water supplies with the germs of typhoid fever. This will require the issuing of strict rules governing this class. The United States Public Health Ser - vice will in the very near future formulate rules and advise the executive health officers in the various states and territories of the lines of activity in which the United States Public Health Service is able to extend aid to the state and local health officials of the country in case of necessity during the war. I deem it unnecessary to offer any further suggestion on this subject, but will submit to you immediately upon receipt of same these rules and advise. It was recommended by the Federal Department of Health and by the Conference that the State Boards of Health of the sev - eral states call a conference of local health officers for the purpose of instructing them as to their duties and responsibilities. That the rules and regulations governing sanitation and the means for the prevention be thoroughly explained so that they may have a correct understanding of what will be expected of them by the state health authorities. Respectfully submitted, H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Delegate representing Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska State Board of Health 15 Reply to the Report of Dr. Charles V. Chapin Who Was Appointed by the A. M. A. to Inspect and Rate State Boards of Health. Frederick R. Green, Secretary, Council on Health and Public Instruction Chicago, Illinois. Dear Sir: In reply to your request of May 29th for any criticisms or comments on the report of Dr. Charles V. Chapin, concerning this state, will say, that owing to the fact that Dr. Chapin only gave me, as secretary of the Board and representing the board, one hour's time in which to inform him as to the work of the Board and the difficulties under which they were laboring and from the nature of his report, I feel confident that his opinions were largely formed from statements made by parties that were unfamiliar with the conditions, or not in sympathy with the Board of Secretaries. His recommendations regarding Nebraska are not in harmony with those to other states, as will be seen by his conflicting statements as to other states in suggestions on organizations and plans of work. He states that "The organization of the Health Department is bad, and it is said that political influence makes itself felt." He also states : "It would seem to be wise to allow the existing Board of Secretaries to remain and to continue as the examining board for physicians which has hitherto been their chief function. All the executive power in regard to public health might be placed in the hands of a Commissioner of Health to be appointed by the ex-officio Board of Health, and he should be a man skilled in sanitary science and who would give his whole time to the work and he ought to be paid adequately threefor. He should be given full au - thority in appointments." Where the "political influence" that he speaks of is most manifest he does not state, but from his recommendations that </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Fourth Annual Bulletin the Board of Secretaries (who are supposed to be the Board of Health) be continued as Examining Board for physicians, and that the appointing power to be taken from their hands and placed in the hands of the ex-officio board would indicate that he considers them better capable of selecting an executive officer or (Commissioner of Health) than the Board of Health composed of four physicians who are appointed on the recommendations of the State Medical Societies. It would also seem that he places more confidence in an ex-officio Board of Health in this state composed of laymen, who are usually expert politicians and skilled in the science of politics, to be better qualified to select an executive officer or (Commissioner of Health) whom he says should be "a man skilled in sanitary science," than a Board of Health consisting of physicians who must have had an experience of seven years in the practice of their profession. Just why Dr. Chapin should single out the State of Nebraska and recommend an entirely different organization from any other state in the Union, and say that the Board of Health or the Board of Secretaries should remain simply as an Examining Board ; and deny them any authority or duties pertaining to sanitation and public health is to the Board of Secretaries and the medical pro - fession, as a whole, somewhat of a mystery. We realize the fact that the laws that have been enacted in this state pertaining to health and sanitation, which we consider to be on a par with those of other states, have been formulated and their enactment secured through the work and influence of the medical profession. We also feel that the medical profession should be recognized in securing their enforcement, which they would not be, only to a limited degree if Dr. Chapin 's recom - mendations were adopted. To convince you of the fact that Dr. Chapin holds the same veiws as we do regarding this matter, I wish to cite you some of the statements in his report : On page 68. Mode of Election. — "This has already been referred to. The best way to keep the office out of politics seems to be to have the Board of Health elect the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska State Board of Health 17 executive AND THIS IS IMPORTANT ENOUGH TO DE - MAND ABOARD OF HEALTH, EVEN IP THE LATTER FULFILLED NO OTHER PURPOSE." On page 21, in his report on Iowa, whose laws pertaining to the State Board of Health are the same as that of Nebraska : "The whole board meets only twice a year and mean - while the state health officer has full executive authority, except as regards finances, and is in close touch with the "Executive Council," which seems to have much more to do with the management of the department than does the nominal board of health. Such a complicated organization suggests that it was not devised along broad lines but to meet some special exigency." On page 30. in his report on Michigan : "Michigan has a State Board of Health composed of representative men who take much interest in the work of the department and whose advice and assistance are of great value. Formerly the board elected its executive officer, but he was a few years ago, made an appointee of the governor, which does not appear to be a wise change, but the last legislature provided that he ia to be recom - mended by the board." I wish to call your special attention to pages 63 and 64 under "Mode of Election," in which he says: "On the other hand the freedom from pernicous politics for long years, and the success of such state health departments as those of Indiana, Kansas, Maryland, Massa - chusetts. Minnesota, New Jersey, North Carolina, Ohio, Rhode Island and Vermont in which the board of health chooses the executive or did so during a long period of usefulness, suggest that this method is the safer one an&lt;l for the present is likely to yield better results. "This method of selecting an executive, by election by the board of health, is the oldest method and, as has been stated, was a natural evolution from the original plan which conceived the board itself as doing most of the executive work. In thirty-three states, • • • • the executive officer is elected by the board. ' ' The only reason that is advanced in favor of appoint- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Fourth Annual Bulletin ment by the governor is the somewhat theoretical one that all executive power should be lodged in the chief executive so as to fix responsibility. To offset this we have the fact that the governor is a partisan and often too much at home in the pernicious methods of practical politics. The board of health is, as a matter of fact, very frequently, though unfortunately not always, free from political entangle - ments and often unfamiliar with the political spirit and methods. Furthermore the selection of a public health executive is no easy task and scarcely any one would claim that the governor is as well qualified to select a competent health officer as are the members of the board of health who are usually far more familiar with the needs of such an office than is the governor. When the Utopian day arrives in which the governor, in his appointments, will ignore all claims to office, except fitness, it may be well to transfer to him all executive appointments, but until then, the states in which the state health officer is selected by the board of health had better cling to this method. It is unfortunate when it is felt necessary to change the method simply as a means of getting rid of an undesirable official." Dr. Chapin has laid great stress on the fact that the best way to eliminate "the influence of pernicious politics" is to place the appointive powers in the hands of the Board of Health, and I believe that Nebraska is no exception to the rule. Having served on this board for ten years, I can truthfully say, that politics have never influenced a member of the Board of Secretaries in the performance of their duties. Our idea of a survey of a Board of Health either state, county or municipal is to go and confer with the Board of Health and ascertain what is needed in each particular case ; show them where improvements can be made in their organization, advise them as to the best means of accomplishing results, find out what opposition they have to contend with whether it be from the people, the politician or the authority to whom they are subjected. The person making the survey assumes a great responsibility, for his influence is great for good or evil with the people whose wishes govern the politician and the authorities. And should the person making the survey, unjustly criticize or condemn the work </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska State Board of Health 19 of the board, he has done them a great injury, lessened their in - fluence and established a prejudice against health work that takes a long time to overcome. Our motto is "Stand by the Health Officer" and the more strenuous the opposition to him, the greatter our efforts to sup - port him and to convince the people that he is the most necessary official in the community. And we are firmly convinced of the fact that it is through the hearty co-operation of the local Boards of Health and the Health Officer that the greatest good can be accomplished. We make it a point to pay no attention to the criticism of outsiders, and those not in sympathy with the local Boards of Health officials, and especially the "knocker." We ask the same consideration to be given us. We feel that Dr. Chapin did not give us just credit for the work we have done, and we are held responsible by the public for neglect in departments over which we had no control, and we have been compelled to defend ourselves in the public press against unjust criticisms arising from his reports. (See Ne - braska State Journal of May 27, 1916. clippipg of same enclosed.) Time and space does not permit our going into detail in re - gard to credits. He would have been of material aid to us in securing the enacting of a bill whereby we would have had an executive officer and could have secured a larger appropriation of money with which to carry on the work had he been fair to us, but his recommendations were used against us by our oppo - nents, and we were defeated in our efforts as we were unani - mously opposed to placing the control in the hands of a governor and for which there was no precedent. Dr. Chapin 's ability as a health officer and sanitarian is un - questioned and he is probably one of the best, if not the best, in the United States, having not only a national but an international reputation as such, but I do not believe that any man, even Dr. Chapin, can go into this state or any other state and in the short space of twenty-four hours make a report as to the health stand - ing of the state that would be worthy of consideration. As above stated he only gave the representative of the Board of Secretaries </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Fourth Annual Bulletin one hour, but gathered some information from outsiders who were not familiar with the facts. Enclosed you will find a copy of my reply to the criticisms through the press by Dr. Henry B. Ward, of the University of Illinois, which will give you more detailed information as to credits, etc., to which I ask your careful consideration. Respectfully submitted, H. B. CUMMINS, Secretary. RESPONSIBILITY OF MUNICIPALTIES FOR SICKNESS AND DEATH RESULTING FROM NEGLIGENCE. The health of the people has long been recognized as an economic asset and a social blessing. It was the subject of ancient literature and philosophy, and never, perhaps, has civil - ized man been oblivious to its importance. Yet it has remained for our own times, which might well be styled the age of con - servation, to take practical cognizance of the matter. As our population has increased and our civilization becomes more com - plex, there has been a steady tendency toward a code of rules to guard against illness, disease and pestilence. Health officers and boards have been appointed for the purpose of devising and enforcing sanitary measures, and there has been much legislation enacted in relation to particular matters affecting health. Preservation of the public health is one of the duties devolv - ing upon the state as a sovereign power. There is no more im - perative duty or obligation resting upon the state, and all neces - sary steps should be taken through its proper instrumentalitiea and agencies to attain this object. The police power residing in the state and which it cannot surrender is ample to support this great duty of the state. With the end in view that it is to the best interests of the state, as well as to the individual, to preserve the public health, the several </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska State Board of Health 21 states have enacted quarantine regulations; established insane hospitals, public hospitals, institutions for the blind, deaf and dumb ; and laws excluding infected cattle, rags and impure food. Some of the states have limited the hours for workers, especially women and children. Every state may pass and enforce quaran - tine regulations, health and inspection laws to prevent the intro - duction of disease, pestilence or unwholesome food, as such laws are properly within the police power of the state and are subjects of domestic regulation. Health boards are created either by direct legislative act and their powers conferred upon them by the legislature or municipalities are authorized to create local health boards for the purpose of protecting the public health. In Nebraska, section 2710, Revised Statutes for 1913, pro vides : ■ " The State Board of Health shall consist of the gover - nor, attorney general and superintendent of public instruc - tion, the governor shall be ex-officio chairman of the board." Section 2714, Revised Statutes for 1913, provides "It shall be the duty of the board of health to see that all the provisions of this and the following article are strictly enforced, to grant certificates as hereinafter pro - vided and to cause to be prosecuted all violations of the next following article. Said board shall have the right at all 1 iim-s to inspect the equipment and methods of teach - ing in all medical colleges and schools of the state, and shall have the power to refuse examination to the graduates of any school, which, on proper notice and hearing, shall be adjudged not a medical college or school in good standing as defined by law of this state. The board shall have and us* 1 a common seal and make and adopt all necessary rules, regulations and by-laws not inconsistent with the constitu - tion and law of this state or of the United States, to enable it to perform its duties and transact its business under the provisions of this chapter." In accordance with the above quoted section of the statutes the state board of health has adopted certain rules and regula- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Fourth Annual Bulletin tions relating to quarantine and other matters of public health. Section 2738, Revised States, 1913, provides : ' ' The state board of health shall have supervision and control of all matters relating to sanitation and quarantine necessary to the protection of the people of this state from disease arising from unsanitary conditions and from con - tagious, infectious and epidemic diseases; and it shall be the duty of said state board of health to formulate, adopt and publish such proper and reasonable general rules and regulations as will best serve to promote sanitation throughout the state, and prevent the introduction or spread of disease. In addition to such general and stand - ing rules and regulations, in cases of emergency wherein the health of the people of the entire state or any locality therein shall be menaced by or exposed to any such con - tagious, infectious or epidemic disease or diseases arising from unsanitary conditions, or when a local board of health having jurisdiction of a particular locality shall fail or refuse to act with sufficient promptitude and efficiency in any such emergency; or in localities wherein no local board of health shall have been established, as provided by law, it shall be the duty of the board to adopt and enforce such special quarantine and sanitary regulations as the occasion and the proper protection of the public health may require; and all necessary expenses incurred in the enforcement of such rules and regulations shall be paid by the city, village or county, for and within which the same shall have been incurred. It shall be the duty of all local, municipal and county boards of health, health au - thorities and officials, officers of state institutions, police officers, sheriffs, constables and all other officers and em - ployes of the state, or of any county, city, village or town - ship thereof, and every person, to obey and enforce such quarantine and sanitary rules and regulations as may be adopted by the state board of health; and each and every person or officer specified in this section, who shall fail, neglect or refuse to obey or enforce such rules or regula - tions shall, upon conviction, for each and every such offense, be subject to a fine of not less than fifteen nor more than one hundred dollars." (1902, p. 351; 1913, p. 571; Ann. 9867; Comp. 4402.) Next to be considered is the powers of local boards of health </seg>
            <seg id="p023">■ Nebraska State Board of Health 23 in counties or the several municipalities within the state, and in discussing this feature of health matters it seems advisable to acertain first the statutory enactments. Section 2737, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, pro - vides: ' ' The county boards of the several counties shall make and enforce regulations to prevent the introduction and spread of contagious, infectious or malignant diseases in their respective counties; and to that end shall make and enforce quarantine rules, and shall establish in each county a board of health, one member of which shall be a legally registered physician, which board shall have jurisdiction throughout all the territory comprising said county, ex - cept incorporated cities and villages having the power to establish boards of health and quarantine regulations. When quarantine rules and regulations have not been made and a board has not been appointed as above specified and provided for, then the county board of supervisors or com - mossioners are hereby charged with and it shall be their duty to enforce the quarantine rules and regulations of the state board of health." (1901, p. 403; 1903, p. 358; 1911, p. 328; Ann. 9866; Comp. 4401.) Under proper statutory enactments all incorporated cities, towns and villages are empowered to provide by ordinance such regulations as may be necessary to preserve the public health, prevent the introduction and spread of contagious or infectious diseases and in cities of metropolitan class to create boards of health in the municipality. The next question to be considered is the civil liability of a municipality for negligence in health matters which results in sickness and death, being properly the subject of this discussion. The leading modern case upon the question appears to be Keever vs. City of Mankato, Minn. 129 N. R. 158, decided in December, 1910. In that case an administratrix, Delia Eeever, brought suit against the City of Mankato, Minnesota, and alleged in her petition : ' ' That defendant, a municipal corporation, negligently </seg>
            <seg id="p024">&lt; 24 Fourth Annual Bulletin allowed waters and the water supply in its waterworks system to become infected and polluted with poisonous substances and large quantities of filth and sewage, all of which were saturated with the germs of diseases • • • and did carelessly and negligently • • • permit filthy, foul and dangerous substances, common sewage, and other filth to escape into and saturate the water supply ; that by reason thereof the water became imminently dangerous to life and health, of which defendant had full notice and knowledge; that plaintiff's intestate, a citizen and resi - dent, used the water, contracted typhoid fever, and died in consequence." It will be noticed that the complaint did not set forth a mere action to recover damages from the defendant because the city failed to provide an adequate supply of pure water. The question here being the liability of the city for recklessly caus - ing dangerous substances, like common sewage and other filth, to saturate its water supply and the wells, mains and appur - tenances thereto. Various contentions were made by counsel for the city in the case, but the court held: "On general principles, liability for negligence is more just and more generally recognized, because it is based upon culpability." While the Nebraska courts have not been called upon to decide an analagous case, yet due care and diligence should be had in all health matters to avoid litigation. In the State of New York, in the case of Danaher vs. Brook - lyn, 119 N. Y. 241, 7 L. R. A. 592, 23 X. E. 745, affirming 51 Hun. 563, 4 N. Y. Supp. 312, which was an action for damages for the death of plaintiff's intestate from typhoid fever contracted by drinking water from a public well maintained by the city in one of its streets, it was held that plaintiff was properly non-suited, the court saying: "The city was not an insurer of the quality of the water and bound under all circumstances to keep it pure and wholesome. This is not claimed. It owned this well as it owned its other property kept for public use, such as streets, parks, and public buildings, and it owed the duty of reasonable </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska State Board of Health 25 diligence to care for it as it was bound to care for such other propery. Its liability for unwholesome water in any of its pub - lic wells must rest upon negligence, ' ' and finding that it was not negligent in that it had no notice of the impurity of the water, which had been used for years, and had apparently remained wholesome until very the near the time deceased contracted the disease from it. The plaintiff was non-suited for the reason that he did not establish by sufficient evidence the negligence of the defendant city. The clear inference is that if he could have established negligence on the part of the city, his suit would have been successful. A later New York case, decided in July, 1914, is Thomas E. Stubbs vs. The City of Rochester, New York, 163 Appellate Divi - sion 245, wherein Thomas Stubbs brought suit against the city and recovered a verdict on the theory that he contracted typhoid fever from the defendant city's domestic water supply, of which he drank daily at his place of employment, and that the water had become polluted with sewage containing the particular germ which produces typhoid fever, through the negligence of the city with respect to its water supply and system. It appeared that the city used water taken from the Genesee river for fire pur - poses, also other water for drinking purposes, for hydraulic power in raising a bridge over the Erie Canal but had installed a check valve in the pipes of each system, so as to prevent the drinking water from being contaminated by the water of the river. In - habitants of the city residing near the bridge complained of the water, and it was finally discovered that the river water was entering the domestic water pipes. The plaintiff was non-suited in the Supreme Court for the reason that the evidence was in - sufficient to establish the finding that for the city's negilgence plaintiff would not have had typhoid fever at the time in question. The cases upon the question are not numerous, bnt it may safely be said that where the evidence is sufficient to establish negligence on the part of a municipal corporation, and where the injury complained of is sufficiently established to be due to </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Fourth Annual Bulletin the city's negligence, the courts will hold the city liable for sick - ness and death due to the negligence of the municpiality ; hence it seems advisable that health authorities of municipalities should be vigilant in the discharge of their duty. — Address by Hon. Dexter T. Barrett, Deputy Attorney General of Nebraska; de - livered before the Conference of State and Local Health Officers, February 21, 1917. THE RELATION OF BOARDS OF HEALTH TO THE CANCER PROBLEM. E. H. McLean, M. D., Creighton Medical College, Omaha. It is without any feeling of apology whatever that I present a paper on a subject which has apparently been so worn out with discussion that when it comes time for it on the program every - body feels that he must go out and have a smoke. A couple of years ago the prevalence of cancer and its rapid increase, espe - cially among the higher strata of society used to be the subject par excellence for full double pages in the Sunday editions, and for long frantic articles in the popular magazines, by a few who knew what they were talking about and by many who did not. At first the public became scared into panic and later hardened by the frequent repitition, but it must be confessed that this panic has left in the minds of all who do any reading, a whole - some fear of any lump of which the character is not at once evi - dent, this after all is the desired result of popular education in this line. If only this fear would give them the proper judg - ment in picking out the right man to consult all would be well. The enviable position in the lime light of public attention that was once occupied by cancer, was captured by twilight sleep, which flourished for a time like the green bay tree. This twi - light, however, is beginning to deepen into the darkness of birth control, which has been graduated from the tame restraint of print and has leaped upon the movie screen. Why has this important subject in public health lost its prominent position T Why do medical men feel like leaving the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska State Board of Health 27 room so soon as a paper is to be read on the subject t The answer is simply: Because we have nothing new to offer. "We are apparently no nearer the solution of the problem than we were several years ago. It is because of this lack of solution that I wish to present my paper today. I am not offering a cure, nor do I intend to harp on the subject that cancer is a dreadful disease with harrow - ing details to prove it, or emphasize the fact that between eighty and one hundred thousand people die every year from cancer in the United States, and that the percentage of deaths from cancer per hundred thousand of population is increasing with every census. These facts, and that early and radical surgical opreation is the only hope of cure for cancer are the only facts that we know or have known for years, notwithstanding the fun we have had playing with X-rays, radium, mesothorium pastes and what not, denying hundreds of patients the possibility of cure by the timely use of intelligent surgery. It is not now so important to emphasize the need of educat - ing the general public, for the seed has been sown by the sen - sational cancer stories in the lay press ; the dissemination is being kept up by the various societies for the prevention of cancer, and the seed is being watered and fertilized by the wholesome fear that has crept into the hearts of the people at the sound of the word cancer, or at the sight of any unfamiliar lump. Of course it is desirable to continue the spread of popular informa - tion, but I am not so sure but that it is even more necessary to make strenuous efforts to waken the medical profession. Many times will a patient report to his doctor at an early stage of his disease, only to be temporized with by the use of pastes and poultices until the one slim chance that he had, has vanished, and his brightest prospect is the undertaker in a few months. It is only in very large metropolises such as New York City or Chicago that boards of health can conduct research work along laboratory lines ; so it hardly falls within their province to under - take to discover the cause and cure of cancer. However, they </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Fourth Annual Bulletin can do a part of the work without which the laboratory work is of little avail. I mean the procuring and tabulating of reliable and complete statistics of the incidence of, and mortality from cancer. During the past few years, as I have been going about doing work in surgical dispensaries, examining pathological material from operating rooms, and doing autopsies, several things have come to my mind, which have seemed to me to be very desirable measures to use if we would know more about cancer clinically and statistically, and if we would be efficient in getting control of it. The first is : To place cancer on the list of diseases that are required by law to be reported to the board of health. By cancer it is gen - erally conceded that we mean any malignant tumor whether it be carcinoma or sarcoma, or some of the more rare types of malignancy. I would place in this list also, any mass or lump that is suspiciously malignant, or in locations where malignancy is- the common cause of masses. This then would include all masses in the breast not of a manifestly inflammatory nature, for most of these, whether they be simple cysts or benign adenomata, are potentially malignant, and are so recognized by most surgeons and pathologists. The public in generall would object to this measure chiefly because everybody hates to have his infirmities made a matter of public record To overcome this prejudice is merely a matter of public education. For a very short time in a very few cases it might make patients hesitate to go to their physicians, for the same reason that they hesitate to have a throat culture taken. The same laws that govern the matter in the case of diphtheria could be made to apply with equal effect here. A board of health that is held responsible for the health of a community is entitled to any information it may desire con - cerning matters directly or indirectly affecting the health of that community, and should have the power to take the necessary means to secure that information. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska State Board of Health 29 What effect would this have on that set of legalized criminals, the cancer cure fakers t These men make their money partly by nursing along the hope of cure that is eternal in every incurable patient until they have all his money, or they delude the patient with incipient cancer into believing he can be cured without operation, by the use of pastes, injections, etc., until his only chance of cure is passed. Another element of the success of this type of practitioner lies in the mistakes of his more ethical confreres. An incident comes to my mind of a man who had a syphilitic granuloma. He was told by his physician that it was a cancer and advised to have it operated. Unwilling to undergo an operation he went to a man who advertised to cure cancer. This man was keen enough to recognize the character of the condition, but said, "Yes, you have a cancer but I can cure it," which he did with the usual anti-syphilitic treatment, and got the credit of being a great cancer specialist. A system of report - ing malignant disease would have made the first man more care - ful, and the second man would have had to be honest with his patient ; so the incident would not have occurred. Such a system would bring the quack out into the open, and keep him from denying the proper kind of treatment to cases of early cancer, and make him more honest in what he diagnosis as cancer, thus removing the alluring bait obtained by cures of conditions that are not malignant The second suggestion that I would like to make is: — That it be required that all tumors removed at operation that come under the heading of tumors that should be reported, be examined grossly and microscopically by a competent pathologist, and that his findings be reported to the board of health. I am not mak - ing a plea for pathologists in general. The work could be done, as are diphtheria cultures, by a man regularly employed by the health board. In another state I had the opportunity to examine routine specimens from several hospitals, that were saved for the medical school as a matter of an accommodation, as the specimens were useful in teaching pathology. So far as many of the operators knew the specimens had been thrown away. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Fourth Annual Bulletin In several of these specimens that would have been discarded without an examination it was our privilege to find malignancy where it had not even been suspected. On the other hand, a patient has a tumor, is told that it is malignant, and an operation is advised in all honesty. The tumor is removed and no pathological examination made. The patient has the joy of going through life in constant terror lest he have a recurrence of his cancer when, in many cases the original tumor may have been benign. I firmly believe that every patient is entitled to know definitely the pathological findings of any piece of tissue removed at operation. The sooner we take medicine from its secretive and mystic basis, just that soon can we treat our patients with intelligence, and expect them to respond with the same degree of intelligence. No one expects a man to go into a busi - ness deal, no matter how small, without knowing all the facts, yet we expect him to risk his life on nothing more assuring than a sublime faith ia a man who, entirely unintentionally may be going to do him his greatest injury. When medicine leaves the company of palmists and clairvoyants it will receive the entire sympathy and support of the intelligent public and not until then. I recall quite vividly the case of a woman, fairly young, who by accident discovered a small tumor in her breast. She imme - diately went to her family physician who treated it with poultices for a few weeks. As the tumor seemed to- be growing, the woman consulted another doctor, who aspirated it and then watched it a while. Finally she went to the right man who, though not a surgeon, advised immediate operation. The surgeon obtained did a purely local operation on a clinically malginant tumor and then never bothered to find out the true condition of affairs. The tumor happened to be saved and was examined patho - logically, but the surgeon does not know yet what the diagnosis was. If there had been a law requiring cancer to be reported, the first man would have been more particular about seeing that his patient secured the proper treatment, for he would have known that his work would be checked up. The woman knew </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska State Board of Health 31 enough to seek immediate advice about a dangerous condtiion, but unfortunately she sought a doctor who did not know as much about it as she did. If a pathological examination were required, that operator would get into the habit of doing more complete operations for he would know that his operation would be a matter of public record, his practice would demand it, and as a result the patient would have had the benefit of the best chance that could have been offered her. The initial report of such a case together with the patho - logists report would make a most valuable and complete record, and in a short time statistics of the greatest worth would be obtained, complete and easy of access. In that way boards of health could do inestimable service in the great struggle to con - trol cancer. The third suggestion I make with considerable hesitation for it sounds somewhat radical. Our medical education, either among the profession or among the laity has hardly reached such a stage of advancement that a suggestion such as this could be made a statute, but it is to be strongly urged that every case dying of internal or suspected cancer be examined on the post mortem table by a physician, or better by a pathologist and the findings be made a part of the records in the board of health cancer statistics. A measure of this last sort would naturally meet with wide spread opposition, but every medical man knows that if this country is to take the front rank in medicine that she deserves, it is necessary to educate both ourselves and the public to the realization that autopsies on all and especially the obscure diseases are of inetimable benefit to the public at large, and are indespensable to a successful effort to study and control disease. At present our cancer statistics are unreliable, incomplete and relatively inaccessible, they are based entirely on death certifi - cates. Very often a cancer may be present, but as the patient may die of an intercurrent disease, the cancer being neither the direct or chief contributing cause of death, it does not appear on the certificate. If ever we expect to make our statistics of value they must be collected along some such line as that outlined, </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Fourth Annual Bulletin and until we do get reliable and complete statistics much of the hard work in the cancer laboratories will be thrown away. To sum up I would urge: That boards of health make in - vestigation of all cases of death from cancer. That all tumors, at least those in a position and of a type liable to become can - cerous, be put on the same basis as regards reporting as are the infectious diseases at present. That the state should appropriate funds to provide officers competent to examine clinically if neces - sary, and pathologically if desired, any tumor before or after removal, and that it be made a misdemeanor to remove any tumor however innocent clinically, without a thorough patho - logical examination being made and reported. And I would sug - gest that the various state boards of health co-operate to secure a uniform system of reporting the occurrence of, and death from cancer. — Read before the Annual Conference of State and Local Health Officers, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 21, 1917. AS TO MEDICAL COLLEGES Seward, Nebraska, September 16, 1916. David A. Strickler, M. D., President National Federation of State Medical Boards, Denver, Colorado. Dear Doctor : Yours of recent date received, requesting that I give you, in more or less detail, what I think should be considered by the Federation of State Medical Boards at their coming meeting. In reply will say, that one of the most important things to be considered is in my opinion, the question of medical colleges. It has been the principle subject for consideration (or at least has received the most attention and brought out the most dis - cussion and a greater variety of opinions) than any other sub - ject, and I believe is further from a satisfactory solution today than any other question that has eome before the Federation. My opinion on this subject may differ very materially from the </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Nebraska State Board of Health 33 other members of the Association, but yet I believe it worthy of consideration. In the first place, a college that does not fulfill the require - ments for turning out graduates that are qualified to begin the practice of medicine should not be recognized by any Board of Medical Examiners and certainly not by the Federation. This would necessitate the establishing of a standard for medical col - leges which might be termed a minimum standard, and I am of the opinion that this is the first and most essential thing to be done. At the present time we have four different classifications A plus, A, B and C which gives a great amount of latitude to the colleges that may claim to be eligible to graduate, and to students. The question may be asked, what one or number of these classes are qualified or should be recognized as being eligible for recognition and upon what they base their qualifications for the same? If we decide to exclude the class C school and will recognize the class B school, the reasons for the accepting or rejecting of either should be fully given. On the other hand, should we decide that class B does not fulfill the requirements, it would seem that it would be an imposition on the public to recognize a class B school, whereas if a class B school is recog - nized as a medical college and its graduates sufficiently qualified to practice medicine, it places the school in an unsatisfactory position as a medical college, from the very fact that it is classed as a class B and is more or less stigmatized. I should say is discredited by the profession and the public by being so classified and results in the classificatoin of physicians who are graduates of different schools. This works an injustice to worthy prac - titioners unless some special reason is given for the classification. It doe not seem just to permit the one who has fulfilled the requirements and has completed a course of study entitling him to the degree of M. D. to be classified without some satisfactory and just reason for the same. It would hardly meet with the approval of the rank and file of the profession or of graduates to be classed as a Class B Doctor, Class A Doctor and a Class A </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Fourth Annual Bulletin plus Doctor. I believe it would be more just and reasonable to establish a standard high enough and make the requirement suffi - cient that anyone receiving a diploma from a recognized medical college, that is, one that is recognized by the Federation, to be classed as a Doctor, to be considered as a Doctor of Medicine, and that the profession and public classify them as they do at the present time, by their special qualifications and the work that they accomplish. Hence, I am of the opinion, that the classi - fication of colleges is all wrong and that colleges should be classi - fied the same as physicians are now classified and recognized, simply by their ability and reputation. I would refer you to the address of President C. R. Bardeen, of the University of Wisconsin, at the meeting of the Association of American Medical Colleges in Chicago, February 8, 1916, and would call your attention to the results of a report on the career of the graduates of the John Hopkins Medical School, which he says, "was the first to assume what have since become, with a few modificatoins, the modern standards of medical education in this country, a statistical study of the careers of the graduates of the first ten years, 1897-1906 inclusive, may be of value in throwing light on the results produced by recent trends in medical education." I would ask you to carefully study the tables therein pre - sented. It shows that of the first five classes, 71.1 per cent were in practice and of the second five classes, 85.2 per cent were in practice and the table number two show, that only 22 per cent of the graduates were in general practice, and of these 22 per cent that not one of the graduates were practicing in towns with a population of less than five thousand, and that only 6.7 per cent were practicing in towns with a population of ten thousand, and that 68.3 per cent were practicing in towns with a population of one hundred thousand inhabitants or over, or in other words, only 30.5 per cent were practicing in towns of less than one hun - dred thousand inhabitants. This would lead one to the con - clusion that a Class B physician would be eligible to practice in the rural district or small towns while a Clam B physician might </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Nebraska State Board of Health 35 be eligible to practice in towns of twenty-five thousand to five hundred thousand inhabitants, and an A plus graduate in cities of not less than five hundred thousand to one million and over. Reasoning from the above, one would be led to believe that if we should decide to recognize none but A plus schools, that in a course of years we would only have graduate physicians in towns of over one hundred thousand inhabitants. On the other hand, should we recognize graduates of Class A schools, in a few years, we would be unable to furnish physicians who would be willing to practice in towns of less than fifty thousand inhabit - ants, for you must realize, that the number of physicians would rapidly grow less and the tendency of those remaining in the practice would be the same as if is now to locate in centers of large population. You can readily imagine what the condition would be in the small cities and rural districts. Charlaticisra and quackery would become rampant, and we could justly para - phrase the poet Goldsmith, and say, "111 fares the land to human ills a prey, where ability centralizes and ignorance runs a-stray. ' ' Dr. Bardeen seems to convey the opinion that in time, if the standard for medical colleges is placed too high, too few physi - cians will be graduated to take charge of the work in a country where the population is rapidly increasing, and the demand for physicians is greater than most any other nation. Dr. "Wilson's paper shows the situation that exists in Maryland and is a very good citerian upon which to base the probable conditions in the future, should we be too exacting in our demand. You will note that I have frequently stated that there should be no classification without just reason for the same. I wish to be understood by this, that if we are to permit the classifi - cation of schools and that which will easily follow the classifi - cation of physicians, the public must be given to understand the reason for such classification. I do not believe that the classifi - cation can be based upon the amount of appropriation, the num - ber of those on the faculty or by the reputation of the faculty. Neither can it be based satisfactorily upon the laboratory facili - ties, for we should not recognize any college that does not main- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Fourth Annual Bulletin tain a laboratory sufficiently equipped to meet the requirements of students that are preparing themselves for the Degree of Doctor of Medicine. We might legitimately classify schools, that are equipped and claim to go further than this and have taken up more extensive work such as that of Medical Research and are qualified to fulfill the requirements of what is now termed Post Graduate Schools of Medicine, for the purpose of educating men for the specialities, when such school may be so classified and their graduates be recognized as such. Very truly your, H. B. CUMMINS. Denver, Colo., January 11, 1917. Dr. H. B. Cummins, Seward, Nebraska. My Dear Doctor: Yours of September 16th should have received an earlier reply and would have done so had I not been too busy in cam - paign matters generally to give it the consideration which was its due. I have recently taken up the subjects relative to Federation matters generally and have read with much interest again your communication. Within the past three days I have had an opportunity of talking over Federation matters with Dr. Bierring, the secretary, and find that he is much in accord with yourself on the advis - ability of establishing but two classes of colleges, those which are acceptable and those which are not. This matter will be discussed fully I am inclined to think when our committee re - ports, and I sincerely trust that you will find it convenient to be present at this conference when I am sure that your views will meet with considerable approbation. I personally am under the impression that you are on the right track. Sincerely yours. DAVID A. STRICKLER. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Nebraska 8UU Board of Health 37 HOW SYPHILIS 18 COMMUNICATED W. L. Copell, M. D., Lincoln, Nebraska The object of this short paper is to call your attention to a few of the many ways that syphilis may be conveyed from one to another without sexual congress, and in this way to rob it of a part of that stigma that marks it as always an evidence of immorality or infidelity. The subject of syphilis is one that must be taken into con - sideration by the health board of this and every other state. It has already been too long neglected. It is not likely that the great awakening that has recently taken place not only in the minds of the medical profession but of the laity will fail to bear fruit. The number of the human family that are infected was hardly dreamed of until Wassermann discovered his test. Since that time setimates have been made by different observers, and while the results have varied widely, sufficient evidence has been brought to light to prove that at least ten per cent of the people are infected with syphilis. If there are one hundred million people in the United States, it would mean ten million people infected with the disease in this country. This condition is truly appalling, and especially so when we consider the great danger of one who is infected infecting others; more especially so as we consider the ease and different ways that this disease may be conveyed from one to another. Lingering in the minds of a great majority of the people is the very erroneous idea that this disease is communicated by illicit sexual approach only, while the facts are that not to ex - ceed one in ten of those infected have obtained it in this manner. This assertion may seem broad and perhaps unwarranted, but the most careful investigation will prove the position practically true. Almost every walk of life furnishes a means of conveying this disease. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Fourth Annual Bulletin Without wearying you by attempting to describe all the ways that this disease may be conveyed, mention will be made of only a few. Before proceeding in this regard let us prepare the indi - vidual to receive the infection. Experience and the teaching of those in a position to know brings out the fact that the normal or unbroken skin or mucous membrane will not permit the spiro - chetes (or, as we formally call it, the virus) to pass through it. While I am not wholly in accord with this teaching, we will desist from discussing it at this time. Assuming, it to be correct, ample opportunity is often furnished by which the broken skin or mucous membrane may be exposed to the contagion. Suppose that a person with aphthae, thrush or sores in the mouth due to some slight indigestion (of themselves trivial in character, usually passing away in a few days, and something that almost every person has at some period of his life) should be eating after and with the same fork or spoon that had just previously been used by a syphilitic in which the storm center of the disease was the mouth and throat, in which large mucous patches and syphilitic ulcers were present. The fork and spoon had only been washed in warm water and carelessly dried. How easy it would be, under these circumstances, to carry into these sores a sufficient number of spirochetes to infect the individual! But this is not the only way the spirochetes may be conveyed to these sores. The taking into the mouth foodsstuffs, especially such as are ingested without previous cooking, as bread and cheese that have been handled by a syphlitic with the eruption on the hands (a very frequent occurrence), or on other parts of the body with which the hands come frequently in contact, conveying the in - fection to the food, on which it is carried to the sores in the act of eating. The drinking cup is a prolific source of infection. (This has been partially remedied by the law regulating the use of public drinking cups.) But we still have the soda fountain, hotels and restaurants where drinking vessels are frequently only rinsed in cold water or simply wiped with a napkin. Last, but not least, we have the home where one member of the family may be infected unknown to the others, and, ignorant of the </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Nebraska State Board of Health 39 danger, the proper precautions are not taken and often the con - tagion is conveyed. Infected guests may be innocently the source of infection by the use of drinking cups. So that any - thing like complete sanitation must also include the home. Or, a barber in the act of shaving may abrade the skin, or by a small cut or decapitated pimple furnish an avenue for the ingress of the infection. Infected children on the playground at school, by the inter - change of gum and by the bringing of infected areas in contact with abraded surfaces, may convey the infection. The frequency with which contamination follows the use of soiled towels, drinking cups, carelessly washed dishes in the hotels, restaurants, and even in the home, have long been known. The home has possibly not received the consideration that it should. One member of the family, having contracted the dis - ease and unwilling to disclose his condition, may in the constant association with the other members, as in drinking, eating and sleeping, convey the infection to one or more of them. This mode of conveying the disease is far more frequent than is gen - erally supposed, and only those who have had experience know how difficult it is to get a young man with father, mother, sisters and brothers with whom he is in daily association to consent that the facts be made known to them so that the proper precautions may be taken to prevent their possible infection, and with that relic of barbarism fostered by the law of the land still dosing the mouths of the physician, making him particeps criminus. a silent watcher to the slow invasion of this insidious poison pass - ing into an innocent family. Then, a few years later, think of the mother of this scion, innocent of all wrong-doing, never dreaming that those seemingly innocent and not even painful patches in the throat and month and on her lips are teeming with the spirochetes and that she is innocently distributing the disease among her friends. Kissing is a prolific source of spreading the infection, and in this way many an innocent girl is contaminated by a thought- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Fourth Annual Bulletin less young man, ignorant of the danger that lurks in the act. The indiscriminate kissing of babies and children of those^ not aware of their condition has sealed the doom of many an innocent one. Dentists have been no mea nfactor in spreading the infection through the lack of proper sterilization of their instruments. We are loath to say that the physicians are not wholly blame - less, and only too often minor surgical operations are performed without proper asepsis, unmindful of the fact that the slightest solution of the continunity of the skin is just as fruitful a source of syphilitic infection as is a large abdominal incision. The most frequently neglected instrument of the physician, however, is the stethoscope. Syphilitic eruption is very frequent on the chest wall. Dragging the bell of the instrument over the infected sur - face is prone to contaminate it, and in turn may infect a harm - less acne on the breast of the next patient examined. Few physi - cians pay proper attention to the sterilization of this instrument. These are but a few of the many ways that syphilis may be conveyed to one too another. The spirochetes, in contradistinction to most pathogenic micro-organisms, is not lowly in character: filth and grime are not essential to their life and growth. They thrive as well among the high as among the low; they are as much at home in the palace of the rich as in the hovel of the poor. Hence the ordinary rules of sanitation cannot control them. This is a subject of great moment to the world, and the initiative for its control must come from men in your capacity. In preparing this paper due consideration was given to the element of time. Many things are just mentioned that would have required more time had they been properly elucidated than is being occupied by this entire paper. But lack of acquaintance with the rules governing this honorable body and the amount of business likely to come before it led to the thought that brevity would probably be preferable. No hint, even, has been given to a possible remedy, believing that this part of the subject had better be left to those whoso </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Nebraska State Board of Health 41 long acquaintance with the workings of legislation gives them the right to deference and superiority. One thing that seems important to me is education. This is a subject on which even the physician is not over-educated, and the laity is groping in the dark. No doubt the most stringent laws will have to be passed and rigidly enforced to stop the ravages of this disease. It seems to me that a campaign of education could not be otherwise than of great benefit, especially making it easier to enforce the law. This subject is far underestimated. Go to all the state institu - tions of our own fair state, and see what a financial burden it is already — and growing every year. No longer can we allow the language of the prude to govern, what shall be said upon this extremely important subject. It must betalked, and talked in language that can be understood. The interest of the home, the interest of the state, and the interest of every individual demand it. If the legislature of this state were to ask me what law they sin mill first pass for the control of this terrible scourge, my answer would be the appropriation of a hundred thousand dol - lars to buy space in the newspapers, in which should be published, under and by authority of a committee appointed by them, such facts as should be known by all people in regard to this matter. — Read before the Annual Conference of State and Local Health Officers, Lincoln, February 22, 1917. NEBRASKA STATE HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS Mr. President and Fellow Members: The State of Nebraska, two years ago, made its first tangible effort to stay the ravages of tuberculosis, by establishing a hos - pital for its segregation and treatment. A large brown stone house, together with about fifteen acres of ground near Kearney was purchased as an administration building and site for the "Hospital for Tuberculous," in January, 1912. The third floor of this building was used as sleeping rooms for the first patients admitted, until the hospital building, a pavilion built to accom - modate twenty-eight patients was completed in August, 1912. It </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Fourth Annual Bulletin is located about seventy-five feet north of the administration building and consists of a main part of two stories. The first story contains the general assembly room, dining room, drug room, linen room and kitchen. The econd story is one large room for entertainments, social gatherings, etc. East and west from this are two wings consisting of dressing rooms and sleep - ing porches for the patients, one side for women and the other for men. The institution was established, primarily, to care for "in - digent tuberculous persons" as the law defines them. However, when there is room we take cases who can afford to pay. A charge of $15.00 a week is made to them, being less than the actual cost to the state. All cases are required to make applica - tion through a physician on a form which is supplied on appli - cation. Indigent cases are required to furnish a certificate from their county commissioner that they are unable to pay for treat - ment. The 1913 legislature appropriated $40,000.00 for a new build - ing and this will be built some time during the present year. We will then be able to accommodate 100 or more patients. The present hospital building is usually kept full, we having had as high as thirty-four patients in it at one time during the past winter. Many more cases make application than can be accom - modated, and we try to pick out and accept only those who have some chance to recover. This is very difficult, as the doctors who make out the application papers are prone to describe the case as in better shape than it really is. One case described as incipient was accepted and arrived at the hospital on a stretcher in the last stages and only lived three weeks. Another case that was described as incipient, died before he could be gotten here. Many cases come braced up on morphine and liquor to make them more comfortable and of course only live a short time. Two such cases were received in April and each died in just sixteen days. Every case that has been sent to us since I took charge, September 1, 1913, that was not too far past the second stage, </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Nebraska State Board of Health 43 gets better, and the condition would eventually be arrested if they would stay, but as soon as they are feeling natural again they think they are able to work. Most of them will not take advice and so leave. I have picked a few of these at random to site to you. Admitted October 7, 1913. Case 1. — Female, age 21 ; admitted October 7. 1913 ; occupa - tion, telephone operator; illness dates back one year when cough and expectoration began fever for several months with night sweats continually, weight 102 pounds, apices of both lungs affected. Marked second stage case. This girl commenced to pick up the second week here and in one month weighed 118 pounds, at end of second month 125 pounds, end of third month 130 pounds. This weight is several pounds more than she had ever weighed and since then her weight has remained about sta - tionary. Her general condition and the condition of the lungs have both improved as the weight, until now very little, if any activity can be detected in the lungs. Cough and expectoration have practically stopped. Occasionally there is a little sputum raised in the morning. When this is the case, tubercle bacilli are still present, however, after seven months residence in the hospi - tal. This case is one of the very few that we have been able to keep after regaining her normal weight. Most of them pay no attention to advice and leave as soon as they regain their weight and feel normal. Case 2.— Male Greek, age 24, admitted September 13, 1913, barber. History gives onset as June, 1913. Had one hemorrhage August, 1913. Normal weight 135 pounds, when admitted weighed 115 pounds. Temperature in p. m. 99 4/5, pulse 110, respiration 24 to 32. Entire left lung dull with broncho-vesicular breathing and rales either dry or moist over entire lung. Few crepitant rales at base of right lung. This man commenced to pick up after three weeks and by the last of December he weighed 135 pounds. On January 11, 1914, he left with the condition in every way improved. Temperature had been nor - mal for some time. Pulse from 84 to 100, respiration 20 to 24. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Fourth Annual Bulletin Tubercle bacilli still abundant when it was possible to obtain a specimen, cough and expectoration having very nearly stopped. He considered himself well however and returned to Omaha to resume his vocation as barber. Case 3. — Male, Austrian, age 42, entered hospital November 26, 1913. Packing house laborer. History gives cough and ex - pectoration as of one month's duration. Temperature 99, pulse 92 to 108, respiration 32 to 36. Weight 142 pounds, normal weight 165 pounds. Night sweats for three weeks. Both lungs involved with some dullness and moist rales. He grew rapidly worse after entering hospital and in a week was unable to leave his bed. Feet commenced to swell and the oedema extended rapidly until the entire lower limbs and external genitals were involved. Condition became so bad that his demise was daily expected. This continued for three months. He then com - menced to gradually get better, and by the last of March the oedema had all left and he was able to leave the bed. Pulse 70 to 80, respiration 20 to 22. The condition of his lungs had im - proved wonderfully during the enforced rest caused by the oedema. At this time his lungs are very near normal. Goes for days without coughing. When he does expectorate tubercle bacilli are still found. His strength is increasing daily. His weight which had reduced to 132 pounds is now 145 pounds and will soon be up to normal if he continues to improve as he is now doing. Admitted December 23, 1913, Case 4. — Female, American, age 35, single, admitted Decem - ber 23, 1913. Present illness dates from March, 1912. Had night sweats occasionally then. Normal weight 180 pounds, weighed 123 pounds when admitted. Temperature 99 2/5. Right lung, apex dull, moist rales, apical and infra-clavicular. Left lung, large cavity in upper part, bronchophony and pectoriloquy with gurgling rales posterior friction rub, entire left lung involved. At present she is gradually improving, weighs 1*5 pounds, cough not troublesome, no pain, and has every indication that the condi - tion will eventually be arrested. Before coming here she had </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Nebraska State Board of Health 45 been denied admission to sveral tubercular sanitoriums in Colo - rado and elsewhere because of her advanced state. We dispaired for three months of her ever getting well, but during the last six weeks there has been a wonderful change for the better in every way with a corresponding increase in weight. Case 5. — Male, age 54, Irish, admitted January 14, 1914, single. Weight 134 pounds, pulse 108, respiration 30, tempera - ture 100 4/5 in afternoon. Entire right lung involved. Few small rales in left. Present illness dates over a year back. Large tubercular ulcer on tongue which had been diagnosed as car - cinoma and been treated for eighteen months but steadily grew worse. He had been a heavy drinker. On April 7th he decided that he was well and went to Kearney to work at his trade as painter. The ulcer on tongue was then entirely healed over, weight 160 pounds, temperature normal, pulse 108, respiration 20 to 24. Felt good in every way. Slight cough in morning, which contained tubercle bacilli. He immediately went to drinking again as soon as he went to work and on April 23rd was back again, weight 153 pounds and cough much worse. After resting up a little he left again for Omaha on May 2, 1914. Case 6. — Male, American, age 45, entered hospital August 22, 1912, weight 161 pounds, temperature normal, pulse 106, respiration 30. Both upper lobes actively tubercular. A tuber - culosis of the ankle developed and on December 16, 1912, he was sent to the Orthopedic hospital at Lincoln. He was sent back to this institution November 18, 1913, the final plasters having just been removed from the foot, weight 200 pounds. On May 12th his weight was 235 pounds, tubercle bacilli still in sputum which is scanty. He is still on crutches but the ankle does not pain him now. This man has lived in state institutions now for twenty months, has gained 75 pounds in weight, and yet he is the worst kicker and fault finder in the institution. The kind and quality of the food does not please him. It is invariable the case that those who receive the most benefit and pay nothing for care what is costing the state over $2.00 a day are the discontented ones, while those who pay $15.00 a week </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Fourth Annual Bulletin are thoroughly satisfied and appreciate what is being done for them. If tliis institution is to accomplish the work for which it was intended, the physicians and laity of the state must awake to the fact that the progress of tuberculosis is inevitable unless radical measures are taken in the earlier stages, while there is yet enough normal lung tisue to sustain life. After the case has advanced so far that he is unable to work, is usually to late for it to recover. We have made several.... radical changes in the rules of the institution since taking charge, such as not being allowed to leave the grounds without permission, no tobacco, must be in bed by eight p. m., no mingling of the sexes, a limit on the drinking of coffee and tea to not more than one cup, etc., all of which has been quite hard to get the older cases to adjust themselves to. These rules were made as we found them necessary to try and conserve what little strength they have left to help them get well. We have substituted a cresol said to be eight times as strong for carbolic acid as a fertilizer of the dishes, clothing, floors, etc. Have put liquid soap containers in the bath rooms, and automatic drips as an antiseptic in all toilets. These all to safeguard the help against infection and the patients against re-infection. We have had canvas curtains put up on the sleeping porches all around, for use during stormy weather. We recently pur - chased thirty canvas backed reclining porch or hammock chairs for the patients' use during the rest hours of the day. These are the same as are used in practically all tuberculosis institutions and are called by the patients "Chasing Chairs." The former practice of feeding hogs the scraps from the patients tables has been abandoned, one hog having died from tuberculosis presumably contracted in this manner. If the people of the state can only be made to understand that tuberculosis is a curable disease if taken in the early stages and will send their cases to us while there is yet any hope, much </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Nebraska State Board of Health 47 lief can be conerved and much good accomplished by the hos - pital, but until this is done, the greatest good the state will de - rive from the institution will be in segregating the cases in it so that they will not be a menace to the public generally. As soon as we get our new building, we expect to accept all cases applying for admission, no matter what the stage, within our capacity. The curable cases then will be separated from the in - curable and the general depression caused by the last stage cases being seen constantly by the curable cases will be eliminated. There was more unrest and dissatisfaction during the month of April just passed than at any other time in my experience and it was caused by the general depression incident to four cases dying within a short time. Every case commenced to wonder whether he would not possibly be the next one. We have an ideal climate here for the treatment of the tuberculous, with an altitude of about 2,200 feet, which is the best for the average class of cases, being high enough for good invigorating air and not too high for those with weak hearts. Competent help is very hard to get as all fear to contract the disease, in spite of the fact that all possible precautions are taken to safeguard against infection. Treatment consists of ten hours sleep each night on the sleep - ing porches, with rest in the chasing chairs during several hours of the day, good nourihing diet of a general nature for those whose digestion is not impaired and a diet table for those re - quiring special diet. Plenty of milk and eggs are provided at meal times. I have discontinued the general practice of feeding between meals as I found it interfered with their appetites at meals and tended to impair digestion. The general results are much better with three good meals a day. Our diet compares very favorably with that of the highest priced sanitoriums of the west and I do not know how it could be made more nourishing, yet there is more or less kick from those who receive free treat - ment, and those who pay are well pleased in every way and really appreciate what is being done for them. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Fourth Annual Bulletin During last summer, Senator Lorimer's portege, Dr. Duket, was given the privilege of treating a few of the cases with his alleged "cure." While this seemed ot help the cases wonder - fully for a time, yet it was not permanent and no real cures were made by him within my knowledge. Practically all of our cases are too far advanced for tuber - culin so that its use has been abandoned in most cases. The only treatment we are using now is symptomatic, the cases being ex - amined after they have been here a few days and accustomed themselves to conditions and then put on whatever medicinal treatment, if any. that seems indicated. Records are kept of the pulse, respiration, temperature, ■weight, treatment, etc., the same as in a general hospital. All cases are examined every thirty to sixty days as seems indicated, by their general condition. I want to extend to the members of the Nebraska State Homeopathic Medical Society in particular, and to all of the mem - bers of the medical in general, a hearty welcome to visit us and inspect the institution at any time. NELLE G. C. DEFFENBAUGH, Medical Superintendent. Read before the Nebraska State Homeopathic Medical So - ciety. Lincoln. Nebraska, May, 1914. CHILDREN IN WAR TIME How Canada Takes Care of Soldier's Children Washington, June. — How Canada provides for the wives and children of her enlisted men is described in a report by Mr. S. Herbert Wolf of New York, prepared at the request of the Sec - retary of Labor and just published by the Children's bureau of the U. S. Department of Labor. In presenting the report, Miss Lathrop, Chief of the Chil - dren's Bureau, says: In the 50 years since the Civil War, legislation affecting the </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Nebraska State Board of Health 49 family and its economic status has .shown marked growth Mothers' pension and minimum-wage are recognized examples, and it is acknowledged that their result has not been to pauper - ize but distinctly to improve the power of the family to pro - tect itself. In view of this tendency it is to be expected that a system of compensation for soldiers and sailors can be developed whereby the Government will make possible for their children the home life and parental care which are the common need of every child. The report points out that in Canada two notable elements have been added to the Government provision for soldiers and their families: First, insurance on the lives of soldiers is car - ried by various municipalities, and second, the Dominion has undertaken as a part of its military system- the re-education, in a suitable occupation, of the disabled soldier so that he can assume again, in whole or in part, the care of his family. The Canadian compensation for the soldier and his family includes not only $33 of monthly pay for the private in active service but a separation allowance to his dependents of $20 a month from the Dominion Government and further assistance in special cases from the Canadian Patriotic Fund. For example, the wife of a private soldier with three chil - dren between the ages of 10 and 15 may receive either $15 or $20 from the assigned pay of her husband, $20 separation allow - ance, and $25 from the Canadian Patriotic Fund, or in all $60 or $65 a month. If her husband is killed, she will receive $40 a month for herself, and an additional $6 a month for each of her children until her boys are 16 years of age and her girls are 17 years of age. In addition, if she lives in Toronto or one of a number of other cities, she will receive life insurance. This will be paid to her in monthly installments unless she shows that she needs the entire amount at once to pay off a mortgage or to make a start in business. If her husband is disabled, she will receive a special mainte- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Fourth Annual Bulletin nance allowance while he is having medical treatment and learn - ing a new occupation, and when he is finally discharged, if his physical disability continues, a pension will be paid according to the extent of his disability and the number of his children under 16 or 17 years of age. Mr. "Wolf is an actuary of recognized authority and he has analyzed especially the municipal provision for life insurance by which certain Canadian cities have supplemented the pen - sions provided by the Dominion for dependents of deceased soldiers. In Toronto, the municipality has not only purchased $10,000,000 worth of insurance from private companies, but it is itself carrying more than $32,000,000 worth of insurance. A municipal insurance bureau has been organized and $2,000,000 worth of bonds have been issued of which the principal and interest are a charge upon the general taxpayer of the city. Every officer and enlisted man residing within the city limits of Toronto who volunteers for oversea service has from the date of his enlistment been protected by a life insurance policy of $1,000, the protection running from the time of his enlistment to his death or six months after his discharge or resignation. The report refers also to the fact that each of the European countries makes Government provision for the families of pri - vate soldiers and sailors. In Great Britain, France and Germany the amount of the Governmental separation allowance depends upon the size of the family which must be supported. U. S. Department of Labor. WHAT TO DO FOR INSECT BITES AND POISON OAK. Everybody going on country trips or to the woods this sum - mer should know what to do for insect bites, especially those who intend camping out. Besides, it's not a bad thing to know if you stay at home. The most common bites or stings are those of the bee, wasp, yellow jacket, spider, horsefly, yellow fly, red bug or chigger, flea, mosquito and bedbug. In case of a sting of any kind the first thing to do, of course, is to remove the sting. This can best be done with the point of a knife or needle but care should be taken not to break the skin for fear of infection. Then the next best thing, perhaps, is to appy ammonia water or soda water to the affected parts. In case of bites as well as of stings, when the sting is removed, as a rule a paste of common baking soda applied to the affected parts or these bathed in ammonia water is all that is necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Nebraska State Board of Health 51 Where the poisonous effect is severe, however, send for a doctor. In the meantime, the patient should lie down and keep quiet. An application of a fifty per cent solution of a saturate solu - tion of potassium permanganate which you get at the drug store is very efficient for insect poisons and for the poisons of plants, too, such as poison ivy ami sumach. In planning your trip or outing, include one or more of these remedies in the list of preparations. The best thing to do about poisoning from poison oak is to prevent it. Wear gloves on going where it is and keep hands from face and nose. If, however, you get the poisoning, wash it off as soon as possible with strong soap and water. If you are in the woods and soap is not available, use fine sand or mud and water and rub vigorouly in order to remove the oily-like sub - stance. If soap and water or strong soap suds do not check the irritation, use baking soda in water, or pnint the affected parts with a solution of potassium permanganate (1 to 2,000). For this treatment, it will be well to call in a doctor. TO KEEP WELL AND ENJOT SUMMER State Board of Health Offers Advice On Summer Health Habits. In order to spend a comfortable, healthful summer whether at home or at some resort, says the State Board of Health, one must look first to his diet, then to his bathing, and then to his sleep, exercise and recreation. A few general precautions are also included in the list. The diet should consist largely of raw and cooked fruits, well-cooked vegetables, milk and butter, but very little of meat, eggs and heavy foods. One should eat less in summer than in winter especially of heat-producing foods such as meats, eggs, and pastries. Besides producing heat they tend to constipation and mental sluggishness. Drink much water but not quantities of ice water. Above all avoid constipation. Take a bath every day. A cool sponge bath every morning on getting out of bed and a tub at night will do much toward keeping the body in good condition and will make for comfort as well. Sleep regularly eight hours. If at all practical, sleep out on a sleeping porch. Arrange to sleep in as much moving air as possible. Nothing enables one to withstand the heat of summer with ease as plenty of undisturbed sleep in the open air. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Fourth Annual Bulletin Exercise some every day. Open air games in the cool of the day are good for both the mind and \he body. Don't leave off walking because the weather is warm. Walk early in the morn - ing or late in the afternoon. Walking is always essential to health. Recreation is another form of mental and physical rest and is necessary to mental and physical health. Vacations, outings, camping parties — anything that will give diversion, that will break the monotony and grind — will be beneficial and health making. Other precautions making for personal comfort during the summer are. Don't talk hot weather, don't think heat; avoid as much as possible direct exposure to the sun ; wear light-weight clothing; go slow and do nothing in excess; don't dissipate, don't over-eat or indulge in alcoholics. But think of the joys of sum - mer and make up your mind to enjoy them freely. VACATION INCREASES TYPHOID CHANCES. State Board of Health Warns Against Going On Vacation With - out Being Vaccinated. The State Board of Health is again urging people not to go on their vacation until they have taken the vaccine treatment against typhoid fever. The Board urges this precaution on ac - count of the many dangers of taking typhoid that are likely to be met on vacation trips, camping parties or outings of any kind. It says that there are many more chances of getting the infec - tion when traveling and when eating and drinking at various places than at home, and that the best and about the only safe - guard against such liabilities is the immunity to the disease that is to be had from the vaccine treatment. The Board says further in its note of warning that often what is in the beginning a bright and joyous vacation is at the end one of sickness and sadness on account of this one un - heeded precaution. People don 't altogether ignore this important feature of their preparation for vaccination but they neglect it until finally for lack of time it is dismissed as out of the question. "Then, too," says the Board, "there are people who, if they are going to the mountains, make themselves think that there is little or no danger, and that their risk against it is only a minor one. And there are those who think if they go to the good hotels and are careful of where and what they eat and drink that they </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 Nebraska State Board of Health will not be likely to meet the infection. It is against the un - suspecting nature of typhoid and against the uncontrolable means of spreading the infection that make the vaccine treatment as a protection so valuable. EVERYBODY SHOULD TAKE A VACATION. Breakdowns and Sickness Often Prevented by Vacation Trips, Says the Board of Health. As to the importance of taking a vacation, the State Board of Health says: "Everybody that works either mentally or physically needs a vacation sometime during the year. Perhaps you think you can't afford a vacation this year, but the fact is, probably, that you can't afford not to take one. You can't afford not to rest your mind and body and get from outine work. Per - haps you have not thought what a breakdown, or spell of sickness would cost you. The old adage, 'a stitch in time saves nine,' is applicable to our health as to our clothes. "You may not be able to afford an expensive trip to the sea - shore or to the mountains, but you can afford a rest and a change of environments for at least a few days. ' ' A few important points not to be overlooked in taking your vacation are: Go where your health will not be in jeopardy. Stay at no place where there are flies or mosquitos. Know that wherever you go there are sanitary means for disposing of sewage. Know that the food served you is not fly-infected and that the milk is clean. Get vaccinated against typhoid fever before leav - ing home, thereby reducing your chances of contracting typhoid fever 90 or 100 per cent. "A few don'ts that should be borne in mind before leav - ing are: "Don't take too much baggage. "Don't take any cares or worries. "Don't exercise too strenuously at first. "Don't eat injudiciously. "Don't spend too much money. "Don't forget that rest is what you are there for and that a vacation that does not put new life into your body and joy into your heart is a failure." </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Fourth Annual Bulletin * To the Honorable State Board of Health — Keith Neville, Gov- ernor; Willis E. Reed, Attorney General; W. H. Clemmons, State Superintendent Public Instruction. Gentlemen : I have the honor to certify that on the 16th day of February, there is filed in this office charges against Dr. I. H. Phillips of Seneca, Nebraska and an application for notice to I. H. Phillips to appear before the secretaries to the State Board of Health and show cause why his license to practice medicine and surgery iu the State of Nebraska should not be revoked. Affidavits at - tached herewith marked exihibits "A," "B," "C," "D," "E." "F, " and "G" were in support of said complaint. I immediately notified Dr. Phillips to appear on February 20th at 8:00 o'clock P. M., at the Lincoln Hotel and show cause why his license should not be revoked, sending said notice, copy of which is attached, by registered letter. His receipt, therefore, is hereto attached. On February 20th, your secretaries met at Room 303, Lincoln Hotel, all present except Dr. Stark, called to order by Dr. C. T. Burchard. The case of Dr. Isaac H. Phillips was called for trial. Accused was present, represented by Attorney Frank M. Tyrrell. Notice of complaint read, also numerous affidavits tended to show that Dr. Phillips is a habitual drunkard. Prosecution filed peti - tion tending to show that his services were good and satisfac - tory. Defendant asked for a continuance and the Board granted a continuance until March 13th. On March 13th, the secretaries to the Nebraska State Board of Health met in the Garden room of the Lincoln Hotel at 8:35 P. 11., to take testimony in the matter of the revocation of the license of Isaac H. Phillips to practice medicine and surgery in the State of Nebraska. Called to order by Dr. C. T. Burchard. Present. Drs. Burchard, Stark and Carr, absent, Dr. H. B. Cum - mins. Prosecution was present and represented by W. T. Thomp - son. The accused was present, represented by his attorney, Frank M. Tyrrell. Dexter T. Barrett, deputy attorney general, was present for, attorney for the Board by special request. Secretary Carr read complaint signed by Geo. McCawley in his amended petition just filed. Miss Hedge acted as court reporter. Sixteen witnesses were sworn for the prosecution and testified in the following order: 1. Wm. Westlake 5. Thomas McCawley 6. Orson Leggett 2. L. W. Westbrook 3. Dr. S. E. Overmass 7. Peter Anderson 8. A. F. Franks 4. Walter Hardv </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Nebraska State Board of Health 55 At this juncture Dr. Cummins appeared and sit as a member of the Board. 9. J. Oliver 15. Frank Thompson 14. R. E. Jones 10. Dr. E. T. Lay 11. David Lay 12. Edd Larson 13. Dr. J. D. Case Adjournment was taken until 8:30 A. M. 8:30 A. M., Lincoln Hotel Garden Room, March 14, 1917. Board called to order by Dr. C. T. Burchard. All members present, Drs. Burchard, Cummins, Stark and Carr. Counsel W. T. Thompson for the prosecution and Frank M. Tyrrell for the de - fense. Dexter T. Barrett, deputy attorney general and legal ad - visor to the Board by special request could not be present. The prosecution called their last witness, George McCawley, number sixteen, and after submitting numerous affidavits, rested their case. The defense swore seven witnesses who tetified in the fol- lowing order: 17. John W. Carney 21. H. G. Mclntyre 22. Judge John Evens 23. Dr. I. H. Phillips 18. J. M. Hanna 19. J. M. Stevenson 20. James Clary After which the defense filed several affidavits. By mutual consent the Board overruled all affidavits and permitted each side to file depositions and continue the hearing to April 10th, at which time the depositions would be reviewed and made a part of the record — the arguments of the attorneys heard and findings made. Board took a recess to Room 503. The secretaries to the Nebraska State Board of Health met at the Lincoln Hotel, Garden room, on April 10, 1917. Present. Drs. Burchard, Stark, Cummins and Carr. Case of Dr. Phillips called. Defendant not present but represented by his attorney, Frank M. Tyrrell. Prosecution present, represented by W. T. Thompson. Attorney Tyrrell filed a written motion, which is hereto attached, for a continuance stating that his client had already left the state and gone to Wyoming to practice medicine and would not in his judgment return to the state or to the juris - diction of the Board. It was stated by the prosecution that in their judgment, based upon the best fact that they had, Dr. Phil - lips was visiting at Kearney at this time. The Board overruled the motion and denied the continuance. Neither the prosecu- </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Fourth Annual Bulletin tion nor the defense filed any depositions, but counsel for the prosecution filed citations for the convenience of the Board which are hereto attached. Time was given for attorneys to make argu - ments and only short arguments were made. All arguments ended and the case closed. Board adjourned to Room 503 for executive session. Moved by Dr. Stark that license of Isaac H. Phillips be revoked, seconded by Dr. Carr. Vote was then taken — affirma - tive, Drs. Burchard, Cummins, Stark and Carr; negative, none. The president, Dr. Burchard, announced the motion carried by unanimous vote and the secretaries instructed to certify same to the State Board of Health proper. I do herewith certify that the above and foregoing is a true and correct copy of minutes and record in the trial of Dr. Isaac H. Phillips. Given under my hand and seal of the State Board of Health, this twentieth (20th) day of July, 1917. (SEAL.) E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Secy. State Board of Health met in office of governor. Present, Governor Keith Neville, Attorney General Willis E. Reed, Deputy State Superintendent of Public Instruction John A. Woodward. Transcript of case of Dr. Isaac H. Phillips was presented by Dr. E. Arthur Carr, secretary of the board of secretaries to the State Board of Health. After reviewing the testimony, it was moved by Willis E. Reed, that the action of the board of secretaries be ap - proved, revoking the certificate of Dr. Isaac H. Phillips of Seneca, Nebraska, No. 3872, granted August 21, 1905, and the same is hereby revoked. ROLL CALL : Ayes — Neville, Reed and Woodard. Nayes — None. Secretary was instructed to officially notify Dr. Phillips. GET RID OF FLIES. The best fly trap in the world is the simplest and can be made by any one. It is recommended in the public health report issued by the government and written by Earle B. Phelps and Albert P. Stevenson. It is made as follows: Take three teaspoonfuls of either the forty per cent solution of formaldehyde, that can be bought in any drug store, which - ever you prefer, and add it to a pint of water. Nearly fill a glass tumbler with this solution; place over the tumbler a piece of blotting paper cut in circular form and rather larger in diameter </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Nebraaka State Board of Health 57 than the tumbler and over this invert a saucer. Invert the whole device so that the tumbler is standing upside down on the blotting paper in the saucer. Insert the end of a toothpick under the edge of the tumbler so as to admit a little air to it and permit the solu - tion to soak the blotting paper. A little sugar sprinkled on the blotting paper around the tumbler will add to its attractiveness for the flies. The formalde - hyde and the salicylate are the best poisons for flies and are per - fectly safe. The former has an unpleasant taste that would pre - vent children from tasting it. while any quantity of the salicylate that a child would be likely to eat would do it no harm. BETTER SANITATION NEEDED IN RURAL SCHOOLS In the interests of efficiency and health there is increasing necessity for the application of scientific medical and sanitary knowledge to the administration of the public schools, in the opinion of the Public Health Service. In general, the faults observed in rural schools, the annual report of the Service declares, are due to a lack of skilled advice, especially in regard to the location, construction and equipment of school buildings and disregard of sanitary principals govern - ing water supplies, the disposal of sewage, ventilation, tempera - ture, illumination, and the arrangement of school desks and black - boards. During the past fiscal year surveys have been made in rural districts of several states and many thousand school chil - dren have been examined. These examinations have included thorough testing of the eyes by competent oculists, tests of mental capacity, and the effect of sanitary environment on school prog - ress, as well as inspections for the customary physical defect. The conclusion is reached that there is great need for im - provement in rural schools and that communities themselves will benefit if conditions are bettered, the schools serving as object lessons for surrounding sections. Conditions in country districts have been found below those in the cities and it is apparent that organized health work has largely been confined to the latter. Considered from a sanitary standpoint alone the Public Health Service is in favor of the consolidation of rural schools, since it must eventually result in the providing of better buildings and the organization of systems of efficient sanitary inspections. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Fourth Annual Bulletin LOSS FROM TUBERCULOSIS GREATER THAN WAR BOND ISSUE. Tuberculosis Considered Allies' Wont Enemy. Men and Women Necessary to Win War. That the loss from tuberculosis in the United States is more than the recent war bond issue which Germany declared this country was unable to raise has recently been computed from the 1913 census figures for tuberculosis by the United States Public Health Service. According to their figures the loss from tubercu - losis alone annually amounts to about $2,272,488,988.00. The num - ber of cases of tuberculosis in this country in 1913 were 600,000, the number of deaths, 142,970, and the average age at death was 35. The present value of lives lost by tuberculosis was computed to be $414,613,000.00; the potential value, 372,512,000; loss of wages prior to death, 24,362,088 ; cost of medical and nursing at - tention, 38,601,900; loss of wages of those sick but who did not die, $170,400,000.00; cost of their nursing and medical attention, $162,000,000.00 ; loss of production from those who were sick but did not die, $90,000,000.00 ; total loss from tuberculosis $2,272,488, - 988.00. That each state is bearing her proportional part of this tre - mendous waste brings home, particularly at this time, the injunc - tion that the first duty of the state is to conserve the lives of its men and women, to check such wholesale waste of manhood and womanhood at the prime of life. It has been said that men and women, and not things, will win the war; it has also been said that tuberculosis is the allies' greatest enemy. Fighting tubercu - losis at the home base becomes one of the most immediate needs not only to prepare our country for war but to maintain her life during and after the war. SUMMER HYGIENE HINTS "What we eat, what we drink, what we wear make us what we are, especially in hot weather. Probably, the first and fundamental rule for healthful living in summer is to keep clean, inside and out. A bath every day is just about as essential as breakfast or any other meal. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Nebraska State Board of Health 59 The average person should drink more water in the summer than in the colder months of the year, to supplement nature's efforts to wash the body through the pores. Drink cool, but not ice, water. The greatest danger from ice water is its excessive use. To persons who are overheated or who work in high tem - peratures, ice water may be dangerous. It may produce conges - tion, better known as cramps of the stomach. Be careful in eating. Don't gormandize. Too much is worse than none at all, especially in summer. Eat fruit, and vegetables. Remember that a meat diet is heating. It is like fuel under a boiler that keeps up steam for the engine. In warm weather wear light weight and light colored cloth - ing. Discard heavy dark garments. Don't hurry, start a little sooner. Be moderate in everything. All kinds of excesses should be avoided in summer. It goes without saying that over-indulgence in alcoholic drinks should be shunned, summer and winter. This is not advised alone from the temperance viewpoint, but as well from that of the highest physical welfare. AMERICA WOULD AVOID MISTAKE OF FRANCE. Would Safeguard Her Troops from Tuberculosis — Warns Physi - cians to Detect Early Cases. That America shall avoid some of the mistakes of other warring countries, particularly that of France of failing to safe - guard her troops from the ravages of tuberculosis, an effort ia being made on the part of anti-tuberculosis organizations to im - press upon the physicians of the country their responsibility in the matter of making prompt and searching diagnoses of not only the boys who will go to the front but of every case under their observation. Physicians examining recruits are especially warned against letting by the incipient or moderately advanced case, for the reason that such cases under the rigors of army life, particu - larly the life in the trenches, are those that develop rapidly and become a menace to all in the ranks. France today has 150,000 men lying in with tuberculosis. Trench life is not the only factor responsible for this condition. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Fourth Annual Bulletin In the first place, France did not have time to pick her troops; she sent the tuberculosis poilu along with the hale and hearty poilu, with the result that the tuberculosis soldier not only came down with a more developed case of the disease, but he infected the strong and well soldiers by his side who also became tubercu - losis victims. Again, France never saw in time of peace that it was necessary, or that it would pay, to protect her people from tuberculosis. She conducted no educational campaigns against the spread of the disease and built no hospitals for its treatment and cure. Consequently, the war has not only placed a heavy burden of diseased soldiers upon France, but she has no hospitals or means for their especial treatment. It has been pointed out in not a few ways whereby the United States might avoid the mistake made by France. In addi - tion to educational campaigns conducted by state and counties, it has been advised that every county or groups of counties erect hospitals or sanatoria sufficient to take care of every one of her soldiers who might return with the disease. Sanatoria are the great need and the county sanatorium is considered the first and probably the most important unit. — North Carolina State Board of Health. BABIES DIE IN POOR HOMES. Fathers Found to Be More Responsible for High Baby Death Rate Than Mothers. It has always been known that the mother was more or less responsible for the baby's welfare and health but not until re - cently has it come to light that the father also, probably more than the mother, is a factor determining the chances of his baby's life. Particularly is this so when a father does not make as much as $650.00 a year. According to a recent study of infant mortality by the Children's Bureau at Washington D. C, it was found that the low wages of fathers and the employment of mothers away from home were the greatest causes of high baby death rates. The study was based primarily on interviews with the babies' mothers. Of all the babies studied, one in six — 165 per 1,000 — had died during the first year of life. Nearly half of the 1,643 babies had fathers whose earnings </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Nebraska State Board of Health 61 were less than $650.00 a year, and more than one-eighth of the babies had fathers earning less than $450.00 a year. Only one in sixteen (6.4%) had fathers earning as much as $1,250.00. The death rate among the babies in the poorest families was more than four times as high as among those in the highest wage group. Low earnings on the part of the father appear to be the most potent reason for the mother's going to work. Where the fathers earned less than $450.00 a year almost three-fourths of the mothers were employed during some part of the year after the baby's birth. As the fathers' earnings rise the proportion of working mothers falls until in the group where fathers earned $1,050.00 or over, less than one-tenth of the mothers worked. The mothers of 267 babies went out to work during the first year of the baby's life and these babies had a death rate consid - erably higher than those whose mothers worked at home, or were not gainfully employed. The rate is especially high — 277.3 per cent 1,000 — among the 119 babies whose mothers went out to work before they were four months old. In each economic group the babies who were artificially fed had fewer chances of survival than the babies whose mothers nursed them. But the economic status of the family modifies the influence of feeding, and the difference in the death rates for breast-fed babies and artificially-fed babies is least striking in the highest income group. — North Carolina State Board of Health. WHEN ACCIDENTS HAPPEN What The First Aider Should Do. As accidents will happen, everybody should know what to do in case of an accident, particularly an accident to the body. Oftentimes a few minutes delay or ill directed aid may mean serious consequences, probably death, whereas a few simple first aid remedies will soon bring relief and lead to recovery. Fainting spells or light states of unconsciousness are fre - quently encountered, and are brought about by lack of a sufficient blood supply for the brain. When a person faints he should be laid flat on his back with his feet elevated. Never give whiskey or any other form of alcohol for fainting spells. It has long since been found to be a nerve, brain and heart depressant instead of a stimulant. Its use is quite harmful in depressed conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Fourth Annual Bulletin A few whiffs of aromatic ammonia, or a half-teaspoonful in a wine glass of cold water, is a good remedy, but to have the head low, the feet high, the clothing loosened and plenty of fresh air are the most important things. The most important thing to remember about wounds is to keep them clean. It is better to never try to treat wounds before the physician's arrival unless you are quite sure your dressings are surgically clean, free from bacterial infection. Never wash a wound with water unless it has been boiled. Make it bleed instead by milking it. Slight cuts may be bathed with peroxide of hydrogen, but never lacerate wounds, especially if dirt has gotten into the wounds. They should be cleansed as soon as possible with gasoline or turpentine and then painted with iodine. If earth has been forced into the wounds they should be made to bleed freely and the services of a physician secured for advice against tetanus or lock jaw. • The first thing to do for a burn is to keep the air from it. This can be done by keeping it submerged in water, or by cover - ing it with a paste of soda or flour, or by applying vaseline or some other ointment. Deep burns should be treated like wounds, care being taken not to infect the burn on attempting to dress it. Sunburn is also treated like slight wounds. ♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Nebraska State Board of Health 63 DO YOU KNOW THAT Keeping healthy is part of doin&amp; "your bit" Universal public health service is the duty of the nation Much valuable food material is diverted in the manufacture of alcoholic beverages The only &amp;ood fly is the dead one Good health is the foundation of personal usefulness, either in peace or in war ? o </seg>
            </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>