<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  CHANGES IN THE COMPOSITION OF THE LOESS SOILS OF NEBRASKA CAUSED BY CULTIVATION.</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
        
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. but i^i^ett list OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXII, Article I. CHANGES IN THE COMPOSITION OF THE LOESS SOILS OF NEBRASKA CAUSED BY CULTIVATION. By F. J. ALWAY. Distributed December 15, 1909. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD IfORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln rORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley NORABLE FREDERICK H. ABBOTT, Aurora fORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City IORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete rORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin tHONORABLE HARVEY E. NEWBRANCH, Omaha THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director J. S. DALES M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF I Lead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany . ALWAY, Ph. D. , Agricultural Chemistry I. Smith, B. Sc. , Animal Husbandry . Petkrs, D. V. M., Animal Patlioiogij u Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry rBENCE Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology r. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy nk J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry Erwin H. B arbour, Ph. D., Geology E. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering . Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering G. A. Loveland, B. Sc, LL. B., Meteorology C. W. PugSlev. B. Sc, Soil Agronomy W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North P J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Associate in Animal Pathology PS Venus W. Pool, A. M., Axsistant in Agricultural Botany 3. Trumbull, A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry I. Barker, A. B , Assistant in Agronomy (Soils) L Kiesselbach, B. Sc, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy 3. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology K'. Howard, B. Sc. in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture W. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant m Soils and t'rops, North Platte in Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Crops and Horticulture, North Platte 7. Perin, Farm Superintendent J Miss Louise M. Allen, A. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing • Resigned July 8, 1909. t Appointed by the Governor on the resignation of Regent Abbott I Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. &lt;t». i.i i or th&lt; ■■ mm i) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CHANGES IN THE COMPOSITION OF THE LOESS SOILS OF NEBRASKA CAUSED BY CULTIVATION. INTRODUCTION. I The recently aroused interest in the conservation of natural urces has caused many owners of Nebraska lands, as well as rs whose business is directly dependent upon the continued cultural prosperity of the state, to ask : ' ' To what extent has fertility of the soil of Nebraska been depleted and what will be result of the continuance of the present methods of farming T" i as a preliminary answer to this question that the present bul - 1 is published. The analyses reported indicate wherein the f changes in composition have taken place during the past ty to fifty years of cultivation and also wherein the most rapid lges of the future are to be expected. The chemical changes are by no means thf only important ones that take place when a rich virgin soil is plowed and kept con - tinuously under cultivation. The physical and biological changes may be much more important. However, when the chemical changes are so marked as to be readily detected by analysis a mere chemical study may serve to indicate precautions necessary in order to main - tain the productive capacity of the fields. tin the present bulletin it is assumed that the composition of soil of the remaining prairie fields, whether used as pastures as hay land, is practically the same as was that of the adjacent tivated fields when they were first plowed. tAs generally used, the term soil includes only the dark, sur - ; portion of the fine material covering the earth's surface, the [erlying lighter colored portion being spoken of as subsoil. In widest sense, however, the term includes the subsoil as well as BUL. Ill, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XXII, ART. I. H\ F. J. Al.WAY. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 (darker, surface material and in the present bulletin it is used this wide sense. Wherever the terms upland and lowland are d in this publication the latter refers to all lands subjected to ■iodical or occasional inundations, while the former includes all er lands, whether level plain or steep hillside. I The only kinds of plant food which are often deficient in soils nitrogen, phosphoric acid, and potash. In the case of lime, ile the amount required as plant food is nearly always present, is a matter of the highest importance whether this constituent abundant or not. Soils rich in nitrogen, potash, and phosphoric d are to be considered as fertile when their physical conditions favorable. When one of these three constituents is low the e becomes different, productiveness being influenced by the pro - ■tion of other constituents, and especially by that of lime. "In leral, lower percentages of potash, phosphoric acid, and nitrogen adequate when a large proportion of lime carbonate is pres- IThe total organic matter of the soil, which includes all the ma - il of vegetable or animal origin that disappears from the soil n the latter is burned, may be roughly divided into two parts, the humified portion (humus) and the unhumified portion, term humus is used in a broad sense by some chemists to mean same as the organic matter of the soil. By others it is used to gnate only the portion of the' organic matter which has beeD oged into the black or dark brown substances (vegetable mold) ch give the characteristic color to the surface soil and which soluble in ammonia. While it is not the intention of the writer to uss the proper use of the term, it should be pointed out that 'humus" is used to designate the total organic matter of the we most employ some other term to designate the portion sol - ; in ammonia. METHODS OF SAMPLING. I The samples to a depth of six inches were secured by means a brass tube 1% inches in diameter and provided with a wide 1 Hilgard, Soils, p. 354. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">brass collar 6 inches from the end. The tube was forced into the ground until the collar rested firmly on the surface. Also, for samples of the second six inches of soil the tube was used after re - moving the first six inches of soil by means of a spade. The sam - ples analyzed were composites of from five to thirty individual cores taken with the tube. To obtain inch sections for analysis, cores obtained as above were subdivided. For samples of soil from below the first foot two augers were used, the one of 1 3 4 inch and the other of 1 inch diameter. The larger auger was used to remove the first foot of soil, after which the smaller was employed to obtain the sample of the second foot. The large auger was next used to enlarge the hole to the bottom of the second foot. Then by means of the small auger the third foot sample was taken. This process was continued for the still lower portions of the soil. If a single auger had been used the samples from below the first foot would have been more or less affected by material from nearer the surface adhering to them. METHODS OF ANALYSIS. I The determinations of potash, phosphoric acid, and lime were de by the Hilgard methods for the acid digestion of soils. For osphoric acid the ignited soil was digested with strong nitric d for two days on the steam bath. For potash and lime the soil s digested with strong hydrochloric acid (1.115 sp. gr.) for five jrs on the steam bath. These methods extract the greater part the phosphoric acid and a large part of the potash. The portions t dissolved by the strong acids may be considered as not avail - e for plant use. tThe organic matter has been calculated from the amount of or - ic carbon as determined by combustion with copper oxide, using factor 1 .724 ; the carbonates were previously decomposed by itment with phosphoric acid. For humus the Grandeau meth - as modified by Hilgard was used . The nitrogen was deter - ed by the Kjeldahl method . POTASH, PHOSPHORIC ACID, AND LIME. L Tables I to VI show the distribution of potash, phosphoric acid, lime in virgin prairies both thruout the surface foot and thru </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 the first six feet of soil. The analyses indicate no regularity in the variation of any one of these constituents in the first twelve inches. It appears probable that if a very large number of such sets of inch sections were analyzed the averages for the different depths would be nearly equal. In the comparison of the foot sections with one another there is, in the case. of the upland fields, a marked indi - cation of higher percentages in the portion of the soil below the surface foot Accordingly, the effect of the washing or blowing away of the surface soil would not be to lower the percentage of any of these constituents in the surface six inches. The removal of crops from the fields without the application of barnyard manure or commercial fertilizers would lower the amounts of all three of the constituents mentioned, but, even if we assume that the plant roots derive their supply of these forms of plant food from only the surface foot of soil, the amounts re - moved will be so small that the losses will not be revealed by the methods of chemical analysis. Table VII shows the amounts in virgin prairie fields and in cultivated fields on the same or ad - jacent farms. In this table, only the surface six inches is con - sidered, as this would be the part to first show the loss of plant food. In some cases the higher percentages are shown by the prairies and in other cases by the cultivated fields. The averages are very close together. The differences are only such as might be found between different parts of the same field or between ad - jacent prairie fields. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Caused by Cultivation &gt; Table I. — Potash at different depths in surface foot of prairies. Antelope County Prairie B, upland Lancaster I Lancaster Countv inty . Prairie A, Prairie C, Average upland lowland Per cent Percent Pti cent Percent First inch .49 .4(t .88 63 Second inch .40 .56 .*1 .52 Third inch .44 .59 .67 .56 Fourth inch .«2 .65 .63 Fifth inch .45 «4 .56 .55 Sixth inch 41 .U .68 .57 Seventh inch .... H4 .6(1 .62 Eighth inch .53 69 .57 .59 Ninth inch .49 .69 .62 .60 Tenth inch .50 .66 .71 .62 Eleventh inch .50 .65 63 .59 Twelfth inch | .48 .69 .68 .61 Table II. — Potasfi at different depths in the first, twenty feet of »oil. Antelope County Lancaster County Prairie 'Prairie Field Pra rie Prairie Prairie Com- B, low- B, posite land upland upland A, B, C, A, upland upland upland upland Per cent I Per cent Per cent Per cent Percent Percent Percent .75 .77 .71 .79 .73 .78 .Hit .61 1.(4 .'.4 .75 .87 .97 First six inches . . . .54 .52 Second six inches .65 .62 60 117 First foot 59 .57 t« Second foot 47 .58 . n Third foot .63 91 .i7l 1.01 Fourth foot 48 .63 .73 ... .96 Fifth foot 47 .61 .81 .... .95 Sixth foot 50 .62 .86 .... .96 Seventh to ninth foot .... 1.11 Tenth to twelfth foot 1.07 Thirteenth to fifteenth foot 1.23 Sixteenth to eighteenth foot .'. .. 1.22 Nineteenth and twentieth feet ... 1.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ABLE ospl ric acid cu different ■ept '18 in 8ur . - - foot' of \ dairies. Antelope County B, upland Lancaster County A, upland Fir«t inch Second inch Third inch... Fourth inch Fifth inch Seventh inch Kigbth inch Ninth inch Tenth inch Eleventh inch Twelfth inch Per cent .07 .08 .08 .06 .05 .09 Per cent .09 .08 .09 .09 .09 11 .08 .07 .07 .08 .08 .09 .08 .06 .07 .05 .06 ABLE 'lospi \oric acid at different } *pL 'is in rat twenty feet of soil. Antelope County Lancaster Co unty i Prairie A, upland Prairie B. upland Field C, upland Prairie A, upland Prairie C, low- land Ss Percent .08 .08 .08 .11 .15 .15 .14 .14 Percent .08 .06 .07 .06 .07 .07 .OU .08 Percent Percent .09 .09 .09 .07 .10 .14 .14 .14 Percent .06 .07 .06 .Hi .10 .09 .09 .08 Percent First six inches Second six inches Second foot Fourth foot Seventh to ninth foot. . . . Tenth to twelfth foot . . . Thirteenth to fifteenth ft. Sixteenth to eighteenth ft. Nineteenth &amp; twentiethft. i .12 .14 .15 .15 .15 I .... </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table V. — Lime at different depths in surface foot of prairies. First inch |&gt;nd inch, rth inch . h inch . . . . ;nth inch , th inch . . . enth inch lfth inch. tLE VI. — Lime at different depths in the first twenty feet of soil. Antelope Lancaster County Countv 3 rairie"B, Prairie A, Prairie C, upland upland lowland Per cent :ii .50 .61 .«:» .41 .30 .40 34 .SB 30 .41 Per cent .40 .44) 51 .55 49 4U 45 .44 .4:5 Per etu .70 .95 .88 .73 .-r&gt; .7!t .80 .65 .72 Ante lope Co jnty Lancaster County i i i Prairie A, upland Prairie B, upland Field Prairie Prairie Com- &lt; . A, B, low- posite upland upland land j upland First six inches Second six inches Fourth foot Fifth foot Seventh to ninth foot ... Tenth to twelfth foot Thirteenth to fifteenth ft. Sixteenth toeighteenth ft. Nineteenth &amp; twentieth ft. Per cent AiS L46 .96 4.04 4.44 4.44 4.21 4.77 Percent .47 .35 .41 .66 .58 .84 .50 .50 Percent Percent Percent Percent .« .«■ 48 J| .74 .« 70 M 107 .83 1.20 1.66 .51 1.54 86 .70 1.51 .80 .91 1.07 3.04 2.64 2.88 2.90 .... ... .... .... I .... </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 rVII. — Potash, phosphoric acid, and lime in the surface six inches of soil of virgin prairies and adjacent long cultivated fields. Imogen, viz., the humus and the unhumified organic matter. The iparative readiness with which changes in these soil constituents induced by cultivation is due chiefly to the two following rea - 3. First, the proportion of these on both upland and ordinary land virgin soils rapidly decreases from the surface downward; jrdingly any removal of surface soil by wind or storm water ens the amount in the surface six inches. Second, the nitrogen from the cultivated fields includes not only that removed in the n of crops but also a large amount which escapes into the air idental to the decomposition of the organic matter of the soil; loss of nitrogen due to the latter is often many times as great hat due to the former. In regions of winter rains, serious losses No. of years in cultiva- tion Potash Pho»v aci ihoric id Lime County Culti- Prairie vated Prairie field CuUi- Cnlrt- vated Prairie vated Held fle ' d Antelope Antelope Aotelope. '. Antelope Antelope. Antelope Antelope Antelope Antelope . Antelope Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster A verage 90 90 Mi 22 22 22 90 30 H'i :io +o 4o 40 I'crreid Percent Percent .52 .46 .08 .52 .55 .08 .51 .50 .07 .."&gt;1 .41 .07 M .46 .07 .51 .59 .07 .44 .45 .08 .44 .43 .« .44 .41 .08 .59 .56 .08 .87 .77 .r6 .77 .92 .OB .77 .H9 .06 .67 .65 .07 Percent Percent Percent NITROGEN, TOTAI a ORGANIC MATTER, AND HUMUS. Altho the changes i: d the content of potash, phosphoric acid. and lime induced by thi tion are too slight in the irty or forty years of continuous cultiva- case of the rich loess soils of Nebraska tc malysis, a marked decline soon appears is s well as in that of the chief stores of soil 1 detected by chemical i content of nitrogen a </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 I nitrogen may occur thru seepage, but on account of the light iter precipitation it is improbable that much is thus lost from loess soils of Nebraska. I The decrease in nitrogen, total organic matter, and humus 1 the surface downward is shown by Tables VIII to XIII. In upland soils the decrease, in general, is marked, even in the sections of the first foot. In the lowland soils the decrease is regular and less rapid. In the upland soils the humus almost ppears below the second foot. As the humus is black or brown, as the surface soils owe their dark color to its presence, the r of the soil will, to some extent, indicate the amount of humus ent. The lowland soils, below the surface foot, show more hu - , nitrogen, and total organic matter than do the upland soils. As both that part of the soil nitrogen removed by the crop and that which passes into the air are derived chiefly from the surface six inches of soil, the loss will be most conspicuous in this portion. The effect upon the nitrogen content caused by the washing away or blowing away of two or three inches of surface soil will be very marked. In Table XIV there is shown the nitro - gen content of the surface soil that would remain after the removal of the original surface to different depths. I The amount of nitrogen that would be removed by thirty crops corn averaging 65 bushels per acre would amount to about half all that was originally present in the surface six inch n s of the ;rage soil or to more than one-fourth of all that was originally sent in the surface foot of soil. As plants derive the chief part their nitrogen from that contained in the surface soil, a compar - q of the nitrogen content of the first six inches of virgin prairies :h that of long cropped fields may be expected to show marked ferences, especially if either blowing or washing away of the •face has taken place. I Table XV shows the content of nitrogen, total organic matter, I humus of a large number of long cropped fields compared with t of adjoining prairies. Without exception there has been a </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 marked decline in the amount of nitrogen and of total organic matter in the surface six inches. The loss of humus has been large in the case of most of the fields, but in the case of two, one in Antelope and one in Gosper, it has been less than the experimental error. While both the nitro - gen and the organic carbon (from which the total organic matter is calculated) can be determined with great accuracy, the methods for the determination of humus which. are commonly used are un - satisfactory and comparatively inaccurate. For this reason the same regularity is not to be expected in the relative losses of humus as is shown in the case of the other two constituents. ABLE itrogen itfei 'ent (. left 'is in t ,e sur ace 'ooto pra Irie8. Adams County A, " upland Antelope County B, upland Lancaster County A, C, upland lowland F, upland Average First inch Second inch Third ioch Seventh inch Eighth inch Tenth inch Eleventh inch .... Percent .276 .226 .191 .178 .165 .159 .153 .145 • .149 .143 .141 .138 Per cent .296 .263 227 .206 .195 .192 .177 .169 155 .149 .133 .128 Per "ent Per cetit .346 .41« .315 .344 .279 .271 .262 .230 .247 .209 .234 .198 .215 .196 .201 .190 .189 .173 .181 .165 .176 .158 173 .153 Per cent .465 .312 .265 .234 .230 214 .197 .190 .184 .177 .165 .165 199 . loo </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Table IX. — Nitrogen at different depths in first six feet of prairie*. Lanc » 8ter County Nance o^e Countv A, up- B, low-E, low County Count v upland lan&lt;l 'and land upland upland Percent Percent Per cert Percent I ■■r cent Per ce,U Adams County upland Percent, tit 6 in.. . .199 ond6in. .142 it foot.. .170 ond foot .091 rd foot . .052 irth foot .041 h foot. . .035 thfoot.. .029 .052 .045 .0HI .080 .042 053 .058 .042 .074 .03H ... .049 .053 [ .042 .061 1 .027 .&lt;V43 Table X.— « Organic matter at different depths in surface foot of prairies. Antelope County Prairie Lancaster County Prairie Prairie Prairie Average a, c, r. K. upland lowland upland upland Mi .278 .335 .338 .242 2JH .161 .203 .595 .221 .210 .101 .201 .2-10 .2«.'&gt; .279 .2-2H 1 '.■- .098 .111 .190 .197 102 .055 .063 i .118 .128 .0S6 O.ni I it inch i ond inch rd inch irth inch h inch . th inch enth inch nth inch th inch th inch tenth inch &gt;lfth inch Per ce« 6 51 5.B2 4.21 4.1(&gt; 3.84 3.53 3.17 2.91 2.81 2.43 2 43 2.19 u er ceut 8.08 6.60 5 95 5.48 5.00 4.79 4.72 4.09 3.80 3 65 3.55 3 51 J Per cent 9.77 7.81 5.91 5.03 4.58 4.48 4 31 4.02 3.60 3 31 3.21 3.08 j Per out 11 51 6.79 5.65 4.*2 »44 3.95 :?.4« 3.15 3 10 2.81 2 65 2.^&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Table XL — Organic matter at different depths in first six feet Table XII. — Humus at different depths in surface foot of ■prairies. Antelope Nanee upland "P laDd Lancaster County A, B, upland lowland It six inches &gt;nd six inches &gt;nd foot rth foot Per cent Per cent 4 64 4 90 2 66. 2.85 3.65 3.88 1 64 1.46 .62 .53 63 41 .67 .29 .57 .25 Percent 5.98 3 89 4 93 1.48 .74 .38 .39 .36 Per cent 6.45 4.15 5.30 4.12 2.69 1.07 1.10 1.07 pra trie*. Antelope County B, upland Lancaster County Av- erage A, upland C, lowland F, upland Second inch Third inch Fourth inch Fifth inch Sixth inch Seventh inch Ninth inch Tenth inch Eleventh inch Per cent 2 12 2 16 2.04 1 68 1.66 1.64 1.68 1.64 1 34 1.28 1.48 1. 00 Per cent 4.20 3 6D 3.16 2.76 2.53 2.85 2.55 2 29 2.25 2.24 2 10 1.72 Percent 4.32 3.34 3 82 3.02 2.84 2 84 2.50 3.14 2 62 v 2.18 2.68 1 80 Per cent 3 94 2.96 2 52 2.18 2 38 2 28 2 20 2.00 1.96 1.45 1.39 1.41 Percent 3 64 3.01 2.88 2.41 2 35 2 40 2 23 2.27 2.04 1 79 1.91 1.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 r[.E XIH. — Humus at different depths in first six feet of soil of prairies. Antelope | Lancaster ( ounty County I B, upland i A, upland B, lowland Percent Percent Percent First six inches 1.88 3.18 Second six iu. hes 1.40 2 19 2.63 Firstfoot 1 64 3.15 Second foot. l.OO 1.00 S.M Third foot 41 .45 1 Tti Fifth foot F 2&lt;i .30 1 21 Sixth foot .15 .15 .m rLE XIV. — Nitrogen that icould be found in the surface six inches if the surface, soil were removed to different depths. ,i Antelope Lancaster County County, &lt;*«-*■ a, cT upland upla ' Dd upland lowland erage Depth of soil removed Per cent Per cent Per cent ■ Per cent Per cen t .199 .179 One inch Two inches .165 Three inches. Four inches. . Five ioehes . . Six inches . . . .158 .178 .225 .200 .190 .152 .148 .145 Fourth foot I .30 20 1.51 VIM. 4nnt &gt;il tl\ 1 ■&gt;! .2-s&gt; .m 24.-&gt; .205 .252 .242 219 .192 .240 .2)5 20.( .170 .211 .188 .1M .162 .199 .180 .17-2 .155 1H9 .172 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 oc ui 5 Shov^c m 5 5c 1 m - : ■ g s P "I s * 1 I I It I H ■« H £ f :- el n^g 1 I 6 -: r- c ■- &lt; \ c *-h : «J : ■iSi 8 SSSS8S 888 SSSSSS S^SS : — »O.| Bh ; 2SSSSS SSS £38383 £822 : _ 'S ; « -e^t-® — «c ce :e e»s ic a -&gt; m rj n 13 in ao ' J j» :,^"^irti-&lt; ei' t4 ipS — &gt;h • «Jl "i : - 1 : ' r •— • -^ — 1— 1 0 c — •"" — •— •" 'i5xi| ; j&gt; '•♦•♦•♦•••o •O'*-* «'«'«ri«e 1:01010 I "a n : : ■a I : : i? 8 :&lt;(S888 gS^SCS j55i3 : P!«c:^i« ?irt« oi &lt;ti m ei *i o«m« S «oc«k* m « x -»■ a st c ■* e cor-io^r-: O . gE^rt^irrf c: rt rt •.--♦m.-sc-'; — xi-^x — C o o o c o o 000 c 0 c o o c " o 0 0 e ft&lt; ' * -A I «Si; 8 er-2«iiN iN'*-* *r-eiefiia ioi«u5'C&gt;o "^S* « NNNNNN °i M — M — 1&lt;liM MNMNM — 'O. i. * • • • • 5 * ' * ■ ' * ' • ez&gt; o a v a&gt; &lt;v e a. 0/ " &gt;: « n o o» t a 000000 000 0*0000- ---_ 0 1 iihiiii s &lt; illll5lfl| lite 1 BS«t s ssssss ana ssssss sssc i 3 i s.s.isai s. is. 1 il ill Ills 5 3 a s||||| |s| § f I s § g ssssr *o c c 3 a c c c a c j; c .5 =s ob ce r I Illii^'il ill 111 s £sl: li ■; ;*-i|-™t-iSc §§s|- = - : -^-s I gi g £ „-- ii-X'rS Sri: = **«»Sn^SSc"i ft &gt;LoP« a «e « («— « &gt;&gt; « s«- ce « l " i'S'5^ — </seg>
            <seg id="p017">IT m . .... . »fi • i- : ; '. '. ' '. ?i : : : : : : : i § I : : : : : : : i S ! ! C t * it :::::. : | '. '. '. (I tri r: 3-- 3-. — o e^ e-i !•■; * x lit c &lt;o ■"♦• r~ o o e ; cs o o © o X I — a - p4 !~. n X — rl » ■?! ■ «3 r- i— i- 3C cc ■* m m pi *C f 1 t =s 5 i 2 s £ : : : : . : S • k a . **£ : : : : : S^IS^ : : . : . &gt; . &gt; . : : : : : :g : g : : , : ! ! ! !l ! b ' ' ••»::•:*:*: : :S : : : :B : 8 : : . P . . . . 3 _ 3 _ ■ s8«B«aiT-"P « £ at : s sssBig g.g E .- &gt;, 3 3 = = &gt;. &gt;&gt; 3 ►&gt;*ooeo°« °® o izzzzy g x. i&gt; it it i! it ■ • ■ SSSSS : : g ao en od en od . a 4 09 eg 99 . a a c c a x X a a a a a a 3 S - S a I 5 e I — a i i I </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 It would appear from the above data that the Nebraska loess soils are rich in potash, fairly well supplied with phosphoric acid, and comparatively rich in lime. The nitrogen content while high in the virgin soils has fallen greatly under cultivation. The only form of plant food that has as yet shown a diminution sufficient to be detected by chemical analysis is nitrogen. The only impor - tant soil constituents, whether used as plant food or not, that have declined appreciably are nitrogen, humus, and total organic matter. These three constituents in the soils in question are similar in distribution, rising and falling together. So far as we now know, then, the main problem in the maintenance of the supply of plant food in the soils of this area is the prevention of the further decline of these three constituents in the surface soil or, in case the loss is already very great, their gradual innivase. As the nitrogen is the most important of the three and serves as an index of the quantities of the other two, we may confine ourselves for the present to the consideration of it alone and state the problem thus : The problem of the maintenance of the fertility of the soil of the loess plains, in so far as the fertility depends upon the supply of plant food, is chiefly the problem of maintaining or increasing the nitrogen con - tent or nitrogen supply. What few fertilizer experiments have been conducted on the soils of this area indicate that there is no deficiency of potash, or even of phosphoric acid, at present. SUMMARY. El. In their virgin condition the loess soils of eastern Nebraska rich in potash, nitrogen, humus (vegetable mold), and un - ified organic matter. The supply of lime is good and that of phoric acid is fair to good. 2. Judged on the basis of their chemical composition these loess soils would be rated very fertile and likely to long maintain their productive capacity if kept in good physical condition and well supplied with nitrogen and organic matter. 13. The content of phosphoric acid, potash, and lime, being lower in the subsoil than in the surface soil, no lowering of the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 percentages of these three constituents is produced by the blowing away or washing away of the surface. 14. The content of nitrogen, humus, and unhumified organic ter decreases rapidly from the surface downward. According - rosion, either by wind or water, impoverishes the surface soil. 5. Chemical analyses do not show any difference between vir - gin prairies and long cultivated fields in the proportion of potash, phosphoric acid, and lime; they do show, however, a great loss of nitrogen, humus, and unhumified organic matter in the case of all fields long under cultivation. 16. The greatest losses of organic matter, nitrogen, and humus j been caused either by the washing or by the blowing away of surface soil. 7. The problem of maintaining the fertility of the loess soils of eastern Nebraska is, in so far as the chemical composition is concerned, essentially that of maintaining the supply of total or - ganic matter, which includes both humus and nitrogen. 8. To maintain the supply of organic matter it will be ne - cessary to prevent erosion by water and by wind in so far as possi - ble. Further, the burning of stalks and straw should be avoided and all barnyard manure should be returned to the land. Even if these precautions be observed there will be a steady decline in the cultivated fields unless legumes be grown or the produce of other fields be fed and the manure applied. By growing clover or alfalfa the nitrogen, humus, and unhumified organic matter may be increased at the same time that a profitable crop is obtained. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>