<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Determining the Sex of Day Old Chicks</title>
               <date value="1935-03">1935-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 51 March, 1935 Determining the Sex of Day Old Chicks H. E. ALDER Depar ent of Poultry Husbandry ■■■■■■' ''. . ' ' '."' ■ '-■".. ,';.'. •" ' .. ■: .'■.;'..■■.■ ■■':'..■. ■•■ :i' ■ • I. ■ ' ■ ■ 1 ■ '■■-■ ■ ■■',■■ « ■ . . . "■■ - ■ ■. THE NIVERS OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE O GRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Determining the Sex of Day Old Chicks H. E. ALDER Department of Poultry Husbandry More than 2,000 years ago people were interested m determining the sex of the embryo m hatching eggs and the sex of day-old chicks. Aristotle thought that long eggs produced males and short eggs produced females. Pliny, several centuries later, held that long eggs produced females and short eggs produced males. Other methods, such as specific gravity and peculiarities of markings found on the large end of the eggs, have been presented, and claims made for them. As yet, however, no method of determining the sex of a fertile egg has been successful. Ancient writings have recorded methods used m the past for determin - ing the sex of day-old chicks. Sometimes the chick was held by the feet and the head allowed to hang down. If it turned its head up sharply, it was regarded as a female. Those that did not so behave were regarded as males. Some claimed to.be able to determine the sex by noting how much struggling a chick did when suspended by the feet. Still others held that when suspended by the feet the males were not noisy, while the females did a good deal of complaining. No method of determining the sex of day-old chicks (except of course m sex-linked chicks) was of the slightest value until the Japanese method was discovered and developed. About 1925 Japanes; scientists discovered the presence of a rudimentary copulatory organ located on the ventral rim of the cloaca which was present m all day-old males and only a few day-old females. Research work done m the University of California has shown that this rudimentary organ (hereafter called the phallic knob) first appears m a six-day embryo, and is then found m both sexes. The phallic knob continues to enlarge m both sexes until about the twelfth day of incubation. At this time it commences to diminisi m the females, but continues to develop m the males. Among day-old chicks from five to ten per cent of the females still have a small phallic kn )b, while all males have a phallic knob, but m some it is quite small. The next problem, then, was to expose it on the day-old chick without injuring the bird. DESCRIPTION OF THE PHALLIC KNOB A pinhead cut off a pin and laid down would give a fairly good pic - ture of the phallic knob m a day-old chick. The general appearance is much the same as that of a small pimple. Frequently it will appear more shiny than the surrounding parts. It will range m diameter from about one-fourth to one millimeter (1/60 to 1/25 of an inch). It is normally nearly round, but occasionally found to be somewhat longer than wide, the long way always extending towards the sides of the cloaca rather than m the direction of the long axis of the chick. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 51 LOCATION O? THE PHALLIC KNOB Figure 1 shows the phallic kAob of a six-weeks-old cockerel. This is a natural-sized photograph of a pasted chicken taken in about the normal body position, with the dorsal side up. The cloacal rim has been severed at the two s.des so that the lcwer rim of the cloaca could be turned ■wvHBU^^vl flW^P^iP^B '■^\['*v ■!■■?* '^"HflHaflfaB muKF W Fig. _1.— The phallic knob in a six-weUs- Fig. 2.— Cloacal parts of a six-wceks-old old cockerel. The arrow numbered 2 pullet indicates the phallic knob. | slightly inside out, thereby exposing the phallic knob. The arrows num - bered 1 and 3 indicate the heads of pins used to fasten the cloacal parts back while the photograph was Being taken. By observing Figure 1 and imagining the process of remov ng the pins and fitting the cut edges ot the cloaca back, and turning tfe parts in as they would normally be in a bird, one can see that the pMallic knob is on the lower rim of the cloacal opening, and situated badW under the rim and half way between the two lateral parts. The arn.w indicates the exact location of the phallic knob. Figure 2 shows the cloacal pa ts of a six-weeks-old pullet. The arrow numbered 2 points to the spot on &gt;vhich the phallic knob would be located in a cockerel, but note that the n n of the cloaca is perfectly smooth </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Determining the Sex of Day Old Chicks Fig. 3. — Cloacal parts o£ a day-old male Fie. •?. — Cloacal parts of a day-old female, chick. Arrow number 2 indicates the Arrow number 2 indicates place where phallic knob. phallic knob would be in a male chick. Figure 3 is a photograph of a posted day-old male chick, showing the phallic knob and surrounding structures. The chick is resting dorsal side up. The phallic knob may be seen at the end of the arrow numbered 2. It is very slightly enlarged. Compare this with Figure 4, which is a similar photograph of a day-old female. The arrow points to where the knob would appear in a male. AGE ,FOR SEXING It is easier to sex a 12-hour-old chick than one that is 24 or 48 hours old. It is not, however, difficult to sex chicks at any age adding the first 5 or 6 days. After they are about three weeks old, they become more difficult to sex, the difficulty in- creasing until one finds it quite I""* ll^fc^^^. hard to uncover the phallic M^ knob in a four- or five-months 9 j .. , jjk cockerel. Chicks should be W 'f'l ■&gt;; ;y.-" " , sexed very soon after being jjji ' •''. ., /m^^Bm hatched or left until they arc ! . ~ wF^R^&gt; four or five days old, unless the H| . 0y?^fl '' 1 operator is an expert. Jt -. F^?V HOW TO HOLD THE CHICK ! ; | There are a number of satis- • / \ factory ways of holding the gg t.'i| Bpr V I chick. (All of the following -*^^^^ :-y^^^Ke. descriptions will be for right- Flc 5._ T he general relation of the finger handed folks; left-handed per- and two thumbs to the cloacal parts. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agriculture l Experiment Station Circular 51 sons will have to reverse them. &gt; One may hold the chick in the left hand with ventral surface to the pain, head down, and feet extending between the index and middle fingers ;is shown in Figure 6, or one may hold the chick in the left hand, dorsal surface to the palm of the hand, head down, and feet dangling free as in Fi: jure 7, or he may hold them as in Figure 8, which is the same as Figure 7,1 except that the legs are inside the hand instead of hanging freely. The operator must discover a method that seems most natural to him and that induces the least amount of struggle and resistance on the part of the click. :'■&gt;■ Fics. 6, 7. 8 (left to rght). — Methods of holding the chick. EXPOSURE OF THE PHALLIC KNOB If one is holding the chicla as shown in Figure 6, he places the left thumb near the ventral side ol the cloaca to assist the thumb and index finger of the right hand, which are placed on either side of the cloaca and a little toward the dorsal aspect. Under no conditions should any - thing more than gentle pressuie be exerted. If the chick is held as indi:ated in Figures 7 or 8, the left thumb is placed near the dorsal part of t le. cloaca with the thumb and index fingers of the right on either side, anc a little toward the ventral aspect. It will be necessary to indulge in considerable practice before the fingers and thumbs become able to coordinate in such a way as to roll back the lower rim and expose the phallic knob. If one practices on older chicks until his technique has developed, it will then be less difficult to learn to sex the younger birds. DOES EXPOSING THE P IALLIC KNOB INJURE THE CHICKS? A day-old chick has very tender skin and membranes. If one is not reasonably careful, he will in the process of sexing break some of the internal membranes. This in most cases will cause the chick to die in a few days. If one is reasona :&gt;ly careful, and has a good technique de - veloped, he will not injure more than one or two chicks in several hun - dred. ACCURACY TO BE EXPECTED The buyer of sexed chicks should not expect an accuracy of more than 90 per cent. About 95 per cent of the cockerels have well-developed </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Determining the Sex of Day Old Chicks phallic knobs, and about 95 per cent of the pullets have no phallic knob. The remaining five per cent of the cockerels and the five per cent of pullets have small or otherwise poorly developed phallic knobs. It is this ten per cent that cause most of the confusion. However, the ex - perience of sexing several thousand chicks at the University of Nebraska College of Agriculture warrants the definite conclusion that an accuracy of from 90 to 95 per cent may be realized. ECONOMIC VALUE OF SEGREGATING THE SEXES OF DAY-OLD CHICKS In many cases poultry raisers do not have brooder house space to raise enough pullets to fill the laying house if they house both sexes. By buying only pullets sufficient numbers may be raised to fill the laying houses. For a broiler business the cockerels are more desirable than the pullets. They will reach a two-pound size in from one to two weeks less time than the pullets, and iii many cases are preferred by the poultry buy - ers. Specialty breeders sometimes wish to retain one sex and have a good sale for the other. In some sections of the country, the cockerels of cer - tain breeds are a drug on the market, and scarcely pay for the feed they cat. So rather than attempt to raise the cockerels to a marketable age, they are segregated and gassed. C5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>