<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00068.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For 1929-1930</title>
               <date value="1930">1930</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General 4 OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA i For 1929-1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL . STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN . . January 1, 1931 From: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. To: His Excellency, A. J. Weaver, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Subject: Biennial Report of 1929 and 1930. 1. In compliance with requirements of Section 1 to 5, Chapter 55, Article 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1929, the following Biennial Re - port for the calendar years 1929 and 1930 is respectively submitted. The Nebraska National Guard occupies an enviable position m its standing m the National Guard of the United States and that steady improvement which has so richly rewarded the efforts of its personnel for years has never been more potent than during the period covered by this report. Each year training' has materially improved and m a logical and progres - sive manner and notwithstanding the fact that many states allot much more money for use of the National Guard, I sincerely believe there is not a better organization m any State m the Union than has Nebraska at this time. 2. The community interest m our units, the assistance given by committees of Chambers of Commerce and that of the citizenship as a whole has been most gratifying and most helpful and I feel that this support is well warranted for it has become known throughout the State that our training camps are absolutely clean and wholesome and the fear of young men acquiring any bad habits m the Nebraska Na - tionl Guard is a thing of the past. 3. During the last year the Nebraska National Guard has been fully equipped by the Federal Government with the new Melton Roll Collar Uniform and this was all we needed m the way of equipment- The ordnance is m splendid condition though some of it has become obsolete. The government gives us paid motor mechanics and our motor transportation, while of the World War supply is kept m serviceable condition and can all be placed m immediate service m case of an emergency. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, CAMP ASHLAND Since my last report the Memorial Building at Camp Ashland has been completed and paid for from the thirty thousand dollars that was returned from the Federal Government to the enlisted personnel of the Nebraska National Guard, being known as 'other funds," and which was taken from our National Guard during the World War, with the addi - tion of five thousand dollars appropriated by the last session of the legislature to equip and furnish same. This building is in memory of the Nebraska National Guard Veterans of the World War who created the fund. There has also been constructed by the Federal Government three supply houses which are very valuable in aiding us to keep our food supplies at all times clean and away from the flies. INSPECTIONS Annual armory inspections are made by officers of the United States Army detailed for that purpose. The results of our last armory in - spections evidenced closest conformity to prescribed schedules and found our organizations as a whole very satisfactory. ' ARMORIES As reported before, the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Nebraska National Guard have to contend is the rental of armories. It is almost impossible to rent suitable buildings and we conduct a continual fight to hold the rentals down; on the other hand the government is very insistent that we have armories which afford adequate protection to government property and that have ample space for armory drills and training. It is realized that Nebraska is behind many of the other States who have State owned armories and the State is frequently criticised by inspectors on this account but, though constantly urged to do so, I have not been willing and am not now willing to submit an armory building program for your consideration, as well as that of the Legis - kiture, until we have finished our capitol construction and conditions generally speaking have become nearer normal. TRAINING The results of the Armory Drill Training and the Field Training for the period of this report have been very satisfactory. The reports of officers from the War Department assigned to make inspections indi - cate that the state of training of all organizations has steadily improved and that our National Guard of today is better fitted to serve the State or Nation in the event of an emergency than ever before in its history. In connection with the armory drills it is gratifying to note that the attendance is better than it has ever been before and that many of our </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL companies have enlisted to full strength authorized by the War Depart - ment and have a waiting list or those anxious to join. REGULAR ARMY INSTRUCTORS The following is a list of the United States Army Officers and Sergeants who are detailed by the War Department to the State, of Nebraska for instructional purposes, and in reporting the increased efficiency of our National Guard proper appreciation of all the elements concerned therein would be lacking were not the regular army instruc - tors on duty with our troops, accorded due recognition for their fine services to us. They have all given us the finest of cooperation, the most, understanding and sympathetic aid in our problems and, in gen - eral, every opportunity to make the most of their efficiency and time. Major Laurence W. Young, Inf. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska Major Emil H. Burgher, MC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska . Captain Jack L- Meyer, QMC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebraska Capt. Harold H. Elarth, Inf. DOL., Omaha, Nebraska Master Sgt. Lee R. G. Ward, Inf. DEML., Omaha, Nebraska Sergeant Emet G. Roach,. Inf. DEML., Gering, Nebraska Sergeant Hjalmar Strom, QMC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska Sergeant Zack Scarborough, MC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska Sergeant Joel G. Gerard, Inf. DEML., Lincoln, Nebraska ■ . ■ • . CONCLUSION In conclusion I wish to express my appreciation to the officers and enlisted men of the National Guard who have, through their hearty co - operation, assisted in bringing the Nebraska National Guard to the present high state of efficiency and the personnel thereof to a much higher standard- I also desire to extend my appreciation to the dozens of Chambers of Commerce and to the thousands of loyal citizens who have given us their moral support and thereby assisted in making the Nebraska National Guard a bigger and better organization. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL FINANCIAL STATEMENT, NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OF JANUARY 1, 1931 Total Appropriations •'■• Warrants Drawn Balance Support— $180,000.00 $132,678.22 $47,321.78 STRENGTH BY COMPANY AND DETACHMENT OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OF JANUARY 1, 1931 134th Infantry . • Enl. War. Officers Men Officers State Staff and State Detachment 7 21 RegtI. Hq. &amp; Regtl. Hq. Co , 9 62 Medical Department Detachment.. &gt; — 5 32 Service Company 4 93 1. Howitzer Company .'. 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 1st Bn :.„ 3 24 Company A 3 62 Company B ,. 3 62 Company C 3 63 Company D 3 62 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 2d Bn ; • 3 25 Company E : 2 64 Company F 3 64 Company G „ 3 62 Company H „ : 3 62 . Hq. &amp; Hq. Co., 3d Bn 3 25 Company I 3 63 Company K 3 63 Company L 3 63 Company M ...'. ■„ 3 63 72 1099 1 110th Medical Regiment Headquarters 5 Service Company 4 58 I 130th Collecting Company 1 61 . 130th Ambulance Company „. 2 46 166th Hospital Company 5 62 110th Veterinary Company 2 39 Division Surgeon's Office 3 7 22 273 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35th Division Train, QMC Hq. &amp; Hq. Detachment .'. 3 14 Medical . Department Detachment 1 16 137 th Motor Transport Company 2 45 138 th Motor Transport Company 2 44 119 th Motor Repair Section 1 18 119 th Wagon Company 2 51 120 th Wagon Company 3 50 14 238 Grand Total, 108 Officers 1610 Enlisted Men 2 Warrant Officers ROSTER OF OFFICERS STATE STAFF AND STATE DETACHMENT Name, Rank, Arm of Service or Corps Official Mail Address Paul, H. J., Brig. Gen., AGD, State Capital, Lincoln O'Connell, Frank 8., Major, AGD, State Capital, Lincoln Stout, Richard F., Major, JAGD, 722 Stewart Bldg., Lincoln Stein H. C, Major, QMC, State Capitol, Lincoln McConnaughey, W. E., Major, QMC, State Capitol, Lincoln Voder, Byron E., Capt., QMC, 1952 So. 25th St., Lincoln Gillaspie Trey. E., Capt., Ord., Post Office, Lincoln 134 TH INFANTRY Headquarters Thomas, Amos, Colonel, Inf., 824 Omaha Nat'l Bank Bldg., Omaha Douglas, Robert G., Lt. Col., Inf., State Capitol, Lincoln McCormick, Clyde E., Major, Inf., 808 So. 59th St., Omaha Blodgett, M. A., Capt., Inf., 661 So. 26th St., Omaha Thornton, Thos. Q., Capt., Inf., 604 Merchants Bank Bldg., Omaha Utterback, Wm. G., Capt., Inf., Box 452, Nebraska City Capsey, Harold C, Major, Chap., Box 485, Geneva Medical Department Detachment Ensor, Rolland R., Major, MC, Box 83, So. Side, Omaha Achenbach, Wm. H., Capt., DC, 100 Central Aye., Nebraska City Attwood, Norman H., Capt., MC, 813 Med. Arts Bldg., Omaha Gerrie, Wallace A., Capt., MC, 428 Aquila Court, Omaha Kinyoun, Floyd H., Capt., MC, 114 So. 50th St.. Omaha 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Headquarters Company McGill, Albert L., Capt., Inf., 1505 Olin Ave., Omaha Bradley, James A., 2d Lt., Inf., 5232 Poppleton .St., Omaha . Service Company Ayres, Charles J., Capt., Inf., 626 Lincoln Ave., York Beckley, Harry A., 1st Lt., Inf., 613 Grant Ave., York Myers Clarence, 1st Lt., Inf., 51 Platte Ave., York Anderson, Raymond J., 2d Lt, Inf., 415 W. 7th St., York McCall, George A., War. Off. (Band), 637 W. 7th St., York Howitzer Company Hinze Alfred F., Capt., Inf., Gering Laughlin, Leslie J., 1st Lt., Inf., Gering Sorensen, Raymond R., 2d Lt., Inf., Gering Hq., 1st Bn. I Stall, Fred H., Major, Inf., 915 So! 12th St., Beatrice Hq. Co., 1st Bn. Yager, Leslie, Jr., 1st Lt., Inf., 1116 Fourth Ave., Nebraska City Janes, Benny C, 2d Lt., Inf., 19th St. &amp; Central Ave., Nebraska City Company A Thurman, Ray A., Capt., Inf., 5th St. &amp; 3d Ave., Nebraska City Casebeer, Albert L., 1st Lt., Inf., 1418 5th Corso, Nebraska City Morton, Thomas S., 2d Lt., Inf., 823 Park Ave., Nebraska City Company B Myers, Merven F., Capt., Inf., 16th '&amp; Dewey Sts., Falls City Jackson, Dewey E., 1st Lt., Inf., 2115 Abbott St., Falls City Spencer, Harold J., 2d Lt., Inf., 1713 Fulton St., Falls City Company C Coonley, Dean E., Capt., Inf., 109 So. Sumner St., Beatrice Collier, Harold L., 1st Lt., Inf., 821 Beaver St., Beatrice Boatsman, Alford C, 2d Lt., Inf., 923 No. 7th St., Beatrice . Company D Miltonberger, Butler B., Capt., Inf., 1202 No. Locust St., North Platte Peterson, Fred C, 1st Lt., Inf., 1018 W. 3d St., North Platte Wilson, Denver W., 2d Lt., Inf., Apt. 4, Reynolds Ter., North Platte Hq., 2d Bn. Grasborg, Bert C, Major, Inf:, 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, Hq. Co., 2d Bn. Davis, Guy T., 1st Lt., Inf., 3551 Leavenworth St., Omaha ■Crocker, Judd W. ( 2d Lt., Inf., 2523 Manderson St., Omaha Company E Eatwell, Ora A., Capt., Inf., 2120 Ave. D, Scottsbluff Runyon, Harold M., 1st Lt., Inf., 1806 8th Ave., Scottsbluff Company F Eby, Louis R., Capt., Inf., Post Office, Hartington Lange, Carl M., 1st Lt., Inf., Hartington Hardy, Lloyd R., 2d Lt., Hartington Company G Riley, Ivan C, Capt., Inf., Hastings Nat'l Bank, Hastings Van Fleet, Robert J., 1st Lt., Inf., 315 Saunders Ave., Hastings Lovell, Robert A., 2d Lt., Inf., 815 No. Lexington, Hastings Company H Barratt, Edgar, Capt., Inf., 1909 W. 2d St., Grand Island James, Percy F., 1st Lt., Inf., 201 W. 7th St., Grand Island McElrpy, Francis L., 2d Lt., Inf., 210 W. 11th St., Grand Island Hq. 3d Bn. Cline, Earl M., Major, Inf., 703 First Nafl Bank, Lincoln Hq. Co., 3d Bn. Van Kirk, Rolla C, 1st Lt., Inf., 802 First Nafl Bank Bldg., Lincoln Dier, Clifford L., 2d Lt., Inf., 2845 P St., Lincoln Company I Hoke Edwin F., Capt., Inf., Post Office, Lincoln Stewart, Clarence J., 1st Lt., Inf., 2348 O St., Apt. E, Lincoln Weyant Foster H., 2d Lt., Inf., 834 Elmwood St., Lincoln Compan K Frimann, Claude T., Capt., Inf., 507 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha Peterson, Emil B., 1st Lt., Inf., 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha Keltz, Fred J., 2d Lt., Inf., 2042 Vinton St., Omaha Company L Elsasser, H. F., Capt., Inf., 3708 No. 21st St., Omaha Thomsen, Alfred, 1st Lt., Inf., 2028 No. 75th Ave., Omaha Drummy, Wm. W., 2d Lt., Inf., 4011 Corby St., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Company M Geesen, Edward J., Capt., Inf., 641 Seward St., Seward Campbell, Chas. H., 1st Lt., Inf., Box 416, Seward Jones, Erwin P., 2d Lt., Inf., 178 E. Roberts St., Seward 110TH MEDICAL REGIMENT Headquarters Hilton, David C, Col., MC, 305 Richards Blk., Lincoln Bartholomew, Philip H., Lt. Col., MC, State Capitol, Lincoln Evans, J. North, Major, MC, Pollock Bldg., Columbus Deppen, Earl N., Capt., MC, 911 Security Mutual Bldg., Lincoln Service Company Ball, Harry R., Capt., MAC, 1120 N St., Lincoln Stearns, Harry C, Capt, MAC, Post Office, Lincoln Eisler, Herbert M., Capt., MC, 2312 Washington St., Lincoln Strickland, Henry H., 1st Lt, MAC, 709 So: 29th St., Lincoln Havlicek, Lumir C, W. O., Band, Crete. 130th Collecting Company Evans Carroll D., Jr., Capt, MC, Pollock Bldg., Columbus 130th Ambulance Company Swanson, Leonard A., Capt, MC, 412 No. Hastings Ave., Hastings Thomas, Dwight P.. 1st Lt., MAC, 510 E. 5th St., Hastings 166th Hospital Company Wells, Francis A., Capt, MC, 826 Sharp Bldg., Lincoln Johnston, Leonard R., Capt.; DC, 919 Federal Trust Bldg., Lincoln Johnson Rodney K., Capt., MC, Friend Anderson, James B., Capt, MC, 1119 Federal Trust Bldg., Lincoln Stone, Ralph L., 1st Lt, MAC, 3042 Q St., Lincoln 110th Veterinary Company Alford, Simon W., Capt, VC, 1311 No. 37th St., Lincoln Skidmore, Louis V., 1st Lt.; VC, 3859 Dudley St., Lincoln Division Surgeon's Office (35th Div.) Brooks Earl B., Major, MC, 705 First Nat'l Bank Bldg., Lincoln Bennett, John R.. Major, DC, 917 Stewart Bldg., Lincoln Norden, Carl J., Major, VC, 227 No. 9th St., Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT Of THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. 35TH DIVISION TRAIN Headquarters . Poteet, Marcus L., Major, QMC, 705 First Nafl Bank Bldg., Lincoln Hq. Detachment Turner, Howard R., Ist Lt., QMC, 1860 Dakota St., Lincoln Browne, William H., 2d Lt., QMC, 2701 Everett St., Lincoln ■ Medical Department Detachment Rose, Wallace E., Capt., MC, 2218% Central Aye., Kearney 137 th Motor Transport Company Ellis, Harry H., Ist Lt, QMC, Ist Nat'l Bank Bldg., Holdrege Leffler, Delbert C, 2d Lt., QMC, 210 4th Aye., Holdrege 138 th Motor Transport Company Oleson, Nels A., Ist Lt., QMC, 537% No. Broad St., Fremont Peterson, Vaughn, 2d Lt., QMC, North Hancock St., Fremont 119 th Motor Repair Section Yakish, Wesley H., Ist Lt., QMC, 1518 No. Clarkson St., Fremont 119 th Wagon Company Bates, Merton 0., Capt., QMC, Court House, Lexington Nielsen, Frederick, Ist Lt., QMC, 1308 No. Grant St., Lexington 120 th Wagon Company ... Henninger, Guy N., Capt., QMC, Court House, Kearney Atkinson, William J., Ist Lt., QMC, 927 W. 28th St., Kearney Mattson, Herman M., 2d Lt., QMC, 107 E. 27th St., Kearney . STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1 1929 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL extend from January 1, 1929, to December 31, 1929. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN • . . March 13, 1929 General Orders No. 2 1. Pursuant to authority of Secretary of War contained M. B. 325.4 (QM) — Neb.-l, dated March 1, 1929, the 119th Motor Repair Section, 35th Division Train, Nebraska National Guard, stationed at Holdrege, Nebraska, is hereby disbanded and will at once be mustered out of State and Federal service. It being impracticable to transfer the enlisted personnel of the organization to an active National Guard unit or the National Guard Reserve, they will be discharged, pursuant to authority contained in par. 60, NGR 25. Major W. E. McConnaughey, Q. M. C, Nebraska National Guard, will muster out said company and promptly forward to this office final Form 100 M. B., also all State and Federal property, books and records, together with the discharges of enlisted men, which were not. delivered at the time of muster-out. 2. The resignation of L. E. Chadderdon, First Lieutenant, Q. M. C, N. N. G., submitted to this office under date of February 6, 1929, is hereby accepted, effective this date. 3. The Train Commander, 35th Division Train, Nebraska National Guard, is authorized to reorganize the 119th Motor Repair Section, 35th Division Train, with station at Fremont, Nebraska. When the new unit is ready for inspection for Federal . recognition application should </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL be made to the Corps Area Commander through this office and Form No. 113-M. B. and a complete roster furnished. By order of the Governor: Hi J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. ■ ; ' ■ . ' ■ . ...■■■' ■ ■ l ■ STATE OF NEBRASKA I ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT • LINCOLN May 14, 1929 General Orders • No. 3 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Thursday, May 30, 1929, con - secrated' to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the Amer - ican Republic, the National Flag will, in accordance with par. 2, sub - par. 11, Army Regulations 260-10, be displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist in the observance of the day by Veteran organizations, Commanding Officers of organizations not in the Federal service will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, • Asst. Adjutant General, ■'!"■'• Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OK NEBRASKA • . ' 'i ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN - ■• July 10, 1929 General Orders • No. 4 1. Pursuant to authority granted m MB 354.1 Nebr.-20, June 24, 1929, being Training Authority No. 43-1, the State Staff and State De - tachment, 134 th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, 110 th Medical Regi - ment and the Detached Medical Department, 35th Division, will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 5 to 19, 1929, inclusive, under command of Brigadier General ■Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty the above named organizations will return to their home stations. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C. Stein and two enlisted men of the State Detachment, will go into camp at the earliest possible moment on August 2, 1929, and will remain m camp August 20 and 21, 1929. 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment on August 3, 1929, taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, one Captain, Ord., and nineteen enlisted men; Service Detach - ment, Service Company, 134 th Infantry, consisting of one First Lieuten - ant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters. Detachment, 35th Division Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six men; and Service Detachment, Service Company, 110 th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain, S. 0., and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance De - tachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to Major H. C. Stein, August 3, 1929. 4. Upon arrival m camp August 3, 1929, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134 th Infantry, will establish mess for his Detach - ment and the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 110 Medical Regi - ment, will immediately establish mess for the State Detachment, Head - quarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, and his Detachment. The officers m charge should see that at least one regular cook is included for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134 th infantry, 35th Division Train and 110 th Medical Regiment will see that equip - ment necessary for establishing commissaries is forwarded with ad - vance detachments. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5. A rear detachment consisting o£ one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, and one Captain, Ord., of the State Staff, and nineteen enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 20, 1929, tor the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., have been handled by letters from this. office. 7. In compliance with par. 4, National Guard Regulations 27, April 1, 1927, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will report to a medical officer during the annual encampment, August 5 to 19, 1929, inclusive, for that purpose, and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Camp Surgeon before the close of the encampment. The Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, will designate such medical officers as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph and will cause to be published the names of same at the beginning of the encampment, in order that those requiring examination may know to whom they are to report 8. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp and company and detachment commanders will cooperate with the medical department in seeing that all men are pres - ent and that their men are so examined. The following named officers are designated to make the examinations called for in this paragraph and will report to the Camp Commander at 9:00 A. M. on the morning of August 5, 1929, for instructions pertaining thereto: Major Earl B. Brooks, M. C. , . Major John R. Bennett, D. C. Captain Herbert M. Eisler, M. C. Captain Rodney K. Johnson, M. C. Captain Glenn D. Whitcomb, M. C. Captain Wallace A. Gerrie. M. C. 9. Travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1930 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season of. Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1930, to December 31, 1930. By oder of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, .' ■ Nebraska. STATE 1 OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 10, 1930 General Orders No. 2 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Friday, May 30, 1930, conse - crated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National Flag will m accordance with par. 2, sub-par. 11, Army Regulations 260-10, be displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at . half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organization m the observance of the day, Commanding Officers of National Guard Organizations will place their respective commands at the disposol of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will, be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL-S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 11, 1930 General Orders No. 3 ; • i 1. Pursuant to authority granted m MB 354.1 Nebr.-22, June 20, 1930, and telegraphic authority from the Chief, Militia Bureau, dated July 11, i 930, being Training Authority No. 43-1, the State Staff and State Detachment, 134 th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, 110 th Med - ical Regiment and the Detached Medical Department, 35th Division, will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 4 to 18, 1930, inclusive, under command of Brigadier General Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duly &lt;he above named organizations will return to their Rome stations. a. Company E and Howitzer Company, 134 th Infantry, will leave their home stations August 3, 1930, and will return so as to arrive at their home stations August 19, 1930. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C. Stein and two enlisted men of the State Detachment, will go into camp at the earliest possible moment on August 1, 1930, and will remain m camp August 19 and 20, 1930. 3. The following will report at the earliest moment on August 2, 1930, taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff and State Detachment, consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, one Captain, Ord., and nineteen enlisted men; Service Detachment, Service Company, 134 th Infantry, consisting of one Captain, S. 0., one First Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six en - listed men; and Service Detachment, Service Company, 110 th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain, S. 0., and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance Detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to Major H. C. Stein. August 2, 1930. 4. Upon arrival m camp August 2, 1930, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134 th Infantry, will establish mess for his De - tachment and the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 110 th Med - ical Regiment, will immediately establish mess for the State Detach - ment, Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train and his Detach- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, ment. The officers in charge should see that at least one regular cook is included for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train and 110th Medical Regiment will see that equipment necessary for establishing commissaries is forwarded with advance detachments. 5. A rear detachment consisting of one Major, QMC, one Captain, QMC, and one Captain, Ord., of the State Staff, and nineteen enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in Camp August 19, 1930, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 6. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equipment, etc., have been handled by letters from this office. 7. In compliance with par. 4, National Guard Regulations 27, April 1, 1927, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will report to a medical officer during the annual encampment, August 4 to 18, 1930, inclusive, for that purpose and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Camp Surgeon be - fore the close of the encampment. The Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Ktgiinent, will designate such medical officers as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph and will cause to be pub - lished the names of same at the beginning of the encampment, in order that those requiring examination may know to whom they are to report. 8. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of the arrival in camp and company and detachment commanders will cooperate with the medical department in seeing that all men are present and that their men are so examined. T,he following named officers are desig - nated to make the examinations called for in this paragraph and will report to the Camp Commander at 9:00 A. M. on the morning of August 4, 1930, for instructions pertaining thereto: Major Earl B. Brooks, M. C. Major John R. Bennett, D. C. Captain Herbert M. Eisler, M. C. Captain Rodney K. Johnson, M. C. Captain Floyd H. Kinyoun, M. C. Captain Wallace A. Gerrie, M. C. . 9. Travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. ■. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 23, 1929 Circular Letter . '••-'." NO. 1 Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG 1. In accordance with instructions received from the Militia Bureau to the effect that all unobliged funds alloted to this State for supplies and equipment will lapse on March 31, 1929, it will be necessary to sub - mit, not later than March 15, 1929, requisitions covering quartermaster, ordnance, signal, medical and engineer property required by your or - ganization for the balance of the fiscal year 1929 and for the annual field training period, calendar year 1929. 2. No requisitions received after the date set forth in paragraph 1 will be honored: By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 33 is the last of series of 1928. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 19, 1929 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Form 100 M. B. To: All Company Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The following copy of letter received from the Chief, Militia Bureau, with reference to Form 100 M. B. is sent all Company Commanders with request that they immediately make a study of same and submit to this office direct any suggestions they may have to offer with reference to the abolishment or simplification of this form: "WAR DEPARTMENT OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF THE MILITIA BUREAU WASHINGTON February 6, 1929 MB 315 (Revision)— 31 Subject: Form 100 Militia Bureau. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, (through the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area). 1. There have been some complaints by unit commanders and in - structors to the effect that the present Form. 100 Militia Bureau places an unnecessary clerical burden on the former. 2. A Militia Bureau board of officers is considering Form 100 M. B. with reference to the advisability of continuing it in its present form, revising it, or adopting another report form or forms in its place. 3. The Militia Bureau does not desire to impose a burden upon a large number of individuals by calling upon them for a study and recom-. mendations in connection with this subject. It is desired, however; to present an apportunity to those interested to submit constructive criti - cisms on Form 100 M. B. which may result in the lessening of work in the preparation of a report that will answer the same purpose. 4. In considering this question the following should be borne in mind. a. Some form of communication between the unit and instructor is necessary in connection with the administrative examination of the pay roll, and a form similar to the now absolete Form 367b might be devised which would answer the purpose. b. Some States use the form as a roster and strength report. c. The Militia Bureau absolutely requires a report covering- the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (1) Identification of O. R. C. status of officers and enlisted men. (2) Data pertaining to changes of status ot" National Guard • ...; officers. (3) Data, for the relative rank file. (4) Data as to assignments of Reserve Officers of the Na - tional Guard. (5) Monthly strength report. 5. Suggestions, by those who believe that there is here matter for correction, and who desire to assist therein, must be in the office of the Chief, Militia Bureau, by March 15, 1929. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 28, 1929 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Company Council Books. To: All Company Commanders, NNG. 1. Recent inspections of Company Council Books have revealed the fact that there is no uniform system for keeping the same, so the fol - lowing Avill be adopted: a. Council Book Q. M. C. No. 15. b. Company designation with words added "State Funds" on cover. c. The account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under "Other Funds" and in accordance with </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL paragraphs 2, Z, 4, 5 and 6 of the instructions (see also the jiiodel). d. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, regardless whether receipts or expenditures. e. Certificates for receipts and invoices for expenditures are required for all transactions from January 1, 1929. f. In case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transactions, cut off bottom of page above words "Total re - ceipts and expenditures" and the top of next page "In ac - count with fund, etc.", under the word '"year" and above "month". 2. All Council Books that have not been audited up to and includ - ing December 31, 1928, will be brought up to that date and will be sent at your earliest convenience (but not later than March 30, 1929), to Major H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Lincoln, Nebraska, who will audit and re - turn same. 3. In case the funds are subject to check, the bank statement of December 31, 1928, is required. For expenditures prior to January 1, 1929, cancelled checks will be accepted so that audit may be expedited. By direction ot the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 5, 1929 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Squaw Camp. To: All Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. ." 1. Arrangements may be made whereby a squaw camp will be es - tablished south of the camp hospital, Ashland, Nebraska, for the wives of officers belonging to the Nebraska National Guard who desire to sppnd their vacation or a part of it in this way. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. 2. In order to establish this camp, it will be necessary to construct floors and frames for the pyramidal tents, water will be piped to the camp and, if possible, a bath house will be constructed close thereto. 3. In order to repay the expense attached to the construction as above enumerated, a charge of $1.00 per day will probably be made. 4. Nothing has been worked out definitely along this line as yet and before anything is done, we would like to know from the respective officers how many would desire to avail themselves of this opportunity of bringing their wives to camp. In case there are sufficient number to make it worth while, we will try to work out definite plans along this line, but in case the number is too few, nothing will be done. 5. It is requested that any officer interested will notify this office on or before March 20, 1929. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant. General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA • ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 8, 1929 Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Target Practice, Small Arms, 1929. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. Courses to be fired: The following courses only are authorized during the year 1929. For rifle practice: Course D, T.R. 150-10. For Machine gun practice: Course A, T.R. 150-35. For pistol practice: Dismounted course, T.R. 150-20. 2. RECORD PRACTICE. Record practice for rifles, machine guns and pistols will be fired during the 1929 field training period. Organiza - tions will complete the preparatory exercises and instruction practice at their home ranges. No instruction practice except a limited number of sighting shots for initial adjustments will be permitted during the field traning period. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. PREPARATORY INSTRUCTION AND PRACTICE. No man will be permitted to fire record practice with the rifle, pistol or machine gun who has not completed the preparatory exercises prescribed in T.R. 150-5, 150-10, 150-20, 150-35, and who has not fired sufficient instruction practice to demonstrate his ability to apply the principles taught in the preparatory exercises. 4. RECORDS OF PROGRESS OF INSTRUCTION. Marksmanship (Preparatory) forms to show the state of instruction of individuals before starting range practice, and in addition score books for rifle instruction practice, and score cards for rifle, pistol and machine guns, will be mailed to unit commanders on requisition. Regimental and company command - ers will require that these be kept in the manner required by Training Regulations, and regimental commanders will require that these marks - manship records, certified by the company commander, be brought to camp and submitted to their respective regimental commanders not. later than August 6, 1929. • 5. Regimental commanders will, upon receipt of the above marks - manship records, appoint a board of officers who will examine the records submitted and will make recommendations as to' who will fire the au - thorized record course in each organization, and. such recommendations will, upon approval, be published in orders: ■ 6. AMMUNITION. a. Ammunition allowances that may be expended at home sta - tions for instruction practice will not exceed the following: Unit Cal. .30 . Cal. .45 Machine Gun Company .: :.. 12000 2000 Rifle Company 6000 600 Hq. Company, Inf. Regt 1200 2000 Service Company, Inf. Regt 3600 2000 Howitzer Company .'. 1200 2000 Hq. Company, Inf. Bn 2400 500 Hq. Det, Div. Tn.. . : 1200 500 Wagon Company ■ 4800 400 Mot. Tr. Company 3600 300 Mot. Rep. Section None 1000 b. Company commanders should submit requistions for the am - munition required for instruction practice. Initial Allowance Ammuni - tion Must Not Be Used. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL \ ■.'.■■'■■■ ■ ..■-■'•' 7. TARGET RANGES. ai. The attention of all organization commanders is called to the provisions of NGR 78. Company commanders desiring ranges should submit application to this office so that leases may be furnished and the instructors on duty with the unit may make the inspection as required. 8. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 5, March 7, 1928, is hereby revoked. 9. Attention is called to National Guard Memorandum, Headquar - ters, Seventh Corps Area, date March 8, 1929, "Precautions to be taken during target practice". By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, ■ Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 12, 1 929 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Overcoats. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. . ■ ■ . - . .'■'':, i ■'■'■ ■ 1. Notwithstanding the fact that it is very seldom found necessary to use the military overcoat, reports are continuously corning in of their not being properly cared for. 2. All overcoats should be thoroughly inspected; the ones that are moth eaten should be placed upon a survey and the ones that are worn out through fair wear and tear should be I and I'd. All good coats should be counted, packed in naphthaline and placed in boxes securely wrapped in tar paper, the box nailed up and the number of coats marked plainly on the outside of the box and only opened in case of an emerg - ency. If it is preferred by the unit commander, each coat can be well jwrapped in paper separately and stored away, but it is thought that the box and tar paper is a better solution. I ■ ' • ■ ' ■ ■ . 3. Overcoats packed according to the above can be stored away in. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the supply or store room and will not cause the company commander as much trouble as when handled as at present. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General, . . Nebraska. ■ STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 13, 1929 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Exemption from Income Tax. To: All Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. The following article was published in the Army and Navy Journal, March 9, 1929, and is reproduced for the information of all concerned. This office has no knowledge as to the correctness ,of same. "Drill Pay Held Non-taxable. It has been pointed out by the experts that Federal income tax need not be paid for amounts received for National Guard armory drill pay and camp pay, nor need these receipts be re - ported. Though received from Federal paymasters, these amounts are disbursed by the Federal Government to the Several States and are to be regarded as moneys received from the States for services rendered thereto, which are specifically exempt from Federal income tax report." By direction of the Governor:. H. J. PAUL, • The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 3, 1923 Circular Letter . No. 8 Subject: Care of U. S. Rifles, Cal. .30. Model of 1903. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. Attention is invited to provisions of Changes No. 1, Training Regu - lations 320-10, which provides for care and cleaning of the rifle, which are being mailed under separate cover this date to organizations equipped with the rifle and which should be strictly adhered to. By direction of the . Governor : H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 15, 1929 Circular Letter '• j No. 9 ■ Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1930. i ■ .To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all unit and sub-unit commanders. "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of drills to be held during the Fiscal Year 1930 will be lim - ited as follows: (a) During the first and second quarters, not to exceed twenty - four (24) Federal pay drills. (b) During third quarter, not to exceed twelve (12) Federal pay drills, m addition to any part of the 24 drills not held during the first and second quarters. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (c) During fourth quarter, not to exceed twelve (12) Federal pay drills, in addition to any part of the thirty-six (36) drills not held during the first, second and third quarters. (U) In no event will the number of drills for which payment • is made with Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year, for any organization of the National Guard." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 13, 1929 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject : Athletic Program. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following Athletic Program, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require it, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. As great benefit is derived from bur camp athletics, it is hoped and expected that each unit and sub-unit commander will give this matter his personal attention and see that his organization gets the full bene - fit of same. PROGRAM. I. For "General's Trophy" Athletics (a) Teams — competition (1) League Baseball All companies to entei 1 baseball teams (2) Playground Ball Team competition to be part of mass athletic program </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (3) Basketball Team from each company allowed (4) Track Each company permitted two entries m each event (b) Individual Competition (1) Boxing — 7 champions Every company entitled to enter one man m each weight division — m tourney (points given for men entered m company elimination however) (2) Wrestling One. man to be entered from each company m each weight (3) Swimming Points and medals for Ist, 2nd, 3rd for each event Individual to enter as many events as he cares to 11. Entertainment — (New Building) Skits — songs — or any other entertainment 111. Mass Athletics 1:30-3:00 ' .."■■ - "THE GENERAL'S TROPHY" General Paul is offering this cup lor best company activity m ath - letics and entertainment. How to Wjn General's Trophy This point system adopted to give every company a fair chance. 1. Athletics — Team Entries (a) Teams — 10 points for entering company team m baseball — (1) .. league — playground basketball, track, swimming, wrestling — boxing and entertainers, a possible 80 points. ll._ Individual points (a) Boxing 5 points for individual entries and each round they survive 10 points semi-finals </seg>
            <seg id="p030">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 25 points for champions m each class or division Possible points • ■ '■ . ■ One m each class 10 Assume he boxes four times Ist round 5 2nd round 5 Semi-finals : 10 Finals &amp; Champ 25 .': T0ta1.... 55 points On above points system — any company entering team — and only one man winning a championship, would receive a total of 55 points credit (b) Wrestling — 10 points team entry 5 for each round winner 10 for semi-finals 25 for champions (c) Swimming — 10 points for entries m all events 5 points for each Ist 3 pofnts for each 2nd 1 point for each 3rd . (d) Track — 10 for team entry — one man or more m each event 5 points for Ist 3 points for 2nd 1 point for 3rd (c) Basketball — 10 for team entry 5 points for each round 10 for semi-finals 25 for championship (t) Entertainment (something new) Any company furnishing any entertainment for evening program will receive points on General's Trophy. These to be awarded on merit to be passed upon by three judges. The point award is based on entertainment furnished camp at large. For that reason boxing scores highest points. Other points Mass Athletics — 50 points 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, (1) Company having best attendance (2) Showing best interest and spirit (3) Leadership, discipline, etc. ■„•■.•■ Other points — (medals individual) Individual medals to be awarded for champions m Boxing — Wrestling — Swimming and Track — as always Bulletin Boards Each company to post entries — time and place on this board each day. A permanent board to be erected listing champion m each company for visitors' day. 100 points given to first company which submits complete list of entries m all competition 50 for 2nd 25 for 3rd 10 for 4th 5 for sth •:' This to be mailed m July 1, giving each company time to organize their teams and entries. ATHLETIC STAFF Announced later. EQUIPMENT Bring all athletic equipment to camp, By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 17, 1929 Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Pay Rolls for Quarter Ending August 31, 1929. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL So many have made inquiry as to whether or not two pay rolls will be necessary for the quarter ending August 31, that the following cor - respondence is published for the information and guidance of all con - cerned: ■ • "June 12, 1929 Subject: Pay Rolls lor Quarter Ending August 31, 1929. To: Finance Officer, Army Bldg., 15th &lt;£Dodge, Omaha, Ne - braska. ; Inasmuch as our next pay period takes in June of one fiscal year and July and August of another, information is requested as to whether or not two pay rolls will be required or if one pay roll can cover this period. - ■ . H. J. PAUL, Th'e Adjutant General. Nebraska. 1st Ind. 240.91 Finance Office, U. S. Army, Omaha, Nebraska, June 13, 1929. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. The new armory drill pay roll form was prepared with a view to meeting the requirements of one pay roll for each three months period regardless of the fact that the period may include part of two fiscal years, hence only one pay roll will be necessary to cover the period mentioned in the basic communication. H. G. SALMON, Major, Finance Department, Finance Officer, U. S -Army." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL . - • June 17, 1929 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Erroneous Credits for Armory Training. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following communication from The Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned. There is no excuse for making this error and it should be guarded against. "WAR DEPARTMENT Office of the Chief of. the Militia Bureau, Washington. May 24, 1929 MB 240.91 Nebr.— 19 Subject: Erroneous credits for armory training. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. 1. An examination of recent records of armory drill pay suspended in the accounts of U. S. Army Finance officers for payments made during 1928 indicates that in an unusual number of cases — very few of which could .be attributed to clerical errors — armory drill pay was claimed for (hills attended and appropriate duties performed for periods during which the individual concerned was in receipt of the pay of his rank or grade by reason of being in attendance at a field training camp. 2. In most of the cases the individual concerned was a member of the advance detachment and was credited with being actually present at an armory drill held by the organization just prior to its departure from the home station and while the advance detachment was in camp. 3. It should not be necessary to state that individuals of the Na - tional Guard are not entitled to pay for armory training for periods dur - ing which they are in receipt of the pay and allowance of their rank or grade, i. e., while attending encampments. 4. Since armory training pay rolls are paid by United States Army Finance officers and field training pay rolls by the United State Property and Disbursing Officers of the state, the overlapping payemnts are not </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL discovered until both pay rolls are audited in the General Accounting Office. It has been the custom of the General Accounting Office to sus - pend payments made for armory training on the grounds that the field training pay was, as a rule, the first payment made, and the individual concerned was no doubt present in camp during the period for which training pay was claimed. As a result, all the suspensions appear in the accounts of the United States Army Finance officers who pay claims for armory training! 5. It is requested that the foregoing be brought to the attention of j»V.- organization commanders and that such corrective measures be adopted as will prevent suspensions of this nature. • C. C. HAMMOND, ■ , • ■ Major General, .-•-.. Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: '.' H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 24, 1929 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 29, 1929. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau, to submit a Return of Strength on the evening of June 30, 1929, and as June 30 comes on Sunday, all unit and sub-unit commanders are requested to wire this office their strength Friday afternoon, June 28, or early Saturday morn - ing, June 29, in order that we may compile same and forward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, on the 29th, . : 2. The following form of telegram, giving officers and enlisted men separately, should be used: "Co. A, three officers, sixty-three enlisted men. (Signed) Smith, Captain." </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. DO NOT FORGET TO WIRE THIS IN BEFORE NOON, SATUR - DAY, JUNE 29, AS THIS OFFICE IS CLOSED SATURDAY AFTER - NOON. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 8, 1929 Circular Letter . . : No. 14 ' Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1929. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1929, having been set, i. e., August 5 to 19, 1929, inclusive, ho organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section III. National Guard Regulations 45, 1927. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non-compliauce therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of Company Officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the United States Property and Disbursing Officer as to the exact hour of departure from home sta - tion, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation re - quests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company, Commanders are authorized to purchase subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40c per meal and will follow instruc - tions received from the USP&amp;DO pertaining thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume command of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained; i. e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct must be oorrect. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chanter IX, Movemets By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The Command - ing Officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp, and report to </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, the Camp Commander immediately upon arrival any defects or faults found with railroads transporting troops. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Com - pany Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian cloth - ing to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear it on leave or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of. the pack as shown in Training 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet ar - ticles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito- bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company Command - ers should check each enlisted, man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc, aid that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. Any Company Commander failing : to bring mosquito bars tiiis year will be required to have same brought in later by express at their own expense. The mosquitoes are bad this year. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment and cleaning materials. In - formation pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment and harness will be furnished in a separate Circular Letter. No target material will be brought to camp as it will be furnished there. No canvas cots will He brought to camp. . • S. Ordnance. All ammunition except the initial allowances, 1929, and the cal. .22 long rifles, will be brought to .camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO, securing memorandum receipt for same, all empty cart - ridges (brass), in packing boxes, Belgian aiming devices, all arm racks and lockers, all rifles and pistols and in fact, all arms with Which each respective organization is equipped, together -with all other ordnance with which the individual and companies are equipped. 9. Special Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer property, including lister bags, is to be carried. 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, Morn - ing Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in triplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in triplicate of all officers </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL .. S! z^uTnTaUTZT 1 ;-:^ a statement as to cause ° f ■«* ab — , win oe tuined in immediately upon arrival in camp. Telegraphic renorts of Strength when entraining are NOT required this year * and 8 " 8 ' ,f " ?° mpany Officers wil1 m^s with their organization Slid h T themselv es with tables and chairs. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants and" l°o°d IT 8 / 8 T ° f "" m ° St imP0Itant thiDgS towa ' d contentment and good morale of an organizaUon The Commandin ■ infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, together w th the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train. Q. M. C. wi.l estab- Sion r r H m l SS^J' Or the Fie ' d aDd Staff Officers of their °^ ization and such Officers of the "State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be opekt ng so as to serve lunch at noon, August 5, 1929. wi/he n! nliS *? d ,^ en ' S , M ° tOr Trans 0° rtati °"- No motor transportation w.ll be permuted in the enlisted men's camp area this year. Enlisted men hnngmg motor transportation to camp will be required to register same and to have passes for same going in and out of "the ground to m where they w, be parked on the south side of the main highway and where they will, be required to stay from taps until 4:00 P. M. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 9, 1929 Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Transportation, Field Training, 1929. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. MOUNTS. Mounts will be furnished to the respective organiza - tions as follows: a. State 8 Officers, 3 Orderlies, 1 Senior Instr., 1 for Staff The Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 134th 1 Col., I Lt. Col., 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., 1 Aux. Inf. Bn. Adj., 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T.. 4 Orderlies (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hqs.). 35th 4 Tn. Hq., 4 to ea. Wag. Co., 2 to Att. M.D. Div. Tn. 110th 1 Col., I Lt. Col., 2 Majors (P &amp; T., Veterinar- Med. ian D. S. O.), 1 Adj., 1 ' Supply Officer, 2 Regt. Orderlies. b. The responsible officers for the following Sub-units will fur - nish riding equipment with grain and feed bags: State Major W. E. McConnaughey, 13 sets. Staff 134th C O Regimental Hq. Co., 6 sets, Inf. C O Battalion Hq. Cos. 3 sets, each. C 0 Service Co., 2 sets. C O Attached Medical Det., 1 set. 35th CO 119th Wag, Co., 4 sets. Dv. Tn. C O 120th Wag. Co., 4 sets. C O Headquarters Det., 4 sets. CO Att. Med. Det., 2 sets. 110th Med. Regt. C O Service Co., 8 sets. 2. MULES, DRAFT. Mules will be assigned as follows: a. Camp Quartermaster 4 134th Infantry. M. G. Companies 4 each Howitzer Company 2 Service Company 20 35th Div. Train. Wagon Co. No. 119 20 Wagon Co. No. 120 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL b. Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows: USP&amp;DO — All harness and wagons required for Service Com - pany, 134 th Infantry, Wagon Companies of the 35th Division Train and Camp Quartermaster. The C Os of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Company will furnish the necessary harness for the animals assigned them. 3, MOTOR VEHICLES. a. USP&amp;DO will transport all available trucks and ambulances stored at the State Arsenal to Camp. b. The Commanding Officer, Co. X, will detail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting Class B, Liberty Truck, so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 5, not later than 9:00 A. M. Drivers will report to Camp Transportation Officer, immedi - ately upon their arrival. c. All organizations having Government owned motor vehicles as - signed them, will immediately after arrival m camp and uploading of equipment have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Of - ficer, to be placed m the camp pool for the duration of camp. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT QENBBAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 10, 192D Circular Letter No. 16 . Subject: . Train Schedule to Annual Encampment, 1929, Asliland, Nebraska. . ■ . a To: All Company Commanders, Field &lt;£ Staff Officers, NNG. q 1. In accordance with Nebraska Circular Letter No. i I, 1929, the following Train Schedule is prescribed: JO Movements Organization Location I 55? | £. ' . Sdiedllle 2 _____ _______ ; ■ . ■ h* No. 1 3d Bn Hq. Co. Lincoln | 24 | 2 Lv. Lincoln Train No. 8 H CB&amp;Q Co. I j 55 at 7:45 A. M. Aug. 5/29 &gt; Ashland 110th Vet. Co. ' | 28 Ar. Ashland 8:26 A. M. . d Field &amp; Staff | 5 3 110th M. R. H Det. Dv. Sur. O. ' 9 S Hq. 35th Dv. Tn. I 10 No. 2 Co. B Falls City | 56 1 Lv. Falls City Train No. 109 § MP • ' at 4:32 A. M. Aug. 5/29 2 Omaha Co A Nebr. City 52 1 Lv. Nebr. City 5:51 A. M.' g CB&amp;Q 1st Bn. Hq. Co. | . 21! Ashland F(eld &amp; Staff Omaha 7 Lv. Omaha Special Train f&lt; 134th Inf. | 9:15 A. M. Regtl. Hq. Co. • | 50 1 Ar. Ashland 10:05 A. M. . Co. K I 60 1 • . '. Co. L j 59 1 Med. Dept. Det. j 30 1 134th Inf. ' ■ 2d Bn. Hq. Co. | 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 1 Location I ' Xpprox7"l Bag. Movements Organization j n 0 . p ass . cai Schedule No 3 Co C Beatrice | 55 1 Lv. Beatrice Train No. 24 at CB&amp;Q i 8:29 A. M. Aug. 5/29 Ashland Band, 110th M. R. Crete 24 Lv. Crete 9:25 A. M. | ■ • . Ar. Ashland 11:17 A. M. ■ M ■ , — ■- H No 4 Co E Scottsbluff 54 1 Lv. Scottsbluff Train No. 32 % CB&amp;Q • V. - &lt; x &gt; 1° : °7 P- M. Aug. 4/29 2 Ashland • Ar. Lincoln 1 P. M. 8/5/29 *j Lv. Lincoln Train No. 38 at O 1:20 P. M. *» Ar. Ashland 2:00 P. M. i : : : : a No 5 120th Wag. Co. Kearney 45 1 Lv. Kearney Train No. 36 H CB&amp;Q Med.Dept.Det. ■'. 12 at 9:00 A. M. Aug. 5/29 &gt; Ashland 35th Div. Tn. Ar. Hastings 10:18 A. M. 2 Co H Grand Island 56 1 Lv. Grand Island Train No. 42 a . : at 9:53 A. M. g I Ar. Aurora 10:22 A. M. 137th M T Co. Holdrege | 35 1 Lv. Holdrege Train No. 2 H "I at 9:08 A. M. Aug. 5/29 q Co G Hastings | 54 1 Lv. Hastings Special Train H at 10:55 A. M. Aug. 5/29 g I via Aurora § Serv Co., 134th Inf. York | 70 1 Lv. York 12:45 P. M. &gt; Co M Seward | 45 1 Lv. Seward 1:25 P. M. I Ar. Ashland 2:50 P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">, — - ■ — ' —^— ■•• ■ _• ~. Location | Approx. Bag. ci,~,i„iv Movements Organization No. Pass. Car bcnenuie No. 6 Howitzer Co. Gering 47 1 Lv. Gering Train No. 54 UP (x) at 3:50 P. M. Aug. 4/29 Fremont Ar. No. Platte 9:10 P. M. CB&amp;Q Lv. No. Platte Train -No. 4 Ashland at 10:40 P. M. Ar. Fremont g • ". 5.05 A. M. Aug. 5/29 '■'*&amp;■ Co. D No. Platte 61 1 Lv. No. Platte Train No. 38 O 6:15 A. M. Aug. 5/19 g 119th Wag. Co. Lexington 40 1 Lv. Lexington 7:50 A. M. 130th Coll. Co. Columbus 45 I 1 Lv. Columbus 12:30 P. M. . ■ :2 | Ar. Fremont 1:40 P. M. i Lv. Fremont Special Train 3 I CB&amp;Q at 2:10 P. M. § ■ ■ | | . AiL-Ashland 2-:55 P M. No. 7 Co. F Hartington 45 1 1 Lv. Hartington Special Train g CSTPM&amp;O | 6:00 A. M. Aug. 5/29 ' Omaha .■■■'■ Ar. Omaha 1:10 P. M. Lv. Omaha &gt; CB&amp;Q Ashland '■••'• •• | -1:15 P. M. Ar. Ashland 5:06 P. M. 3 Via 130th Amb. Co. Hastings | 45 I ■ Lv. Hastings 7:00 A. M. 8/5/29 2 Government 'II Ar. Camp 3 : 00 P. M. Z Motor Service Co. Lincoln |. 33 | Lv. Lincoln 7:00 A. M. 8/5/29 H Vehicles 11.0th M. R. | | Ar. Camp 9:30 A. M. P 166th Hosp. Co. | 55 | &amp; 138th M. T. Co. Fremont | 48 | . Lv. Fremont 5:00 A. M. 8/5/29 119th M. R. Sec. Fremont j 21. "J Ar. Camp 9:00 A. M. SS&amp;SD Lincoln |21 ' Lv. Lincoln 7:00 A. M. 8/3/29 1 ■ J \ Ar. Camp 10:00 A. M. (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Co. E (Scottsbluff). </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 1. Co. I, 3d Bn. Hq. Co. and Hq. 35th Div. Tn. will load in one baggage car. Vet. Co. No. 110, F&amp;S 110th M. R. and Det. Div. Sur. O. will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 2. Co. A and 1st Bn. Hq. Co., will load in one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and F&amp;S 134th Inf. will load in one baggage car. Co. K will load in one baggage car. Co. L will load in one baggage car. Med. Dept. Det. and 2d Bn. Hq. Co. in one baggage car. . •[■" Movement No. 3. Co. C will reserve space for Band 110th M. R. Movement No. 5. Wag. Co. No. 120 and Med. Dept. Det., 35th Div. Tn. will load in one baggage car. Movement via Govt. Mot. Vehicle. 138th M. T. .Co. will transport the 119th M. R. Section personnel. C. O. 119th M. R. Section will see that the Artillery Repair Truck accompanies this movement. 2. TICKETS. Government Transportation Requests on the Railroad concerned "will be exchanged tor tickets at the local ticket office. Requests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. . 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT. Baggage cars to be set the day preceding the movement to per - mit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is neces - sary. Tourist, cars or coaches to be loaded in a quiet and orderly man - ner in ample time to permit trains to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based, in most instances, on last year's camp attendance. 4. BAGGAGE. 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each Tiassenger, consisting of trunks, barraek bags, bedding rolls, hand bag - gage, etc., (Par. 28 NGR 71 J. Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bills of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting. of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Govern - ment on Bills of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. ■■-!." </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, • By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, .■•■'. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG. USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 11, 1929 Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Passengers Carried on Transportation Requests, Annual En - campment, 1929. ' To: All Company Commandeis, All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. S, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 14, 1929, the following table will be used for the guidance of all Company Commanders to whom transportation requests are issued: Officers to Whom Company and Additional Passengers Requests Issued to be Carried 134th Infantry Capt. H. R. Wilson :....Regtl. Hq. Co., Field &amp; Staff, Omaha Capt. C. J. Ayers Service Co. (Less Service Detachment) Capt. J. Ned Allison Howiti er Co. 1st Lt. Leslie Yager, Jr ....Hq. Co. 1st Bn Capt. W. H. Achenbach Capt. Ray A. Thurman Co. A Capt. W. G. Utterback Capt. Wm. Schneider Co. B Capt. Dean E. Coonley Co. C. ..: Major F. H. Stoll Capt. B. B. Mlltonberger Co. D 1st Lt. Guy T. Davis .Hq. Cc. 2nd Bn. Major B. C. Grasborg Capt. Ora A. Eatwell ..Co. E Capt. L. R. Eby ....:.Co. F Capt. A. Rieber Co. G . Capt. A. F. Miller Co.H 1st Lt. Rolla C. Van Kirk Hq. Co. 3rd Bn Major E. M. Cline Capt. E. F. Hoke ...Co. I. ...Lt. Col. R. G. Douglas Capt. Claude Frimann Co., K Capt. H. F. Elsasser Co. L Capt. E. J. Geesen : Co.l M Major R. R. Ensor AttlMei. Detachment - .' '.. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35th Division Train 1st Lt. Howard R. Turner Hq. net. (Less Serv. Detachment) Major M. L. Poteet 1st Lt, H. H. Ellis 137th Mot. Tr. Co. Gapt B. Clarence Neff. 119th Wagon Co Capt. V. M. Hovis Capt. G. N. Henninger 120th Wagon Co Att. Med. Detach. 110th Medical Regiment W. O. L. C. Havlicek Band Sec, Service Co. Capt. S. W. Allord 110th Veterinary Co., F &amp; S Det. D. S. O. Capt. C. D Evans..... 130th Collecting Co Major J. N. Evans By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, rSP&amp; DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 11, 1929 Circular Letter 'No. 18 Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment, 1929. To: Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Government Transportation Request No. WQ is inclosed herewith, to cover railroad transportation (tickets) for your company to Ashland, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows, after the number of persons for whom transportation is required has been de - termined: a. Enter with pen, ink or indelible pencil under the block, "Num - ber of Persons", the total (aggregate) to be transported. b. Opposite "Est. cost $ ", enter the TOTAL cost. c. Signature of Responsible Officer with title thereunder on the lower right hand corner of the Request. : </seg>
            <seg id="p046">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL d. Postal card report (WO MB No. 36) will be completed as required thereon and turned in imn ediately upon arrival at camp to the USP&amp;DO, (Company Quartermaster's Office). 2. If, prior to the surrender of Transportation Request to the ticket agent, it be found necessary to aJtsr entries made thereon, such changes will be fully explained over your I ignature and rank in the blank space under par. 2 of the instructions an the reverse thereof. Postal card report required above must be absolutely correct, showing the number of persons actually travelling as members of your party. 3. In view of the fact that a 1 accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations when actually used, must be charged against the officer responsible for the error, the suggestion is made that, prior to leaving, you familiarize yourself with the provisions of NGR 70 and 71. 4. In addition to the above tl e conductor of each train is required to make a report in duplicate of the troops carried, which will be verified by the Officer in charge of the con pany, and signed by both. The dupli - cate copy of this report is to be given to the Officer in charge and will be sent to the Finance Officer, D. S. Army, Transportation Branch, Washington, D. C. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. . STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 12, 1929 Circular Letter No: 19 Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Annual Encampment, 1929. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 3, ] Nebraska Circular Letter No. 14 1929, Company Commanders will purchase the necessary subsistence for en- </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL listed men at not to exceed 40 cents per meal per man for tho time involved in travel only, e. g., contingents arriving at siding in A. M. one meal, those arriving in P. M. before 6:00 o'clock, 2 meals and the Howitzer Co., 134th Infantry, 3 meals. Balance of meals for first day will be Garrison Ration. 2. Public Vouchers, Standard Forms Nos. 1034 and 1034a, with ex - tra sheets, are inclosed for stating accounts due and must be accom - panied by invoices in duplicate. 3. To expedite the payment of vouchers attention is invited to the following : a. Complete the voucher in detail. b. Certificate, that account if correct — see note at bottom of Form 1034. . c. Certificate, that articles have been received, etc., to be signed by Company Commander and completed in accordance with No. 4 with the word "oral" opposite No. 4 on back of original and duplicate voucher. d. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across the fact of the voucher, "Travel Rations, Co , Refit, (so many) Enlisted Men (so many) Meals". e. The use of colored inks or carbon paper other than black and alterations or erasures will not be accepted. f. It is suggested that the subsistence be purchased from one firm to avoid delay in payment of vouchers to determine whether the amount authorized has been exceeded. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG. USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. ', STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 12, 1929 . Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1529. To: Officer Responsible for Same. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">' REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ is inclosed herewith for excess baggage (freight) involved in movement of your company to Ashland, Nebraska, which should bj completed as follows:.' a. Opposite "Est. Cost '$...'. ", insert the total actual cost after ascertaining same from the agent, upper right hand corner. b. Insert number of packages under column "Number and kind of packages" (see par. 40 b (7) NGR 71), and the total weight un - der column "Weights ". In case of M. G. and Ammunition Carts, or other wheeled material, add to Bill of Lading giving the' No., description and weights (se| par. 40 b (6) NGR 71). c. Insert length of car furnished, the date, initials and car number. 2. Bill of Lading will be disposed of as follows: a. Original and three memo. Copies to be signed by your 'local Agent. b. Shipping Order to be surrendered to local Agent. c. Original surrendered to At ent at Ashland, Nebraska, properly executed, under Consignee's Certificate of Delivery. d. Two memos to be immediately delivered to IT. S. Property and Disbursing Officer upon arrival at camp. . e. Retain one memo for company files. 3. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable rate for the purpose of transporting baggage and equip Ttent from the Armory to the Depot and return. Invoices in duplicate should be furnished this office with Public Voucher, Standard Form.Nts. 1034 and 1034a, properly executed for the incoming and return movement. These accounts must be in by the last of August so that settlement may be made on the whole, to see that this allowance has not been e tceeded. 4. Transportation will be provided by this Department for hauling organization equipment and baggage to the Rifle Range from the Sioux City-Ashland branch of the C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. on the DLD Highway. Im - mediately upon arrival, the Officers in charge of companies should desig - nate a baggage detail for handling this equipment and see that they stay there until the unloading is comple ed. By direction of the Gt vernor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 22, 1929 Circular Letter No. 21 W ■a Subject: Train Schedule, Return Movement, Annual Encampment, 1929. g To: All Company Commanders, Field &amp; Staff Officers, NNG. § 1. In accordance with Nebraska Circular Letter No. 14, 1929, the following Train Schedule is prescribed for the O return movement: ' ■■..... . ' j Location I Approx. I Bag. ■ . • ■ , tS Movements Organization No p ags c ar Schedule No. i 110 M. R. Band Crete | 24 | w/Cp.C Lv. Ashland Spl. Tn. CB&amp;Q c| CB&amp;Q I I 9:20 A. M. Aug. 19/29 g Dest. | | Ar. 11:27 A. M. 5 Co. C Beatrice 55 1 Ar. 12:30 P. M. -3 Co. M I Seward | 45 1 Ar. 12:10 P. M. O Serv. Co. lU4th York | 70 1 Ar. 1:00 P. M. • H Co. H : Grand Island| 56 1 Ar. 3:05 P. M. g Co. G Hastings 54 1 Ar. 2:55 P. M. « 137 M. T. Co. Holdrege 35 1 I Ar. 5:21 P. M. &gt; 120 Wag. Co. Kearney 45 1 Ar. 5:00 P. M. Med. Dept. Det. 12 35 Div. Tn. Co. B Falls City 56 1 Ar. 4:45 P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Movements Organization Locatiou | | Bag. Schedule No. 2 130 Uoll. Co. Columbus | 45 | 1 Lv. Ashland Spl. Tn. CB&amp;Q CB&amp;Q j i 11:00 A. M. Aug. 19/20 Fremont I Ar. 2:00 P. M. UP 119 Wag. Co. Lexington | 40 1 Ar. 6:45 P. M. JO • Dest. Co. D No. Platte | 61 1 ; Ar. 8:30 P.M. . g&gt; Howitzer Co. Gering | 47 1 j Ar. 11:15 A. M. Aug. 20,29 n • W I : . '_ § No. 3 Co. F Hartington |. 15 | 1 Lv. Ashland 11:17 A. M. ■ O CB&amp;Q ".'. CB&amp;Q Tn. No. 24 Aug. 19/29 •' Omaha ' | . Ar. 7:10 P.M. 1 H CStPM&amp;O Hq. Co. 1 Bn. . Nebr. City 23 1 Ar. 3:20 P. M. S ■ ■ , Dest. ; Co. A ■ ' | 52 | • ;• ' ■, .- ; . g No. 4 |Hq. Co, 3 Bn. Lincoln . I 24 Lv. Ashland 2:05 P. M. 2 CB&amp;Q j CB&amp;Q Tn. No. 7 Aug. 19/29 2 Dest. • Ar, 2:45 P. M. &gt; Co. I 55 1 ' • 2 . . ■ • 110 Vet. Co. 28 ■ 1 ' . ■■: ■ H Field &amp; Staff 5 . . O M. R. S Det. Dv. Sur. O. 9 g I Hq. 35 Dy, Tn. ' 10 . . . W Co. E Scottsbluff | 54 1 Ar. 3:21 P. M. Aug. 20 29' &gt; (x) i :■■■ r </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Movements Organization Location j *!*"*_ | Bag Schedule No. 5 Co. K Omaha 60 . 1 Lv. Ashland 4 : 00 P. M. CB&amp;Q CB&amp;Q Spl. Aug. 19/29 Omaha '. Ar. 4:50 P. M. MP Co. L . 59 1 • a Dest. Med. Dept. Det. : 30 . H 134 Inf. £ Regtl. Hq. Co. 50 . 1 2 Field &amp; Staff 7 H 134 Inf. o Hq. Co. 2 Bn. .27 I 1 *j Via | I X Government 130 Anib. Co. Hastings 45 Lv. Camp 7:00 A. M. H Motor .'■'.,. | Aug. 19/29 Ar. 3:00 P. M. . &gt; Vehicles Service Co. Lincoln 33 Lv. Camp 1:00 P. M. 2 110 M. R. ' Aug. 19/29 Ar. 3:30 P. M. • cj 166 Hosp. Co. I 55 Lv. Camp 1:00 P. M. £ | Aug. 19/29 Ar. 3:30 P. M. S 138 M. T. Co. Fremont I 48 I Lv. Camp 3:00 P. M. H 119 M. R. S. | 21 | Aug. 19/29 Ar. 7:00 P. M. O SS&amp;SD Lincoln I 21 I Lv. Camp 7:00 A. M. H | j Aug. 20/29 Ar. 10:00 A. M. 2 (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E (Scottsbluff). &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p052">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 1. Co. C and Band, :11O M. R. ( will use one baggage car, 120 Wag. Co., and Med. Debt. Det., 35 Div. Tn., will use one baggage car. Movement No, 3. Hq. Co. 1 Bn. and Co. A will use one baggage car. Movement No. 4. Co. I, Hq. Co. 3 ijn. and Hq. 35 Div. Tn. will use one baggage car. 110 Vet. Co. and Det. Div. Sur. O. will use one baggage car. Movement No. 5. Med. Dept. Det. £.nd Hq. Co. 2 Bn. will use one bag - gage car. Movement via Govt. Mot. Vehicle, bs M. T. Co. will transport the 119 M. R. S. personnel. C. O. 119 M. R. S. will see that the Artillery Repair Truck accompanies tlhis movement. 2. TICKETS. Government Transportation Requests on the railroad concerned will be exchanged for tickets at th ; Camp Quartermaster's Office Re - quests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for ac - commodations actually furnished. 3. BAGGAGE. 150 pounds of personal baggige will be transported free for each passenger. Excess baggage (freigh:) consisting of property, other than - checkable baggage will be handled i i baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bills ol Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from Camp to home stati n, at freight rates. 4. Passengers and organizations to be carried will be those that are shown in Nebraska Circular Letter No. 17, 1929. 5. Postal Card Report WD MB No. 36 will be mailed to the USP&amp;DO as soon as possible after securing i he signature of the conductor The report required by par. 4, Nebrask i Circular Letter No. 18 1929 must be mailed to the Finance Officer, Washington. D. C., as soon as possible. 6. Two memorandum copies ol Bill of Lading must be given to the </seg>
            <seg id="p053">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL USF&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to your departure. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, j The Adjutant General, Nebraska^ OFFICIAL: H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 24, 1929 Circular Letter No.22 j Subject: Nebraska Circular Letter No. 21, 1928. To: All Unit and Sub : unit Commanders. 1. The attention of all unit and sub-unit commanders is invited to Nebraska Circular Letter No. 21, July 16, 1928, and are notified that the provisions of this letter will be strictly adhered to this year. 2. Unit and sub-unit commanders will cause to be read Nebraska Circular Letter No. 21, 1928, to their respective commands upon the first meeting after the receipt ol" this letter and -will see that the require - ments set out therein are strictly complied with. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 31, 1929 Circular Letter m No. 23 . ' • • M Subject: Correction in Train Schedules, Annual Encampment 1929 W To: All Company Commanders, Field arid Staff Officers NNG O 1. Movement No. 3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 16, Train Schedule to Annual Encampment, 1929, Ashland, g Nebraska, is rescinded and the following substituted therefor: . gj . Movements \ Organization F~ C^ to^|^ n^rr?af~t : 1" ' : — : — I ; — : ' — ' ; g No. 3 Co. C Beatrice | 55 1 Lv. Beatrice Tn. No. 24 2 A C ? &amp; Q at 8:04 A. M. August H Ashland 5/29 • n Band, 110th M. R. Crete 24 Lv. Crete 9:02 A. M. gj ; : Ar. Ashland 11:17 A. M. | . . ■ &amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 2. Movement No. 5, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 21, Train Schedule, eRturn Movement, Annual Encampment, 1929, is rescinded and the following substituted therefor: Movements Organization Location Approx. Bag. .Schedule No. Pass. Car No. 5 Co. K • Omaha 60 1. Lv. Ashland 2:00 P. M. w CB&amp;Q CB&amp;Q, Tn. No. 38, August H Omaha . 19/29 % Co. L 59 1 Ar. 2:50 P. M. ■ M Med. Dept. Det. 30 .. H . 134th Inf. I O RegtI. Hq. Co. | 50 | 1 *1 Field &amp; Staff j 7. | 134th Inf. | S 2 Bn. Hq. Co. j 27 | 1 ' H • By direction of the Governor: g H. J. PAUL, OFriCIAL: The Adjutant General, &gt; H. C. Steinl Nebraska. Major, QMC-NNG, o USP&amp; DO— Nebraska @ </seg>
            <seg id="p056">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN _. , August 2, 1929 Circular Letter No. 24 - . '■.'■■'■ - • Subject: Mess. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Comn anders, NNG. 1. In checking over the Company Council Books by a representative of this office it was disclosed that it h;.s not been the policy of Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, who mess witi their respective commands to pay anything for their mess. 2. Inasmuch as rations are issue 1 for enlisted men only and that each meal an officer eats without paying for same is robbing his men of just that much; that it is required b^ regulations and a common seuse of fairness and justice, each officer eating at a company mess will be expected to pay the sum of $15.00 for same and paid at the beginning of camp. • . By direction of the Govenor: ,■•.; h. j. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NE BRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ....■ - -_. . •-■_ September 21, 1929 Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Requisition for New Uniforn s. » To: All Company and Detachmen: Commanders, NNG. 1. Requisition for the new Meltoi Cloth Uniforms should be sub - nutted to this office not later than October 20, 1929, based upon strength as shown m Nebraska Circular Letter No. 31, of 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Requisitions should be prepared in duplicate on Form QMC-51, the original to be forwarded to this office and only Coats and Breeches should be included. In that we have not received sufficient numbers of uniforms the 10% for stock cannot be authorized at this time. Actual measurements should be taken of each individual enlisted man, breast measurement for coat and waist and inseam measurement for breeches. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 23, 1929 . Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: Exchange of Uniform Clothing. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. 1. With reference to Militia Bureau Circular Number 03, dated July 31, 1929, a copy of which has been furnished all organizations, the following instructions will be carefully followed by all responsible of - ficers': a. The amount of clothing that may be replaced during any fiscal year will not exceed $1.30 per each enlisted man. Strength will be taken as of July 1 each year. b. The minimum shipping weight for articles to be turned in lor exchange is fixed at 100 lbs. as any amount less than this does not justify shipment on Government Bills of Lading. c. In no case will articles other than uniform clothing be sent in for exchange: d. Certificates as outlined in paragraph 2 of the above referred to circular must be furnished with each shipment and in addition one copy of QMC-Form 51 (requisition for clothing in bulk) showing sizes required for the replacement of articles shipped in. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. The provision for the replacement by certificate must be care - fully studied and care exercised so as to not exceed the 30c per man allowance as authorized. .: 3. In connection with this circular all responsible officers should study carefully provisions outlined in National Guard Regulations 75-7, dated July 1, 1929, the provisions of which are now in effect. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 27, 1929 Circular Letter No. 27 Subject: Repair, Renovation or Clotiing and Individual Equipment and Maintenance of Organization Equipment,' F. Y. 1930. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. 1. It is directed that you furnish this office, not later than October 26, 1929, separate estimates for the fallowing: a. Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment, (except the old woolen coits and breeches which will be re - placed by the New Melton Cloth Uniforms). b. Maintenance of Organizat: on Equipment, typewriters are to be submitted on a separate estimate giving serial number and make with width of carriage. 2. In no case will any obligation be incurred until estimate called for above has been approved by this office. 3. Major repairs of heavy tentage that Was left at camp, Ashland, Nebraska, will be repaired by the USP&amp;DO-Nebraska insofar as Federal </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Funds will permit, providing they have been tagged as requested during the Field Training Period. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. \ :■■■■■ ■ ■ • ■ .'■.'■.■ ■ ' - . ■ ' STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 2. 1929 Circular Letter No. 28 -. . ■■ ■' Subject: Examinations of Candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of. one enlisted man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive examination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office beginning November 5. 1929, at 9:00 A. M. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of the unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date, of admission, July 1, 1930; have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 18 and 22 years and must not be less than 5'4" in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot, be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an ap - plicant's eligibility. The requirements for admission to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the inclosed pamphlet. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 4, 1930, and the appointments available on July 1, 1930, will be awarded to the qualified candidate in the order of merit established at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. :•. • 4. Previously, applicants have presented themselves to this office to take this examination who were in no way qualified and could not </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL hope to pass the rigid examination given. Company Commanders will make any members of their command who have a desire, to take this examination conversant with the requirements of the inclosed pamphlet and while some believe that a High School graduate can pass this ex - amination, it has been demonstrated that unless they have had at least one year in college, in addition to their High School education, it will be time wasted. 5. No State Funds are avail ible for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. 6. The return of this pamph et is requested. If pamphlet is not inclosed, one may be had upon application. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 21, 1929 Circular Letter No. 29 Subject: Care and Preservatio no' U. S. Property. To: Officers Responsible for Same. 1. This office is in receipt oi: a communication from The Chief, Militia Bureau, on the above sub ect and the following extracts are quoted therefrom: ''The Militia Bureau considers that the supply situation in the National Guard has become a matter of great moment to all concerned, and that greater efforts must be exerted to con - serve the property now issued to National Guard troops. Up to the present time the money value of property which has been lost, stolen or damaged while in the hands of the National Guard has reached an appreciable sun , as evidenced by a compilation of many reports or survey in tie Militia Bureau. It is felt that coordinated effort should be riade to determine the reasons therefor and to suggest to State authorities and National Guard commanders proper precautions which may preclude the possi - bility of such losses in the future. "To this end the following juestionnaire, ♦ * * is furnished you with the idea that it may be used to advantage in future </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL armory inspections, * * • this questionnaire was filled in by the ■ : : inspector and the responsible officer was required to state over his signature whether he concurred iu the observations and con - clusions of the inspector." ■ 1 "Questionnaire, a. Facilities. (1) Does the armory afford adequate protection against fire, elements and theft to United States property? (2) Are the locker rooms so located that armory em - ployees may have knowledge of persons entering the same? (3) Are exterior windows of locker and store rooms pro - tected by iron bars? (4) Are doors to locker and store rooms so protected? (5) Has all wheeled transportation been properly cleaned,' greased and painted? (6) Have all weapons been properly cleaned and those in storage properly oiled? 2. In order that the Militia Bureau may be advised, it is requested that you answer this questionnaire, by November 15, 1929, and this office will appreciate any suggestions that you may have toward solving the problem presented. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: • H. C. Stein, Major, QMC-NNG, Nebraska; STATE OF NEBRASKA ~ ' ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 25, 1929 Circular Letter No. 30 Subject: Members of National Guard in Employ of Railroads. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-unit Coi inlanders, NNG. It is requested that the following information be furnished this office at once: 1. How many men in your command are in the employ of the railroads? 2. By what railroad, giving the number, are they employed? 3. What, if any, pay is allowed these men by the railroad com - pany during their attendance at Camp? 4. Is any difficulty experienced by your men in obtaining leave from the railroad or railroads to attend Camp? . ■ 5. If you have members of y&lt; ur command working for different railroads, give the number vorking for each and the above requested data. By direction of the Gov ;rnor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENER; lL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN - ■ •' : . -December 2, 1929 Circular Letter No. 31 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. ; 1. There are inclosed herewith blank ■ efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 3:., 1929, which should have your im - mediate attention. . .._']' 2. After giving a thorough stm.y to instructions contained in par. 74, Changes 1, NGR 20, dated January 1, 1929, make out your reports and forward same without delay to the officer to whom directed., 3. The reports should reach tin? office before the expiration of the </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL month. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Uet us all attl them in, in proper form, and AT ONCE. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 17. 1!)29 Circular Letter. No. 32 ■ • ; Subject: Economy in use of I'iank Forms. To: All Field, Staff, Company and Detachment Officers, NNG Aneniion is invited to the following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, with reference to econmy in use of blank forms. This has be - come a very serious question and rigid economy must be practice'! from fhis time on along this line: "1. Ii is deemed advisable to invite attention to (he absolute nec - essity lor .strict economy in the use of blank forms by the National Guard during this fiscal year. The allotment to the Militia Bureau from yi\e "VVar Department appropriation -for Printing and Binding is less this year than that tor the fiscal year 1929, and considerably less than for previous years. ■ 1'nless there is a very considerable reduction in the Quantity of blank forms ordered on requisitions by the National Guard,- it is feared the Bureau will be placed in the embarrassing position of beinp: unable ■to liieet the demands of the states due to lack, of funds. ■■ •■■■ .. ";■: ' . ■■■■ \ : . I ;■ 2. The purpose of this communication is, therefore, in the nature of an appeal to the State authorities for their help and cooperation in the matter, Many requisitions received in this office call for large quan - tities of forms, especially Form 367, Standard Forms 1013d and 1013e, M. B. Forms Nos. 67, 62, 337 and 367c, which appear to be out of pro - portion to actual needs as viewed by the Bureau. In this connection attention is invited to Militia Bureau Circular No. 13. dated April 22, 1929, relative to the use of pay roll forms. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. The responsibility for cutting requisitions should not be placed on the Militia Bureau. However, cuts must be made in all cases when requisitions are excessive. 4. The Bureau is in sympathy with, the difficulties -and problems which must be met by National G lard authorities, and desires to assist the states in every way. It therefore does "not wish to reduce the issue of blank forms too closely, but its purpose is to avoid unnecessary wast - age. Your cooperation in this matter is earnestly requested. E. R. Redmond, .Colonel, Spec. Res., Acting Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT '■'., LINCOLN December 18, 1929 Circular Letter No. 33 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books, 1929. To: All Commanders Responsible tor Same. 1. Company Council Books wi 1 be closed on December 31, 1929, in accordance with instructions contained in Nebraska Circular Letter No. 3, February 28, 1929, and will be sent immediately to Major H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Lincoln, Nebraska, who will audit and return same, making report, to this office of any discrepancies found. 2. Attention is invited to the following: a. Nebraska Circular Lettt r No. 24, August 2, 1929, re - quired that each officei eating at a company mess should pay $15.00 to tins fund. b. State pay for Annual Field Training is not' to be run through the Council Books. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. Itemized bills for expenditures, and certificates for re- • ceipts, are required. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 24, 1929 Circular Letter No. 34 Subject: Service Medals. To: Members of Nebraska National Guard. 1. As provided in our new military code this state has now procured and is ready to deliver service medals to all members of Nebraska Na - tional Guard who have had five or multiples of five years of service, i. e., five, ten, fifteen, twenty, or twenty-five years. 2. It is suggested that unit and sub-unit commanders make appli - cation for. all members of the unit or sub-unit who are entitled to these service medals and forward to this office. A check will be made of the service records in this office and then the service medals will be for - warded to the unit or sub-unit commanders for distribution. 3. In distributing these service medals it is suggested that a cere - mony be made of same. One way would be to have the mayor, presi - dent of the Chamber of Commerce, or one of your leading citizens pre - sent the medals at a meeting where all members are present. As much publicity as possible should be given to this meeting and it is requested that a copy of same be furnished this office. 4. While members of the National Guard are entitled to wear this medal or service bar at all times when in uniform, attention is invited to AR 600-40, section V, par. 49, sub-pars, g and h, which read as fol - lows: "(g) Authorized uniforms but not on the white mess jacket nor on civilian clothes. Badges of societies will not be worn with decora - tions, service medals, or substitutes therefor, except at meetings, cere - monies, or functions of such societies." "(h) The wearing of decora- </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. tions, service medals, or miniatures on civilian clothes should be limited to ceremonial occasions, and then only when strictly appropriate to the occasion." It is also suggested that m ;mbers of the Nebraska National Guard familiarize themselves with all of section V, quoted above in part, as a knowledge of this section will sav: members embarrassment in not attaching to the uniform many unautl orized badges when. in the mili - tary service. 5. The service to be figured in ob gaining these medals must be Na - tional Guard Service, or service connected therewith, i. e., if a member •went into the World War as a member of the National Guard he would be entitled to compute all World War Service as such. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The AdjuU.nt General. Nebraska. STATE OP NE BRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN v : ' February 1, 1930 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Requisition for Blank Forms and Publications. Form No. 22, NNG. (Ed. Jan. 21, 1930), To: All Responsible Officers. NNG. 1. Officers responsible for Requisitions for Blanl: Forms and Pub - lications will use the new form referred to above (supply inclosed) tor future requisitions and destroy all torn s now on hand &gt;f former editions. 2. The revision of this form became necessaty on account of changes in form numbers, some of wh ch are as follovs: a. Statement of Charges, A.C .O. 36, is now Statement of Property Lost, etc.. MB 18. b. Armory Drill Pay Rolls' MI! 367 and 367a o the new form (which comes in sets if 1 original and 4 memos) 367-367d: 367a-367e and 367 3-:i67f. c. Individual Clothing and Equipment Record A.G.O. ::2 and 33 to the Individual E luipment Record. MB 30. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL o. Certificate of Transfer of Pay Roll Information, MB 367c to Report or Transfer, MB 367c (Ed. July 1, 1929). e. Special Measuring Blank. QMC 50, is not authorized for NG. 3. The loaning of forms from one unit to another must stop itn - medfately as the amounts used are charged to the companies concerned and the units are judged from the amounts they use (see Nebraska Cn - . cular Letter No. 32, 1929). . During the last requisition period several companies asked for twelve to sixteen sets of Pay Rolls for the quarter, which would be a sufficient supply for three to four years. 4. Non-commissioned officer's warrants, NNG 13, should be fur - nished by the Regimental or similar headquarters properly filled out when the appointment . is made. The Discharge and Dishonorable Dis - charge, MB 5G and 57, will only be furnished upon approval of conviction by reviewing authority. 5. These requisitions must be submitted at the time as shown in the note at the bottom of the form and should cover the requirements for the coming quarter (three months supply); requisitions received after that date will be returned unfilled. By direction- of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, • The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Februay 7. 1930 Circula Letter No. 2 Subject: Requisitions for Supplies and Equipment. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with instuctions received from the Militia Bureau to the effect that all unobligated, funds allotted to this State for sup - plies and equipment will lapse on March 31, 1930, it will be necessary to submit, not later than March 15, 1930, requisitions covering quarter - master, ordnance, signal, medical and engineer property required by your organization for the balance of the fiscal year 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. No requisitions received after the date set forth in paragraph 1 will be honored. By direction of the Govenor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF N: DBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 17, 1930 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Modification of Nebraska Circular Letter No. 2d, September 23, 1929. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. 1. The policy of exchanging articles of uniform clothin? as outlined in the above referred to Nebraska Circular Letter is modifiel as follows: a. No exchanges of uniform clothing will be made at the State Arsenal except upon receipt of prior author - ity from this office. b. Articles of uniform cloth ng that have becomu un - serviceable through fair xrt ar and tear must be placed • on an I. &amp; I. Report and su Dmitted to this office cl irect. c. AH articles of Quartermaster equipment, regardless of whether or not it is cl Hiring or other equip nent, can be placed on one I. &amp; I. Report. In this connec - tion, attention is invited to the provisions in NGIt 75-7 which governs classes of property that may be placed on an I. &amp; I. Report. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, '..'•■•; Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 28, 1930 Circular Letter ■...'. No. 4 Subject: Receipts and Disbursements, Soldiers Memorial Hall. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders and All Officers of the Ne - braska National Guard. There is submitted herewith a statement of receipts and disburse - ments of monies connected with the construction ol Soldiers Memorial Hall, Ashland, Nebraska, for the information of all concerned: RECEIPTS Returned by units ..$26,831.12 Other funds from Federal Government 2,670.61 Interest Lincoln Trust Company 724.73 Interest National Bank of Commerce 491.25 Interest Peoples Savings &amp; Loan Company.... 187.69 . Legislative Appropriation 5,000.00 $35,905.40 DISBURSEMENTS Meginnis &amp; Schaumberg, Architects $ 1,519.65 Wilson. Bros., Contractors 26,147.00 Yoho Electric, Contractors : 1,684.00 Central Bridge &amp; Construction Company 2,312.00 All-Steel Office Equipment, Chairs 2,110.00 $33,772.65 Balance on Hand $ 2,132.75 H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. ■ ■■■'.'■'■ ' ' ."'■"■■' ■ ■".'■■ ■ .... - . ■ ■ ■ j * ' . i </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF THE AD; UTANT GENERAL, STATE OF N 3BRASKA • ADJUTANT GENERA VS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN .-. .March 25, 19M0 Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Target Pratt ice, Small Ann, ltioO. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. COURSES TO BE FIRED. The following courses only are au thorlzed during the year 193&lt;&gt;. For rifle practice: Cou:se D, T. R. 150-10. For machine gun practice: Course B, T. H. 150-3 i, "For pistol practice: Dismounted course, T. R. ] 50-20.' 2. RECORD PRACTICE. RTecor 1 practice, for rifles, machine Runs and pistols will be fired during the 1130 neld training peril d. Organiza - tions will complete I he preparatory exercises and instruction practice at their home ranges. No instruction- practice except a Hinited number of sighting shots will be permitted during the field trainir g period. ■). PREPARATORY INSTRUCTI )X AND PRACTICE. No man will be permitted to fire record practice with the rifle, pistol or machine gun. who has not completed the prepara ory exercises prescribed in T. R. 150-5, 150-10 and 150-35, and who has not fired sufficient instruction prac - tice to demonstrate his ability to apply the principles taiigit in the pre - paratory execises. * . ■I. RECORDS OF PROGRESS C F INSTRUCTION. .Marksmanship (Preparatory) forma to show the state of instruction of individuals be - fore starting practice, and in additicn score books for rifle instruction practice, and score cards for rifle, pistol and machine ;uns, will be mailed to unit commanders on requisition.- Regimental and company commanders will require that these je kept in the manner required by Training Regulations, and regimental commanders will require thai these markmanship records, certified by the company commands r. be brought to camp and submitted to their resi ective regimental corimanders not later than August 5, 1930. 5. AMMUNITION. a. Ammunition allowances tiat may be expended at home sta - tions for instruction practice will not exceed the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Unit Cal. .30 Cal. .45 Machine Gun Company 12000 2000 Rifle Company 6000 600 Hq. Company, Inf. Regt 1200 2000 . Service Company, Inf. Regt 3600 2000 Howitzer Company 1200 2000 Hq. Company, Inf. Bn... 2400 500 Hq. Det., Div. Tn 1200 500 Wagon Company ! 4800 400 Motor Transport Company 3600 300 Motor Repair Section _...... None 1000 b. Company commanders should submit requisitions for the am - munition required for instruction practice. INITIAL ALLOWANCE AM - MUNITION MUST NOT BE USED. 6. TARGET RANGES. The attention of all organization command - ers is called to the provisions of NGR 69 and NGR 78. Company com - manders desiring ranges should submit to this office so that Iease3 may be furnished and the instructors on duty with the unit may make the inspection as required. 7. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 5, March 29, 1929, is hereby revoked. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT ' LINCOLN March 27, 1930 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Charts for Company Administration. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. There is inclosed herewith 3 sets of Charts showing Titles and Forms, use and disposition of same, which should be studied carefully and followed closely so as to avoid unnecessary correspondence. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF THE ADJ JTANT GENERAL 2. These have been prepared after a careful study of the Regula - tions and will be a great time saver for Responsible Officers. 3. The Charts are as follows: a. PROPERTY RECORDS OF A RESPONSIBLE OF - FICER—Edited March 25, L930. b. RECORDS OF AN ENLISTED MAN— Edited March 20, 1930. c. RECORDS INVOLVED IN QUALIFICATION OF ARMS— Edited March 12, 1930. 4. These Charts supersede all Charts on these subjects and those of previous dates should be destroyed . ■ . . Bq direction of the Goverior: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, , ■ Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA • ADJUTANT GENERAl/S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 28, 1930 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Armory Drill Pay Rolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Cor inlanders, NNG. The following telegram from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY ALL INSTRUCTIONS RE - QUIRING CARBON COPY OF ARMORY DRILL PAY ROLLS BE SENT TO CHIEF MILITIA BUREAU ARE DESCINDED ROLLS WILL BE PREPARED IN QUADRUPLICATE AND DIS - POSED OF AS PRESCRIBED IN INSTRUCTIONS ON FORM THREE SIX SEVEN F EXCEPT COPY OF CHIEF MILITIA BUEAU WILL NOT BE REQUIRED. EVERSON WASHINGTON DC." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL '■';,';■' STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 1, 1930 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Mothers' Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The second Sunday m May having been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization who may be separated from their motehrs on May 11, the duty which they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mothers' Day. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN i May 23, 1930 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1931. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, pertaining to the above-named subject is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of drills to be held during the Fiscal Year 1931, will be limited as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p074">REPORT OF THE AD; UTANT GENERAL. (a) During the first and se cond quarters (July 1 to Dec. 31, 1930, incl.), not to exceed twenty-four (24) Federal pay drills. (b) During the third quarter (Jan. 1 to March 31, 1931, incl.), not to exceed twelve (12) Federal "pay drills, in addition to any part o : the 24 drills not held dur - ing the first and second quarters. (c) During the fourth quarter (April 1 to June 30, 1931, incl.). not to exceed twe ve (12) Federal pay drills, in addition to any part of the thirty-six (3fi) drills not held during the first, second and third quarters. (d) In no event will the number of drills for which pay - ment is made with Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty -eight (48) during the fiscal year, for any'.orj anization of the National Guard. W. H. Waldron, Colonel, Infantry, M. B. For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The- Adjutant General. .',';• Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJTTANT GENERA VS DEPARTMENT . . LINCOLN June 5, 1930 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Squaw Camp. To: AH Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. In asmuch as several applicants fir a ten house in the Squaw Camp changed their minds last year after having made application for same and as there will only be ten (10) tent houses available this year, the following rules will be adhered to by those desiring ten houses: </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OK THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (a) $15.00 will be charged each family occupying a tent house for all or any part of camp. In case more than one family occupies a~ lent house $15.00 will be charged each family. (b) Requests for tent houses will be accompanied by a check for $15.00. (c) In case a tent house is ordered by an officer and he later finds it will be impossible to use same it will be up to that officer to sub-let it to some other officer. (d) No enlisted men's families will be accorded the privileges of the Squaw Camp. (e) Tent ■ houses will be awarded applicants in the order re - ceived and when the ten (10) have been applied lor further applications with inclosed checks will be returned to applicants. By direction of the Governor: ■ H. J. PAUL, l The Adjutant General. ; Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 11, 1930 Circular Letter No! 11 '.; ■ Subject: Erroneous Credits for- Armory Training. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. - The following letter from the Chief', Militia Bureau, pertaining to the above named subject is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. The Chief of Finance has again called the attention ol" the Bureau to the unusual number of suspensions appearing in the accounts of U. S. Army Finance Officers charged with the payment of armory drill pay in cases where officers and enlisted men were credited with being actually present at .an armory drill held by the organization just </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL prior to its departure from its home s tat on for field training where in fact such officers and enlisted men were at the time on a Federal pay status with the advance detachment at the camp. 2. In order to eliminate such suspensions in the future, it is re - quested that the following instructions be brought to the attention of all organization commanders, and others charged with the preparation, certification, or approval of armory drill ;jay rolls: When an individual has been detached from his organization and is in a Federal pay status during any pan of the period covered by the payroll, the inclusive dates of such services will be shown opposite the name of the individual concerned. This is applicable to duty at schools with the Regular Army and especially tj duty at training camps as members of the Advance Detachment, Carip Supply Detachment, or the Rear Detachment. The inclusive dates during which the organization as a whole was in a Federal pay status at the annual encmpment is shown in the affidavit. Form 367, and neec not be repeated opposite the nines of the individuals concerned. For the Chief, Militia Bureau: W. H. WALDRON, Colonel, Infantry, M. B. Executive." By direction of the Governor: . H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRi* SKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S D EPARTMENT LINCOLN • . June 25, 1930 Circular Letter No. 12 . • ;■ ..", Subject: Return of Strnegth as of June 3d,. 1930. To: All Unit and Sublunit Commanders, NNG. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau, to submit a Return of Strength on the evening of Juni 30. 1930, therefore all unit </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL and sub-unit commanders are requested to wire this office their strength Monday A. M., June 30, In order that we may compile same and forward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, that day. 2. The following form of telegram, giving officers and enlisted men separately, should be used: "Co. A, three officers, sixty-three enlisted men. (Signed' Smith, Captain." By direction of the Governor: • H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 3. 1930 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1930. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The dates Of the annual encampment, 1930, having been set, i. e., August 4 to 18, 1930, inclusive, no organization will be excused from at - tending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section III, NGR 45, 1927. At this •point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non-compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of Company Officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to the exact hour of departure from home station, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation requests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company Commanders are authorized to purchase subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 40c per meal and will follow instruc - tions received from the USP&amp;DO pertaining thereto. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">REPORT OP THE ADJl TANT GENERAL 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume command of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained, i. e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The Commanding Officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at cam;), and report to the Camp Com - mander immediately upon arrival any defects or faults found with rail - roads transporting troops. Each Company and Detachment Commander upon arrival at detraining point will irimediately report to Transporta - tion Officer with reference to baggage detail. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat i:ords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoe?. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Com - pany-Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing —to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear it on leaves or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. . 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Training Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet ar - ticles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the bs.rrack bag. Company Command - ers should check each enlisted man to see that .he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth b -ush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., ;otton breeches and O. D. shirt. Any Company Commander, failing to brii g mosquito bars will be required to have same brought in later by express at his own expense. Cotton , blouses and new Melton Cloth uniform will not be brought to camp. All old style service caps will be brought to camp and turned in to the Camp Quartermaster. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess bag - gage (freight) organization equipment a id cleaning materials. . Informa - tion pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment and harness will be furnished in a separate Circular Letter. No target materials will be brought to camp as it will be furnished there. No canvas cots will be brought to camp. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except the initial allowances, 1930, and the cal. .22 long rifle, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP&amp;DO, securing memorandum receipt for same; all empty cartridges (brass) in packing boxes, aiming devices, arm racks and lockers sufficient for men in camp, rifles, bayonets and pistols for same and all other </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ordnance with which the individual and companies are equipped. The Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only sufficient ammunition to be used in the conduct of its fire on the range. 9. Special Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer property, including lister bags, is to be carried. . 10. Record. All records and office supplies will be taken, i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, Morn - ing Reports, all text books, all blank- forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in quadruplicate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. Telegraphic reports of strength when entraining are NOT required. 11. Messes. All Company Officers will mess with their organization and should provide themselves with tables and chairs. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, Q.M.C., will establish Officers' messes for the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned there - to for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch, at noon, August 4, 1930. 12. Enlisted Men's Motor Transportation. No motor transportation will be permitted in the enlisted men's camp area. Enlisted men bringing motor transportation to camp will be required to register and to have passes for same going in and out of the grounds from where they will be parked on the south side of the main highway and where they will . will be required to stay from taps until 4:00 P. M. 13. Any equipment other than enumerated above, which becomes excessive equipment, brought to camp will have to be paid for by the Unit Commander bringing or permitting same to be brought (M. B. file 554.4, Gen-80, November 7, 1929, Subject: Transportation of Equipment to Camp). By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOI N July 3, 1930 Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Transportation, Field Trainirg, 1930. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. . 1. MOUNTS. Mounts will be furnished to the respective organiza - tions as follows: a. State 7 Officers, 3 Orderlies, 1 Senior Instr., Staff 1 for The Governor 134th 1 Col., 1 U. Col., 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., Inf. 1 Aux. Bn. Adj., 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T., 4 Orderlies (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hq.) 35th 1 C. O., 1 Adj M 1 S. O.. 1 Orderly, 4 to ea. Div. Tn. Wag. Co. (1 ea. Officer and 1 Orderly) 1 to Med. Dept. Det. 110th 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 2 Majors (P. &amp; T. Veter- Med. inarian D. S. O.), 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, Regt. 2 Orderlies b. The responsible officers for the following sub-units will fur - nish riding equipment with grain and :'eed bags: State Maj. W. E. McConnaughey, 13 sets Staff 134th C. O. Regi nental Hq. Co., 6 sets Inf. C. O. Battalion Hq. Cos. 3 sets, each C. O. Serv ce Co., 2 sets C. O. Med. Dept. Det., 1 set </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35th C. O. 119th Wag. Co., 4 sets D v- Tn. C. O. 120th Was. Co., 4 sets C. O. Headquarters Det., 4 sets C. O. Att. Med. Det., 1 set 110th Med. Regt. C. O. Service Co., 8 sets 2. MULES, DRAFT. Mules will be assigned as follows: a. Camp Quartermaster _. 4 134th Infantry M. G. Companies 4 each Howitzer Company 2 Service Company 20 35th Div. Train 119th Wagon Co 20 120th Wagon Co 20 b. Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows: USP&amp;DO — AH harness and wagons required for Service Com - pany, 134th Infantry, Wagon Companies of the 35th Division Train and Camp Quartermaster. The C. O.s of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Company will furnish the necessary harness for the animals assigned them. 3. MOTOR VEHICLES. . a. USP&amp;DO will transport all available trucks and ambulances stored at the State Arsenal to Camp. b. The Commanding Officer, Hq. Co., 2d Bn., will detail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting Class B Library Truck so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 4, not later than 9:00 A. M. Drivers will report to Camp Transportation Officer immedi - ately upon their arrival. 4. All organizations having Governemnt owned motr vehicles as - signed them will, immediately after arrival in Camp and unloading of equipment, have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Officer to be placed in the camp pool for the duration of camp. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCO LN July 3, 1930 Circular Letter '. No. 15 Subject: Subsistence Allowance to Amual Encampment. To: All Company and Detachme it Commanders, 'NNG. 1. In accordance with par. :;, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13, 1930. Company Commanders will purchase the necessary subsistence for en - listed men at not to exceed 40 cents er meal per man for the time in - volved in assembling, travel ami arriv il at camp. Balance of meals lor first day will be Garrison Ration. 2. Public Vouchers. Standard Foims No. 1034 and No. 1034a, with extra sheets, are enclosed for statins it-counts due and must be accom - panied by invoices in duplicate. ?,. To expedite the payment of vcuchers attention is invited. lo the following: a. Insert Payee's name and addrt ss. b. Complete the Voucher in deta 1 as to date of delivery, articles, quantity, unit price with cost a ad per unit with the amounts and the total. c. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across ihe face of the voucher. "Travel Rations, Co ; , Regt., (so many) enlisted men (so many) meals". d. The use of colored inks or carbon paper other than black and alterations or erasures will no. be accepted. e. It is suggested that the subsistence be purchased from one firm to avoid delay in payment of VDtichers to determine whether the amount authorized has been exceeded. f. Have Payee sign the c'ertifieati? "I certify that the above bill is correct", etc. See • note the bottom of Voucher. g. Certificate, that articles have b?en received, etc., to be signed by Company Commander and con pleted in accordance with No. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL with the word "oral" opposite No. 4 on back of original and duplicate Voucher. h. The report listed at bottom must be filled in and signed and turned in with Voucher. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Major. QMC-NNG, rSP&amp;DO-Nebraska. Organization : :...:......... Home Station I Period of Travel (Show date and hour of assembly) Show date and hour of arrival- at Camp : Name (Signed by C. O.) Rank and Branch </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Circular Letter July 3 - l^ 30 No. 16 Subject: Train Schedule to Annual Encampment, 1930, Ashland, Nebraska. To: AH Company Commanders, Field &amp; Staff Officers, NNG. W 1. In accordance with Nebraska Circular Letter No, 13, 1930, the following Train Schedule is prescribed: g Movements Organization Locatlon . | j}f p r °* s | ?£* Schedule O . , . ' ■ ' ; ! ; O No. 1 ' 3d Bn. Hq. Co. Lincoln 22 1 Lv. Lincoln Train No. 8 K CB&amp;Q »" Co. I 43 at 7:55 A. M. Aug. 4/30 H Ashland 110th Vet. Co. . 20 . Ar. Ashland 8:33 A.. M. . &gt; Field &amp; Staff • g 110th M, R. — I- 1 : cT Det. D. S. O. • . H Hq. 35th Dv. Tn. 2 No 2- Co B Falls City | 45 | 1 Lv. Falls City Train No. o •MP ■ I 109 4:42 A. M. Aug. 4/30 ■ W Omaha Co. A Nebr. City j 48 1 Lv. Nebr. City 6:00 A. M. Z CB&amp;Q Hq. Co. 1st Bn. | 21 S Ashland Field &amp; Staff Omaha Lv. Omaha Special &gt; 134th Inf. • Train 9:15 A. M. K Regtl. Hq. Co. 32 1 Ar. Ashland 10:05 A. M.. Co. K 46 1 . . Co. L | 58 1 Med. Dept. Det. j 15 134th Inf. . I ' Hq. Co. 2d Bn. | 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Movements Organization L ° cation | £™™L j Bag. Sched ule No. 3 120 th Wag. Co. Kearney 44 1 Lv. Kearney Train No. 18 CB&amp;Q Med. Dept. Det. at 6:30 A. M. Aug. 4/30 Ashland Co. G Hastings 47 1 Lv. Hastings Train No. 24 • • at 7:50 A. M. Aug. 4/30 W Co C Beatrice 52 1 Lv. Beatrice 8:29 A. M. H Aug. 4/30 &#132; O Band, 110 th M. R. Crete 17 | . Lv. Crete 9:25 A. M. JO • j 8/4/30, Ar. Ashland 11:17 ; O No 4 Co E Scottsbluff 47 1 Lv. Scottsbluff Train No. 32 "9 CB&amp;Q (x) 10:07 P. M. Aug. 3/30 g Ashland ' Ar. Lincoln 1:00 P. M. 8 '4 * Lv. Lincoln Train No. 38 at 1:20 P. M. 5 . Ar. Ashland 2:00 P. M. «-. . ■ Q No 5 Co. H Grand Islandl 54 1 Lv. Grand Island Train No. 2 £ CB&amp;Q I at 9:53 A. M. Aug. 4/30 2 Ashland Serv. Co. 134 th Inf. York I 45 1 Lv. York 11:17 A. M. Co. M Seward 35 Lv. Seward 12:10 P. M. O J Ar. Ashland 2:00 P. M. H to &gt; tr 1 85 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">Movements Organization Location | Approx. Bag. Schedule I No. Pass. Car No. 6 Howitzer Co. Gerlng 53 1 Lv. Gering Train No. 54 UP ' (x) at 3:50 P. M. Aug. 3/30 Fremont Ar. North Platte 9:10 P. M. CB&amp;Q L V | North Platte Train No. 4 a Ashland at 10:50 P. M., Ar. Fremont H 5:05 A. M. Aug. 4/30 g Co. D No. Platte 58 1 Lv. No. Platte 7:50 A. M. W Train No. 16 Aug. 4/30 H 119th Wag. Co. Lexington 41 1 Lv. Lexington Train No. 1G O """ '.'".••• Ar. Fremont 2:16 P. M. &gt;3 130th Coll. Co. Columbus | 43 . 1 Lv. Columbus 8:40 A. M. £ 8/4/30, Ar.. Fremont 9:52 ra A. M. Train No. 38. Lv. Fremont f. ■ ■ - I Special Train CD&amp;Q g I ~~ at 2:45 P. M. =T Ar. Ashland 3:30 P. M. , ■ ' £ No. 7 Co. F Hartlngton | 41 | . 1 Lv. Hartington Special H CStP&amp;O .;•- . | . j Train 8:00 A.M. 8/4/30 O Omalla I Lv. Emerson 10:10 A. M. g | Train No. 1. 8/4/30 2 i.| Ar. Omaha 1:10 P. M., Lv. h . l| Omaha 4:15 P. M. Train No. 37 g ; ; I I Ar. Ashland 5:06 P. M. r </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 Movements ' I. Prwniaation LocaUou | J*| g' Schedule Via iSOtli Amb. Co. Hastings VI . Lv. Hastings 7:00 A. M. Government 8/4/30, Ar. Ca.np 3:00 1\ M. Motor Service Co. Lincoln ::!» Lv. Lincoln 7:00 A. M. S/4/30 Vehicles ■ llOlh M. It. ■ ' Ar. Camp 9:30 A. M. W lGtilJi Hpisp. Co. &lt;&gt; :: • S . I i::st.h M. T. Co. ■ Krcnioni l(i ; Lv, Frojuont . r &gt;:00 A. M. o 119th A1. : R. Sen! Krcnioni IT, 8 /-I '".(I, Ar. Camp .0:00 A. M. pa \ 137th M 'I'. Co. Hohln'Rc :;T | -Lv; Holdrege 3:00 AIM. | 8/1 30, Ar. Camp 5:110 r. M. O SS*SD Lincoln I-v. Lincoln 7:00 A. M. ■ | | [' 8/3/30 Ar. Camp 10:00 A. M. H (x) Tourist cars will bo rcquiri'il Tor I lowitzor Company (&lt;!rriup) ami Co. K (Scot tshliifT). ~~ B z &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p088">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Movement No. 1. Co. I, Hq. Co., 3d. ]3n., 134th Inf., and 110th Vet. Co., will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 2. Co. A and Hq. Co., 1st Bn., will load in one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co. and Med. Dept. Det. will load in one baggage car. Co. K and Hq. Co., 2nd Be., will load in one baggage car. Co. L will load in one baggage ca : Movement No. 3. Co. C will reserve space for Band, 110th M. R. 12oth Wag. Co. and Med. Dept. Det., 35th Dv. Tn., will load in one baggage car. 2. TICKETS Government Transportation R« quests on the railroad concerned will be exchanged for tickets at the local ticket office. Requests for berths will be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommoda - tions actually furnished. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT Baggage cars are to be set tin; day preceding the movement to permit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is necessary. Tourist cars or coaches ire to be loaded in a quiet and Orderly manner in ample time to per nit trains to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based on last year's trans - portation requests. 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personal, baggs.ge will be transported freo for each passenger, consisting of trunks, Darrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, etc. (par. 28 NGR 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggaee will not be included on Bill of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Govern - ment on Government Bill of Lading, covering such impedimenta for - warded from each station, at freight ates. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 5, 1930 Circular Letter ■ No. 17 Subject: Passengers Carried on Transportation Requests, Annual En - campment, 1930. To: All Company Commanders, All Field &amp; Staff Officers, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 2, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13, 1930, the following table will be used for the guidance of all Company Com - manders to whom transportation requests are issued: Officers to Whom Company and Additional Passenbers Requests Issue to be carried i , . 134th Infantry Capt. A. L. McGill Regtl, Hq. Co., Field &amp; Staff, Omaha Capt. C. J. Ayers.-i: Service Co. (Less Service Detachment) Capt. A. F. Hinze .Howitzer Co. 1st Lt. Leslie Yager, Jr .Hq. Co. 1st Bn Capt. W. H. Achenbach Capt. Ray A. Thurman Co. A Capt. W. G. Utterback Capt. M. F. Myers .....Co. B Capt. Dean E. Coonley. Co. C Major F. H. Stoll Capt. B. B. Miltonberger Co. D 1st Lt. Guy T. Davis Hq. Co. 2nd Bn Major B. C. Grasborg Capt. Ora Eatwell Co. E Capt. L. R. Eby Co. F Capt. Ivan C. Riley Co. G Capt. Edgar Barratt Co. H 1st Lt. Rolla C. VanKirk Hq. Co. 3rd Bn Major E. M. Cline Capt. E. F. Hoke Co. I Lt. Col. R. G% "Douglas Capt. Claude. Frimann Co. K Capt. H. F. Elsasser ...Co. L Capt. E. J. Geesen.. Co. M . Major R. R. Ensor Med. Dept. Detachment 35th Division Train 1st Lt. Howard R. Turner Hq. Det. (Less Serv. Det.) Maj. M. L. Poteet Capt. M. O. Bates 119th Wagon Co. Capt. G". N. Henninger 120th Wagon Co Med. Dept. Detachment 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">REPORT OF THE ADJ JTANT GENERAL 110th Medical Regiment W. O. L. C. Havlicek .Band Sec, Service Co. Capt. S. W. Alford... 110th Veterinary Co., F &amp; S Det. D. S. O. Capt. C. D. Evans, Jr ...130th Coll cting Co Major J. N. Evans By direction of the Goverror: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. . STATE OF NE BRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN • July 7. 1930 Circular Letter No. IS Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment, 1930. To: Officer Responsible tor Same. 1. Government Transportation Request' No. \VQ is inclosed herewith, to cover railroad transportat on tickets) for your Company to Ashland, Nebraska, and should be completed as follows, after the num - ber of persons for whom transportation is required has been determined. a. Enter with pen. ink or indel ble pencil under the block, "Num - ber of Persons", the total aggregate) to be transported. b. Opposite "Est. cost $ ", enter the TOTAL cost. c. Signature of Responsible Oi fleer with title thereunder on the lower right hand corner of the Request. d. Postal card report (WD MB No. 36). will be completed as required thereon and turne 1 in immediately upon arrival at. camp to the TTSP&amp;DO (Camp Quartermaster's Office). e. SERIAL NUMBER — See tint ticket agents show on each ticket and on each coupon thereof, the SERIAL NUMBER </seg>
            <seg id="p091">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ■ OF THE TRANSPORTATION REQUEST used in getting the tickets so that tickets and transportation requests can be checked against each other. 2. If, prior to the surrender of Transportation Request to the ticket agent, it be found necessary to alter entries made thereon, such changes will be fully explained over your signature and rank in the blank space under par. 2, of the instructions on the reverse thereof. Postal card report required above must be absolutely correct, showing the number of persons actually travelling, as members of your party. 3. In view of the fact that all accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations when actually used, must be charged against the officer responsible for the error, the suggestion is made that, prior to leaving, your familiarize yourself with the provisions of N. G R 70 and 71. •1. In addition to the above, the conductor of each train is required to make a report in duplicate of the troops carried, which will be veri - fied by the Officer in charge of the Company ,and signed by both. The duplicate, copy of this report is to be given to the Officer in charge and will be sent by him to the Finance Officer. U. S. Army, Transportation Branch, Washington, D. C. and must compare with par. Id. as to number of passengers. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, USP&amp;DO. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT OENERAL'S DEPARTMENT ;■•■ LINCOLN July 7. 1930 Circular Letter No.l 9 Subject: Nebraska Circular Letter No. 24, 1929. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. Attention is invited to Nebraska Circular Letter No. 24. 1929, with the information that paragraph two thereof was not complied with </seg>
            <seg id="p092">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL by Company Officers. The Companj Commander is held responsible by this office to see that the money for ness is collected from the respective officers messing with him and in case he is unable so to do will notify this office, in writing, of the delinqu&lt; nts at orce. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT - . . .- LINCOLN ':■ July 8, 1930 Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Physical Condition of Enl sted Men. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The attention of all Unit ant Sub-unit Commanders is called to the necessity of knowing their men are physically fit before taking same to camp as the number of major operations in our camp must be re-, duced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line . of duty. 2. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will make sure that they ara not bringing any venereal cases to camp and in case any are found on the physical examination that will be made on entering camp, same will be returned to their home station at t leir own expense, without pay or allowances, as they will not be permitted in camp; such men will also be required to refund both railroad fare and subsistence expended on them in bringing them to camp. ' 3. Unit and Sub-unit Commande's will make every effort to ascer - tain that their men are physically fit before bringing them to camp and that they do not come under the heads mentioned above and will read this letter to their command at every armory drill between the time, of receipt of same and the time of entrifning lor camp. . By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. p ■.-■■■.'- </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 9, 1930 Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1930. To: Officer Responsible for Same. 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ is closed herewith tor freight (not checkable baggage) involved in movement of your company to Ashland, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows: a. Opposite "Est. Cost 5 ", insert the total actual cost after ascertaining same from the agent, upper right hand corner. b. Insert number, of packages under column "Number and kind of packages" (see par. 40b (7) NGR 71), and the total weight under column "Weights". In case of M. G. and Ammunition Cars, or other wheeled material, add to Bill of Lading giving the No., description and weights (see par. 40b (6) NGR 71). c. Insert length of car furnished, the date, initials, and car number. 2. Bill of Lading will be disposed of as follows: a. Original and three memos. Copies to be signed by your local Agent. . b. Shipping Order to be surrendered to local Agent. c. Original surrendered to Agent at Ashland, Nebraska, properly executed, under Consignee's Certificate of Delivery. d. Two memos to be immediately delivered to USP&amp;DO upon arrival at Camp. e. Retain one memo for company files. 3. Property List, M. B. Form No. 34 (supply inclosed), is again required for this year's Camp, par. 30 NGR 71 as, changed by C-2. In that the responsible officer is also the transportation officer, three of </seg>
            <seg id="p094">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL these will be prepared and attached tc each memorandum Bill of Lading, properly filled out and executed in at cordance with the paragraph cited herein. 4. In that a great many resporsible officers have been shipping unnecessary equipment on Bills of the inclosed certificate is required and must be tinned in wit 1 two memos referred to in par. Id. (See par. 13, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13, dated July !!, 1930.) 5. Transportation may be hired al a reasonable rate for the purpose of . transporting baggage and equipmeit from the Armory to the Depot nnd return. Invoices in duplicate sh mid be furnished tin's office with Public Voucher, Standard Form No. .034 and 1034a, properly executed for. the incoming and return movein -nt. After the service has been listed, indicate thereunder across the ace of the voucher, Drayage Com - pany , Ilegiment. These accounts must be in by the .last of August so that settlement may be made on the whole, to see iliat this allowance has not been exceeded. 6. • Transportation will be provided by this Department for hauling organization equipment and baggage i&gt; tin- Rifle Range from the Sioux City-Ashland branch of the CB&amp;Q It. It. on the DLI) Highway. Immedi - ately upon arrival, the Officers in- Charge of Companies should designate a baggage detail for handling this equipment and see that they stay there until the unloading is completed. (See par. 4. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13. 1930.) By direction of the Govern jr: H. J. PAUL, • -■■.■fh« Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, . • ■'■ Major. USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. STATIC OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENEUALS DEPARTMENT ' LINCOI N July 18. 1930 Circular Letter No. 22 To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, XNG. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p095">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Circular Letter Number 13, AGO Nebraska 1930, is amended by adding the following paragraphs: 14. Travel by Privately Owned Motor Vehicles. In move - ment of troops to and from camp in unit and sub-units having same, two officers, one of which shall be the Company Com - mander, must accompany troops en route and will not be per - mitted to travel by a privately owned motor vehicle. 15. Camp Post Office. Inasmuch as our postal system last year fell down to some extent on account of delivering mail to Regimental and like organizations, this year each unit and sub - unit commander will appoint a mail orderly who will get mail for his unit or sub-unit direct from the camp post office. The camp post office will sell stamps, register letters, fill mall orders and conduct a general business such as is done by post offices over the country. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 18, 1930 Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: 1930 Primaries. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. All unit and sub-unit commanders are directed to call to the at - tention of their respective commands that they will be able to obtain and cast an "Absent Voter's Ballot" with the County Clerks of their respective counties before leaving home station for camp and to im - press upon all officers and men their duty in taking advantage of this privilege. 2. It is the duty of all American citizens to vote at both primary • and general elections and in this members of the National Guard, stand- </seg>
            <seg id="p096">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Ing for what they always do, should do their full duty along this line. By direction of the Govsrnor: &lt; h. j. paul. '■'.'•:■' The Adjutant Gene al, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 8. 1930 Circular Letter No.24 Subject: Attendance at Service Schools. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from The Chief, Militia Bureau, pertaining to the above named subject is publish t d for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Your state is allotted" students at the Army Service Schools in the number and to the various courses as here listed: Approximate Course School Dates Number Company Officers' Infantry, Feb. 19-May 22, 1931 1 Ft. Benning, Ga. Field Officers' Medical Field Service, Sept. 1-Oct. 11, 1930 1 Carlisle Bks., Pa. Enlisted Men '■• Communications Infantry, Feb. 10-June 6, 1931 1 Ft. Benning, Ga. . ' " • • . I '■ ' ' ' : 2. While at school, enlisted m&lt; n must serve in the grade held at the time of recommendation by state authorities. 3. The provisions of Circular No. 19 A-ll, Militia Bureau, 1929, as amended by Circular No. 13 A-ll, May 20, 1930, will hold in all par - ticulars of selection and recommendation. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. Applications will be forwarded to arrive at the Militia Bureau not later than one month prior to the opening date of the course to which they apply, in order that they may all receive equal consideration. It is impossible, in many cases, to insure attendance of personnel on shorter notice. For The Chief, Militia Bureau: C. G. Foltz, Captain, C. A. C, M. B., Assistant." By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 19, 1930 Circular Letter w No. 25 . ..;•;. ■&amp;. Subject: Train Schedule, Return Movement, Annual Encampment, 1930. }0 To: All Company Commanders, Field &amp; Staff Ofllcers, NNG. . O 1. In accordance with Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13, 1930, the following Train Schedule Is prescribed for the H return movement: . . H Movements Organization "^^""^^plaTT^T^ Schedule g~ — : ; : : *3 No. 1 110th M. R. Band Crete ■ I 17 w/Co. C Lv. Ashland Spl. Tn. . &amp; CB&amp;Q ' f CB&amp;Q 9:20 A. M. Aug. 18 3 Dest. . • | Ar. 11:27 A. M. . o Co. C Beatrice 1 52 1 Ar. 12:30 P. M. . H Co. M . Seward | 35 1 Ar. 12:10 P. M. g . Serv. Co. 134th Inf. York | 45 1 Ar. 1:00 P. M. g Co. H Grand Island] 54 1 Ar. 3:05 P. M &gt; Co. G Hastings 47 1 Ar. 2:30 P. M. . . r 1 ■ ' Co. B Falls City 45 1 Ar. 4:39 P. M. ' . </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 Movements Organization Locatltm | £"££. | Cta Schedule No. 2 130 Coll. Co. . Columbus 43 1 Lv. Ashland Spl. Tn. CB&amp;Q CB&amp;Q 11:00 A. M. Aug. 18 Fremont Ar. 2:00 P. M. UP 120th Wagon Co. Kearney 44 Ar. 4:30 P M ._, Dest. Med. Dept. Det. , 2 36th Dv. Tn. 119th Wagon Co. Lexington 41 1 Ar. 6:45 P. M. 2 Co. D No. Platte 58 1 Ar. 8:30 P. m! ' £3 Howitzer Co. Gering 53 1 Ar. 11:20 A. M. Aug. 19 o (x) *j No. 3 Co. F Hartlngton 41 1 Lv. Ashland 11:17 A. M. • W CB&amp;Q • CB&amp;Q Tn. No. 24, Aug 18/30 H Omaha Ar. 7:10 P. M. &gt; M&amp;O Hq. Co. 1st Bn. Nebr. City 21 1 Ar. 2:48 P. M O &amp;MP Dest. Co. A 48 3 No. 4 Hq. Co. 3d Bn. . Lincoln 22 Lv. Ashland 2:05 P. M. H CB&amp;Q CB&amp;Q Tn. No. 7, Aug. 18 t Dest. Co. I 45 1 Ar. 2: 45 P. M. j 110th Vet. Co. 22 1 „ Field &amp; Staff g M. R. Z Det. Dv. Sur. O. H Hq. 35th Dv. Tn. Co. E Scottsbluff 47 1 Ar. 3:21 P. M. Aug 19 F I (x) </seg>
            <seg id="p100">Movements Organization Location I Approx. Bag. Schedule | No. Pass. Car No. 5 Co. K Omaha | 48 1 Lv. Ashland 2:00 P. M. CB&amp;Q j CB&amp;Q Tn. 38 Aug. 18/30 Omaha Co. L I 58 1 Ar 2:50 P. M. Med. Dept. Det. 15 3 134th Inf. • ■ . % Regt. Hq. Co. 32 1 O Field &amp; Staff 2 134th Inf. Hq. Co. 2d Bn. 15 § Via 130th Amb. Co. Hastings 42 Lv. Camp 7:00 A.M. w Government Aug. 18/30, Ar. 3:00 P. M. H Motor Service Co. ■ Lincoln 39 v:. Lv. Camp 1:00 P. M . ■ &gt;&gt; Vehicles UOth-JVL-R, — | - Aug^4&amp;/30, Ar. 3^30-Pr^fc 9 - 166th Hosp. Co. . 63 Lv. Camp 1:00 P.M. U Aug. 18/30, Ar. 3:30 P. M. hj' 138th M. T. Co. Fremont 46 Lv. Camp 3:00 P. M. &gt; 119th M.R.S. 15 ■ , Aug. 18/30, Ar. 7:00 P. M. g SS&amp;SD Lincoln 21 . Lv. Camp 7:00 A. M. Aug. 19/30, Ar. 10:00 A. M. 2 137th M. T. Co. . Holdrege 37 Lv. Camp 5:00 A, M. Aug. g ■ 18/30, Ar. 7:00 P M. H (x) Tourist Cars -vrill be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Company E3 (Scottsbluff). |h </seg>
            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. Movement No. 1. ' Co. C and Band, 110 M. R., will use one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Hq. Co. 1st Bn. and Co. A will use one baggage car. Movement No. 4. Co. I, Hq. Co. 3 Bn. and Hq. 35th Dv. Tn. will use one baggage car. 110th Vet. Co. and Det. Dv. Sur. O. will use one baggage car. Movement No. 5. Med. Dept. Det. and Regtl. Hq. Co. will use one bag - gage car. Co. K and Hq. Co. 2nd. Bn. will use one baggage car. 2. TICKETS. Government Transportation Requests on the railroad concerned will be exchanged for tickets at the Camp Quartermaster's Office. Re - quests for berths will be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for ac - commodations actually furnished. 3. BAGGAGE. 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger. Excess baggage (freight) consisting of property other than checkable baggage will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bill of Lading, covering such impedi - menta forwarded from Camp to Home Station, at freight rates. 4. Passengers and organizations to be carried will be those that are shown in Nebraska Circular Letter No. 17, 1930. 5. Postal Card Report WD MB No. 36 will be mailed to the TJSP&amp;DO as soon as possible after securing the signature of the conductor. The report required by par. 4, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 18, 1930, must be mailed to the Finance Officer, Washington, D. C, as soon as possible. 6. Two memorandum copies of Bill of Lading must be given to the USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to your departure. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: . H. C. STEIN, Major, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA : ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July !1, 1930 Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: Requisition for New Stylj Pershing Caps. To: All Company and Detach nent Commanders, NNG. Requisition for new style Persh ng Caps should be submitted to this office on QMC form 51 not later than September 1, 1930, based upon the strength as shown in Nebraska Clrc liar Letter No. 31, 1927. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. ■.■■• . . ■"■■.••• STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 2, 1930 Circular Letter No. 27 ■ . Subject: Athletic Program. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Coi inlanders, NNG. 1. The following Athletic Prog 'am, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require, is publish d for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. Each unit and sub-unit con mander will give this program bis personal attention. 3. PROGRAM. (a) Field Meet. Saturday, Aug. 16 (after 9:30 A. M.), is re - reserved as the Camp \thletic Field Day. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (1) All entries in athletic events scheduled tor that period . will be released from all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared of troops prior to the above designated hour (Field Training Directive 6 (6)). (2) Track. AH track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd and 3rd in each event. (b) Swimming. (1) Swimming events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for 1st, 2nd and 3rd in each event (c) Boxing. (1) There will be competition in each weight division and a medal awarded to the winner in each weight. (d) Mass Athletics. (1) All enlisted men not employed during the afternoon period, as provided in Section 6, Field Training Direc - tive, sub-paragraph a-1 to a-5 inclusive, will be as - sembled for physical training, athletics, recreational games and sports and training for athletics or military competitions during the period from 1:15 to 3:00 P. M. upon all days except Aug. 4, 9, 10, 16, 17 and 18. ! ' ■ (2) The above activities will be grouped as follows: Period from 1:15 to 2:00 P. M., mass athletics, group games and other sports requiring close supervision. Period from 2:00 to 3:00 P. M., baseball, boxing, swimming, preparation for field meet and similar ac - tivities (Field Training Directive 6a (6)). 4. GENERAL PROVISIONS. (a) Each regimental and separate battalion commander will im - mediately upon arrival at camp designate a regimental or battalion athletic officer, who will immediately report to the Camp Athletic Officer, to assist him in the supervision of the recreational and athletic activities of the camp. (b) At least one non-commissioned officer or qualified private in each company, or like unit, will be excused from school :■'.'..- or other duties to have charge of the assembly and control </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL of the men of his- unit [or the afternoon periods. For lhat duty he will be under tie direction and control of the regi - mental or battalion athetic officer. (c) The non-commissioned officers or qualified privates detailed as provided in the abc ve paragraph (b) will also be ex - cused from school or other duties to attend the school of instruction in mass atliletics in the morning of each day at an hour to be desigtated by the Camp Athletic 1 j Officer. (d) All regimental athletic officers, battalion athletic, officers and others assigned as Camp Athetic Instructors! will be under the orders o fthc Camp % Athletic Officer and will re - port to him for duty. (e) All unit and sub-unit commanders will prior to; leaving their respective home stations have all men who will be entered in the boxing contests accurately weighed i and im - mediately upon arrival at camp will deliver to the Camp Athletic Officer a list af their respective entries 'together with a statement of thoir accurate weights. 5. GENERAL'S TROPHY. (a) Adjutant General Paul is again offering a cup to the com - pany showing the greatest activity and efficiency in atnletics. (b) Points will be awarded to the various companies upon tne basis: • , (1) Boxing. . • 10 points will be {.warded for each entry appearing at __], the ringside in condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. An additional 10 points will be awarded to the winning entry in each bout. 25 points will be awarded ,to each entry who enters the semi-finals. 50 points will be awarded to the champions in each weight division. (2) Swimming. 25 points will be awarded for each 1st. 15 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 5 points will be awarded for each 3rd. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (3) Track. 15 points ' will 'be awarded for each Ist. 10 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 6 joints will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Mass Athletics. 100 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the greatest activity and efficiency m mass athletics. 50 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the second greatest activity and efficiency m mass athletics. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28, 1930 Circular Letter No. 28 Subject: Number of Privately Owned Motor Vehicles Permitted m Camp. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. Owing to the fact that our camp at present is divided by one of the main highways of the state, that numerous accidents have hap - pened during camp on this highway, that the great number of privately owned motor vehicles previously brought to camp have added materially to this danger, only three privately owned motor vehicles for the en - listed personnel of each company will be permitted m camp until such time as this main highway has been changed, which will not be before next year or the year following. 2. Any privately owned motor vehicle per company or like organ - ization m excess of three brought to camp this year will immediately be impounded for the duration of the camp. The company commander will designate the three motor vehicles authorized to be used. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">REPORT OF THE AD FUTANT GENERAL 3. All cars, whether belonging to commissioned or enlis ed per - sonnel, will be required to be registered on the first day of camp and the owner of the car will be required to show his state registration certificate at the time the camp registration is made. Registration will be made with Camp Adjutant at Camp Headquarters. By direction of the Governor : H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant Genen 1, Nebraska. STATE OF K EBRASKA ADJUTANT- GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August , 1930 Circular Letter No. 29 Subject: Additional Information Required on M. B. Form 10( To: All Unit and Sub-unit Comnanders, NNG. 1. The following additional information and corrections oi M. B. Form 100 will be made commencing with form submitted for th i month of August, 1930. I a. The Militia Bureau keeps a record of all duty performed by each officer, warrant ofHc&lt; r and enlisted man of the National Guard and in order for them to do this it is necessary that the Form 100 show actusl dates of attendance at Camp or whenever under federal jay. If a man is a member of an advance or rear detachment the actual dates he was on tnis duty must be shown in column or remarks behind his name. If a majority of the orgarization attends the annual encamp - ment a remark similar to the following should be placed at the bottom of the form: "AH members of this organization attended camp under federal pay from (date) to (date) ex - cept as noted behind the individual's name in column of re - ■ ■■• marks." b. Rank and date of ORC co nraission must be shown in column of remarks behind name of each officer and enlisted man holding same. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. Any remark affecting an individual should be confined to column of remarks and not carried across under his name. d. Certificate at bottom of the form, ' which is signed by the organization commander, should bear the date of the last day of the month for which the report is rendered. 2. Attention is invited to previous instructions from this office, which direct that three copies of this form be mailed to the Adjutant General's Department, instead of to the instructor as directed on back of form. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 18, 1930. Circular Letter No. 30 . Subject: Examination Of Candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. .1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of one en - listed man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive ex - amination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office beginning November 10, 1930, at 9:00 A.M. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Gov - ernment. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1931, have served as. an enlisted man not less than, one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years and must not be less than 5'4" in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former ser - vice in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibil - ity. The requirements for admission to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the inclosed pamphlet. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled </seg>
            <seg id="p108">REPORT OF THE AD. UTANT GENERAL, to be held beginning on March 3, 191 1, and the appointments available on July 1, 1931, will be awarded to the qualified candidate in the order of merit established at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously, applicants have presented themselves to this office to take this examination who were i i no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. Company Commanders will make any members of their command who have a desire to take this examination conversant with the requirements of the inclosed pamphlet, and while some believe that a High School graduate can pass this ex - aminatin, it has been demonstrated that unless they have had at least one year in college, in addition to their High School education, i it will be time wasted. 5. No State Funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. i 6. The return of this pamphlet is requested. If pamphlet is not in - closed, one may- be had upon application. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT '■'■-.*■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ',,.."'■■■■ LINCOLN ■ September 22, 1930 Circular Letter No. 31 Subject: Repair, Renovation of Clothiiig and Individual Equipment and Maintenance of Organization Equipment, F. Y. 1931. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG . 1. If funds are required by your organization it is directed that you furnish this office, not later than October 31, 1930, separate esti - mates for the following: a. Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment. b. Maintenance of Organizational Equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, c. Repair of Typewriters, giving the serial number, make with width of cariage, complying with the maintenance allowance authorized in Militia Bureau Circular No. 12 A-10, dated May 19, 1930. In case the allowance is exceeded they should be placed upon I &amp; I Reports. 2. In no case will any obligation be incurred until estimate called for above has been approved by this office. . 3. Major repairs of heavy tentage that was left at Camp, Ashland, Nebraska, will be made by. the USP&amp;DO-Nebraska, insofar as Federal Funds will permit. 4. The authorization of funds for Repair and Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment is intended for articles where the enlisted men have been discharged and not for the purpose of cleaning clothing for active men. Pressing of the overcoats, uniforms and the shining of shoes will not be authorized. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, TBe Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 14, 1930 Circular Letter No. 32 Subject: Rendition of MB Forms 100. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. Your attention is invited to the following extract from Militia Bureau letter dated November 6, 1930, on the above subject: "The prompt and early receipt in the Militia Bureau of MB Forms 100 has become an absolute necessity due to the increas - ing calls for more exacting strength data of the National Guard from the War Department, and requirements in the Militia Bu - reau itself. Much embarrassment is caused when calls are made • </seg>
            <seg id="p110">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL for information which should be readily available, but which cannot be furnished because the information has not arrived in the bureau. • This condition of affairs can and must be rectified. It is be - lieved that the main cause of delay lies in the hands of the com - pany commanders, and, likewise, the remedy is also in their hands. Unless these conditions become much improved, more positive action will be necessary. It is hoped no such action becomes necessary, as the only desire is to have the Forms 100 reach the Militia Bureau in time to meet requirements." ■-■•■" ■■.'." ■'" \ 2. With a view to improving this condition, you are advised that this office will in the future expect FDrms 100 to be made immediately following the last drill of the month for which submitted in order to allow time for return for correction if necessary and receipt in the Militia Bureau by the tenth of the ironth. If Forms' 100 are not sub - mitted as outlined the company commander's administrative pay will be disapproved. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT . LINCOLN ' '/ . ;.'■ ':■ December 4, 1930 Circular Letter No. 33 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG . 1. There are inclosed herewith blank' efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1930, which should have your im - mediate attention. 2. After giving a thorough study to instructions contained n par. 74, Changes 1, NGR 20, dated January 1, 1929, make out your reports and forward same without delay to the officer to whom directed. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. Therep orts should reach this office before the expiration of the month. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Let us all get them in, in proper form, and AT ONCE. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 12, 1930 Circular Letter No. 34 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books, 1930. To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1930. in accordance with the following instructions. a. Council Books Q.M.C. 15." b. Company designation with words "State Fund" added on cover. c. The account will be based on the calnedar year and will bo posted only under ''Other Funds" and in accordance with paragraphs 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6, of the instructions (see also the model). d. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, regardless whether receipts or expenditures. e. Certificates for receipts and invoices for expenditures are required for all transactions from January 1, 1930. f. In case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transaction, cut off bottom of page above words "Total re - ceipts and expenditures" and the top of next page "In account with -.fund," etc., under the word "year" and above "month". g. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of December 31, 1930, </seg>
            <seg id="p112">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. h. Certificate must be submitted as a voucher showing the of - ficers that messed with your Company and the amounts. 2. These Council Books with vouc hers will be sent immediately to Major H. C. Stein, USP&amp;DO-Nebraska, who will audit and return same, making report to this office of any discrepancies found. By direction of the Goveriior: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers 'who partici - pated in the service of the -Spanish- At lerican War in the First, Second and Third Nebraska "Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry : COMPANY A— FIR5JT REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rink Name Amt. Due Pvt. Bye, Joseph G : $3.20 Ivt. Gelvin, Robert N 1...I3.20 Pvt. Allen, Roller C 3.20 Pvt. Hensley, Minor N 3.20 Pvt. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 Fvt. Kremer, Cochron A L. 4.00 Pvt. Morgenstern, Henry A... 3.20 I vt. Sommers, Nels J I... 3.20 Pvt. Shively, Bion 3.20 Ivt. Turner, Robert W.: I... 3.20 Pvt. Freeman, Charlie O. 3.20 I vt. Wompler, Elmer B 3.20 COMPANY B— FIRJT REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rink Name . Amt. Due Pvt. Garinger, Albert $0.80 Ivt. Grainger, Louis I L. 1.60 Pvt. Andrews, Chas. J .....4.00 Ivt. Killhom, Perry A L. 4.00 Pvt. Black, John 4.00 Ivt. Ressekuie-, Herbert L. ... 4.00 COMPANY C— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Johnson, Hans $3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 Pvt. Campbell, Roy G 3.20 COMPANY D— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due F ank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alley, John S *4.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 ]&gt;vt. Bloom, John J j 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY E— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F. 3.20 Pvt. Amerman, Arba B 1.60 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. MofCet, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 Pvt. Bays, Wm 80 COMPANY F— FIRST REFIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P.i J3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 T»vt. Davids.ra, Houston 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 COMPANY G— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John $3.20 Pvt. Mohler, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Deaver, Harvey W 3.20 Pvt. Underwood, Henry C 3.20 Pvt. Dowis, Jonathan E... 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt. Merryman, John R 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 COMPANY H — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H $3.20 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 Pvt. Brisbane, Lewis H 2.40 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M......... 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S 4.00 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 1.60 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Winagel, Anthony J 2.40 Pvt. Peterson, Hanc C... 4.00 COMPANY I— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Hotsell, Leon V $4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 Pvt. Berndtson, John E 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Arm. Due Pvt Bordwell, Frank J 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert ... i 4.00 Pvt Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Pvt. Miller. Wm. D.......... 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis d! 4.00 COMPANY K— FUST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name \mt. Due Cpl. Delong, Herbert B $3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F.. [ 3.20 ' Pvt. Fingado, Harry, Jr 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N.. I 3.20 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 3.20 COMPANY I FIRST REGIMENT ■ • " ..■ I Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Downs, James W $3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin O .' 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L..... 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B. 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H.....;. 3.20 COMPANY M— FIFST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin. A J 3.20 Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L 3.20 Pvt. Jack, Cecil B .....j 3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 Kennedy, Phillip S 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due P. M. Brown, Robert S $4.00 ]rlus. Murnhouse. F. Edd 4.00 COMPANY A— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Fank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupemell, Ernest H $3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M...J.... 3.20 Cpl. Paine, Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K : 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S.... 3.20 Ivt. Mott, Mathew 1... 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W.I 3.20 Ivt. Packwood, Arthur T ... 3.20 Pvt Cornell, George S. 3.20 Ivt. Tuffs, Frank 3 20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick *. 3.20 Ivt White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David A 3.20 I vt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Ivt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 Ivt. Woodruff, Charles 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY B — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Frink, Alberto D $3.20 Pvt. Jackson, Wm 3.20 Cpl. Whitmer, James K 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3 20 Wag. Crow, Wallace H 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Frank 3.20 Art. Grossett, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Briggs, Ernest G. Pvt. Wilson, Eli A 3.20 (Died in service) 3.20 COMPANP C — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George 13.20 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C... 3.20 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Ira B.--.-! 3.20 Pvt. Kime, David 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C... 1.60 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E 160 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R.. 3.20 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester 1.60 COMPANY D — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00. Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 COMPANY E — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W $3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COMPANY F— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton, George $3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY G— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Atnt. Due Fanlf Name ' Amt. Due 2nd/*Lt. Hodglns, Eli $3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T i 80 Jftl. Hays, Robert A. 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S I 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F ; ..i... !so :Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S. ..... 3.20 Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V 80 Pvt. Newton, William L. 3.20 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H SO Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 1... 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L .80 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E J 80 Pvt. Fisher, Leo 80 Pvt. Ritter, David :..!... .80 Pvt. Gainey, John H 80 I'vt. Thompson, Eddie D....L. .80 Pvt. Horn, George L., 3r 3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry 80 COMPANY H— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due R ink Name Amt. Due Cpl. Borland, John A ;$4.00 Pvt. Johnston, George H J... 4.00 Art. Niell, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvah ]... 4.00 Pvt. Bowers, Henry H 4.00 Pivt. Meitner, Joseph L 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J... 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John J... 4.00 Pvt. Davis, Harry E 4.00 Prt. Perry, Herbert N ...L 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Serensen, Ole C. L 4^00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry O. ._ 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L..... 4.00 . Prt. Whitney, John A 4.00 COMPANY I— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Riink Name AirL Due QM Sgt. Rainey, Jacob A $4.00 PVt. Schooler, John H L 4.00 Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 PVt. Schuelke, Herman A....!.. 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Prt. Thompson, Theodore ...L 4.00 Pvt. Humpal, John J 4.00 Prt. Walker, Joseph H.. 1. 4.00 Pvt. Penland, John W.... .80 P 't. Way, Rueben D 4.00 COMPANY K— SECOUD REdlMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T ?3.20 Pvt. West, Charles .. . J 3 20 Cpl. Hill, John T 3.20 COMPANY L— SECOND REGIMENT Ranfc Name Amt. Due Rank Name AmfcTJue Cpl. Jack, Charles H $2.40 p|t. Clarenden, Alvin T L 4.00 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Evans, John L 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Sage, John M 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Pvt. Leonard, Win. C 80 Art. Carter, Charles J 3.20 Pvt. Powell, Joheph A 3.20 Pvt. Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Cottrell, Eugene W 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 COMPANY M— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Wag. Alfreds, Frank H $5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm -5.60 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncon C 5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 FIELD STAFF AND BAND— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, Roy D ?9.60 RB Mus. Parkhurst, Harry .... 3.20 . " . RB Mus. Wells, Richard L 12.00 COMPANY A— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W ?32.55 Pvt. Horahan, Chas 5.60 Cpl. Ford, John J...... 5.60 Pvt. Hinckley, John S .1.60 Cpl. Steinbach, George 12.72 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Matthew „ 1.60 Pvt. Koontz, Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 . Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N... 1.60 Pvt. O'Leary, John J. 2.40 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 Pvt. Pace, Perle R 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Reynolds, John A ::.. 1.60 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Schneider, Wm 2.40 Art. Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Smith, John J 1.60 Pyt. Allen, Thomas 4.80 Pvt. Taylor, James J 2.40 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 . Pvt. Trombly, Warden, A. F...18.39 Pvt. Bliss, Gottle $1.60 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr 2.40 Pvt. Collins, John H 1.60 Pvt. Gallenbuck, Frank J 1 .60 Pvt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 COMPANY B— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Covell, Herbert E $33.64 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. McGrew, Frank 80 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W. 33.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">REPORT OF THE AD rUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due *ank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Px-adford, George H 80 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard ...J......18.53 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas .80 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H J 33.64 Pvt. Custer, Elisha 80 Pvt. Place, John F ! 21.36 Pvt. Francisco, John H .80 Pvt.. Ray, Evert P .■„.] 20.42 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Greenlee, "William 3.20 Pvt. Roop, Scott D .80 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E 33.64 Pvt. Habbick, George W 1.60 Pvt. SchwartE, Win. 80 Pvt. Jarvis, Chas. T.. 80 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N 80 Pvt. Keanes, James N ,. .80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy £ 33.64 Pvt. Line, Jno. M 17.59 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 Pvt. Metts, Edmond M 80 Pvt. Whalen, Edwin F 3.20 COMPANY C—TH RD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due tank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. White, Thomas R $27.46 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip .1 2.40 Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Pvt. Costello, Michael F.J 13.30 Cpl. Dillion, Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P.....L 8.58 Cpl. Sydow, Emil 27.46 Pvt. DeRivieres, Francis L... 4.80 Cpl. Miller, Wm. E...: ...27.46. Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 1 2.40 Cpl. Burkett, Harry B 2.40 Pvt. Henske, Fred L... .80 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Pvt. Hawkins/Elgin C 1 8.58 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W 27.46 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E .27.46 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F l 2.40 Pvt. Hbwell, Harry H .22.74 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Keliher, John F.. 4.80 Pvt... Taylor, Edward 4.80 Pvt. Long, Wilber W.... 5.75 Pvt. Vernon, George A.... 12.36 Pvt. Mitchell, Edward F 2.40 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albin F.. 2.40 Pvt. Norton, Ernest H.... 11.41 Pvt. Zurubsky, James 7.64 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Pvt. Shiel, Daniel J 7.64 COMPANY D— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D ? 4.80 Pvt. Jansen, Nels P i 22.91 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Pvt. Juul, John M..... j 30.52 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B .....26.74 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C 1 80 Cpt. Christensen, Pvt. Landsbury, Harry ....} 1.60 Christian A 36.18 ?vt. Lundell, Ernest j 4.80 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M 1 8.00 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G ....:..... 8.00 Mus. Howell, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Pool, John E i 4^80 Pvt. AUwein, John C 1.60 Wt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. "Due Pvt. Anderson, Edward ....:... 4.00 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S 4.80 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew ... 3.20 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Bandy, John W... 1.60 Pvt. Sutton, Frank E 6.40 Pvt. Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Wiederbolz, John J 28.63 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 , Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 COMPANY E— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Siddell, Bert E..., .....;.?13.01 Pvt. Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Pvt. Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Flenniken, Robert B 13.96 Pvt. Smith, Fred S .22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L 80 Pvt. Lewin, Samuel C 80 COMPANY F— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A ?36.69 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P 36.69 Pvt. Baughman, Chas .2.40 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Brunker, Frank 1.60 Pvt. Hon, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius .....36.69 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Johns, Olvey O 80 Pvt. Hayes, John C S.80 Pvt. Johnson, Wm. L 36.69 Pvt. Kment, Joe 1.60 Pvt. Karges, John 36.69 Pvt. Knott, Fred 80 Pvt. Phillips, George W. 1.60 Pvt. Loss, Isaac .". 36.69 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H 80 Pvt. Manzel, Charles „ 36.69 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Underhill, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Nicholson, James T......... 1.60 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 Pvt. Olson, Chris 80 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J 3.20 COMPANY G— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burnett, Hamilton H $29.72 Pvt. Forsman, Oscar 29.72 Cpl. Larson, Felix G J29.72 Pvt. Fuller, Guy W 1.60 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S 29.72 Pvt. Howard, Edward 29.72 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Jones, Frank 27.72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt. Knapp, Willie R 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Larson, Axel W 29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL flank Name Ami Due Hank Name Anit. Due Pvt. Bowerman, Wm. F 4.80 Pvt. Morton, Frank H | 29.72 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William J 4.00 Pvt. Conner, Clement T... 29.72 Pvt. Pickard, Harry M .......29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A 1 29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac 80 i COMPANY H— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Headwell, Axel ?31.09 Pvt. Robinson, Andrew M..... 3.20 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N ...6.55 Pvt. Thomas, James T J 3.20 Pvt. Keever, Oscar W .15.16 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T.... 31.09 Pvt. Leichty, John 6.55 Pvt. Matson, Albert 5.60 Pvt. Robinson, Edward 3.20 COMPANY I-THIHD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Derienger, George $36.61 Pvt. Brown, Frank H L... 4.00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry D. S-37,56 Pvt. Carroll, John W 4.00 Cpl. Dickenson, John W 12.07 Pvt. Center, Albert ...; 4^80 Cpl. Felts, William B 6.40 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R...i 9^24 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M .4.00 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander J 3.20 Cpl. Meyer, Otto .....4.00 ' Pvt. Fairchild, Homer i 160 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A...\ 4^00 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D.....J 1.60 Pvt. Hutchinson, Albert L..... 1.60 Pvt. Hanks, Harry E.........J 1.60 Pvt. Jones, Lloyd 0 4.00 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Marqwadt, Fred W 1.60 pvt. Palmer, Archibald G.. 5 60 Pvt. Miller, Fred S ...9.24 Pvt. Ray, Warren Hopkins.... 2.40 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F 9.24 Pvt. Roberts, James W J 9.24 Pvt. Padol, Adam .80 Pvt. Selby, Arthur L j 9.24 Pvt. Perry, Chas. E 11.12 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus ..... ... J 37 56 Pvt. Phillips, Ellis J ...3.20 Pvt. Stohe, John G i... 4.00 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W 23.40 Pvt. Swan, Richard B i... .80 Pvt. Aitken, George F....,....:...37.56 Pvt. Vandyke, John T I.;.. 6.40 Pvt. Baird, Francis H „ 4.80 Kt. Vandyke, Sherman ..!... 6.40 Pvt. Bersley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Warrington, Albert jL.. 2.40 COMPANY K— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Ftank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. Jacobson, Carl L $34.29 Pvt. Meade, Wm. B .'. 3 20 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N 34.29 Pvt. Mines,' James sZIZlI L60 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H. 80 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Cofleld, Chester A.. 11.64 !Pvt. Porterfleld, James A.......34!29 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank ' Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Gray, Lyman 3.20 Pvt. Reardon, Patrick J 2.40 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Gress, Henry C 14.47 Pvt. Roff, John L 29.57 Pvt. Hightower, Harry A 2.40 Pvt. Smith, Albert L 34.29 Pvt. Kennedy, George H 7.20 Pvt. Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kankright, Clinton D 27.68 Pvt. Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Pvt. Kruger, Wm 80 Pvt. Thompson, James B 3.20 Pvt. Matthews, Stanley 30.52 Pvt. VanSlckle, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. McCaulley, Wm. G 1.60 Pvt. Williams, Wm. M..!. 1.60 COMPANY L— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Brown, Cleveland W $ 7.20 Pvt. Jones, Joseph B 4.80 Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J... 4.00 Pv£. Kelley, Robert S 1 . 6.40 Cpl. Lowe, Walter 8.00 Pvt. McColl, John 14.40 Cpl. Taft, Charles C 21.01 Pvt. McCormick, Benj. D 8.00 Wag. Stockton, Andrew 32.34 Pvt. Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman ....: 6.40 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H 5.60 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt. Bradshaw, Thomas H 5.60 Pvt. Lee, Justivin E 1.60 Pvt. Burns, James E 3.20 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A ,,....21.01 Pvt. Chisolm, Ralph 0 5.60 Pvt. Mardock, John E 1.60 Pvt. Foster, Louie C 32.34 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E 6.40 Pvt. Redfield, Cyrus R 4.80 Art.. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. Runtius, Frank 32.34 Pvt. Athos, Andrew G 27.62 Pvt. Sherry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Black, Wm '. 2.40 Pvt. Swanson, Nels 32.34 Pvt. Fox, Ernest S.. : 24.79 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Pvt. Walker, Chas 27.62 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 COMPANY M— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name • Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Foster, John E $4.00 Pvt. Heisler, Robert D 80 Sgt. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt Hensel, Wm. A 2.40 Cpl. Alsen, John C 35.38 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris 35.38 Mus. Porter, Lester E 16.50 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H 17.44 Pvt. Bennett, NHes 21.22 Pvt. Maddan, Chas 35.38 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E 11.78 Pvt. Brewlck, Andrew T 3.20 Pvt. Ratekin, Janson L 80 Pvt. Cantello, John 10.84 Pvt. Short, James* S 27.83 Pvt. Carigan, Robert J 35.38 Pvt. Timmons. Alfred D 34.44 Pvt. Custard, Marshall 1.60 Pvt. Wiesman. Jacob 2.40 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A 13.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt Foster, Frederick W 17.44 Pvt. Alley, Franc 2.40 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Beardsley, Wm. S. 80 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 Pvt. Johnson, John D... 13.60 TROOP K— THIRD CAVALRY Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred i 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger, Claude G 2.40 It is recommended that this list be given a--circulation in the news - papers of the State with a view to locating such of these men as possible. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>