<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Drouth and Grasshopper Relief in Northeast Nebraska IN THE WINTER OF 1931-32, REPORT OF THE State Relief Agency Appointed by the Governor</title>
               <date value="1931-10-31">1931-10-31</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Drouth and Grasshopper Relief In Northeast Nebraska IN THE WINTER OF 1931-32 I REPORT OP THE State Relief Agency Appointed by the Governor . WM. H. SMITH State Tax Commissioner In Charge of Relief Work </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF RELIEF ACTIVITIES To Hon. Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln. My dear Governor: ■- I am herewith submitting to you a report of the activities of the State Relief Agency designated by you m October, 1931, to assemble and distribute supplies to the people of the counties m northeast Ne - braska who suffered the loss of their crops from drouth and grass - hoppers during the previous summer, the work terminating May 1, 1932, when, free movement of supplies over the railroads ceased. On October 31, 1931, the following proclamation was issued by your Excellency: </seg>
            <seg id="p004">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT — — A PROCLAMATION To the People of the Commonwealth of Nebraska: ■ Hundreds of families which include thousands of good citizens of Nebraska are in need ol food, clothing and fuel to carry them through the winter. Two years in succession of drouth followed this year by a devastation by grasshoppers in seven of the counties of Nebraska along the South Dakota border has rendered many human beings prac - tically destitute. After careful personal investigation and inspection I feel it is my duty as the chief executive of the state to bring to the attention Of the big-hearted, generous people that make up the citizenship of our great state the conditions as we found them to exist in the section of the state referred to above. Nebraska as a whole has an abundance and to spare of the necessities such as are needed to succor and pro - vide for its own people in distress. In order that no citizen of our state may suffer the pangs of hunger, the chilly blasts of winter or for the lack of shelter, among the splendid people who have developed farm lands, built their homes and reared their families in the north tier of counties in northeastern Nebraska, and in order that contributions from our fortunate to our unfortunate citizens may be properly solicited .and applied, NOW, THEREFORE, I, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska, declare to all the citizens of our state that an emergency exists in those few counties devastated by drouth and grasshoppers and earn - estly urge that those who can do so will freely and liberally contribute of their substance to the proper organizations which I have authorized to solicit aid; that all solicitations be confined to our own citizens, without appeal to any person beyond the borders of Nebraska. This appeal will not be in vain. Nebraska pride must come into action. We must show the world that Nebraska is able to care for her own. The American Legion posts of the state have generously and patriotically offered the services of their membership and it has been accepted and they have been authorized to solicit contributions of food stuffs of all characters, clothing and cash funds from the people throughout the state of Nebraska outside of the counties of Douglas and Lancaster. The membership of this great organization has also made a personal house to house canvass In the seven drouth stricken counties and we have a list which includes each family and each person and what their needs will be for the coming winter ■ v S Disbursing committees will be immediately announced which will distribute the supplies to every human being who is in need. I call upon all Christian organizations, civic clubs, charity and fraternal </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT organizations, commercial clubs, including the local Red Cross chapters throughout the state to make their contributions through the Ameri - can Legion solicitors in each county who will report them in detail to the State Tax Commissioner, Win, H. Smith, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska, who will in turn direct shipment to the proper disbursing committees and who will also be prepared to direct how freight ship - ments will be made. Other instructions as to details concerning how food and other supplies will be collected, shipped and distributed will follow. Solicitors are requested to keep an accurate and complete list of each contribution of whatsoever character and amount and forward the report to Wm. H. Smith, State House, Lincoln, who will also keep a complete record of all receipts and disbursements so that each ar - ticle and penny will be accounted for and properly credited. All donations and shipments into the drouth stricken counties are earnestly requested to be contributed through the American Legion and reported to the state headquarters at the State House where all shipments will be properly directed so that there will be no duplica - tion of effort among other charity organizations and in order that no individual- needing aid will be overlooked. Subscriptions in Douglas and Lancaster Counties will be under the supervision of the Chambers of Commerce in Omaha and Lincoln. In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Governor's seal to be affixed. Done at the Capitol in the city of Lincoln, this 31st day of October, in the year of our Lord, nineteen hundred and thirty-one. CHARLES W. BRYAN, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">■ DROUTH RELIEF REPORT Prior to the Issuance of this proclamation, a survey had been started by members of the American Legion and World War Veterans who had volunteered Their services for that purpose. The following form was used in making the survey: County. SUPPLIES NEEDED ■ Of food, fuel and clothing for drouth and grasshopper stricken area. . Individual needing supplies: — Name Present Rescources Address Nebraska. Tw P - County '''ZZZ Occupation • • Renter or Owner ;.. Number in Family Ages ....Z."... Needs: — Food 1 , """ Fuel ; ZZl'...Z.""."..".'.ll Clothing ZZZZZZ. If food and fuel, how soon needed? For how long a period? ; Remarks: Information collected by....... p - ° Nebraska Signature of Applicant As these questionnaires were returned, the results were tabulated. The first and final totals of these tabulations were as follows: October 17, 1931. December 29, 1931. No. of No. of No. of No. of Connt y Families Persons Families Persons' Bovd 162 832 206 1043 Brown 30 . 142 30 142 Cedar • 12 65 82 472 Holt • 84 453 203 1055 Keya Paha 62. 280" 87 394 Knox - 223 1051 295 1341 Rock - 39 165 55 242 TOTAL 612 2988 95i 4689 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">_^ DROUTH RELIEF REPORT At the outset there were but seven counties in the district indicat - ing the need for aid, but three others. Antelope, Thurston and Pierce, were later added to the list. Many families in the original seven counties who at first thought they would be able to get through the winter without aid, found it necessary to ask for help, and the total number of families that has been supplied with food for themselves or feed for their livestock, increased from 958 in December to ap - proximately 4000 before the work ceased. Following the issuance of your proclamation calling for aid, the offer of the American Legion to conduct a drive for contributions was accepted, and 'this force was augmented by Chambers of Commerce, schools, farm organizations, the W. C. T. U., local Red Cross, D. A. R., P. E. O., churches, lodges, and other civic organizations, and citizens generally in all parts of the state. The first consignments were made to Knox County on November 30, and consisted of a car of supplies assembled by the Legion at Broken Bow and sent to Crof ton, also a part of a car assembled by the Legion and citizens of Ceresco and sent to Bloomfield, and a part of a car assembled by the Legion at. Norfolk and sent to Niobrara. Then on December 3, a mixed car assembled by the Ladies Aid Society of Waverly was sent to Spencer, and the following day the Legion Post at Lyman reported in a car load of potatoes which was sent to Nio - brara. Other shipments then followed in rapid succession. There were many discouraging obstacles to overcome along the way, but about this time the services of the broadcasting period of Woods Brothers Companies of Lincoln, over radio station KFAB, were tendered the movement with Floyd Atkins in charge. Mr. Atkins and myself made a trip to the district December 11, 12, and 13, and upon our return, he renewed his appeals with increased vigor. Other sta - tions and the newspapers cooperated, and the supplies and cash con - tributions increased tremendously. FREE SERVICE Arrangements hadibeen made with the railroads to handle all con - tributed shipments for the district, free of charge, from points within the state, and the Union Pacific, Burlington, Northwestern, Rock Island, Missouri Pacific, and M. &amp; O. roads all shared in this service. Likewise, the Railway Express Agency tendered its service to the or - ganization, and the Lincoln Telephone and Telegraph Company gave long distance service in connection with the relief work, free of charge. This service closed May 1, 1932. LOCAL DISTRIBUTING COMMITTEES Local distributing committees to supervise the distribution in the various counties were set up, these being known as the "State Relief </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 I ■ HttH supplies |P©^iSfflH^^^BiH w CAR OP SUPPLIES LOADED AT OXFORD This car was loaded and ready to move from Oxford at the time the picture was made. Men responsible for its loading are shown in the picture. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT Committee for . County". All shipments were con - signed to the chairman, no matter what point they went to in the county. The following is a list of the committees as named in the various counties: Antelope County : J. I. Stringflellow, Chairman.... Oakdale Legislator O. A. Snodgraas Brunswick... ■ ■ C. E. Rundquist Royal .Farmer Dr. D. L. Fletcher Orchard Physician Boj-d County Crist Andersen, Chairman Bristow .State Senator Wm. McQuistan Gross Supervisor Herman Storjohann Spencer Legion em ,™ A - Clifton Fairfax, S. D Supervisor Mr r a n 6 «";:&gt;■ Butte Attorney, Legion Mrs. C. A. Brownfleld Spencer Brown County John B Stoll, Chairman.. Johnstown County Commissioner c. C. Jones Ainsworth Editor A !bert Salzeman Ainsworth County Com., Legion w w dim ! per Long Pine Service Officer, Legion w. bi. Billeter , Ainsworth " Cedar County •X A ; K- Lammers ' Chairman..lHartington Retired Merchant Will Ferguson Hartington Farmer Oliver Rinehart Hartington..... Farmers Union H. H. Johnson :. Hartington Legion J. P. O'Furey. Hartington Editor W. H. O'Gara j Laurel Legislator Holt County John Sullivan, Chairman O'Neill Supervisor A. G. Miller Atkinson :...X,egion Geo. A. Miles O'Neill Editor E. O. Slaymaker Stuart Legislator John Longsworth Agee .Legion Roy Corr Meek Legion Keya Palm County M. M. Wood, Chairman Burton Supervisor £ aU i A - Mock - Springview Commander, V. F. W. K. S. Brookman 1 Springview Editor B. L. Genung 1 Cams Stockman Bert Stone..... J Brocksburg .Veteran ' Knox County Wm. Bruce, Chairman ....Verdigre County Commissioner Geo. C. Koster........ i Niobrara State Senator E. E. Jacobs L Creighton Legion A - L - Burbridge I Bloomffeld County Atty, Legion Fred Mueller Bloomfield Auto Dealer ?m° B 2S ner " Crofton Real Estate Allen Edson, Chairman Venus, Knox Co..Walnut Gr. Townahlp j-..-. .•:...-... ■,.:.■.. i .... - , ..... - ■'■ i-iriftB </seg>
            <seg id="p010">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT Pierce County John W. Blezek, Chairman Plainview Mayor M. Welch...: Osmond \V. A. Munson Wausa Wm. Nissen Plainview :.. Legion Dr. W. E. Weeces . Osmond ...Legion Rock County Chas. Riley. Chairman Bassett Com. American Legion M. Fredrickson Bassett County Commissioner J. M. Alderman Newport Harold Allen :..... Newport Adj. Am. Legion Thurston County R. J. Norris, Chairman- ...Winnebago Supervisor Chester Boughn Walthill Merchant Geo. Maryott Macy Merchant * In Cedar County, Mr. H. A. McCormick, Sr. of Wynot, succeeded Mr. Lammers, who resigned the fore part of the year because of a lack of time to devote to the work, These committees were empowered to set up local committee's at the various points within their respective counties to aid in the task of handling the supplies, but they retained general supervision over the work of distribution. Tht members of the committees had an untiring task, and many of the members worked all day and far into the night to keep the work in hand. SHIPMENTS HANDLED A total of 851. consignments were made from various points in Nebraska to the drouth district, distributed to the various counties and towns as follows: Antelope County — 81. Brunswick, 23; Orchard, 23; Orchard for Walnut Grove Township, 11; Royal, 24. Boyd County — 189. Anoka, 36; Anoka for Naper, 1; Bristow, 45; Lynch, 35; Lynch for North Holt County, 4; Monowi, 32; Spencer, 36. Brown- County — S. Ainsworth, 4; Long Pine, 4. Cedar County— 99. Coleridge, 2; Fordyce, 46; Hartington, 22; Randolph, 3; Wynot, 2 6. Holt County — 109. Atkinson, 21; Emmet, 7; Ewing, 10; O'Neill, 51; Page, 12; Stuart, 8. Keya Paha County— 13. Springview, via Bassett, 13. Knox County — 299. Bloomfield, 64; Bloomfield for Lindy com - munity, 3; Bloomfield for Bloomfield, Crofton and Lindy community, 2; Creighton, 18; Crofton, 71- Crofton for Lindy community, 1; Nio - brara, 62; Verdel, 34; Verdigre, 33; Winnetoon, 11. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT . Pierce County — 31. McLean. 3; Osmond, 12; Pierce, 4; Plainvlew, 12. Rock County — 7. Bassett, 5; Newport, 1; Newport and Bassett Jointly, 1. Thurston County — 15. Winnebago, 7; Walthill, 5; Macy, 3. At the outset, these shipments consisted almost exclusively of food supplies and clothing, and the contents of some of the cars were valued at from $1200.00 to as high as $1500.00 per car by the contributors. The shipments of grain were worth from $250.00 to $600.00 per car, ac - cording to the size and price when purchased, while the hay was worth from $75.00 to $150.00 per car at the point of loading. If the ship - ments averaged $500.00 per car, the total value of the supplies sent to the drouth district was $425,500.00. Add to this an average of $100.00 per car for freight and you have .an additional item of $85,100.00, making the total value of the supplies delivered approximately $510,600.00. I have stated that a total of 851 consignments were made to the district. A few of these were not delivered, but I have no way of knowing the exact number. After the consignment had been made and application filed for its free transportation, the assembling of the shipment was not completed for one reason or another, and the car was not used. The cash contributions to date have totaled $17,398.87, which has come from all sections of the State, and some from outside the State. Of the total, $5,906.86 represents Nebraska's share of the football game staged at Denver Dec. 5th, 1931, between the University of Ne- Draska and the Colorado Agricultural College teams for charity pur - poses. THE CONTRIBUTORS To the people who responded so generously throughout the State to the call for aid, is due sincere thanks. In all the history of the United States, I "doubt if there has ever been a response by the people of a single state to a call for help within their state, equal to the re - sponse on the part of the people of Nebraska in the winter of 1931-32. There has been more widespread distress on other occasions in other states, and more supplies hav? been shipped into those districts, but they have come from all parts of the country, while these supplies were contributed by Nebraskans for Nebraskans. A WORD OF APPRECIATION To Mr. Carl R. Gray, President of the Union Pacific Railroad Com - pany, Mr. P. Montmorency, General Freight Agent for the Burlington, Mr. G. A. Remington,! Assistant General Freight and Passenger Agent for the Northwestern, which line penetrated most of the afflicted territory, Mr. J. R. Duckworth, Assistant General Freight Agent for </seg>
            <seg id="p012">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT the Missouri Pacific, and. Mr. F. J. Shubert, General Freight Agent for the Rock Island, are due sincere thanks for the splendid co-operation extended on behalf of their respective roads. Likewise are thanks due Mr. S. B. Culbertson, Superintendent of the Railway Express Agency, for the co-operation extended in handl - ing the smaller shipments, and to Mr. J. H.' Agee, General Manager of the Lincoln Telephone and Telegraph Company, for providing free long distance service in connection with the relief work. The American Legion with Mr. Robert D. Flory as State Com - mander and Mr. H. H. Dudley as Adjutant, rendered a fine Bervice in making the first survey of the district and in assembling supplies, while the publicity given the work by the newspapers and radio sta - tions was of inestimable value. Out in the communities of the State, generous-hearted citizens gave of their time and effort in assembling supplies, and bperators of trucks contributed their services in getting them to the depots for shipment. It was a wonderful work, and a grateful people up there in the drouth district are appreciative of it. IX CONCLUSION Attached hereto are two statements. One shows the consignments to the various counties,- and the points in the counties to which the supplies went. This statement shows the date the consignment was made, where assembled, and who assembled by, where consigned to, the quantity, and contents. The second statement shows the amount of cash collected and how expended. The books and records in connection with the work have been audited by Mr. E. J. Avery, State Accountant in the State Audit - or's office, and his certificate is attached thereto. No one connected in any way with the state relief work has drawn one cent from the funds contributed, for services or for any other purpose. The work has been handled through the State Tax Com - missioner's office with the assistance of volunteer clerical help from other state departments. The Tax Commissioner's department has borne the expense for stationery and postage. There has been no expense of any kind to the relief fund except the cost of printing and mailing this report which will be paid from the balance on hand. Respectfully submitted, WM. H. SMITH, State Tax Commissioner. In Charge of Relief Work. Dated, Lincoln, Nebraska, May 6, 1932. : </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DISTRIBUTING SUPPLIES AT BLOOBIFIELD This picture shows how the conveyances lined up to receive supplies at Bloomfleld. Similar scenes were enacted throughout the entire district, distributions being made at most points on Wednesdays and Saturdays. Lines, often two and three blocks long, would form in the morning, und the work of distributing would con - tinue throughout the day. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">CONSIGNMENT OF SUPPLIES BY COUNTIES ANTELOPE COUNTY 1&gt;ii!c Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Jan. 23, 19.12 Doniphaii Legion Royal Car Hay 25 Artums Legion Royal Car Supplies 25 Adams Legion Orchard ....Car Supplies 25 Alexandria Comm Chas. Cane in chg. Brunswick Car Supplies 2G Sutherland Legion Brunswick Car .Hay 27 Morse Bluff Comm J. E. Vech in chg Brunswick Car Supplies 28 Jansen Legion Royal Car .Grain g 2S Barneston Legion Orchard Car .Feed ' 5 2S Sweetwater H. Aden in chg Brunswick Car .Feed d 29 Bancroft Legion Orchard Car .Hay *3 HO Gothenburg .'. Legion Royal Car .Hay * 31 Hazard Comm H. Aden in chg Brunswick Car .Grain ft) 31 Bennington Comm Leonard Mangold in chg Orchard Car .Hay M 31 Bennington Comm Leonard Mangold in ohg Royal Car .Hay E Feb. 2 Benkelman Legion Orchard Car .Corn jjjj 2 Sutherland Legion : Brunswick Car .Feed 3 Douglas community N. W. Dunlap in chg Royal Car .Corn and oats 2 3 Wann Community club....Fred Krahmer in chg Orchard Car Hay and corn 2 !! Darr Albert A. Kjar in chg Brunswick Car .Hay O :S Linwood ;..\V. J. Anderson, David Cy. Orchard— Wai. Gr. Car Hay V 4 Rising City Comm Com. Cl. Hargleroad. in chg. Orchard — Wai. Gr. Car '. Feed "* 6 . Elmcreek — pen. by Kearney Legion Brunswick Car .Hay (i Lexington Wlnside Legion Royal Car .Hay 8 Arlington Comm. W. I. Nelson in chg Orchard Car .Feed and Clo. 5 Beatrice Chamber of Commerce Royal Car ! Hay and grain 8 Seward Comm -■.-Erie Smiley In chg Brunswick Car .Grain and straw S Seward Comm Erie Smiley in chg. Orchard — Wai. Gr. Car .Grain and straw ' 11 Beaver City ..Comm. Club and Legion ....Orchard ,..Car Corn 11 Elmcreek from Richard Shoffstall ' Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p015">AXTKLOPK COUNTY Date Assigni-il Assc-mhlcri at Assembled by Consigned to Qunntlty Contents 11 . Odessa from Richard Shoffstall Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Hay 12 Pickrell : Lesion Orchard Car .Feed 12 Minden loaded at Newark Rollin Orcutt in dig Orchard for Wai. Gr. Twp Car Hay 12 Winside load. Lexington Legion Royal Car Hay 13 Kenesaw pch. by Hast-/? ings. Legion K....J. Floyd Arnold in dig.! Brunswick Car Straw 13 Kenesaw pch. by Hast- 2 ings Legion J. Floyd Arnold in dig Royal Car Straw O 13 Kenesaw pch. by Hast- ' cj ings Legion .1. Floyd Arnold in clig ..Orchard Car Straw 3 13 Lincoln Uni. Students Daily Nebraskan- in dig Orchard 5 or G bx Clothing 14 Willow Island Richard W Shoffstall In clig Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard for Wai. £2 Gr. Twp ..Car.. Hay rj 1G Elm Creek ;. Lincoln Chamber of Com Rrunswick Car Hay *j 1G Elm Creek Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Hay J 1G Auburn '. Legion, Kiwanis, Im. Club Orchard Car ; Grain and hay 3 17 Seward thru Erie Smiley.. Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw *q 18 Iluda Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Straw O 18 Hilda Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw j* 18 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car -Hay . 19 Seward :. Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Straw 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Cum Royal Car Straw 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car .Hay 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard — Wai. Gr. Car Hay 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Hay 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Hay 25 Riverdale Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Straw 25 Riverdale Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw 2G Gothenburg Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard — Wai. Gr. Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p016">ANTELOPE COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 26 Lexington Farmers U. St. Ex., Omaha Royal Car Hay 28 St. Paul Legion Brunswick Car Straw 28 St. Paul Legion Royal Car Straw 28 St. Paul Legion Orchard Car .....Straw 29 Mason City Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car... Alfalfa 29 Mason City Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Alfalfa Mar. 2 Fairbury Legion Brunswick Car .Corn and feed 3 Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Alfalfa Q 3 Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard for Wai. % Gr. Twp Car Alfalfa O 7 Linn, Kansas, loaded at cj Washington C. A. Johnson in chg Orchard for Wai. •'■.'. 2 • Gr. Twp Car .Grain and hay 7 Seward L Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick , Car .Straw &amp; oil cake g 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal .........Car .Straw &amp; oil cake 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw &amp; oil cake « 14 Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick Car Hay 14 ' Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Hay 14 Kearney ...: Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Hay g 16 Byron Comm Frank Schukar in chg Orchard — Wai. Gr. Car .Grain Apr. 1 Lyman — pch. with state Orch. R'yal, Brims, ■ O relief funds Wai. Gr Car.. Potatoes •» 4 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Com Brunswick ....Car Straw ' 4 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Com Orchard Car Straw 4 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Com Royal Car Straw 11 Tamora — pch. with state relief funds Orchard Car .Corn 11 Oxford — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Brunswick Cai .Corn 11 Oxford — pch. with state " relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Royal Car .Corn 19 Danbury — pch. by Lin - coln Chamber of Commerce thru Gunn of Lexington.-Orchard- — Wai. Gr. Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p017">BO YD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to _ Quantity. Contents Dec. 3, 1931 Waverly Ladies Aid Society Spencer ...Car Supplies 14 Tecumseh Legion Anoka 15,000 lbs .Mixed supplies 15 Lincoln -Pch. with relief funds .Spencer Car .Meat, flour Syrup, clothes 15 Wlsner Legion '■ Brlstow Car •. Mixed supplies 16 Scotia Fish Creek School Brlstow 2 boxes Supplies 16 Glenvil Schools Bristow 500 lbs :...Supplies 22 Emerson Legion Anoka- ............Quantity &amp; food M 23 Elm Creek Legion ..'. Spencer ..„ Car. .Hay , S 24 . Cambridge Legion Bristow Car....' Supplies O 26 Kimball &amp; Bushnell Legion, Lions, Farm Bristow Car Potatoes &lt;3 Bureau Federation .....: 3 28 Barneston Legion - Spencer Car. Supplies 28 Kearney Legion Bristow Car Feed &lt;*J 29 Lexington Citizens : .-...Anoka Car : '. Supplies 29 Beatrice-Blue Springs Legion and W. C. T. U Anoka Car Supplies H 30 Farnam Legion Bristow Car Supplies *J 30 McCook C. of C. &amp; Legion Lynch Car Supplies „ 31 Rlverdale E. R. Eliott in chg Spencer Car. Supplies 2 Jan. 3, 1932 Gresham vicinity S. J. Thompson in chg Bristow Car.. .Corn 5 Mlnden Carl T. Curtis in chg ...Anoka Car .Hay O 5 Lindsay Ladies Improvement Club ..Monowi 91 lbs Clothing 2 6 Moorefield 1 Legion Spencer Car ......Corn 0 Stromsbu'g, Polk, Osceola Legion Monowi Car Supplies 8 St'aplehurst Walter Zillig in chg Bristow Car :.. Supplies 9 Alfalfa Center community Guy Mansfield in chg Brlstow Car Peed supplies 11 Pleasanton Legion Monowi Car .straw 12 Battle Creek Bertha Koester Monowi Package Clothing 13 Cozad community Chas. Allen In chg Brlstow Car .Hay 13 Cozad community Chas. Allen in chg .-..Spencer Car .Hay 14 Wahoo community E. S. Scheiselbein in chg Anoka Car Supplies 14 Fremont Mrs. M. Sick in chg Spencer 5 sacks Clothing 1G Papillion community G. P. Miller in chg Bristow Car Supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p018">nOYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 16 Bartley Legion Lynch Car Corn 1 8 Wilbur Legion Bristow Car Corn lg Darr .'..Wayne business men Lynch Car .Hay 19 Talmage Legion Spencer Car .Hay 19 Hallam community W. L. Wiek in chg Monowi Car Feed 19 Cozad community ...: Sen. Allen in chg .....Lynch Car .Hay 19 Cozad community Sen. Allen in chg Monowi Car Hay ' 20 Nehawka Legion Spencer Car Feed o 20 Lexington Nebr. Wesleyan at Lincoln..Bristow Car..... Hay 20 Berea community .....Anton Stenberg in chg Bristow Car Supplies O 20 Bralnard community Chas. Novak in chg Spencer Car .Corn &lt;3 20 Cedar Bluffs Legion Lynch ..Car Supplies 3 21 Lincoln Nebr. Wesleyan Uni Bristow Car Supplies ™ 21 Gibbon ...:..... Legion Bristow Car Feed j* 21 Gibbon Legion .'. Monowi Car .Feed 21 Gibbon . Legion Lynch Car -Feed g 21 Milligan community Chas. Smhra in chg Spencer ,. Car '. Corn 21 Birdwood North Platte Legion Bristow Car Corn and hay 22 Oak Farmers Union Bristow Car Feed g 22 Bee community Win. Johannes in chg Spencer Car Straw &gt;3 22 Lexington Albert A. Kjar in chg Lynch ...„ .Car Hay O 22 Lexington Pch. by Wayne Busi. men ..Lynch Car .Hay g 23 Mitchell &amp; Morrlll Legion Bristow Car Potatoes 23 Palisade Pch. by Bancroft Legion ....Monowi Car ; Corn 24 Burr community G. J. Kahl in chg Lynch Car Feed 24 ■ Tekamah Legion '. Spencer : 3500 lbs Flour 25 Merna &amp; Berywn Legion..Ira Cool in chg Lynch Car Feed 25 Cozad community Sen. Allen in chg Bristow Car Hay 25 Cozad community Sen. Allen in chg. Monowi Car -Hay 26 Fairbury Legion Anoka Cai ....1 Corn 26 North Platte Legion Anoka Car Feed .26 Shelton .-.Legion Anoka Car .Supplies 27 Aurora and Hampton Legion Anoka .'.Car .Supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p019">BOYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents ■it Bennington .....Farmers Union State Org...Spencer Car Corn 27 Bruning community club..G. A. Paine in chg Monowi ...... Car .....Grain 28 Hershey Legion V. R. Taylor in chg Monowi Car .Feed 28 Chester community W. A. Fellers in chg Anoka , Car , .Feed 29 Miller community Geo. Harrington in chg Anoka ■. Car Corn 29 Prague community Edw. E. Bures in chg Spencer ...Car Grain and hay 29 Loup City Legion Ashton Bristow Car Corn and oats 29 Bancroft .Legion- ;...-.— .:r.~.-.Lynch — rrrr^nr. Car Hay . 30 Dorchester Legion Monowi Car .Grain 2 30 Gothenburg Legion Anoka Cm- Hay O 30 Gothenburg .-.Legion Spencer Car .Hay d 30 Cozad community Sen. Allen in chg Lynch Car Hay |3 Feb. 1 Culbertson Legion Anoka Car .Feed 2 Ohiowa -. Legion Spencer Car —Corn W 2 Bennington community ..Leonard Mangold in chg...Lynch ....Car..., , Hay 2 2 Fairfleld community John Broderick in' chg Bristow Xar Grain and flour « 2 Cortland community B. R. Burling in chg Spencer Car Grain 2 Louisville Legion r ....Anoka Car Feed 3 Cozad Pch. by Wayne Bus. men ..Lynch Car Hay 3 3 Dawson Legion and 1$ Humboldt community ..Legion Monowi Car Grain and hay O 4 Trenton community Victor Madsen in chg Spencer Car „ , Corn and flour jjj 4 Garland community F. W. Buls in chg Anoka Car Feed "' 4 Fairbury Legion : Bristow Car. Corn and hay 26 Lexington Pch. by Unl. PI. Bus. men..Lynch .....Car Hay 4 Tecumseh com. &amp; Legion J. B. Douglas in chg Monowi Car Hay 5 Talmage Legion Anoka Car Grain and straw 5 Ravenna community F. M. McGrew in chg Spencer Car Hay 6 Elba community Octave LeBlanc in chg Monowi Car Grain 6 Stella Chamber of Commerce Bristow Car Feed 7 Lyons Legion Anoka Cai Supplies 7 Peru Peru State Normal faculty.. Lynch Car Corn 8 DeWitt Legion Monowi ; Car Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p020">I1OYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to , Qunntity Contents 8 Garrison community C. A. Jaeke in chg Spencer Car ....Grain 8 Hastings Legion Lynch Car Corn and hay 8 Shelton Legion Anoka Car :Straw and feed 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in chg.. Bristow Car .Grain and straw 8 Seward community .-Erie Smiley in chg Lynch Car Grain and straw 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in chg Spencer Car Grain and straw 9 Bancroft By Swed. Mis. Ch. Pender.-Bristow Car. Hay and grain 10 Gothenb'g by Mr. Adams W. H. Brokaw in chg Monowl *. Car.... Hay 10 Gothenb'g by Mr. Adams W. H. Brokaw in chg Anoka Car .Hay g 11 St. Paul '. Legion Spencer Car. Flour, gram, etc. o 11 Guide Rock Com. C. Sen. Pedersen in ch.Spencer 2 or 3 boxes Clothing a 11 Red Cl'd com. from Cozad F. J. Munday and O. C. 53 Teel in chg Lynch Car Hay - . ™ 12 Cheney Community W. F. Ring in chg Monowl Car Grain and feed g 12 Verona Willis Hall Clay Cen. In ch. Anoka Car Grain and feed J3 13 Tamora community Otto Weld in chg ; Lynch Car .Grain « 13 Elmc'k by R. Shoffstall....pch. by Lin. Cham, of Com. Anoka ....Car Hay - *, 13 Elmc'k by R. Shoffstall....Pch. by Lin. Cham, of Com. Spencer Car .Hay 13 Elmc'k by R. Shoffstall....Pch. by Lin. Cham, of Com. Monowl Car.. .Hay . £ 14 Willow Is., R. Shoffstall....Pch. by Lin. Cham, of Com. Anoka for Naper ..Car .Hay 14 Rockford Farmers Union Coop. Ass'n. Anoka Car .Corn O 15 North Platte Legion :Monowl Car .Feed , w 15 Wallace North Platte Legion Lynch Car .Feed 15 Gering Legion Lynch Car Feed 16 Willow Island Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bristow Car Hay 17 . Willow Island Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowi Car Hay 17 Willow Island Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Spencer ...Car Hay 18 . Wahoo Legion Bristow Car .Feed 18 Lincoln park department.. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Lynch Car .Hay 18 Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Anoka : Car ; Straw IS Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Spencer Car ..Straw 18 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowl : Car .Hay 19 Broken Bow D. A. R Spencer Car ......Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">BOYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 19 ' Maywood Legion, Commercial Club.—Lynch Car Corn 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowl .Car Straw 20 Lexington Oakland Legion Anoka Car Hay 20 Lexington Oakland Legion Bristow Car Hay 20 ■ Lexington Oakland Legion Spencer Car Hay 22 Henry ..., Is Legion Bristow Car Potatoes 22 Wahoo Legion Bristow Car Straw 22 Litchfleld . JVpc. Ag. Stu... Public Schools .Lynch .........7..~-.....Ca.r. -Feed M 24 Shelton ...:. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Lynch Car -Hay 2 24 Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Anoka Car -Hay O 24 Shelton : Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowi Car -Hay . c! 24 Wood River Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Spencer .... Car -Hay jjj 24 Paul Oakland Legion Bristow Car Corn "■" 25 Qrd Noll Seed Co. Quiz, Legion-Spencer Car Feed and flour V 25 Ord Noll Seed Co. Quiz, Legion..Lyhch Car Feed and flour S 25 Josselyn bil, fr'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Anoka Car -Straw g 25 Josselyn bil. fr'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bristow .'. Car -Straw 26 Lexington Legion ;.Monowl '. Car Hay J 27 Buda shpt. from Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Lynch for Scott Tp. Car Hay 3 Mar. 2 Virginia community Rev. C. H. Zimmerman in . charge Lynch Car Grain and hay O 2 Liberty community J. A. Barr in chg Spencer Car Grain # 3 Johnson Legion :.j..Monowi Car Hay, grain, straw ""* 3 Buda , Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Lynch Car Straw 3 . Buda .■ Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Anoka Car..: Straw 3 Arcadia Ladies Auxiliary „ Bristow Cai Hay 7 Hindrey by Sutton com...E. F. Ochsner in chg Bristow Car Hay 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowi Car Straw &amp; oil cake 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Lynch Car Straw &amp; oil cake 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Anoka Car Straw &amp; oil cake 9 Goth'b'g, Fremont citizens Ray W. Hammond in chg.. .Bristow Car Hay 9 Goth'b'g, Fremont citizens Ray W. Hammond in chg.. .Monowi Car .Hay 9 Goth'b'g, Fremont citizens Ray W. Hammond in chg...Anoka Car .Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">BOYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 1 1 Exeter Community Bristow ..; .Car Supplies 11 Shpt. from No. Platte thru Gunn of Lexington Stanton Legion Anoka Car .Hay 12 Elmcreek pen. by New - man Grove ..„ Harry Henatsch in chg Lynch Car Hay . 14 DuBois community Rev. 0. J. Krueger in chg...Anoka Car Food and feed 14 Shelton Legion Bristow .-. Car .Hay 14 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Monowl Car .Straw O 15 St. Paul loaded at MidwayLegion .Spencer Car Feed g IB Gothenburg — : Wayne . § business men Rollie W. Ley in chg Lynch Car .Hay &gt;3 16 • Callaway Future Farm- X ers of America H. E. Blum in chg Lynch Car Straw j0 19 Overton L. C. of C. .........Anoka Car Hay H 19 Overton Lincoln Charber of Comm. Bristow Car Hay £ 20 Union — pch. with State H Relief funds From W. B. Banning Lynch for No. Holt .' and Boyd Car ,.Corn S3 20 Oak by Davenport Legion R.- J. Lowery in chg Lynch for No. Holt Cai.... Straw KJ 22 Amherst Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Spencer Car.... Straw 24 Minden Future Farmers . pj of America Alton Young in chg Lynch Car Grain i-3 28 Lexington . Legion Anoka Car Hay 28 Arnold Legion .....: Monowl Car .Hay 29 Pch. at Lincoln State Relief Funds Bristow 2500 lbs Groceries Apr. 1 Scottsbluff — pch. with state relief funds Bristow Car Potatoes 4 Lexington — pch. by Gretna Comm. with B. H. Schroder in chg Monowl Car .Hay 4 Lexington — pch. with Gretna Comm. funds with B. H. Schroeder in chg Anoka Car Hay 4 Curtis ....Edith Gramlich in chg. Bristow Box.... Clothing 7 Stromsburg Legion Bristow Car ...Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BOYD COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by ■ Consigned to Quantity Contents 11 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of Lexington Monowi Car Hay 11 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of Lexington Lynch Car Hay 11 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of Lexington Bristow Car .Hay 12 Holdrege — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Anoka Car ; Corn H 12 Holbroofc — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. § of Omaha Spencer Car Corn O 16 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of ' ' • S Lexington- Lynch for No. Holt Car Hay S O </seg>
            <seg id="p026">BROWN COUNTY Dale Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Dec. 17, 1931 Holdrege Legion Ainsworth Car Supplies 29 Lorton C. A. Peterson in chg Long Pine Car .Supplies Jan. 12, 1932 Lincoln Public Works Ainsworth ..2 Boxes Clothing 15 Exeter Exeter Elev. Co. &amp; Legion..Long Pine Car Supplies Mar. 1 Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Ainsworth Car JUfalfa Mar. 1 Elmcreek Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Long Pine Car .Alfalfa 14 Buda Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Long Pine Can Hay Apr. 11 Farnam — pch. with state relief funds Ainsworth Car Corn . o . ■ O ■ ■ ■ r ... . 1 O ... w </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CEDAR COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Doc. 4,1931 Fremont Legion Hartington. % Car Supplies 15 Scribner, with additional pickup at West Point .Legion Hartington Car Mixed supplies 2 9 Franklin Legion Hartington Car Supplies 31 Pickrell Community F. L. Pothast in chg Hartington Car Supplies Jan. 4, 1932 Pleasanton Legion Fordyce Car .Hay 12 ■ Odessa community G. H. Bentz in chg Fordyce Car JHay and grain 12 . Oxford community C. G. Gupton in chg Fordyce Car Supplies 5 13 Cozad community Chas. Allen in chg Hartington .....Car Hay O 14 Shelby Legion Car Supplies cl 15 Lexington community Albert A. Kjar in chg. Wynot Car Bay 16 Paul Legion Fordyce Car Supplies ~ 16 Talmage Legion Fordyce Car ■. Supplies W 16 Pawnee City : Legion Wynot Car Supplies 9 18 Palmyra Legion Fordyce Car Supplies g 19 Blair community Dr. Burr and Harold . S Stewart in chg Hartington Car Supplies 20 Denton community Frank Daniels in chg Hartington Car Feed 2 20 Weeping Water Legion and Farm Bureau ..Fordyce : Car .Feed 20 Springfleld J. H. Weise in chg Fordyce Car Feed O 21 Brady Legion :....: Wynot Car Hay g 21 Stuart pchse Cornbelt Comm. Co. Omaha Hartington Car ; .Hay 21 North Platte Legion Hartington Car. ■. Mixed feed 21 Unadilla community B. G. White in chg Fordyce Car Feed 21 Unadilla community B. G. White in chg Fordyce Car Feed 21 Darr Albert A. Kjar in chg Fordyce Car Hay 22 Pleasanton Legion Fordyce Car. Straw 22 Lexington Gunn Hay Co Fordyce Car .Hay 22 Lexington Gunn Hay Co Hartington Car Hay 22 Paul Legion Wynot Car Supplies 24 Gibbon Legion r. Hartington Car Hay 24 Gibbon Legion Fordyce Car .Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p028">CEDAR COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by " Consigned to Quantity Contents 24 Gibbon Legion : Wynot Car Hay 24 Greenwood Legion Wynot Car Grain 24 Callaway Legion Hartington Car .Supplies 25 Nebr. City community G.- E. Conkey Co. in dig Fordyce Car Feed 25 Nebr. City community G. E. Conkey Co. in clig Wynot Car ......Feed 25 Greeley Center comm Geo. O'Malley in clig Fordyce Car Grain 26 Fullerton Albion Legion Wynot Car , .Hay 26 Geneva Legion Hartington Car Corn and oats „ 27 Wilsonville Legion Wynot Car Supplies § 28 Union community W. B. Banning in chg Fordyce Car Corn and oats o 28 Tarnov ~ Father Narclssia coiigrega. Fordyce Car Grain c! 28 Garland community F. W. Buls in charge Hartington Car .Feed d 29 Talmage .• Legion Wynot Car Supplies "" 29 Loup City Legion Randolph Car Grain g 29 Stelnauer community ......Rev. E. TIschauer in clig.. .Fordyce Car Grain . P 30 Gothenburg Legion Hartington Car Corn g 30 Callaway Legion Fordyce Car Feed !| Feb. 2 Fairmont Legion , Wynot Car Corn 2 Platte County : A. W. Frlschholz in chg Fordyce Car Straw ' 2 3 Lexington C. H. Gunn in chg. Hartington Car Hay 3 Lexington ,." ,....C. H. Gunn in chg Wynot Car Hay O 4 Wheeler, Kansas Com. — G. Fichtner in clig.. .Hartington Car Corn • . j* 4 Palisade Commercial Club Fordyce Car Corn 4 Ashland i Kuhl-Reese Co Fordyce Car Mixed supplies 5 York — ship, from Strang Legion : ; Wynot Car Corn 6 Caltaway — ship, from Cozad '.Legion Fordyce Car Hay 6 Callaway — ship, from • Willow Island ...., Legion Fordyce Car ......Hay 7 Hendley community C. E. Goble in chg Hartington Car Corn 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in chg Wynot Car Grain and straw 9 ■ Ravenna community F. M. McGrew in chg Hartington Car Hay and grain 9 Peru Legion Fordyce Car Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p029">CEDAR COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 10 Shipped by County Agt. ■ from Gibbon ...W. H. Brokaw in chg Fordyce Car Hay 10 Shipped by County Agt. from Gibbon W. H. Brokaw in chg Hartington Car Hay 11 Eddyville Legion .Wynot Car Feed 12 Hayes Center community Spt. from Palisade ...L. W. Enyeart in chg Fordyce Car ..Corn 13 Haspur by Grand Island. .Legion .'...Wynot .Cnr Hay O 13 Haspur by Grand Island.. Legion Coleridge Car Hay W 13 Benkelman Legion Fordyce Car... Feed O 14 Wil. Is. by R. ShoffstalL.Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Hartington Car Hay 18 Cedar Rapids community..\V. M. Smith in chg Fordyce :..Car Straw H5 18 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wynot Car Hay M 20 Doniphan ..Gr. Island C. of C. &amp; Legion Wynot Car Hay g 20 Doniphan Gr. Island C. of C. &amp; Legion Fordyce Car Hay p 24 . Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Coleridge Car '. Hay H 25 Aurora Business Men's Club Wynot Car Straw *1 25 Aurora Business Men's Club Fordyce .....Car Straw 27 Pleasanton Legion — baled and loaded by Fordyce men Fordyce .5 Cars Straw H 27 Uuda shpf. from Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wynot Car Hay Jtf Mar. 1 Pleasanton Legion — Fordyce men doing baling and 2 loading :. Fordyce 5 Cars Straw hj 1 Mason City ....Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wynot Car Alfalfa 2 Litchfleld community A. \V. Johnson in chg Wynot Car Hay and grain 7 Pleasanton Leglon : — baled and loaded Fordyce citizens Fordyce 2 Cars Straw 14 Davenport, loaded at Oak R. J. Lowery in chg Wynot Car Straw 31 Amherst Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wynot Car Straw Apr. 2 McCook A. T. Holcomb in chg Wynot Car Corn 4 Cambridge — pch. with state relief funds Randolph Car Hay 11 Oyerton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of </seg>
            <seg id="p030">CEDAR COUNTY T);ite Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Lexington Wynot Car Hay 12 Bertrand — pen. with state relief funds thru Fin. Un. of Omaha Fordyce Car Corn 19 . Danbury — pch. thru Gunn of Lexington by L. C. C Randolph Car ......Hay 19 Edison — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Fordyce Car Corn § as to o </seg>
            <seg id="p031">HOLT COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at .Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Dec. 8,1931 Dannebrog and Boelus ....Legion ...O'Neill 4000 lbs Supplies 4 Hooper l...Legion Atkinson ...20,000 lbs Supplies ' 14 DuBois Legion O'Neill 3700 lbs Mixed supplies IB Lincoln Pch. with relief funds O'Neill : Car Salt pork, syrup, flour, clothing 21 Davenport, Neb. ...: Rev. Hershey in chg Atkinson Car ...Supplies 21 Scottsbluff Boy Scouts ...-O'Neill Shipment of Xmas supplies 21 North. Bend Legion Stuart ....3500 lbs Supplies 23 Platte Center Rev. Leo Malnzer in chg.....O'Neill Car Supplies 2 23 Holdrege Legion Ewing Car Supplies O 24 Cambridge Legion O'Neill Car Supplies c! 28 Elmwood E. J. Cook in charge Stuart Car Supplies Jjj 28 Kearney .' Legion O'Neill Car Feed * 30 Plattsmouth .....Legion .". O'Neill Car Supplies V Jan. 3,1932 Minden Carl T. Curtis in chg. ........Stuart Car .•-Supplies S 4 Maxwell Legion Atkinson Car Hay and corn « 8 Curtis Legion O'Neill Car Corn S 9 Scottsbluff ...■: Station KGKY O'Neill Car Supplies 11 Elkhorn community C. D. Bull in chg ..Ewing Car Corn g 12 Alvo community Carl Ganz in chg O'Neill Car. Corn 13 Firth community ..: J. E. Harms in chg O'Neill Car Supplies O 14 Millard community G. E. Nelson in chg .O'Neill Car Supplies jjj 14 Falls City community M. J. Helnzelman in dig; O'Neill Car Supplies 18 Columbus community A. W. Frischholz in chg O'Neill Car Supplies 19 Albion Legion Atkinson Car Hay 20 Stanton Legion Purchased at Lexington Ewing Car Hay 20 Hazard community Ernst H. A. dela Motte, chg. O'Neill Car Feed 20 Hemingford community ..Anton Stenberg in chg O'Neill Car Supplies 21 Hazard community H. Aden in chg O'Neill Car Hay and grain 21 Darr Albert A. Kjar in chg Ewing Car Hay 18 Columbus community A. W. Frischholz in chg O'Neill Car Supplies 22 Ord community E. C. Leggett In chg Atkinson Car....: Supplies 22 David City community Verne Campbell in chg Atkinson Car Grain </seg>
            <seg id="p032">HOLT COUVTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled l&gt;y Consigned fo Quantify Contents 22 Elwood community I. S. Fitzsimmons in chg Atkinson Car Feed 22 Elwood community I. s. Fltzslmmons in dig Swing Car Feed 23 Amherst community Roy Curd in dig Stuart Car Grain and flour 21 Darr Albert A. Kjar in chg Ewing Car Hay 25 Shickley community Dr. C. W. Wiggins in dig. ..Ewing Car Corn and oats 2G Fullerton , Albion Legion Page Car Hay 26 Clarkson community Anton Odvarka in dig Page Car Supplies 2G Clay Center community ..H. M. Hanson in dig Atkinson Car Supplies 27 Craig Legion Page ..Car Supplies 2 28 Sterling Legion and Farmers Union..Atkinson Car Grain O 28 Legion Curtis Page Car Corn S 29 Talmage Legion Page Car Supplies 3 29 Ashton Legion Ewing Car Corn and oats * 29 Avoca and Otoe jointly ....Elmer Hallstrom in dig Atkinson Car Oats B&gt; 30 Gothenburg Legion . Atkinson Car Corn M 30 Gothenburg '. Legion Ewing Car Hay £ 30 Cozad community '.Sen. Chas. E. Allen in dig. .Page Car Hay H Feb. 2 Platte County A. W. Frischholz in chg Atkinson Car Straw 3 Litchfield and Sw. Water Nebr. State Granges — JO S. W. Samuelson ..•. O'Neill Car -Grain 5 5 Emerald community ...Mgr. Pm. Un. Coop. El. chg. Stuart- Car.... Grain O 8 Gothenburg Legion Page Car ---Corn f 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in chg Ewing Car Grain and straw* 3 11 York County Board and radio station KGBZ O'Neill Car Mixed supplies ' 11 Burchard community ......P. J. Ullman in chg Atkinson Car....' . . Feed and Sup 12 Reynolds Legion Page Car : Grain and hay 18 Cedar Rapids community W. M. Smith in chg ..O'Neill Car Straw 19 Pleasanton Legion with A. G. V. Hays in charge Page Car Straw . 20 Doniphan G. I. Cham. Com. &amp; Legion. .Page Car Hay 24 Overton Lions club H. H. Beltner in chg O'Neill Car.... Hay 25 Belfast Greeley citizens O'Neill , Car.... Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT 0) eu a; &gt;■ ~~~ — — — —^— &gt;&gt; aa* 2 * rt o u o w cd .c ____ K £ ~ •= 555 -O " d ' 2 &lt;o 2 o — — S £ t t h 2 t. a BJiiiaaaiEiSacsOiii'; ! X fc, K o &lt;I •&lt; C5 en 02 &lt;w en U p S 53 p to. S3 S3 S3 w p ro oo 33 33 fa w oa ai w ■! i Mi 1 1 1 s i i i. i i iii!!Hii.ji!i.nii •*• •!■*•!!!!!!•: ■ i : i i i ' i i i '•'•'''■ I | M j| I ] | j j I IgS ji ; • i i ■ i i i_ • : ; IS • i • • c ' b h ■- ~' "' ■"' ** ■" ** •" ** ° o ti ti ti t; ti t. 1 1.' t.' t.' tj t; t,' o u t.' ti t&gt;' aaaadassiaaaau) "-&gt; assddadadsaasoaeias OUUUUUUUUUUHiia n OOUOUOOOUDUUnOUaO : '• '• :;:.':: r : : : : ::::::::::: ■ i i i : • i ::;;::::::;;: ■ ; • . • g I ! | [ i I | I | i | : | : ; j : ! i j ! j j j j j j I j I I j i I'M i i i ! 1 1 i i 1 1 I' i I ! N i 1 1 M j i M 1 1 1 ,§ f s i : a i e '• .'* a ■&gt; i- i i s i i i i : i : ; I I I i I i c i i ' = = = =-= 25=S«iS= ~ i«S5 = 'S = = ' = * j = - = « ° o ioooo-«io&lt;!po&lt;iKqq q &lt; h q q b H q q b- q S q S b h ■&lt; h £ ■liiEiES'EEEEi! I fi-S M g g . g | g i 3 ISSiSSSS.ii j :|- i55 US i i i \SS6 I Eh ••o;co c oooo«: ; •c'H — jSoo'^oM'iiet-Oy. "i IJIIliPI ! I"iIlElI?f nil § i • r&amp; i i M M ! M-s i M l£ M-s 1 1 J I i I ! \ j I :: E : i :!:::: i § j- : i i j g ] rO • • | g | \ \ j j | . i IS m n.i 1 1 Uni»i 1 1 1| Mi^UI I i I ! ! ! a &lt; ■ •? s " j «» • I ! o ■ * S S . i I Ji jgi M!I*lf»|H| kMiJ&amp;ljlU! •" S^-§S|=^|g|-g-g£S'SES3'S 1 S l gg^g|S; = 9 3Slg Qi5&lt;!&lt;!gSfcC3torato&lt;B. o o S &lt;! t&gt; P3 « Q S 02 m O? fe &lt; &lt; K 03 £ t-" e . « j </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036">HOLT COUNTY bate Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consl K ned to Qunntity Contents ■ 24 Wymore community J. A. Maguire in chg Emmet Car Grain 24 Newark Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Atkinson Car Straw 25 Grand Island Legion 0. E. Cunningham in chg. ..O'Neill Car Bran 28 Lexington by Red „ Cloud citizens P. J. Munday in chg O'Neill .-. Car Hay Apr 1 Scottsbluff— pen. with state relief funds O'Neill Car Potatoes 8 Pleasant Dale — pch. with state relief funds O'Neill Car Corn 11 Seward— pch. with state relief funds O'Neill Car Corn o 11 Seward— pch. with state relief funds O'Neill Quantity Hour, corn meal g 11 Ashland — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un, O of Omaha Page Car Corn =j 1 1 Oxford — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. ■ S of Omaha Atkinson .....: Car Corn 12 Funk — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of H Omaha Stuart Car Corn £ 15 Beaver City — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. H Un. of Omaha O'Neill Car Corn 18 Stockham .....Lincoln Chamber of Comm. O'Neill : Straw Car 19 Oxford — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. M of Omaha Emmet Car Corn JO 20 Lyman— pch. with state relief funds „. Atkinson Car Potatoes g 21. Albion - Legion OINeM ..Car Straw </seg>
            <seg id="p037">KNOX COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Nov. 30, .1931 Broken Bow Legion Crofton Car Supplies 30 Ceresco Legion Bloomfield Part of car Supplies 30 Norfolk .. : Legion Niobrara Part of car Supplies Dec. 4 Lyman Legion Niobrara Car Potatoes 10 Friend Legion . Crofton % car Mixed supplies 14 Oakland Legion Bloomfleld (for Lindy Comm.) Car Mixed supplies 14 Merna Legion Crofton Car Feed ■ 16 Lincoln '. Pch. with relief funds Bloomfleld - Car Pork, clothing, 2 flour, syrup o 15 Crete : Ladies organizations Crofton Car Mixed supplies d 16 Hickman 1 Farmers ....Niobrara Car Supplies 2 18 Louisville Rees Hastin in charge Verdel Car. Mixed supplies 18 Lincoln Ply. Cong, church, Lincoln. .Crofton 3 boxes -Clothing W 18 Bertrand ...Legion ...: Crofton Two cars Supplies S 18 Bertrand Legion Bloomfleld Car Supplies j-j 18 Geneva Rev. Tudor In charge Crofton Shipment of Clothing S 20 Seward and Milford Legion Verdel Car Supplies 21 Auburn Nemaha Co. Legion Niobrara Car. Supplies 3 22 Lincoln ...Grainger Bros Bloomfleld Shipment of Dolls 22 Bennington ...Luther League Bloomfleld 10 barrels Supplies O 23 Oconto Mrs. J. J. Bobllts in chg Bloomfleld (for W Lindy Comm.) ..Car.'. Supplies 23 Elm Creek .....Legion Verdigre Car Mixed supplies 24 Cambridge Legion Niobrara Car Supplies 24 Table Rock Legion ...Crofton Car Supplies 24 Albion Methodist S. S Bloomfleld Bbl, box,2 sacks..Clothing, etc. 26 Beaver Cros. and Cordova.-Legion Niobrara Car Supplies 26 Arcadia Legion Auxiliary Bloomfield Box. Clothing 26 Giltner High School Verdigre 2 boxes Clothing 2 8 Kearney Legion Bloomfleld Car Feed 28 Kearney Legion Niobrara ....Car .-. Feed 2 9 Lexington Citizens Crofton Car Supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p038">KNOX COUNTV Dnte Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 29 Grand Island Legion Niobrara Car Flour 30 Huraboldt Citizens with Rev. Theo. Shepard in charge Crofton Car Supplies 31 Spalding Legion Niobrara Shipment Shoes &amp; Clothing Jan. 2, 1932 Axtell Legion and Auxiliary :.. Crofton (for Lindy Comm.) Car '. Supplies 4 Herman Legion Verdigre Car Supplies 6 Oxford Lions Club, A. S. Pettit chg. Niobrara Car Corn 7 Bennett Community, E. D. Wiley O in charge Creighton Car.... Supplies o 7 Ravenna Legion Bloomfleld Car. Supplies c! 7 Riverdale community E. R. Elliott in charge Niobrara ...-. Car Straw H 8 Columbus community A. W. Frischolz in chg Bloomfleld Car Supplies 8 8 York KGBZ, Geo. R. Miller, chg...Niobrara ...Car Supplies fd 9 Gering Station KGKY, Scotts bluff. .Crofton Car Supplies M 9 Erling, Iowa Rev. Jos. Steiger in chg Crofton .Car Corn m 11 Bennett :..... Com., E. D. Wiley in chg...Creighton Car 'Supplies jjjj 11 . Arapahoe Legion ...Verdigre Car Supplies 11 . Arapahoe Legion Verdel Car Supplies W 12 Orleans E3. -M. Neubauer in chg. ......Niobrara Car Supplies S 21 Poole Legion Crofton Car Straw O 13 Falls City community M. -J. Heinzelman in chg Niobrara Car Supplies . JS 13 Doniphan Hastings Legion '. Bloomfield Car Hay ** 13 Edgar community Oscar Schlechtman in chg...Bloomfield Car Supplies 13 Cozad community Chas. Allen in chg Niobrara „ 2 cars ..Hay 13 Cozad community Chas. Allen in chg Crofton Car Hay 14 Pleasanton Legion Bloomfleld Car Corn 14 Lexington Kiwanis Verdigre Car Hay 14 . " Darr Albert A: Kjar of Lex., chg. Creighton .Car Hay 15 Darr Albert A. Kjar of Lex., chg. Crofton Car Hay 16 Lincoln H. J. Amen in chg. .... Niobrara Car Supplies 15 Ravenna Legion Verdigre Car Hay 16 Malcolm community Al Otterman in charge Bloomfleld Car Supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p039">KNOX COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by .Consigned to Quantity Contents 16 Lexington Albert A. Kjar in chg Crofton Car Hay 16 Bellwood Legion Bloomfleld Car Supplies 18 Syracuse Legion Crofton ...Car Supplies 18 Lindsay A. P. Peterson Verdel Package ..-Supplies 18 Omaha Business men, Wayne Bloomfleld Car Grain 18 Lexington Wayne business men Bloomfleld Car Hay 19 Wllsonville Legion Niobrara Car Feed 19 Lexington Legion : Crofton Car Hay M 19 Cozad Sen. Allen in chg Verdigre Car Hay S 19 . Milford community A. J. Welch in chg. Niobrara Car Grain O 19 Davey community Mike Gleason in chg '.. Crofton Car Corn Q 20 Superior community. Mayor Lentner in chg Verdigre, Car Supplies 3 20 North Lincoln churches Fred Johns in chg Bloomfleid Car Supplies "" 20 Hubbell Legion Crofton Car .' Feed •£ 20 Bee community Wm. Johannes in chg ..Niobrara 2 cars Supplies 2 • 20 Stanton Legion '. Lexington Verdel Car Hay . £ 20 Alliance farmers Anton Stenberg In chg Bloomfleld Car Supplies § 20 Omaha, Farmers Union State Exchange Niobrara Car Feed J 20 Gretna Legion, Woman's Club Creighton Car Supplies 3 20 Cook Legion Bloomfleld .Car Hay . 21 Raymond community Edw. Olson in chg Niobrara Car Supplies O 21 Papilllon community G. P. Miller in chg Niobrara Car Supplies 2 21 Birdwood Nor. Platte Leg. in chg Verdigre .....Car Baled cane 21 Lexington Albert A. Kjar in chg Niobrara Car Hay 21 . Lexington Albert A. Kjar in chg Creighton Car Hay 21 Lexington Albert A. Kjar in chg Crofton Car Hay 22 Updike Grain Co., Omaha.. Pch. by Wayne Bus. men ....Verdel Car Oats 22 Cook community E. W. Frisch in chg Bloomfleld Car Supplies 22 Denton community Frank Daniels in chg Verdigre Car Supplies 22 Murdock Farmers Union Bloomfleld Car Grain 22 Cedar Bluffs community ....°- M. Festermacher in chg...Crofton Car Supplies 22 Darr Albert A. Kjar in chg Bloomfleld Car Hay 22 Lexington Pch. by Wayne Bus. men....Bloomfleld Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p040">KNOX COUNTY Dntc Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 23 Lexington Legion Crofton Car Hay 23 Ft. Crook Farmers Union Niobrara Car Corn 23 Alliance ....Farmers Union Bloomfleld Car Potatoes &amp; feed 23 Dunbar community Martin Peterson in dig Crofton Car Supplies 24 Willow Island community..C. B. Wilson in chg Niobrara Car Hay 24 Blair Com. and Legion Mayor Stewart and Dr. Burr in charge .Verdel Car Supplies 25 Pawnee City community ....Art Davis In charge Verdel Car Supplies 25 Blue Hill ....County Agent Taggart chg...Niobrara Car ... Grain 2 25 Waterloo community H. B. Lang in charge Niobrara Car Feed O 25 Birdwood Nor. Platte Legion in chg...Creighton Car Hay d 25 North Platte .....Legion Bloomfleld Car Feed 25 Greeley Center community Geo. O'Malley in charge Verdigre Car Hay ■ w 25 Cozad community Sen. Allen in charge Verdel Car Hay SJ 26 Greenwood Legion Crofton Car Grain 2 26 Hershey .Legion Verdigre ....„....'. Car Feed w 26 Birdwood Legion Verdel ...Car Feed % 26 Wauneta by farmers C. E. Aldrich in charge Bloomfleld Car Corn 26 ' Hemingford community ....H. C. Hansen In charge Crofton Car. : Potatoes 2 26 Odell community J. C. Doehling in charge Verdel Car... Supplies 27 Odessa Legion Crofton .......Car „ Feed O 27 Omaha, reported by Wayne Nels P. Updike, sole • 2 contributor . Verdel Car Oats 27 Fremont Dodge County Farmers Un...Crelghton Car. Grain 27 Beemer community Rev. H. J. Buerger in chg.. .Niobrara Car Supplies 27 Dodge Legion Bloomfleld. Car.... : Feed ■28 Crete '. Legion and business men ..Bloomfleld •. Car : Grain 28 Hoag Farmers Union Verdigre Car Oats 28 Pleasanton Legion Creighton Car Straw 28 Stella community R. E. Uhley in charge Creighton Car Grain 28 Hebron community W. R. Wicks in charge Crofton Car.. .-... Corn 29 Hastings ...Legion Crofton Car Food Sup. 29 Eustis community Henry Oelkers In charge ....Verdel Car Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p041">KNOX COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 29 Loup City Legion Bloomfleld Car Hay 29 Loup City Legion Crofton ....'. :Car_ Hay 30 Gothenburg Legion Bloomfleld Car Hay 30 Maxwell Legion ..Crofton Car Hay 30 , Cozad community Sen. Allen in charge Verdigre Car Hay Feb. 1 _J Holbrooke Legion~_ — Verdigre Car Corn — 1 Omaha Geo. Brandels ......Niobrara 4 boxes „ Clothing . . 1 Omaha Paxton &amp; Gallagher Co Niobrara 4000 lbs Groceries 2 Fremont Dan V. Stephens Niobrara 4000 lbs Groceries 2 2 Poole by one farmer Baling done by Legion O and Lit. Society Creighton Car Straw d 2 Goehner community M. Madison in charge Bloomfleld Car Supplies ■ a 2 Bennington community Leonard Mangold in charge.. Bloomfleld (for Lindy) Car Hay W ' 2 Pleasant Dale community ..Sam Allen in charge Verdel Car : Grain &amp; hay [3 3 Cozad Pch. by Wayne Bus. men....Bloomfleld Car Hay w 3 Cozad Pch. by Wayne Bus. men....Creighton Car ...Hay j| 3 Cozad Pch. by Wayne Bus. men....Verdel Car ...Hay 3 New. Gr. : — Ship. Kearney..Legion Crofton Car Straw 5 3 New. Gr. — Ship. Kearney..Legion Verdigre Car Hay 3 Lindsay ; Legion Verdel 602 lbs Supplies O 3 Darr Albert A. Kjar Crofton : Car .'.., Hay W 4 Ceresco community A. B. Blomstrom in charge..Winnetoon Car Corn 4 Sumner community ....S. E. Pearson in charge Bloomfleld Car Mixed Sup. 4 Guide Rock community ....Sen. Henry Pedersen Winnetoon Car Hay 4 Tecumseh Com. &amp; Legion..J. B. Douglas in charge Creighton Car Hay and Groc. 5 Kimball community A. L. Miller In charge Niobrara Car Potatoes 5 Holstein community L. G. Langhorst in charge..Crofton Car Supplies 5 Cozad — pch. by Scotia citi. P. J. Seefus in charge Verdigre ..: Car Hay 5 Elmcreek community E. H. Mack in charge Bloomfleld Car Grain and hay 7 Fullerton Legion Winnetoon Car Hay 7 Lexington — Mr. Busskohlof Blfleld Bloomfleld Car Hay 7 Miller community Geo. Harrington in charge.-Crelghton Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p042">KNOX COUNTY Date AsslRiied Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 7 Dalton community club ....G. P. Neikum In charge Bloomfield Car Corn 7 Dalton community club ....G. P. Neikum in charge :BTd, Crof." &amp; L'dy Car Potatoes 8 Bruno community Ben Doeckel in charge Nlobrara Car Corn and hay 8 Alliance community C. E. Brown In charge Nlobrara Car Hay 8 Red Cloud Com. Shpt. from Cozad P. J. Munday In charge Crofton .Car Hay 8 Millerton community Rev. Enno Schuelke in chg. Bloomfield iCar Straw 8 Millerton community Rev. Enno Schuelke in chg. Winnetoon Car Straw and Grain 8 Benson loaded at Irvington J. E. Haaae in charge Verdel Car Grain and Sup. 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in charge Verdigre Car Grain and straw o 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in charge Crofton Car Grain and straw C 8 Seward community Erie Smiley in charge Bloomfield Car Grain and straw 3 9 Belvidere Legion Crofton Car ...Hay and grain * 9 Franklin Com. Shpt. . 5 from Hildreth Leon Samuelson In chg Niobrara Car Corn and oats £j 10 Overton thru Gunn of . . S Lexington Farmers Union of Omaha ..Crofton Car Hay 10 Bruno community Ben Doeckel in charge Niobrara Car Hay 11 Culbertson Legion Winnetoon Car Feed g 11 Naponee community M. R. Beckord in charge Crofton Car Grain and hay 11 Paul thru Schmitt of M'd'n Pch. by Farm. Un., Omaha..BIoomfield Car Corn O 11 Ravenna, Slip, from Poole..Legion Niobrara Car Hay •« 11 Beemer Com. pch. at Updike Omaha Rev. J. H. Buerger jn chg...Niobrara Car Grain 11 Odessa from R. Shoff stall.. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel J Car Hay 11 Odessa from R. Shoff stall.. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdigre Car Hay 11 Odessa from R. Shoffstall.-Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Creighton Car Hay 11 Fullerton Legion Crofton Car. Flour and hay 12 Bancroft Legion, thru Milligan &amp; Son of Sioux City ....Crofton Car Hay 12 Bancroft Legion, thru Milligan &amp; Son of Sioux City ....Bloomfleld Car Hay 12 Franklin community Leon Samuelson in chg Creighton Car Alf., hay, meal 12 Grand Island Shpt. from Maxwell Legion Niobrara Car Hay </seg>
            <seg id="p043">KNOX COUNTY Dntc Assigned- Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned. to Quantity Contents 12 Valparaiso, community* J. W. Tokorny in charge ....Winnetoon Car Corn 14 Sutton community E. F. Ochsner in charge Crofton Car Corn 14 Sweetwater community Christ Rathjen in charge... .Verdel Car Straw and grain. 14 Alma Odd Fellows Lodge, Fratik Werner in charge Bloomfleld Car Grain 14 -.Fremont : Dodge County Farmers Un. Niobrara Car Corn and oats 14 Roca and Hickman Legion with J. R. Smith in charge Crofton Car...... Grain, food and _ clothing 2 15 Omaha ..;. Farmers Un. St. Exchange..Niobrara Car Groc. and Cloth, o 15 Kearney State Teachers College Crofton Car Hay d .15 Kearney State Teachers College Bloomfteld Car Hay Jj| - 16 Hindrey Kearney D. A. R Winnetoon Car Hay * 16 Loaded at Odell by Be'tr'e..Mrs. Koslowski in charge ..Niobrara Car Hay SJ 17 ■ Shpt. from Lexington by L.B. Clithero and County S Board of York County ....Verdigre Car '. Hay ' G 18 Lindsay community A. P. Peterson in charge ....Verdel 1000 lbs Supplies S 18 Culbertson church people..F. C. Bbinger in charge Crofton Several boxes Clothing, shoes 18 Josselyn, ship, f'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel Car Hay *jj 18 Josselyn, ship, f'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Hay 18 Josselyn, ship, f'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Hay O 18 Josselyn, ship, f'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Winnetoon Car Hay 3 18 Josselyn, ship, f'm Overton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdigre Car.; Hay 19 Broken Bow D. A. R Verdel Car Hay 19 Linwood community F. F. Mundil in charge Crofton Car Hay, grain, flour 19 Brainard Com. Shpt. from Gothenburg' Chas. Novak in charge Verdigre Car Hay 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfield Car Straw ,20 Abie community Ed. Brt in charge Crofton Car Corn 20 Grand Island Cham, of Com. &amp; Legion Crofton Car Food and Cloth. 23 Kearney by A. R. Hecht ....Lincoln Ag. College Creighton Car Hay 23 Fremont May Brothers Bloomfleld 200 lbs Beans </seg>
            <seg id="p044">5 . \ KNOX COUNTY Date AsslRned Assembled nt Assembled by ' Consigned to Quantity Contents 23 Alliance Trainmen with Roy Howard in charge Niobrara Car Hay 23 Blue Hill Commerce Club..N. I. Stork In charge Bloomfleld Car Straw 23 Millerton Rev. Enno Schuelke in chg. Verdigre Car Straw 24 Greeley citizens Geo. O'Malley in.charge Crofton Car Hay 24 Greeley citizens Geo. O'Malley in charge Bloomfleld Car Hay 24 Greeley citizens Geo. O'Malley in charge Verdel Car , Hay 24 Wood River Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Winne'toon Car. Hay 24 Ogallala Legion Verdigre Car Corn 2 24 Shpt. from Wyoming Farm. Un. St. Ex., Omaha..Creighton Car Corn O 25 North Loup community ....Rev. L. A. Hawkes in chg...Bloomfleld Car Hay and food d 25 Gr. Island Legion, C. of C. 0. E. Cunningham in chg...Crofton Car Sugar beet pulp d 25 Odessa •. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car. Alfalfa w 25 Odessa i...Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel Car Alfalfa . ffl 25 Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Com'm.Winnetoon Car Straw 3 26 . Broken Bow Pub. Ser. Cl...Claris Talbot in charge Verdigre Car Wild hay « 26 Hamlet by Grand Island ' B Leg. and C. of C O. B. Cunningham in chg...Nlobrara Car Corn 27 Alt. Center billed from . g Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Hay m, 27 Shelton ■ Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Hay O 27 Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Niobrara Car Hay # 27 Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wlnnetoon Car Hay ' H 28 Ulysses community Dr. C. E. Mack in charge ..Bloomfleld l...Car Grain 20 . Fremont Dodge County Farmers Un. Niobrara Car Grain 29 ' Ogallala pt. load at Paxton Legion Verdigre Car Grain Mar. 1 Scottsbluff Legion — pch. Creighton people Creighton Car. Potatoes 1 Litchfleld - Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel Cai Alfalfa 1 Litchfleld ;..Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Niobrara Car Alfalfa 1 Litchfleld .Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdigre Car. Alfalfa 1 Buda .-. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Straw 1 Buda ..: Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car , Straw *• ■ : , "' </seg>
            <seg id="p045">KNOX COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Qunntity Contents 2 Minden Carl T. Curtis in charge ....Crofton Car Straw 3 Hastings Legion Niobrara Car. Hay, grain, Gro. 4 Ulysses .„ Dr. C. E. Mack in charge ..Niobrara ...Car Grain 7 DuBols community ....Rev. 0. J. Krueger in chg...Niobrara Car Peed 7 Seward — loaded at Leahey.-Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Straw &amp; oil cake 7 Seward — loaded at Leahey.-Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Straw &amp; oil cake 7 Seward — loaded at Leahey.-Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel ......Car Straw &amp; oil cake 8 Seward thru Freeman Graff M loaded at Goehner Pch. with relief funds Crofton Car Corn g 9 Lincoln — pch. with State O Relief Funds Lincoln Niobrara 6500 lbs ..Groceries cj 11 Lincoln — pch. with State . w Relief Funds Lincoln Niobrara 1 16000 lbs Flour 11 Milford Cha. of Comm. and Legion.. Verdel Car Grain and straw W 12 Pch. at North Platte thru P Gunn of Lexington Wayne business men ...Bloomfleld Car Hay g 12 Stratton — Future Farm- i era of America Kenneth Ball in charge Verdigre Car Grain . 14 Goehner Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Straw g .14 Goehner Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Straw 14 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel Car Straw O 14 Columbus — loaded at . 2 Sheldonville A. W. Frlscholz in charge.-Crofton Car Food and feed 14 Emerson citizens M. D. Wagers in charge Niobrara $135.00 Groceries 15 Aurora Dr. W. H. Baker in charge.. Bloomfleld Car Straw 15 Aurora Dr. W. H. Baker in charge.. Crofton Car Straw 15 Aurora Dr. W. H. Baker in charge..Verdel Car Straw 15 Gothenburg — by Wayne Bu. men Rollie W. Ley in charge Crofton Car... ...Hay 16 Overton thru Gunn of Lexington Farmers Union of Omaha ..Niobrara Car Hay 18 Lincoln W. C. T. U. Ladies Verdel Bxs. &amp; Bbls Food supplies 21 Auburn organizations H. D. Bancroft in charge ..Crofton Car Grain lilhtettttaitarfiMt'iiltiirt-liiriiJrii'ii ','iimii'' V ii'ri'--' i •in- ■] • 7 i -ii-riii' ■i^lVli-'iTfr'rii'- ' '-if — V ' -i ' ''--jv'r -Vl-irti i l-pi -*■*»*'- ■&lt;- -■"■-^- **&amp;, i^yjA^rjigi^Kafl-fftftAi </seg>
            <seg id="p046">KNOX COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents 22 Elsie Legion Bloomfleld Car Corn 22 Amherst Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car. Straw 22 Aurora Dr. W. H. Baker in charge.. Verdlgre Car Straw 23 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car Straw 23 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Niobrara Car Straw 23 Aurora Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Straw 25 Lindsay A. P. Peterson in charge ....Crofton 1000 lbs Food supplies .. 28 Columbus A. W. Frischolz In charge ..Niobrara 3000 to 4000 lbs.Grain 29 . Gothenburg Legion Bloomfleld Car :Hay 2 30 Holbrook community Earl Proud in charge Verdigre Car Hay O 30 Lincoln — pch. with state relief funds Verdigre 8000 lbs .Groceries C 30 Kearney F. F. A. &amp; Legion Verdigre Car Corn &amp; clothing Jjj 31 Goehner — pch. with state relief funds Crofton Car. Corn * Apr. 1 Scottsbluff — pch. with state relief funds Blf., Crof. &amp; L'dy...Car ;. Potatoes W 1 Lyman— pch. with state relief funds :..Nio., V'd'l., V'de. Santee .Car Potatoes £ 4 Buda Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Crofton Car Straw S 4 Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Niobrara Car Straw * J 4 Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Verdel Car Straw £J 4 Gibbon Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Bloomfleld Car ; Straw 7 Garland — pch. with state relief funds Bloomfleld Car Corn O 8 Beatrice — pch. with Btate relief funds Verdel Car Hay . W 11 Overton — pch. thru Gunn of Lexington with state . ■ relief funds Bloomfleld Car Hay 11 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of » Lexington Crofton Car Hay 11 Overton — pch. with state relief funds thru Gunn of Lexington Niobrara Car Hay 11 Holdrege — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Verdigre Car Corn 12 Lindsay A. P. Peterson in charge ....Verdel 1800 lbs Supplies 13 Oxford — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha ...Bloomfleld Car Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p047">KNOX COUNTX ' ' ' Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by . Consigned to Quantity Contents ' 13 Bartley — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha , Crofton Car Corn 13 Eustis — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Nio'brara Car Corn 15 Cambridge — pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Un. of Omaha Crofton Car.-. Corn 18 Friend community F. L. Bollen in charge Crofton Car Corn , 29 Cozad — pch. by Lincoln C. of C Bloomfleld Car..., Hay Q . • ■ . ■ ■ SB mi » </seg>
            <seg id="p048">KEYA PAHA COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Dec. 29, 1931 Deshler Farmers Sp'gv'w via Baasett Car Supplies Jan. 19, 1932 Schuyler Legion Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Supplies 22 Clarks community Rev. E. W. Price in charge.. Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Food and feed Feb. 4 Tecumseh Com. &amp; Legion.. J. B. Doug/as in charge Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Grain 7 , Beaver City Legion and Com. Club Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Corn 9 Ruskin Legion ..Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Feed 12 Schuyler Legion Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car , Feed Mar. 1 Litchfield Lincoln Chamber of Comm, Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Alfalfa O 2 Murray D. O. Dwyer of Platts- V mouth reported .Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car. Grain 2 14 . Columbus A. W. Frischolz in charge ..Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Food and feed § Apr. 6 Bee Pch. with St. Rel. Funds Sp'gv'w via Bassett Car Oats X 11 Lincoln Pch. with St. Rel. Funds Sp'gv'w via Bassett Quantity Flour, corn meal u 11 Lincoln Pch. with St. Rel. Funds Sp'gv'w via Bassett Quantity Groceries H o to </seg>
            <seg id="p049">PIERCE COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Feb. 15, 1932 Aurora Aurora Business Men's Club Plainview Car Corn 17 Nelson Farmers Union Elevator Co. Osmond :..Car Feed 17 Seward thru Erie Smlley....Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car..... Straw 17 Seward thru Erie Smiley....Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond : Car Straw 18 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Hay 18 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Hay 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car ..Straw 19 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Straw M 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Hay § 24 Odessa Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Hay O 29 Mason City Lincoln Chamber of Comm. McLean Car Alfalfa d 29 Hazard Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Alfalfa 2 29 Hazard Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Alfalfa Mar. 3 Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond : Car Straw g 3 Shelton Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Straw p 4 Hampton ship, by Aurora.. Dr. W. H. Baker in charge-Osmond Car Straw £j 4 Hampton ship, by Aurora.. Dr. W. H. Baker in charge.. Plainview Car Straw § 4 Loaded at Henry Kearney D. A. R McLean Car Hay • 5 Litchfield : Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Hay . 2 7 Bird City, Kansas John H. Timmons In chg. ..Plainview ........Car Corn *a 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Straw &amp; oil cake O 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. McLean Car Straw &amp; oil cake 2 14 Goehner s Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Plainview Car Straw ' 14 Staplehurst Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Osmond Car Straw 14 Staplehurst .-. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. McLean Car Straw 25 Union W. B. Banning in charge ..Pierce Car .Hay 28 Arnold Legion Pierce Car Hay Apr. 11 Lincoln — Pch. with state relief funds thru Gooch's ....Plainview Car Corn 13 Edison — Pch. with state relief funds thru Fm. Union of Omaha Pierce Car Corn 20 Lyman — Pch.' with state relief funds Osmond Car Potatoes 21 Albion Legion Osmond Car Straw </seg>
            <seg id="p050">IIOCK COUNTY Date Assigned Assembled at Assembled by Consigned to Quantity Contents Dec. 17, 1931 Holdrege Legion Bassett Cur Supplies 29 Henderson Farmers Newport Car Supplies Jan. 15, 1932 Schuyler Legion Bassett Car Hay 25 ■ Grant Legion Basset &amp; Newport.. Car Corn and barley Mar. 23 Ellis Community H. E. Foster in charge Bassett Car ;....Grain and hay Apr. 11 Lincoln Pch with St. Rel. Funds ....Bassett Quantity Groceries 13 Enders Geo. Ballard in charge Bassett Car Corn o . o : ■ ' . ■ -to </seg>
            <seg id="p051">47 THURSTON COUNTY Dnto Assigned Assembled nt Assembled by Consigned to • Quantity Contents Feb. 23,1932 Josselyn, Sh. f'm Overton..Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Walthill Car : Hay 23 Josselyn, Sh. I'm Overtoil.. Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Winnebago Car Hay 23 Josselyn, Sh. f'm Overton..Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Walthill for Macy..Car Hay 25 Gl'w'd Pk. Sh. f'm Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Wlnnebago Car Straw 25 Gl'w'd Pk. Sh. f'm Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Walthill Car : — Straw — 25 Gl'w'd^fc-Sh-f'm Kearney Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Walthill for Macy..Car ....:. Straw Mar. 7 Gothenburg by Oakland ....Legion — Dr. Benson in dig. Walthill Car Hay 7 Gothenburg by Oakland ....Legion — Dr. Benson in chg. Winnebago Car Hay O 7 Seward Lincoln Chamber of Comm. Macy via Walthill.. Car Straw &amp; oil cake W 10 Da'd Cy. Sh. f'm Linwood..Legion Winnebago Car Hay g 15 Wilcox by Future Farm- H ers of America Harold M. Adams In charge.-Walthill Half car Grain K 1G Darr— thru Gunn of . 3 Lexington Bancroft Legion ..Winnebago Car Hay H 30 Lawrence Legion Winnebago Car — part Grain £ Apr. 14 Guide Rock community ....S. E. Vogler in charge Walthill Car Hay H 14 Guide Rock community ....S. E. Vogler in charge Winnebago Cai Hay 1 a </seg>
            <seg id="p052">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT FINANCIAL REPORT 1032 May 6 Total Receipts to Date Expenditures as follows: 1031 Dec. 12 Fred S. Mueller, Knox County $ 25.00 18 Grainger Bros., groceries ....:. 423.55 21 Lincoln Packing Co., meat 271.32 28 Check returned, acct. bank closed 5.00 28 Check returned, acct. bank closed 8.00 1032 Jan. 2 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Co., flour $ 298.13 4 Exchange charged by banks for December .98 16 Win. Bruce, freight charges on rabbits .^ 5.16 20 C. &amp; N. W. Agent at Davenport for freight 1.11 22 W. C. T. U., for relief work in Holt County 25.00 28 Union Pacific for freight from Carleton .67 Feb. 10 Wilson &amp; Co., meat 5.00 10 Western States Grocery Co., groceries 18.76 11 Refund 5.00 11 Exchange charged by banks for January .40' Mar. 1 R. H. Brandt, groceries 1.95 1 Western States Grocery Co., groceries 9.23 1 Wilson &amp; Co., meat 5.75 7 E. H. Gribble, Chmn., Welfare Board of Dak. Co. 268.83 7 Exchange charged by banks for February .10 12 C. H. Gunn, car hay .'. 113.47 12 C. H. Gunn, car hay 96.57 14 Freeman Graff, car corn 287.04 15 Geo. E. Gould, supplies 10.00 17 Grainger Bros. Co., groceries „. 346.07 21 Shoffstall Hay Co., car hay 160.65 • 23 Geo. A. Stites, car corn 390.00 Apr. 1 C. H. Gunn, car hay 102.88 2 Grainger Bros. Co., groceries 289.79 4 Fred Steinheider, car corn 259.38 4 A. A. Hulse, car potatoes 179.45 4 R. H. Brandt, groceries 6.74 4 Wilson &amp; Co., meat 3.37 4 Western States Grocery Co., groceries 21.76 7 Exchange charged by banks for March ■ .40 8 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Co., flour 331.63 9 F. L. Perdue, car hay , v .. 96.00 9 C. H. Gunn, car hay 94.96 9 A. A. Hulse, car potatoes 181.57 9 A. A. Hulse, car potatoes 174.72 11 Bee Elevator Co., car oats 300.00 14 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 346.19 . 14 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 369.40 14 Farmers Coop. Grain Co., car corn 288.00 14 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Co., car corn 431.25 14 Fossey-Johnson Legion Post, Lyman, two cars potatoes 299.18 15 Imig &amp; Schnebeck Grain Co., car corn 420.00 15 Germantown Farmers Grain Co., car corn 271.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">! DROUTH RELIEF REPORT 15 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 385.87 . jO 15 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 367.50 15 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 367.50 16 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn , 393.00 15 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 349.68 15 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Co., flour and corn meal 115.00 15 G. C. Shaffer, car hay 131.02 16 C. H. Gunn, car hay 98.96 16. C. H. Gunn, car hay 97.27 16 Farmers Grain &amp; Coal Co., car corn 341.80 16 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 370.13 16 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 385.71 16 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 393.75 16 Farmer^ Union Grain Co., car corn 380.36 16 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 467.28 19 Seward City Mills, flour and corn meal 200.00 19 Grainger Bros. Co., groceries 582.07 19 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 1 384.00 19 Farmers Produce &amp; Supply Co., Enders, part car corn _ 19.72 20 C. H. Gunn, car hay 76.65 20 C. H. Gunn, car hay 83.26 22 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 392.00 22 .Grlswold Seed &amp; Floral Co., garden seeds 171.90 . . 25 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 390.00 26 C. H. Gunn, car hay : 101.48 26 C. H. Gunn, car hay 95.52 26 C. H. Gunn, car hay 130.64 26 C. H. Gunn, car hay 85.68 : 26 C. H. Gunn, car hay 88.45 ' 27 Farmers Union Grain Co.", car corn 393.00 ■ 28 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 404.69 28 Farmers Union Grain Co., car corn 356.28 28 Cancellation charges on two cars corn 15.00 May -2 Fossey-Johnson Legion Post, Lyman, two cars potatoes , 333.13 2 Farmers f Grain Co., Osceola, part car corn 242.12 3 Seward Nursery, Seed &amp; Floral Co., garden seeds 139.50 6 Exchange charged by banks for April .05 6 Checks returned 89.00 6 Rob't S. Grlswold Seed &amp; Floral Co., garden seeds 36.00 TOTAL EXPENDITURES $16,705.78 Total Receipts : $17,398.87 Total Expenditures 16,705.78 May 6 Balance- on Hand $ 693.09 Bills outstanding (estimated) . 290.00 Net balance on hand ; $ ■ 403.09 •- ' J </seg>
            <seg id="p054">DROUTH RELIEF REPORT ' AUDITOR'S REPORT May 6, 1932. Mr. Geo. W. Marsh, State Auditor, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: As requested by you I have examined the books and bank account of the State Relief Fund, Wm. H. Smith, Treasurer, for the period beginning November 25, 1931, and ending May 6, 1932, and submit the following: Total amount deposited in bank $17,398.87 Deduct-checks deposited twice, having been returned unpaid' but later paid 102.00 Amount of cash contributions $17,296.87 Expenditures were all made by bank check which I have classified as follows: Livestock feed i..$ll,790.51 Food 4,098.17 Garden Seed 357.40 Welfare Board, Dakota County ; 268.83 Holt County Relief 25.00 Knox County Relief 1 25.00 Mrs. Chas. Reed Relief 10.00 Cancellation charge 2 cars 15.00 Refund „. 5.00 Freight 6.94 Exchange on checks 1.93 $16,603.78 Balance on hand May 6, 1932 $ 693.09 Bank Reconcilement Bank statement of First National Bank, Lincoln, Nebr. shows at the close of business April 30, 1932, to the credit of State Relief Fund: $ 1,440.84 Add: Deposit made May 6, 1932 3.00 $ 1,443.84 Deduct — Outstanding checks — No. 76 _ $ 333.13 3 No. 77 242.12 No. 78 139.50 No. 79 36.00 • " $ 750.75 Balance as shown by Treasurer books _ $ 693.09 Am informed there are outstanding unpaid accounts amounting to approximately $290.00 for flour, printing report and postage. Respectfully submitted, (Signed) E. J. AVERY, State Accountant. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>