<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>WATER CARRIED FOR HOUSEHOLD PURPOSES ON NEBRASKA FARMS</title>
               <date value="1929-05">1929-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 234 „ , nnn May, 1929 WATER CARRIED FOR HOUSEHOLD PURPOSES ON NEBRASKA FARMS M. RUTH CLARK AND GRETA GRAY Department op Home Economics THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY Data used in this bulletin came from all parts of Nebraska. Owner households made up 38 per cent of the group, tenant households 57.8 per cent; This is a higher percentage of tenant farmers than is shown for Nebraska as a whole by the Agricultural Statistics of 1927. In every case except one the well was the ultimate source of water used for household purposes. Both cisterns and wells were found in 66 cases. More than half the wells were over 100 feet deep. Eight per cent were not tightly covered; 41 per cent were located less than 100 feet from the privy, 42 per cent less than 100 feet from the barns. Of the cisterns 18 per cent had loose covers. In 79, or 28.3 per cent, of the households the farm homemaker alone carried all the water used in the household. In 155, or 55.3 per cent, of the households she helped carry the water. In only 46 instances, or 16.4 per cent, the homemaker had no part in this task. In 4.5 per cent of the households all the water was carried by children. No rela - tionship was found between the person carrying water and the number of persons in the household. Very few of the homes had modern conveniences. Only 13 per cent had bathtubs, while 1.7 per cent had chemical toilets. Separators were reported in 80 per cent of the homes, washing machines in 77 per cent. Cream separators create a demand for water peculiar to the farm home. Home laundering also demands a considerable amount of water. In 98 per cent of the households all the family laundry was done in the home. An average of 178.8 gallons of water was used by each household. This was an average of 41.1 gallons per person per week and 5.9 gallons per person per day. In summer months more water was used by each household but slightly less by each individual, as summer households averaged 4.6 members and winter households 4.08 mem - bers. As households increase in size, the total amount of water used increases while the amount used per person decreases. The consumption of water shown in this study is much below the average amount consumed by households with running water in the home and with bath and flush toilet facilities. It is also below esti - mated minimum requirements for households without running ■ water and modern conveniences. This means additional effort on the part of the housewife if standards of cleanliness are to be maintained. Water used for general household purposes was carried an average distance of 75.7 feet, that used in laundry an average distance of 62.6 feet. Each week an average distance of 4,311.5 feet was traveled in carry - ing water in each household. In one month this meant 3.5 miles, and 42 miles in a year. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">The time consumed by each household in this work was, on the average, 2 hours and 20 minutes per week for general household pur - poses and 46 minutes for laundry water. This made a total average time consumption of 3 hours and 7 minutes per week, or 13 hours and 31 minutes per month. In one year this would mean 162 hours and 4 minutes. This time does not include putting on and taking off wraps in winter months. In 66 per cent of the cases waste water was carried from the house in pails or pans. Almost 50 per cent of the households emptied waste water within less than 20 feet of the kitchen. In 16 per cent of the instances waste water stood on the ground after being emptied. Waste water was emptied further from wells or cisterns than from the kitchen. A water system would be labor-saving equipment and a sound in - vestment. The inefficiency of the carrying method constitutes an ex - pense greater than interest and depreciation upon a simple water system. Information as to water systems and their installation can be obtained from the Agricultural Engineering Department, University of Nebraska, upon request. . r ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">Water Carried for Households on Nebraska Farms The uses of water in the household are very largely condi - tioned by the method of supply and by the equipment with which the housewife works. In a home with running water the practices of the housewife will differ very greatly from the practices of the housewife who must carry into the house every pail of water used and then carry out the waste water. The effort of the latter homemaker will| be to make each pailful of water go as far as possible, with the result that standards of cleanliness, both personal and household, may be lower than in cases where water is easily accessible in unlimited quantity. Table 7 shows the distribution of household conveniences be - tween owners and tenants. Twenty-five, or 22.5 per cent, of the owners possessed bathtubs; 13, or 7.8 per cent, of the tenants had this convenience. Two, or 1.8 per cent, of the owners had chemical toilets, while such toilets were found in the same percentage of the homes of tenants. Eighty per cent of the owners and 84 per cent of the tenants had cream separators, while 73.8 per cent of the owners and 81.2 per cent of the tenants reported washing machines. I Two wash - ing machines were in homes for which tenancy was not given. Only 38, or 13 per cent, of the entire group reported bath - tubs, while 5, or 1.7 per cent, had chemical toilets. In 228 households, or 81 per cent of the entire number^ separators were reported. In 218 households, or 77 per cent of the entire number, there were washing machines. The care of the cream separator and of the pails and pans used in the care of milk and cream constitutes one of the most important single demands for water in the farm home. Among the households under consideration in this study, a total of 228, or 81 per cent of those answering, owned sep - arators. The homemakers on these farms cared for the separator and for an average number of 5.8 milk pans and pails per day. Those households without separators which reported care of milk utensils averaged only 3.66 pans and pails per day. The demand for water for the care of such utensils is peculiar to the farm home, and an inadequate supply of water increases the work of caring for I separators and milk utensils to a very great extent, if the separator and milk utensils are cared for in a sanitary manner. Because of water scarcity, however, many farm homemakers do not wash the separator as often as desirable and milk pails and pans are often washed in the same water used for dishes, and are not properly rinsed and scalded. In 98 per cent of the 284 homes studied, all of the family laundry was done in tjie home. This means that once in each week, in most of the homes, a greatly increased supply of water had to be carried. The family washing creates the </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">Table 7. — Distribution of conveniences according to tenancy . Number _ . . a Tenancy answering Having bathhubs Chemical toilets Cream separators Wash, machines g . , . — : : n Number Per cent Number Per cent Number Per cent Number Per cent gj Owner ■ 111 25 22.5 2 1.8 89 JO 82 73.8 § Tenant ~ 165 | 13 7.8 8 | 1.8 I 139 | 84 134 81.2 g Not given I 6| o|o| 0 I 0 0 0| 2 33.3 g All „ 282 I 38 13 5 1.7 228 81 218 77 a o Table B. — Average consumption of water per household and per individual w Average number of gallons Average number of gallons Average number of gallons 55 Average size of water used per week of water used per week of water used per day of hosneholds per household per person per person S General Laundry All General Laundry All General Laundry All £! 09 Summer 4.6 135.6 48.5 184.1 30 10 40 4.3 1.4 5.7 Winter 4.08 128.0 45.0 173.0 81 11 42 4^4_ 1.6 | 6 g Total 4.34 132.1 46.7 178.8 30.6 10.5 41.1 | 4.4 1.5 | 5.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 234 that during the summer months, when the housewife is in the midst of her busiest season, more time and energy must be devoted to securing water for household purposes than at other times of the year. In the 45 cases where double records were secured, an average of 129.6 gallons per household were used in the summer in one week, while an average of only 120 gallons per household were used in the winter. When the total records kept during summer months were compared with those kept during the winter months this finding was sub - stantiated, as is shown by Table 8. The summer records show a total weekly consumption of water per household of 184.1 gallons, while the winter records show a total weekly consumption of 173 gallons. When, however, the size of the household is considered, it is found that the summer house - hold contained an average of 4.6 members, while the winter household had only 4.08. This means, as Table 8 indicates, that while consumption of water per household was greater during the summer months, it was slightly less per individual. This may be in part explained by the fact that during the summer months the men usually wash outside, very often near the well or cistern, and thus the water used is not carried to the house. Many times, also, when vegetables are brought in from the garden they are carried directly to the well or cistern and washed there, thus reducing the amount of water which must be carried. The average daily consumption of water for each member of the household, in a modern home with bath and flush toilet, has been found to be about 25 gallons. 4 In a home which is not equipped with running water in the bathroom nor with a flush toilet, the amount of water per day per person will be materially reduced. The amount of water needed for main - taining sanitary conditions per day per individual in such households has been variously estimated at from 8 to 20 gallons. 5 The difference between 5.9 gallons per day shown in Table 8 and 25 gallons per day is very great and the lack of water piped into the house means not only greatly increased labor, but lowered standards of cleanliness and sanitation. There is also a considerable difference between the amount of water actually used by the households surveyed in this study and the estimated required minimum amounts of water in house - holds which do not have water piped into the house. Eight gallons is the lowest estimated amount per person per day, while this study shows as average daily use by each person of *Farm*t*id Water Svpply. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Farmers' Bui. 1448. p. 7. Clrl^4" * TJizJ t^'"Z S »; U ™ '&lt;»■ Farm Home,. West V.. Univ" CoL of A«r. Circ. 44; Farmstead Water Supply. TJ. S. Dept. of Art. Farmers' Bui. 1448- Water Supply and Sevaae DiBposal System.. TJniY. of Nebr. A*r. Ex. Circ. 723. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Water Carried for Households on Nebraska Farms less than 6 gallons. The maximum estimated amount, 20 gallons, is almost four times the amount actually used by the persons in the group studied. In the amount of water used daily the facts obtained from this study show that little change has taken place in recent years. A study made at the University of Nebraska ° in 1913 shows that farm homes in which all water for household purposes was carried into the house averaged 5.8 gallons of water per day for each indi - vidual in the households considered. While the demand for water has increased in city homes, the demand for water for household purposes in farm homes has remained unchanged, when that water must be secured by the method of carrying it into the house in pails. This discrepancy between the average of 25 gallons per day per person in a modern home and that of 5.9 gallons per day in the farm households of this group, indicates very clearly the tremendous disadvantage under which the farm homemaker must work when she has neither a pump nor run - ning water in the house. It indicates just as clearly less com - fortable living conditions than in homes equipped with run - ning water and bathing and indoor flush toilet equipment. But even the limited supply of water used by the house - holds studied requires a very considerable amount of time and energy expenditure on the part of the homemaker or other members of the household. . The distances the water was carried from the well or cistern to the kitchen and to the place where laundry was done are shown in Table 9. Only 259 out of the 284 households included in the study answered this question fully. Others answered it either not at all or so incompletely that the information given is not included. The water used for general household purposes was carried, on the average, 75.7 feet from the source of supply, while that used in laundry was carried an average distance of 62.6 feet. There are two circumstances which explain this difference. A portion of the water used for laundry purposes was taken from cisterns, which were on the average located nearer to the house than were wells, a con - siderable number being either on the porch or very near the kitchen. In the second place laundering was very often done in a wash house, or in summer months on a porch or in the yard, and such places were usually located nearer the well or the cistern than was the kitchen, to which water for general household purposes was carried. Since laundry water must be carried on one day each week, or within a few hours of one day, the desirability of shortening the distance it must be carried is more obvious than in the case of water for other •Chase, L. W.. Simple Water Systems for the Farm. UnW. of Nebr. Agr. Ex. Bui. 18. Sept.. 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 234 age time per pail shown in Table 10, a total of 3 hours and 7 minutes, or almost one-half hour each day, was spent in one S3? *n&gt;^ at . er - carr y in ?^ one or more members of the house - hold. This m one month would mean 13 hours and 31 minutes HT a car T n « water aR d in one year a total of 162 hours and 4 minutes per average household. These figures are based upon the assumption that only one pail of water was «™i «JS? «5" P&gt; I" two P aiIs are at the in™ \ ? %} US r + ed ««ng the time consumed in water-carry - ing, but adding to the effort involved, especially when the SS^H S / arried . by WOmen or childr^ ThL figurelof timl ffiSS, I fh W ? ?er " Cai 27l ng d °. I l Ot ' however . take into con - fili«« £ e * ime hlch L must be s P ent in Putting on and taking off wraps during the winter months nor do they £- ™ e . P e tl ™ e s P en t m emptying waste water. If the time spent m getting ready to bring in the water, taking off wraps and galoshes, and in emptying water were included the time shown would be materially increased. It is obvious that when the farm homemaker herself did the water-carryinTa heavy burden was placed upon her. Hi^Sm* 6 % at + l r 1 l as been car ried into the house, however, the problem of the homemaker as to time, energy, and sani - 5 thP 1? regar , d £ ?* Water SUpply is noi ended^ Very f ew wast wXr% S r Udie^ W^ re e « ui PP e .d with drains for carrying Pi e ™ ter £ rom the house. This meant, therefore, that a hi*™ * P °/ the - Wa c ter carried int0 th e house had also to water fronffv, 3^ 111 \ b . e . in §. used - The removal of waste ™Z,fh h r e ant l lts disposal in a sanitar y manner are problems the homemaker must meet. In 34 per cent of $ w»T e i°l dS f vln &amp; as to method of removal SueTon^ a w/ r ° m th « ho . use + &lt; 259 ou t of 284 answered this k?tchen whSf ?n fi a | a dr am to carry waste water from th kitchen, while in 66 per cent it was necessary to carry the water Tvfr f 5^ 8 ° r Pa " S - In the dis P° sal ofKfndr? t^to? oa^ "i f t he number answering (212 out of the w« J , 2 84). reported drains for laundry waste- when laundry was done in a place other than the kitchen, or arrangements whereby the water could be permitted to run from thfSbo? machine directly to the ground. In 94 per cenT of the in - </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 234 indicated by some of the answers given. For example, in one case all waste water from house and laundry was emptied less than 7 feet from a well which was only 12 feet deep; in another, all waste water was emptied about 7 feet from a well SO feet deep. These were the most outstanding instances of such conditions, but in numerous other cases conditions were only siightly better. The disposal of the waste water by the method of throwing it outside the kitchen door near the porch or in the back yard, or by emptying it by a drain within a short distance of the house raises the question of contamination of the source of the supply of water and of sanitary conditions. Figure 4 shows the distances from the kitchen and from the well or cistern of the place where the waste water from the house - hold was emptied. As will be seen by referring to Figure 4, almost one-half of the households emptied waste water within 40 feet or less of the kitchen. This means that there is created near the house a gathering place for flies in summer. In 16 per cent of the households the waste water from the kitchen stood on the ground after it was emptied, and in 10 per cent of the instances, laundry water also stood on the ground. The appearance of the back yard or of that portion of it which is used as a dumping ground is made very unat - tractive. A drain pipe to carry the waste water from the house would relieve the homemaker of the necessity of carry - ing out the waste. Drainage tiles to distribute this water over a suitable area would result in much more sanitary and sightly surroundings. In terms of distance alone it is impossible to tell whether or not the wells or cisterns are contaminated by the waste water poured upon the ground. The structure of the soil, the slope of the land, the depth of well, and the method of building the well or cistern would have to be considered be - fore a judgment upon this question would be of value. This information was not obtained in the present study. The total amount of water used per household increased as the number of members of the household increased, while the amount of water used per week or per day by each member of the household decreased. This is entirely logical, as there are many uses of water in the household which will not vary greatly whether the household consists of two or five persons. This is true of such activities as the washing of dishes, the cleaning of vegetables, and the scrubbing of floors ; and even in the use of water for laundry purposes the increase will not be m direct proportion to the number of persons for whom laundry is done. The figures in Table 11 show this decrease in the amount of water used per person per week as the </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 234 bathroom, the consumption of water would without doubt in - crease very materially and the labor of the farm housewife would in like manner become easier and farm life more at - tractive. If the conditions shown in this study were irremediable, there would be little point to the study. The farm home bears a very important relation to the farm business and from an economic as well as a social point of view, a method of sup - plying water as antiquated as the one considered in the present study should not be tolerated. Industry everywhere is acting upon the assumption that the comfort and well being of the worker is an essential condition of successful work. And nothing could so add to the comfort and well-being of the workers on. the f«r m as a supply of hot and cold running water. Most farmers have shown themselves interested in labor - saving equipment and most farms are equipped with some labor-saving machinery. It is in the farm home, more than upon the farm itself, that the lack of efficient methods and equipment still prevails. The time and energy expended in the carrying of water show inefficiency. A water supply system, from the point of view of a labor-saver, would be as good an investment as could be made by any farmer. Good farm economy demands the most efficient use of labor. The time and energy expended in carrying water for household purposes constitute an expense greater than the interest and the depreciation upon a simple water system. There are water systems which can give the great advantage of running water in the farm home without great expense in either monev or labor. ' It is no doubt largely due to the lack of knowledge of how to install water systems that farmers and farm homemakers continue to employ the inefficient method of obtaining water shown in the present study. .^Agricultural En K in .ee r ing Department of the University of Nebraska expects to issue in the hear future a bulletin giving a discussion of various electrically operated farm water systems with materials needed for their installation. This bulletin is not available at the present time, hut informa - tion upon farm water systems and directions for their in - stallation will be sent upon request by the Agricultural Engi - neering Department. : ■ ■- '. ■'"•'■ ■ i ■ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>