<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1911-1912 VOLUME I</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1911—1912 Volume I </seg>
            <seg id="p002">PUBLIC LIBEAIT 5123021i ASTOR, L8N0I AND TILDBN fOl'NDATIONS » 1949 L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i 1 t Or I ■&gt; Volume I Governor's messages a. Chester H. Aldrich, Biennial message, 1913 b. John H. Morehead, Inaugural message, 1913 Secretary of State. Biennial report, 1911-191 rditor of Public Accounts, Biennial report, 1911-1912 a. Appropriations, etc.. 33rd legislative session. 191 State Treasurer. Biennial report, 1911-1912 rmmissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Biennial report, v. is 1911-1912 a. Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln, Biennial report, v. 21 b. Penitentiary. Biennial report, 1910-1912 C. Norfolk State Hospital, Biennial report, v 12. 1912 d. Ingleside State Hospital, Biennial report, v. 12. 1912 e. Industrial Home, Milford, Biennial riport, v. 12. 1912 f. Girls' Industrial School, Geneva. Biennial report, v. 11. 1H12 g. Boys' Industrial School, Kearney, Biennial report, v. 16, 1911' h. Institute for the Blind, Nebraska City, Biennial report, v. 1H 1912 Institute for Feeble-minded Youth. Beatrice, Biennial report v. 14. 1912 j. School for the Deaf, Omaha, Biennial report, v. 18, 1912 k. Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Burkett, Biennial report. 1912 1. Tuberculosis Hospital, Kearney, v. 1. 1912 m. Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Biennial report, 191 Superintendent of Public Instruction. Biennial report, v. 22, 1012 State Board of Education, Biennial report, 1911-1912 </seg>
           
            <seg id="p004">MESSAGE of Chester H. Aldrich Governor of Nebraska to the 33rd Session Nebraska Legislature 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">Cientlemen: I am in your presence on this occasion in accordance with a time honored custom and the fundamental law of our i to deliver a message based on the experience acquired as a chief executive of our commonwealth during the past two years. I congratulate you upon being elected, as members of a legislative body, to enact laws for and on behalf of the most tgressive and intelligent people to be found in any state in common country. You will find your duties varied, exacting and onerous. But if you ever keep before your mind's eye what you and each of you have promised in order to be elected, your path - way will be unobstructed and the results of your labors will reflect honor upon yourselves, and do much to advance the cause of social justice and a people's government. No legislature ever assembled with promises more specific or duties more clearly and well defined than the present one. At the last election five constitutional amendment - adopted, containing many new and important provisions, which. to become effective and operative, must be supplemented by new enactments. These several amendments are as foil to-wit: 1st, the initiative and referendum; 2nd, fixing of term of office and salary of members of the legislature ; :5rd, non - partisan board of control of state institutions; 4th, providing for a general election once in two years; 5th, allowing cities tover five thousand inhabitants in this state to frame their 1 city charters. And in addition to these, all political parties are pledged to much other specific legislation, among the most important of which may be mentioned a bill to remedy the inequitable and antiquated taxation system now in vogue in our state, a blue sky law, a publicity measure to the end that the resources and ad - vantages of Nebraska may become more widely known, a public highway commission for the general improvement and systematic and intelligent working of the roads of the state, the proper </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 Governor's Message developing in our state, a reform in the methods and system of handling the penitentiary, the prevention of log rolling in the legislature, the enforcement of the anti-lobby law, the enactment of a law prohibiting the liquor interests from contributing to po - litical campaign funds (the last three are especially empha - sized by the democratic party), the enactment of an eight hour day law for all toilers, especially in state and municipal work. rLaws framed and enacted to effectively reach each one these propositions specifically promised will indeed make onerous the duties of the legislators of this session. By enacting intelligent and honest laws, in the carrying out of these specific and general promises, Nebraska will, in that event, become a model state government, under which her people will have the opportunity to thrive, because each man will be given a chance to succeed commensurate with his ability and merit. Of the constitutional amendments adopted, I regard the initiative and referendum and the non-partisan board of con - trol as the most important and far-reaching amendments ever adopted by the people of Nebraska. The initiative and referendum has for its object and pur - pose the placing of the government, with all of its duties and responsibilities, directly into the hands of the voter. It is the agency through which the recreant legislator or other public of - ficial may be made to feel the heavy hand of the public. It is the proper and all powerful instrument which affords the peo - ple a method of writing into the laws of the state any impor - tant piece of legislation that the majority of the voters desire. The last legislature submitted to, and the people adopted an effective initiative and referendum. The only thing now necessary for this session to do is to pass a law making effective the provisions of that act. In my judgment, there is one important and necessary provision for this legislature to consider and that is the pro - cedure by means of which a law may be initiated or referred. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Legislature 1913 5 ted the initiative and referendum and enacted laws to make effective that particular constitutional provision. So in this important matter of legislation, we have history, fact and precedent to which we can refer for guidance. The danger to which the public is generally exposed in making effective a constitutional provision of this kind, is that there are often enough members in every legislature hostile Lthe initiative and referendum, to succeed in getting enacted aw imposing impossible conditions. That was the case" in Oklahoma, where the law provided that before a petition could be circulated, a copy of the same must be filed in the office of the secretary of state, and that within sixty days after the filing of this copy, the original copy must be filed, thus making it impossible, by reason of the time required to get the necessary number of signatures, to fulfill the requirements of the law. I recommend that in the enactment of a law fixing the methods and ways of having signatures attached to a petition that you make it direct and simple and as easy as possible, consistent with safety and prevention of fraud. A law in one state was passed making it necessary for every signer to a petition to initiate, to go before a notary public and get his acknowledgment. Such a provision, of course, nullifies and kills the initiative and referendum. In my judgment, it is simply necessary to have uniform blanks to be issued by the secretary of state when application shall have been made and to take the oath of the person cir - culating the petition to the effect that he solemnly swears that the signatures to which he attests were made in his presense and are the genuine signatures of the persons whose names appear thereto, and when the person so making said oath acknowledges the same before a justice of the peace or other officer havinp the right to take an acknowledgment, that if the person so making oath shall be found to have falsely made the same, that he shall be deemed guilty of perjury and punished in accordance ■the statute on perjury made and provided for in the state &gt;braska. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">6 Governor's Message BOARD OF CONTROL Puext important matter to which I direct your attin - le amendment recently adopted providing for a non - board of control of our state institutions. This in ircely second in importance to the initiative and n It is a new departure in this state and its sued operation means the entering wedge to really a new form of government. Kiis is the first time that Nebraska has ever provided state office under and by virtue of the provisions of the ution without making it elective. EBy this constitutional amendment, we have created three state officers to be filled by the governor. This i&gt; ed a new and radical departure. But nevertheless, it has approval of experience and is one step in a reform that is lutely necessary. The important feature which the adoption of this amend - ment suggests, is the short ballot. If you can provide for the creation of three important officers by the appointive power of the governor, and it is a good thing so to do. why is it not just as good to provide for the appointment of other state officers? We will eventually conn - to electing only two or three state officers and I hope our con - stitution will provide for the election only of a governor once in four years, with an adequate salary, and make him ineligible for re-election, and possibly the state treasurer and supreme Pin enacting a law to make effective this new constitutional vision it will be necessarily elaborate and of some detail. The qualifications of the members to be appointed should be clearly defined, their duties specifically set out, their rela - tions toward ( the various superintendents defined, the method of procedure enabling the board to make investigations, the time that each member shall devote to his position, the salary to be provided for. and to what extent these institutions are under the management and control of this board, how it shall </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Xebraska Legislature 1913 7 Fss, put them under oath and force them to testify. « how often it is necessary to make visitations to the various institutions under the charge of the board, to define the duties of inspection and extent and frequency of the same, the con trol over books and records concerning the furnishings and property used in said institutions, to prescribe a uniform method of bookkeeping to be used in the several institutions, and where the said board shall keep its office, the repairs to be mail the board, and in making these reports, suggestions for new and needed legislation, limiting the power of the board in Eg for new buildings, and no member should be a f the county in which any institution under his control ted. I recommend that all buildings and improvements author - ized by the legislature costing more than $1,000. the specifica - tions of the same should be furnished by the state architect and it should he his duty on the application of the board to make, prepare, and furnish the same and that all such buildings and improvements costing over the sum of $1,000 should be under the direct supervision of said architect. They should be pro - hibited from contracting, or directing or promoting any sup port for buildings, betterments or improvements in excess of the amount provided therefor by law. Then there should be provided adequate punishment for the violation on the part of the board or any member thereof by removal from office. ETie board should be given the power of examining the su tendent and other executive officers of each institution i office in Lincoln and to consider in detail all questions rning the running of the institutions, and to secure *al management. Provision should be made for the superintendents of each institution to make daily or weekly reports, in writing to the board, of the number of additional inmates that his institution may accommodate and with such other information as the board may require. The law, in my judgment, also should provide that the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 Governor's Message board, in making appointments of superintendents, should be limited in the matter of the asylums to appoint as superintend - ents thereof only such physicians as are qualified by at least two years of experience as experts or assistants in some insti - tution similar to that of which he aspires to be a superintendent and he shall be a qualified specialist in nervous and mental diseases. And if the spirit and intent of this constitutional amend - ment is carried out, this law will also provide specifically and definitely to the effect that any member or officer of the board or any officer employed in any institution under its control who by solicitation or otherwise either directly or indirectly tries to influence another member of the board or its appointees or attempts to get him to adopt his political views or to favor any particular person or candidate for office, this member shall be removed by the proper authorities. Nothing short of a provision like that will carry out the object and the purpose of this constitutional amendment. Prom these details, only partially set forth, you gentlemen of the legislature can understand something of the difficulty and care that should be exercised in framing a law to meet the requirements of this constitutional amendment. But you are fortunate in having a commission provided for by the last legislature that will render you valuable assistance. kThis commission, composed of eminent lawyers of much erience, has prepared a bill to carry out the provisions of constitutional amendment which I herewith submit. If you enact a law along the lines suggested herein or pass the measure suggested by the statutory commission, you will render an invaluable service to the governor in the per - formance of this, the most responsible appointment that any chief executive has ever been called upon to make. By enacting the provisions as before suggested, you at once place the duty of the chief executive upon the highest plane possible and direct him, by force of law, to remove from con - sideration all applicants of the mere politician variety and to consider only such men as are well and favorably known, — </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Legislature 1913 9 men whose character, integrity, and reputation is of such quality that a mere mention of their name ensures faith and confidence that duties imposed will be well, ably, and conscientiously per- If the spirit and intent of this constitutional amendment is carried out, only such men will be appointed as have made a success of their own affairs and who are noted for un - selfish devotion to principle and who are always in the attitude on public matters of the greatest good to the greatest number and who are willing to make any sacrifice for principle. It is certainly a pleasure and a satisfaction to any executive to be thus directed in the performance of his arduous duties. The real intent of this constitutional amendment and the statute enacted, of necessity, eliminates a large class of appli - cants that are bound to pester and annoy the governor. The duty of our chief executive in making this appoint - ment will be so clear and so well denned, that it is hardly pos - sible to make a mistake. This board should be composed of men who are not only the incarnation of integrity and honor but should be possessed with much administrative and executive ability. At the same time, they should have profound sympathies and a keen inter - est in Nebraska's defective insane and unfortunate wards. In this position, these men will find an opportunity to exer - cise many phases of philanthropy and suggest in detail the man - agement of desperate and hardened criminals to the end that the law may be satisfied and at the same time that these men may have the opportunity to become better. In short, there is no state officer today who fills a position that demands a keener sense of discrimination and a profounder conception of justice or a better business head than do the men who are to become members of this commission. Lin the adoption of this amendment all the powers hereto - re vested in the governor and the commissioner of public lands and buildings, is now vested in the State Board of Commission - era of the State Institutions. 'I'tiTiH it f nl Irtws th At t Vi p AnnoiTitiVf* tv^tbtpi* of t hp sUDonii- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 Eent and of all of the attendants and the entire corps of tants is vested in this board. in order to safeguard matters and not repose too much wer in one man, the governor can only appoint members, save and with the consent and approval of a two-thirds vote of the senate. Thus, again, does the chief executive get assistance in obtaining the best ability possible in the appointment of this board. Lit is, in the first place, not to be supposed that a chief ecutive would for a moment consider appointing any man to this commission, save on the basis of qualifications alone, but should he make a mistake or refuse to comply with his well known duty, he would find a check in the senate, which would refuse to confirm an unworthy man. PJnder the provisions of this new amendment, the board not be vested with full power until July 1st of this year, only duty the governor has to perform in the matter is to submit the names to the senate to be acted upon, and when confirmed, they are to meet early in May for the purpose of organization. But no power whatever is vested in them to manage or make these appointments. Hence it devolves upon the incoming governor to leave these institutions under their present management until July 1st, or take the responsibility of removing the present superin - tendents and reorganizing each of these institutions and then run the risk of meeting the approval of the board that has the real and only right to make these appointments. In any event, no appointment should be confirmed until a statute is enacted, defining the powers, duties and qualifi - cations of this board. The senate has a duty co-equal with that of the governor. 1 am passing over without discussion the other three con - stitutional amendments adopted, not because they are unimpor - tant, but because of the many other things which I prefer to discuss and can, in my judgment be of more assistance to the legislature than by devoting any time to these other amend - ments. They contain no such sweeping and radical provisions </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 as do the two just discussed, but nevertheless are very impor - tant and I recommend that carrful and conservative consideration necessary to carry out the provisions of each of them. SPECIAL ACTS Wage Earners' Insurance Act. At the last session of the legislature, a commission was provided for to report to the next legislature the results of its investigation and to prepare a bill for the consideration of the legislature in the matter of the Wage Earners' Compensation I am informed that there is to be a majority and minority report at the hands of this committee. I have seen neither of these reports and have no information as to the recommen - dations to be made. This is a most important measure. Outside of the consti - tutional amendments there has been no special act of more far - reaching importance than this working man's insurance and in the enactment of a proper law, Nebraska at once assumes a new sense of governmental responsibility. yjpon this legislature, largely depends in the beginning, ler our state shall add its mite or portion to the advancing of civilization. Ee purpose of this act is to compel employers of labor to inancial provision for the inujred employes. More ac - y speaking, this act is the Working Man's Insurance. Sixteen states have already enacted this kind of a law. Ke investigations that I have been able to make lead me ?ve that the provisions of the act of the state of Wash - more nearly meet our requirements than those of the tates. In the first place, this act makes the state directly respon - sible. The injured party deals with a state commission, com- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 Governor's Message posed of three men, and the men appointed to fill this position did not seek the place, but the place sought them. Eself-serving, unscrupulous, ubiquotous politician should find a place on a commission of the importance of this d of the non-partisan board of control. Pe commissioner represents the manufacturers, another is ess agent, the third an eminent lawyer, and this commis - an administrative body. The employer does not become ible to the party injured and has no dealings with him matter of personal injury, but is responsible to the state The commission classifies, according to the risk of the busi - ess, commencing with extra hazardous and thus continuing until forty-seven groups or classifications have been formed, 'hen it levies on the employer a certain sum based on the per - entage of the payroll. In this way, a fund is provided for ach group or classification which the employer is compelled o maintain and when an employe is injured or killed, the state ommission has money on hand to pay any claim and the in - ured employe or his estate, as the case may be, notifies the com - mission, investigation is made and settlement had at once. In lis way, the employe and his family are immediately provided for and no one is made to suffer, and the family gets money when its needs money, and the corporation or employer is saved paying many fraudulent or exhorbitant claims and avoids an innumerable number of lawsuits and vexatious annoyances. El recommend that in the bill which shall be passed that you least have these provisions here outlined, incorporated into your asure. Development of Roads. tnext call your attention to the importance of some legis - providing for a state wide system in the development public highways. This is a subject that is attracting state wide attention </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Legislature 1913 13 tem should be provided, for it is only by systematic and intel - ligent direction that satisfactory results can be obtained. There is no subject which can more profitably engage your attention than the enactment of laws for good roads. In an agricultural state such as ours, where farm produce is hauled a considerable distance to a market place, it becomes a question of dollars and cents. The better the road, the larger tonnage hauled and consequently the expense of the transpor - tation is reduced accordingly. Travelling by automobile" has now become general, and eventually the almost exclusive way of getting across the coun - try, both for business and pleasure. To use automobiles suc - cessfully, good roads are necesssary. There already is enough money being expended upon the roads of our state to make them vastly better than they are. The trouble is that what work is done is of a spasmodic nature. tThe road overseer or a community, as a rule, works on the ds between showers when work on the farm cannot be carried conveniently. The most of this work is pursued at all times of the year and very much is done at an inopportune time. I recommend that a law be passed specifying the time in which roads shall be. worked. For instance, from the 1st of May to the 1st of September, all grading should be completed. Weed cutting should be done in the month of August. Nebraska has the best soil for the making of ideal roads to be found anywhere. Nature has done more for our state in this regard than we have done for ourselves, and yet we have only indifferent and bad roads because of our negligence and utter lack of system and time chosen in building these roads. I have to some extent examined the road laws of Maryland, Kansas, Pennsylvania, Missouri, and Ohio. And while I have not found in any one of these states provisions such that we should adopt the entire law of any one, yet in each I find many things that are applicable to the conditions here in Nebraska. Kid in the state of Maryland a most elaborate and «ys - supervi8ion of state roads by a state highway commis - his commission consists of three citizens of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 ro men from the geological survey, and the governor. The vernor has the power to designate one member of the com - mission as chairman. The chairman of the commission receives $2,500 a year. The other members receive $2,000 per annum and they are authorized to hire a secretary at $1,800 per year. The commission is given wide discretion in the employment of a chief engineer, assistant engineer and the professional and tech - nical help needed. This commission is authorized to improve a system of main roads of the state and to select, construct, im - prove, and maintain a general system of state roads and high - ways in and through all the counties of the state. The commission is given the power to make a general in - spection of all the roads in the state on the completion of same, and to inspect and make selection of certain roads to be im - proved within the counties and said roads to be so related to each other as to become a part of a general system of road de - velopment. I In my judgment, this is an important feature and I recom - nd that it be enacted into law in this state. For instance, some general section line road or series of such roads be selected by the commission and then make provision to have Ke cross roads leading up to these main trunk roads be de - loped. In other words, let our road system be analagous to the trunk line of some of our great railroads running across the state and then make provision to have other roads or cross Eds leading up to it prepared so that these cross roads may simply termed as feeders to the main roads. The state engineer should be a member of this highway commission and all reports of assistant engineers and county engineers should report to the state engineer, he, the state engineer, having an assistant, whose duty it should be to make personal investigation and receive general reports and report the results of his own investigation to the state commission. Prom the nature of the case to comply with our constitu - tion, the governor would be the state highway commissioner and the deputies under him would constitute the commission whose </seg>
            <seg id="p018">15 and repairing. The governor Aen having the appointive powar, should appoint, in addition to the state engineer, two other well known men of business ability who have made a study and gen - eral investigation of road building. It is unnecessary in this message to go into elaborate detail and discuss the provisions of the several state laws in - states, but I refer you to a careful study and investigation espe - cially of the road laws of Kansas. In my judgement, the sys - tem adopted there under law, more nearly meets the situation than do the statutes which I have examined in several other states. I again urge upon you the importance of enacting 1 lation along the line of development of our roads. No other legislation which will engage your attention this session will be more conducive to good results and general - faction, both from a standpoint of material benefit and com - fort and pleasure than will the enactment of some wise road In this connection I desire to call your especial attention to an item incorporated in the last federal appropriation bill providing for the house and senate to direct a general inquiry into the subject of federal aid in the construction of post roads and that the secretary of agriculture and the postmaster general were authorized to expend certain moneys in improving post roads within the states of the union. Under this act, fifty miles of road have been selected in each state in the union for experimental purposes, said road to be designated by the governors of the respective states and I have designated in this state the stretch of road between Omaha and Lincoln, via Ashland, which coincides approximately with what is known as the Omaha-Denver Automobile Route. Under appropriation of the federal government, they are to spend $10,000 in improving this road, conditioned that the state and their legal subdivisions will provide a sum of $20,000 to be in conjunction therewith and I wish to urge upon you to make some appropriation for this purpose. I am heartily in favor of the United States aiding the state </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 such aid to be extended to us by a willingness on our part to meet the conditions imposed. Publicity and Development. EThe one thing which the people of Nebraska have always ected and have never seemed to fully realize is the benefit ie derived from letting the outside world know what we ly have within the borders of our commonwealth. Three things conspire to make a great state. First, is the climate; second, the soil; third, the people. Climate is the basis of health, happiness, good cheer, thrift, and prosperity. In our state, we have a climate whose product is that energy and enterprise that gives to our people the initia - tive, — the self-reliance, and resourcefulness that makes of Ne - braska a potent factor in representative government. EIn combination with this magnificent climate, we have a le soil that produces in marketable quantities all of the als that go to make agriculture the king of industry. For instance, the chief agricultural product of Illinois is corn, and Lsame may be said of Iowa. The chief product of the Red ir country is wheat. Eit Nebraska produces in vast quantities corn, with as quality and certainty as does Illinois and Iowa. It pro - wheat of a quality scarcely inferior to the Red River country and in addition to all of this it produces luxuriantly that greatest of all forage crops, alfalfa. tin other words, Nebraska produces corn, alfalfa, and wheat certainly and with as much quality and with as great a yield does any of these other states that are adapted to produce y one of these great cereals. But this climate and this fertile soil would be of little con - sequence unless there was a people to take advantage of it. The many and manifold blessings found here in Nebraska. both from the standpoint of soil and climate, have been fully realized by the thrifty men and women, coming from the states across the Mississippi River. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Ot/7 l*O/V Ivt I/*' •*■ *&amp;J.*J 17 Eebraska, in the beginning, had for her pioneers, citizens heroic mould. This state was settled largely by the sol - of the War of the Rebellion and working hand in hand hese men came the best blood from foreign shores. BAs a result of all of this, our commonwealth can boast today aving a citizenship from the standpoint of intelligence, en - rise and patriotism that stamps it as a model political di - vision in representative government. Progressive, yet conserva - tives-religious, yet tolerant, — self-confident and self-satisfied, yet seeking more knowledge, and ever eagerly pursuing higher standards. P r et, with all of these blessings, our population is compara - ' stationary and we do not have half the inhabitants here we ought to have. I have travelled through many eastern states and have talked with many people concerning Nebraska and I say here to - day, without fear of successful contradiction, that Nebraska is probably the poorest advertised and the least known state in the entire union. There is no state in which there are better opportunities for the home seeker and the investor than in our state. What Eneed today more than anything else is more men. Enough lilies should be brought here to make our farms smaller and ter tilled. In all of the years that are gone we have made no effort and spent no money, worthy of mention, in the advocacy of the benefits and the opportunities to be derived and found here in California spends literally more than two millions of dol - lars per annum to advertise her state. And yet Nebraska, from an agricultural standpoint, from the home seeker's standpoint, is far better than is California. A large portion of southeastern Nebraska is adapted to fruit growing and raises a fruit of better flavor and more de - sirable in every particular than do any of the western states whose chiefest industry is fruit growing. The outside world knows nothing of this and the only way to show our goods is </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 Governor's Message to hold out inducements to investors and home seekers to make a personal inspection. El urge upon you to enact a law providing for a publicity •eau, — a bureau that will co-operate with the commercial clubs our cities and towns, carrying with it an appropriation con - ling facts and data pertaining to our commonwealth. Eyou will but appropriate one-half the money which I lereafter point out to you that can annually be saved by sing with all unnecessaries, we may reasonably expect to have thousands of new families settled within our state during the next biennium. Lin northwest Nebraska we find a vast irrigated section, some already under the ditch and much more that ought to be. Eiile visiting there last summer, I saw spring wheat that average forty bushels per acre, beets growing from six - twenty-two tons per acre, alfalfa, from four to five tons per acre, oats from seventy-five to one hundred bushels per acre. In short, what I saw was an agricultural scene that can - not be surpassed anywhere in any country or in any clime. And yet today there are not half enough people living there to till this land. In one town where I visited there were four thousand acres of land growing luxuriant crops. There were twenty-two thousand acres more that had not been plowed but with the water waiting. I asked a gentleman, a prominent busi - ness man of that little city, why they didn't farm more, why they let all of this splendid land go to waste. His reply was that every man in the town is working all of the land that he can take care of. LThis was a thriving village of twelve hundred people, with y one acre in five being worked, when if there were people enough there to till this soil properly, instead of being a village of one thousand or twelve hundred, it would be a magnificent little city of five or six thousand. It takes no casualist or prophet to exhibit the vast wealth that an increased population sufficient to till all this land, would produce. It takes no great stretch of the imagination to see the results in increased market centers and the vast growth </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Legislature 1913 19 of our cities that would come by reason of the development of In other words, take care of the country and the cities will take care of themselves. I urge upon you to establish a bureau composed of capable and earnest men who know how to let the world know what we have here in Nebraska and to give to them ample means to carry forward this work. In my judgment, one hundred thousand dollars would not be an unreasonable sum, but a very modest amount, with which to beg in this work. It is not necessary to go into detail as to what this bill should provide, for it is easy to provide an independent bureau managed by the right k.nd of men with ample means to do what you and each of you know ought to be done for and on behalf of the state of Nebraska. Law to do Away With Defense of Assumption of Bisk. Lin the session of 1907, there was passed a law known as Employer's Liability Act, which had for its object and pur - pose to do away with the defense in personal injury cases of contributory negligence by a fellow servant. kThis is a wise and beneficent law and was in justice de - ded by a large class of our ctizens. But in this class of s, an ingenious device has been found which, in effect, does away with the benefits of this law. Our federal courts have allowed the defendant to make the defense of what is known as the assumption of risk, — that is, the master takes the posi - tion that when the servant enters into his employment, he as - sumes whatever risk there may be, incident to his undertaking. And in this way, evidence is permitted to be introduced show - ing the risk and the hazard of the employment which the em - ploye entered upon and that the injury received was simply incidental to or was a natural consequence which follows the kind of employment he voluntarily entered into. Kie federal court of the eighth judicial district permits ce of this kind to be introduced and when so received, m arbitrarily directs a verdict against the plaintiff and </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 in favor of the defendant. This procedure is not only arbitrary and unwarranted, but in my judgment, invades the province of If this employer's liability act is to be effective and per - mitted to accomplish the purpose for which it was enacted, it is absolutely necessary for you at this time to enact a statute that will do away with this defense. A bill to accomplish this act can be concisely stated, and I submit to you for perusal and careful consideration the following measure : KCT FOR THE BETTER PROTECTION OF EMPLOYES sT THE SERVICE OF ALL RAILROAD COMPANIES ITHIN THIS STATE AND TO CHARGE THE CARRIER ITH ASSUMPTION OF RISKS. Be it Enacted by the People of the State of Nebraska : Pection 1. When a Railroad Company, or its representative, order or direct a servant in a particular manner, or way, or upon or to a particular place, or to work upon, or with a paticular appliance or machine, the servant shall not be deemed to have assumed the risk of injuries or damages thereby oc - casioned, although continuing in the employment of the Rail - road Company. Piection 2. Whereas, an emergency exists, this act shall effect and be in force from and after its passage and ap - proval. Sackett Law. Lin the session of 1907 there was passed what is known as Sackett Law providing for the removal of derelict officials. I have been, during the past two years, trying to enforce this law, but find as it now stands, that it is not sufficiently effective. Under the provisions of this law, the governor, upon sut - ficient complaint and showing, is given the authority to order the attorney general to institute ouster proceedings in the su - preme court. I have been obliged to resort to this procedure in several instances. But I find that by this method an oppor - tunity is given for protracted and vexatious delays and it is imrtAOci Vil A t f\ O fa\ ft \ \ \\ C* TT1 PT*1 1 at Q pocp q Tl/1 \ C\ Vl QVC it (\ of «■ </seg>
            <seg id="p024">21 rLed by the supreme court before the term of office expires the part of the official complained against. Pin my judgment, the law ought to be so amended as to ide among other things for the filing of a complaint with governor supported by an affidavit substantiating the charges set forth in said complaint. The governor should then be authorized to conduct a preliminary hearing upon notice to the party or parties affected. Upon such hearing, if he deems the evidence sufficient after being fully advised in the matter, authorizes the attorney general eral to proceed against the officer or officers complained against t'' suspend such officer or officers from the performing of their official duties pending the final hearing in the supreme court. The vacancy thus created could be filled by appointive power provided to fill a vacancy when one occurs. This is no experi - ment, but is the law in several of the leading states of this union at this time. Water Power Development. The development of the water power of our state has long been neglected and only recently has it attracted the attenion of the capitalist. Eie constantly increasing demand for cheap power and the strides in the development of the uses to which electricity i applied, has challenged the attention of the investor to some of the natural advantages in cheap power which Nebraska possesses. BFhe steady flow of a large volume of water in the Loup ■, beyond question, affords a power for manufacturing and portation purposes not hitherto appreciated. Reports of experienced engineers disclose the fact that the water power of the Loup and the Platte can be diverted to beneficial use to sufficient extent to afford all the power neces - sary for years to come. R fader existing laws, rights have been granted for the build - f power canals involving an investment of several mil - of dollars. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">22 Governor's Message Lin my judgment, this is the most important project tint occurred in Nebraska since the building of the railroads. What our great trunk line railways and their feeders are to transportation, that these power canals will be to the commer - cial development of our state. Its importance can scarcely be over-estimated and every encouragement, necessary to the devel - opment of these great projects, should be entered into by the people of the state. I Cheap power is the one thing that has ever been lacking our state and deprived it of diversified industries. P Under the proper management and direction of this enter - i, on the part of the public, there will come a development is bound to be of far-reaching importance and will change entire commercial features of our state. In the matter of regulating and controlling these public service corporations care and caution should be exercised in the enactment of laws on the one hand that will not be so drastic and radical as to frighten capital and legitimate investment in this important undertaking, and on the other hand we should not be derelict or indifferent in protecting the rights of the pub- I see no reason why his water power industry should not come under the same system of regulation that is provided for in the control of the railways of the state. Public ownership of this water power development is as impractical as would be the public ownership of the railroads of the country, and in my judgment we only need that kind of regulation which insures good service at just and equitable rates. Anything more than this would be contrary to public policy and result in keeping out capital and the development of this natural power which is so much needed. Historical Building I wish to urge upon you the necessity of taking some steps to provide a fund for the completion of the state historical building, the foundation of which is already erected. The plan of this building is to provide Quarters for the state historical </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Legislature 1913 23 society, the supreme court, the state library, and the attorney general's office. These are matters of vital importance to the people of this state. At present, we have a state library of the value of something over one-half million of dollars, which is crowded into one of the wings of this building. The present library room is not only a fire trap, but it is impossible to pro - tect the books from being stolen. We have many volumt the shelves of our state library that could not be replaced. The state historical society in the years past has accumu - lated some very valuable literary productions and it has a large and valuable museum, a part of which is crowded into cramped quarters, and a part of which is stored in the basement of the present building site. This museum, among other things, con - tains one of the finest natural history collections of Nebraska specimens in the West. In addition to this, the providing of adequate quarters for the supreme court and the state library would give much needed room in this building, especially dur - ing the session of the legislature. Many of the departments, by reason of the want of room, have to be moved in with some other department during the session of the legislature, and the legis - lature itself is compelled to rent rooms in the city for commit - tee purposes. rrhe state should acquire title in fee simple to the real estate occupied by the historical society. The report of the state librarian is herewith submitted and made a part hereof. Marriage and Divorce. During the past two years, my attention has been frequently directed to the desirability of more uniformity in the marriage and divorce laws of the United States. The divorce evil is a very serious problem in this country. The growing tendency towards more and more divorces is due primarily to the laxness of our marriage laws and with very few exceptions practically every European country is far in advance of us alone this line </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 Governor's Message This problem is by no means theoretical. We are confronted with an actual condition. I have fouiid during my administration that this matter vitally affects at least one administrative department and in- Emay not be generally known, but it is a fact that not an eighty-five per cent of the feeble minded children born irasak trace their mental condition directly to the marriage of mentally or physically incompetent parents, and that a large percentage of the inmates of all of our state institutions are the offspring of defective parents. At one of our asylums is confined a woman and two of her grown up daughters and a grandchild is an inmate of the in - stitute for the feeble minded. A careful inspection would dis - close a large number of such instances as this. PI direct your especial attention along this line to the law the state of Ohio, which takes most advanced ground. It is the only state that I know of requiring some measure of publicity to be given for a proposed marriage and it keeps a careful and complete record of all persons in the state author - ized by law to perform marriage ceremonies, and requires them to hold licenses for that purpose from the particular county in which they are a resident. Eut of still more importance is the statute of this state itely prohibiting the marriage of an habitual drunkard, ileptic or a mental incompetent. In making the investigation on this subject, I am strongly impressed with the wisdom of the legal requirements in some of our foreign countries, notably Italy, Spain, and Bulgaria. Each of these countries prohibit persons, known to be criminals, from entering into the marriage contract or persons who are accomplices with each other in the crime of homicide, as well as all mental and physical incompetents. Our restrictions against the marriage of insane persons are altogether too limited. I believe that this should be extended to the point that any person who has been found insane and </seg>
            <seg id="p028">25 prohibited from marrying unless he or she would be able to show by certificate of a competent expert that a complete re - covery had been had. Intermediate Penitentiary or State Reformatory. In the handling of our criminals confined in the peniten - tiary, Nebraska has permitted a system so antiquated and in - effective as to be absolutely indefensible. kWe have confined in our penitentiary at the present time »re than four hundred criminals of all degrees of viciousness d depravity, some total degenerates, others not really bad, but rather unfortunate, yet under the system in vogue at this insti - tution all male prisoners of all classes are permitted to be to - gether, to work together in the same shops, and to mingle gen - erally. Good results cannot be obtained by this method. Experience has proven to a certainty that classification and segregation of criminals confined in a state penitentiary is nec - essary. It is true that punishment for the sake of its deterrent effect must long continue to be the principal method in the protection of society, yet it must not be forgotten that punishment in the Sif imprisonment, even in the best of regulated penal in - ms, carries with it a certain undesirable effect. This, of is incidental to penal institutions, but it can to a certain be reduced vastly below what it is at the present time. The most important evil to avoid is the contamination of young men who are first offenders, by coming in contact with older and confirmed offenders. Such a situation results in educating the first offender in evil ways and makes the prisoner unfit for useful employment. Imprisonment deprives a man of the normal conditions of life and is indeed a serious situation. Then it follows that meth - ods and devices to minimize this evil of imprisonment are not only commendable but humane. One of the most effective ways of bringing about this de - sired result is the establishment of an intermediate reforma- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">26 Governor's Message tory, by means of which persons of a certain class may be con - fined and be enabled to return to a useful life after their term of imprisonment has expired, by giving opportunities for school - ing, farm work, productive occupations or industrial training. Not only will an intermediate reformatory establish facilities along this line, but it will also enable the state to make a sys- Eatic classification and a consequent segregation of its crim - population. fA law defining the class of offenders who should be com - ted to a reformatory is largely a matter of detail for this islature to work out and much discretion should be left to trial court as to whether or not an offender should be sent the penitentiary proper or to an intermediate reformatory. An investigation of the laws of some of our sister states where reformatories have been in operation for some time and the reports of boards of control, wardens, and superintendents of these institutions, discloses the fact that the best classifica - tion to be made is something like this — a person sent to the reformaory or intermediate penitentiary should be a man not previously an inmate of an asylum and should be anywhere be - tween the ages of sixteen and thirty years, except persons who are committed for such crimes as treason, murder in the first degree, sodomy and incest. Some states provide that in ad - dition to the above exceptions, persons convicted of rape, rob - bery, breaking and entering in the night with the intention of committing some crime, may in the discretion of the court be confined either in the reformatory or the penitentiary. Two ways are open to you in solving this problem : First, if you desire merely to patch up and temporarily meet the exigency, you can build a new cell house and enlarge the grounds of our present penitentiary. This would require a considerable outlay and would not in any way finally solve the problem or meet the issue. E«cond, build an intermediate reformatory in some suit - location in the state where a body of land can be had mection with the institution. I call your attention to the Soldier's Home at Grand Island </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Legislature 1913 27 where the state has 640 acres of good land and where in the im - mediate vicinity more can be added, if required, at a reasonable B Nebraska has two Soldiers' Homes and she never needed one. Why not abandon the Home at Grand Island and erect tever buildings necessary over at the other Home located at ord and then take the grounds and the buildings at Grand Island and use them for a state reformatory T While these build- Eit is true, at Grand Island, are not exactly suited for this ose, yet they could be made so or torn down and others, ble, erected in their place. In my judgment, the best possible treatment that could be given to inmates of a state reformatory is the opportunity to work out in the open air. A large number of these young men and first offenders come from large centers of population and have never had the beneficial influences obtainable on a farm. The state of Pennsylvania, at the expense of many millions of dollars, purchased a very large tract of land. The warden of this institution, whom I have met and gone over the matter with, informs me that the tract of land purchased by the state and on which modern buildings are being erected, affords every facility for the inmates to learn how to farm the land, being so diversified in its resources that it has water power, a forest, and mineral resources, thus giving the opportunity for many different kinds of occupations. While Nebraska can go into nothing so elaborate as that, yet the principle involved is the Pis my experience during the past two years, as a chief ive. that the difficulty of the prison employment in our penitentiary is the monotony and tedious hum-drum that permits of no mental exercise and thus keeps the morale of the men in an undesirable condition. I also notice that a large number of the men confined in our penitentiary come there as a rule in a weakened and debilitated physical condition. An opportunity, under health - ful surroundings, to work at something that is conducive to health- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 Governor's Message build up these men and to make it possible for them ever to be come useful citizens. EThe problem of keeping men at something that will bring best financial results to the state is only secondary, and as pared to the welfare of the men is worthy of no considera - tion at all. If, by having these prisoners working on a farm and learn - ing how to farm intelligently and scientifically, we afterwards induce them to take up agricultural pursuits, the chances of their becoming useful citiezns ever after, are greatly increased. Lit has been suggested that the state purchase land having il suitable to make brick. This, in my judgment, is imprac - ticable, and is nothing short of a species of slavery because of the heavy work and the monotonous drudgery which it en - tails and, besides, such an establishment would come in com - petition with several well established industries of that kind here in Nebraska, where free labor at liberal wage is employed. PJut it may be said that brick will only be manufactured IBcient quantities to build state institutions and other build - erected by the state. But then, in that event, will you not deprive the manufacturers of this state of an important cus - tomer t The manufacturing of brick involves much heavy, monoton - ous and undesirable work, and I know from experience that men forced to a task of this kind would complain bitterly and feel that the state was imposing upon them a burden that was de - signed to crush their spirit and break their strength. E Nebraska cannot afford to go into the brick business with convicts. The making of brick on the part of our Nebraska victs would be the establishment of a bondage not unlike t into which the Children of Israel were forced. Ee contract labor now used in the penitentiary cannot be come in competition with free labor in any important y. A new branch of labor has been added by entering into a contract to manufacture porch furniture which is light work and at the same time requires no small amount of skill, and </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Legislature 1913 29 when a prisoner becomes proficient in the manufacture of these chairs and many other articles he has a trade upon leaving the penitentiary. E manufacture of brooms is a vast improvement over re - convicts to make shirts and overalls. That contract celled by the board, and wisely so I think. But in the building of an intermediate reformatory and operating land in connection therewith and making arrange - ments to have convicts work upon the roads so far as it is prac - ticable to do so in Nebraska, in my judgment, goes a long way toward solving the convict labor problem in our penitentiary. An examination discloses the fact that there is much needed improvement in the repair of the buildings as now existing. For instance, the dining room and the kitchen are unsanitary. The dining room is poorly ventilated and it is impossible to maintain proper conditions with what we now have. I recommend the building of a new dining room and kitchen. This could be done by erecting a building in the center of the yard without any great expense. By erecting a new building in the center of the prison yard you would have a place that would be cheerful and well venti - lated, and would be large enough for a kitchen as well as a dining room. Siere is one thing which has never been adequately pro - for and that is a hospital. In case of an epidemic of ty - fever or other contagious and infectious disease that would spread among convicts, such as has been the experienced in the cities in this state, there would follow much suffering growing out of the inability to properly care for the patients. There is urgent need for a new hospital at our prison. A building for the dining room which I mentioned could be extended to two stories and a hospital room provided above the dining room. I am merely making these suggestions for the purpose of urging upon you to make provision in some proper and ef - ficient way for a new kitchen, a new dining room and a new hosDital I recommend the appointment of a committee that is </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Governor's Message 30 posted upon prison affairs to make an investigation and re port to you as to what ought to be done. Advisory Board of Pardons In this connection I call your attention to the advisory board of pardons and paroles, created by the last legislature. I have been intimately associated with the workings of this board and report that the law creating it was a wise provision and the workings of this board have proven very satisfactory. By reason of their investigations and decisions rendered, a vast amount of good has been done and much money saved to the state. Under the indeterminate sentence act and the law providing for the parole of prisoners, such a board is an absolute necessity. It is impossible for a chief executive, with his almost in - numerable and exacting duties to take the necessary time for investigation and the hearing of evidence in the matter of ap - plication for paroles and pardons. Since the organization of this board, three hundred and seventy-five applications have been filed and hearings had. E'hese applications may be classified as follows : For par - one hundred and thirteen; for commutation of sentence, two ; and for parole, two hundred. The board have concluded their findings as to two hundred and sixty-two applications, of which one hundred and twenty - five were for pardon or commutation of sentence and one hun - dred and thirty-seven were for parole. Of the cases considered for pardon or commutation of sentence, twenty-nine were favor - ably recommended to the governor, nine of which were on ac- Ent of serious illness of such a nature and condition as to en - ger the life of the applicant and the health of the inmates he penitentiary. They declined to recommend executive clemency to forty applicants for pardon and thirty-three for commutation of sen - tence. Of the thirty-nine applications considered for commuta - tion of sentence, they recommended a reduction of sentence for six and that no executive clemencv be extended the other thirtv- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Xebraska Legislature 1913 31 three. Of the two hundred applications filed for parole, the board have disposed of one hundred and thirty-seven, having granted eighty-three. Of the men paroled, twenty-eight have keived their final discharges on account of the termination of ir sentences. Pin paroling the men, the board have been successful in ing forty-six on farms. The eighty-seven men on parole who have worked for wages have received in cash $14,402. In case an applicant was single ami had aged parents and needed assistance, one of the conditions in the parole has been that all or a greater portion of the wages received should be paid to the parent or parents of such prisoner. Ee indeterminate sentence and parole law, when operated lection with a board of paroles and pardons is very satis - and is certainly a most humane way in which to treat prisoners; not only that, but from a business standpoint, it is entirely satisfactory. These paroled prisoners have earned nearly $15,000 and of the prisoners paroled, eighty-eight per cent have made good. Khen it is known that one-third of the inmates of our irison are boys under twenty-one years of age, and it is : majority of this class of men that have been paroled, one alize something of the importance and of the good that determiate sentence and parole law operated by a board Ions and paroles has done, not only for the state, but for unfortunates. EThis board has exercised much care and patient investiga - in passing final judgment upon the several applicants and y here that if the parole law and the indeterminate sentence are to be retained on our statute books, then you must also in and provide for an advisory board of pardons and paroles. The legislature passing this act only provided for a certain sum to be paid when the board was actually in session or doing work. I recommend that in lieu of this, you appropriate the sum of $1,000 per year as a salary for each member of this board and then they can act independently and stay in session as long as necessary without being subject to criticism and harsh </seg>
            <seg id="p035">32 attacks. Such a provision would place the board in an independ - ent attitude. The report of the proceedings of this board, together with correspondence received from the prisoners and the names of each prisoner paroled or pardoned is herewith submitted and made a part of this message. In this connection, I recommend that in the case of convicts who have families dependent upon them that a certain per - centage of their earnings in the penitentiary be turned over to their families. The board of pardons and paroles could make an examina - tion and investigation for the purpose of ascertaining the sit - uation of a convict's family and then report to the board of control and let them, when fully advised in the matter, if they deem it proper, direct the warden to remit each month a certain percentage of the convict's earnings to the wife or guardian of his children, as the case may be. The Drug Habit at the Penitentiary. One of the most difficult tasks that the management of our penitentiary has to undertake is the prevention of the use of opiates and liquor. I recommend the enactment of a law making it a felony for any person to carry any opiates, drugs or liquor or what is commonly known as "dope" and giving it to the prisoners or in any way, either directly or indirectly, causing convicts to procure "dope." is absolutely necessary to resort to drastic means to ak up this most nefarious traffic. The certainty of a term in the penitentiary for anyone deal - ing in these injurious drugs will, in my judgment, effectually settle the question. And it is one of the laws pertaining to the regulation of the penitentiary that should not, under any circum - stances be neglected and overlooked. State Board of Charities and Corrections. This department through the activities of its chief clerk has continued to carry on the work connected therewith in the same </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Legislature 1913 33 efficient manner that gave it the approval of previous governors. The quarterly visits and inspection of the penal and chari - table institutions have had a wholesome effect. The chief clerk of this department is ex-officio secretary of the state prison board, and the combining of the two offices makes it one of the important departments of the state. Eis board has done an immense amount of good and I lend that it be given sufficient financial support to carry maintain this work. EXERCISING ECONOMY IN PUBLIC AFFAIRS Economy in the conduct of public affairs is a desideratum always to be sought. For many years past there has been a growing tendency to increase the amount and extent of red tape in the conduct of public business which means an ever increasing demand for deputy and clerical hire and new officers. In some of the largest and most important departments of our state government where business is running into the millions of dollars we find a wise exercise of economy and amount of help reduced to actual requirements. This is notably true in the office of the state treasurer and that of the attorney general. The former officer doing business with scores of banks and other institutions, has to assist him a deputy, a stenographer and two clerks. The state treasurer has under his management and direct charge all of the bonded interests of the state together with educational funds, the financial accounting of the state univer - sity and of the normal schools and, in fact, has dealings with every county treasurer in the state. In addition to this, vast and complicated interests of the state pass through his hands and under his direct management. This is a responsibility that takes scrupulous and painstaking can- and a clear head, to per - form satisfactorily. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">34 EIn the attorney general's office we find the attorney general ducting the legal affairs of the state with one deputy, one stant and one stenographer. This office conducts hundreds of cases annually in the su - preme court involving not only criminal trials but several cases running into millions of dollars and he also appears before the railway commission in which the state is interested and he does this work with the help of three people. Then the question arises, why should the other officers or departments where work cannot be said to be more onerous or important employ many times as much help as does the depart - ment of the state treasurer and the attorney general's office? In the office of the state superintendent we find the super - intendent and a deputy superintendent and in addition three other "assistants and six clerks, the total force aggregating something like ten or twelve people. In the office of the secretary of state, we also find a large force working. The present final report of the state auditor shows that there are employed in this office sixteen people drawing an aggregate salary of $18,240 and that up to the time of the filing of his final report the state auditor was obliged to hire eight extra employes, expending therefor $5,201.20. tin my judgment, there is much unnecessary work done in offices in the way of recording in long hand. This is ab - utely unnecessary. It would be just as effective, for instance, in the insurance department, to file all bonds in a large book for that purpose properly indexed, and save the expense of several clerks. EAn examination discloses that there is a triplication of book - ing in the offices of the state auditor, the state treasurer and secretary of state. For instance, when an item is audited he state auditor and entry made thereof, the same entry, in t, is made in the office of the state treasurer and in addition to this the whole proceeding is again recorded and goes through the office of the secretary of state. Here we find the same account kept in three sets of books in 1 11 1 ctr st? jJttr I" nitti^ uillL."s. 1 Ills LrctllcS I lie IlcCcoollj' Ol 21 II 111- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">35 Eased amount of help and extra expense and to say the least system is antiquated and should be abolished. There is no necessity whatever of having this matter pass through the office of the secretary of state. It possibly is n sary to have this transaction pass through the auditor's and the state treasurer's offices. That is as far as it is necessary to go and all the record that is necessary can be had in tht&gt;s.&gt; two offices. This item alone would save a large sum of money. Coming to the office of the governor, the law provides for a chief clerk and a recording clerk. It is my experience that here is an unnecessary duplication and expense. The chief clerk can, if a few changes are made, do all of the work and perform both the duties of the chief clerk and the recording clerk. This item alone would be a saving to the state of not less than three thousand dollars. And in this connection, I point out to you that there is a duplication in the office of the governor and secretary of state in the record kept of commissions issued to notaries public. Consequently here is a large amount of bookkeeping with all of the expense attendant thereto that is merely sur - plusage. There is no necessity of having a record kept in but one office of the commissions issued to notaries public. "With this duplication wiped out, the chief clerk could easily take care of all the work in the governor's office. It is now required to copy the messages of the outgoing and ingoing governor in longhand. This is unnecessary. In the department of the clerk to the supreme court and librarian, we find a large amount of help employed in this depart - ment which, in my judgment, is wholly unnecessary, if more business-like methods were introduced. There is a clerk and a deputy clerk and a librarian and a deputy librarian, reporters and stenographers galore, when as a matter of fact, the duties and labors of the clerk are not sufficient to keep him busy alone. There is expended in this department for salaries alone $1 per annum. ■n the office of the commissioner of public lands and build - we find several clerks and deputies employed where, with </seg>
            <seg id="p039">36 a change in the office methods but one would be necessary and could easily do all of the work. Now, let it be understood that this criticism is levied at the system and at no officer or employe. All of this extra expense running into many thousands of dollars is simply the result of an antiquated system and the amounts expended in excess of what is necessary could be avoided if a better system of business were introduced. fl am satisfied that under a proper organization and a proper tem with red tape abolished, that not less than two hundred usand dollars to the biennium could be saved to the taxpayers the state. rl recommend to the legislature the appointment of a com - ttee consisting of men of ability ; in fact, men who are experts their knowledge and experience in the working of departments like these to the end that a careful and impartial investigation may be made for the purpose of ascertaining to what extent a reorganization may be made, uniform systems of bookkeeping introduced and a change in the methods adopted during a long series of years. It is my opinion that much unnecessary work is done that is of no real value to the state. And the state uni - versity should be included in this investigation. In some of the departments of state a large amount of litera - ture is sent out which is surplusage and wholly unnecessary. The committee appointed by the legislature possibly might be able to take up an investigation at once and report to the pres - ent session so that this much needed reform could be had. In all events, a committee should be appointed to carefully study and investigate the situation and report either to this legislature or to the ensuing one. Country Life Commission Should be Abolished P Continuing these suggestions along the line of economy, ill your attention to the fact that the last legislature made appropriation creating a country life commission. While such a commission has a laudable purpose and pos - sibly some good may have come from its workings, yet it is en- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">37 Ejly unnecessary. The work done along the line of this com - jsion can more effectually be done by the agricultural depart - nt of the state university. This department has already conducted meetings throughout the entire state and awakened much interest and with the assist - ance given to it by the various commercial clubs of the &gt; great work has been accomplished. Investigations can be made by this board. rThis commission, in my judgment, is a useless expenditure should be abolished. I see nothing that it has done but what could just as well be done by the agricultural department of the university. And in abolishing this board, you save to the state in this one item not less than $1,500. Junior Normals Should be Abolished. There is no state in the union that pays higher tribute to the cause of education than does Nebraska. In no state is the percetnage of literacy and general intelligence higher. Educa - tion is widely disseminated among our people. It is our d&gt; — in fact, our determination, to maintain this standard by gen - erously appropriating all the funds necessary to place within the reach of all the advantages of an eudcation. Eis can only be done under intelligent direction and only h money expended as is necessary to accomplish the desired A lavish and loose expenditure of money for our schools that results in duplication and cannot bear the scrutiny of close business methods and public needs, is injurious and should be avoided. Nebraska has four normal schools splendidly equipped with all modern facilities and an able corps of teachers installed in each institution and each school located wisely, so that each of them can be patronized in the aggregate from all portions of the state. As a matter of fact, our state has more normal schools to the population than any state in the union except one. The state </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Governor's Message 38 E Oklahoma with a population of 1,650,000 inhabitants has six mal schools, a normal school to every 276,192 inhabitants. E Nebraska with a population in round numbers of 1,192,000 our normal schools or a normal school on an average to 298,054 inhabitants. The governor of Oklahoma in his recent message recommends the dropping of three normal schools and in case his recommen - dation is accepted, that leaves Nebraska with a larger number of schools in proportion to the population than any other state in the union. EIn addition to this training provided for by means of splen - normal schools we have between seventy-five and one hun - i high schools with normal training. Thus it would - : the desirability of giving to the school population the efits of a normal training had been generously and amply pro - »d for ; and it is a question if it has not already gone too far. It was the session of 1907 that established what is known as the junior normals, eight in all. The last legislature provided for an appropriation of $20,000 to carry out the provisions of ENhen these junior normals were originally provided for it have been wise and proper, but since their organization the has established two new normal schools, one at Chadron in the extreme northwest part of the state and one at Wayne in the northern part of the state. Thus we have four normal schools today, one in the southern portion of the state, another in the extreme northwest, another in the northeasterly part of the state and another at Kearney, in the central portion of the state. It would therefore seem that these junior normals were unnecessary. One junior normal last year had twenty-three in attendance and it cost the state $1,400, and this is a fair sample. Every pupil attending these junior normals could just as well attend one of these state normals and have far greater facil - ities than it is possible to have at a junior normal. The state of Nebraska could afford to pay the personal expenses at the normal schools for every student who attends the junior normals and be money ahead. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">39 Elf we are to maintain and equip these state normals at so sh pains and expense why should we provide for and make ucements to keep pupils away from them? I recommend to this legislature that this law providing for junior normals be repealed and no further appropriation made to continue the same, that every facility necessary and essential to normal training is afforded at our state normal school. In my judgment, there is every reason to repeal this law and no valid reason to continue it. State Should Go Out of Business of Game Birds. The last session of the legislature provided $5,000 for the purpose of purchasing certain game birds to be raised and de - veloped here in our state and the state now has on hand for its money expended a few hundred dollars worth of Chinese and Japanese pheasants and other game birds. In going into the business of raising game birds, the legis - lature overlooked the altogether essential feature in the first place, that was before it got a large number of expensive birds on its hands it should have provided a suitable place in which to keep them. There is at the present time no suitable place provided for the rearing of these birds and unless the legislature makes an adequate appropriation to buy a tract of land somewhere suit - ably located to put this industry into the hands of experts and under proper environments, it is in my judgment unwise to con - tinue in this undertaking and I recommend that there be no further appropriation made to maintain this industry and that the state should close out its undertaking in this department. I do not wish to be understood as taking the position that we should not protect the birds of our state. As a matter of fact, there should be every effort made to protect the game that we now have and we should have an appropriation made suffi - cient to obtain enough local game wardens to see to it that the state laws are enforced. But I believe it unwise for the state of Nebraska to embark in the industry of raising game birds that are not indigenous to our state. It would be far better to direct 512302U </seg>
            <seg id="p043">40 PSach ensuing legislature is called upon to appropriate scores ousands of dollars more than its predecessor. The time has come when we should call a halt on this matter and make an intelligent and impartial survey ; in other words, an open and fearless investigation as to the needs and interests of these con - stantly increasing demands for more money. It is true that we have a rapidly developing state, that its industries and its institutions and its society is becoming more complex and varied from every view point and its requirements are constantly growing and that it of necessity will take more money each biennium and for that reason it behooves the legisla - ture, representing the tax payer, to see to it that only so much is appropriated as can be economically and intelligently invested. I am satisfied that if these suggestions of economy are fol - lowed out and an investigation of the various departments of the state, including the state university, had, it will be discovered that much more expenditure can be avoided than I have pointed out. I personally know there is unnecessary duplication almost everywhere. Again, let me repeat, that I am criticising no officer or any department. I am pointing out the defects of a system that has been growing up for many years. Today this system is burden - some and expensive and I am simply asking for an investigation to disclose what ought to be done away with and what ought to be retained. UNIVERSITY REMOVAL In the matter of the state university, there is an issue now presented to you for consideration and definite action. L Nebraska is justly proud of this great institution of learn- She has amply provided for it. But unfortunately, in the beginning, or in the years follow - ing its location, adequate grounds so that this institution could </seg>
            <seg id="p044">41 Bd in accordance with the needs of a great and growing were not provided. We are now facing a situation where buildings are demanded and actually needed without a suit - ocation upon the city campus to erect the same. The question is, from a financial standpoint, — would it be cheaper to purchase more ground for purposes of enlarging the campus, or erect all new buildings from now on out on the beau - tiful grounds of the state farm! It is argued that it will cost between seven and eight hun - dred thousand dollars for ground anywhere near adequate to build these structures and have proper surroundings on the city And the question is, after we have expended this large amount of money, — will we then have grounds enough to provide for this big institution, not only for tomorrow, but for all time to comet Remember this is a state that in a few decades hence is cer - tain to have many times the population now living here. The lack of symmetry, general design, and uniform archi - tecture of the buildings that are thrown together promiscuously upon a little crowded space of ground does not reflect credit upon Elf it is your purpose to allow the institution to remain upon city campus, certainly some model or general plan should be jted where there would be uniformity in architecture. If we are to allow this university to remain in the city and adopt, as some suggest, the German plan, then we should adopt the German style of architecture and location of buildings. For instance, if all the buildings of the future are to be crowded in upon this little narrow confine, they should be erected around the borders of the ground now used for the campus. That is, they should be constructed on the outer lines of a quadrangle, leav - ing an open space or court in the center. EiVhen you come to investigate and analyze, there are not so many buildings on this city campus but what should be down and new ones created. The central building, known as University Hall, is absolutely </seg>
            <seg id="p045">42 unsafe and should be torn down and the same condition prevails with reference to Nebraska Hall. Ee chemical laboratory and the larger portion of Grant ial Hall are old buildings and while not unsafe, they could down without much expense and are not of such a char - acter as to be desirable buildings for any permanent development of the university. LThe building situated between Memorial Hall and Nebraska 11, where the museum is situated, while a newer building than those mentioned, is by no means first-class and would eventually have to be remodeled. In fact, there are only five buildings on the city campus that can lay claim to any degree of permanency or are modern and up-to-date in their equipment. These five buildings are the university library building, and the two buildings north thereof and the new building now be - ing erected for the law school, and these five buildings are of such a character that they could be used to advantage by the state for purposes of housing some other institution, together with the colleges of law and medicine, should the university be re - moved from the present campus, for by reason of location, the colleges mentioned should be left where they are. The amount of money necessary to purchase real estate to annex to the city campus would practically erect as many new buildings out at the farm as we now have of old and worthless ones here upon the campus, and which must in the very near future be replaced by modern fireproof structures. EThe buying of a few blocks of ground at enormous expense in the eity would at the most be only a temporary expedient would not solve the problem for all time to come. The replacing of these old buildings by new ones and the additional amount of real estate bought would mean an outlay of one million dollars, approximately, and that would not even settle the question. This amount of money expended in new buildings at the farm would make an institution of greater importance and better equipment by many fold than it is at the present time. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">43 E'.t is impossible to give the argument pro and con in so ira - mt a matter as this in a single paper. Hut suffice it to say this legislature should fix a policy that will settle this i definitely. ■ other words, at this time make provision for ample rooa t regard to expense, which you will have to do in the ou propose to leave the university here on the city campus. I am unable to understand by what process of reasoni: kind of business principles you should adopt that you would he justified in buying as much real estate as new buildings v. when you have already on hand, in the name of the - better and more desirable ground than any that you could pur - chase at the very edge of the city. Ehis provision necessary to build these new buildings eotdd de in easy payments so that there would be no appreciable ce in the taxes of the state. I therefore recommend a careful and conservative examina - tion into this matter to the end that a policy may be established which will be for the best interests of the state university ::U its patrons. What is the best thing to do for this institution ? AY ! the kind of policy to establish that will bring the great to the greatest number? What will really and truly promote the genuine interests of this university! E These are the questions that should be uppermost in your Is. The uncertainty now prevailing is a positive injury to university. So thus it devolves upon you to build perma - ly for all time to come a lasting foundation for the grt tution of learning to be found in the West. COURT PROCEDURE, PLEADING AND PRACTICE Eis a demand in this country for a more simplified pro - our courts. Altogether too much time is given to quib - 1 legal technicalities rather than to a consideration of of a controversy. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">44 IXOVCtTwt S MeSSQyc I The great trouble is that we are laboring under an anti - ated system of procedure that should be replaced by an up-to - te and modern system. Many states in the union are conducting investigations along this line of simplifying their practice and procedure and prob - ably no state has gone about the work as systematically and as thoroughly as has Florida. In the winter of 1911, pursuant to a resolution of the legis - lature, the governor of Florida appointed a commission of three men, headed by the Hon. James B. Whitfield, Chief Justice of the supreme court, who were to examine the laws of their state and all other states in the union and prepare and report a bill for this coming session of the Florida legislature, the object and pur - pose of which bill would be to simplify legal procedure generally and dispense with useless forms and pleadings. This commission was assisted in its work by the circuit judges of the state of Florida and I invite your careful consideration to the measures which they have proposed along this line. The principle act in section 1 provides as follows, to-wit: "Section 1. That the provisions hereof are intended to sim - plify Pleading, Practice and Procedure in the courts of this State so as to dispense with immaterial forms and technicalities, to ob - viate unnecessary pleadings and procedure and undue delays in maturing causes for trial, and to facilitate the trial and final dis - position of causes upon the merits, to the end that justice may Lad ministered by the courts without needless delay and ex - se, as contemplated by the constitution." You will see from the first section of the bill that a measure which covers the field pointed out in said section will accomplish great good. In the examination of their report in detail and the measure for the simplification of procedure which this commis - sion have proposed, I am impressed by many features therein which certainly must expedite the hearing of causes. For instance, the law provides that if a defendant wishes to make a special appearance in a cause and therafter to demur to th3 pleading of the plaintiff and if the demurrer is overruled to </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Legislature 1913 45 plead to the merits that he shall file all his pleading at one and the same time — that is to say, he will enter his special appear - ance, challenging the jurisdiction of the court and file his de - murrer and his answer to the merits at one and the same time. And if the preliminary pleas are overruled, then no additional time is necessary for the defendant to further plead. Another wise provision in this law, it seems to me, is the sec - tion providing for the fixing of certain days by statute as "Rule Days," upon which days all special appearances, demurrers, pre - liminary motions, etc., are disposed of, so that at the regular terms of court, there is nothing on hand but the actual trial of Section 26 of the act provides that no judgment, order, or de - cree shall be set aside, reversed, or annulled or new trial grant - ed, on the ground of misdirection to the jury or of any error at law or in any matter of practice or procedure unless it shall ap - pear probable from the entire record that the error complained of has injuriously affected the substantial right of the party com - plaining thereto. PI believe that there is no one thing that this legislature can that will be of more lasting benefit to the people of this state who have rights that they want adjudicated and to relieve over - burdened courts, than the enactment of a measure along the lines suggested by the learned bench of the state of Florida. IN BE INTERMEDIATE COURT My attention has been brought by the supreme court to the crowded condition of its docket and to the fact that it is impos - sible to keep abreast of the work before it and I submit to you for consideration, with my approval, the following recom - mendation of said supreme court judges : "To the Governor: Knder the provisions of section 22, of article 5, of the Con - on, referring to a report to be made by the judges of the ne court as to defects in the Constitution and laws," the </seg>
            <seg id="p049">46 Governor's Message members of the supreme court, observing the rapidly increasing business of the court, have had certain provisions of the Consti - tution under consideration and recommend the submission to the people of the following proposed changes. L First : Section 1, of article 6, should be amended to read as ws: ' The judicial power of this state shall be vested in a supreme court, district courts, county courts, justices of the peace, police magistrates, and in such other courts inferior to the supreme court as may be created by law.' The necessity for this amendment to the Constitution grows out of the fact that all causes are appealable to the supreme court and the Constitution as it now exists prohibits any other method of reviewing errors of the trial court. All case,s, without refer - ence to the amount or question involved, if appealed at all, must be taken to the supreme court for final review. With the amend - ment made, changing the word 'district' to 'supreme,' the legis - lature could provide for a review of such cases without delay and at much less expense to litigants. Second: It is provided in section 24, of article 1, of the Constitution, that, 'The right to be heard in all civil cases in the court of last recort, by appeal, error, or otherwise, shall not be denied." We recommend the submission of an amendment in substantially the following form, to- wit: 'The right to be heard in all cases in an appellate court, by appeal, error, or otherwise, shall not be denied.' Eiese recommendations being deemed of great importance spectfully submitted and recommended as the unanimous of the judges. M. B. REESE, Chief Justice. December 19, 1912." Kfile as a part of this message the biennial reports of the and boards of trustees of the state institutions, state officers le various deputies of the executive department. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Sebraska Legislatun 191&amp; 47 STATE INSTITUTIONS The institutional heads have various recommendations as to repairs and extensions which merit your careful consideration, as they are urged solely with a view of affording better facilities for carrying on the work which they have in charge. I call your special attention to the recommendations of Drs. Johnson, of Norfolk, and Kern, of Hastings, with refereii. the purchase of additional land and erection of buildings, and Dr. Williams, of Lincoln, as to needed additional improvements and buildings. LThe Girls' Industrial School, at Geneva, is having a serious lem as to proper segregation of the inmates for want of room. A better salary should be provided for the superintendent and matron of the Women's Industrial Home, at Milford. The character and importance of the work being done at the Milford Home is not generally understood. The state is fortunate in having two such women as the Misses Ward, who have discharged their duties with such fidelity to the trust reposed in them that the changing fortunes of politics have not afl'ected their positions and I hope never will. STATE OFFICERS The recommendations of the state officers are based on the experience of their service to the state. I have hereinbefore dwelt at length upon the necessity of a readjustment of the system of conducting the state business in the various departments and the recommendations of the auditor are supplementary to this and should be considered in conjunction therewith. His report in this regard will be of great assistance as he specifically points out some excellent methods whereby the business of the state can be conducted in a more expeditious and economical manner. Ee state treasurer has recommendations as to the state gency and educational lands and founds of which I heartily e. His views on these important matters, if enacted into legisla- </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Governor's Message DEPUTIES OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT rhe reports of the deputies of the Executive Department that the various duties imposed upon them have been faith - fully, efficiently and economically discharged. The law creating the department of Building Inspector has resulted in a saving to the tax payers of the state of a large sum. You will find the state architect has a report of much value. It gives you a good general idea of conditions of the build - ings of all state institutions and what is needed by way of re - pairs, improvements, and new buildings. EThe department of Hotel Inspector, created two years ago, proven so beneficial that a more liberal appropriation should lade therefor. Eie Game Department, Fire Department, Labor Bureau, Veterinarian, and Pure Food Department have each im- Jy enforced the law. The laws governing the practice of the veterinary should be amended to the end that more rigid qualifications to practice may be imposed and enforced. I A law should be enacted governing cold storage plants, and t under the supervision of the Pure Food Department. Race does not permit of a more extended mention of these ant matters, but they should receive careful consideration r hands. Economy without parsimony, — efficiency, not partisan consid - eration, should be the watchword of every legislator and execu - tive officer during the coming biennium. Respectfully submitted, CHESTER H. ALDRICH, Governor of Nebraska. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>