<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00031</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' AGRICULTURAL CLUBS, THE CLIMATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Distributed June 16, 1913 THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, NEBRASKA, V. S. A. NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' AGRICULTURAL THE CLIMATE OF NEBRASKA By Gromok A. Lovelaxd KThe Hoys' and Girls' Club Work in Nebraska is conducted by the Uni - ity of Nebraska in cooperation with the United States Department of iculture. Bureau of Plant Industry, office of Farm Management. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C W. Ptusley, Superintendent Thermometer Shelter and Kain Gage. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Clubs 1 Nebraska EXTENSION BULLETINS Alfalfa Management. i. Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska. _&gt; 3. Testing Seed Corn. ■ Cooking and Sewing 1 Boys' and Girls' Clubs). Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle (Boys' and Girls 5- Part II.— Corn. I Part III. — The Home Garden. Spraying Apple Trees. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm The Selection and Care of Seed Corn Organization of Nebraska Bovs' and Organization of Nebraska Boys' and ( iirls' Clubs Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. Nebraska Boys" Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) ■ Agricultural Extension Short Courses. The Climate of Nebraska. The above bulletins will be sent free to residents of upon request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">iie vegetation of any part of the earth is controlled by the soil the climate. Plants can grow only when the sunshine, tempera - , rainfall, and wind, that is, the weather conditions, are favora- The climate of a place is its average weather. The average es of the elements that make up weather can be determined only leans of careful observations continued for many years. ihe climate of Nebraska is known because a large number of rec - ; have been kept, most of them by the intelligent, progressive ens of the state. The earliest preserved records commence in fifties. They were kept in part by the early settlers and in part he soldiers at the frontier army posts. Many citizens cooperate i the United States Weather Bureau at the present time, freely ng their work to continue the daily record of Nebraska's ther. General Climatic Conditions I he climate of Nebraska is determined by the geographical loca - of the state, near the center of a large continent with a high ntain range near its western border, conditions which cannot be ified by man. The important factors in determining its climate First, the distance from the equator, because the heat received i the sun is greater at the equator and decreases northward. &gt;nd, the altitude, or elevation above sea level, because the er localities have lower temperature. Third, the distance and ction from the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean, because supply of moisture for rain and snow comes mainly from these e bodies of water. Fourth, the Rocky Mountains, located near western boundary, because they have an important effect upon i temperature and moisture. I.'ebraska is in the general path of the low pressure, or storm, is (technically called cyclones) that move across the United tes from west to east. These are large eddies in the great river air that is flowing constantly around the earth from west to c between latitudes 35 and 80 degrees. They move with the cur - t of air and are similar to the eddies, or whirlpools, that float h the current in a river of water. However, these eddies or lones are drifting in an enormous river of air and are very je, frequently five hundred to two thousand miles in diameter ; letimes one cyclone covers more than half the United States. Ey violent and extensive commotion in the atmosphere is called rm and these cyclones are one kind of storm. The thunder - 1 and the tornado are also storms, much smaller in area, and more violent. In fact, they occur in, and are a part of, a By George A. Loveland </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 cyclone. All storms are characterized by a strong upward move - ment of the air, and the vapor of water, or moisture, is condensed by the cold of elevation. Storms are accompanied by clouds and usually by rain or snow, but often the storm (commotion of the air; extends beyond the area of rain or snow. These large storm areas move with an average speed of 600 miles in 24 hours, and are pre - ceded by southerly winds and higher temperature and fol - lowed by northerly winds with lower temperature. Each storm causes an average of one or two rainy days as it passes eastward, when the center of the storm is near enough to Nebraska. I here is an average of two of these storm areas passing across country each week with fair weather between, and if the center he storm passes over the state the change in weather conditions ither rapid. However, if the center is some distance north or h of the state, as frequently occurs, the change in weather condi - s is less rapid and less pronounced. I is rarely the case that the storms follow each other in exactly same path, and the regular change suggested by the average ement of storm areas does not occur at any one place. Besides, storms vary in energy and rapidity of movement. Especially lis true at the different seasons of the year. They move more dlv in winter than in summer and have greater energy. This is use the difference in temperature between the equator and the s is greater in winter, which causes more rapid eastward move - t of the river of air and more energetic eddies in it. In the fair weather period between these storms, especially in winter, large volumes of pure, invigorating, and relatively cold air flow across the state. The most severe of these are called cold waves. A cold wave is a sudden fall of temperature of at least 20 or more degrees in 24 hours, with zero or below as the lowest tem - perature in December, January, and February, and with 16 degrees or below as the lowest in the other months of the year. Sunshine 11 Nebraska the all important sunshine — without which vegeta - cannot develop — is practically always sufficient. Sometimes ng the hot months when the continued sunshine, day after day, hes a relatively dry soil it is injurious, because of the high tem - ture produced in both earth and air. Such injury occurs only n there is a lack of moisture in the soil, for when the soil is *t the sun evaporates a part of the moisture and heats the soil Kjrtionately less, because the heat is used up in changing the :r in the soil to vapor or steam. Thus, a part of the sun's heat no effect upon the temperature of moist soil. §the chart the upper line indicates the number of hours the sun ove the horizon in the different parts of the year, and the lower indicates the numbe- of these hours it is on the average free of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">i ! :: 11 10 : : ! ! : : i i o o lig. No. 1. — Hours of Sunshine in Nebraska. ids and so actually shining on the earth. The space between lines indicates the average number of hours the sun is obscured louds in the various parts of the year. Jt will be noticed that anuarv the sun is obscured nearly one-half of the nine hours it ■jove the horizon, while in July and August it is obscured but a ; more than one-quarter of the fifteen hours it is above the zon. The number of hours the sun is shining on the earth, tell as the directness of the ray, is important in the control of perature. Both tend to increase temperature in the summer both are caused b\ - the fact that the sun is farther north in the summer. Tk.m perature K'he temperature in most of Nebraska is not a limiting factor he growth of crops common to the temperate zone, but in parts the northern and northwestern sections the low temperature, ibined with other unfavorable climatic conditions, limit produc - ness. An accurate thermometer is needed to determine temperature. It is a waste of time and effort to keep a careful record from an in - accurate thermometer. A set of one maximum and one minimum thermometer trives the best temoerature data for from these instru- "■■sal Is 3 22«*^j§is:s:t:ti^&gt;o6 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Its the highest and lowest temperature can be obtained from one f reading and from these a good mean temperature can be ob - ed. The daily mean temperature is really the average of the rly temperatures, but the average of the highest and lowest will ' but little from the true mean and is frequently used. Very i results can be obtained from readings taken from an accurate mon thermometer at 7 a. m., 2 p. m., and 7 p. m. (or better 9 1.). The mean is then made by adding the 7 a. m., 2 p. m. ( and e the evening reading together, and dividing the sum by 4. The / minimum temperature usually occurs just before sunrise the maximum from 3 to 5 p. m. The highest and lowest tem - .tures can be approximated by noticing the thermometer at times mentioned. I he thermometer should be located in the shade, for if it is ed in the sun it gives the effect of the sun on the mercury in thermometer and not the temperature of the air. Mercury, iron, metals generally become very hot when in direct sunshine, much er than air, soil, vegetation, or animals. The standard test of result of the sunshine is the temperature of the air. Therefore thermometer should be protected from the direct rays of sun and from radiated heat from the earth or buildings. This best be done by placing it in a shelter or box made with louvre lattice work for sides, which allows the air to pass freely &gt;ugh, but with boards for top and bottom to protect from radi- Ee following chart shows the mean annual temperature, which is ned by averaging the mean monthly temperatures and that in is obtained by averaging the mean daily temperatures for the h. Fig. No. 2. Mean Annual Temperature. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The lines are drawn for each degree. The average temperature for the state for the year is 48.5 degrees. The highest mean tempera - ture, 52 degrees, occurs in the southeastern portion of the state at an elevation of 900 feet. The temperature decreases westward along the southern border to 50 degrees in Dundy county at an ele - vation of 3,000 feet ; however, the mean annual temperature is about 51 degrees in most of the southern tier of counties. It decreases northward about 1 degree for each 38 miles in most of the State, but is more rapid in the northwestern section and less rapid near the Missouri River in the northeastern section. Besides being farther north, the northern border is more elevated, ranging from 1 ,300 feet in the east to 3,700 feet in the west. The tempera - ture ranges from nearly 48 degrees in the northeast to less than 45 degrees in the northwest. January is the coldest month, with a mean temperature of 25 degrees in the southeast and 20 degrees or a little below in the north. February is almost as cold, averaging about 3 degrees warmer, while December is next, with an average of but 2 degrees higher than February. While the coldest weather of the year may occur in any of these three winter months it is most likely to occur in January, and it most frequently occurs in the last half of that month. In the coldest days of winter the temperature usually falls to between 10 and 20 degrees below zero, while on rare oc - casions 30 degrees below zero occurs. In the elevated portion of the northwestern part of the State as low as 47 degrees below zero has been recorded, while in a large portion of the northern and central counties the lowest temperature is about 40 degrees below zero. The temperature rises rapidly after February, approximately one - third of a degree a day until the latter part of June. This is fol - lowed by two and one-half months of hot weather, with a normal daily mean temperature from 70 to 78 degrees. The maximum temperature frequently exceeds 95 degrees and usually a few times each summer it exceeds 100 degrees. The hottest days in summer mostly occur in the last half of July, but the hottest spell of the year sometimes comes in August or September. The highest tempera - ture recorded is 114 degrees, and in several years, at a few places, temperatures ranging from 108 to 112 degrees have been recorded. These high temperatures seldom last more than a few hours in the middle of the day. Usually there is a fresh wind blowing and the air is quite dry, making the high temperature less oppressive than the figures would seem to indicate. From the middle of September the temperature decreases rapidly, approximately one-third of a degree a day, to December. Dew and Frost In the clear, relatively cold air of the fair weather periods be - tween the storms, objects on the earth lose their heat rapidly by </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 radiating it into space. Vegetation, for instance, becomes cooled below the dew point of the air near it and small drops of water are dc]&gt;&lt;&gt;sited. This is called dew. Ii spring and fall when the temperature of the vegetation falls w 32 degrees, the de]x&gt;sit instead of being water is crystals of This is called frost. The temperature of the vegetation may o or more degrees lower than is indicated by the thermometer ie shelter located about five feet alnjve the sod. Frosts usually re vegetation. Iight frosts, sufficiently severe to kill tender vegetation or only i\ of the less vigorous fruit blossoms, are likely to occur through- Ma} and sometimes early in June, especially in the northwestern ities. The average date, when the last freezing temperature or t sufficiently severe to kill staple crops occurs, is shown by the •wing map: MAY 10 I Jf •••Til y^ z »| — . \ _. J.T-JL M Hlllll 0 »• «O ■■ j Wltk^t H A L &gt;DltHWIt C-I«l GMatl llltl MOatilt f\ %-* j* (in ,*° Uu^ - ■ — -— , ■ 1TI HIT 1. APBIL _ Fig. No. ::. — Average dates of the last killing trust in ipring. Ihe latest that a killing frost has occurred in most of the -tate lay _7th. This was in k^jJ. when the freezing temperature COT- I most of the southern and eastern counties. In the northwot - part of the state such severe frosts have occurred in June, and 90a one occurred on June 21st. The last killing frost, it will be ;rved, happens as a rule in the southeastern section in the last days of April, but comes gradually later northward and wot - d, occurring near May 1st in the greater portion of the southern eastern sections and from May 10th to 15th in the more elevated ions in the north and west. tight frosts, not sufficiently severe to cause any practical damage egetation, have occurred in a few years in the very last days of ust, and in several years in the first half of September. Such </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Its. and in some yean more severe ones, are to be expected dur - the last half of September. The map shows the average date le fall when the first freezing temperature, or frost sufticientlv re to ",&lt;ill staple crops, occurs. Fig. No. 4. — Average date of the first killing frost in autumn iwill Ik.- noticed that severe frost hap]&gt;ens usually after October in a large area in the southeastern part of the State. It occurs ier in the northwest, where for a large area the date averages ieen the _'ist and 25th of September. The earliest date in the irds of the past fifty years for the southern and eastern sections September 12th. This was in i«a&gt;-. The average number of s without a killing frost ranges from i(» days in the southe:i-» 30 in the northwest. This is usually called the growing sea-, in. ough grass and some small grain extend the period of growth ■ral weeks at each end. Clouds The invisible vapor of water, which is always in the air, is con - verted into visible drop* of water by cording the air below dewpoint. This is the temperature at which the air is saturated or holds all the vapor it can hold. With a further cooling some is condensed, that is. changes form and appears as drops of water. The cooling of the air sufficiently to cause extensive condensation is caused by an upward movement such as takes place in storm areas. The condensation takes place usually from one to five miles above the earth, and the collection of drops or ice crystals is called clouds. The clouds are named from their appearance. The white. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Fig. No. 5. — Cirrus clouds. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 called cirrus. The heavy, thick, woolly-appearing clouds are called cumulus. These frequently develop into the cumulo-nimbus, or thunderheads, so often noticed in connection with thunderstorms in Nebraska. The lowest clouds, a simple veil frequently covering the whole sky, are called stratus. Clouds combining the characteristics of the primary kinds are given a name indicating the fact, like cirro - cumulus, etc. When the upward current of air is rapid large volumes of air are cooled below the temperature of the dew point, condensation is rapid, numerous small drops of water will be formed, and from these will develop the larger drops which fall as rain. When the temperature where the condensation takes place is below 32 degrees crystals of ice and flakes of snow will develop. Precipitation (including rain and snow) It is the amount and distribution of rainfall that will best repay study, for it is most likely to be the limiting factor in crop growth. A larger proportion of each rainfall is absorbed by a cultivated soil than was absorbed by the prairie soil of early days, and the same rainfall makes more water available in the soil for vegetation now than before cultivation was general. But from records covering more than sixty years the rainfall is fairly well determined for the state, and it seems to be established that there is no noticeable pro - gressive change. How to Measure Rainfall The rainfall is measured in a gage like the one shown in the cut. The top, cylindrical portion marked "A" is exactly eight inches in diameter and is provided with a funnel shaped bottom to conduct the precipitation to the measuring tube "C." The diameter of this tube is 2.53 inches, which makes the area of the cross section of the measuring tube just one-tenth that of the receiving funnel. There - fore, the depth of water in the measuring tube is ten times what it would be in the receiver. This magnifying of the depth allows more accurate measurements as .01 of an inch in the collecting funnel would measure 0.1 of an inch in the measuring tube. The overflow "B" is to collect water in a heavy rain after the measuring tube is full. The increased accuracy of measurement is the only reason for the smaller tube. Any receptacle with perfectly vertical sides and which is about 8 inches in diameter can be used as a rain The depth of water is measured by inserting the measuring stick into the gage through the funnel. When the stick reaches the bot - tom of the measuring tube it should be held for one or two seconds and then withdrawn and examined to see at what division of the graduation the top of the wet portion comes. It is best to use a </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 horizontal Section, EJ! 0 l2i436769t0tlltti 14 ti 16 17 /6 19 JO tl &lt;Y ?J S4 /mc*u SCAlt.. l ; ig. N« E lender and small in order to displace as little water as possible, vessel with vertical sides is used the reading on the stick will lie rainfall. {"he exposure of the rain gage is a very important matter. The it serious disturbing effect in collecting rainfall is the wind. A ition should be selected, therefore, which is unobstructed by ;e trees, buildings, or fences. Low bushes and fences or walls t break the force of the wind in the vicinity of the gage are, .•ever, beneficial if at a distance at least as great as the blight the object. Every precaution should be taken to protect the e from the interference of animals or unauthorized persons. : gage is best placed upon the ground with the top level. Distribution of Precipitation. The average annual precipitation for the state as a whole is 23.67 inches. Most of this is rain, the snowfall for the year averaging only about 25 inches, equal to nearly two and one-half inches of water, or about one-tenth the annual precipitation. 7. — Rain Gage </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 The year is divided into wet and dry seasons. May, June, and July constitute the wet season with 46 per cent of the annual amount, while November, December, January, and February are the four dry months with but 11 per cent of the normal amount. The other 43 per cent falls during the remaining five months or approximately one-twelfth of the annual amount for each month. As this indicates, very little rain or snow falls during the late fall and winter months, the average being less than an inch of water a month. A slight increase is manifested in March, but the spring rains begin in April, when from two to three inches is the normal for most parts of the state. Iine is the month of heaviest rainfall. It is also the period when fall is most certain, that is, least likely to vary from the average n ordinary June, rain falls at one place on eight or nine of the y days. This would mean a rain every third or fourth day. ; average condition rarely occurs ; still several consecutive days out rain in June are unusual. While the average monthly rainfall for May and July is nearh the same as that for June, there is a greater liability to variation from the average. Jn May this variation is less likely to be impor - tant, as the temperature is lower than in July and the rainfall is less likely to occur in heavy showers when a large percentage of the water would run into the streams without soaking into the ground Rain falls in May on the average aixmt the same number of days as in June, and drought periods are unlikely to occur. In July the sin &gt;\vers are slightly farther apart, and drought periods rather more frequent. The decrease in rainfall after July is rapid. The average for August is only three-fourths that of July, and for September only three-fourths that of August. In an average August rain falls at any one place on six or seven days. Heavy rains are much less likely to occur than in June or July, and drought periods are much more frequent. Eie rainfall for the crop season, April to August inclusive, for ;tate as a whole averages 16.18 inches. It exceeds 20 inches \ most of the Missouri valley and decreases rather regularly to le more than 10 inches along the Wyoming border. The accompanying map shows the average annual precipitation ( rain and melted snow ) for the various parts of Nebraska. the slightly more than 30 inches along the Missouri River de - ses to about one-half that amount, or 15 inches, along the Wyom - line. This is an average decrease of one inch for each thirty s as one travels westward across the state. In general this ratio s true for the various months; that is, the rainfall along the &gt;ming border is about one-half that along the Missouri River. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 The Climate of Xcbraska </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Climate of Nebraska 15 This diagram indicates the average annual precipitation for Ne - braska from 1850 to 1912. The averages for the first 25 years are computed from rather meager data, but much care has been exer- Z x it IC 186O( 1866 1860 1866 1870 1876 1880 1886 1890 1896 1900 1906 1910 1912 I L No. 9.— Averag .; .nn ial eci lit iti' m for fete as! from 1850 to 1912, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">II and they are considered fairly reliable. For the last $J years records were sufficient to allow a good reliable state mean to Ik - pitted. Comparing the yearly amounts with the normal as shown he heavy black line it will be noticed that a very large number of s do nut depart much from the normal; that there are as many s deficient as in excess; and that this chart does not show ;mv odicity in the wet or dry years. Wind The prevailing winds for the year are from the northwest, but they vary during the season. In winter and. in fact, the seven months, October to April, the direction from which the prevailing nriad comes is northwest. In May, June, and luly it is south and southeast, and in August and September it is south. tie average hourly wind movement is but slightly more than 9 i an hour. This also varies with the season, being most in 1, nearly 12 miles, and only one mile less in March and May. It 1st in the summer, being about X miles an hour in July, August. September. Wind velocities of 30 to 40 miles an hour are not and higher velocities are recorded every year. The highest ity usually occurs in a thunderstorm and lasts but a ihofi In these storms 50 to So miles an hour have been recorded. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>