<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Influence of Whole Wheat, Bran and Shorts on Body Weight and Feather Growth in Chicks</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION ¦:¦ RESEARCH BULLETIN 119 The Influence of Whole Wheat, Bran and Shorts on Body Weight and Feather Growth in Chicks F. E. Mussehl, C. W. Ackerson, and M. f. Blish LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY 1940 i </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">The Influence of Whole Wheat, Bran, and Shorts on Body Weight and Feather Growth in Chicks ¦¦: F.E. MUSSEHL, C. W. ACKERSON, and M. J. BUSH Wheat has long been recognized as one of the most valuable feedstuffs for all types of poultry. In the wheat-producing areas much wheat is fed as grain largely because of its availability on the farms and its high pal - atability. Most of the wheat produced in the United States is, however, grown primarily for the manufacture of flour, and large quantities of mill - ing by-products are available for animal feeding. Approximately 414 million tons of bran, shorts, and low-grade flour are available each year. The practical question asked by poultry raisers is, to what extent can these milling by-products be combined successfully in poultry rations? The answer to this question can, of course, be developed only from research work, and the results of certain experiments which should be helpful are presented in this publication. &#132;.\'w. COMPOSITION AND NUTRITIVE VALUES The wheat.kernel consists of three rather distinct parts, each of which has characteristic chemical and physical properties. The outer coats, or bran layers, comprise about 16 per cent of the weight of the kernel, the endosperm about 82 per cent, and the germ about 2 per cent. In modern milling practice, the wheat is first cleaned and moistened to toughen the bran. It then passes between pairs of steel rollers, the first pairs of which are corrugated to increase crushing efficiency. These rollers gradually break the kernels into smaller pieces, /fatten the bran layers, and separate them from the middlings. The flour is removed as made available from each grinding by means of bolting cloths. ; In the milling process about 72 per cent of the original wheat is con - verted into flour, about. 11 per cent is recovered as bran, 11 per cent as shorts, and 5 per cent as "red dog" flour. The bran and shorts are most commonly used in poultry rations, though low-grade flour is sometimes used in fattening formulas. ; Wheat and its products are valued for their protein, vitamins, ash, and energy-producing nutrients. Notwithstanding the common use of wheat and its products in poultry rations, relatively little research work has been done on their biological value in poultry rations. &#132; ; Protein Values Considerable research on the nutritive value of wheat proteins has been done with laboratory animals other than chicks. Osborne and Mendel (6) pioneered in this research with the conclusion that wheat proteins rank well toward the top of cereal products in biological value. Murphy and Jones (4) concluded that wheat-bran proteins are particularly high in the nutritionally essential ammo acids: arginine, lysine, tryptophane, tyrosine, and cystine. -They state that "When patent wheat flour was used as the </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 119 sole source of protein in a similar ration, rats grew during the first 15 to 16 weeks at a rate only one-half to two-thirds of that of the rats receiving bran. Normal reproduction was not, however, obtained on the bran ration." [ones and Gersdorff (2) studied the amino-acid distribution of the proteins of wheat bran and found them characterized by a high content of the basic amino acids. It is these amino acids which are often the limiting factor when rations made up of certain cereal products are used. Tully (10) compared red durum wheat with bran and middlings and combinations of these by-products, with the conclusion that ground durum wheat is a satisfactory poultry feedstuff. Equally good results were obtained in rations for mature birds when wheat bran and middlings were used to replace half ihe wheat. The latter substitutions did not, however, give good results in chick rations. Poley (7) studied the value of common pro - tein concentrates as supplements to wheat and wheat-milling products and concluded that the protein values of wheat and its milling by-pro - ducts differ significantly. Vitamin Values Wheat was early recognized as a good source of the antineuritic vitamin li, or thiamin. Daniel and Munsell (1) have evaluated all published research work on vitamin B, values which they express as follows in international units per 100 grams of material (values for shorts and middlings ate not given): Wheat 150 Bran 200 Germ 1200 Wheat is also known to carry a small amount of carotene, the precursor of vitamin A, and relatively larger amounts of vitamin G. Vitamin G values are expressed by Daniel and Munsell (1) as 80 units per 100 grams lor whole wheat and 300 units for wheat germ. Wheat germ is one of the richest sources of the vitamin E factor. In ordinary milling practice, most of the wheat germ goes into the shorts. Vitamin E requirements for normal growth of chicks have not yet been determined. Wheat-germ oil is available commercially, and is being pro - moted as a source of the vitamin E factor. Ash Constituents The ash content of the milling by-products is appreciably higher than that of wheat. Wheat and its products are especially high in phosphorus and the by-products contain appreciable amounts of manganese, an element which has received much attention recently because of its perosis-pre - venting quality. Sherwood and Couch (8) reported that the substitution of 20 per cent of gray shorts of wheat for a like amount of corn or kafir was effective in reducing perosis or slipped-tension disorder. Skinner and Peterson (9) report magnanese values in parts per million for representative wheat pro - ducts as follows: wheat. 54.5; bran, 140.4; standard middlings, 155.8. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Body and Feather Growth in Chicks EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS As a basal ration for our experiments we used feedstuffs which are commonly used with wheat products in poultry rations. Details of the rations are listed in Figures 1, 2, 3, and 4. The chemical composition of the wheat and milling by-products used in our experiments are given in Table 1. RATION I _ ™a'.• ¦ • ¦ ' 800 " YELLOW CORNMEAL IO '. GROUND OATS 10 GROUND BARLEY 10 MEAT SCRAPS ,87; FISH MEAL ' 4 ¦_¦ . . ' .. ' 700 "SOY BEAN OIL MEAL 4 —J : 1 J ; — :. ASH NO. Sll 2 / / I COO LIVER OIL 2 ;/ / / WHEAT PRODUCT ADJ. '¦-¦'' I / / to a.tyi, prot. so / / / ¦___; ' -r— ~ —r—- m ' —j- -f J— soo -—— —— ———— / I — -f- ; — '¦ 400— —: :— -j— I / -—— • '• .¦¦'..-' aoo — : — ~7~~y* ' — ~7 ~~ —; — / ~ : —'— &amp; \ &amp; Jr _/ ) Jsr *y ______— j? Jx etV 60 CHICK 5 PER LOl « '¦._?. Jy if/ CROSSES KLOW CU IVES 3 iSy V ' -\X REPRESENr MORTAtITIES , 00 JrL — £/—--y—- ; — ..''¦; Ficußii 1 ;....' Table I.—Chemical composition of wheat and milling by-products as used : in our experiments. Protein Fiber Fat N-Frcc. Ash Water ''¦ , 7- ..i-.7 ¦-..¦¦¦' extract % % :'¦- %¦ '¦':' '% : % % Wheat 12.3 ¦ 2.4 ' 2.1 70.3 2.0 10.9 Bran 15.2 9.4-4.8 53.9 6.0 10.7 Shorts 16.fi "-.. &lt;i.4 -¦¦¦: 4-(i 56.6 4.6 11.0 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">6 Aiißi&gt;:i'LTt°RAL Experiment Station Research Bulletin 119 I i RATION 600 _ YELLOW CORNMEAL IO GROUND OATS IO GROUND BARLEY IO ! MEAT SCRAPS 8 j FISH MEAL 4 / / / 500 -SOYBEAN OIL MEAL 4 _£_ J- J-i ASH NO. ill 2 / / J 1 COD LIVER OIL 2 / / / WHEAT PRODUCT ADJ / / / TO 12 69_ PROT ___S / / / 400 1 _ too— ./ yL J. 300 1 / j— / K / ¦ *y* M J?* 200 wvy+Jy\ _i .7 ye j/ S4 CHICKS PER LOT 5 ¦&gt;/ *&gt;A s _/ CROSSES BELOW CURVE! ° e}/\ Zy\ r_/| REPRESENT MORTALinE; too y Z/~ ZjZA ' j 1 4 _¦ I- OAY3 » Fi.a.KK 2 ! 1 1 i RATION i ! . YELLOW CORN iOjOV ___&#132;„_.- I _?/ •00 - PIXV OATS . o .ote LAVED h"^ ™_£__ :&gt;— / &gt;.Xi MEAT MEAL 8.0 / £/ * SOO FISH MEAL 4 0 ' ~/ — $/~*/± ' coo liver oil 20 jT/ »y _/ ' ASH NO. 311 20 4% __'•£/' WHEAT PRODUCTS __ / aVV A..V 400 ADJ TO 12 3*4PROT 500 s^t -£&amp;x —(Tft^ 1 1000 «r* *&gt;/ x v* i .fk-M—Af- 1 V* »y ' oTX ONE HUNDRED CHICKS 200 . w^A PER LOT CROSSES y -X ./ BELOW GROWTH CURVES _/ _/ _/ REPRESENT MORTALITIES Jjf oY ZZ 1 ] - iOO y ¦ • _/- - —t ~— r _ S / f - '4 OAYS-. O I I ol I I 1 1 1 Figure 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Bopv and Feather Growth in Chicks too i—— ¦———, ; __ ; RATION .'¦/ YELLOW CORN 10 &lt;&gt;) / 600 _ PULV OATS , 00 AUTOCLAVED / . / PULV BARLEY 10 0 * M~' _ . &#132;/ $/ • SOY BEAN MEAL 40/ T 'LB &amp;/ £/ MEAT MEAL 8 0 J ff/ ' «»/ ' _ FISH MEAL 40. j ~. SI */ . ¦'.. 3°° CODLIVEROIL 2.0 .-!"-—- ¦«, t- 2f— -t ASH NO 311 20 •"1.. , ,' /_"/ &lt;J| i WHEAT PRODUCT I*l ADJTOI26% 10/ §1 ¦100 -PROTEIN 50.0 -•' £¦ A/ -V- ii-- iooo sr/w/ : ,t/_ ii. I ¦ i ¦ */_v . iff*. ' " • */#/':*/* ' joo a __. J/*/ J/- — -.-:¦¦ _&gt;/x / */ I'i ' ZVes/ _V '-' 'I I £_/£"&gt;/ Sy FIFTY CHICKS -„ . ! __X**!X ' s_/••-.! PER LOTI £00 — . -^w: y£^ ,jW————— CROSSES:BELOW I' *_/; 'JrV. &lt;_/ CURVES REPRESENT »|_/ ¦¦''•!_/ o*srf I ¦ ¦' '.MORTALITIES. .. •P/ *V, v" ¦ 'ii ' : .:!.»'^*^j*:^:-# -. -----—,f— — -^ , - -,40»"-i ': ¦ ol '; •'•¦••¦-=¦ i ; -'¦ _l ; ,-¦"'.¦ FIKURE'. .-,.''.:'¦'.¦ i' - Chicks of the same age and general genetic background were used for parallel groups in each experiment. Electric brooders were used to provide suitable temperature conditions, and other environmental factors affecting growth were under good control. To assure selection of normal chicks of inherently good vigor, chicks were selected for the experiment when five or eight days old. ¦ . Lots 69, 70, and 71; consisted of White Rocks, which were eight days old at.the beginning of the experiment. Lots 114, 115, and 116 were'five- - dayold White Leghorns. Each chick was identified with a wing band, and sex determinations were made at the end of the experimental period. Rations were kept constantly before the chicks in clean feeders. Tap water was also provided. i The first .two series of experiments were planned to answer questions on the relative growth-promoting values of the proteins of whole wheat, bran, and shorts. All of the wheat products used were derived from the same sample of wheat. Adjustments were made with cornstarch so that all the rations in each series contained the same quantity of protein. The chicks grew satisfactorily, and there was no evidence of protein, vitamin, or mineral deficiencies. Feathering was very satisfactory, and several experienced observers rated the lots as entirely normal. ... I-. '¦'¦"'".¦¦-¦¦'.-.¦ ¦ '¦'. ¦ ..¦;..';:. ' /'.:.."•:j </seg>
         <seg id="p008">At.Riti lti ral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 119 Differences in the rate of growth of the chicks in the two series of ex - periments as summarized in Table 2 are due to breed and seasonal factors. Extremely warm weather during the last half of the second experiment (Lots 114. 115. and 116) affected the growth rate, but all lots in each experiment were subject to the same environmental factors. Table I.—Growth-rate data for duplicate Experiments I and 11 (Figs. 1 and _'). comparing bran, shorts, and ground wheat as sources of protein for groin ng chicks. Wei. ,t l.i,i Variable N". Dearie at 2X-&lt;lay Sri-day W clucks Man weight weight (,'• _.'• B - EXPERIMENT I i," Wlu.it hr.ir. Ml 2 M MR 717+11) "II Whr.il sh..ri&gt; Ml I t&lt;4 305 "01 ±10 Tl t,r„uri,l when Ml 2 (o 2R4 691± R EXPERIMENT 11 IN Whc.it Wan S-l 2 if. 258 534_8 Ifi Whc.tr %/itiri. H4 I) 56 25H siß_7 lid (rrnuntl wheal JH 3 57 255 5-)7±7 These duplicated experiments with relatively large numbers of chicks in each lot indicate no significant difference in the utilization of the pro - teins ol ground wheat, bran, and shorts when used to contribute 29 per cent oi the protein of the ration. Daniel and Munsell (1) reported differences in vitamin-B values of wheat and its by-products. In the following experiments we investigated some of these differences, using the same basal ration except that the yellow corn. oats, barley, and soybean meal were autoclaved for two hours at It pounds of pressure. This treatment quite completely destroys the antineurilic factor (B,) and may reduce or completely destroy other parts ol the B complex. To the autoclaved basal ration were added the wheat products as indicated in Figures i and 4. The floors of the brooding units were covered with hardware cloth tor this series of experiments to prevent coprophagy, previous experiments in our laboratory having indicated that this is a par - ticular problem when vitamin-B deficient rations are used. To insure :i sufficient supply of vitamins A and D, two per cent of U. S. P. cod-liver oil was included in the rations after the basal ration was autoclaved. Direct sunshine was also provided all lots in a sun porch attached to each brood - ing unit. Jn the third and fourth series of experiments very significant differences in the rate of feathering of the chicks in the three lots were observed. The ground-wheat lot (No. 146) was poorly feathered, the shorts lot (No. 148) was intermediate, and the bran lot (No. 147) significantly the best </seg>
         <seg id="p009">9 Body and Feather Growth in Chicks . ms-l i ____r^^j^: M__l _ :_^ Br '*4sßp§_^ '-' "^t—W jiß .'jjk'' &gt;—,^fl _________'"'v&gt;,i/kj v_%ntf a ___i _ _________¦&gt;.' * ufl ___r^____l IvtjM H ____i&gt;L * ')_¦ K^l _K_/&lt;n'l _________L___^__R__n? '__I^_l _____________¦__? _flß_.^^B____' _^L ' ___. H __L. _, . _________________________p.r '; / ' J_^^EH _________! IC.' __*______f_fl__ ______________________________________________________________________________________ li___^Si__ ¦ ¦BBJ_BBBBBB_B-88-B_B-_B^B-_^tii7if!3_-B •¦* .:^_3__i ___. H_ -i*S_H _¦ W __^_ B ¦"¦^¦¦'^l -Li-Viiffl B V B '''^____i li_B!WllpniP/_l ___L fl IV-_ ¦ El Kb E?fl __K_f____ ______ _______________¦__*___________ ___B^___F'*^fl_____? _r_l ' Ik. V,,_r7Mi. '~«___,i m-.. -WOrnF ¦ fl '__________________»&gt;-'4f ,_J_____.' ¦_¦_¦* __JJ_j_______¦ _________."-'*" "* __l ____' -" _¦_. r ""^B___^B__________Ufc__/BB __B_______H _BL- _____H_B___t ~ '^si^B^B_-_____fl _¦ L_____B__Br^7^____^^V!^H B*re___^- - l/l liL3 ___R*l_r_-____: _N_.___! fl ¦^¦¦R: IflHli «__¦_____._¦ Fie. s.—Lots 146, 147, 148, at eight weeks of age. Differences in feathering arc apparent. -.-''.. j ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p010">At.Rit i i.ti r\i. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 119 in both experiments. The differences were so striking that photographs were taken when the chicks were eight weeks old. Figure 5 shows Lots 14(i, 147, and 148 respectively. Lots 161, 162, and 163 showed similar differences. It is apparent that some factor essential to normal feather growth was destroyed when part of the basal ration was autoclaved. It is not probable that this factor was inorganic, since the original unautoclaved rations failed to express these differences in feather-growth quality. The significant factor was. therefore, apparently organic in nature. It is found in greater concentration in the bran layers than in other parts of the wheat kernel. Chicks receiving wheat shorts grew more rapidly, but feathering was not as normal as in the bran lots. Apparently that part of the wheat kernel which goes to make shorts has a higher concentration of growth-promoting factors, whereas the bran layers are richer in the feather-growth principle. Growth data for Experiments 111 and IV are given in Table 3. Tihli. &#132;—G rowth data for duplicate Experiments 111 and IV (Figs. 3 and 4), comparing ground wheat, bran, and shorts as sources of protein for growing ihukj. _—_____________=_==__==— T"; Si,, , Wci|!lu 2X-.lav 56-day Z. V'"M' chick. "'•"''* Jg n weight weight A'. «• S - EXPERIMENT 111 Hi, Cruun.l when Hill HI 55 234 *.'*"' I .: When Wan Kill - 5(1 268 520±2 |.s Wheal &gt;h..rts IHH I" 55 2Xj O+ttlJ EXPERIMENT IV W.I U„un hea, 5,1 4 51 204 «I±H 1,,: Wheat Wan Sll II 52 262 619± 4 1... Wheal shnris 511 4 52 2/6 699±16 CONCLUSIONS The proteins of the entire wheat kernel and of the bran and shorts are apparently utilized with equal efficiency by growing chicks when used with n hase of corn, barley, oats, meat scraps, fish meal, and soybean meal. The relatively higher protein levels of bran and shorts, as compared to ground wheat, should be considered by the poultry producer in deciding which product or products can be used with greatest economy. A good concentration of a feather-growth factor is found in wheat bran. Other common feedstufls carry the same essential, and the amount of bran which should be used in poultry rations will depend upon price relationships and certain well recognized payability factors. Our experi - ments indicate that as much as 40 per cent of bran can be used in chick rations with good results. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">;¦';.', Body and Feather Growth in Chicks LITERATURE CITED 1. Daniel, Esther P., anil Munsell, Hazel E. . 1937. Vitamin Content of Foods. U. S. IX A. Misc. Pub. 275. 2. Jones, D. Brccsc, ami GcTsclrir,. C. E. F. 1925. Proteins of Wheat Bran. J. Biol. Chcm. 64: 241-51. 3. Klein, A., Harrow, 8., Pitta, L., and Funk, C. 1926. The Nutritive Value ov Various Layers of the Wheat and Corn Kernel. Amcr. J. Phys. 76: 237-46. 4. Murphy, J. C. and Jones, D. Brccsc. 1 1926. The Nutritive Properties of the Proteins of Wheat Bran. J.Biol. | Chem. 69: R5-99. 5. Osborne, T. B. '¦¦'.'] 1909. The Proteins.of the Wheat Kernel. Publication No. 84, Carnegie Institution, Washington, D. C. 6.—— - and Mendel, L. B. 1919. The Nutritive Value of the Wheat Kernel and Its Milling Pro - ducts. ). B'mi. Chcni. 37: 557-601. .7. Poley, W. E. 1938. The Utilization oi Wheat and Wheat By-products in Feeding Young Chickens. Poultry Sci. 17: 399-404. 8; Sherwood, R. M., and Couch, J. R. 1936. Wheat Gray Shorts for the Prevention, of Slipped Tendons in Battery Brooder Chicks. Texas Ajir. Exp. Sta. Bui. 525. 9. Skinner, J. T., and Peterson, W. H. 1928. The Iron and Manganese Content of Feeding Stuffs. J. Biol. Chcm. 79: 679-87. 10. Tully, W. C. 1934. Wheat and Wheat By-products for Laying Hens. S. Dak. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 284. ¦ UV.M] </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>