<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0082.0001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT State Child Welfare Bureau of Nebraska 1935-1936</title>
               <date value="1936-12-01">1936-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1935-1936 VOLUME 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">•' TDK REW/ydiTjp'"" ) PUBLIC LIBJIAEY V 168518 ASTOH, LENOX AND 1939 t </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS V0LUME4 1. Child Welfare Bureau, Biennial Report, 1&amp;35-1936. 2. Board of Agriculture, Annual Reports, 1935, 1936. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">I ■ I ■ ■ STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ ■ ' ■ j ■■.■•'■■■... . . ,..'.■•.■■ ' ' .'■-.■'■ ' - .'.■■■ ■ ■ ■ "" ' ■'■.,:-■ | ' -' ■.■■'.-. - ■ _ • ■ * ~ ;' ' . - ■ ' ■ / . ', ■ ■ , ... '■■.';' I ■. ■ . ■ ■ ' ■ ■■..■". : : ' ■ ' . ■ ■ ■ • ■ . ■ ■■ . ■ -. . ■.'■■' ■■ " . ■ I BIENNIAL REPORT 1935-1936 </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">BIENNIAL REPORT State Child Welfare Bureau . of Nebraska 1935-1936 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">TABLE OF CONTENTS Pagie Th^ Children's Charter "... 7 Development of Child Welfare m Nebraska 11 1 The State Child Welfare Bureau 15 Functions Prior to Nebraska Assistance Act 15 . Functions Under Nebraska Assistance Act 15 Child Welfare Bureau Budget 23 Work Under the 1933 Act 27 1935 Child Welfare Act 31 Problems of Child Welfare 49 Special Activities 65 Information and Interpretation 67 The County Organization 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">"Political Society Exists for the Sa\e of J\[oble Living"* ■:.; .e . ■ ;'■■■ ■ ■■■: : ■; ; ■ ■"■ ; '■ ' ; , ''■■'.' : '■■'■:. ' '-..-"•■.■.' 'Inscription above south entrance to State Capitol Building </seg>
            <seg id="p010">LETTER OF SUBMITTAL December 1, 1936 To the Honorable Roy L Cochran Governor of the State of Nebraska Dear Governor Cochran: It is a pleasure to submit to you the biennial report of the State Child Welfare Bureau. The new duties delegated to the Bureau through State Assistance legislation have brought not only increased responsibility but also increased funds. This has enabled the Bureau to function more efficiently and more in conformity with the ideas of the forward-looking citizens who were instrumental in the creation of the State Child Welfare Bureau. This report may seem detailed, but it is my hope that it will better interpret the function of the Bureau in the scheme of Nebraska State government. Physically, mentally, and socially maladjusted children provide the future inmates of our State institutions. To cure social ills in the earliest stages is as fruitful of good results to the body politic as is preventive medicine. As Director of the Bureau, I have endeavored to conduct the duties of my office to the end that a preventive program may be established in line with the best practices prevailing in other states with wider experience in public welfare than Nebraska. I desire to express my appreciation for the loyalty and efficiency of my staff. If the administration of the Bureau has been acceptable, it is they who deserve the credit. The compilation of this report has been the responsibility of the Assistant Director. I am most grateful for your understanding of the problems presented by the work of the Bureau and for your personal counsel and assistance. Respectfully, Maud E. Nuquist, Director j STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU </seg>
            <seg id="p011">lite Cltiwiens Gnaltel I . . I. For every child spiritual and moral training to help him to stand firm under the pressure of life. II. For every child understanding and the guarding of his personality as his most precious right. III. For every child a home and that love and security which a home provides and for that child who must receive foster care, the nearest substitute for his own home. IV. For every child full preparation for his birth, his mother receiving prenatal, natal, and postnatal care; and the establishment of such protec tive measures as will ma\e child-bearing safer. V. For every child health protection from birth through adolescence, including: Periodical health examinations and, where needed, care of specialists and hospital treatment; regular dental examination and care of the teeth; protective and preventive measures against communicable diseases; the insuring of pure food, pure tnil^, and pure water. VI. For every child from birth through adolescence, promotion of health, including health instruction and a health program, wholesome physical and mental recreation, with teachers and leaders adequately trained. VII. For every child a dwelling place safe, sanitary, and wholesome, with reasonable provisions for privacy, free from conditions which tend to thwart his development; and a home environment harmonious and enriching. VIII. For every child a school which is safe from hazards, sanitary, properly equipped, lighted, and ventilated. For younger children nursery schools and \indergartens to supplement home care. IX. For every child a community which recognizes and plans for his needs, protects him against physical dangers, moral hazards, and disease; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">provides him with safe and wholesome places for play and recreation; and ma\es provision for his cultural and social needs. X. For every child an education which, through the discovery and development of his individual abilities, prepares him for life; and through training and vocational guidance prepares him for a living which will yield him the maximum of satisfaction. XI. For every child such teaching and training as will prepare him for successful parenthood, homema\ing, and the rights of citizenship; and, for parents, supplementary training to fit them to deal wisely with the problems of parenthood. XII. For every child education for safety and protection against acci' dents to which modern conditions subject him — those to which he is directly exposed and those which, through loss or maiming of his parents, affect him indirectly. XIII. For every child who is blind, deaf, crippled, or otherwise physu colly handicapped, and for the child who is mentally handicapped, such measures as will early discover and diagnose his handicap, provide care and treatment, and so train him that he may become an asset to society rather than a liability. Expenses of these services should be borne pub' licly where they cannot be privately met. XIV. For every child who is in conflict with society the right to be dealt with intelligently as society's charge, not society's outcast; with the home, the school, the church, the court and the institution when needed, shaped to return him whenever possible to the normal stream of life. XV. For every child the right to grow up in a family with an adequate standard of living and the security of a stable income as the surest safe' guard against social handicaps. XVI. For every child the protection against lavot that stunts growth, either physical or mental, that limits education, that deprives children of the right of comradeship, of play, and of joy. XVII. For every rural child as satisfactory schooling and health services as for the city child, and an extension to rural families of social, recrea - tional, and cultural facilities. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">XVIII. To supplement the home- and the school in the training of youth, and to return to them those interests of which modern life tends to cheat children, every stimulation and encouragement should he given to the extension and development of the voluntary youth organizations. XIX. To ma\e everywhere available these minimum protections of the health and welfare of children, there should be a district, county, or community organization for health, education, and welfare, with full' time officials, coordinating with a state- wide program which will be responsive to a nation-wide service of general information, statistics, and scientific research. This should include: (a) Trained, full-time, public health ojjicials, with public health nurses, sanitary inspection, and laboratory wor\ers. (b) Available hospital beds. (c) Full-time public welfare service for the relief, aid, and guidance of children in special need due to poverty, misfortune, or be - havior difficulties, and for the protection of children from abuse, neglect, exploitation, or moral hazard. For every child these rights, regardless of race, or color, or situation, wherever he may live under the protection of the American flag. •Adopted by the 1930 White House Conference for Child Health and Protection. </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">I. Development of Child Welfare in Nebraska 1 Revietv of Welfare Services 1885-1936 From the earliest beginnings of civilization welfare, the condition of well-being, has been the aim of society. The goal of those who make and those who administer the law has been the well-being of the people, and the term "public welfare" has been adopted to mean the work of political divisions in the field of welfare. Specifically, this embraces work with certain classes of unfortunate, handicapped, and unadjusted per - sons; the economically dependent, the convicted criminal, the mentally diseased, the mentally deficient, and the dependent, neglected, and delin - quent. As child welfare signifies those services which promote the well - being of children, this report is concerned with that particular approach to the problem of public welfare. STATE RELIEF FUNDS APPROPRIATED FIRST TIME IN 1935 From the earliest territorial period in Nebraska county govern - ments have been responsible for public welfare services, through a county tax for poor relief and for such local institutions as jails and poor-houses. Except for the Mothers' Pension Act, passed in 1919 authorizing the several counties to make a levy for this purpose, methods of aiding dependent children remained unchanged in Nebraska from 1855 to 1933. In 1933 federal funds were made available for relief to the State Emergency Relief Committee. Then in 1935 the Nebraska Assistance Act was passed at the Special Session of the Legislature making state funds available for the purpose of matching federal funds for dependent children and for corrective care for crippled children as well as for relief. Also, the Nebraska Assistance Act clearly placed responsibility with the local officials for service to special classes of children's cases and enlarged the work of the State Child Welfare Bureau in this field. DEVELOPMENT OF INSTITUTIONAL PROGRAM FOR CARE OF CHILDREN The first institution for children was established in 1869, the Insti - tute for the Deaf. In 1875 the Institute for the Blind was established. These institutions constitute the major service available to these classes of handicapped children at the present time. Other services for deaf arid blind children are those available through the "opportunity" or "special class" rooms of the public school systems in a few cities in the state and the provisions for education and maintenance of deaf-blind children and their mother-teachers made by the Special Session of the ' iSee: Williams, Dr. Hattie Plum, "History of Public Welfare In Nebraska," unpublished manuscript. — 11 — </seg>
            <seg id="p018">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU Legislature in 1935. The Boys' Industrial School opened in 1879 and the Girls' Industrial School in 1887 — the only agencies for state care of delinquent children to this date. (The State Child Welfare Bureau, however, can and does advise with local officials on the care of such children.) Homeless children were cared for first in the Home for the Friendless organized" in 1881. An institution for the mentally handi - capped child was provided in 1885, the Institution for the Feeble-minded. The next child-caring institution was the Orthopedic Hospital estab - lished 20 years later in 1905. Six years after the Orthopedic Hospital was opened, the Hospital for the Tuberculous was founded in 1911. This was the last State institutional care made available to children in Nebraska. Nebraska has had state institutional resources for healtK - handicapped persons for 25 years, for mentally handicapped for 51 years, for homeless children for 55 years, for delinquents for 57 years, and for education for deaf and blind for 61 years. It is interesting to observe the approach to the problem of welfare through institutional care. First, the education of handicapped children was given state consideration, then custodial care, and latest medical care. Medical care followed the educational institutions by 26 years. Services for individual cases are only now developing and not yet accepted by most of the institutions. PARDON AND PAROLE In 1901 the State Board of Charities and Correction was created. This Board was the first State supervisory and administrative welfare agency that was given power broader than the management of institu - tions. It was largely supervisory, performing few administrative functions. By law this Board was given duties which included fact - finding and interpretation relative to the improving of health standards, methods of education, punishment, and reformation of inmates. Ad - ministrative duties consisting of duties in connection with pardon and parole were assumed by the chief clerk. Prior to this assignment of the duty of fact-finding with reference to reformation of inmates, custodial care for delinquents was the only consideration given to this class of offenders. In 1911 the State Prison Board was created by legislative act; The same board was made the advisory Board of Pardons to assist the Governor. At the present time parole is handled by the Board of Pardons. The only children undbr this Board, however, are girls sent to the Re - formatory for Women for treatment of venereal disease, boys at the Industrial School, and boys at the Reformatory for Men. The Chief State Probation Officer^ as he is known, is responsible for securing for the 2 According to the National Probation Association, "probation" is used here incorrectly. Probation is social case work for individuals brought before a court and who have not served a sentence. Probation refers to the process of modifying behavior through individual and social adjustments and the development of character. The term "parole" should be used in this instance rather than "probation." "Parole" may </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DEVELOPMENT OF CHILD WELFARE IN NEBRASKA Board of Pardons information on individuals who are to appear before the Board. At the present time this work is done by only one person, the Chief Probation Officer. CHILD LABOR AND JUVENILE COURTS In 1875 the compulsory education law was passed; among its pro - visions was the regulation of child labor. This was followed by an improved child labor law in 1907. In 1905 the first Juvenile Court act was passed. DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE— 1919-1933 Under the Civil Administrative Code a Department of Public Welfare was established. In this department was the Bureau of Child Welfare with a division of child hygiene. In the 14 years of its legal existence the Department of Public Welfare actually functioned actively in all Bureaus for only four years, from 1925 to 1929. The Department of Public Welfare was abolished with the Administrative Code in 1933. This department was not permitted to function actively as a public welfare department long enough to establish itself and demonstrate its worth. Coincident with the establishment of a Department of Public Welfare there was created the Children's Code Commission. This Com - mittee was appointed by the Governor in 1919 and was not the .State Child Welfare Bureau, but was a research committee with no administrative functions, and was dissolved when its report was completed in 1920." STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU ESTABLISHED 1919 The State Child Welfare Bureau had a stormy career from its be - ginning in 1919 to the revision of the law in 1933. Its location in State government and its functions were misunderstood, and it suffered from economy regimes and particularly from the struggle over revision of the Civil Administrative Code which lasted more than a decade. Repeated attempts to transfer it from the Department of Public Welfare to the Department of Public Instruction failed, as did also the effort to abolish it and to deprive it of its functions and staff. When the Code revision bill of 1933 threatened to abolish the Department of Public Welfare, a new Child Welfare Bureau bill was introduced. The Governor's Code bill passed with the emergency clause on April 1, 1933. The Child Welfare Bureau bill passed on May 13, and went into effect in August, 1933. 4 This act placed the Bureau directly under the Governor, who is empowered to ap - be defined as a method by which prisoners who have served a portion of their sentences are released from penal institutions under the continued custody of the state, and upon considerations which permit their reincar - ceration in the event of misbehavior. These two terms are often confused although their meaning is very different. 3 See : "Report of Nebraska Children's Code Commission, 1920." 4 See: Section II, page 15, "Functions Prior to Nebraska Assistance Act" for explanation of this program. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU point the Director to serve during his term of office. In 1935, at the Special Session of the Legislature, the children's work under the Nebraska Assist - ance Act was placed under the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau » These added activities include Aid to Dependent Children, Crippled Children, and Child Welfare Services. Another chapter or two, no doubt will be written before the Bureau is definitely established as a cooperating Bureau in a State Welfare program with trained and experienced per - sonnel. The trend, however, has been steadily in this direction and with the passage of the Nebraska Assistance Act makes a well-coordinated public welfare service, with limitations, a mandate of the legislature. This will be realized more nearly as progress is made in strengthening the administration through better laws, the result of Nebraska's experi - ence in welfare administration. =See: Special Session Laws, 1935, H. R. 19, Section V this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">II. The State Child Welfare Bureau Functions and Administration The State Child Welfare Bureau functions directly under two laws and is directly responsible for the administration of two others. 1 Under these laws the Bureau has the necessary authority to develop an adequate public welfare program for child welfare. During the present biennium much has been accomplished in meeting the needs for child welfare. Previously, budget restrictions, policy, and administrative limitations have made a full program impossible of administration. FUNCTIONS PRIOR TO NEBRASKA ASSISTANCE ACT Under the 1933 law the Bureau is given the following powers and duties: Section 81-5715: "First, to promote the enforcement of all laws for the protection and welfare of defective, illegitimate, dependent, neglected, and delinquent children except laws whose administra - tion is expressly vested in some other state department or any division hereof, and to take the initiative in all matters involving such children where adequate provision therefor has not already been made. Second, to administer and enforce all laws originally under the jurisdiction of the State Board of Charities and Correc - tion including Sections 71-2501 to 71-2701, inclusive, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, and any such laws as may hereafter be passed and assigned for administration to the Bureau. . . . ." In the administration and enforcement of all laws originally under the State Board of Charities and Corrections the Bureau is -given the responsibility for licensing and inspecting maternity homes and lying-in hospitals, maternity boarding homes in which children under two are kept, and "the department of public welfare shall inquire into the whole system of public charities and methods of and the practice in the public and correctional institutions of the state, counties, and cities to ascertain the condition thereof from time to time by inspection " (quoted from Section 71-2701, Compiled Statutes, 1929.) These last named wel - fare duties were given to the Bureau on the abolishment of the Depart - ment of Public Welfare. FUNCTIONS UNDER NEBRASKA ASSISTANCE ACT In addition, under the Nebraska Assistance Act, the Director of the Bureau is made responsible for cooperating "with the State institutions for delinquent, defective, and physically handicapped children to ascer - tain the conditions of the home and the character and habits of the parents of a child before his discharge from a State institution, and to iSee C. S.Supp., 1933, 81-5714 to 81-5717, inc.; C. S. 1929, 71-2501 and 71-2701 ; and Special Session Laws, 1935, H. R. 19. 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU i si a 1 £i— P P II SS Is I I -I I - w Bf I ll I S ..51 — SS it i_j i 1 ] rl I * i j 11 m m n I! : 1 HUE ■°|i ~ i j_ I i fii si I l h* ** i 211 . • | I 1. |-S Io | : be"' OPQffi </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU make recommendations as to the advisability of returning said child to his home. '[ (Sec. 8, H. R. 19, Special Session Laws, 1935.) The Director of the Bureau is responsible also for the supervision of the local adminis - tration of Aid to Dependent Children and the administration of Child Welfare and Crippled Children Services. TRAINED AND EXPERIENCED PERSONNEL NECESSARY From this can easily be seen the wide scope and important part the Bureau has in administering the welfare activities of the State. The lives of a great many children and adults in the course of a year are dependent on the proper administration of these laws. Handling the social problems of human beings is a serious matter for the State and must be done with the same care that the Supreme Court gives in hearing the pleas of a condemned man. The future of the well-being of an indi - vidual often hangs in the balance and is guided by the action of a social worker from the" Bureau. For this reason each staff member has been selected on the basis of training and experience for child welfare work in the same manner that a hospital chooses its staff of physicians; in both instances the lives and future happiness of people are concerned. Aside from the humanitarian standpoint, it is good business for the State to give the best of case work service to the individuals needing it, because one mistake may cost the state many thousands of dollars. 2 To supervise and administer nearly three-quarters of a million dollars a year, make plans for the lives of several thousands of children and adults, and to carry out properly the mandate that the Bureau "in - 2From the Child Welfare Bureau case files: "Mr. and Mrs. G were divorced and the five children placed in the custody of their mother. Mr. G had since become insane, and Mrs. G had become a problem to the community by reason of her asocial behavior. She frequently left home for two or three days at a time during which the children, aged five to thirteen, stayed alone. The police found men in her home. She was caught shoplifting. Finally, she was arrested for forging grocery orders and was sentenced to the Women's Reformatory without investigation of the case by a properly trained case worker. The County Assistance director wisely placed a WPA housekeeper in the home. The cost in this plan was the WPA wages and direct relief of groceries and clothing. The District Judge, however, believed that Mrs. G would never give the children a wholesome life and committed the five children to the State Home for Dependent Children. The per capita cost to the State for children at the Home is $42.89 per month, a total cost for this family of $214.45 per month or $2,593.40 a year. While the children were with their mother, Aid to Dependent Children of $49.00 per month was supplying the needs of the entire family. If these five children had been placed with relatives instead of being committed, Aid to Dependent Children could have been granted to those relatives who could not take the children without assistance. The Child Welfare Bureau case-worker talked with the relatives. Some of the relatives are of no better caliber than the mother and, therefore, could not be approved. Two, however, were en - tirely satisfactory. Had the Judge used a case-worker and the children been placed with relatives, the State would have been saved over $2,000 per year as long as these youngsters are wards of the State, as well as giving them a normal, happy home life." </seg>
            <seg id="p024">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU spect, license, promote, and enforce"— children's agencies, institutions, programs, and laws— requires a sizable staff as well as an able one Fortunately the State legislature has recognized this need, and through the regular State appropriation, the Nebraska Assistance Act, with the augmentation of federal funds, more nearly adequate funds are available to meet these administrative needs. Under the 1933 law, C. S. Supp 1933, 81-5716, "the Bureau shall be under the immediate management and control of a director who shall be appointed by the Governor to serve during his term of office. He or she shall appoint such assistants, agents, and clerks and shall be allowed such traveling and other expenses as are necessary to carry out the duties imposed upon the Bureau." This law places the Bureau directly under the Governor; however, in making the biennial appropriations the 1933 and 1935 legislatures included the biennial budget appropriation for the Bureau in the Health Department. This was for budgetary purposes only; there is no legally authorized administrative control or supervision of the Child Welfare Bureau through the Health Department. FUNCTIONS AND ADMINISTRATION DELEGATED UNDER ASSISTANCE ACT When the legislature enacted the Nebraska Assistance Act measures concerning Aid to Dependent Children, Child Welfare, and Crippled Children Services, these functions were placed under the Director of the Bureau. The law is as follows: Special Session Laws, 1935, H. R. 3, Sec. 7, established the "sole agency" as required by the Federal Social Security Law for the administration of these services in the several states, and under which the Director of the Bureau functions: Sec. 7: "The State Assistance Committee shall be the sole agency of the State of Nebraska to supervise the administration of relief, blind assistance, old age assistance, aid to dependent children, crippled children, and child welfare activities in the State of Nebraska." DELEGATION OF ADMINISTRATIVE CONTROL: H. R. 19 * i$ ec^, : i " The State Assistance Committee through the Director ii j. j h i ld Welfare Bureau shall expend state assistance funds allocated for child welfare services in establishing, extending, and strengthening, especially in rural areas, child welfare services mentioned in this Act, for which other funds are not specifically or sufficiently made available by this Act or other laws of this state." * j.£ eC Ai??i : .i " The State Assistance Committee through the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau shall expend state assistance funds allocated for crippled children, to supplement other state, county, and municipal, benevolent, fraternal and charitable expenditures to extend and improve (especially in rural areas and in areas suffering from severe economic distress) services for locating physically handicapped and crippled children, and for providing medical, surgical, correction and other services and care, and facili - ties for diagnosis, hospitalization, and after care, for children who are physically handicapped or crippled, or who are suffering from conditions which lead to crippling. . . . ." </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU h« f eC&gt; if 1 * " The °"? !tor o£ Child Welf are B «reau and the county boards shall extend the assistance and services herein provided +w +u chlld i en ln ™ r&amp;l districts throughout the state, in order that the same benefits and facilities shall be available to children in such districts as in urban areas." ' «,«.fc ? ™L 2 Jll l' T^ D i r 4 ec * or ; ot . the ChM Welfare Bureau shall make such reports to the State Assistance Committee arid to the Secre - tary of Labor of the United States in such form and containing such information as the Secretary of Labor may from time to time require, and comply with such provisions as he may from time to time find necessary, to assure the correctness of such reports." COOPERATION AND COORDINATION: H. R. 19 nf Jw&amp;fi w h i5 Sta £ Assistance Committee through the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau and the Director of Health shall co - operate with the Children's Bureau of the Department of Labor a I United States, to develop plans for child welfare services and shall make such reports as may be requested to said children's bureau in regard to such services in this state." Sec. 3: "The State Assistance Committee and the Director of Assistance through the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau shall cooperate and coordinate their child and maternal welfare activities with those of the .Board of Control, state institutions, Vocational Rehabilitation Division of the State Department of Vocational Education, Department of Health, Bureau of Child Wel - fare, courts, county boards, charities, and all other organizations, andhealth " aeencies ' state and national . to promote child welfare Sec. 24: "The Director of the Child Welfare Bureau shall co - operate with medical health, nursing, and welfare groups and organizations and with any agency in the state charged with pro - viding for local rehabilitation of physically handicapped children." This means that the Bureau operates under two. laws and two ad - ministrative authorities, the State Assistance Committee for Aid to Dependent Children, Child Welfare, and Crippled Children Services, and the Governor for functions provided, C. S. Supp., 1933, Sec. 81-5715 (See above.) It is interesting to note that essentially the same plan adopted by the Nebraska legislature was adopted by Congress— that of placing activities for children in the Children's Bureau. ADMINISTRATIVE SET-UP3 All of the work in the Bureau is under the Director. Because of the great amount of detailed work, and the occasional absences from the office of the Director necessitated by many requests for talks, leading of discussion groups, and work out in the State, an Assistant Director has been appointed. The work of the Bureau is assigned to four divisions, which divisions are discussed separately, as follows: CHILD WELFARE BUREAU DUTIES As has been pointed out, there are certain State responsibilities for child welfare the expense of which must be carried by the State under o * * 8S f e - C ? art ' "Organization State Child Welfare Bureau Including State Assistance Activities," page 16. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU the biennial appropriation. Federal Funds for Child Welfare Services cannot be used for these activities. Part of the appropriation from the State Assistance Fund is used, however, for these services, because the regular state appropriation was not sufficient to develop a satisfactory child welfare program. The Director of the Bureau, assistant director, and supervisor of the maternity and placement division are the only staff members paid from this fund. Considering the responsibilities of the State in supervising institutions and agencies, developing and adopting child welfare standards, developing juvenile probation practices, super - vising maternity homes and maternity boarding homes, protection of the child born out of wedlock, and the large amount of time necessary in supervising the activities of the Bureau, a larger amount of money than is at present available is needed for salaries and expenses in connection with the State work. Although these services are closely integrated with the Federal Social Security program for Child Welfare Services, it is necessary that these functions which are strictly State responsibility be fully carried from State funds. An increase of $5,000, or a total of $20,000, has been requested for the next biennium. CHILD WELFARE SERVICES* "To extend and improve (especially in rural areas and in areas suffer - ing from severe economic distress) services for child welfare," is the direction given in State and Federal laws. To this end five districts were established in the State, a district child welfare consultant assigned to each district. Supervising this program and supervising the district consultants is a person known as the Supervisor of Child Welfare Services. Early in the coming year a training unit under the joint direc - tion of the Director of the University of Nebraska's Training Course for Social Work and the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau will be estab - lished. The district child welfare consultants are paid one month out of twelve by State funds and are doing in their respective districts all of the work of the Bureau excepting Crippled Children Services and Aid to Dependent Children. These district case workers do the social service work for Crippled Children and Dependent Children cases referred for case work but are not responsible for the administration of these two programs. With added State funds these districts can be made smaller; they are much too large at the present time. District III has not had the services of a case worker during most of the year as a properly qualified person with Nebraska residence could not be located, a situation which exists as this report goes to press." 4 See Map, "Child Welfare Districts and Demonstration Areas," page 221* &lt;j According to "Objectives and Organization of Child Welfare bervtees, Report of Advisory Committee, U. S. Children's Bureau, 6236, a properly qualified person is one who, in addition to personal qualities of tact, industry, understanding, and liking for people, has had specific training and experience in social welfare work as applied to individuals in need of assistance or service including experience in an agency giving </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHILD WELFARE DISTRICTS AND DEMONSTRATION UNITS October, 1936 I" 0 "* MIKS situ/out m^ m '^^ mmm^^ mmmm V!a!Smr^'^^orD |***W* ARTHUR M*PH£ft3QN L06AN CUSTtR VAUcy GttUUY PiATT£ CttMX tfOPtf* fi5J5T^ OUNOt HITCHCOCK RIMMUm MUM* MAKIAM r/TANKUM WtKTt* MKKOIU BMW* imUSOH MWHU |«OM#«3^ Key: Shaded counties indicate demonstration units. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU CRIPPLED CHILDREN SERVICES This program has necessarily moved slowly. Finding properly qualified personnel, coordinating these services with the private agency programs, establishing plans for cooperation with physicians, and de - ciding policies and administrative procedure have all required much time. The administrative organization consists of a supervisor directly responsible for the division's work and, when plans are fully carried out, a staff of three field assistants. Each assistant is assigned a dis - trict and aids local officials and interested persons in making arrange - ments for crippled children to be examined and treated. Responsibility for locating crippled children and providing follow-up service lies with these assistants. One person is assigned to the Lincoln and Omaha areas and is responsible for much of the detail work in arranging hospitaliza - tion, contact with the orthopedists, writing the parents, arranging for convalescent care, and acting as the liaison person between the district workers who visit the homes and do the social case work and the physi - cians. 0 The physician makes the medical plan with consideration of the social report made by the district worker. AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN The Child Welfare District Consultants carried the responsibility for administration and supervision for the Aid to Dependent Children pro - gram until August, 1936. The pressure of work in the field of Child Welfare Services and the need for coordinating the Aid to Dependent Children program- with other forms of assistance necessitated the reliev - ing of the consultants of this responsibility, or making the districts smaller and enlarging the staff. By administrative agreement the super - vision of the county administration of Aid to Dependent Children was placed with the State case supervisor, who is also responsible for old age assistance, blind assistance, and relief under the Director of Assist - ance. A coordinated accounting division and staff were established under the same agreement. The field people under the case supervisor work with the county officials administering Aid to Dependent Children funds, referring problems of child welfare to the district child welfare con - sultants. The field supervisors are also responsible for old age assistance, blind assistance, and relief. Responsibility delegated by statute to the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau for general supervision of this program remains un - changed Under this agreement. It was agreed also that Child Welfare and Crippled Children's Services are both exclusive provinces of the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau. case work service to children. Positions for organizing and supervising Child Welfare Services require skill in promoting the development of social resources of the community and utilizing them in the most effective way. "Social case work means the process of understanding the factors other than physical that affect the crippled child and contribute to his maladjustment, and the making of plans for the amelioration of these factors. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">III. Child Welfare Bureau Budget Appropriations and Expenditures The appropriations to the Bureau are for three general purposes assistance, service, and administration. Practically all of the money for Child Welfare Services is for administration in that it is used for salaries and operating expenses. Where formerly the total amount of the Bureau s budget was $7,500 per annum, it is now $16,826.80 (the amount of $9,326.86 is from the State Assistance Fund). The Crippled Children's appropriation carries a small administrative load. MUCH NEEDED SERVICE DEVELOPED The quality of service has improved greatly. Services by necessity neglected previously are now being extended. Before the present en - larged program to meet this need was made possible a year ago, the staff of the Bureau consisted of the Director, office secretary, and two field workers. The salary for the field workers was not enough to attract persons with specialized training or experience in child welfare work Funds for travel were inadequate; only one worker could be in the field at a time. In the early months of the biennium not more than one-tenth of the cases referred could be handled in even a supervisory way. Seldom was it possible to give adequate service to county judges on cases prior to commitments. At the present time it is possible to visit every county on the average of once each six weeks— some oftener and others without immediate problems not quite so often. Before additional funds were available, the Bureau averaged hardly one visit in a year's time. It is hard to realize the many thousands of dollars the State has spent needlessly because qualified people were not available for case work with children's cases. In one month alone the past year, by actual record count, the child welfare consultants made plans in a sufficient number of cases to save the State more than an entire year's appropria - tion for the Bureau in actual money, to say nothing of the saving in human values. Multiplying this saving by twelve months, it is hard to realize that a comparatively small department can effect such a saving to the State. This means a definite. decrease in the number of children referred to the institutions. This is extremely significant, for in 1930 Nebraska was one of the states in the United States with the highest number of children in institutions per capita. A small amount of the child welfare fund is used for boarding care and psychological and psychiatric fees as well as for printing, telephone and telegraph, and other expenses. FEDERAL FUNDS AVAILABLE FOR CHILD WELFARE A total of $26,337.97 is available annually from the U. S. Children's Bureau for strengthening the extension of child welfare services in 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU rural areas and areas of severe economic distress. This money cannot be used for carrying out necessary State functions described in the 1933 law. It is being used to give the communities in the State intensive service and to help County Assistance Directors with their difficult children's cases, to lend case workers to counties -with special problems, and to develop training programs in order that Nebraskans desiring to receive social work training in preparation for public service can receive their training in practice. It has not been possible to spend our full allotment, because people with training and experience who could do this work and who were Nebraska residents could not be obtained. This money is not lost to the State but may be spent in a later quarterly period when a plan worked out jointly with the U. S. Children's Bureau can be developed and qualified personnel is employed. MATERNITY HOME LICENSE FUND The Bureau is given the $3.00 license fee from Maternity Home Licensing; there are 141 Homes, bringing in a little over $400 a year. This money is used largely for the salary and travel of the supervisor of the Maternity Home division. The cost for supervising and licensing these Homes is greater than the revenue; however, it is one of the very important functions of the Bureau. Nearly 250 unmarried mother cases are reported annually to the Bureau through the licensed Maternity Homes. CRIPPLED CHILDREN FUNDS From Federal Social Security funds $46,163.92 is available annually for Crippled Children services, provided the amount can be matched by the State. The Bureau has $31,584.65 available from the State Assistance Fund. In order that the full federal allotment can be matched, the Board of Control has made $15,290.15 of the Orthopedic Hospital appro - priations available for federal matching. This makes a total of $92,327.84 a year for administration, diagnosis, hospital, medical and social services, and after-care. The administration of this fund is necessarily higher than that for other forms of assistance because of the great amount of service and care to be given each case. Funds not used for administra - tion are spent on treatment and care for crippled children whose parents are unable to provide such care. AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN The Special Session of the Legislature, 1936, appropriated a total of $456,244.10 per year for Aid to Dependent Children, to be spent by the County Assistance Committees. Three per cent of this amount is to be used by the counties for administration. The amount allotted to the counties depends on the 1930 census population ratio of the county to the total population of the State. This has enabled the counties to pay an average of $9.63 per child. However, a third of the counties in the State are paying less than 75 per cent of the budgeted needs in their dependent children cases, and only 26 counties have sufficient funds to meet all </seg>
            <seg id="p031">CHILD WELFARE BUREAU BUDGET of their Aid to Dependent Children needs. The two per cent allotted to the State for administration amounts to about $12,000 a year. This amount is not used for Child Welfare Services but is added to the amount available for administration of old age, blind, and relief assistance supplementing the amount for supervisors and accounting and statistical staffs. SALARIES AND EXPENSES Salaries have been much lower for the professional staff than pre - vails in other states. The District Child Welfare Consultants, who are required to be graduates of Grade A colleges and to have further training in social case work as well as experience with children's work, are paid from $125 to $150 per month. The supervisor of the Child Welfare Service program, a person with broad executive and supervisory experi - ence in child welfare, who has not been appointed as this report goes to press, should receive a salary in keeping with the requirements of the position. This salary is paid from federal funds. The county demonstration case workers are paid from $110 to $125 per month. They are required to be graduates of Grade A colleges and to have special training and supervised experience in social case work. These salaries are all paid from federal funds. The experienced clerical staff is paid $90 per month. The secretary to the Director is paid $100 per month. Inexperienced clerks and typists are paid $75 and $80 per month. On the executive and administrative staff there are two salaries — one at $200 and one at $175 per month. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU APPROPRIATIONS (12 Month Basis) Child Welfare Bureau State Federal Account 171 Salaries (administration and service).. $ 6,000.00 Account 172 Maintenance 1,750.00 Account 173 Maternity Home License Fees 400.00 '■ . : ■ 'i i Child Welfare Services Account 351 Administration 288.77 . Account 352 Services 9,089.69 Account 352 (a) Services $26,337,971 Crippled Children Services Account 351 ' Administration 728.58 Account 352 Services 22,870.84 Account 352 (a) Service and Administration 46,193.92 Aid to Dependent Children State Administration 21,746.65 10,873.33 County Administration 20,530.98 10,265.49 Assistance ...! 663,835.16 331,917.58 J An accumulated balance gives a total of $41,780.97 for the present fiscal year ending June 30, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">IV. Work Under the 1933 Act State Responsibilities There are certain child welfare activities that are universally recog - nized by the States as state responsibilities. Social security funds for Child Welfare Services cannot be used for this work. The appropriation to the Bureau from State funds has been inadequate to permit the Bureau to do well the work assigned to it. Duties recognized as State functions are the licensing and inspection of child-caring and child-placing agencies, development of placing standards, licensing and inspection of maternity homes and lying-in hospitals, upholding juvenile court standards, en - forcement of laws for the protection of children, promotion of Child Welfare Service, development of case work standards for care of special children's cases, including juvenile probation, and coordination of child welfare activities. The Nebraska law in this regard says: "To this end, the Bureau shall: (1) Visit and inspect all public and private institutions, agencies or societies caring for, receiving, placing out or handling children. (2) Issue certificates or licenses as provided by law to such institutions, agencies, or societies and have power to revoke such licenses or certificates for good cause shown. Provided, that in case a license is refused or revoked, appeal may be taken to the State Child Welfare Council hereinafter designated, or in case there is no such Council, to the district court of the county in which the agency is located. (3) Exercise general supervision over the administration and enforcement of all laws governing the placing out and adoption of chil - dren. (4) Advise with judges and probation officers of courts of domestic relations and juvenile courts of the several counties, with a view to en - couraging, standardizing, and coordinating the 'work of such courts and officers throughout the State. (5) Cooperate with county boards of public welfare and their executives, in the various counties, in all matters relating to the special classes of children heretofore designated, and in any other matters coming under the jurisdiction of such county boards. (6) Prescribe the form of reports required by law to be made to this bureau by public officers, agencies, and institutions." The staff of the Bureau has endeavored to administer these activities in the light of the best knowledge gained from experiences over the United States. Standards have been worked out and adopted for use by child-caring and -placing institutions and agencies. 1 Superintendents of both public and private agencies have met and discussed the standards and agreed to conduct the affairs of their agencies in the light of these accepted practices. Pointing the way, not dictating or forcing standards, has been the approach of the State Child Welfare Bureau to this problem. Licenses cannot be issued to agencies obviously !See: (1) Standards for Child Placing Agencies, 1936, State Child Welfare Bureau Publication. (2) Standards for Child Caring Agencies and Institutions, 1936, State Child Welfare Bureau Publication. 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU s^rvevtf !? *? Ptable T Hty ° f W ° rk Snd institu «onal supervision. A necessary, are using the State Child Welfare Bureau staff for case work tion and education. For a more complete discussion of this problem SlSSS? VI ' " Pr ° blemS ° f Child - Welfa - '" Pa-XhsTn advis^wftn £v SKS Welfare «"«*«*. the Bureau has advised with juvenile judges on problems of welfare. These district workers have given assistance to County workers also. The Bureau has not done so but should develop a definite program for juvenile probation^ in conjunction with the Board of Control. juvenile probation fl£ ™? Ch JT th th u BureaU receives reports from a11 child-placing SesL f nUmber ° f Children P lac^. names of children, names and addresses of persons with whom they are placed. These reports eive an Sr 7 1CtUr H ° f tHe Child -P lacin^ *»»* done by these agents County and th * S T rCPOrtS ; Unfortunate ly the children are oftentimes placS a*d the adoption completed before the report is received. From these made S ° U Effort 'T T* ° f "" ChildrCn PlaCGd f ° r adoption ca "^ made. Effort is being made to secure cooperation from outstate child - placing agencies to clear cases through the Bureau theJlMrrl*? Prote ?. tion wil1 be iven t« unmarried mothers and 5 J? 1 i ren&gt; .?f Bureau llcenses and Aspects all Maternity Homes and Lying-in Hospitals.^ During the past year the Bureau has worked closely n^sPiSlsa T h r ° n ad ° Pted Standards f0r these home « ™* Home inH J he TT homes . are by the Supervisor of the Maternity Home and the Unmarried Mother division and by the district workers Licenses are issued after approval by the local Board of Health In conS^w T the J Bureau has refu -d licenses to homes operating contrary to rules and regulations. In October, 1936, there were 14? hcensed maternity homes and lying-in hospitals. Applications are pend - nourTaf/ er ° therS aWaiting fUrther investigation. WitWn 24 Se C hl ld Wh" Unmarrled . m °ther enters a licensed home or hospital, Jf tf,? ff I aU 1S nOtified ' and Case work services a re offered if the mother wishes to take advantage of them old ST ? rin f l 93^* 116 BureaU had Occasion to funct ion under the old State Board of Charities and Corrections law.* A secretary of a 2 C. S., 1929; 71-2501. *C. S., 1929; 71-2701. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">WORK UNDER THE 1933 ACT local Chamber of Commerce reported an old folks' home that was soliciting money for an institution that was not in any way charitable. This institu - tion had been reported to the Bureau at different times since 1928. A careful investigation of the home was made and a report given to the local Board of Health. The local board ordered it closed at the recom - mendation of the Bureau, and the Bureau made arrangements for the removal and future care of the old folks at the home. In the other sections of this report the Social Security duties of the Bureau are enlarged upon; this is intended to give a skeleton outline of the structure on which the larger program has been built. </seg>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037">V. 1935 Child Welfare Act Nebraska Assistance Activities Three programs are delegated to the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau under the Nebraska Assistance Act. Definite responsi - bilities for case work for certain classes of children's cases are outlined in the act for the County Child Welfare Boards also. The County pro - gram is discussed in Section X. Aid to Dependent Children is administered by the County Child Welfare Board, which consists of the County Board of Commissioners or Supervisors, and the County Treasurer. Crippled Children Services and Child Welfare Services are administered directly by the Bureau according to plans developed jointly by the U. S. Children's Bureau and the State Child Welfare Bureau. AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN On November 1, 1936, 2,771 families were receiving Aid to De - pendent Children grants. In these families were 6,887 children. The monthly expenditure was $64,347.03. The average per child was $9.80. The figures for April, the first month this program was in operation, give a total of 154 families representing 415 children receiving a total of $2,392.66. In six months' time nearly 3,000 applications were taken, investigations made by the counties, and certificates issued by the state office. Aid to Dependent Children funds were slower in reaching the coun - ties than some other forms of assistance. County Assistance Committees gave all of their time to Old Age Assistance because of the pressure of applications. Forms were not sent to the counties until March. Probably the peak load of approximately 9,000 children will not be reached before March, 1937. The number of dependent children was determined by the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau through a census required of the counties before funds were released. 1 Before issuing instructions to the counties, best practices in the Mothers' Aid field were studied. State assistance was new in Nebraska. However, several states had had much experience in this field and had developed certain techniques. Counties were ' instructed through con - tacts by the Child Welfare Consultants (until August, 1936; see page 22), through institutes and bulletins from the State Child Welfare Bureau, and through letters from the certification department on individual cases. This is necessarily a technical program, and the County Directors co - operated splendidly. The response of the County Directors and County 'See: Administration of Mothers' Pensions and Aid to Dependent Children in Nebraska, Harry J. Becker, State Child Welfare Bureau Publication (in preparation). 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">COUNTY EXPENDITURES AND GRANTS TO COUNTIES FROM AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN FUNDS October, 1936 £67.00 S74.OO 8**-.»3- SfcO.1* *7».I9 )(«..(« 439.OO «0S.9t t*\ ««&gt; «5 -9V 204T8S JJ»»« RJJ^TX 31S.O6. 377.04- 82.0«S *-«-l.SO 3SO.«O 37*.B3 6*5.4i t5«a.*5 6701.0 1012.91 54V7^J«VV^^^ Key: Upper figure is amount spent for aid to Dependent Children per month. Lower figure is amount available for aid to Dependent Children per month. • Shaded counties are giving less than $8 per child. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">1935 CHILD WELFARE, ACT officials to the supervision and leadership extended by the State Child Welfare Bureau made possible the carrying out of investigation, eligi - bility, and budget standards. Although the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau is charged only with the supervision of the local administration, it was necessary to adopt certain principles for County and State administration to assure best use of Federal and State funds, and to adopt uniform records for the proper accounting of public funds. Counties were asked to have a good and sufficient written public record on each case to fully support the appropriation of funds. If the county did not make a home investigation and a written record establishing verification of data required by law and by good administrative practice, the State Child Welfare Bureau did not authorize payments, by the authority of the law, when eligibility requirements were not fully supported. Each Aid to Dependent Children case was budgeted. In this procedure a careful statement is made in each case showing the family needs and sources of income toward meet - ing the established needs. The County Child Welfare Boards prepared for the approval of the State Child Welfare Bureau a standard budget of family needs. The budget standard is the only method of determining eligibility and the amount of assistance for which the family is eligible. Before granting assistance the counties figured what per cent of needs in their Aid to Dependent Children cases funds available would meet, thus establishing the County percentage. Following are a few of the comments that have been sent to the State Child Welfare Bureau by County Directors: "Pensions before were entirely inadequate. Mothers say they can live decently now. The County is paying less in doctor bills and has had no delinquency cases. The Aid to Dependent Children has been much more adequate. All cases we have now had been receiving help. Children are better fed, mothers are learning to buy correctly, and the family can keep its self-respect." "Prior to March, 1936, the county board took care of dependent children without going into the real needs of the case. Now, we have a complete record of work being done, and the board recognizes the im - portance of the work. Prior to March, 1936, all dependent children cases were taken care of out of relief funds (no Mothers' Pension levy was made). No definite plan for care of children was made. Through regular home visits better school and health habits have been brought about." "Mothers' Pensions have been coordinated in our county with Aid to Dependent Children. There have been many advantages, most of which can be summarized by stating that it has made it possible to give ade - quate assistance to dependent children cases and has made it possible for one agency to complete the work of the case instead of having mothers' pension going to the client at the same time, making it neces - sary for the person to secure supplementary aid through the county relief office. We feel that it has given a greater sense of security and general well-being to the individual families concerned." "The families that we have under Dependent Care are pleased and do not complain. Some have their homes repaired, children's teeth, eyes, and tonsils treated, with small payments that they make after their </seg>
            <seg id="p040">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU groceries and fuel are paid for. Our county, perhaps, does not have the conditions found in cities." "Our Aid to Dependent Children cases have received more money than received through Mothers' Pension. These cases have been helped by receiving necessary medical attention. The County has been helped by the money. The main advantage is that the cases are now thoroughly investigated and homes visited." n u " Aid to De P end ent Children has allowed the county to enlarge its field of assistance and to extend a better type of help to individual fami - lies. The county feels that there are many advantages: better investiga - tion, increased financial assistance, a closer control of cases due to home visits and home reports, financial assistance to the county, so badly needed now because of drouth conditions." "The increased allowance of Aid to Dependent Children has enabled mothers to devote more time to care of the children and also provides means of doing so. It has helped the county to increase Mothers' Pension allowance. Investigation enabled the county to eliminate, some cases Others were given larger allowances. It has centered our attention on a long time program. It has been a decided advantage." "Mothers' Pension work is coordinated with Aid to Dependent Chil - dren, consequently a more thorough investigation is made, the needs of the families are better known, and they receive bstter service." NUMBER OF DEPENDENT CHILDREN FOR WHOM AID WAS GRANTED IN OCTOBER, 1936 No. of No. of | Average Families | Children Iotal Per Child One child 829 829 $11,662.18 I $14.07 Two children 705 1410 15,173.66 10.76 Three children 512 1536 14,777.94 9.62 Four children 280 1120 9,720.50 8.68 Five children 173 865 7,083.64 8.19 More than five children 124 805 5,929.11 7.37 Tota I 2623 6565 $64,347.03 $ 9.80 TABLE SHOWING BY COUNTY, AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN EXPENDITURES, AVERAGES PER CHILD, AND NUMBER . ■ RECEIVING AID IN OCTOBER, 1936 No. of No. of Tot.Monthly Av.Per child Families Children Expenditures per month Adams • . 57 130 $ 1,414.58 $10.88 Antelope 36 79 854.49 10.82 Arthur. -2 10 34.00 3.40 Banner 4 8 61.50 7.69 Blaine 2 6 41.40 6.90 Boone 34 69 808.89 11.72 Box Butte 23 55 644.00 11.71 Boyd 19 36 349.00 9.69 Brown 17 45 268.50 5.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT TABLE SHOWING BY COUNTY, AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN EXPENDITURES, AVERAGES PER CHILD, AND NUMBER RECEIVING AID IN OCTOBER, 1936 — Continued Total Average No. of No. of Monthly. Per child Families Children Expenditures per month Buffalo 60 137 1,241.22 9.06 Burt . 31 98 630.25 6.43 Butler 30 84 791.87 9.43 Cass 18 33 279.29 8.46 Cedar 56 137 1,204.20 " 8.79 Chase 15 44 261.00 5.93 Cherry 30 73 527.17 7.22 Cheyenne 19 55 454.56 8.26 Clay 26 60 492.35 8.20 Colfax 14 29 400.01 13.79 Cuming 24 73 691.08 9.47 Custer 76 196 1,412.99 7.21 Dakota 21 55 493.06 8.96 Dawes 8 30 292.00 9.73 Dawson 30 89 841.53 9.46 Deuel 9 16 139.41 8.71 Dixon 20 55 550.69 10.01 Dodge 63 169 1,536.40 9.09 Douglas 384 1,028 13,025.95 12.67 Dundy 13 38 274.33 7.22 Fillmore 26 48 475.00 9.90 Franklin 13 41 337.04 8.22 Frontier 22 47 376.43 8.01 Furnas 34 71 641.45 9.03 Gage 43 123 999.67 8.13 Garden 10 28 245.00 8.75 Garfield 4 15 97.28 6.49 Gosper 6 12 143.00 11.92 Grant 3 5 63.00 12.60 Greeley 22 55 455.15 8.28 Hall 47 97 1,091.08- 11.25 Hamilton 12 33 307.75 9.33 Harlan 30 59 655.35 11.11 Hayes 9 32 172.78 5.40 Hitchcock 17 46 365.28 7.94 Holt 35 112 904.00 8.07 Hooker 3 6 38.00 6.33 Howard 29 64 631.62 9.87 Jefferson 27 65 775.16 11.93 Johnson 18 41 504.01 12.29 Kearney.. 19 32 334.91 10.47 Keith 9 28 299.73 10.70 Keya Paha 6 17 140.00 8.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU TABLE SHOWING BY COUNTY, AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN EXPENDITURES, AVERAGES PER CHILD, AND NUMBER RECEIVING AID IN OCTOBER, 1936— Continued Total Average No. of No. of Monthly Per child Families Children Expenditures per month Kimball ; 10 30 240.30 8.01 Knox 57 137 917.54 6.70 Lancaster 138 344 3,438.94 10.00 Lincoln 67 164 1,165.42 7.11 Logan 4 13 77-50 5.96 Loup 4 11 88.50 8.05 Madison 67 186 1,498.82 8.06 McPherson 8 19 82.50 4.34 Merrick 19 50 431.28 8.63 Morrill 18 51 550.40 10.79 Nance 19 48 390.68 8.14 Nemaha 33 50 639.10 12.78 Nuckolls. 19 51 594.54 11.66 Otoe 30 81 750.41 9.26 Pawnee 21 47 456.29 9.71 Perkins 18 40 223.36 5.58 Phelps 21 42 525.12 12.50 Pierce 30 55 589.26 10.71 Platte 32 96 880.69 9.17 Polk 13 23 238.14 10.35 Red Willow 24 68 693.35 10.20 Richardson 42 90 967.08 10.75 Rock 9 18 99.44 5.52 Saline 14 23 281.13 12.22 Sarpy 10 38 381.46 10.04 Saunders 24 55 580.86 10.56 Scotts Bluff.... 55 139 1,509.93 10.86 Seward 22 56 664.00 11.86 Sheridan 23 56 534.90 9.55 Sherman 11 36 359.07 9.97 Sioux 5 18 161.53 8.97 Stanton. 12 35 340.75 9.74 Thayer 28 54 592.12 10.97 Thomas 5 12 74.35 6.20 Thurston .' 16 53 479.00 9.04 Valley 12 32 307.30 9.60 Washington 21 49 576.00 11.76 Wayne 24 51 453.03 8.88 Webster 19 47 433.00 9.21 Wheeler 5 17 143.88 8.46 York 29 66 867.65 13.14 2,623 6,565 $64,347.03 $*9.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT TABLE SHOWING COUNTY PERCENTAGES FOR AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN ON DECEMBER 1, 19361 100% 75% to 1007c 50% to 75% Under 50% Boone Adams Arthur Custer Cass Antelope Blaine Garfield Colfax Banner Box Butte Wheeler Cuming Boyd Brown Deuel Buffalo Cheyenne Dixon Burt Clay Douglas 2 Butler Dundy Fillmore Cedar Franklin Grant Chase Frontier Greeley Cherry Furnas Hall Dakota Gage Hamilton Dawes Hayes Jefferson Dawson Hitchcock Johnson Dodge Holt Kimball Garden Hooker Nemaha Gosper Keya Paha Phelps Howard Knox Polk Harlan Logan Rock Kearney Loup Richardson Keith Madison Saline Lancaster McPherson Stanton Lincoln Otoe Valley Merrick Pierce Wayne Morrill Sherman York Nance Sheridan Nuckolls Thomas Pawnee Thurston Perkins Platte Red Willow Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sioux Thayer Washington Webster 1 County percentage is the amount of the family need budgets available funds will meet. Because most of the counties did not reach their present peak load until late summer, the appropriation is meeting the needs much more adequately than the same appropriation would for the next •- biennium. It is significant that thirty counties with accumulated balances are meeting their needs less than 75 per cent. This means that a family that should receive $25.00 is receiving less than $18.00. Several of the </seg>
            <seg id="p044">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU CHILD WELFARE SERVICES Child Welfare Services is a less tangible program than Aid to De - pendent Children. These services consist of making plans for children's cases presenting social problems and in the developing of resources for child welfare. During the month of October, 1936, for example, the staff handled a total of 317 cases. This does not include the cases carried by the demonstration county case workers. Cases in District III are not counted, as no one was assigned to that district. In the same month County Assistance Directors were given supervision on 115 cases. Fifty - two counties requested case work service and supervision during October. Following are the types of cases given services in this month: Unmarried pregnant women 21 Physically handicapped children 10 Case work service on problem Dependent Child cases . 53 Foster home and adoptive placements 12 Institutional placements 4 Boarding home placements 7 Children supervised in boarding homes 8 Juvenile delinquency cases 64 Cases of neglect , 99 Other types of cases 28 317 TYPES OF CASES ACCEPTED BY DISTRICT CHILD WELFARE CONSULTANTS 1. Cases with question of the suitability of the home in respect to Aid to Dependent Children. 2. Cases of children being removed from their own homes for any reason whatsoever. 3. Problems of placement of children, foster and boarding homes. 4. Questions of adoption when not being handled by a licensed child - placing agency. 5. Cases rejected for Aid to Dependent Children which require services and follow-up plans. 6. Crippled children cases referred by the Crippled Children's Division for case-work service. 7. Cases of delinquent, abandoned, abused, and neglected children. 8. Cases of school problems such as truancy, retardation, behavior prob - lems, etc. 9. Children with venereal disease and other serious health problems such as tuberculosis, cardiac conditions, malnutrition, etc. larger counties will have to reduce their grants greatly as pending cases are investigated. 2100% is paid on cases receiving aid; however, when pending appli - cations are investigated, funds will probably be insufficient. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT This little house made largely from pasteboard boxes is not going to be very warm when the north wind blows this winter. Sickness is going to take a heavy toll in homes such as this one. Inadequate housing is a serious problem facing most communities in the State. 10. Unmarried pregnant women and mothers for whose children a plan is requested. 11. Other children's cases which require intensive case work or super - vision. SOURCES OF REFERRAL OF CHILD WELFARE CASES TO DISTRICT CHILD WELFARE CONSULTANTS 1. Cases may be referred directly to the District Child Welfare Con - sultants from the County Assistance Director and other County officials. 2. Certification Department may refer cases. 3. Cases that have come to the attention of the Bureau are referred to the District Child Welfare Consultants. For example: personal ap - plications, letters from County officials, requests from other agencies, references by interested citizens, etc. DEMONSTRATION COUNTY WORKERS There are five well-qualified case workers assigned to rural counties selected for such services for their particular problems after application from County officials has been made. These workers, paid from federal funds, devote full time to doing intensive child welfare work on cases referred by local officials, in the counties to which they are assigned. (See map showing location, page 21.) The following are typical case stories referred from rural communi - ties, selected at random from the files of the State Child Welfare Bureau, and illustrate the types of work done by the District Child Welfare con - sultants and Demonstration County Workers: </seg>
            <seg id="p046">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU A Juvenile "Gang" — State Saved $186.60 a Month During the past four years a group of a dozen boys, ranging in age from five to fourteen years, has been engaged in a series of petty thefts, depredations, truancy, and destruction of property. The activities have developed from this childish stealing to well-organized racketeering. On chicken stealing escapades, one boy watched for the police, one held the bag, one actually picked up the chickens; each had his specialized duty. Their final and most profitable business was their arrangement with storekeepers. If the merchant agreed to provide them with all the cigarettes and candy they wanted, they protected his store. One night the system failed. The boy assigned to watch for the police was caught by an officer and was unable to warn the others. All were arrested. These boys were playing junior gangsters. As they were successful, their work increased. The County Attorney, not wanting to send .them to a correctional institution, fearing they would return to society deter - mined to be Public Enemy Number One, requested the services of the Child Welfare Consultant. The Consultant called at the home of each boy and talked with the parents. The ringleader's home was entirely unsatisfactory. He had an uncle, however, who lived in another county and who was interested in him and offered to take him into his home permanently. He will be able to guide the boy into more wholesome interests. Also, with the ringleader out of town, the gang automatically disbanded. A search is being made for a satisfactory boarding home for a second boy whose home is entirely broken up. *0fr- m V ■XSrJIVl ''JtmT^ln 1 ±M ■H t wf ■■ \ \ *^ jH MKJ r^| • jail 1 B^HS^jhI tftolUdLJI I;! flbtg** "Eg2t BJIiiP^ y &lt;#! ■ I El7'-i&gt; In trailer houses similar to the one pictured here the child welfare consultants frequently find six and seven children living. Delinquency and other costly social problems are inevitable results of home conditions which this picture suggests. The Bureau's worker is often asked by local welfare officials for suggestions for planning for transient families. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT A typical home in one of the western Nebraska Demonstration Units which is visited regularly by the Demonstration County child welfare workers. Sometimes it is because the school authorities have reported a child as neglected or under - nourished. It might be a case referred by the county attorney because one or both of the parents have deserted, or the county judge has asked that plans be made for a delinquent boy or girl. With each of the other boys, the County Assistance Workers, in co - operation with the Child Welfare worker, are visiting in the homes and trying to adjust the family situation. The Child Welfare consultant is planning with interested individuals in the community for supervised recreation. If the five boys involved in the theft had been sent to Kearney State Industrial School, the cost would have been five times $37.32, which means $186.00 per month saved the State by not institutionalizing these boys. Not an Institutional Case John's family life was unhappy. His father and mother argue vio - lently and erratically scold John so that he hardly knows how to act to please them. The parents frequently put John out of the home. One night when John had been put out, he wandered through the alleys and was picked up by the police. As his family was not interested in him, he was sent to the Boys' Industrial School. The Judge, however, has asked the child welfare worker to help him locate a good home where John may live. As John is a colored boy, the Urban League is working with the child welfare worker in finding a suitable home where John will be wanted, loved, and given the benefit of home training, which is the best preparation for good citizenship. A Runaway Boy A boy, aged 13, was a resident of the State Home for Dependent Children. He ran away three times and returned to his family each time. Since the child had become a problem to the county officials, the Child Welfare consultant was asked to assist local persons with the case. The boy was an illegitimate child. The mother was not interested in him, and he lived with his maternal grandmother. When his mother married the man for whom she was housekeeper, he was taken into their </seg>
            <seg id="p048">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU home. She had five children during the next five years and little could be done to give the boy a sense of security, which he so needed because of his earlier background. The situation was further complicated by the attitude of the step-father. _He forced the boy to work long hours. He punished him rather than giving him any encouragement or kindness. As a result he became a problem child at school where the pupils teased him about his illegitimacy. When the boy's problem was discussed with the mother, her only suggestion was that of returning him to the Home or placing him in the Boys' Industrial School at Kearney. Relatives, however, thought the boy could adjust himself very well if placed in a good home. A relative took the boy into his home until a boarding home could be found. With the cooperation of the County Judge and County Assistance Director, a boarding home was found. Private Instruction Arranged For a Handicapped Boy The case of 9-year-old Junior B. was referred to worker after his mother had interviewed the County Attorney concerning the advisability of sending him to the State Institution for the Feeble-Minded owing to a speech defect and his inability to progress beyond the first grade in school. The home was found to be above the average. The B. family, which includes the father and mother and three boys, lives with Mrs. B.'s mother in the home which she has owned and occupied for years. Mr. B. is working on W.P.A., and there is every evidence of good management and the existence of a satisfactory relationship between this family and the grandmother. After consulting the family physician and learning that Junior is normal physically with the exception of poor eyesight, he was taken to a psychologist, who found him to have the very low I. Q. indicated by a Erv&amp;VnBaflfllH IK! Si 1* In this home plans were made by a child welfare consultant for care and treatment of a crippled child, who without the aid of the State Child Welfare Bureau would probably have gone through life as a hopeless cripple, dependent on county funds for food, clothing, and shelter. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT 54 rating. The doctor's recommendation was that ideally the boy should have instruction in manual arts, but because of the crowded condition at the State Institution for the Feeble-Minded he would probably not receive this attention. The fact that Junior has good care and is so well adjusted in his own home made it seem wise to attempt to use local resources. The Lutheran minister was then interviewed, and he agreed to arrange daily individual instruction at the parochial school. The parents ■were very happy to make this arrangement since they had really pre - ferred to keep him in the home, but had felt that they should not 1 deny him better training by refusing to give him up. Attention was called to the boy's need for glasses, and the parents agreed to supply these out of their W. P. A. income. A Case of Serious Neglect Four years ago Jack's father was brought into court and fined $50.00 and sentenced to ten days in jail for beating Jack, then five years old. Mr. C. has not improved his behavior. His hatred for Jack has not lessened but rather increased. He insists Jack is not his child, and his punishment shows scars on this little child's body. Jack, a bright youngster, nine years old, but the size of a six-year - old, has lost his spontaneity. He is afraid to express himself, afraid to complain, afraid to answer if offered an ice cream cone, afraid to go home. He spends nights in a corn crib. He is given work which is much too hard. Finally, he asked the sheriff for a new home. The sheriff relayed Jack's request to the Child Welfare Consultant, who discussed the situation with the parents, relatives and neighbors. The father would have nothing to do with Jack or any plans for him. The mother felt it. was necessary that he live elsewhere and therefore relinquished him to the custody of the County under the supervision of the Child Welfare Bureau. No relative was found who seemed a desirable person to take him. Because Jack is in such poor physical condition and because he has no "life in him," he was not immediately placed out for adoption. He is being boarded in a private home. The boarding mother and the Child Welfare Consultant are trying to make Jack's life a happy one so that he can know a normal life, so that he can feel he is wanted and understood, so that he can be dressed in clean clothes, so that he can have a few possessions of his own, so that he can learn to have confidence in the adults. When he has become more normal, some family will want him, and through adoption he will be given a permanent home. If a careful study had been made when the father was arrested, Jack could have been saved four years of misery and many fears which per - manently affect his personality. Homeless Child Given Family Care Last year, Tommy's father was sent to the State Penitentiary on a charge of robbery. This summer his mother was drowned while swim - ming in the nearby river. Tommy, aged two, was then left to the mercy of anyone who would give him a home. One hot day he was forgotten and left in the sun so long that he suffered sunstroke. The family with whom he was staying asked the County Assistance office for medical aid. As he was so severely injured by the sun, was almost unconscious, had completely lost his ability to speak, and could no longer walk, he was placed in the local hospital at a cost to the County of $1.50 per day, or $45.00 a month. After four weeks of skillful care at the hospital, he was so improved that he was just beginning to try to walk. Although he did not need to remain in the hospital, he did need to be cared for by someone who loved him and would be willing to spend much time in teaching him. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU The County Assistance office at this point asked the aid of the Child Welfare Consultant, who called at the home of Mr. and Mrs. T. who had become interested in Tommy, a sweet child with curly hair, when they visited their own son in the hospital. The T.'s were pleased to be able to take Tommy for $15.00 per month and are as much interested in teach - ing him to walk and talk as if he were their own baby. An Unmarried Mother Mary, aged 19, gave birth to a child in a maternity home. When visited by a worker for the Child Welfare Bureau, Mary appeared un - emotional. She insisted that she did not wish to keep her child, although several ways for her to do this were pointed out as well as the advan - tages of a child receiving the love and care of its own mother. The father was an older man, twice married, who had known Mary and her family for years. Mary's parents were divorced and remarried. She lived with her mother and her second family in a shack without even the necessities of life. The alleged father, who was living with his step - daughter, a good friend of Mary's, admitted being the child's father. Marriage of the father and mother was discouraged as well as any plan for Mary to keep her baby, because the two persons would be unable to establish a home and Mary, not wanting the child, would not give it a satisfactory home. The young mother was given a mental test and found to be of average intelligence. She signed relinquishment papers for the child, which was to be placed in the State Home for Dependent Children for adoption. A good home for the child will be found by the State, and it will have a better chance to develop into a self-supporting citizen with a normal adjustment in the community. A Delinquent Boy Needing a Home Jack, a fourteen-year-old, was brought to the attention of the State Child Welfare Bureau when he was arrested for stealing money from a store. An investigation of his home disclosed an unsatisfactory environ - ment for normal development. His mother was dead, and his father was attempting to provide a home for Jack and his sister. His father often displayed a violent temper and punished his children unduly. However, he shielded Jack in his wrongdoings and would not admit that his own son was a delinquent. Jack was emotionally unstable and was said to draw a knife when - ever he became angry. After a series of other delinquencies, Jack was committed to the State Home 'for Dependent Children. Later, he disappeared from there and was not heard from again until word was received from California where he had been apprehended for "crashing a show." After he was returned to Nebraska, he did not wish to go back to the Home. The worker from the State Child Welfare Bureau suggested that a placement be made in the home of an aunt. Jack was happy over this plan and agreed to return to the State Home for Dependent Children until such arrangements could be made. Investigation of the aunt's home revealed that the aunt was a pleasant woman and sincerely interested in Jack's welfare. She had a son about Jack's age and felt that the two boys could play together on the ranch. This plan would not only save the State the expense of providing for Jack at the State Home for Dependent Children but would also provide a happy home for the boy. Upon a visit several months later, the worker found Jack was enjoy - ing his school work, his new friends, and rural life. None of his previous delinquency problems seem to be present. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT CRIPPLED CHILDREN SERVICES* The Bureau, working closely with representatives from the Crippled Children's Division of the U. S. Children's Bureau, has planned a State program which will meet the crippled child's needs. With Crippled Chil - dren funds crippled children are located, given diagnosis, and if neces - sary, surgical, corrective, and other services and care. Hospitalization and after-care are included in services given. To the first of November applications had been received for 228 children. Of these, 61 were re - jected as non-remedial or ineligible. Hospitalization and corrective care had been provided for 89 children on November first and service given on 199 cases. To November first, a little less than $10,000 had been spent, leaving a total of $83,624.55 to run until June 30, 1937, or nearly $12,000 a month for care of crippled children for the remainder of this biennium. The difficulty in getting this program under way arises from two factors: (1) responsibility rests with local officials and family physicians to refer cases. County Assistance Directors have been too busy with other phases of the assistance program to prepare reports on crippled chil - dren sooner. Bulletins, institutes, and publicity have been worked out, but the Crippled Children work is done last by many counties; (2) lack of administrative staff. Persons properly qualified to serve as field supervisors and assistants are not easily obtained for the salary offered — $125 to $150 per month.* The problem of the physically handicapped child is jointly a social and medical one. His education, adjustment in the community and in his home, and vocational training are definitely social problems as significant as his physical condition. Social data is given to the physician to assist him in planning the medical program for the crippled child. The problems in the social environment which are factors in the maladjustment of the crippled child are the concern of the medical social worker working with the physician to coordinate the physical and social rehabilitation plans. Policies and administrative plans are worked out in close consulta - tion with the technical advisory committee, which is composed of medical men, and the general advisory committee, composed of members rep - resenting different groups and organizations interested in the crippled child. Cases are not accepted if the parents are able to pay for medical services needed; these cases are carried only on a service basis. Records must show clearly whether the parents and relatives are able to pay for needed services, the social background, diagnosis and prognosis of physical condition, extent of crippling condition, social plan, and medical plan. The State Child Welfare Bureau is not justified in spending public 2 See: Preliminary Manual of Crippled Children's Services, 1936, State Child Welfare Bureau Publication. 3 Properly qualified field staff may include medical social workers,, public health nurses, or nurses with public health training. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU funds on a case until a good and sufficient record is established showing clearly why expenditures should be made. Per case cost of services averages approximately two hundred dollars, and care must be taken that this amount of money is wisely spent. Keeping a financial and social record of this sort protects the taxpayer, the physician, and the child. Care is given in following up the crippled children cases to see that the recommendations of the physician in regard to food, change of braces, check-up examinations, etc., are followed. The following case of a crippled child illustrates the work of the Bureau: Charles is the fourteen-year-old son of a drouth relief tenant farmer. He had infantile paralysis when he was two years old. This left him so afflicted he could not walk, and at fourteen he talks with much difficulty, saying only a few words. Because of these circumstances he has not progressed in school. His parents had lost confidence in what might be done for him by medical science as they had spent much money on un - successful treatments. The County Assistance Director referred the case to the State Child Welfare Bureau. She sent a complete summary of the social information and a statement of referral from the family physician, who suggested a specialist who should examine the child. The parents refused to permit the examination. After a visit to the home by a Crippled Children's worker, the parents saw the need and consented to arrange to bring the lad in for an examination. After the specialist, with the aid of the social data pre - pared by the County Director and the Crippled Children's worker, fully understood the case, he and the worker from the Bureau were able to show the parents why the child should go to the hospital for surgery and other treatment. Charles is now ready to leave the hospital, and frequent letters of progress have been sent to his parents. He will have to wear a brace for about six months. The Crippled Children's worker will keep in close BHm^^ •. ' ' vii ii Mi' ' w b si ■ SjHjfc. 1 PsfPfK'^ Ib SI f fll Before Treatment After Treatment </seg>
            <seg id="p053">1935 CHILD WELFARE ACT I 1 * A ; f : i- Before Treatment After Treatment touch with the family and make certain that the brace is worn the length of time the physician recommends and that he sees the specialist at the intervals recommended. The cost of the case will probably be about $200.00. The lad will be a self-supporting citizen, living a normal, happy life. Without this service and assistance he would probably have been a dependent adult requiring constant care. </seg>
            <seg id="p054"/>
            <seg id="p055">VI. Problems of Child Welfare Special Classes of Children The Bureau is organized to give assistance and service through several categorical programs. All of these programs are directed toward one goal — the protection and care of the child needing assistance and service. Child Welfare can be broken into integral parts — the conserva - tion of life and health, training and education, child labor, juvenile delinquency, and dependency. This section is intended to show in what ways the integrated State Child Welfare Bureau administration and other Nebraska agencies are meeting the needs of the special problems of child welfare. THE DEPENDENT CHILD Figures on the actual number of children dependent on public aid are not available, but the number of children thrown on the public for support in Nebraska is large. Practically every county has a number of destitute, homeless, and abandoned children in addition to those whose parents are receiving public aid. Some of these children are boarded out, and others are institutionalized at County or State expense. 1 In January, 1936, 31% of the children in the State under 15, based on relief figures (not including W.P.A. and Rural Resettlement), were receiving public assist - ance. The pitifully low relief budgets cannot possibly provide adequate nourishment, medical care, glasses, and school supplies. Scarcely a mail delivery in the Bureau office fails to bring one or more inquiries from parents whether there is not some way in which the Bureau can help to provide their children with milk, tonsillotomy, glasses, school supplies, and other necessaries. In July, 1936, the N. E. R. A. Special Research Bulletin, No. 1, Relief Need in Nebraska, stated, "The effects of the dis - continuation of milk and special diets have been so disheartening that the children's clinic of the City Health Department has stopped making examinations for malnutrition unless an organic cause is suspected." Many communities in the State have records of great increases in the number of health problems among children as well as adults. County relief is inadequate in practically every county. Many counties have no county funds for relief. W. P. A. wages for unskilled labor vary from $40 per month in the rural counties to $55 in the largest urban area. Many unskilled workmen with large families do not have sufficient income from their W. P. A. wages to support their families adequately. For the most part the counties are reluctant to supplement W. P. A. wages. Relief agencies, as a general thing, do not supplement workers engaged in private employment at an insufficient wage. The * Although the law prohibits the housing of children in county poor houses, in July, 1936, children were known to be in county poor houses in two counties in the State. 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU CHART SHOWING INCAPACITY OF PARENTS IN 2164 AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN CASES 45 : 40 3g fH [^DWORCEfr AND SEPARATED 30 ||H ' US INCAPACITATED 1111 pPENAL \NSTITUTIONS 20 ■■ t^» _^H____L_ | "pUNMARRlED M0THE.R5 fHH I ■■■■ | q -1^ F INSTITUTIONS seriousness of inadequate relief grants is a story that is just beginning to unfold. Lowered morale and increased discouragement, health handi - caps, and leaving school at 16 years or younger are the early chapters. Aid to Dependent Children funds- are giving adequate assistance to those families of children in the counties which meet the full budget AGE DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN IN 2116 AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN FAMILIES 1500 I ■»., 1200 -TT : 145 900 226-T- - 600 -n-TI- - - 11 o n n n n n i i ■ % *± n .$. 2~r~ C * = = — - 1 W W W O» OJ z, ow a» v&gt; to a\ cd — -u-j o I I i i I I I I I I I I £2 a» to — — — aj "• *** en oo — Key: The white columns indicate those children receiving Aid to Dependent Children funds. The black columns indicate those children not receiving Aid to De - pendent Children funds. 2Charts and graphs presented here are from Administration of Mothers' Pension and Aid to Dependent Children in Nebraska, Harry J. Becker. Child Welfare Bureau Publication (in preparation.) </seg>
            <seg id="p057">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE deficiencies. Families with one child can receive only $18 per month, which is not at all adequate, and the Bureau as a matter of policy does not certify these cases unless supplementation from relief funds is planned, so that the $18 is not expected to cover the needs of those persons in the family over 16 years. In these families with children 16 and over, there is again the prob - lem of supplement from other funds. The map on page 32 shows the counties spending less than $8 per child as well as the monthly Dependent Children expenditures and allotments from the State. Many of the counties are not spending the maximum amount available to them for Aid to Dependent Children. In a few counties the funds are not needed, while in others the amount available is only half enough. Funds are allocated on a population basis, which is the cause of this discrepancy. The chart on the need for medical care in Aid to Dependent Children families, is significant. The number of fathers needing medical attention is high, because the law requires that one parent bs incapacitated before aid is given; a large proportion of the fathers in these families come in this group. Material for this chart was obtained from the investigation reports sent to the State Child Welfare Bureau. Another study made by the Bureau is the one showing causes of dependency in Aid to Dependent Children families. In very few of the cases is the cause something the parent could avoid. These are not the chronic "reliefers"; death and illness are the outstanding causes. They are normally a wage-earning, self-supporting group which knows what it means to have adequate living. CHART SHOWING PERCENTAGE OF PARENTS AND CHILDREN REPORTED ON AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN APPLICA - TIONS AS NEEDING IMMEDIATE MEDICAL ATTENTION 60 40 II 30 II 20 || || o I H_ H H : FATHERS MOTHERS CHILDREN Note: The percentage for fathers is abnormally high, because one requirement is that the parent must be incapacitated and in many cases application is made because of the father's illness. </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059"/>
            <seg id="p060">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU CHART SHOWING INCAPACITY OF PARENTS IN 1344 MOTHERS* PENSION CASES 7 r^&gt;ECEASED _ _ 1 '?*DESERTED 6 0 —^ sn IS pklVORCED AND SEPARATED PH} '"Pother 4 0 —^M pll f'PHYSlCAJA.Y \HCAPACITATEO 30 _M _ — 0 ~~^H ■■ it ** PENAL l0 MNSTrTUTIONS o I 1 I 1 1 1 L i L_—::-. .m,', .,.. Mothers' Pension funds, although very inadequate, have supple - mented county poor funds and State and Federal Aid to Dependent Children funds. In many counties Mothers' Pension funds have been co - ordinated with Aid to Dependent Children, adopting the Aid to Dependent Children budget system for all cases, and providing grants-in-aid which are more nearly adequate. Some counties have granted the maximum allowed under Aid to Dependent Children and in cases of insufficiency have granted additional allowances from Mothers' Pension and relief funds. All cases eligible for Mothers' Pension are eligible for Aid to De - pendent Children; however, the latter program extends to many cases not eligible under the old law. CHART SHOWING FIGURES AVAILABLE FOR THE AMOUNTS SPENT ANNUALLY BY THE COUNTIES FOR MOTHERS' PENSIONS, AND THE AVERAGE GRANTS PER CHILD a § i :■ • ■ l li - a i ? b 6 ■■ I \ \\ [j I I I- I *&amp; y S 5 5 o 5 ■ ■ «' ■ " ; f. "• . ♦ ■ • * </seg>
            <seg id="p061">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE CHART SHOWING FIGURES AVAILABLE AS TO THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN AND NUMBER OF MOTHERS RECEIVING MOTHERS' PENSIONS 4000 '? \ 3000 „, *s^ 2000 I N10THES -SSS -*» . «o 1000 _§a==!:dflll . n nj 1 gj g n n In counties in which the Mothers' Pensions are not coordinated with Aid to Dependent Children the grants are generally inadequate, being as low as $1.07 per child per month. In a report of the United States Children's Bureau 3 regarding pen - sion grants in the various states in June, 1931, it is stated that of the 43 states granting pensions at that time, Nebraska ranked thirtieth in regard to the amount of the grants allowed. The average grant was given as $17.81, or about $3.00 more than that in 1935. In many cases one of the primary purposes of the pension has been defeated, because the mother has been forced to work away from home and neglect her family. Not all County Judges are familiar with the principles 1 of the Mothers' Aid grants; one judge stated that he did not give Mothers' Pension grants, because he believed it "might make mothers less anxious to get out and work." 4 The levies made for Mothers' Pensions are unnecessarily low in many counties. Fifty-four counties did not make the maximum levy in 1935. Of the 23 counties paying less than $8 per child under the Aid to De - pendent Children program, seven decreased their Mothers' Pension levy in 1936, and not one increased it, although only seven had levied the maximum amount. There is no uniformity among the counties in the , Aid, 1931, U. S. Department of Labor, Children's Bureau. ' *Nebraska Survey of Social Resources. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU administration of the Mothers' Pension provisions. In many counties, however, the Aid to Dependent Children funds would be entirely inadequate if it were not for the Mothers' Pension funds available. Following are several case stories from the Child Welfare Bureau files illustrating what happens in individual cases of child planning with inadequate assistance and without case work service available: "About ten years ago Mrs. D. and her four children, Harry 11, Ruth 10, Edna Mae 4, and Martha 2, were deserted by their husband and father. He left somewhat unexpectedly, and they have had no contact with him since then. Mrs. D. had no funds and had very few friends. Her husband's relatives had criminal records, and it seemed that all of the members of the family who carried the name of D. were stigmatized in the community and looked upon as 'jail birds' and violators of the law. "The amount of assistance was inadequate for Mrs. D.'s family to live on, but finally she secured a job as cook in a cafe earning $5.00 a week. This required her to be away from home ten or twelve hours a day, and the children were left to their own resources. At the age of twelve Harry was committed to the Boys' Industrial School where he was to remain until he was twenty-one. He was institutionalized because he and his cousin, Keith M., had been stealing. Ruth, at the age of eleven, was committed as a dependent, neglected, delinquent child, to the Girls' Industrial School, where she was to remain until she was twenty-one years old. Edna Mae, a large, attractive blue-eyed girl, with blonde hair, and quite intelligent, became pregnant and at fifteen married a man fifteen years her senior. "At this period in the case, a welfare worker started making plans with the family. The mother had definitely made up her mind to make plans to leave town. Martha, the youngest daughter, was placed in a boarding home. At the end of the first six weeks, teachers in the school stated that they believed Martha was the happiest child that they had ever seen, and that girls her own age were accepting her socially. Scholastically, she could be classified in the superior group." Institutional care is provided by the State at the Home for De - pendent Children; children are committed as wards of the State or may be boarded at the home without commitment. During- the biennium end - ing June 30th, 1935, the average number of children in the institution was 116. This institution has two field workers who visit adoptive homes and supervise children placed by the Home in adoptive, free, and boarding homes. Private institutions and agencies were caring for 1,654 children on January 1, 1936, according to reports received by the Bureau. This is an increase of 18% over 1930, with three agencies not reporting in 1935 which reported in 1930. The table for the agencies reporting is the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p063">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE . . Aclive Active Cases New Dis- Cases Jan.l, Cases charged Jan.l, 19S5 1935 1935 19S6 Bethphage Mission Axtell Not reported "Catholic Child Welfare Omaha Not reported "Child Welfare Association Omaha 187 171 154 204 The Creche Omaha 20 35 18 37 Christian Orphan's Home Holdrege 100 12 13 101 Convent of the Good Shepherd Omaha , 129 104 256 Dutch Reform Mission School for Indian Children Winnebago Not reported Father Flanagan's Boys' Home Boystown 173 196 178 191 5 Hattie B. Monroe Home Omaha Not reported Immanuel Deaconess Institute Omaha 41 18 19 40 'Jewish Community Center and Welfare Federation Omaha 3 22 Lutheran Orphan's Home Fremont 18 22 53 Martin Luther Home Sterling Not reported Masonic Home for Children Omaha 12 13 56 Mothers' Jewels Home York 74 13 28 ' 59 . ■■ ' v ■ x Agencies for child welfare service only. 2 Convalescent home. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU Active Active . _ Cases New Dia- Cases Jan. 1, Cases charged Jan. 1, 1935 1935 1935 1936 •Nebraska Children's Home Society Omaha 149 20 25 144 Nebraska Masonic and Eastern Star Home Fremont Not reported Odd Fellows Home York Not reported Salvation Army Home and Hospital Omaha 15 93 96 12 St. James Orphanage Omaha 56 148 St. Thomas Orphanage Lincoln . 82 58 50 90 ■Social Welfare Society Lincoln 23 12 10 25 Tabitha Home Lincoln 15 58 3 Also a child-caring agency, and not all children reported are in the institution. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE CASE STORIES FROM THE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU FILES OF CHILDREN INSTITUTIONALIZED BECAUSE OF DEPENDENCY: Note: A family of seven being separated from their father at the death of their mother as "homeless, destitute, and dependent children." It seems a tragedy that public aid cannot be given in a case of this sort and the children kept together with their parent, when he is a suitable person, and the home supervised, if necessary, by the county welfare worker. THE JUVENILE COURT OF COUNTY, NEBRASKA The State of Nebraska, "1 IN THE INTEREST OF J , B , D \- JOURNAL ENTRY R- , N , R B J I Now, on this 31st day of August, 1936, at 9 o'clock A. M., this cause came on for hearing upon the petition of the Chief Probation Officer of this court, who is also in support thereof. It appears that no Judge of the District Court is within the boundary of , Nebraska. The complainant appears in person and the Sheriff, Probation Officer, and County Attorney, and it appears that the father has been duly summoned as required by law and is personally present in court. and were sworn and testified for the State , , and were also called and testified. Upon consideration of the evidence the court finds that V B is the father of all of these children; that he was born De - cember 5, 1891, and is now 45 years old; that the mother, F B , departed this life on or about July 4, 1935; and that the family consists of V B , the father, and the following children: J , born May 3, 1916, age 20 E , born August 1, 1918, age 18 D :, born June 21, 1921, age 15 R , born March 16, 1923, age 13 N , born September 7, 1924, age 11 R , born March 14, 1926, age 10 B , born February 19, 1929, age 7 R , born March 24, 1931, age 5 O , born May 10, 1933, age 3 The court finds from the evidence that the allegations contained in said petition are true; that said children are under the age of 18 years, are destitute, homeless and dependent on the public for support; that the burden of the family rests upon E ! B : , aged 18, and that because of her tender age and lack of training she is incompetent to maintain the home and furnish the children with the necessary care; that the circumstances surrounding this home and children, despite the best efforts of said V. B , are such as will tend to cause such children to lead a vicious and immoral life and interfere with their education. It appearing to the court that the Chief Probation Officer, the County Relief Committee and the Lutheran Church are negotiating for the care of said children. IT IS ORDERED that this cause be continued for thirty days. (SEAL) County Judge. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU THE JUVENILE COURT OF COUNTY, NEBRASKA The State of Nebraska, 1 IN THE INTEREST OF V. :., B , D . I- ORDER R. , M , R I and O B J Now on this 26th day of September, 1936, this cause came on further to be heard and it appearing to the court that Mrs. M D •. , residing in the city of. , has taken the children R and N , for a consideration to be paid through the County Relief Organization and arrangements have been made with (an orphanage that very seldom places children) for the care of M , R , B and R ; that J B has a job in which he is to receive $13.00 a month and his board, and that E B is now em - ployed and making her own way; that O B:. is now employed under the direction of his guardian and there only remains V. B in the home; It is ordered that this case be. continued indefinitely, but that the matter be taken up on the further order of this court at any time when it becomes necessary to do so. County Judge. (SEAL) Note: Had case work service been available, possibly, a visiting housekeeper could have been placed in the home and the father kept his children and the State saved the expense of institutional care. The child's own home is usually better than no home at all. After an operation for cancer, Mrs. E. died. Her husband was working on an FERA job and found it very difficult to provide adequately for the five children. The two older boys, who were in their early twen - ties, did not take any interest in their younger sisters and brother. All of the children were poorly clothed. There was no one to prepare meals properly. The house was often cold. At last the younger children were placed in a boarding home. The children were well-cared for. However, the father felt he should keep the children in his own home and thought he was still capable of caring for his family. As a 'result the children were again returned to their father's two-roomed home. Since no plan had been made to further provide for the family, the former conditions again arose. After the children were quarantined for measles, the father realized that in his present financial situation he could not provide for his children. Plans were then made to send them to the State Home for Dependent Children. They were accepted and taken to the institution. THE DELINQUENT CHILD The State Child Welfare Bureau provides case work service for delinquent children in every instance which comes to its attention, ad - vises with other groups and individuals working with delinquent chil - dren, and endeavors vigorously to promote community action for the prevention of delinquency. The term "delinquent child" as defined in the Compiled Statutes of 1929, Sec. 43-201 was used to describe 383 children who appeared be- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE fore juvenile courts in the six-months' period from September, 1935, to March, 1936. The problems involved included: injury to person, sex offenses, stealing, violations of orders and ordinances, injury to property, incorrigibility, running away, truancy, aiding and abetting a delinquent, and violation of parole. Forty-seven counties did not report any juvenile delinquency, but this was partly because the cases were handled in - formally without making records. A questionnaire sent from the Bureau to County and Juvenile Judges in the State in January, 1936, brought answers indicating strong feeling that the "liquor problem" combined with public and unsupervised dance halls and pool halls was a serious cause for delinquency in children; that unemployed parents and older children constituted another funda - mental problem; and that lack of adequate recreational facilities was one of the most frequent causes. Many judges suggested the need for better home training and greater sense of responsibility on the part of the parents, and others suggested that a full-time worker with skill in dealing with children's problems would be extremely valuable — this was before State Welfare Consultants were assigned to make regular visits to the counties. During the preceding biennium the Boys' Industrial School handled an average of 198 boys per month and the Girls' Training School an average of 185 per month. Eighteen children and young women under 20 years of age were committed to the State Reformatory for Women and 127 boys and young men under 20 to the State Reformatory for Men during the same biennium. Probation, defined elsewhere in this report, would save many of these young delinquents from the experience of incarceration and would do a tremendous good in guiding the youths into satisfactory adjustment in the communities. The District Child Welfare Consultants advise with Juvenile and County Judges on cases of juvenile delinquency and with them try to develop best disposition of these cases. The following case story from the Bureau files indicates what can bs done on a case work basis with cases of delinquency: The Bureau was notified of the case of Ellen W., aged 14, who was considered by her mother as a problem child. She was reported as a disobedient girl who told lies, stole things, and had tantrums. Ellen was referred by this agency to a psychiatrist for a thorough examination. The results of this examination showed that Ellen's maladjustment was probably due to her home environment. There were ten children in the family, who, with the exception of Ellen, all seemed to have made a fairly satisfactory adjustment. The family was receiving relief and because of the size of the family, funds were always inadequate. The things Ellen stole she invariably presented to her friends as gifts, hoping in this way to win their favor. Both the father and mother were unstable and often whipped the children severely. It was suggested by the psychiatrist that the girl be placed in a boarding home where she might live under normal family conditions rather than being placed in the girls' Training School at Geneva. Plans are now being made to provide a board - ing home for Ellen. ******** </seg>
            <seg id="p068">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU Note: The case of Jim shows the need for boarding home funds in handling delinquency problems. Jim had gone to live with his great uncle. His mother was dead, and his father had disappeared. For a while Jim lived with an aunt, who also died. Then he went to his maternal grandmother's home. She was bed - ridden and wholly unable to give Jim a home. As a result he spent most of his time running the streets. Twice he ran away to Lincoln, and several times he was found in petty thievery. After this, his great uncle took him into his home. Although he had his wife and two children to support with his small income, he was willing to care for Jim. His wife liked Jim and felt that he needed the influence of a man's guidance. However, the family could not care for Jim financially unless they re - ceived some assistance. When Jim was included in their budget their monthly expenses amounted to $95.42 while their monthly income was only $69.40. The family applied to the Aid for Dependent Children's fund, but was rejected because the great uncle did not fall within the required degree of relationship. Neither the juvenile court nor the Bureau had any money for boarding home care and therefore could not assist Jim. THE MENTALLY HANDICAPPED CHILD The mentally handicapped child has been one of the first classes of children's cases to be provided for in institutions and the last to receive any other type of care. There is not a single Child Guidance clinic in operation in the State. In 1920 the Children's Code Commission recom - mended an Institute of Juvenile Research to operate under the Board of Control, but such an agency was never undertaken. Mentally handi - capped children are not included in the Crippled Children's program. The only care provided is the Institution for the Feeble-minded, at Beatrice. The school census report made to the Bureau lists 381 mentally defective children, but this is not an accurate figure; the actual number is much higher. For certain cases coming to the attention of the Bureau and par - ticularly needing psychological examination the Psychology Department of the University of Nebraska has cooperated with the Bureau. A few cases have been examined and treated by private psychiatrists. Seven hundred and fifty dollars has been set aside by the Bureau for psycho - logical and psychiatric examinations and treatment, but this amount does not begin to meet the need. Children should never be committed to insti - tutions because of behavior or indications of feeblemindedness without the opportunity for mental and physical examination. Probably one of the most acute needs in the field of public welfare in Nebraska is the need for a mental hygiene program, since Social Security legislation has pro - vided for public health, child welfare, crippled children, old age, blind, and relief needs. The following case cited in the Nebraska Survey of Social Resources illustrates the need for mental examination and extension of planned treatment for this class of children : "Marian, an .eight-year-old girl, was one of a family of five children. At the time that she came to the attention of a social agency, one brother </seg>
            <seg id="p069">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE had already been placed in the state institution for feebleminded. The other children apparently presented no particular problems. The mother of the family was a neurotic and emotionally unstable person, although she appeared to have a fairly good mentality. She was most anxious to have the child institutionalized. The father was unstable, abusive to his family, and erratic in his work habits. There was some history of insanity and general instability in the relatives of both the mother and father. Marian was reported to be presenting very decided behavior problems, which, considering her home environment, was not at all strange. Five physicians had observed this child while she was under care in a local hospital, and it was the opinion of all that she should be committed to the State institution for the feebleminded. The worker from the social agency which came into contact with the case immediately after the commitment had been decided upon, quite naturally contacted the school and was told that the girl was doing satisfactory school work and appeared to be very bright. Arrangements were made for an examination by a trained psychologist and the child was found to have an I. Q. of 106. The committing judge, who had never seen the child, finally agreed that perhaps a mistake had been made. A boarding home was found and psychiatric care provided. The behavior problems, which were serious, have needed intensive treatment, but during the last 18 months the child seems to have shown steady improvement. By means of an adequate mental test, ' the case work treatment, Marian escaped the experiences of a life in the institution for the feebleminded, and the State was saved the expense of her maintenance, perhaps over a period of years. A case from the files of the Bureau is cited: A two-year-old boy suffering from malnutrition, rickets, and gen - eral neglect had been placed in a hospital by County authorities. He was retarded in every respect and it was thought that perhaps he was mentally deficient. Six weeks' hospital treatment made a great change in him, and he became the pet of the nurses and was of interest to visitors of other patients. As there was no longer need of hospitalization, the expense of such care was too great for the County to continue. The child still could not speak, nor had regular habits beep established, but his improvement had been so great it was felt that his mind would develop normally if properly stimulated. Institutional care was the solution, according to the County au - thorities, when the case was referred to the Child Welfare worker. As the child so definitely needed individual care, a suitable boarding home was found. The County Commissioners were persuaded to permit the case worker fo place the child in the home temporarily after it was proven to them that the expense would be no greater to them than it would be if he were placed in an institution. The child has made such great progress both mentally and physically that recently the Commissioners voted to leave him there indefinitely under the supervision of the case worker. PHYSICALLY DEFECTIVE CHILD Children in this class are reasonably well cared for. The schools for the deaf and blind provide specialized schooling; in January, 1935, 204 were receiving instruction at the Nebraska School for the Deaf and 59 at the School for the Blind. At the Hospital for the Tuberculous, in the biennium ending June, 1935, 18 children under 18 years of age were admitted for treatment. The Orthopedic Hospital cared for an average of 95 children each month in the same two-year period. The </seg>
            <seg id="p070">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU State Child Welfare Bureau's Crippled Children program can care for about 500 children annually. Many Nebraska children are crippled by accident; the activities of the Safety Council should result in a decrease in the number of children crippled annually by accident. Children over 16 may be given instruction by the Department of Vocational Rehabilita - tion which received an increased appropriation for service at the most recent session of the legislature. The 1936 School Census report to the Bureau gives the following number of physically handicapped children: Crippled Children 582 Deaf 146 Deaf and Dumb 37 Speech Defects 26 This report is incomplete, however, and cannot be taken to be a true picture of the situation. For example, there are 1,800 crippled chil - dren known to the Bureau, and only 582 appear in the school census report. CHILDREN OF, UNMARRIED PARENTS* The Bureau of Vital Statistics reported 438 children born out of wedlock during 1935. Plainly there were many not so reported to that department. This is because, in part, many birth registrations do not show this status even though it exists. Under the State Child Welfare Bureau a definite program for case work service to the unmarried mother and her child is being built up with the aim of giving the child born out of wedlock equal opportunity with the child of married parents. The only other agencies offering similar services are the private child welfare and family welfare agencies whose scope is definitely limited. Besides giving this case work serivce, the Bureau licenses and inspects maternity homes and lying-in hospitals, maternity boarding homes, child-placing agencies, and develops child-placing standards and standards for adop - tions. The State is responsible for control of this problem, and the Bureau is working toward the fulfillment of this responsibility. The Nebraska law places sufficient control in the hands of the Bureau to accomplish this goal effectively. Under both the Mothers' Pension and the Aid to Dependent Children programs the unmarried mother has the same opportunity to obtain aid as a married mother. The Nebraska Assistance law states that County Child Welfare Boards shall: 8 "As to children born out of wedlock: (a) Provide for a child born out of wedlock and his mother as for any other person in need of public relief and care, (b) Institute proceedings to establish paternity and secure the support and education of such child or make a compromise with the father of the child, in accordance with provisions of law, relating to children born out of wedlock, (c) Hold the money received from such compromise or pay it to the mother if she gives security for the support 7 For further information, see Nebraska Survey of Social Resources. Session Laws, 1935, H. R. 19, Sec. 6. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">PROBLEMS OF CHILD WELFARE of the child, (d) Care for such child with his mother in her own home or in a family free or boarding home or institution, and, when practicable, require the mother to contribute to the support of the child." The following brief review of a case in the State Child Welfare Bureau files illustrates the work being done with these cases: "Mary S. with her third child, all three born out of wedlock, was ready for release from the Women's Reformatory, when the case was referred to the Bureau for follow-up treatment. Mary's two older chil - dren had been taken from her and placed in adoptive homes. The mother was determined to keep Jimmie and feared he too would be taken from her. "Using her attachment for her baby to develop responsibility, Mary and the child welfare worker found a foster home where she might stay, pending receipt of Aid to Dependent Children. The Bureau financed a month's boarding care until the aid money was available. Mary receives $18.00 monthly, which is the maximum allowance for one child under Aid to Dependent Children, and she pays for the remainder of her ex - penses by working for the foster mother." ******** CHILD LABOR The State Child Welfare Bureau is not charged with the administra - tion of the laws relating to Child Labor; however, it takes~every oppor - tunity to cooperate with the Department of Labor, whose duties include the enforcement of these laws, and to further the cause of reduction of child labor. Nebraska has not ratified the child labor amendment. In November. 1936, twenty-four states have ratified the amendment, leaving twelve more needed before the amendment is effective. For a recent discussion on child labor problems in the Nebraska beet fields, see The American Child, September, 1936, Vol. XVIII, No. 6. CHILD-PLACING AND ADOPTIONS In the State at this time there are 19 private organizations engaged in child-care for normal children, either in natural homes, foster homes, boarding homes, or institutions, and 13 are licensed child-placing agencies. Licenses are granted to only those agencies meeting certain require - ments and coming up to certain standards. The Bureau itself does not place children. The two cases cited below from the Bureau files indicate the need for investigation of foster homes and supervision of placements: A very good example of what happens when a child is placed without proper investigation is the story of a boy who ran away from the Home for Dependent Children and returned to the county from which he had been sent originally. All his family except two sisters were in some institution, and he had no place to go. When he returned, therefore, he was placed in jail. A kindly family offered to take him into their home, so, without further investigation, he was sent there. When a worker was placed on the case, it was soon discovered that the boy was in the home of a man who harbored criminals escaping from justice. It was a more difficult task to have him removed from the home than it would have been to keep him out in the first place. On the surface the home seemed a perfectly safe place for the boy to be until other plans could </seg>
            <seg id="p072">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU be made for him; but it was in reality a dangerous place for a boy who « d £ m K f £ m I !»&lt;*Bronnd in which the father was in the penitentiary and the brother had already begun a life of crime. «=»"»ry * •''■■* *. ♦ • * * *h v R Ol i°^ ng re - pe^ ed reports of mistreatment of eight-year-old Doro - thy B., an investigation was made. Dorothy was placed in the G. foster i» me % her .™ ente »y deficient father. The foster mother whipped hir frequently with a buggy-whip and otherwise mistreated her. Mrs. G. would not cooperate in adjusting the situation When Mr SntSrt ?l im h . iS *™ ehter &gt; Mrs - G - ref " sed to let him S ee Dorothy SSottv B fS l m tv^"l the p ext « nt *£ he u was very anxious to removl +w w r?^J-i ; ? m ?' B . esldes othe r objectionable points, the fact M^* G&gt; dld not^eve in High School made it appear that removal from this home would be of benefit to the child. oV»lH C »nH e M en £ y ' Whe S f • s « ! . ond cousln stated her desire to adopt the S' ?1 * B / a ? reed t i thls J P roced «re, a thorough investigation was made of the foster home offered by the cousin, and adoption papers were fcw be t C0 ™P leted ? fc the end of a six-months" triaf period! Dorothy is fitting into her new home without any difficulty and her new parents are very happy to have her with them. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">VII. Special Activities Research and Projects The State Child Welfare Bureau has endeavored to sponsor worth - while projects and to do some research on specialized subjects. Social agencies have long recognized the value of research; it is felt that there is tremendous value in the collection of statistics for self-analysis and future planning. A governmental agency such as the State Child Welfare Bureau, pioneering in new fields, has great responsibility for evaluating and interpreting the work it is doing. Especially during the formative and experimental period of public welfare development must the administering agencies keep close check on what they are doing, what the results are, and where these things are leading. Only in this way can the agencies and the people whom they are organized to serve be sure they are actually accomplishing their purpose of increasing the condition of well-being. These accurate studies offer the taxpayer tangible proof that he is getting the services he pays for. All studies and collections of statistics will be available to the legislature for its use. This report is lacking in statistical information, because the organi - zation work involved in setting up the new program has absorbed so much time that statistics, for the most part, have been gathered only in the past few months and are not yet complete enough to indicate sig - nificant trends. However, in certain fields, noteworthy accomplishments within the past year are available for summary. SURVEY OF NEBRASKA SOCIAL RESOURCES j One of the most remarkable and valuable contributions to child wel - fare and public welfare generally in Nebraska has been this study and survey suggested by the State Conference for Social Work, sponsored by the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau, a 700-page volume representing an expenditure of $66,913.00 in W. P. A. funds and six months' work by a staff of trained and experienced people supervising work relief labor. Every phase of public welfare has been touched in this study. An advisory committee of representative lay and professional people has been meeting several times a month for a year planning, studying, evaluating this material. Coordination and cooperation between welfare agencies has been accomplished to an extent unknown before in the State. Many indicated recommendations have been made, and many others are being made as a result of the survey. A very limited number of mimeographed copies is available without charge. Better welfare laws and better administration can be expected as a result of this extensive study and survey. STATEWIDE RECREATION PROJECT* Through the use of W. P. A. funds a statewide project for recreation iFrom a report of one of the District Child Welfare Consultants: "Everyone contacted mentioned the amount of sex delinquency in this 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU was sponsored by the Bureau with recreation set-ups established in 24 communities in the State. Play for children is accepted as a means of education and growth, and these play groups, supervised playgrounds, and arts and crafts groups made possible in the rural areas have been of great service in preventing delinquency and providing normal and healthful outlets for youth. The value of groups in meeting child wel - fare problems has been stressed by welfare authoi-ities, and this value has been demonstrated through this project in Nebraska. In many instances Juvenile Judges and the District Child Welfare Consultants helped boys and girls with serious delinquent tendencies to become par - ticipants in recreation groups with excellent results. In many communi - ties these recreation projects were the only resource for group activity for young people. STUDY OF MOTHERS' PENSIONS AND AID TO DEPENDENT CHILDREN ADMINISTRATION The Bureau has collected much data on the administration of Mothers' Pensions in the counties, and this data is being studied in the light of statistics and information available on Aid to Dependent Chil - dren administration. Some of this material has been presented in this report in Section VI under "The Dependent Child." The compilation of the material will be published about January first. This study will be helpful to the legislature in planning future legislation in the Mothers' Aid and Aid to Dependent Children fields. It makes an excellent com - parison of the effectiveness of an aid program administered locally with - out guidance from the State and an aid program administered locally with State supervision. COOPERATION WITH THE BOARD OF CONTROL The staff of the State Child Welfare Bureau is now giving case work service to the Board of Control. The Board has referred special children's cases, and these have been handled by the Bureau staff. In some of these cases homes have been found for wards of the State, and supervision has been given to children and young people released from State institutions. The Board of Control has been cooperating with the Bureau on unmarried mother cases, temporary boarding care, and helping to make plans for suitable institutional care in special cases. county. One-third of the county population is Polish. Many Americans are very poor and seem to have deteriorated in their standard, of living. As the children stop school, they are unable to find work and return home. There is_ no activity for them. The barn dance near gathers those without resources. Drinking and sex delinquency at this dance is 'disgraceful.' The County Agent has offered the regular activities for the farmers and has recently offered 4-H club work. This does not, however, include the older adolescent and younger children. The County Attorney and the County Judge are very much concerned. They have been wanting to give a course in sex education. Arrangements were made to have a local physician give such a course. Several citizens were interested in urging a recreation project for the 'in between group' not reached by other group activities.'' </seg>
            <seg id="p075">VIII. Information and Interpretation Activities and Responsibilities The State Child Welfare Bureau is the State agency to which is delegated by law the responsibility for the promotion of activities for the protection of children and for interpretation of child welfare needs. To further enlist public opinion in favor of social legislation and to influence individual attitudes in regard to child welfare are specific tasks in the promotion of child welfare. As is often remarked by leaders in government and social work, "You can go no faster and no farther than the people as a whole understand and approve." The welfare departments of government are probably the most variable, the most intangible, and the most difficult to understand, and are therefore misunderstood by the general public. One of the greatest difficulties an administrator of public welfare has to meet is the fact that the citizenship of the state at large is not sufficiently informed as to what the State's needs really are and what the social significance of the welfare activity is. • It is with these things in mind that the Bureau has accepted responsibilities in this field. A number of bulletins of instructions and information have been prepared and mailed to county officials. News letters have been sent to physicians, judges, county superintendents, and county welfare officials. Almost monthly news releases to all newspapers in the State have been made. A pamphlet on Actual Case Stories has been prepared. Study group outlines have been mailed out on request to various club and study groups. During the past year talks have been given before groups by the Director and members of the staff. The Director or a member of the administrative staff has attended various meetings on child welfare, in many instances at private expense. These meetings include those of the Child Welfare League of America, National Conference for Social Work, meetings held by the U. S. Chil - dren's Bureau in Washington, National Probation Association meetings, and State Conferences for Social Work. The Director and members of the Staff are active in community, State, and National welfare groups. Executive offices are held by staff members in the State Conference for Social Work and the Nebraska Chap - ter of the American Association for Social Workers. Staff memberships are held in the State Conference for Social Work, National Conference for Social Work, the Lincoln Social Service Club, American Public Wel - fare Association, the National Probation Association, the Child Welfare League, the State Child Labor Committee, the Council of State Govern - ments, and other professional organizations concerned with public and child welfare. 67 </seg>
            <seg id="p076"/>
            <seg id="p077">IX. The County Organization 1 , Unit for Child Welfare County organization for child welfare means efforts directed toward bringing together the work being undertaken in the county for the care and protection of dependent, neglected, delinquent, physically handi - capped, and mentally defective children. In Nebraska the administrative unit has been the county except in a few instances in which it has been the township. The township is too small. The county is the most practicable unit for child care and welfare generally. The State Child Welfare Bureau has made every effort to assist the county officials in developing their communities to the fullest extent for the improvement of conditions causing dependency, delinquency, and other maladjust - ments. In most Nebraska counties the County Commissioners have their own private business enterprises and devote only part of their time to County duties. The County's need for social service requires full time and is most effectively economically met when centered in one individual. Legislative trend has been toward the establishment of county welfare officials to fill this need. The Bureau recognizes that knowledge and training in social problems becomes increasingly effective with famili - arity with the community. The district consultants and other members of the staff have cooperated with the county workers, and with this pro - fessional guidance the local people, many of whom were previously unfamiliar with child welfare, have been able to do highly creditable work in this field. The Nebraska Children's Code Commission's report of its study on child welfare in 1920 gives as one recommendation the creation of county Boards of Child Welfare and the appointment of county superintendents of child welfare in every county, suggesting further that it "will combine the work of juvenile probation officers, investigators for mothers' pen - sions, and investigators on behalf of the State of all divorce cases in which the welfare of children is involved. County superintendents of child welfare may act as school attendance officers and enforce the child labor laws. The Board will serve also as a bureau for coordinating the work of all private welfare organizations and act as the representative of the State Child Welfare Bureau in all counties in the State." NEBRASKA'S NEED Welfare problems are a major business of county as well as State officials. In 1935, $15,835,065.10 was spent in the counties in Nebraska for relief activities alone. This is a per capita cost of $11.49 per year. iThe County as an Administrative Unit for Social Work, by Mary Ruth Colby, U. S. Children's Bureau publication, 1933. 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU On the basis of the Board of Control report for the biennium ending June 30, 1935, the annual expense of maintaining the State Institutions was $2,190,403.83 or a per capita cost of $1.58 per year. Per capita cost of institutional care and out-door relief is $13.07 per year, not including funds spent by private charities, the Works Progress Administration, or Rural Resettlement Administration. During 1936 the cost will be about the same figure, because, although federal funds have been with - drawn for relief, the State and Federal Social Security program is carry - ing a large portion of the relief load. With these vast sums of money being spent and the number of human lives being touched the matter of welfare is serious. Child wel - fare is of particularly serious concern, because dependency in adults may in many instances be prevented by proper care and protection of children. In adult delinquents very often the root of the real causal' factor dates back to early childhood. The treatment of these problems is not a hit-and-miss, trial-and-error task, but a task for a person with knowledge of these problems and experience in handling them, and should be closely supervised. Problem cases should be discovered early and treatment and preventive measures wisely applied. A COUNTY WELFARE BOARDS A County Child Welfare Board, or Public Welfare Board, is the most effective form of county organization for child welfare and welfare, generally. This Board can coordinate the several types of welfare services and carry out the other functions of study and formulation of plans for prevention of causes of dependency. It provides for active participation of philanthropic citizens, provides representative action, establishes con - tinuity of planning and policy-making, and lifts welfare work out of the realm of vagaries and prejudices. It gives an understanding and un - selfish administration. The State Child Welfare Bureau has urged local communities to establish citizens' advisory or planning groups. In October, 1936, thirteen counties had established such groups to plan with the County Boards. Some of these groups are concerned only with child welfare, others with all welfare problems. Several discuss and plan for Mothers' Pensions, probation, and school attendance. The School and Public Health agencies should be represented on the Board and are in most counties having such Boards. The trend over the United States is to develop public welfare boards assigned all the duties of welfare for their respective counties. NEBRASKA COUNTY PUBLIC WELFARE BOARD LAW The 1931 session of the Nebraska Legislature passed the County Unit Law. It provides that a County Board may create by resolution a 2By a County Child Welfare Board or a Public Welfare Board is meant: a group of non-partisan, non-paid citizens interested in the com - munity's welfare, which serves in an advisory capacity to the County Board of Commissioners. This Board should have the power to appoint the welfare worker or director, but not to assume administrative duties. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">THE COUNTY ORGANIZATION County Board of Public Welfare. A copy of this resolution should go to the Director of the State Child Welfare Bureau. The County Board •with the County Judge appoints five persons serving three years and with overlapping terms. If a secretary is appointed, he must be a person qualified by training and experience to handle the problems of public welfare. This worker may, when requested by proper authorities, act as juvenile probation officer and supervisor of Mothers' Pensions, in - vestigate for the court divorce cases involving children, and act as school attendance officer, thus carrying out the suggestions of the Children's Code Commission. COUNTY ASSISTANCE COMMITTEE DESIGNATED COUNTY CHILD WELFARE BOARDS The Nebraska Assistance Act shows recognition of these principles of county organization for child welfare and the State Child Welfare Bureau has made every effort to administer this law to bring about the fullest development of the responsibility placed on the County Child Welfare Board. The law requires that, if a County Public Welfare Board be created, it becomes a part of the County Child Welfare Board. This law does not, however, make possible the functioning of a County Public Welfare Board as outlined in the permissive public welfare board law and as suggested above. The County Child Welfare Board is an . administering body, and when the members of the County Public Wel - fare Board are added to it, if one be established, it virtually destroys the County Public Welfare Board as it no longer remains a separate body, nor does it have equal financial authority with County Board members, but constitutes the combined County Child Welfare Board. Ideally, the most effective county organization is a County Public Wel - fare Board as described in the permissive law set up as a separate organi - zation and responsible for the general supervision and administrative policy for assistance and welfare services in the county, the county Director to be appointed by the Board" and to be responsible for its administrative functions. The appointive board should be an advisory or planning body. For this reason the Bureau has placed emphasis on the appointment of a citizens' planning group with overlapping terms rather than the public welfare board under the permissive law. The Nebraska Assistance Act '•Special Session Laws, 1935, H. R. 19, Sec. 2: "The County Assist - ance Committee of each County in the State of Nebraska is hereby designated as the County Child Welfare Board, hereinafter called the Board. . . ." H. R. 3, Sec. 10: "The Board of county commissioners or supervisors, as the case may be, county treasurer and the county board of public welfare, if now or hereafter lawfully in existence in each respective county of the State of Nebraska, are hereby designated as the County Assistance Committee of each respective county." °In a general way this same set-up is recommended and finding favor in the states following such a plan for the state administration as well as for the local units. See: Suggested State Legislation for Social Se - curity, American Public Welfare Publication. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">NEBRASKA STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU makes the County Child Welfare Board responsible for social service for special classes of children's cases, outlining specifically social case work duties: family circumstances are to be investigated and care, supervision, and treatment to be given. Physical and mental examina - tions are provided for. The Board is to supervise home placements made by the county. Probation is not mentioned, nor is school attendance, except to say that the Board should meet once a month and coordinate and cooperate with all local welfare organizations, groups, and indi - viduals, public and private. Although it is recognized that child and general welfare work de - mand a full-time employee in almost every county, material gathered by the Bureau indicates tfyat seven counties do not have full-time people, in several others the workers are paid by the day although apparently putting in full time, and in a few instances the county workers are paid a percentage of funds handled. One county pays the local worker by the application. Many of the county workers are without any preparation for welfare work. Salaries generally are inadequate for the amount and nature of work required by the law. A number of workers are paid less than $50 per month, and very few receive more than $100 a month. Several are paid 3% of the funds handled. Mileage allowance is made in only a few counties. In only seven counties is case work service available. Only a few counties have a coordinated county welfare program. It is a policy of the Bureau not to accept case work responsibility for cases until requested by local officials, for case work with individuals is conceived by the Bureau as a local function. In counties which have sufficient child welfare problems to justify having a worker for these problems alone, the Bureau concentrates its efforts on developing com - munity interest and interpreting the need for having this worker. In counties which have a qualified worker the Bureau accepts case work responsibility for a selected few cases and gives more time to advising with the local worker; Even if it were practicable for the State to assume responsibility for the local cases, the State staff would need to be in - creased many times to render adequate case work service. Emphasis is placed on working out the most serious cases and on developing local organization and resources to handle the others. In some of the counties with very small population it would be advantageous to employ jointly one person for a group of counties. Compiled by HARRY J. BECKER December, 1936 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>