<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE State Veterinarian of Nebraska FOR YEARS 1911-1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE State Veterinarian of Nebraska FOR YEARS 191W912 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Lincoln, Nebr. II have the honor of transmitting to you and the Legislature biennial report as Deputy State Veterinarian for the period nning January 10, 1911. and ending December 10, 1!)12. During this period this department has made an effort to render the best service possible under the present eircunistai I fully realize that during this period the people of this state have suffered a greater loss of horses than ever before in the same length of time. This perhaps is also true in geard to hogs. With cattle we have been more fortunate and I believe that the loss of cattle during this period has been less than usual. Sheep are not Mind to any great extent in this state, but quite a number are shipped in from other states west and northwest of us for feeding purposes. No great loss of sheep has been reported and as far as I know they have been free from serious diseases; only a few i of scabies have been reported. In this report you will find the details and summary of the most important work done during this period. Glanders This is a specific contagiojis and infectious disease affect - ing horses and mules, and is sometimes transmitted to man. by inoculation into wounds or abrasions of the skin, in handling such animals. This -disease has been quite prevalent in this state for several years, especially in the northrrn part. It is caused by a germ known as the bacillus Mallei. This germ is found in the lesions wherever they may be located and in the discharges and excretions from the animal. This germ is killed when directly exposed to the sun and to hot. dry winds for three or four days. It lives in water at ordinary temperature for about twenty-five days. In stables and manure piles this germ m iv live for five or six monuis. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p004">4 I This germ is the direct cause of the disease and without it iiiimal could be affected with glanders. There may be pre- Miaf or accessory causes such as other diseases, hard work. fficient food, impure water and general neglect ; but the eoiu - i and quite popular belief that distemper, strangles, influenza catarrh runs into glanders is erroneous. These diseases are &gt;ed by other germs, and these organisms do not change their as. structure and habits, but each individual is under the MM which governs the higher organization in both the animal and vegetable kingdom. KThis disease is generally contracted by partaking of food or r soiled by the glanderous discharges from another horse or ■. by direct inoculation, and by coining in contact with an af - ■d animal or contaminated bridles, harness, blankets, etc. I Glanders may appear in various forms, such as glanders of lymphatics of the nose, of the lungs, of the bowels, or of the i, and the symptoms would vary accordingly. Again, any of forms may appear in either acute or chronic form; the symp - s in the latter form may hardly be discernible while in the e form they are easily detected. It is my opinion that the diagnosis of glanders from the phys - ical symptoms alone cannot always lie made, even by those who have had ample training and experience. In such cases we resort to certain methods of testing for glanders. These tests are known as the complement fixation and the agglutination tests, which are made in the laboratory on a sample of Mood taken from the ani - mal, and the mallein test, which is m ide by injecting a product obtained from cultures of the glander germ upon potatoes, and is known as mallein. Other methods of testing horses for glander - have been used, but at all the various methods the complement fixation tests seem to be the most reliable. I So far as we know now there is no cure for this disease. As ■eventive. a certain vaccine has been used, but it is as yet in experimental stage and its efficiency is uncertain. The only itical method in dealing with glanders is to destroy all affected lals as soon as a positive diagnosis is made and a proper dis - il of the carcass by either complete burning or burying under :ast four feet of dirt with a barrel of lime scattered over the aas in the grave before filling up with dirt. A thorough disin- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 feetion of the barn, feed racks, yards, water tanks, bridles, har - ness, blankets, etc.. should always be made M soon as possible after the disposal of the animal. I During this period. Jan. 10, 1911. to Dec. 10, 1912, we de - red 210 horses, mules and cults on account of being affected glanders; 167 of these have been paid for according to law 37 have been killed without indemnity to the owners, of which rere killed before the appropriation became available, 9 bad I n in tin 1 state one year, and .'{ were Ism than one year old. claims of indemnity are still pending. In doubtful cases and where physical lesions were not suffi - ciently developed for a positive diagnosis we have used the mullein test and in addition to that we lure taken blood samples from those which reacted to the mallein test. The blood samples ■ sent to the Pathological Department of the Rureau of Animal In - dustry. Washington, D. C. where they were driven the complement fixation and the agglutination tests under the direction of Dr. J. K. Mohler. Chief of that Department. One hundred and seveir samples have been tested for us, of which 44 gave a positive reac - tion. All of those that gave positive reaction have been killed !&gt;t 2. which are held under &lt;|inrantine. while those giving .tive reaction were released from quarantine. The comple - ment fixation test is. in my opinion, a very reliable test. KThe following is a detailed report of animals destroyed on unt of being affected with glanders without indemnity, prior ily 7. 1911. or before the appropriation became available: No.De- Destroved By Date Owner's Name Address st- Dr. A. Bostrom Jan. 25, 1911 Logan Lambert winne- bago i Hank Pinn Hebron Carl Lund Genoa J. B. Gallaher Harting- Tan. 31, 1911 Apr. is. 1*11 Apr. SO, 1911 ton ? ■H. T. Hahnof ills City Feb. 9. 1911 Apr. :.». 1911 Camping Outfit ! Weslev Schafer Palls'cit'y ■C. A. McKim of -&gt;rfolk E. E. Huffman Duff Apr. Id. l'.m Apr. 19. I'M I 1 F. I. Lake Ains- 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 IThe following is a detailed report of all animals destroyed on »unt of heinp affected with |l9il&gt;H that were paid for Me rd - to law since .Inly 7. 1911 : Destroyed By Date Owner's Name Address \" De- Dr. A .T. Norman of Chadron Apr. :t, 1911 C. S. King Harden, Mont. l Dr. H.C. Colletteof Oxford Dr. A. \V. Sprague of Crawford Dr. P. L. Cady of Fremont Dr. L. Walker of Deiatur Dr. P. Simonson of Lexington June 3, 1911 Lee Hicks Stamford 1 Feb. l.*&gt;. 1911 Not known Glen... 1 Feb. 1.1. I'.Hl Not known 1 Apr. 9, Hill Ralph Redings Decatur 1 Mar. 4. 1911 Harvey Wallace Lexington 1 Mar. 24. 191 1 John Sladky Lexington Mar. 23, 1911 Ross Harris Lexington 1 Apr. 11, 1911 Chas. E.Orthman Lexington 1 IB. T. Baker of [itchell V. Schaefer of ekamah Rogers of lecatur I. J. Drasky of rete D. C. Scott of imaha ..June 'i. Itll E. A. Feathers Mitchell 1 Apr. tS, 1911 Frank Eaton Decatur I Apr. 2% 1911 Ralph Redings Decatur 1 Apr. J:&gt;. I'.Hl Mr. Rogers Decatur 1 Feb. :s. 1911 Not Icaowa ...... i Mar. j:». 1911 Not known I ' Total Address No. Be Amount stroyed , Received Date Owner's Name By Dr. A. Bostrom— 1 1 July 7. 1&lt;tll Wm. L'eke Scribner July 7. Kill Xelson Bros St. Edwards.. luly i:t. 11(11 J. B. Gallaher Hartington July IX 1911 Geo. H. Ducker Ft. Crook luly 13, 1'JllG. \V. Herron Ft. Crook .July 14. l'.MlJ. H. Perkins Rosalie July 14. 1911 Henry McBeth Rosalie July IS, 1911 Ed. White IViatur July 20. 1911 Hirsch-Hahn Cattle I Co. Irwin July ao. 1911 P. H. Wadill Irwin I * •i :&lt; 1 l 1 l </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE VETERINARIAN 7 No. De- Amount rtroyed Received Date Owner's Name Address July 21 I'.Ml E. A. Feather Mitchell Brownlee Mitchell . Mitchell Ravenna Avoca 2 » July 90 1911 L. O. Nelson 1 July 1911 B. H. Kemper 24, 9 160.00 July •J4. 1911 John W. Youngheim 1 90.00 July 26, 1911 Frank Cizek 1 1911 Henry Hunterman s. 1 1911 Fritz Spreen 1 2 Clarkson Lincoln 1 14 1911 J. A. Witters 1 100.00 Sept 13, 1911 l.irgen Knuth Grand Island Lincoln _ 1 1911 W. B. Miller 18, 1 I Oct 13, l!»ll C. F. Shiers Gibbon Genoa St. Paul 1 Oct. IS, 1911 Carl Lund 1 1911 E. Bly 19, 3 33, 1911 C. \V. Wallace Round Valley Lexington I 1911 F. W. Orthman &lt;&gt; Dec. 27, 1911 Tim Murphy Homer 1 1912 Jacob Carstens Aspinwall, Iowa Crooktton 1 so.OO I 1912 L. H. Overman 9. 7 1912 J. F. Morgan Tekamah Rosalie 13, I 23. 1912 Rov Underwood 9 2.i. 1912 Ed. White Decatur Wai thill Allen 1 1912 Albert Means 24, 1 1912 Mrs.C.Christopherson 26, 3 May 1 1912 B. J. Sheldon Walthill Omaha Schuyler Fern" 1 £ 1912 H. W. Butts 21 Mav 1912 John Casev 31 1 1912 Sam Henion 1 12, 1912 D. A. Melton Valentine Lvnch .T I 1 V 1912 Henrv Kortie 1 Julv 1912 C. R. Pettvcrew Harmony Lexington Lexington Decatur ... 9, 1 July 19, 1912 Edwin Orthman 1 1912 Edwin Orthman 3, 1 9, 1912 Ed. Miller ! 13, 1913 M. F. Edmiston Walthill I 1 1912 Tim Gravhair Winnebago Winnebago Homer ia 1 1912 Philip White 13, 1 26, 1912 Wm. Lake 1 12. 1912 Wm. Buckland Homer Homer 1 1912 Pete Peterson IS, 1 12, 1912 C. T. Hrabak Walthill 2 By Dr. C. A. McKim if Norfolk t28, 1911 Oscar Esterly M, mi i I. II. Moon M, 1!»11 I. H. Davisson 28. 1911 Dr. J. A. Meehan :tO. ltli Dr. I. A. Meehan 11, 1811 I. K. Ensley _ 2."&gt;. 1911 Mr-. K. McDonnld 17. Kill Prank Carlwalader .... 11. 1!H2 E. C. Hoag i2, Itlt'V. F. Talcott 2a 1911 Oscar Esterly Ainsworth 2 $ 110.00 Ainsworth 2 $ no.00 Julv 29, 191 1 I. II. Moore Long Pine 1 80.00 Long Pine 1 80.00 Julv 1911 I. H. Davisson Ainsworth 233.33 Ainsworth 29, 233.33 Ainsworth 2 183.32 2&amp; 1911 Dr. J. A. Meehan Ainsworth I 183.32 :m. 1911 Dr. I. A. Meehan Ainsworth 2 uo.98 Ainsworth 2 149.98 Aug. 31, 1911 1. R. Ensley _ Ainsworth Ainsworth Oct 2."&gt;. 1911 Mr-. K. McDonald Valentine l Valentine 1 1911 Frank Cadwalader Stuart 1 46.66 Stuart 1" 1 MLM 1912 E. C. Hoag Orchard Orchard .. 1 83.33 II 1 83J3 Jan. -&gt;2, 1912 V. F. Talcott ...i Crofton 2 176.64 Crofton 2 176.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BIENNIAL REPORT Date Owner's Xame Add] No. De- Amount stroyed Received Apr. lh. KM-: T. M. Davis Duff B. Overman Crooksti ■i. HH2 L. H. Overman Crookaton . Mav -I. 1012 A. E. Green Crookston u. 1(112 Otto Knittel Butte lune IK. 1012 J. M. Davis [),,,. Tulv 2H. 1012Gus Gunderson Co.lv Aug. 'p. KH2 T. G. North Stuart Aug. 14. 1012 Roy Johnson Basaett :.. KH2 (has. Viquest R a v Od 2.i. 1012 C. O'fnnniT Randolph f 1 IIT.N BBy Dr. J. D. Sprague of David City- -. ar Steineman Lexington -i ar Steineman Lexington 1012 A. E. Bagley Allen 1012 G. E. Kennedv Genoa 1912 Henry Kortie Lynch 1912 Clyde Walker M a . v 1012 Henry Bliven Homer 1012 C. B. Dorfmeyer Allen 1012 Henry Kortjr Lynch 1012 D. A. Melton Valentine 1012 E. V. Woodhull Macy 1912 las. H. Perkins Walthill 1012 C. A. Hammond Lvmh 1012 Wm. Buckland Homer 1 . By Dr. J. S. Vinnedge of Ord Dei. 1. Kill F. Blv l.i. inn Wm. Dunn 2.1. 1412 Lee Blv ifi, Hil2 T. A. OW- 1! St. Pa Purdum Schaupps Purdum 1 $ 1 o 2 By Dr. W.P. Kellenbarger of Merna - 27. 1!il2 Nick Lee Tuly 10. 1012 K. F. Kime Tulv 24. 1012 E. C. McKinley Lewanna Fern Senneoa 1 $ 1 By Dr. P. Simonson of Lexington 23, 1912 John Sladkv Aug. 2(1. 1012 A. R. Havden IS. l'.H2 A. W. Bellamv Lexington Lexington Lexington 1 $ l l By Dr. F. L. Ree&lt;i of Codv ■ Tuly 15, 1912 Rav \V. Barnes Tuly 30. 1012 Tohn H. Bush Aug. I. 1012 T. H. Tack Aug. 3, 1012 A. J. Barnes ... Cod Valentine ly Iv ! * </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE VETERINARIAN 9 No. De- Amount Date Owner's Name Address stroyed Received 1911 S. E. Rosseter 1912 I. Bradshaw .. Aug. 26, Cody Codv : • ss By Dr. V. Schaefer of Tekamah feS litll John Daggot 1911 Tim Murphy Rosalie Homer 2 $ 233.33 1 13.-t.33 » Bv Dr. J. A. DeCow of Holdrege Oct in. Kill T. II. Bouser Bertrand 2 $ 133.33 By Dr. W. H. Tuck Weeping Wate* ' 1912 Fritz Bon hers Berlin 1 $ 67.33 Bv Dr. H. L. Prouse of Allen julv 8. July M. Oct. U, 1U12 C. B. Dorfmeyer l'.iU' C. B. Dorfmeyer 1912 John MeNeil .. 1912 John MeN'eil Allen Allen Lynch Lynch 1 60.00 I -'(UK) 1 83.33 MOV. 14 Bv Dr. A. A. Anderson c if (irand Island 1912 R. P. Cruitt 1912 R. F. Cruitt Kearney Kearnev * 209.99 Max s. 1 133.33 By Dr. J. C. Myers of Butte Nov. in. Hill Barnev PutthoiT Butte 1 $ 66.M By F. A. Bernard of Chambers Chambers Total numtier destroyed and p«id| for ■ Six claims of indemnity are still pending for lack of proof horses hive been in this state one year prior to date of killing. The following 12 animals were destroyed since July 7. 1911. tint could nut lie paid for according to law. as they were either in the state less than one year prior to the date of killing or they were less than one vear old: \&lt;M\i Sam Earl 1 * 16.33 167' $13,416.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BIENNIAL REPORT Destroyed By Date Owner's Name Address stroyed Dr. A. Bostrom July 13, 1911 J J. \V. Herron Ed. Pilgrim Ft. Crook 1 Homer .... 1 Jan. 6. 1912 1 Apr. 9, 1912 L, H. Overman. D. MeCowen R. Pettverew. iCrookston 3 (Wayside 1 June 11. 19!? C. 1 June 12, I9IMC. I Harmony 1 Dr. J. D. Sprague of David City May U, l'.HV IL. L. Million Valentine Dr. F. L. Reed of B. O. Goodrirh Merriman 1 Cody May M, 1-.H2 Dr. P. Simonson of Lexington Aug. 21, 1911 Wm. Faggot- did not claim the money Lexington 1 1 Reports of suspected glanders at the following places investi - .1 and no (jrlandi-rs found, lint some other disease or BO di^ 1 as indicated below: Owner's Name Address Condition Found Date By Dr. Bostrom — Jan. 26, 1911 S. E. Morgan Feb. 27, lyllC. F. Buchholz Mar. 27. Hill Fred Stichweh Winnebago Falls City Kenesaw No disease No disease Mycotic Lym- phangitis Apr. 24, 1911 A. H. Kroh Verdon and Falls Cit Falls City Mason City Wallace *24, 1911 Wesley Shaffer 13, 1911 A. J. Murish 17, IM1 H. C. Robbins May 2a. 1'JllT. F. Gilispie June 10, 1911 W. A. Ouart June 13, l in l Nels Anderson June IS, Itll Louis Krumweide June 13, 1911 Roy Wilse\ July 11, 1911 Thomas E. Doolittle July 28, 1911 Porter at Hotel July 30, 1911 Louis Dishaw ... .Aug. 1, 1911 Dr. J. S. Vinnedge Aug. 18. 1911 Mr. Hutton Sept. 8, 1911 Dr. Geo. BaxU Sept. 11, nil J. B. Roark Sept. IS, l'.illW. C. Starkey 'I. 1911 Dr. F. E. Rathbun Nov. 7. 1911 Dr. H. L. Feistner Nov. 16, 1911 J. A. Reed Dec. 11, 1911 D. C. Feldhoff .... Feb. IS, 1912 Jack Higgins ... Gretna Newport Hubbard Dakota Cit Hubbard Somerset Broken Bow Greeley Center Sargent Cedar Bluffs Alma Fullerton Diller Palisade Auburn Cedar Bluffs Dorchester Rogers No disease No disease Blood poisoning Ifycptac Lym- phangitis Catarrh Melanosis Mange Maxillary abscess Swamp fever Lymphangitis Lymphangitis Choking Lymphangitis Empyemia No disease Heaves Dead and buried Lymphangitis Pneumonia Empyemia Orchitis Lymphangitis </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE VETERINARIAN 11 Condition Found Date Owner's Name Address Mar. I-'. 1912 Pete Beckues Schuyler St. Paul- Western Purdum Lincoln Abscess Mar. is. KH2 Ely Bly No disease Mar. 22, 1(112 Dr. G. L. Cline Catarrh Mar. 84, 191* I. A. O'Neal No disease Mar. 85. 1&gt;.»12 Dr. Geo. Tucker Lymphangitis Mar. 2.1. 11M2 H. S. Wakefield Waterloo Catarrh Mav 7. IBIS Roy Underwood June 5. 1912*0. S. Lawrence.. Rosalie Halsey Old age Mvcotic Lym - phangitis June 14, 1012 Clan Dates Kilgore Genoa Dead Aug. 20. l'.M2 Jacob Nelson Mycotic Lym phangitis 22, 1&lt;J12 Gordon &amp; Tittering Hershey Lymphangitis By Dr. C. A. McKim of Norfolk- Sept. M, 1911 A. J. Fouts Stuart Chronic catarrh Long Pine j Sept. 27. 1(111 S. L. Eckert No disease Sept. 27. Kill I. H. Moore Long Pine. No disease Sept. 27, Kill ~H. W. Cudney Duff Carious tooth Sept. 28, 1911 G. H. Flegley I Norden Distemper Sept. 19, Kill F. M. Long Ainsworth Lymphangitis Catarrh Nov. B, Kill Lester Kert/ Horsefoot Nov. 17. 1911 C. B. Monroe Newport .Swamp fever Dec. 7. Kill Ivan Coulter... I Bassett Abscess Dec. 7. Kill W. Ravensdorff Bassett Catarrh Jan. 12. 1912 Chas. Dahl Valentine Dead n, 1912 A. J. Fouts Stuart Lymphangitis Apr. 21. 11(12 (). j. Booth Inman No disease June 21. 1!H2 Chris Nelson Tilden Lymphangitis Aug. 11. KH2 H. Gelligen I Stuart Lymphangitis AtiK. a, 11(12 J. G. Norths Stuart Chronic catarrh Aug. 14. 1(112 Frank Buell Duff Influenza Aug. 14. 1012 Mrs. Bertha Davis Duff Influenza Aug. IS, 1912 Jack Dunn Duff Strangles Aug. IS, 1012 Geo. Goodwell Duff Influenza Auk- IS, KH2 John A. Dugger Sybrant Injury Aug. 15, 1912 E. D. Beach Bassett Chronic catarrh Aug. 15, 1912 Edwin Davis. Duff Chronic catarrh Aug. Ifi. 1912 John Stickmyer O'Neil Lymphangitis (lit. 21, 11(12 Aug. Kochmeister Raven Lymphangitis By Dr. J. S. Vinnedge of Ora- Dec 6, 1911 W. F. Spencer Dec. 6, 1911 James Gray te reeley Center Empyemia Greeley Center Pharyngeal paralysis ti. 22, 1912 Wm. Dunn y 22, 1912 S. D. Richey Sargent Mycotic stomatitis Brewster Mycotic lym phangitis June 24. 1912 Ben Ackerman. July 12. 1(112 I. E. Meuret July 22. KU2 L. R. Hansberry. Loup City No disease Burwell Rosevale Ulcerated tooth Mycotic Lym- phangitis </seg>
            <seg id="p012">This i« a specific infectious disease affecting cattle and hoga and other animals and man. It is now generally recognised that this disease can be communicated from animals to man through dairy products, especially to infants raised on milk from the tubular cows. The cause of this disease is a germ known as tubercle bacillus. which generally attacks the lymph glands of the body primarily Condition Found Date Owner's Name Address By Dr. J. C. Myers. of Butte - Feb. 30, 1911 Wm. Hall Apr. 20, lyil P. J. Schoettger Apr. 28, 1911 Frank Briggs Lynch Enterprise .... Naper Ulerated tooth Catarrh Catarrh By Dr. J. D. Sprague.. I of David City §10, 1912 H. A. J. Schunnemann 12, iai2 Ed. Aronson 14, 191^ Mr. Wallace. Spencer Central City Round Valley Bad teeth Lymphangitis No disease By Dr. B.J. Baker _.. of Mitchell- Feb. 10, 1911 C. D. Brown- Sept. li, lyil L. Lackey _ Chappell Mitchell Lymphangitis Lymphangitis By Or. W.P. Kellenbarger ol Merna — July 20,1911 Not known is miles south of Merna _. Fern Nov. 20, 1912 D. T. Henion Old age No disease B&gt; Dr. J. A. DeCow.. of Holdrege- Mar. 18, 1912 Dr. Philipson... Holbrook No disease By Dr. F. L. Reed. of Cody- July 7, 1912 W. H. Wells...- Nov. l-t, 1912 H. Homar _ _.. Clinton Lake Lymphangitis Influenza By Dr. Walter Nichols... of Ravenna — 7, 1&lt;j12 Frank Cizek _. Ravenna .... Injury By Dr. \V. E. McBain of Minden-- S, 1912 Mose Rohlin Campbell , Lymphangitis </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE VETERINARIAN 13 PtiwiH ii of the body. The lymph glands most coin - are those of the neck, lungs, bowels and udders, n be recognized by physical examination only in of the disease. Jn its incipiency it can be det' erculin test. This test is very reliable when prop - interpreted by experienced men. KThe spread of this disease is due to germs in the discharge excretions from affected animals being scattered wherever animals are kept. Therefore it is quite common to tind hogs :ted with this disease in feed yards where they follow and on the excretia from tubercular cattle. The eradication of tuberculosis in animals is MM of the great problems which will have to be solved in the future. B During the period covered by this report the work done iu lection with tuberculosis in this state is as follows • B Individual tests: The tuberculin test has been applied to head of cattle at the request of individual owners. Of this ber 127 reacted, of which 42 have been killed and the balance under quarantine. Ki co-operation with the federal government, 4637 head of were tested at South Omaha, of which 268 reacted and were ed of according to government regulations. Scabies in Cattle, tThis is an infectious disease, caused by a skin parasite known soroptis bovis. This parasite if placed upon a smooth black ice can be seen with the naked eye as a small white moving k about one-fourth the size of the head of a pin, but a magni - l glass of low power is generally used to discover the mite, is commonly called. I About 8 years ago most of the cattle in the western half of state were badly affected with this disease, and therefore all lat part was placed under quarantine by the federal govern - t. An agreement was entered into by this state and the fed - government and certain rules and regulations were adopt-.-d jo-operation in the eradication of this disease by dipping all ;ted and exposed cattle. Eie federal government, through the Bureau of Animal In - at Washington, D. ('., of which Dr. A. D. Melvin is chief, ven this state a great, valuable, efficient and effective ser- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 BIENNIAL REPORT in co-operating with us in the efforts to stamp out this dis- § During the period covered l&gt;y this report we have practically icated this disease in 17 counties, and which have been re - d from quarantine, leaving only 12 counties and a fraetio* other counties remaining under quarantine in this state. KThe federal government has had several men stationed here his time at the expense of the government, and during t'.c ing season this state lias had I men employed at the SXp le state. Anthrax. Anthrax is an infectious disease affecting nearly all the f the domesticated animals, and is frequently transmitted la men in handling infected animals or their products, such as hides and hair. §lt is caused by a fam known as bacillus anthracis. which may r and cause infection of the animal, either by ingestion. bj illation, by inhalation or by transmission. I Cattle and sheep are most frequently affected, and next in ■r of susceptibility comes the horse, hog and dog. Our [ire - knowledge of the exact nature and cause of anthrax ffH de - pad largely by the researches of 1'ollender. Davainc. Koch. eur, Taussaint anil others. The literature on the cause, tissue :id prevention of anthrax has become very extensive. »The symptoms of this disease vary, but there is often a bloody large from the natural openings of the body, the animal and falls and may die in a few hours or may linger for days. Treatment of this disease is useless. When the disease breaks out in a herd of cattle the vaccination of all the apparently healthy animals should be resorted to at once with the anthrax ine prepared exclusively as a preventive against this di« All animals having died from anthrax should Ih- completely burned. During the period covered by this report we hue iiau two outbreaks of anthrax in this state, in which 2(1 head of cat tie were lost and -i head of horses. Two men became infected in skinning • carcass and handling the hide but both recovered. In these two outbreaks about 1000 head of cattle and horses were vaccinated and the disease promptly checked. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE VETERINARIAN 15 Blackleg in Young Cattle. This disease is being gradually stamped out through vaccina - tion. The government vaccine, distributed through the depart - ment of Animal Pathology of the Nebraska Kxperiment Station, is generally used. tit is well known that blackleg affects only young cattle, and ■ most frequently affected are from six to fifteen months old. rely affects cattle altove two years of age. tit is caused by a germ which usually enters the system ugh abrasions of 1he mouth or feet while on pasture. This 1 may live in the surface soil of pastures on infected farms lot ral years. Therefore it is advisable to vaccinate mi such in - nl farms all calves from three to four months old. One tion seems to produce lasting immunity, but calves vaccinated &gt;r six months old should be revaccinated when a year old. ■ There is no cure known for this disease. All affected animals within a few hours to two days. Hog Cholera. This is a contagious and infectious disease of the hog and no other domestic animal seems to contract the disease. During this period I have visited quite a number of outbreaks of clis hogs supposed to be cholera, and I have found th.it many of t cases have not been cholera, but some form of pneumonia of in - fectious nature, perhaps swine plague; others have shown upon post mortem examination lesions of both cholera and swine plague; and again others have shown plain lesions of cholera, but no lesions of any other disease. In those last named cases the anti-hog cholera serum seems to be very efficient as a preventive when properly applied to exposed hogs, but before they have contracted the disease. In cases of infectious pneumonia or swine plague and where there is a mixed infection the serum used does not seem to do much good. tDr. J. H. Gain of the Nebraska Kxperiment Station is manu - iring the serum as provided for by the last legislature, and is distributing the same, lie has also directed most of the work ■e serum has been used, and ho will no doubt issue i report lis subject in the near future. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Dourine. K Dourine is a specific infectious dpMM affecting, under nat - conditions, only the horse ami ass, transmitted from animal limal by the a&lt;-t of copulation, and due to an animal par. rotozoan known as trypanosma equiperdam. »In the United Static this dJMMC was tirst discovered in 1888 V. L. Williams at Hloomington. 111. The infection was traced I'ercheroii stallian imported from France in 1SM2. whicli had a brand mark under the mane very much resembling the letter "D." In 18'J2 Dourine was brought into public notice by the ap - pearance of an outbreak among the breeding horses of north - western Nebraska, the history of which suggested that it orig - inated from a stallion ■hipped from the infected territory ■ Illinois to Gordon, Nebr. An inspector of the Kureau of Animal Industry investigated the outbreak and found that upward of 100 mares and stallions were affected with the disease and it took - to stamp it out. An outbreak has recently i.June. 191 1) been located in Taylor County. Iowa, where four stallions found to be affected with the disease and five were expose, I to the same. One of the four stallions has since died with the in - fection. In addition to this five mares have shown symptoms of Dourine, one of which subsequently died from the disease, nine are suspicious eases anil ninety-four have been exposed. I This disease has been reported at Oakdale. Albion. Dorchester llershey. l'pon investigation one stallion was found affected this disease at Oakdal; . This stallion had been brought into •ask a from a community in Iowa where an out break of rine was discovered during the summer of 1911. anil after ging owners several times while in Nebraska this stallion finally located at Oakdale. where it was destroyed by order i the Federal Hureau at Washington. I). ('. The other three i reported a« suspected of being Dourine were also invest i d. but found to be free from this disease. Ulcerative Ano-vulvitis in Cattle This is a disease caused by a germ known as the Necrosis bacillus. The principal parts affected are the external parti the genito-urinary organs, where it appears in the form of blis- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE VETERINARIAN 17 fles or ulcers, and may extend &lt;|iiite deep into the muscular !8. It does not seem to cause any great amount of geaaral rbance. but remains I local atfection. Frequent Wl a five per cent solution of carbolic acid seems to give fairly results, and nearly all cases make a complete recovery in one to three months. tOn February 3, 1011. I visited a herd of cattle at Spr.-i. r.. where 2,1 head of heifers were badly affected, and later ly all the eattle in this herd heciime affected. Carbolic acid lions were used and all recovered in about three months, ■ral other cases have been reported in milder forms, which vered in less time. Swamp Fever, t Swamp fever, also called Pernicious Anemia. Malarial fever. has appeared only in a few isolated cases in the North Centra! of the state. It i* usually of a chronic nature, but during the of 1911 several eases seemed to be more of an acute type and dag its course and ending fatally in one or two weeks. The nature of the disease is not well known. The symptoms Mated at first are not very definite: the appetite generally re - mains food, but in spite of this fact the animal is' losing flesh, the mucous membranes become pale, general weakness and exhaustion takes place and death follows sooner or later in most BM t There is no treatment that has been of any particular value eating this disease. Report of a New Disease. Reports of a new disease of horses in the western part of the were received at this office during the fall of 1911. T reports came from horse owners located in various places in the western counties in tbat part of the state. All of these re] were similar in the description of the disease, stating that there wm a great number of horses in their community affected with swellings in the breast, with formation of abscesses which would break in a few days and discharge a thick white creamy pus. Such swellings and abscesses were some times found in the flank, thigh, and the lower part of the abdomen. Dr. Sturdevant of the Nebraska Experiment Station and myself investigated a number of these cases at Mullen and Alliance. Nearly every stockman </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 we it .1 that he had souk- horses affected with tin- sanu trouble and that mt eculd find hundreds of horses in his eoin - inunity affected with the same disease. I It was thought by some that this disease iv.is a certain form stemper. Imt most of the stockmen and the (Jo\ eminent Wt - irians located in that part of the slate ■greed that they did not i it was distemper. The reason for such opinion was th.it the -s affected did not show at any time the symptoms usually in the early stage of distemper, such as difficulty in swal- IK food and water, and swelling of the glands of the thro it. that the abscesses in the breast and other parts of the body not secondary or sequel la some other rtiiTT a^ we MB0 - 5 find in irregular distemper. The appetite usually remained normal. In most cases no at - tention or treatment was gtaea to these cases. The disease runs ■ lurse in about three weeks, terminating in recovery in nearly The Horse Plague. During the latter part of last August we began to receive reports from various places in the southwestern part of Ne - braska that the horses in that section were dying from some un - known disease. Within a few days we had similar reports from all over the central part of the state, and in three weeks time the disease had spread over one-half of the state. It seemed to id from the southwest to the northeast with "Treat rapidity. nding its scope in width more gradually; this, however, was licit always uniform, as frequently we found cases twenty-tiw to fifty miles away from a ease of the same kind, wd this condition would remain for a few days, after which a great number of e would appear in that vicinity. After three weeks time the disease began to abate in its id as well as in its virulence, and many of the cases wait - cred. while in the early part of the outbreak nearly all of them died within two days. tThis plague affected the horses on the range in the sandhills. e pastures on the plains and in the bottoms in Nebraska, and quite a number of work horses that were kept in the barn. It ted the horses in the dry sections where the crops had failed 1'cnint of no rain, as well as in places where the rainfall had </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 been heavy and rrops were (IMtL It occurred in pastures where there was practically nothing to eat. as well as where the grvwtk of the grass was as rank as it em grow under the most favorable conditions. It occurred in pastures where there was stagnant wa - ter as well as where this was absolutely out of the &lt;|iiestii;n. This disease affected the horses on nearly every farm in sonic communities and in other places appeared only on one or two farms, and no other place within several miles, although the ha WH left in the pasture all the time. I Horses of all ages died from this plague. Mules did not. to knowledge, contract the disease, but it has been reported that mules died of this plague in Nebraska. Cattle and Imirs w.p affected with this disease in our state. KWe have no exact figures of the number of horses lost during outbreak, but a very conservative estimate would, in my opin - be about 12,000. ■ This plague run its course in about forty days in Nebraska, it disappeared almost as suddenly as it came. When this plague started it was thought by many to be For Poisoning, because the symptoms presented were similar to eases of that kind and which frequently occur, especially duriiu' the fall ami winter. In cases of forage poisoning, which ha\. curred occasionally in Nebraska, the veterinarians have found ;\ certain condition of the feed in that locality to which they could trace such cases, and it has been supposed to be due to mouMy fodder and wormy corn. It is my opinion that this outbrcal. eoold hardly be due to these causes, because of the great extent of tN - outbreak, and from the fact th-it it appeared under all condition-. of forage and grain or no grain at all; and from the fact that the affected animals had a high temperature in the early stage of the disease, which is not the case in what has been called forage 'tiing. would indicate an infection instead of poisoning. It was thought by some that the paliside worm was the cause of this plague because upon post morten inspection this worm often found in great numbers both in the intestines and blood sels. As it is a well known fact that this worm is often found upon post mortem examination in horses on pasture that have died from some other disease, and that this plague appeared very sud - denly, extended over several states under all condition and disap- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BIENNIAL REPORT peared as suddenly as it came, therefore it seems very doubtful that this worm could be the original cause of this plague. IThis plague has also been called Cerebro-spinal Meningitis by others Kncephalo .Myelitis. Roth of these terms are BMd &gt;nvey the same idea, as the Knglish definition of both m mmation of the brain and the si)inal cord. A bulletin issued by the Tinted Slates DlllWI of Animal In - dustry, entitled "Bpisootk Pc mhm flpiiiel .Meningitis." has bees referred to as describing similar outbreaks in Xorth Carolina. Virginia. Maryland and parts of other states where the average ation of the land is but a few feet above the sea level. In this bulletin it is stated that these outbreaks are invariably traceable to unsound or mouldy forage or feed or to contaminated water, and that horses at pasture may contract the disease when Up - growth of grass is such that it mats together, causing the lower part to die and ferment and become mouldy, or by drinking from wells or pools containing surface water which is drained through imposed and mouldy vegetation and contains organic matter lated from these. ■ It is also stated that nudes were seized with equal facility and. tile horses, they rapidly slleelllllbed to the disease. I The recent outbreak in Nebraska appears to differ in som- Is. in that it occurred at a high altitude and also in pastures •e the entire ration for the horses ((insisted in very short rie grass, and where the drinking water came from good wells no stagnant water could be found in the pastures when' they been kept day and night all summer. Bacteriological research and experimental inoculations have been made at various laboratories and experiment stations, but no definite report! have bee* made as to the result of such work so far as I know at this time. Interstate Shipments IThe state sanitary requirements governing the admission of stock into the various states have been complied with as near has been possible to do so. Nearly all of the states require the rculin test for dairy and breeding cattle. Only ten &gt;t ire the mallein test for horses and mules, but most of the inire a physical inspection and a health certificate if </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE VETERINARIAN 21 ing that such horses ami mules are free from all contagious and infectious diseases. The records on tile in this office for the period covered by this report show that 4.H21 head of dairy and breeding cattle for in- terstate shipment have been tuberculin tested, and that out of this number 14 reacted, of which t&gt; have been destroyed and 8 re- main under quarantine. Nine hundred and twenty head of esttit were given a physical examination only. These records also show that 7,172 horses and mules included in settlers' effects for inter- state shipments have been inspected and that H,997 of these have been mallein tested according to the requirements of the states into which they were shipped. There were 5,822 head of cattle and 8,213 head of horses ship- ped into this state during the past two years. The cattle were m- ted and tested, while the horses received only a physical ex- amination as required by the state. Financial Report. rnce in treasury for office supplies, traveling ex - penses of the Deputy State Veterinarian, and for salaries and traveling expenses of Assistant State Veterinarians, on Jan. 11. 1!H1 | :M8.'Jl Deficiency fund appropriated by the Legislature WMi.OO Total money available from Jan. 11, 1911, to May 1 19H $ 918.91 t Money expended from Jan. 11, Itll, to .May 1. 1!H1 91 Balance in treasury $ ft4K tropriation for ofiee supplies, traveling expenses of the Deputy State Veterinarian, and for salaries and traveling expenses of the Assistant State Veterin - arians available May 1. 1911 tl&amp;flOOM tpy expended for office supplies, traveling expenses of the Deputy State Veterinarian, and for salaries and traveling expenses of the Assistant State Vet - erinarians from May 1, 1911. to Dec. 10, 1912 ll.:i_&gt;J t,4 Balance in treasury on Dec. 11. 1911 $ :!.ti77.:*b' </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Money appropriated for fflandered horses available July 17, 1911 $2.-».(XMI.imi upended from July 7. 1911. to Dec. 10, till 1S,41CJU Balance in treasury on Dec. 11. 1912 Respect fully submitted. Deputy State Veterinarian. *1 !.:&gt;*:{. in A. BOKTROM. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>