<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pump Irrigation Results</title>
               <date value="1928-06">1928-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 227 June, 1928 Pump Irrigation Results HARRY E. WEAKLY AND L. L. ZOOK . Bulletin 27 of the North Platte Experimental Substation W. P. Snkder, Superintendent " ' ■ ■ ' - * I .■. ' j ■ Hi ■■i'"^^B- ' h ■* -' ■. ■ t^v*B ;. I lh!_.&lt; ■— •■■ iV- *■■ ■■ "'^^^VV' ):■'•'■'■:':- "-^S Deliverinc a thousand gallons of water per minute at the University of Nebraska North Plattc Substation's pump irrigation plant THE UNIVERS' TV OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OD" AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">".' ■ - Pump Irrigation at the University of Nebraska North Platte Substation HARRY E. WEAKLY AND L. L. ZOOK • A means of irrigating that will supplement the natural rainfall is one of the greatest needs of agriculture m the western part of Nebraska. The amount of water available m open streams is sufficient to supply only a small portion of the land which might easily be irrigated. The under - ground water supply is abundant. As more efficient means of lifting it to the surface and applying it to the land are developed, this source of supplemental irrigation becomes of increasing value. The successful operation of numerous pumping plants m areas where, on account of low rainfall, crop yields on unirri - gated land have been very low, has furnished, m several recent years, vivid proofs of the value of an additional water supply. The conditions and contrasts have stimulated much interest m the possibilities of pump irrigation. It is the purpose of this bulletin to make available certain results secured by pump irrigation at the University of Ne - braska North Platte Substation. The chief crops irrigated were corn, potatoes, alfalfa, Sudan grass pasture, and forage sorghum. These crops were grown m fields of one or two up to ten acres m size, and an attempt was made to handle them on a practical farm basis. Some irrigation was given to garden crops, lawns, trees, and shrubs. The results of some earlier work m which fall irrigation was compared with fallow for winter wheat are also given. This work was on plats of one-tenth, acre m size. For the seasons of 1925, 1926, and 1927, complete records were kept of the amounts of water pumped and applied, the costs of operation, the yields secured, and the amounts and values of the increases m yields due to irrigation. For 1924, yield records were incomplete, but records were kept of the amount and cost of water pumped by kerosene engine power, and these compared with the costs m later years when the pump was operated by an electric motor. THE PLANT The original equipment, which was installed m 1918, con - sisted of a 6-inch horizontal pump operated by a 30-horse kerosene engine. The pump (Fig. 1) is set m the pit of a central well, just above the level of the water table which 'Junior Agronomist and Agronomist respectively at the North Flatte Experimental Substation, detailed by the Bureau of Plant Industry. Office of Dry Land Aericulture. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 227 n H ii lit p ... $M. _-y/^//sy^^ Si /^J ill /MMMfim* Lie fCTtH f=^ p ; Fi.. 2. — Three wells connected to one pump c//w r\\ q. } **'^*&gt;*&gt;^ot \\ -ZA *'&lt;^3____ lfO»] «^N Fig. 1.— Showing installation of hori- g _gL^W&lt;l - zontal certrif ugal pump, with pitcher ' V^~f — - — Cv^ pump primer "'&lt;^ / 3^q^ </seg>
            <seg id="p005">■■■■ * •. ■ Pump Irrigation Results lies 31 feet below the surface at this place. Connections were made to two other wells located on either side at 50-foot distances in a north-and-south line with the center well. The plan of connection is shown in Fig. 2. The well casings are 24 inches in diameter and extend down below the level of the pump about 22 feet. The casings are of galvanized steel with 10 feet of heavy-gauge galvanized wire screen strainer on the bottom. In 1925, a 40-horse-power electric motor was installed to • replace' the kerosene engine. As the electric motor operated at higher speed than the engine, the three wells failed to supply sufficient water for, operating the pump at full ca - pacity. Therefore, a fourth well was added. This is a covered, uncased well with 6 feet of strainer on the bottom of a 6-inch suction pipe and is located 50 feet east of the central well. • A. 30-horse-power motor would furnish sufficient power for the present wells, but a 40-horse-power motor was installed to provide for a possible increase in capacity. The discharge pipe is equipped with two openings, one into a ditch at the ground surface, and the other 5 feet above the surface into a flume. The total lift, when a stable draw-down has been reached in the wells, is approximately 52 feet from the lower and 57 feet from the upper opening. The capacity of the original plant was 900 to 1,000 gallons per minute, or approximately 2 second-feet. With the fourth well added and the electric motor substituted for the kerosene engine, the flow has been increased to between 1,100 and 1,250 gallons per minute, or about 2.5 to 2.8 second-feet. cost of irrigation by pumping at the university of nebraska north platte substation The cost of pump irrigation may be. divided into two classes of charges, operating costs and fixed costs. The chief items of operating costs are power and attendance charges, dis- . tributing costs, and such incidental items as oil and minor repairs. Table 1 is a summary of operating costs for each ' of the four seasons from 1924 to 1927 inclusive. The fixed cost is a charge made to cover interest, taxes, overhead, and ' depreciation on the plant and distributing system, and as such is charged against the project rather than against the water pumped. operating costs Operating costs for the four years, 1924 to 1927 inclusive, are shown in Table 1. The power cost in 1924 included mainly fuel and oil for the engine. For 1925 and succeeding years the power cost has been for electric current, which is delivered at the Station at costs as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 227 First 200 kilowatt hours per month $0.07 Next 400 kilowatt hours per month 055 Next 1,000 kilowatt hours per month 045 All over 1,600 kilowatt hours per month 035 All electricity used at the Station for power purposes other than irrigation is charged off first. The result is a lower power cost for irrigation than would be the case on farms where less electric current is consumed. The average cost of electricity used for irrigation was 3.7 cents per kilowatt hour in 1925, 3.91 cents in 1926, and 4.4 cents in 1927. Table 1. — Summary of pump irrigation operating costs, and of operating costs per hour and per acre inch for the seasons of 1924 to 1927 inclusive i_ | % i = il-' _b = I. 1 I ii s 1| .Si S | - V Eu _- -a _ as 2 - _ ' _ _ °-- _ 5^ -S _!£- 5°- =_? -. x Ss- E_ -» -- c. = ._ o-ls , s__ o§_ S_ o§ I s| : Is 1924 $178.20 $111.78 $167.07 $457.05 310.5 $1.47.2.00 G21.0 $0,737 1925 404.74 187.1)0 592.34 469.0 1.26 2.20 1,031.8 .574 1926 381.72 178.00 559.72 445.0 1.26 2.42 1,076.0 .520 1927 209.48 87.80 297.28 219.5 1.35 2.78 609.5' .488 As the electric motor requires practically no attention, the charge for an attendant does not appear in the table after 1924. The distributing cost includes the labor of getting the water on the land. This varies with the amount of water to be handled and the number of hours the pump is operated. As one man was still able in most cases to handle the larger head delivered by the electric motor, the distributing costs .per acre inch were not so high in 1925 and succeeding years as in 1924. While the cost of electric current was considerably more than the fuel cost of operating the engine, this difference was more than offset by the savings in attendance and distribution costs. As shown in the last column of the table, the operat - ing cost per hour and per acre inch of water pumped was less during 1925, 1926, and 1927, when electric power was used, than in 1924, when power was furnished by the kero - sene engine. The cost per hour of operation was the same for 1925 as for 1926. The price of current was slightly less in 1925 on account of the greater amount used and the variations in </seg>
            <seg id="p007">If ■ "■ ■ Pump Irrigation Results monthly requirement, but on account of less efficient pump - ing, due chiefly to belt slippage, the increased cost of distribu - tion offset the saving in current. The total number of acre inches pumped was thus less and the cost per acre inch greater for 1925 than for 1926. For 1927, since the pump was operated less than half as many hours, the price per kilo - watt hour of current used was considerably more than for either of the two previous years. While the hourly cost of operation was 9 cents greater than for 1925 or 1926, the cost per acre inch of water delivered, owing to still greater pump - ing efficiency, was less than for any previous year. Power requirements vary with the lift, it must be understood; and cost figures as given in this bulletin would be increased or decreased in pumping the same volume of water from a greater or shorter depth. Pumps of a similar type now on the market are capable of being operated more efficiently than the pump here in use. The use of a pump of higher efficiency would result in a corresponding lowering of operating cost. As operating costs depend upon many factors, among which are the efficiency of operation, the availability of water, the height of lift, and the manner of pump installation, careful considera - tion should be given to these factors and competent advice received before costly equipment is purchased. FIXED COST In 1924 the fixed costs were calculated on a $2,500 valuation for the plant, which was its approximate original cost. Six per cent was allowed for interest, 10 per cent for depreciation, and 21/2 per cent for upkeep; making the total fixed cost I8V2 per cent of the valuation. In 1925, in order to care for the cost of making the changes in equipment, the fixed cost charge was continued at 18 V_ per cent. As the original cost and the rate of depreciation are less for the motor than for the engine, the fixed cost for 1926 and 1927 was figured as 12 per cent of the original valuation. With continued operation, it is . likely that the fixed cost can be still further lowered. The rate of fixed charges, the total fixed cost, the number of acres irrigated, and the cost per acre are given in Table 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 227 Table 2. — Summary of the total fixed cost, number of acres irrigated, and cost per acre for each of the four yearn, 1924 to 1927 inclusive. Y __ Rate of fixed charge Total "^m.*! 0 ' Cost upon valuation fixed cost irrieated per acre ; | 1924 : 18V. per cent on $2,500 §462.50 I 42.20 | $10.96 I II - 1925 1 18 V. per cent on $2,500 462.50 74.20 I 6.23 I : : I 1926 12 per cent on $2.500 300.00 79.00 3.80 I ' ■ ! 1927 12 per cent on $2,500 _ 300.00 61.00 4.92 It is obvious that increasing the amount of water pumped, or the number of acres irrigated a given amount, will decrease the fixed cost per acre. An idle pumping plant is a liability. To realize maximum returns, the pump should be made to serve the greatest number of acres consistent with good irri - gation practices. TOTAL NET RETURNS FROM IRRIGATION PLANT As data on the complete crop yields are available for the three years, 1925, 1926, and 1927, both on irrigated and on unirrigated land, and as costs of irrigation for these years are known, it is possible to calculate the net profits which have accrued from the use of the irrigation plant. Table 3 shows the number of acres of each crop irrigated, the amount and total cost of water applied, the average yields secured with and without irrigation, the amount and value of the increased yields, and the total net value resulting from irri - gation for each of the three years. The total cost of irriga - tion of each crop is the sum of the operating cost for that crop figured on the cost per acre inch shown in Table 1, and of the fixed cost per acre shown in Table 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Pump Irrigation Results Table 3. — Total cost, increased production, and gross and net value of crops produced by irrigation in 1925, 1926, and 1927. . ■a -o ' 8 S 5 !_ 8 ■ e j_ ** e* &gt;• c &gt;, s. _ —. _ -j Crop- ot. S° u v o u u -a £ J_ *R«U S ca 8,5. SfiiS SS 1 5 -.1 °J_ J » ■ 1 |?i 3 I |M| Si'l 3?| 111 8 J &lt; &lt;oS Hoi &lt;%.*£ &lt;!So- -H--3 &gt;^A £eg 1925 (Rainfall 14.94 inches) Corn ._ 136.7 398.81 $ 451.461*43.7 Bu. 7.B Bu. 1,292.3 Bu. $ 904.64 $ 453.18 Potatoes 3.5 66.6 60.00 478.6 Bu. 100.0 Bu. 1,125.0 Bu. 1,125.00 1,065.00 Alfalfa |15.0 274.21 250.921 3.6 T. 1.5 T. 30.0 T. 300.00 49.08 Miscellaneous! :.. 120.0 292.31 292.461 493.44. 200.98 Total -.74.2 1.031.8 $1,064.84 j »2,823.08 $1,768.24 . 1926 (Rainfall 15.12 inches) Corn |39.6| 401.51 $ 368.881 40.6 Bu. 2.6 Bu. 1,498.0 Bu. $1,213.38 $ 864.60 Fotatoes ..: ( 4.6] 120.1 79.56 253.0 Bu. 102.0 Bu. 678.0 Bu. 1,866.00 1,276.46 Alfalfa I 8.0 1 114.7| 90.041 8.8 T. 1.6 T. 18.0 T. 284.00 148.96 Sorshum 1 6.0) 41.2) 40.42] 6.5 T. | 0.0 T. 32.6 T. 258.80 218.82 Miscellancoust (22.01 398.61 290.831 .,.[ 623.67J 232.74 Total .179.0 1,076.0 $ 859.72 $3,585.75 $2,725.97 1927 (Rainfall 22.45 inches) 7* Com 136.61 340.01$ 345.341 60.0 Bu.l 42.0 Bu. 662.8 Bu. $ 413.32 $ 67.98 Potatoes ..) 4.6) . 77.0) 59.68 290.0 Bu. 150.0 Bu. 630.0 Bu. 473.10 418.42 Alfalfa 3.01 29.6 29.19 4.0 T. 2.0 T. 6.0 T. 48.00 • 18.81 New alfalfa 6.0 69.8 68.43 68.43. 0.00 Miscellaneoust 11.0 103.6 104.64 180.67J 76.08 ■ I. Total 61.0 609.5 $ 697.28 $1,178.62. $ 676.24 * Value of crops based on current market prices each season. t Garden, lawns, parking, nursery, and pasture-crops included under miscellaneous. . Estimated value. . ' . As would be expected, the greater profits are shown for the drier years. At North Platte the 53-year average rain - fall is 18.86 inches. For 1925 and 1926, the rainfall deficits were respectively 3.92 and 3.73 inches. The differences be - tween the net returns of 1925 and 1926 are due partly to variations in relative acreages of crops grown and of yields secured, but they are more largely the result of differences in current prices. For 1927, with an excess rainfall of 3.59 inches, the net returns are greatly reduced, but even under these conditions there was still a considerable profit from operating the plant. IRRIGATION OF MAJOR CROPS In Table 4 certain data shown in Table 3 are summarized to show the net returns per acre on the three major crops, . corn, potatoes, and alfalfa. The net returns per acre vary </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 227 in different years from as little as $1.86 with corn in 1927 to $304.29 per acre with potatoes in 1925. Table 4. — Average number of inches of water per acre applied, cost per acre, increased yields, and net returns per acre of each of the three principal crops irrigated for the seasons of 1925, 1926, and 1927 | Av. yield per acre = _I 'i = _ -ai ■ •»§ i_ „ .-—i, — - £ - __ 2 8. 0 fSo x{ U 3 «C i «- ~ ~ c 5t £ - S2»- JZ Z. •-»*-•__' S ** «• :: S "SO a ■ »-. cj . s_ *_i= r -ll\ I - £.«-_ gSS ? 1 _: s i -_•-&gt;- _.'»■■___ i- I*" o o t« a* *r t_**t. g I z. I &lt;.£__ &lt;S_- I i o £&amp;&amp;.l .!__ CORN 1925 35.7 11.20 $12.05 43.7 Bu. 7.5 Bu. 3G.2 Bu. I §12.60 1926 30.5 10.17 0.00 40.5 Bu. 2.5 Bu. 38.5 Bu. 21.63 1927 36.5 0.32 0.46 f&gt;0.0 Bu. 42.0 Bu. 18.0 Bu. 1.86 ; ! potatoes I i 1925 3.5 10.00 17.14 478.5 Bu. 100.0 Bu. 378.5 Bu. 304.29 1926 4.5 26.70 16.68 253.0 Bu. 102.0 Bu. 151.0 Bu. 283.66 1927 4.5 17.11 13.26 290.0 Bu. 150.0 Bu. 140.0 Bu. 91.87 I _ ALFALFA 1925 15.0 18.30 16.7.'! 3.5 T. 1.5 T. 2.0 T. 3.27 1926 8.0 14.34 11.26 3.8 T. 1.5 T. 2.3 T. 18.00 1927 3.0 9.8" 0.73 4.0 T. 2.0 T. 2.0 T. 6.27 IRRIGATION for corn Preliminary results have been secured from studies to determine the effects of applying water at different times and in different amounts to corn. During 1926 and 1927, water was applied at three different dates, designated as early, inter - mediate, and late. The early application was made before the first tassels appeared. The intermediate application was made about two weeks later, or at about the time most of the shoots had appeared. The late application was made after pollenation was complete. Various combinations of these times of watering were also made and in certain instances double applications were made at one time. Each application amounted to about 5 inches measured at the pump. The treatments, yields for the two years, the 2-year averages, and the average increases from different treatments are shown in Table 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pump Irrigation Results Table 5. — Time and amount of irrigation for corn arranged , in order of 2-year average yields " 1926 j 1927 I Two-year I Average Irrigation treatment yields I yields \ average * increase • Bushels per acre Early, intermediate, and late.. 66.4 102.4 84.4 42.6 Intermediate and late 50.7 92.7 71.7 29.9 Early and intermediate 49.2 93.7 71.5 29.7 Intermediate, double. 55.8 75.8 65.8 24.0 Late, double 34.5 80.5 57.5 15.7 Early, single 23.6 89.8 56.7 14.9 Intermediate, single (check).... 32.6 78.0 55.3 13.5 Late, single 18.0 81.9 50.0 8.2 No irrigation.. 11.6 71.9 41.8 The land used for these experiments was broken up from alfalfa one year previous to its use for corn, and cropped for one year. Potatoes preceded the 1926 and sorghum the 1927 crop. The corn- was surface planted on spring plowing. For the 1927 corn crop, an irrigation was given the preceding fall after the sorghum was removed. There was thus a good sup - ply of moisture in the soil at the beginning of the 1927 season and more rainfall later in the season than there was in, 1926. These conditions made good yields possible regardless of irri - gation practices.' An obvious effect of the early watering was the increased stalk growth. In 1926 the soil was becoming dry when the first water was applied. Where early watering only was done, there was insufficient moisture for the plants in the later stages of growth. The waterings made at the inter - mediate date were of the greatest benefit. In 1926 a double intermediate application was of more benefit than either early and intermediate, or intermediate and late applications. Maximum yields were secured in both years from a com - bination of early, intermediate, and late waterings. Under these conditions there Was no shortage of moisture at any time, and the plants reached full development without being checked in growth. FALL IRRIGATION Late fall irrigation for the purpose of storing moisture in the soil for the use of the succeeding crop is desirable and profitable under certain conditions. It may increase the acreage which can be handled from a single irrigation plant. Also, it may make possible a better distribution of farm labor, by helping to carry crops thru the early stages of growth, when the urgency of other farm operations may make irrigation difficult. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 227 On soils of good storage capacity, good yields of small grains can frequently be produced by fall irrigation only. Corn, with a heavy moisture requirement late in the season, and potatoes, which do not root so deeply as small grains, cannot be as successfully carried thru dry seasons on stored moisture. The loss of stored moisture during the winter months is ordinarily not heavy. In the fall of 1926 a field of alfalfa at the Station was broken up and irrigated the latter part of October. Samplings made on November 13 showed a storage • of 11.9 inches of water in the upper 6 feet of soil. During the winter there was but little snow or moisture of any kind. The field was again sampled on March 3, 1927. On this date there was 11.7 inches of moisture in the 6-foot section. The moisture content of each foot section remained practically unchanged during the 4-months period. The 6-foot section in this case contained at seeding time 6 inches more available water for the use of the crop than comparable land which had not been irrigated in the fall. Comparisons of annual and of average yields of winter wheat after fall irrigation with yields secured after fallow, for the 6-year period from 1913 to 1918 inclusive, are shown in Table 6. These comparisons were made on plats of one - tenth acre in size. The irrigating was done with inexperi - enced labor, and the land was not carefully leveled. There was consequently a considerable variation in the amounts of water applied. The results indicate only in a very general way the value of fall irrigation under similar conditions. Table 6. — Annual and average yields of winter wheat after fall irrigation and after fallow at the North Platte Ex - perimental Substatioyi for the 6-year period from 1913 to 1918 inclusive Crop raised the i 1913 m4 j 1915 I ]. 16 ] J^ j lglg j Six-year previous year I I I I I j | average Fall irrigated . i ; . . Oats 28.3 12.1 | 48.5 33.2 21.5* i 26.4 j 28.3 Potatoes 28.2 10.5 | 45.3 30.1 | 22.2* j 29.2 I 27.6 Corn 31.2 11.3 ; 47.0 26.8 15.4* ! 8.7 : 23.4 Average 29.2 11.3 ' 46.9 30.0 19.7* I 19.7 j 26.4 1 I Fallowed — I | j j , j j None i 18.4 32.2 | 40.0 34.8 | 2.0* i 12.2 23.3 1 I I i I I 1 • These plats of winter wheat winterkilled and were reseeded to spring wheat. IBM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>