<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00059.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00059.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirteenth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="1926-11-30">1926-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Thirteenth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 1926. AMERICAN HUNTING COMPANY LINCOLN. NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">"After all— there is nothing like A GOOD BOOK!" </seg>
            <seg id="p003">&lt; ftiX*u~4 J^ j Vt&amp;$**, £^- &gt; r /9 * * i/i/' Oo. - cM^eer, Help the adult of tomorrow by helping the child of today. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Public Library Commission EDITH TOBITT, President Omaha, Nebraska S. AVERT Chancellor of the University of Nebraska GILBERT H. DOANE Librarian of the University' of Nebraska J. M. MATZEN State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY State Librarian NELLIE WILLIAMS, Secretary MARGUERITE NESBIT Reference Librarian ■ EDNA BOOTH Clerk for Traveling Libraries </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 LETTER OF TRANSM1TTAL Hon. Adam MeMullen, Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sir: Complying with the requirements of the law, I herewith present the report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission for the biennium ending 'November 30, 1926. Respectfully yours, EDITH TOBITT, President. </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">Personnel 7 Nebraska Public Library Commission SECRETARY'S REPORT December 1, 1924, to November 30, 1926 THE COMMISSION The Library Commission consists of a board of five members, four ex-officio and one appointed by the Gov - ernor for a term of five years. There have been two changes in the personnel of the board within the bien - nium. As noted in the last report Malcolm G. Wyer, for eleven years our wise counsellor, severed his relations with the University of Nebraska, becoming librarian of the Denver public library. For a year his assistant, Miss Nellie Jane Compton, was acting librarian. In September, 1925, Gilbert H. Doane succeeded to the position of li - brarian of the University of Nebraska, by virtue of which he became a member of the Library Commission. Mr. Doane came to us from the staff of the University of Michigan library. Mr. Doane is generous in giving time to Commission problems and helpful in his advice. Due to plans which necessitated long absences from the state, our president, Mrs. Margretta S. Dietrich, re - signed her position in June, 1925, six months prior to the expiration of her term. We were thus deprived of our one appointive and only woman member. Mrs. Dietrich was a valuable addition to our number. Her keen mind, her appreciative interest and the charm of her person - ality were ours to enjoy. To the position left vacant by Mrs. Dietrich's resignation has been appointed one who is qualified by profession and experience to aid in the program and policies of the Library Commission. On June .2, 1925, Edith Tobitt, librarian of the Omaha public library, was appointed by Governor McMullen to complete Mrs. Dietrich's unexpired term. In the Decem - ber following, Miss Tobitt was reappointed for a term of five years. By virtue of his election to the position of State Super - intendent of Public Instruction, Charles W. Taylor, of </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 the Teachers' College of the University of Nebraska, will become a member of the Library Commission January 1, 1027. Mr. Taylor will succeed J. M. Matzen who has been a member of the Commission since January, 1920. Mr. Matzen has the distinction of having missed no meeting of the Commission during the years that he has been a member. Another change in the personnel of the board will take place January 1, 1927, when Judge C. B. Letton, for twenty years an able member of the Nebraska Supreme Court, will succeed H. C. Lindsay as State Librarian. Mr. Lindsay is the senior member of thie Library Commission having held his present position since May 1, 1904. During all the years of his adminis - trstion Mr. Lindsay has been actively interested in the development of the Commission and has assisted in securing increased funds for carrying on its work. The foregoing has to do with changes in the personnel of the board. There remains a fifth member, Chancellor Avfery, who is second in years of service, having been on the Library Commission for seventeen years. The board acts in an advisory capacity, the secretary and her staff carrying: on the work of the Commission. The secretary needs the help of each member of the board. She wishes here to express her appreciation oi the co-operation which she has received. During the administration of Governor Bryan a de - creased appropriation necessitated a reduction in the staff of the Library Commission and for two years the secretary had but casual stenographic help. Governor McMullen recommended to the last legislature an increase in the appropriation, for the Commission. Due to the generosity of the legislature it was possible to restore &amp; fourth member of the staff. The present office staff consists of the secretary, Nellie Williams, who is also the librarian for state in - stitutions, the reference librarian, Marguerite Nesbit, the clerk for traveling libraries, Edna Booth, and the stenographer, Lucille Grattan. Since the last report there has been one change in the personel of the staff. In August, 1925, Grace Houts, who had been with the Commission for three years, resigned her position as clerk of traveling libraries, the staff and the state she served thereby suffering a distinct loss. The same spirit of service characterizes her successor, Edna Booth,. who has been with us since September, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Aim Activities 9 kin addition to the above the Commission employes on rt time two or three student assistants, as need re - ires and funds permit. As stated in former reports "the aim of a library com - mission is to promote library extension, to encourage the founding of libraries where none exist and to aid in their intelligent and economical administration." Perhaps the fulfillment of this worthy aim is slow of realization but the activities of the Nebraska Public Library Commission are carried on with the goal of library extension to all the people of the state always in mind. The burden of the secretary's song is the improvement in service and administration of all existing libraries in Nebraska. To librarians and members of library boards who are co - operating in an effort to raise standards she wishes to express her appreciation. The work of the Nebraska Public Library Commission is organized under three general divisions, field activities, a system of traveling libraries and reference loans, the building and supervising of libraries in the state institu - tions under the Board of Control. The policy in directing these three lines of work is as in former years. The attending growth is not phenomenal. However, there are always specific cases of peculiar interest. There is likewise a healthy increase in all of our activities. On the other hand there are constant contacts to acquaint us with the possibilities of additional service to the state and many reminders of the limitations of that service, due to an inadequate number on the staff and to insuf - ficient funds to meet the demands upon the department. Monotony seldom besets the Commission staff. From the opening 1 of the morning's mail until the packages and boxes of books are on their way, the day is fraught with a variety which keeps interest at a high point. There are letters from within and without the state. They come from the A. L. A., from a near-by or far-away Library Commission, or it may be a Macedonian call. Usually there is a questionnaire at hand to preclude any possible leisure. Always there are questions of administration. Whether it be specifications for building shelves, aids to book selection, or how to budget the library funds, the secretary is Always glad to render such help by corre - spondence as she can. The Nebraska Public Library Commission is addressed in a variety of ways. It may be State or City Library, often it is Traveling or Circulating Library or Library </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Fieid Work 10 trected to the Library Mission while ona letter was addressed to Missionary Williams. It is our desire that oar work be imbued with such a spirit of service. It is again necessary to report a library field but parti - ally surveyed. Only by regular visits to all libraries of the state can wet be of assistance in keeping with our hopes for Nebraska libraries. With the increased de - mands of general administration and in all lines of our work, it is impossible to cover the field in a reasonable period of time. As a result some libraries are always on the waiting list. Specific calls for help are answered as promptly as possible. For the most part the people of the state are charitable in their judgment, realizing that the number on the Commission staff is inadequate. Because it is a vital need the members of the library Commission are asking the Governor to recommend to the incoming legislature an appropriation which will make possible the addition of a Field Agent to the Commission staff. To assist in organization, cataloging or in some problem of administration visits have been made to Adams, Arcadia, Axtell, Bloomfield, Clay Center, Comstook, Cozad, Genoa, Hastings, Holdrege, Lexington, McCook, North Bend, Oakland, Papillion, Randolph, St. Edward, Springfield and Wahoo. Ir connection with library meetings and as opportunity otherwise offered sixteen other libraries were visited within the biennium. Visits by the Commission are made without expense to the communities receiving help. Next to the field work of the Library' Commission comes the circulation of books to groups and individuals. Read - ing matter is thereby provided for many/ who do not enjoy local library privileges and public library collec - tions are supplemented by the loan of specially requested books. The requests for the past biennium were 11,055. These were filled by the loan of 103,675 volumes. Of this number, 75,684 volumes were in traveling library groups and 27,991 volumes were sent to individuals. No effort is made to secure a. record of circulation from the traveling library borrowers but it is conservatively estimated at five circulations to a volume. This would bring the number of readers for these 75,684 books to 378,420. The total estimated circulation would thus reach 406,411. This is a 20% increase over the loans of the last biennial period. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Traveling Libraries 11 Statistics should never take first place but they do bring a certain sense of gratification. By comparison, they take on an added interest. A summary of requests and loans for the biennium just closing is given on page 37 of this report. There is also a graph showing some comparative statistics to which we call your attention. A. Commission letter of information reads in part as follows: — "Books are sent out by the Nebraska Public Library Commission according to two general plans. There are traveling libraries which are loaned for three months with the privilege of extending the time. Usual - ly a general group contains adult and children's books in about equal numbers. To any general traveling library books along special lines will be added on re - quest. The number of books loaned is determined, In part, by the size of the community to which they are sent. There is no expense to the borrower except the transportation charges. A traveling library will be sent on receipt of an application card properly filled out and signed by at least three taxpayers." Traveling libraries are sent to public libraries, rural and urban schools, clubs and churches, printing offices, county agencies, banks and stores, Y and scout camps. From these centers the books reach many people of the respective communities. The libraries travel over every railroad in Nebraska. They go by stage and truck to points far from the railroads. Always they are coming and going. It may be to a community in Lancaster county or to sparsely settled and distant parts of the state. It may be to a river town on the east or to the sugar beet country of western Nebraska. During the biennium traveling libraries have been sent to 91 counties. Hall and Grant counties alone have not made application to the Library Commission for books. On page 37 is a summary of statistics showing the dis - tribution as to groups to which traveling libraries have been sent. Lancaster county led in the number of loans, 37 traveling libraries being sent to 17 communities. Next in order are Custer 33, Gage 29, Cass and Thayer 24 each, Butler 22, Furnas 21 and Lincoln 20. We often wish that we might follow the traveling libraries and see just how eagerly they are received. From the letters which come we know that to some they are a real joy. The following are extracts from a few letters received within the past two years. "The libraries you have sent this year have been </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Reference 12 veritable life-savers. I think they have helped the Girl Reserves to spend thirty dollars in books for the school library." "I would like to have you send lm&amp; some primers for a little girl of five. And I want to tell you that because of the help you gave me through your choice of books her sister whom I started reading two years ago is now do - ing fourth grade work in school." "We are keenly disappointed that we cannot procure a traveling library at once but will welcome the books when you can send them." "I have three husky young Americans under five. I am a great lover of books, but I am too far from the library to walk there to get them. Will you allow me to have a box of books sent to met I also have my brother's boys, three of tt'em, — seven, nine and twelve — so I have a real need of books which I cannot now see my way to buy. Please .... is all I can say. Please put in some good books on cooking, home serving and nurs - ing, some books of fiction for the mister and Hans Brinker, Little lame prince or Heidi and oblige forever." "We now have 250 books in our library but we simply could not exist without the Traveling Library. Please send as many juvenile books as you can spare." "The books we have been getting are very fine. The children wanted to stay after four o'clock and have me read to them." "May we have an extension of time on our traveling library T It is giving excellent satisfaction. Most of ;he books are in use all the time. We certainly appreci - ite the advantages which the library offers." "I am a minister of a country church. It is well nigh impossible to get in touch with a library. I am informed that the state has traveling 1 libraries. I should like to know about the possibilities and rules for their use. Your help will be gratefully received." The Library Commission also loans books to individu als and clubs for special study, the number of books am the time limit depending on the needs of the case. Th time is usually a month, however. Special loans are sen by parcel post, the borrower paying the charges to ant from Lincoln. Daily Uncle Sam takes many packages o books addressed to a scattered clienWe which we know largely by correspondence. During the biennium refer ence loans were sent to 552 communities, in 92 counties Banner was the only county in the state which was not </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 served. Lancaster county with 274 requests filled, leads in the number of reference loans. Cass follows with 247, Gage is next with 212. Then come Custer 180, Saunders 174, Dodge 154, Dawson 152, Hitchcock 144, Valley 131, Webster 130, Saline 125, Scottsbluff 124, Thayer 121, Butler 117, Furaas 115, Fillmore 107, Antelope and Mer - riek each 104, York 103 and Otoe 101. Besides being scattered our borrowers are varied. They include the "Doctor, lawyer, merchant, chief, rich man, poor man" of the familiar couplet, and even the "beggar man, thief" are with us for we have a few bor-&gt; rowers who seem rather greedy and some who fail to re - turn their books. Besides coming from all parts of the state, from people of all professions, from young and old, the requests cover a variety of subjects. They range in reality from "a to izzard", with many letters duplicated several times. For instance, there are calls for books on acoustics, bees, costuming, dentistry, etiquette, foreign relations, Girl Reserves, household budgets, illiteracy, jazz, Ku Klux Klan, librarianship, marriage laws, Nebraska, in her ev - ery phase, oyster culture, pageantry, quilt-patterns, ra - dio, sculpture, tractors, unemployment, village improve - ment, world court, X-ray, the "Y" and zoology. Our borrowers are appreciative and many tributes to Miss Nesbit's selection reach us. With the return post - age often comes a word of thanks for promptness in sending well-chosen references. Not being a mere mail - ing machine without personal interest in those served, we are pleased when our "customers", as a small boy put it, send us messages like the following:- "I wish to express my appreciation for the promptness and thoroughness with which you have always answered my requests for help. References are so definitely indicated that the books are easy to use." "I am sorry your pamphlets were not returned on time. If I can make it right by paying a fine or in any other way I will gladly do so. I think this Commission is a wonderful help for us backwoods women." This is an extract from a beautifully typed letter. "The University Debaters' Annual was received and we derived much, good from it. I am returning it to-day if our mail carrier can get through. I think the Public Library Commission is a wonderful help to those living so far from cities." Here are a few other letters selected from the many. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Libraries 14 "Please send me some literature on the subject of gro - ceries. I am studying to be a grocery salesman." "The Omaha Bee referred me to you. I wish to obtain a history of the Boxer uprising. I will send a draft at once on receipt of this information". "I have just been given a Spitz pup and as I know nothing of the care of a dog, please give me any infor - mation as to food and training. I am unable to find a suitable name I am a thirteen-year-old girl and this is my first real pet. I will be thankful for any information you may give." "I thank the Library very much for the books. Nine people read The making of an American. The other book was used by the entire junior class as a reference to study the cost to the state of marriages of the unfit." "I desire a good practical book on child training. My baby girl is now a year and a half old and I desire her to grow to be considerate, respectful of authority and able to obey cheerfully." "I received my book and was glad to get it," writes young David. "I have read my story and now I am go - ing to send it back. I am going to send postage due by stamps. Many thanks for it." " I am returning the Jungle Book with the sincere thanks of four 'Freshies' of the English class. And add the thanks of one mother who has profited by your oblig - ing kindness. Trying to hold a boy family on the trail does seem to require a helping hand sometimes. Thank you for yours. P. S. These 'four* are only one-fourth mine." The third activity of the Library Commission is its service to those who are confined in greater or lesser degree within institutional walls. This is a field of libra - ry work which is teeming with human interest. There are many instances of the part which books have played in the lives of people, as human as you and I, who for one reason or another are not free to come and go as you and I are. Whether it be a lack of the fifth sense, a crip - pled body, a distorted mind, a moral illness or merely the ravages of age which confines within institutions this portion of our people, we know that books have been a boon to many of the wards of the state. In 1909, Charlotte Templeton, secretary 1 of the Ne - braska Public Library Commission, began considering ways and means of securing legislation to provide books </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 for the population -within the state institutions. Such book collections as were then in the institutions were largely the result of indiscriminate giving. Very little money had been spent, the books were ill-cared for and not always used to the best advantage. Our library friend, the late S. C. Bassett, of Gibbon, became inter - ested in a legislative appropriation for this work ana helped in securing the passage of a bill whereby the Li - brary Commission was given full authority for the selec - tion of books and the supervision of libraries in the state institutions under the Board of Control. In May, 1911, began the actual work of organizing the institutional li - braries by weeding out undesirable books, getting a know - ledge of the regime of each institution and studying the types of inmates that books might be wisely chosen to fit their varied needs. Florence Waugh Humphrey did this work of organization and gained mang friends by her sympathy and insight. There is no need to theorize about our institutional readers and their interest in reading. Many specific in - stances of what books mean to them might be given. Obviously, there is more reading done by some classes of inmates than by others. More interest and local super - vision is found in some institutions than in others. In fact, the work is hindered in some cases for lack of a li - brarian to see that books reach those who wish them. Aa we have stated in former reports, the vital need of the institutional libraries of Nebraska is a librarian in each institution. The books in the penitentiary library are the most widely read. The circulation of books for the last two years is 30,140. The Commission also subscribes to 30 magazines thus providing the best of current periodical literature for the penitentiary readers. The men have just been furnished a newly-printed catalog for which they are expressing appreciation. We have been buying rather liberally for this institution in order to include a goodly number of replaced titles and to add books which have been specially requested. One man has been read - ing books on psychology with a view to writing on the subject. Realizing his need, he is now registered with the Extension Department of the University for a course in English. The following is quoted from his letter under date of November 11, 1926 :- "I have just received one of the splendid new catalogs which you so kindly com - piled and edited for us. Please accept my sincerest </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 thanks for the unstinted labor in preparing this catalog Cor me and my co-mates in exile." Another letter of November 12 reads :- "Just a line to thank you for your work on our new library catalog. In its entirety it shows judgment and consideration of the want it fills. Subjects grouped to aid the choice, well-bound, neat and handy. I am sure every one in the institution feels that he owes you a vote of thanks for your splendid efforts in our be - half." The librarian in charge writes:- "In apprecia - tion of the great amount of work you did in preparing the new library catalog, I am glad to inform you that your efforts are appreciated by the men at Lancaster. Some of the men upon receiving the catalog looked upon it admiringly and turned the pages with eagerness in looking for some favorite titles. The catalog is filled with books on almost any subject one might wish for. Personally I am very grateful for your interest in tlie library and in the need of good literature." There is no more appealing phase of institutional li - brary work than that within the hospital for the insane. There are two reasons why the secretary has felt a peculiar interest in the selection of books for these patients. One is due to an actual experience of reading to various gronps, trying out different types of books and finding both men and women appreciative listeners. Because of this contact with the patients the secretary was asked to appear on the program of the Nebraska State Nurses' Association in Lincoln in 1925. The paper read by her on "Books as tools" appeared in the Septem - ber, 1926, issue of the American Journal of Nursing. The second reason why the secretary has found hospi - tal library work gratifying is because of the cooperation she has had in trying by means of books to bring a new interest into the lives of the patients. She wishes here to pay tribute to the late Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent of the Hospital for the Insane at Ingleside, whose passing on June 27, 192G, brought sorrow to so wide a circle of friends. Dr. Fast believed not only in the efficacy of books to relieve apathy but he looked upon them as a therapeutic agency. We have previously quoted him as saying that "the date of beginning improvement in many mental and nervous cases corresponded to the date the patient began reading." It is due to Dr. Fast's vital in - terest in the patients at Ingleeide that we have there a large, attractive, centrally-located room for the library to which patients and employees have daily access. The library at Ingleside is one of the many memorials which </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Needs 17 will be erected to the memory of Dr. Fast. With as de - sirable a location and a librarian on duty daily, the other hospital libraries might be as useful agencies as is the one at Ingleside. In the institutions that are more or less educational books informational as well as recreational are selected. The very best books for boys and girls are chosen for the School for the Deaf and for the training and industrial schools. The superintendents and teachers are apprecia - tive of the books which may thus be used to supplement their school work. Books are a wholesome diversion to those within all the institutions. To some they are more than a diversion. They are a means of directing by sane ways to normal avenues of life. For those who will continue to be shut - ins and for those who will become citizens at large we believe in books for our institutional wards. Again we register the need of the state for more ser - vice from the Library Commission. As stated elsewhere in this report, it has become an urgent need. With each biennium there are additions to the list of taxed and as - sociation libraries. All libraries should be visited if not for assistance in organization or cataloging at least to acquaint librarians and library boards with the state de - partment which is maintained to serve them. It helps the secretary to meet personally those who are locally in charge of library interests. We hope that it is mutually helpful for us to know each other. But this is not stat - ing the case strongly enough. There are libraries in the state which are failing their communities by their pre - sent systems of administration. This is a reflection up - on the library cause at large as well as upon the depart - ment delegated by law to assist local libraries. It does not take great acumen for one to perceive that with the other demands upon her time the secretary can not meet all the needs of the growing list of libraries. The number on the staff is altogether inadequate to allow the time of one person in the field. So burdened has the secretary bcome it seemed to her in her travels over the state last spring that every meadow lark was calling, "Need a Field Agent! Need a Field Agent!" One of our strong aides in trying to secure funds com - mensurate with the needs is the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs. As with former administrations so is the present the Commission's friend and helper. The </seg>
            <seg id="p018">president, Mrs. W. EL Minier, of Oakland, is making as - sistance to the Library Commission a plank in her plat - form. The following resolution was thereby passed at the N. F. W. C. conference in Lincoln, in October, 1926 : - "Be it resolved that the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs actively support the Nebraska Public Library Commission in securing, from the coming legislature, an increased appropriation to cover the special need of a Field Agent and to carry on more adequately the work of the Library Commission." As stated elsewhere we are asking for an increased appropriation that existing and newly-organized libraries may be given the assistance due them. To meet the demands of normal growth we are also asking increases in the maintenance and book funds. The Library Commissions of many states issue bul - letins at stated times. The only publication of the Ne - braska Commission is its biennial report. This is sup - plemented by occasional circular letters sent out as need requires. This is a very casual means of publicity. Other avenues of advertising come by way of organi - sations of allied interests. We are given space in The Club Woman, the official organ of the N. F. W. C. We an asked to explain the Commission's system of loans for publication in the bulletin of the Parent-Teachers' Association. The League of Women Voters is also our ally, materially assisting in securing the appropriation for the Library Commission during Governor Bryan's administration. The American Association of University Women also lists us as an agency maintained to serve the people of Nebraska. The daily press gives the Library Commission occa - sional space. The magazine section of the April 18, 1926, issue of the Omaha World-Herald gave us a page write - up which was appreciated because of its insight into the limitations under which the work is carried forward. We are not unmindful of the good words spoken in be - half of the spirit in which we serve. Monthly magazines include us in their columns. The Woman's Home Companion, McCall's, and the Pictorial Review make the library Commission known to their readers and borrowers are thereby added to those who look to us for books. Instances like this make us feel that in spite of our twenty-five years of service we are unknown to many within our borders. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 We use the radio as a medium of publicity, the pro - verbial "as free as air" suiting us admirably. The secretary was asked to give a series of radio talks on library topics of her own choosing. They covered a period of six weeks during the past summer. They were given at the Nebraska University Studio, Station KFAB. The subjects were The Nebraska Public Library Com - mission, Library Commission loans, Institutional libraries, A county library, The A. L. A. and some of its projects and Children's reading. Many interesting returns came from this means of advertising. We believe so much in the opportunity of - fered that the secretary has agreed to give a second series of talks in the near future. The foregoing may well be classed as "hot-air" talks since they were given during the days of excessive heat of which we boast in Nebraska as the producer of corn to feed the millions. In addition to radio talks the secretary has made the work of the Library Commission known by face-to-face talks to various groups. Among these were a Mothers' Vacation Camp at Arlington, P. T. A. organizations, University summer school class in children's literature, N. F. W. C. state meetings, Lancaster county Teachers' Institute and District and Regional library conference*,. She has also given talks in observance of Children's Book Week, to Women's Clubs and to several groups of adults on books which might be named "As interesting as fiction." Calls also come from beyond the state. Incident to a campaign against undesirable books for children the secretary appeared upon the program of the Children's Librarians' section of the American Library Association at Seattle, in July, 1925. She also gave the story of this book house exhibit before a joint meeting of Colorado and New Mexico at Pueblo in October, 1925. At a Regional A. L. A. meeting in Sioux City, Iowa, in October, 1925, the secretary was in charge of an afternoon session, giving in that connection a talk on Book selection. She also sent a paper to be read by Miss Nesbit at the meet - ing of the League of Library Commissions in Chicago In January, 1926. Preparation of these talks and attend - ance upon such meetings consume much time, but we feel that they are legitimately witjbin our field, the wider con - tact being desirable to strengthen us for the work at hand. In addition to talks,se veral exhibits have been prepared. It is our custom annually to arrange an exhibit for the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Public Libraries 20 N. F. W. C. meeting. We had one at Seottsbluff in 1925 and one at Lincoln in 1926. The place of meeting made possible a more extensive exhibit this year in cooperation with Mrs. W. T. Fried, state chairman of Library Exten - sion. Miss Tobitt and Miss Neebit were also present to answer questions relating to library matters. The Library Commission sent an exhibit to Omaha in 1925 in connection with the Teachers' Association. This was in charge of Anna V. Jennings, librarian of the Teachers College, Kearney. The most extensive exhibit which the Commission has prepared recently was one used in connection with a series of six district library meetings held during the spring of 1926. We are pleased to record that a picture of one of these exhibits appeared on the cover of the Library Journal of June 1, 1926. A few days after its issuance a letter came from the president of the Florida Library Association asking for suggestions on the Nebraska method of conducting district meetings. We are glad if we can help ever so little in welding a link in the chain of library progress. In answer to a request, an exhibit was sent by the Nebraska Commission to be used at a Regional A. L. A. meeting of Indiana, Michigan, and Ohio, held at Ft. Wayne, in 1925. Two years ago we reported for Nebraska 126 public libraries, supported by municipal or township tax. The number has now reached 134. The libraries added during the biennial period are in Axtell, Atkinson, Comstock, Lyons, St. Edward, Sargent, Tilden and Walthill. Sargent made a levy several years ago but no organization was formed. We are glad to report it among the township libraries. Comstock and Atkinson are also township li - braries. There are now six libraries in Custer county, a municipal library at Broken Bow and township libraries at Ansley, Arnold, Comstock, Merna and Sargent. Broken Bow with a good plant at the county seat is geographical - ly the center of the county. This seems a logical location for a county library and we believe that a demonstration would convince the citizens of Custer county that a single unit of service would greatly increase their library facilities. Nebraska must again report two towns above 2,000 population without tax-supported libraries. These are Ord and South Sioux City. Both maintain association libraries. There are eight towns above 1,000. population </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 which do not have free public libraries, as against thirteen of two years ago. They are Beaver City, Benkelman, Cambridge, Curtis, Ogallala, St. Paul, Valentine and Wilber. Five of these towns have association libraries, supported other than by tax. Benkelman, Curtis and Wilber are without libraries. The recently added libraries deserve special mention. Each has something to contribute and we welcome them all to the fold. Atkinson, Lyons, St. Edward, Tilden and Walthill have been so administered by fostering clubs that it was our expectation to have them pass from association to free public libraries. Sargent and Corn - stock as a part of Custer county became township li - braries. Sargent is too newly organized to furnish a report. Comstock has made a creditable beginning. Library interest had been brewing there for some time, a tax was levied and funds were accumulating but no organization effected. In 1924 a P. T. A. was formed and the library idea developed. In October, 1925, the library was opened. To quote the librarian, "The library is 'going strong 1 and seems to be growing beyond our fondest hopes." The librarian traveled 354 miles to attend a district library meeting in 1926. May her kind increase. The Axtell library deserves special mention. Sum - moned to this town of 385, with its one hundred wind - mills, the secretary was asked to help in organizing a library. Somewhat dubious that their ambitious plans could be carried forward she nevertheless gave en - couragement because of the real library spirit existing there. Undesirable books were discarded, only approved ones were added and administration must be in keeping with that of larger systems. Axtell had one of the most satisfactory of library beginnings. It is a minature to which the attention of larger and older libraries may well be called. To our surprise it reports a small tax. It should eventually become a part of a county library system. An upward tendency is seen in the status of Nebraska libraries, in the aggregate. During the last two years there have been increases of 4% in income, 7% in amount spent for books, 8% in circulation and 9% in salaries. According to statistics received the following towns have reached or exceeded a library income of $1.00 per </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 capita, the amount considered by the A. L. A. as a reasonable Tninimnm revenue Arcadia* Arnold* Clarks* Clay Center Cozad Hartington Lexington Merna* Orleans* Plattsmouth Shelton* David City Fairbury Fairfield Gothenburg Guide Bock University Place Wausa* Wayne Weeping Water Towns having an income within $100.00 of $1.00 per capita: Bloomfield Silver Creek' Broken Bow Stanton Friend Tilden Pierce Wymore 'Those starred are township libraries, the population considered being that of the unit taxed. There have been changes in librarians in 17 public and 5 school libraries during the two years just closing. Space does not permit individual mention. It is fitting to pay tribute to Margaret Anderson, of Central City, who died January 7, 1926, after 21 years of service as librarian. Among our number none was a more regular attendant at state library meetings. We could wish that her mantle might fall upon several of our librarians who have not been so faithful in their attendance. After ten years of service as librarian of the Harvard library, Mrs. A. J. Jenisen resigned her position in February, 1926. We quote from a Harvard paper which says, — "That there has been real work done is attested by the fact that the Harvard library for the year 1924 ranked eighth per capita in the circulation of books iu the state. The library is cataloged. Bequests on many subjects are answered and the people of Harvard and community have an institution of which we are proud. Mrs. Jenisen deserves much credit for her efforts to build the Harvard library to its present state." We are always pleased to add to our list of librarians those who have library training. By this means will Nebraska standards be raised. The Hastings library is fortunate in securing a librarian who is a graduate of </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Book Week 23 the New York City library school, Nellie M. Carey, formerly of University Place, Nebraska. Miss Carey became librarian at Hastings October 1, 1926. A unique celebration of the library's anniversary was observed at Clay Center January 26, 1926, on the oc - casion of its sixteenth birthday. From the station KMMJ, owned by the president of the library board, H. H. Johnson, Miss Williams was asked to give a mes - sage to the librarians of the state. Following the broadcasting a ceremonial was conducted at the library. Within a large wreath were placed three unlighted candles representing the past, the present and the future. The first librarian of the Clay Center library lighted the candle of the past, speaking of the days when Clay Center had no Carnegie building and the library was little more than a traveling library station to which the Library Commission loaned books. The light was car - ried from the past to the present by a patron who ex - pressed appreciation of the service which the library renders. The representative of the present passed the taper to Miss Williams who, in lighting the third candle, spoke of the library's future opportunities and obliga - tions. Children's Book Week is regularly celebrated in a number of oar libraries. As the late Dr. Stuart Sherman said, it is a sort of week of prayer and as such it has taken its place as an essential observance. The libra - rian from Loup City writes, "I have to observe Book Week Inow whether I want to or not. It went over big this year. The grown-ups seem to enjoy it as much as the children do." Miss Nesbit had a part in the 1926 Book WeeK program at Wymore. The library is fortunate in having the cooperation of the Pennington Book Store which believes in the best books for children. A contest was conducted by the store this year, essays being writ - ten on "The book I like best" The prize winners were announced the evening of the Book Week program. Miss Williams talked on children's reading to the Women's Club at Lexington, the president of the club being also a member of the library board. Posters in the store windows, a school contest on finding "Hidden Titles" and distribution of printed booklists for the grades were some of the library's part in putting over Book Week in Lexington. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Buildings 24 Occasional inquiries as to Carnegie grants tor library buildings reach this department. We print again Dr. Learned's letter given in our last report. "The Carnegie Corporation has definitely discontinued all appropriations to towns and cities for library buildings. No exceptions whatever are made to this policy and even when circumstances are most urgent it is quite useless to apply here. The Corporation has by no means abandoned its interest in library service but it feels that in so far as buildings are concerned, its work has been accomplished." We are pleased to report new library buildings at Auburn, St. Edward and Table Rock. The story of each deserves to be told in greater detail than space allows. The Allen brothers of Auburn gave to the library board a site and the use of the house thereon provided a building be erected within a given time. A campaign for funds began, community spirit was aroused and the Chamber of Commerce arranged for a system of five year notes. A house to house canvas was made. The Women's Club pledged $1,000. The members of the library board and the librarian gave $100.00 each. The P. T. A., a quilting circle, the W. C. T. U., the Chamber of Commerce, the M. E. Aid and many others were donors. The school children brought their offering. The librarian says, "The oldest girl of a large family who always looks hungry and I know is cold in winter said with pride that they had given twenty-three cents." Probably the spirit attending no gift was finer than that of a certain ex-soldier who wanted a part in the building because he had learned to use and appreciate a library during his University days in Lincoln. Inquiring of the Chamber of Commerce as to the size of gifts he was told that any amount would be acceptable. Though he was advised to the contrary, this young man mortgaged a war-bonus certificate and contributed twenty-five dollars toward the Auburn library. In June, 1926, the corner stone was laid and in Oc - tober the building was completed. The school children moved the books which were tied in packages conveni - ent to carry. Policemen guarded the traffic, teachers helped to keep the lines in order and the children marched in, placing their packages in numerical order on the shelves. The Auburn library was dedicated Sunday afternoon, October 31, 1926. Mr. Doane was present and .had a part on the program. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 To the president, Mrs. Anna Gipson, to the librarian, Mrs. Lillian Mastin, and to many other people of Auburn credit is due for carrying persistently forward the cam - paign for a library building. Interest in the library at St. Edward is so great that a building was erected by the town. A, letter from the librarian reads: — "We are now located in our new brick library built by the town. The building is modern and we are very proud of it, as the library has been in operation only two years. The grounds have been landscaped and present a very fine appearance. We moved into the building August 26, 1926, in the rain but we were&gt; so anxious to get moved. The library board has voted a salary for the librarian. Heretofore the work was donated." As in so many library beginnings, so at St. Edward the initial credit is due to a group of women who fostered the library child. That it seemed to the city fathers a goodly child is evident. May the child grow in stature and usefulness. Here follows the story of the Table Rock library and its new building, as given by Mrs. A. R. Kovanda : "In 1892 the business men of Table Rock instituted a library for the benefit of the community. It was housed over a period of years in more or less temporary loca - tions. The next move of enthusiam that rent the air with electric rapidity was the creation of Chapter Houses for libraries. Twenty-one women and one man were caught in the current. To electricity we look for strength and light. In this instance it proved to be a conflagration without any fire escape. We emerged short a chapter house but rich in experience!. We said, 'Temporary defeat shall not daunt our courage.' And we were rewarded, for in 1916 came into existence the Altrurian woman's club, composed of twenty-six ener - getic women. They said, 'We must learn to give the best there is within us to our community. Such service can only be rendered through knowledge. Knowledge comes through books.' Then began the quest for books. Upon this altar of quest for knowledge many sacrifices were made. Because of untiring efforts to make prosper that which they believed to be for the good of the com - munity, public sentiment for a library erystalized into a belief that a library is a necessary part of an educa - tional system. After a time public sentiment began to wax strong for a suitable building to house its precious </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Gifts 26 collection of books. Then came the federation of the Methodist and Presbyterian churches. The Presbyterian church was for sale and the women of the church, having in mind the preservation of the building for some public welfare service, thought it a worthy cause to transform it into a library and rest room. The Presbyterian Ladies' Aid' Society had a little fund of its own. They decided that the best thing they could do with their money would be to appropriate it to some purpose that would serve the community whence it came. Mr. Mayor, with the highest intention of doing good they bought the building and I wish now in a formal way to present it to the city to be used as a public library building and rest room. In behalf of the Ladies' Aid Society I deem it a privilege to hand you the keys of the church build - ing." The story continues as taken from a Table Rock paper. "The Altrurian club, the Community club and other organizations took up the work of transforming the church into a library and rest room. The next question to be met was location. Mr. and Mrs. W. C. Fellers offered to donate ground enough to meet the needs and the offer was accepted. Then the work of securing the necessary funds was begun. Our citizens responded splendidly and the result is a beautiful stucco building. It is a splendid achievement ; a monument to the devotion of our citizens; a credit to the desire of our men and women to give to our community life the culture of moral and educational development." The spirit of service and the fine zeal found in Table Rock may be incentives to some other Nebraska town needing a library 1 building. Small gifts are probably all the time being presented to libraries of Nebraska, but no list of large sums has been reported within the biennium. Wakefield alone seems to have a substantial library gift. Citizens there gave $3,000.00 in 1926, the interest of which is to be used for books. In connection with gifts to libraries the A. L. A. has recently issued a broadside called "Remember the Li - brary." In part it says: "The American Library As - sociation believes and declares that the community served is primarily and directly responsible for the financial support of the library, as it is for the support of its schools. We believe nevertheless that through the provision of endowment or trust funds, supplement- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 ing those received from taxation, the work of libraries may be greatly enriched and improved. It is the kind of public service that the American Library Association especially recommends to the consideration of persons of means. Funds given for such purposes not only continue indefinitely to provide for the enlargement of the educational opportunities of the people, but they may also serve as a splendid memorial for an individual or a Eup, carrying a name identified with a service that tinues through the years. The development of trust ds presents a vast field for constructive work on the part of library boards." COUNTY LIBRARIES The A. L. A. Council at the Hot Springs meeting in 1923, voiced itself as follows: "The American Library Association has viewed with interest the growth of the county library system and wishes to express its belief that the county is the logical unit for most parts of the United States and that the county system is the solu - tion of the library problem for country districts." Nebraska is a state of country districts. It has a law making possible the establishment of a county library. The law reads as follows : — "The city council of any city, the board of trustees of any incorporated village, the county board of any county and the electors of any town - ship, shall have power to establish a free public library for the use of the inhabitants of such city, village, county or township, Provided, when the county board makes a levy for a county library, it shall omit from the levy of the library tax all property within the limits of any city, village or township in such county which already maintains a library by public tax: Pro - vided further, before establishing such county library, or levying such tax the county board shall submit the question to the voters of the county, and a majority of the voters voting thereon shall have authorized tha establishment of such county library and the levying of the tax. Such question shall be submitted at a general election only, and when so submitted and carried, it is hereby made the duty of the county board to include the county library in its next succeeding estimate and levy." Nebraska has an undeveloped field in which county libraries would flourish, but there is no county; library </seg>
            <seg id="p028">The N. L. A 28 in the state. Why not? We wish to call attention to the playlet "Why not?" by Harriet C. Long of the Wis - consin library Commission. Apply it to almost any county in Nebraska and see if the negative has any substantiating arguments. Under the direction of Mrs. Fried, the chairman of Library Extension of the N.F.W.C. the play "Why nott" was effectively staged by the club women of Cuming county at the Federation meeting in Lincoln in 1926. In a radio talk on county libraries, the secretary of the Library Commission adapted "Why not?" to Burt county which lends itself well to the county library idea. Why not try it out? Why not make a county library in Nebraska the means of supply - ing books to everyone within the county? LIBRARY ASSOCIATIONS There are two professional organizations in which Nebraska librarians should become members. Every librarian in the state should belong to the Nebraska Library Association. The present N. L. A. membership is 111. This is a creditable number but it might well be increased. The same strong statement made by Miss Jennings on page 31 as to membership in the American Library Association applies to state membership. The secretary, Miss Nesbit, will be glad to receive the N. L. A. annual fee of $1.50. The Nebraska Library Association has held no state meeting since the publication of the last Commission report. In that time, however, there have been nine meet - ings of unusual interest. In the spring of 1925, district meetings were held at Beatrice and at Wayne. While the librarian and library board did well their part, the spirits of all were dampened by the small attendance at Beatrice. Epidemic and rain combined to keep some away and we feel forced to confess a fear that indiffer - ence detained others. Weather conditions were better at the time of the Wayne meeting and a gratifying number of librarians and trustees was present to enjoy and profit by the meeting. In 1925, a Regional A. L. A. meeting was held instead of the regular fall meetings of the states participating. The states joining in this conference were Iowa, Minne - sota, Missouri, North and South Dakota and Nebraska, meeting in Sioux City, Iowa, October 14-16. By action of the American Library Association in 1922 such confer - ences were recognized as official A. L. A. meetings. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 It was therefore our privilege to have present at Sioux City the president, Charles F. D. Belden of the Boston P library and the secretary, Carl H. Milam, both of addressed the meeting. We were also fortunate ng Dr. Bostwick, librarian of the St. Louis public , with us. He told of his visit to China as a intative of the A. L. A. An outstanding feature of leting was a program in which Lew Sarett read is own poems to the delight of the audience. Nebraska stood second in point of attendance at the Sioux City meeting, with 65 registrants. The N. L. A. president, Bertha Baumer, of the Omaha public library, was chairman of the program committee. The secretary of the Nebraska Commission was asked to arrange for one afternoon's program of the Sioux City meeting. This took the form of a library institute for the librarians of the smaller libraries. The program consisted of a talk on Administration by Clara F. Baldwin, Library Division, Minnesota Department of Education, Work with children by Grace Shellenberger, Davenport, Iowa, public library and Book selection by Miss Williams. At the Sioux City meeting it was voted by the N. L. A. "to forego a state meeting in 1926, to hold district meetings in the spring and to concentrate on attend - ance at the fiftieth anniversary meeting of the A. L. A. to be held in Philadelphia in October." Accordingly a letter was sent to the Nebraska libraries asking for invitations for meeting places. Responses came from Alliance, Clay Center, Fremont, Kearney, Lincoln, Norfolk, North Platte, Omaha, Scottsbluff and Cperior. It was decided to hold meetings of one day :h in six of the ten places mentioned. The places were Alliance, Fremont, Lincoln, Norfolk, North Platte and Superior. We are indebted to many of our members for help in making these meetings successful. The president, Miss Langdon, of Nebraska Wesleyan University, presided at the Fremont and Lincoln meetings, the first vice-pre - sident, Eleanor M. Wheeler of North Platte at Alliance and North Platte, and Miss Williams at the Norfolk and Superior meetings. The secretary, Miss Nesbit, acted in her official capacity at five of the meetings, at four of Etch she conducted a reference hour. Maude Mont - aery of the Lincoln city library had charge of the erence hour at the Lincoln meeting. The meetings were enhanced by the attendance and help of two </seg>
            <seg id="p030">The A. L. A 30 member's of the Library Commission. At Fremont and Norfolk Miss Tobitt talked on Book selection and on the Business side of the library. At Lincoln and North Platte Mr. Doane delighted us with his "Story of the Book." We were fortunate in having Miss Jennings with as at North Platte. Interesting talks on Children's reading were given by Mrs. Reed of the Lincoln city library at Lincoln and Superior and by Miss Batchelder of the children's department of the Omaha public library at Fremont and Norfolk. To many others who assisted on the programs and to local librarians and library boards we wish to express grateful acknowledgment for their help and for courtesies extended to the members of the N. L. A. Nebraska is a state of magnificent distances. Cherry county alone is twice the size of the state of Rhode Island. The combined area of Lincoln and Custer counties equals that of Connecticut. Accordingly, the attendance of 172 at the district meetings of 1926 meant that great distances were traveled. While some had to go but a few miles others had far to go to reach the nearest place of meeting. The total number of miles traveled by those attending the six meetings was 13,140. This bespeaks a sense of need and an active interest that is gratifying. The N. L. A. Committee of Five, consisting of Miss Tobitt, Miss Home, Miss Jennings, Miss McQuaid and Miss Williams, has sent the questionnaire on library standards to all public libraries for the third time. It includes items relating to income and budget, board meet - ings, aids in book selection, membership in and attend - ance upon library meetings. The answers to the ques - tionnaire are to be tabulated and presented at the 1927 N. L. A. meeting. The Education Committee of the N. L. A., appointed in 1925, consists of Miss Jennings, Miss Ingles and Miss Nesbit. This committee has done a creditable piece of work in the issuance of a bulletin, How to organise a school library* with Lists of recent books for the Elementary School, the Junior High School and the High School. Mimeographed copies of the bulletin were distributed at some of the district meetings of the Nebraska State Teachers Association. As a chapter of the American Library Association the N. L. A. is closely affiliated with the parent organization. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 In the interest of membership we quote from a letter of Anna V. Jennings the Nebraska representative of the A. L. A. membership committee : — "As an earnest, ener - getic librarian you are endeavoring to make your library the best possible. Do you realize that in order to do this most effectively, you should keep in touch with the people who are furnishing the ideas and are making the standards that mean progress f You are receiving the benefits from the A. L. A. and the least yon can do is to show your appreciation and interest by enrolling as a member. The fact that your library or trustee is a member does not relieve you from your personal responsibility. The enterprising physicians of your community are members of the American Medical Association as well as the state organization. Is it not quite as important that you should show your loyalty to your profession by membe* - ship in the A. L. A.I" I Nineteen hundred and twenty-six is a notable year in b history of the A. L. A. In October it celebrated its "tieth anniversary at Philadelphia. In speaking of this celebration, the president, Mr. Belden, said, "The main object of the fiftieth anniversary is not to point with pride to past achievement but to bring to libraries the recognition they deserve and to* aid libraries in creat - ing a public sentiment which will make for a greater achievement in the future." One might speak at length of the jubilee meeting and enthusiastically of the program. Space allows mention only of Dr. Bowker and Mr. Dewey, fittingly the central figures of the occasion, and of the delegates from twenty - five foreign countries who furnished so interesting a part of the program. Sixteen Nebraska librarians at - tended the A. L. A. anniversary meeting. Town, city, high school, college, and university libraries were re - presented. Miss Tobitt, Mr. Doane, Miss Nesbit ami Miss Williams of the Library Commission were in at - tendance. A number of librarians from Nebraska contri - buted to the A. L. A. anniversary fund. Nebraska did not rank high in the amount given but the spirit in which it gave we believe was second to none. In some cases we know that even small gifts were made at a sacrifice. "This jubilee year has brought to the A. L. A. a great gift. The Carnegie Corporation has set aside $4,000,000 for library work. Of this sum one million is to endow </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 a graduate school of librarianship. Another million is to be used to aid other library schools. The third million is for general endowment of the American Libraiy Association. The fourth million will be used in carrying on the general activities of the Association. President Keppel of the Carnegie Corporation, in explaining the grant, expressed the hope that this would enable the A. L. A. to develop more extensively the small town service. 'Of all his benefactions the one nearest Mr. Carnegie's heart was the small library,' said Dr. Keppel." It is desirable for every librarian to become acquainted with the A. L A. publications. Nebraska libraries might profitably have a standing order for these publications. We wish to urge the purchase of the A. L. A. catalog of 1926 which is an annotated list of 10,000 books. The editor says in the introduction, "We believe the catalog to be an excellent, authoritative compilation which will prove indispensible as a basic tool for libraries for some years to come." It is a tool which every library in Ne - braska should own. "One project of the American Library Association is the preparation of reading courses to help the library in its service to the serious reader. These courses aie called 'Beading with a Purpose'. They are prepared by authorities in their respective fields, and are written in a popular but scholarly manner. On each subject a selected list of books is given, a list long enough to lead one afield in a line which interests him but not so long as to be formidable. The popularity of the 'Reading with a Purpose' courses is almost phenomenal. They are being used extensively in many libraries of the United States and a librarian from a foreign country writes, 'When I see such work being done, I realize how greatly the world of readers, thinkers and students is indebted to your country.' " A few of the reading courses thus far prepared are English literature by W. N. C. Carlton, Some great American books by Dallas Lore Sharp, Ears to hear, a guide for music lovers by Daniel Gregory Mason, Our children, by M. V. O'Shea, Religion in everyday life by W. T. Grenfell The poetry of our own times by Marguerite Wilkinson, The United State in recent times, by Fredric L. Paxson, and The modern essay by Samuel Crothers. The purchase of these pamphlets by Nebraska libraries is recommended. The books listed can be bought by some of the libraries. The </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 Nebraska Library Commission will loan the pamphlets and the books to libraries that cannot afford to bny them. Adult education is a project of the 'American Library Association which is being carried forward through » Commission on the library and Adult" Education appointed by*, the A. L. A. in 1924. In a recent report of the Com - mission it 'says that if it were to summarize its findings in one sentence that sentence might be: "Libraries have very definite responsibilities and very clearly defined functions to fulfill in the 'present movement for adult education." As a part of the whole Nebraska libraries thus share this responsibility to assist those beyond school age in the "continuing processes of education." The report says further: "Among national and com - munity leaders there is a growing conviction that in order to insure the success of democratic institutions more adequate provisions for adult education must be made. There is abundant evidence of a growing demand upon those organizations already engaged in adult education. From the librarian's point of view, one of the greatest needs is an adequate book service to the students connected with these organizations. Libraries have, furthermore, an inherent duty in their own right to provide books and advisory service for those indi - viduals who wish to enlarge their horizons, but prefer to accomplish this result through private study." By the latter means particularly does the Nebraska Library Commission have opportunity to serve. As an example we quote the following letter of April 19, 1926: "My attention has been called to the State Traveling Library by an article which appeared in yesterday's edition of the Omaha World-Herald and I am very anxious to begin a reading course under your supervision. I am employed in clerical work and have found little time to devote to reading. It is my desire to do some reading of a cul - tural nature. If you will take it upon yourself to send me the books which you think would be the most broad - ening I shall be very grateful to you." We feel a peculiar interest in that phase of adult education which begins with the child. We believe that Nebraska libraries should provide the best in literature for the children. In this connection the Commission on Adult Education quotes from an address of Miss Effie L. Power in which she says: "Our task is to reach all the children, and having done so to establish pei- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 manent interests; to train them to use books and to love books; and to relate their use of books and their general reading to their lives. If we fnlfill our obligations to the children w« should have an ounce of prevention to offer against illiteracy, dullness, pessimism, loss of faith, lack of ambition and unhappiness which is well worth a pound of adult education as cure." ' It is (with this thought in mind that we reproduce as a frontispiece of this report tiiie letter of Wilma who is forming so early in life a taste for good books. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">i SUMMARY OF STATISTICS v Volumes accessioned to December 1, 1924 32,958 Volumes in library December 1, 1924. 26,464 Volumes added from December 1, 1924 to 4,892 November 30, 1926. Volumes withdrawn to December 1, 1924. 6,494 Volumes withdrawn from December 1, 1924 to November 30, 1926 726 Volumes accessioned to November 30, 1926 37,850 Volumes in library November 30, 1926 30,631 EXPENDITURES DEC. 1, 1924 to NOV. 30, 1926. From From Appropriation Appropriation 1923-1925 1925-1927 Books J$ 960.40 $ 4,194.61 Maintenance 1,080.94 2,565.85 529.88 Binding 416.45 Institutional libraries 2,592.62 3,783.70 Salaries and wages 2,995.6o 8,713.08 18,046.06 $19,787.12 8,046.06 Total $27,833.18 Appropriation July 1, 1925 to June 30, 1927....$29,400.00 Expended July 1, 1926 to November 30, 1926™. 19,787.12 Balance 9,612.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 I i I i ! i 1 P. o 5 u 03 at -I' sM 1*1 Si* 1 * s •§ «s i o S-S S. 3 g.s . a si Haft •§ 1 s 1 g o a I H </seg>
            <seg id="p037">I I petretvi sannip^ wT o 1-1 ■a i paiM s^saab»s t-l a pauBoq sanmiOA. s iH IM P 9 IM s;sanbay O iH OO* Ice 1 O m • a ! °5g panBoq saumio^ i-T P»IM s OQ u 1! 8* paireoi sanrnp^ CD s •§"9 is is P 9 IM s^S3nb»a i—i S-* I *l3 sanmio^ s^sanfaay 1O |1 pairaoq saumio^ 9 r-l CO CO II pauBoq P9IM 8}9anb»g &amp; panBoq saam|0^ o r-l paiM s;sanbaa i r-T paireoq sanmio^ o (N 00 P9IM s^sanbag; o" o s poirooq s^saQbag CM patreoq saom|o^ 5 "I g o I s s s^sanb&amp;a © 00 H a s s pairaorj sanmpA 8jS3nb»a </seg>
            <seg id="p038">II 1 is ill if mi i A ill ri .3:5 £'£*£&gt;'«&lt; £'***£'£'£ I I i t l a l&lt; I e^ t-^ ea » e w «_ © !«nies«H * . * • *=• ■* « 55 ifH* j3&lt;5 !«►- •«ir«e&lt;i lo'io* i«*i4 :o • CO rt i] ! Ill ||S|SSS|SS'gSSgSS WNH» HCn rH •* iH CC^ |H_ CO 13 n rm 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 y ! II i i II iJjjUiJ i j I M ill! kJJett'iuu illllliliiliilll | </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 « 2 I 1? 1 -a 'S Sj ■" &amp; 1 1-3 &lt;0&lt;N&lt;OOOOOI&gt;.0000 : : : : I ! { J iJJJJ Sill! O o o o » sllll i: lh 2 I ijflf CO CU J 0Q i CO [ I | j I I 1 1 I 1 j | | I ] I I 1 I i ] i S(Smo5fc(S«SSoMtS i jjii i |l|!lfilll 3 S • otJoSCfcTt PQUOQEbOOOOUM </seg>
            <seg id="p040">- i aiJ^JUJ Jli-iJii Ji H 3* ©©(N©S?IM&lt;M&lt;Mlft©O©t&gt;©©©© io oo e^o^o^oo^oq,©,!^ © in © •* © © © 5 O •* rn io "5 t&gt; »c &lt;n to ■* ao in tjT en © io I^H H r-l CO CO rH i in mi nil i i i i . ■ ■ l ■ i ! i Mi! II : IflliifillJII'l | t 1 ! i ! I, illNjiMli! § J J J | a J : &lt;§ 1 4 5 4l 8 J »§ ll llTl In l Jlrii II I ! 1 1 -g 1' S Mi! ■la I j l™Sil &gt; a»«uS || 6 °° »4 ». s'S *a B n .2 e b » s J w gSMisshmwiy s ljjsii!i!jiiiiiis i ill Hi I -aw | *J|J 2 -a •*» .C "S TS — e g § a Oil **« » CC CO I </seg>
            <seg id="p041">I B 41 I l%iijjflijt!ii = dlll^iif|ll|fl:!il £ 2 E B S3 S 2' B" g S E' 2 = &gt;: £ C « 2 g HoooccosNicoon it-mcti-Kso nHOHaoNioceno ;mocj^«c&lt;oo t^Or-iOrHedcoomciemco^orHiooe agenoHNOtoiaeoneieooncgo o s s n io a n e N e n n ic o s a oo io n **"'#' r-7 eo" of of erf r-T in" erf i-T t-* «T mt&gt;*fcic* i— i w tH « &gt;St S « Si rn : •* m rn ih ® « eo SSS3**5 |SS lii i§iii s of * oo n * o o o • © t&gt; je^ioo^aese IH ooooooo^*'©'*' u&gt; • i a « h2e!!P2SS :oeooio«cNooe « 9 SS 2 ° lOOOO^OOORCOO qo n qo^o^coio in ■ s oo i3t-_n wee vo «e-T-le»9r-i r-l | I H'rH"r4'e&lt;fiH' iH«fe9*tH'r4' H22!ili N iH«ONHi6««01«IOH 1 -,i-lr1iH»-«!-lT-l f H'-i!-iiHr-lr-liH!-l?-li-l»-i!-i 3 - lo rH«o«».t»oDOOoseoiH»i»The&lt;i 00 «^iq^« rt"H*Hrt i-l i-H ,-? ,-T N* N*" ef OT N i-T iH IllllllllUIIIIHi!"* HN«*'Qt0N00OO'-'WW*10l8N00» • : *»■ *«j "^^ kj *•* fc™ **w *^-&lt; r-i |HH t» i-i uoi^inoaij &lt;* H ffl HrlR sanmio^ OO O O5 ■^■^Tr-r r4 led aino jj JJMflO siBoipouaj Iss «e- sauupig o o o 1-1 o W "^ CO amoouj Hgg (snBuao 026T) 3M i i i I I I. iS i49 H«M </seg>
            <seg id="p042">iiiiiiUilliiiiiiiii nopjBinoiio inaNs»Hfti*aatoooNONCDiflNM oTt- t» fH ef oT cf •*" cT «T i-T c&lt;T oT oo" &gt;o erf ad" sanraio^ OMOOnOdHHrlffiTjllOfflOOOriOlOO jad smog oojetoosgooo^iaiot-ogcjOHo n N (M00r-ft&gt;Tii00cvl&lt;M5O ; &lt;O H H H « ■» H" j rH" (N ao»oo«NoiMNMio«io :8SS2d WOO t^NN iNt»H *.&lt;-! spotpouaj puB SJ[oog B9trer«S O S Ol CO O rH O O O5 O ■* O O US : ■* O O 00 O lO O N tH 3 O "O H 00 H IO 00 » | © • » a O i-T of t-T «-T i-f i-T id" r-T ;h« io"i-i i (snsoao 0S6I) nopBpidoj 0««^»«©«H10H10t»NWeOH«Offl rHrHOH0&gt;OC&lt;l&gt;HOOOC&lt;lr-lf-lrHt~OOOO aaaaxaaaaAaoiaiaaaoaaaiSi i-liHiHiHiHi-lrHiHrHi-tiHi-lTHiHi-li-lTHt-(THi-t efi-T cf -"iT i-T &lt;h n"*©" ih ih c n ea io E 1 1 1 1 1 II 1 1 1 111 II 1 1 II I . 1! U II ill i it iHiilm 'll Wa I £ S &amp;-§ a-a § § 3 * -S 1 -S -g -C -fi *B P3PQUUUUUOUUUUU O U O Q O fa P=t OHNM^afflb-ooaoHNM^iototjeoa </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 i!j.;i a Jiil,;!5|:i;j noi;B[noji3 «N*l6«OM«M«Cl«iaB&gt;(iOgBCe ■^0^1-1 to ih «c &lt;e t- as 10 ot^ tc_ Oi_ «c^ o o_ ©_ a^ ao_ 00 t-h" oT eo" ao" i&gt;T cf ■*" t-T t«T ao" i-T *" ad" oT oT cT ad" t»" as" 10 «o t— i 1— i 10 10 cj i— 1 stramfOA •^ c^ m o rl © im o © 3&lt; » w. •* ©, e&gt;]_ •_ os, •*_ « '*'i&gt;'»o"evr«e &gt; iere | i'er3'ei5'eircf©*e&lt;fw e&lt;f©"»o'»H t- ef 3J33A aod ainojj g©©©"* 0 soo©c«"*&gt;ot-t«o»2g£2S2S 0&gt; CO I-H «Ol0OHl0H«O(&gt;ni0HSO«i5HOO Nnm^oo r-i«iHP5©cj^'Oco,«e«t- 4H«eaeo«|SSomoio nonNBH NMOOH«ec&lt;i£^ooot-a0NNONe «HIONlOlOH«« H ©HH(.HN«w!bH spoipouad pus s^oog I B8TJBtBg H (f Of 1-1 oooo«o&gt;sejoeoseeoenier| tO tHt*C$ Hrt eft-* Cif »-T IO N i-T C&lt;f omoonj (snsuao 0S6I) aoifspidoj OrieeHOOHHMHgOHHrHOOMOlH oiCiaioscscsososOioiOaocsOicscsCiOicco; HrlHHHHHrtrlrlrlHHrlrlnplH&gt;"rl a o e o a 10 t&gt;o Nae^aveSno ■*" i-i oT i-T i-T r-t .-T e« r-i rn" pT eo" i-T ih" as" r-T of t-T : i i i i ; ; : I i ; i i i ■ i i ! ! i I IIIIIIII 1 ■ I I I I I I I ?llilii.Wil?J| 1 llili i I |-*^^'*T»iT»&lt;T»i'&lt;»i^T|.»cio«5ioio&gt;aioioioi3 l </seg>
            <seg id="p044">I I a it I - 111 SSI fit in j^ 44 ffflJfllKMlfl*?! 50 2 2 fe -2 m.-ScnStoaJcnnJajuTaoJoo) l °d2S2 weiN « hnnoo : &lt;o ■* i&gt; ■«* C0©^O00C&lt;l©C0«0 HOCQ00O ! tH CO W r-i « te a qo o&gt; oo s ii] ia i^nncoo :h nnco ©"*« a&gt; i-&lt; io t&gt;~&lt;«rc&lt;f •*"" • t.-od'aTo'cir i BTt^t^w rHCfS r-l IO H jHH rHrH;c&lt;liH ocoiOeN^ONitoomoinio :oooio o»tjnN'i'onNO(os«ooM :©t»©e&lt;5 !«_ c&lt;^ us tj^ «&gt;_ p^ i- irs^N iq_o oo^e^t^©^ | ia s a h co'co'c*' i-TafcsT r-T erT i-T uf t-T^f of : oT^Tej" i-i" CO cqnooo««iaeeOoeci«soo«iot&lt;» m ■* co ■* t»( t&gt; SsiHSwcaNeii eoi-ir-ir-i co t- cc :h sioes icodiooooisoHooia oiooo :o»HHa isHnnnne^Hoo na^wcTtuNNN :«nnoHioooonn ffllMOHlOOHOOS iOJOSOlfllOOeiHO n an hn oh m : oo» n n n iq co h n i-\ r-t aoooo^ocooiooooot-ooooo l-T ef i-T t-T .H OOOlUOOCOtOOOiOOOOOOIMOr-ICOO eonejonnoniaoaoooeoioo^ 3S &gt;o «,■* &gt;omii}naTtiioio&gt;oaoiN«n&gt;ot&gt; ■"jfrH Cd oT of wTiHr-J" t-T efiH" rHrHrHiHtHiHrHiHi-ll-li-ttHi-liHrHrHiHiHi-ltH CO NtOX CQ 0^04 CO a.O CO t&gt; «, IO (N S N N O&gt; N i-Tt^rn" cfjg"!-? r-t rt* TjT th" »H r-T rH 1 (O* i-T iH" mini 1 1 1 1 1 i i i 1 1 1 I i i |j llljjjmiliijifffjf OOI^vpiOITQ i i-H saomp^ o © H&amp;9M. J9d amog en CD jaiflO sfBoipouaj pire s^oog I •*■ SOUBJBg T-l ernooni 00 tft- p«pn&lt;w 8 a «3A o s i-H (snsTOo 0Z6T) nopBjndoj </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 ■&lt; P ■&lt; i •8 2 § S 8 I" 8 2 2 " c E E 5 B B » 5 Sf '"g UOtJBpOJIQ 0IJ . a . l 'l'*.t» 1* « o n e « S o S n o k s oo oo t~ * &gt;h i-Tt- eo'orw'orefw'co'ioefw'w"^ W^iHrH iH PS r-lr-( 1 3[9ejt jed sonoH sanni[o^ c^t^txe^c^wic^e^o^cc iq.usoorHooosaoeiSao oo (M « w eo''*'eq'e"'eo'er5 &lt; c4"'i»!"u5"r-5'ei"er5'Tj&lt;'e&lt;r gs§sgScsas« e6 sg"s t -s§ &lt;cw s rt § I * |4fr rH t—i pn s^oog jaq^O setrepsg araooni 25i2t2°6° :©oooo©©©© . 8. N 5 ! - i M iH CO iH « &lt;N r-l rH t-T V r-T iH* ooggi-j«0£.cgt&lt;.«D*2;aooo«e©'*oooocot-ito 22SSfcdd222°«« rt « H r(*nN 05&lt;»e»«oo«e»»e»«e»050D050s«o:ec«o-. HnHrirlrlriHriHHHrlHHUHnnn " e '2 H d c ' rlH " ri ' i-T ih* ■* ,-r i-TefrH i-T ; S I | I I ii I I I 4 1 I I I | « i I I I I I I I J I j I raj M I 'Mil 1 i !f s !ff!|rt!iliilil!]j« { (snsnao 026T) noi^BjnclOjj QDacewooxngDwooaaaoaaaaaa 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 iiljlillll^llilill : oo 10 so t&gt; ■* •&lt;* :oioeoiHTjit~©os&gt;oio©i&gt; : io" t- ■* eo r-T us" i &lt;xT «T w" ■*" to" «" eo «" t-"" m j H Cl H H H OS iH ©C5©©lO(M©©©t~©©©&lt;M©©t-©&lt;N oootoomsoooianoiosoiinoooi ©^O^i-^^HOWiolOOSOlOTttCSIWOSWlO^ w'ceTiHuskd'm'fH'iH'ei'eis'ei'cforec'cf i-Teo"'* : © © © *o od © © :oooo©©ocooo© o«en««o © © n&lt; ■* ■* oo in © oo pa © i~t © r—^ C*J O5 CD © CO kO US O © IQ CO CO O) © © a © 10 O GO GO t*&gt; © Od CO kQ d © © CO C4 CO 00 © ! s O(6NH»NNS«gN&lt;l&lt;HartOOl000H MMHINt0HiaOs»00O!0HO00ONC0H &lt;Ocoa»oco &gt; Q &gt; aD©.GO c&lt; 2.Tt&lt;aocoi&gt;ceaot&lt;-iacoao &lt;-* 0? &lt;O t4 C* I* CS f-* rt i-T f-Tefl'rH" i-J" rH ill ■MI ilflillltllfllllllilJjfi CQQQaQaQOQQQQDOQQQGQaOQO^QQQQQGDExEHtHEH OOOOOOOOOOHHHHHHHHnn -^«*^rHi-trti-ii-it-tiHi-lt-l»-l»Hf-(»-(iHfHr-ir - I N « &lt;N (N CO &lt;N ■«* rH«iH«e»9efJiHrHiHCOeO lOSNOOiOOSNOnOHiOffiSSaiO) J&lt;(NaSl&gt;ooS»OOOS»»0« M US • KS b- W ■mat NOHOaOHHHHHOHOOOOHStDH .2 2 Jq r^ T _| rHrtr _ lr -(i-ll-(rHr-lrHrHi-irHiH I -lrti-lr-i him ui noi)«|ii02!Q : in © : co 10 t CO CO sanm[O^ : © a : o ao : © to : «T?o" JJ93M. JOd UQOQ : ■* © ; im co ■ 8 siBoipouaj pm s^ooa : © c»s : ■* evi : im t&gt; J " : © © 89U«1«S 2" fhS" «8i 815 (snsnw 026T) uoiiBindoj </seg>
            <seg id="p047">V In! i .a uogvpuMX) ■*SHiot&gt;moo«Nioo*an loco^atfoooqcot-ooooooa eo BJ^C H « N W.rt^ft N S 8 • o" in" OO" O&gt; t&gt;ri-Tl&gt;rGrr-| O~ m Ci Tf~ r-T crT 1 sanmjo^ aU5Cl)Oa*B»»OO«NM0 3J38M .iad araog MifK) i— i sjuoipouaj pire s^oog onoiQri iciao^cociem Oftaioa iccaoeooMOOSio mrtio^*« ;mn«mHHHOS i-l i-T t-TrH* sauBfeg araoonj oor-toeooeeoc3&gt;ooorH OlONOOOTtloOCOTliNOOlO o««&gt;oioc4ioon oicnioiooq i-h" t-TeoiHr-T cJwf p9TpnqBj3a NriHOeNMOr-HHOOHOS O3 Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Ob Cl Ot Ob 00 HHHHHrlrlHrlHpllir&lt;rlH o S iHCISf ~ |T *'J2'~ |00 ® a 0'~ lc '® 0B HWHmHH°.Heo«Maoion i-T &lt;"jT «" i-T i-T rn e&lt;T i-T pf i-T ei" w* § I II f| 1*3 (snsnao 026T) ' uoi^tfjndo &lt;j I I ll I I If I I I I I I j I I I | I I I I UJJliiUtiiliti HHHHHHHrlHHHrlpirtn </seg>
            <seg id="p048">• 48 ASSOCIATION LIBRARIES f libraries in the following towns, financed other than taxation, are under the auspices of Women's Clubs or other civic groups. Some of these are scarcely more than traveling library stations. Others are near the line of tax support. If other towns should be included in this list such information would be appreciated by the secre - tary of the library Commission. Adams Elkhorn Ord Oshkosh Alexandria Elm Creek Alvo Elmwood Oxford Angora Eustis Page Avoca Fairmont Palmyra Bartlett Farnam Papillion Battle Creek Grant Pilger Platte Center Beaver City Gresham Beaver Crossing Hardy Polk Beemer Hay Springs Potter Hayes Center Republican City Belgrade Boelus Hemingford Ruskin St. Paul Bradshaw Herman Brock Homer Salem Brownlee Humphrey Scotia Bruning Inavale Shelby Cambridge Jansen Shickley Carleton Keystone Shubert South Sioux City Cedar Bluffs Leigh Chester Lemo: Lemoyne Springfield Liberty Steele City Clarkson Crab Orchard Lushton Stratton Mason City Sutherland Crofton Crookston Meadow Grove Trenton Culbert8On Minatare Valentine Valley Dakota City Monroe Mullen Valparaiso Davenport Wahoo Decatur Murray Nemaha Wallace Deshler Diller Nora Waterloo Oak Wauneta Dorchester Dunning Oakdale Western Ogallala Wolbach Edgar Wynot Elgin Orchard </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>