<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Landlords of Nebraska Farms</title>
               <date value="1924-11">1924-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 202 Landlords of Nebraska Farms J. O. KANKIN LOOKING OVER THEIR CATTLE This landlord and tenant live together and work together for the good of both and of their community. Cooperating: University of Nebraska U. S. Department of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station Bureau of Agricultural E. A. Burnett, Economics Bureau of Agricultural Economics Director. H. C. Taylor, Chief. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY BY LINES Pages Farm landlords are too little studied. ;;-.-. Their very great power is increasing 5-6 Some economic and social results 7-10 Rented land is a storehouse for owner's savings 7-9 Rented land is credit to tenants. Good, resident landlords may lead communities and tenants 8 Nebraska landlords risk land price changes and generally take part of the chances of crop returns in yield and price. ... 8-9 The number of landlords owning more than one farm apiece is apparently increasing 10-16 Landlordship is attained in many ways 16 Kinds of landlords 16-21 Kinsman landlordship is likely to be affected by family con - siderations 16 Women are much less frequently landlords than men 18 Nebraska landlords are mainly American-born men .. 19 Foreign-born landlords are more than half as numerous as those of American birth in the areas studied IE Over half of the landlords are active or retired farmers and two - thirds or more have had farm experience at some time in their lives -.. 19 Resident landlords are decidedly in the majority 19-21 Written and oral contracts appear to be about equally frequent. ...21-22 The one-year contract predominates in all areas studied 23-25 Land is furnished by landlords 25 Labor and equipment are furnished by some landlords 25-29 Supervision by landlords is very limited in Nebraska 30-32 The landlord who rents for a share receives from a third to half of the crops 33 A little smaller average share of the crop goes to the landlord of western than of eastern Nebraska 33-34 The landlord gets a little smaller share of wheat than of corn 35-36 The landlord gets a still smaller share of oats 37 The landlord's share of alfalfa and other hay is extremely variable 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Landlords of Nebraska Farms J. 0. RANKIN « INTRODUCTORY Landlords little studied. — Landlordism is the other side of tenancy. The one implies the other ; if one grows in size, so does the other ; abolish either and the other is automatically abolished. They are not, however, equally studied and written FIG. 1. — WHERE THE FACTS WERE OBTAINED From 100 to 125 farms were studied in each area except the one in Logan County. A different schedule was used in the Geneva area which was surveyed in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement. about. Tenants and tenancy have had the almost exclusive attention of writers on the subject. The landlord has been ignored or given brief, passing, or incidental comment. 1 The author bases this bulletin largely upon a survey conducted in cooperation with Drs. C. J. Galpin and L. C. Gray of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture, who paid the salaries of the field men who obtained most of the data in 1920- The manuscript was submitted to that Bureau. Some portions are based in part upon a survey made in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement, but that survey was largely devoted to securing social rather than economic data. Acknowledgment is due to one or two enumerators who were employed to do the field work in each area, to tabulators, and to a number of members of the faculty of the University of Nebraska and others who have made valuable suggestions at various stages of the work. Earlier bulletins published on the basis of this survey are : Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 180. 1922. pp. 31. tigs. H. Lincoln. Out of print. The Nebraska Farm Family : Some Land Tenure Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 185. 1923. pp. 31, figs. ». Lincoln. Out of print. Nebraska Farm Homes : A Comparison of Some Living Conditions of Owners, Part-owners, and Tenants. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. pp. 48. figs. 19. Lincoln. Out of print. Nebraska Farm Tenancy : Some Community Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui.- 196. 1923. pp. 50. figs. 25. Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 The few articles on farm landlords have sometimes been quite partisan, and sometimes quite judicial, sensible, and worth while in tone. In most cases they are largely opinion, based on observation over more or less time and territory. They do not show any statistical basis in most cases, there - fore it seems well to give especial attention to data at hand with regard to 720 landlords of Nebraska farms, and to com - pare them with other available data. Even the new Nebraska data presented here are rather a by-product of a study of tenancy. Data on a few of the points covered by the Nebraska survey were obtained by the 1900 United States Census, so we can compare 1900 with 1920 and see in what direction we are going. Table 1. — Landlords studied Areas Landlords of All landlords County Town Full tenants Part-owners All 1 720 561 159 'The part-owner is a farmer who owns part of the land he operates and rents part of it from someone else. A mortgage on a full owner's land does not class him as a part-owner. The terms owner and tenant are here used in the usual sense, which doubtless need not be explained to any of our readers. "Part-owners not separately reported in this area. Why landlords are not studied. — There are a number of reasons for landlordism being studied from the tenant rather than the landlord angle : ( 1 ) Popular sympathy goes to the tenant as the weaker party who is striving to improve his condition. (2) The tenant is younger, more plastic, and has a greater expectation of life during which to profit by any improvement in policy which can be formulated as a re - sult of investigation. (3) The landlord is assumed to be quite able to take care of himself in any contingency. He Eastern Nebra Cass Clay Gage Fillmore . . . Fillmore. . . Polk Thurston Southwestern Furnas Perkins .... Sandhill Logan ika Nehawka .... Fairfield Filley Milligan Geneva Stromsburg. . Walthill (ebraska Cambridge . . . Grant 72 79 82 66 66 76 99 58 96 62 63 68 52 66 58 69 51 49 10 16 14 14 18 30 7 47 Stapleton .... . 26 23 3 a </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 5 gets rent enough to support him altogether, or with reduced effort on his part. It is generally assumed that we need not worry about the landlord, but should let him alone to do as he pleases. He may well afford to be generous to a tenant, especially a kinsman tenant, but we seem to have assumed that we may leave this question entirely to his judgment and pleas - ure. Why study landlords? — Nearly half of the farms of the United States and much greater fractions in some other countries are more or less completely controlled by landlords. In the United States the landlord's importance has steadily increased thruout the country districts and no one can say positively how long this growth will continue or how great the landlord's importance and influence may become. It is important that such a great and growing power be carefully analyzed. It is also important that the analysis avoid (1) the alarmist, propagandist, or demagogic attitude on the one hand and (2) the ultra-conservative attitude on the other hand, which paraphrases Pope and says, "Whatever is, is best." Of nearly six and a half millions of farms in the United States (6, 448,343 in 1920) nearly two and a half millions, which are tenants' farms (2,454,804), are rather completely controlled by landlords. To these we must add more than half a million (588,580) part-owner farms operated by men who own part of the land they farm and rent part from someone else. These part-owner farms are often overlooked, but they cannot be ignored in estimating the landlords' importance and influence. This influence is not measured in full by saying that 2 out of every 5 (38.1 per cent) of our farms are occupied by tenants. We must add the further 8.7 per cent of part - owner farms, making 46.8 per cent of our farms which are more or less under the landlords' influence. The extent of their influence varies greatly from farm to farm in the same section and from section to section in the United States. In Nebraska nearly 3 farms out of every 5 feel the influence of landlord ownership, as 42.9 per cent of all Nebraska farms are oper - ated by full tenants and 15.4 per cent of them by part-owners, making a total of 58.3 per cent. There are other ways of measuring the landlords' in - fluence. For the period 1900-1920 we can measure it in terms of acreage and value as well as number of farms. In the United States as a whole, full tenants are operating a much lower percentage of the total acreage in farms than they are of the total number of farms, but in Nebraska they have al- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 most as great a percentage of improved land in farms (41.1 per cent) as they have of number of farms. In this state they are operating 42 per cent of all farm property as in - dicated by value and 42.7 per cent of the land and buildings, as compared with 42.9 per cent of the total number of the farms. 2 Landlords' influence growing. — The landlords' influence is growing in (1) number of farms, (2) total acreage in farms, (3) improved acreage in farms, (4) values of land, improvements, and other farm property supplied to tenants, and (5) closeness of personal relations with tenants and supervision of their operations. The first four of these are matters of statistical record, but the fifth is much more largely a matter of personal opinion and observation and is doubt - less less generally recognized as true than the first four. It seems reasonable, however, to believe that as the value of a Nebraska farm, for example, advanced from less than $2,000 in 1860 to $30,000 or $40,000 in 1920, the owner would exer - cise more and more carefully the power which his ownership gave him over the land which he rented to his tenant. The tenant, on the other hand, would be more and more compelled to accept the supervision of the landlord, whether he desired that aid or not, as land became scarcer and scarcer and the rental or purchase price became higher and higher. The fact that 2 out of every 5 Nebraska landlords are now related to their tenants adds to their influence. The statistical history of the increase in landlords' in - /iuence has already been briefly reviewed in an earlier bulletin in this series. 3 Prior to 1880 no data were gathered by the Census or any other agency which give any definite idea of even the number of farms controlled by landlords. We only know that the landlord was not so rare as might have been surmised in the absence of such figures. The earlier agri - cultural papers and books give us glimpses of the relations of landlord and tenant thruout the history of the United States. Even during colonial days there were farmers and others who rented their land to their sons or to other tenants who pre - ferred to pay rent rather than move to the cheaper lands of the frontier. The English system of gentleman farmers who rented their land to tenants also found a foothold even in the colonial days of free or very cheap lands. 4 'Agriculture: Reports for the states. The Northern States. Fourteenth Cen - sus 1920. Volume 6, Part 1. 690. 3 Nebraska Farm Tenancy: Some Community Phases. Univ. of Nebr Agr Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. pp. 52. fiirs. 25. October, 1923 'Taylor, Henry C, Tenant Farmers in the United States Prior to 1880. Chap - ter 20 of Agricultural Economics, pp. 238-260. The Macmillan Company, N. Y. pp. 4SS. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 7 Some landlord functions. — Some of the functions per - formed more or less generally by the institution of landlord - ism are : ( 1 ) A storehouse for the savings of retired farmers or others is provided by the opportunity for safe investment in farm land which would not be possible in the absence of landlordism; (2) credit or quasi-credit is afforded to the ten - ant who obtains the use of land, improvements, and in some cases, of operating equipment, which he is not yet able to buy, but which his apprenticeship as a farm hand or farmer's son, or otherwise, have qualified him to use; (3) a source of leadership and guidance for (a) the community, and (b) the individual tenant, especially in case of a resident landlord, who understands farm people and their problems and takes a proper interest in them; and (4) risk-taking in land price fluctuations. It is not contended that all of these functions are perfectly performed. The data presented in this bulletin are intended largely to throw as much light as possible on the third of these functions so far as the landlord's dealings with his tenants are concerned. (1) A storehouse for savings. — Farm lands or mortgages upon them, if judiciously purchased, are widely prized as un - usually safe places for savings not immediately needed. Such investments, altho often wisely made by people of various classes, are peculiarly advisable in case of farmers who may put their savings into farm lands or leave them there on re - tiring. They usually understand this investment much better than the stocks and bonds which are often offered to them for sale or the mercantile and other businesses which they sometimes undertake to operate on retirement from the more rigorous, active farm life. For any such investor who is not operating the farm lands, landlordism is, of course, the result. The savings bank function is inseparable from landlordism and is usually the outstanding function desired from it by the landlord. Such an investment should usually be made in the home community, as even good farmers are only too often duped when they buy in strange localities where they do not know the soils and climate. (2) Credit to tenants. — Landlordism is associated with many kinds and degrees of credit extended to the tenant. He may or may not, in individual cases or in accordance with the custom of a given section, be assisted by the landlord in secur - ing livestock, farm implements, and food for use of the house - hold while tilling the farm. In all cases, however, he is given credit or quasi-credit in being allowed the use of land. This credit is especially real in case the rent is not paid in advance, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 and of course advance payment is rare. The credit which comes with landlordism may not in all cases be precisely what the tenant desires ; it is at least better than none, and is to be regarded as one of the functions of landlordism as in oper - ation at present, whether it is to be approved or disapproved. (3) Leadership and guidance. — The leadership function of landlordism shows greater variation in both quantity and quality than any of the others mentioned. It depends upon (a) the landlord's familiarity and sympathy with rural life, (b) his wisdom, (c) his temperament, (d) his financial con - dition, and (e) the distance he lives from the farm, as well as upon (f) the tenant's willingness and ability to profit by leadership, (g) the family relationship, if any, between land - lord and tenant, and (h) the attitude of the community. It is extremely important that neither landlord nor tenant be unwise in any way which will prevent them both from getting the benefit to be derived from the older man's longer exper - ience and the opportunity leisure gives him to study carefully the problems of the individual farm and of the community in which it is located. Those who have retired from active farm - ing should be encouraged in every possible way to support financially and otherwise the schools, roads, churches, re - creations, and other forces of the communities in which they have lived and perhaps continue to live and from which they draw all or a part of their sustenance. Landlords in the Geneva area are by no means out of touch with community affairs. One out of every 7 or 8 of them is a member of a farm organization, 1 out of every 16 holds polit - ical office, and 1 out of every 3 supports church work in the vicinity of his farm. One out of every 11 is a member of a club or lodge, 1 out of every 13 a church member, and 1 out of every 6 or 7 a church attendant. As this information was obtained largely from the tenants it is possible that the figures are lower than if the landlords themselves had given the in - formation. (4) Risks. — The landlord is a risk-taker in matters of (a) fluctuations of land values, (b) fire and other danger to im - provements, and (c) sharing the tenant's risks in most cases. The landlord and tenant both share the risk of crop failure in case of share tenancy, and cash rent is rather likely to be adjusted accordingly in case crop failure or other causes bring financial trouble to the tenant. With the exception of the first, these classes of risk need only be mentioned to be fairly well understood by anyone who is at all familiar with the farming business. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 9 Land price variations, however, are not so well understood even by some of those who seem to feel surest upon the sub - ject. They are determined by interest rates and net annual cash income or rental values. These in turn depend upon the prices of the products of farm land, instead of rent being de - termined by the price of farm land as some wrongly believe. Taxes and cost of production, of course, affect net income. For nearly a quarter of a century, beginning in 1896, the prices of farm products rose generally and almost continu - ously. This brought up the rent and prices of farm lands. The feeling became very well established that they could move in only one direction, and that almost any reasonable price might be paid with assurance that it would be only a matter of time until land could be sold at that price, even tho it was much above current, productive value. The farm land market is not an organized one because land cannot be sold by either sample or grade and cannot be brought into an organized market place. The resulting pe - culiarities have been stated as follows: 5 (1) There is no or - ganized group interested in keeping prices down, so in any outbreak of land speculation those interested in raising prices "have full control, so long as their enthusiasm and capital suffice to support and advance the market." It takes a very cool-headed land-owner to avoid doing unwise things during such speculative fevers. (2) Sales of land cannot be made on short' notice as in case of a well-standardized product which is easily transported to any place where those who desire to use it may happen to live. (3) Prices of land change much less rapidly than those of most other things because the main thing we buy in the purchase of land is the perpetual use of it. (4) Speculative buying of fictitious land on margin can - not enter either thru legitimate exchanges or thru bucket shop plans to affect prices. No attempt is here made to determine whether price of grain is affected or not, but the price of land certainly is not. Of course, this is not meant to deny the influence of speculation just stated in (1) above, or the de - ception of the unwary by illegal and dishonest, fictitious statements of sales prices in deeds. (5) There is a legitimate and proper difference between "present productive value" and the "present sales value." If there is good reason to be - lieve that future productive values will be much greater than those of the present, of course no wise owner would sell on the basis of present productive value or a capitalization of pres- 1 Hardy. Charles O., Risk and Risk-Bearing. The University of Chicago Press, Chicago. Illinois. 1923. pp. 220-222, 384-385. The discussion follows Hardy only in part. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 10 ent net annual income. Since no one can definitely forecast the future, the actual selling price can only be based upon the shrewdest and most careful estimate, and in this sense all farm land values are speculative, and involve risks of financial loss to the holders, or the possibility of financial gain. Table 2. — Landlord^ other farms 1 ■Includes no data from Geneva area in Fillmore County -Percentages distribute "unspecified" proportionately. FARMS PER LANDLORD Survey data were secured with regard to 654 landlords, 495 of whom owned full-tenant farms while 159 owned only the rented portions of the part-owner farms. Of these 654 landlords, 314, or nearly half, owned other farms besides those included in this survey, thus owning two or more farms apiece. This multiple-landlord group included more than half the owners of the full-tenant farms studied, and about a third of the owners of the rented portions of the part-owner farms. The 314 landlords of the full-tenant farms and the rented por - tions of part-owner farms studied in the survey owned 652 other farms, or 966 in all — an average of about three farms apiece if we count each rented portion of a part-owner farm as a full farm. Not only were the owners of tenant farms in greater pro - portion the owners of additional farms, but they doubtless ! I ■ J Landlords of All landlords ! Full tenants j Part-owners Per cent \Per cent jPer cen Total number of landlords . . . Landlords owning other farms Other farms owned Acres per man Location of farms In Nebraska 2 Elsewhere 5 How acquired Purchase 2 Homestead* Inheritance 2 Gift' '. Deals with tenant Directly 2 Through agent 1 .654 100.0 495 100.0 159 100.0 314 48.0 255 51.5 59 37.1 652 ! 526 126 . 287 600 237 606 50 571 571 91.4 478 91.8 93 90.2 ...54 8.6 44 8.2 10 9.8 . . . 422 78.8 350 81.1 72 i 70.6 .9 1.2 7 1.2 2 2.0 . . . 87 16.8 63 14.6 24 23.5 . . . 17 3.2 13 3.1 4 3.9 .434 96.1 376 97.0 58 90.8 . . . 18 3.9 12 ! 3.0 6 9.2 i i i i &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 11 owned additional acreages out of proportion to their greater number. Two hundred fifty-five of them owned 526 additional farms or 781 farms in all, thus giving them a slightly greater average number of farms apiece, even aside from the fact that their farms were all full farms, and not merely the rented portions of farms made up in part of rented land and in part of land owned by the operators. The owners of the rented portions of the part-owner farms have an average of 571 acres additional as compared with 606 in case of the owners of the full-tenant farms studied. Of all the "additional" farms owned by the multiple landlords studied, only 8.6 per cent are located outside of Nebraska. Nearly four-fifths of them were secured by purchase, a sixth by inheritance, about a thirtieth by gift, and only 9 out of the entire 314 landlords owning other farms than those studied in this survey had obtained their farms by homesteading. In all the points dealt with in this paragraph, the percentages were substantially the same for owners of full-tenant farms as for owners of the rented portions of part-owner farms, except that the latter had ob - tained their other farms by inheritance in between a fourth and a fifth of the cases, instead of only a seventh of the cases. NUMBER OF FARMS PER LANDLORD: 1900-1920 ONE-FARM LANDLORDS We have thus far presented data dealing mainly with the holdings of landlords as a class. We are now ready to discuss in greater detail the diffusion of these holdings among a great number of landlords or their concentration in the hands of a small land-owning group. Among the many questions whose answers we should seek in the field of landlord and tenant problems are two of primary importance: (1) Are farm lands widely scattered in the hands of many owners or concentrated in the hands of a relatively small number? and (2) What change, if any, is going on in this particular? So far as data on number of farms are concerned, the census answers this question rather satisfactorily. This answer is complete and final as regards the farms operated by their owners, as their value and acreage per farm are also the averages per owner - operator, except that owner-operators may own tenant farms of which they are the landlords. No one knows to what extent this is true. We are much further from having satis - factory data as to the concentration of ownership of tenant farms, because of the fact that one landlord may have any number of farms and, as we have just seen, often does have </seg>
            <seg id="p012">2 Nebraska Expi UMEN1 Station, Bulletin 202 Pabi&lt;e 3. — Landlords o. variou, i numbers of rented farms: 1900 W0 l Residence of landlords Landlords of North Central States Nebraska Nebraska United States 1920 1900 1900 1900 juidlords 466 Per cent 100.0 Rented farms with owners reported 997 Per cent 100.0 Per lessor 2.1 Total acreace 218,583 Per cent 100.0 Total value Percent 100.0 Acres per lessor 469.1 Per farm 219.2 Value per lessor Per farm )ne farm apiece 229 Per cent 49.1 Farms 229 Per cent 23.0 Per lessor 10 Total acreage 56,887 Per cent 26.0 Total value Per cent Acres per lessor ■ 248.4 Per farm 248.4 Value per lessor Per farm rwo farms apiece 129 Percent 27.6 Farms 258 Per cent 25.9 Per lessor 2.0 Total acreage 56,537 Per cent 25 8 Total value Per cent Acres per lessor 438.2 Per farm 219.1 Value per lessor Per farm 1-4 farms apiece 74 Percent 15.9 Farms 251 Per cent 25.2 Per lessor .. 3.4 Total acreage 47,329 Percent 21.7 Total value Per cent Acres per lessor 639.6 Per farm 180.6 Value per lessor Per farm i-9 farms apiece 82 Percent : 6.8 Farms 201 Per cent 20.2 Per lessor 6.3 Total acreage 45,990 Percent 21.1 Total value Per cent 29,920 100.0 474,894 100.0 1,256,927 100.0 37,750 100.0 1.3 6,526,304 100.0 162,510,882 100.0 218.1 173.1 5,432 4,305 25,727 85.9 25,727 68.2 1.0 4,563,300 69.9 108,:i01,915 66.6 177.3 177.3 4,210 4,210 MN 7 5,792 15.3 2.0 917,914 14.1 25,902,336 66.6 316.9 158.5 8.944 4,472 920 3.1 3,032 8.1 3.3 497,723 7.6 14,394,401 8.8 541.0 164.1 15,646 4,748 322 1.1 2,091 5.5 6.5 325,111 4.9 9,228,347 5.7 570,195 100.0 1.2 72,928,715 100.0 2,633,833,007 100.0 153.6 127.9 5,546 4,619 419,900 88.4 419,900 73.6 1.0 53,589,918 73.5 1,891,090,259 71.8 127.6 127.6 4,504 4,504 39,124 u 78,248 13.7 2.0 9,971 ,934 13.7 385,514,546 71.8 254.9 127.4 9,854 4,927 12,070 2.5 39,449 6.9 3.3 5,176,312 7.1 198,616,500 7.6 428.9 131.8 16,455 5,035 3,127 0.7 21,184 3.7 6.8 2,654,071 3.6 102,541,652 3.8 1,933,249 100.0 1.5 184,433,683 100.0 4,518,881,942 100.0 146.7 95.4 3,595 2,234 1,005.469 79.9 1,005,469 52.0 1.0 114,944,565 62.3 3,021,532,398 66.8 114.3 114.3 3,005 3,005 142,838 11.3 285,676 14.8 2.0 25,292,206 13.7 646,010,897 66.8 177.1 88.6 4,523 2,262 67,719 U 224,457 11.6 3.3 17,393,538 9.4 378,107,147 8.4 256.8 77.5 5,583 1,686 28,694 2.3 187,981 9.7 6.6 12,812,845 6.9 235,491,794 5.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 13 Table 3. — (Continued) — Landlords of various numbers of rented farms: 1900-1920* Residence of landlords ing the 1900 census figures with the 1920 survey figures. The figures are, of course, not entirely comparable because of (1) the vastly greater number of farms covered by the census enumeration, and (2) the necessity for relying in the survey almost entirely upon information furnished by tenants as to their landlords' other holdings. In some other states there might be a strong tendency for the ignorant tenant to magnify his report of the holdings of the landlord, whose other farms he did not know very well, if at all. In the Nebraska areas studied, however, it is probable that the facts were understated rather than overstated by reason of the tendency to state only that which was definitely known, and the probability that absentee landlords in some cases, have farms elsewhere of which the tenants have no knowledge. Landlords of North Central States 1 Nebraska Nebraska United States 1920 1900 1900 1900 Acres per lessor Per farm Value per lessor Per farm )ver 9 farms apiece Per cent Farms .». Per cent Per lessor Total acreage Per cent Total value Per cent Acres per lessor Per farm Val ie per lessor Per farm 437.2 228.8 ........ . .„ .. 0.5 58 5.5 29.0 11,840 5.4 ;:::;; "6,920.6 204.1 1,009.7 155.5 43,325 4,414 55 M 1,108 2.9 20.1 222,256 3.4 4,683,883 2.9 4,041.0 200.6 85,161 4,227 848.8 125.3 32,792 2,016 673 0.1 11,414 2.0 16.7 1,536,480 2.1 56,070,070 2.1 2,268.2 134.6 83,314 4,912 446.5 68.2 8,207 1.253 12,207 0.9 229,666 UJ 18.8 13,990,531 7.6 237,739,706 5.2 1,146.1 60.9 19,475 1,035 'Figures for 1920 original. Comparative figures for 1900 compiled from As rwelfth Census 1900, Volime V, Page LXXXVIII, Table LXXXVIII, and Pal Fhe North Central states as grouped by the 1900 census are Ohio, Indiana. I] Wisconsin, Minnesota, Iowa, North Dakota, South Dakota, Nebraska, and Kai Ericulture. Part I, «?e 312, Table 23. llinois, Michigan, nsas. more than one. Only in connection with the Twel taken in 1900 did the Census Bureau secure data i followed by the publication of the number, value, a of farms per landlord, altho at all recent census* been given data with regard to the average acreagi per tenant farm. It therefore seems worth while to determin multiple landlordism is increasing or decreasing 1 Ifth Census which were ind acreage es we have e and value ie whether by compar- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 In spite of this probability of a less complete survey re - port for 1920 than was secured by the 1900 census, the 1920 figures seem to show a tendency toward the concentration of greater numbers of farms in the hands of smaller numbers of landlords. Studies made by the United States Department of Agriculture do not indicate that this is generally true thru - out the country. Dr. L. C. Gray, Economist in charge of the Division of Land Economics of the Department, authorizes the statement that his division has undertaken a study of the degree of concentration of ownership of tenant farms in which the 1900 census methods were applied with modifications to select areas in various parts of the United States. None of these areas were located in Nebraska. No general statement of the results can be announced at this time. The Nebraska survey figures are as indicated in these pages in spite of the omission of outstanding landlords such as the famous Scully estate. A number of these super-multiple landlords owned farms in the areas studied. Their other farms are not includ - ed in Table 3 for the reasons that (1) data with regard to their other farms were not available and (2) they are not typical Nebraska farm landlords. Such cases were doubtless included by the more complete study of 1900. Of 466 owners of full-tenant farms studied in the survey in 1920, 229 or nearly half owned only one farm each. Altho these one-farm owners were nearly half of the total number of landlords, they had only about a quarter of the total aci-e&amp;ge. This is in marked contrast with the much greater importance of the one-farm landlords of the United States as a v.'hcle in 1900 when 80 per cent owned only a farm apiece, totaling as many farms as all the other landlords combined, with a combined value more than one and one - half times as great as all the rest of the rented farms, and a combined acreage twice as great. If we compare the 1920 Nebraska figures with the 1900 figures for the North Central States and for Nebraska separately from the rest of this group, we have almost as great a contrast as that just stated. In 1900, 73.6 per cent of the rented farms in the North Central States and 68.2 per cent of the rented farms in Nebraska were owned by men who owned no other farms, and their owners included 88.4 per cent of the owners in the North Central States and 85.9 per cent of the Nebraska owners. As we have just seen, 49.1 per cent of the Nebraska landlords studied in 1920 fell into the group of those owning but one farm apiece. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 15 TWO-FARM LANDLORDS In the United States in 1900, about 1 landlord out of every 9 (11.3 per cent) had two farms, but the two-farm landlords had a little more than their proportionate per - centages of farms (14.8), acreage (13.7), and land value (14.3). In Nebraska in 1900, 9.7 per cent of all landlords had two farms apiece but they owned 15.3 per cent of all the rented farms, 14.1 per cent of the acreage, and 15.9 per cent of the land value. By 1920 more than a quarter of the landlords included in the survey had two farms apiece, and ;hey owned a little more than a quarter of the farms and of the acreage. In 1900 but not in 1920, therefore, the two - farm landlords seem to have had a little more than their proportionate share of the rented farms. Each is able to provide two sons with a farm apiece. Doubtless in many cases he is already renting the two farms to sons or sons - in-law. THREE-OR-MORE-FARM LANDLORDS The landlords who rent three or more farms comprise the only group which has very much more than its propor - tionate share of acreages and of land value as compared with other groups of landlords, saying nothing here as to the landlords' per capita wealth compared with that of the owner who farms his own land, the tenant, or that of any other member of society, urban or rural. These three-or - more-farm landlords existed in 1900, but they were less than 10 per cent of all landlords in the United States, and less - than 5 per cent in Nebraska, while in the North Central States as a group they were only about 3 per cent of all land - lords. By 1920, however, they constituted nearly a quarter of all landlords studied in connection with the survey, and owned 50.9 per cent of all the farms of all landlords and 48.2 per cent of all the acreage. Other land holdings. — Nearly two-thirds of the farms studied in the Geneva area were owned by landlords who had other farm land also. They usually had two or three farms apiece, but one had eleven, one sixteen, and one forty farms. One had even rented his own land to a tenant and then become a tenant on another farm which he had rented and was operating. Nine others were personally operating other land, but they were owner-operators rather than tenants. The landlords of nearly half of the farms studied had all their assets invested in farm land and had no income except farm rental. About a quarter of the landlords were </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 at that time intending to increase their land holdings. No information was available with regard to the remainder. One had sold four farms since 1910 and eight others one farm apiece. Of the 66 landlords, 33 had sold no land since 1910, but the tenants in the remaining cases gave no infor - mation. In more than 6 cases out of every 7 the farms studied were not for sale, during the winter of 1920 when this area was studied in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement. KINDS OF LANDLORDS We have dealt thus far with the landlords' functions, power, and responsibilities. We come now to consider the landlord himself and his relations with the tenant. Land - lords may be classified upon various bases, such as occupa - tion, degree of ownership, sex, age, nativity, and distance of residence from farm. Retired owner. — The landlord stage may, in many cases, be thought of as the topmost rung of the agricultural ladder, whose lower rungs are birth on farm, boyhood on farm, hired man, tenant, owner, and finally retired owner or landlord. Of course, not all farmers have passed thru all of these stages, and some have passed thru other stages, such as birth in town, or living off the farm for a portion of life. As we shall see more in detail, not all landlords are retired owners. Sooner or later any farmer becomes too old to continue active farm operation. He may also stop farming for any one of a great number of other reasons, such as discourage - ment because of hard work, or poor returns, or both, in - efficiency on his part, or such success that he is able and prefers to retire. If he has been a farm owner, he now (1) sells his land, (2) rents it to a son or other near rela - tive, (3) rents it to someone else, or (4) may give it to a son and thus not become a landlord. In either the second or the third case a landlord results, but in case of renting to a son, son-in-law, or other near relative, landlordship is likely to be subordinated to family consideration. The retiring or "retreating" farmer may retain ownership to assure his life income, or to protect the interests of those of his family who have gone to other farms or to other occupations. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 17 Other landlords. — By no means are all landlords re - tired farmers. A little less than half fall into this class. In addition to (1) retired farmers, they include at least (2) widows or heirs of former owners, (3) investors in farm lands, (4) former mortgagees, who became owners by fore - closure, and (5) active farmers. More than a third of the 654 landlords studied fall into this last class of active farmers, who may be either owners or tenants on the farms which they are operating. Each is an operator of one farm, Table 4. — The landlord: all areas Unspecified distributed proportionately in computing percentages, but not in stating absolute numbers All farms Tenant farms Part-owner and a landlord of one or more others. The landlords who are experienced farmers are at least three times as numerous among those studied as are those of no farm experience. The landlord of farm experience may be of considerable leader - ship value, if he lives in or near the community and takes an interest in it. arms Total number Male Female Age in years Under 50 50—60 Over 60 Nationality American Other Occupation Retired farmer . Active fanner. . Other Distance from farm On same farm . . . Less than 1 mile 1 — 5 miles 5 — 10 miles Over 10 miles 1 Out of state I- - F I 1= Per cent Per cent Per cent 654 iOO.O 495 100.0 159 100.0 497 82.8 389 81.4 108 88.5 103 j 17.2 89 18.6 14 11.5 178 32.4 137 31.5 41 36.0 203 37.0 158 36.3 45 39.5 168 30.6 140 32.2 28 24.5 387 77.2 298 76.4 89 | 80.2 114 22.8 92 23.6 22 19.8 198 47.0 159 ! 47.3 ! 39 45.9 143 34.0 116 I 34.5 | 27 31.8 80 19.0 61 j 18.2 19 22.3 31 | 5.5 24 5.3 7 6.1 27 ! 4.8 17 I 3.8 10 8.7 232 41.2 197 43.8 36 30.7 118 i 20.9 94 21.0 24 21.0 108 19.2 78 17.4 30 26.3 47 • 8.4 39 8.7 8 7.0 • ' I 'But in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 In the central Fillmore County area about Geneva, infor - mation was obtained with regard to more than 60 landlords which was not obtained in any of the other areas studied. Nearly a quarter were still living on the same farms, usually without any employment, but sometimes with other than farm employment which they pursued from residence on their farms. In two cases they were overseeing and helping on the farms and in one case the landlord was also a hired farm laborer on his own farm. Landlords as full owners and part-owners. — A quarter of the landlords studied in the survey own only parts of the farms studied — the rented acreages of part-owner farms. Such owners are more generally non-residents and below sixty years of age. They are only about two-thirds as fre - quently women, and are much less frequently foreign-born. Sex of landlords. — Men are the landlords rather than women in the ratio of more than 4 to 1 among tenant farms and nearly 8 to 1 among part-owners' landlords. The ratio is about 4 to 1 in eastern Nebraska full tenant cases, and 5 to 1 in the case of the rented portions of the part-owner farms, but in the westermost or Grant area the ratio is 10 to 1 for full-tenant farms and 40 to 1 for the rented portions of the part-owner farms. In the Milligan area, however, women are almost half as frequently landlords as men, and in the Stromsburg area the ratio is about 5 men to 2 women. A third of the women (34.5 per cent) and nearly half of the men landlords are related to their tenants. The women are usually mothers, but sometimes are mothers-in-law, or sisters of their tenants. One man reported himself as a tenant on his wife's farm. Perhaps there were others who might have given similar reports but who preferred to be listed as owners with or without statements that ownership came by marriage. The widowed women in this group are doubtless in most cases the widows of former farmer owner - operators of the farms, but may be the widows of men who gained ownership or landlordship in any of the ways enumer - ated above. They may even have gained ownership after widowhood. Age. — The landlords fall into three age groups of fairly equal size: (1) those under fifty years of age, (2) those between fifty and sixty, and (3) those over sixty. The average age is 54.3 years — 53.7 years among the men, and 56.4 years among the women. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 19 Foreign or Native. — Foreign-born landlords are more than a quarter as numerous as those of American birth in the areas studied. The foreign-born are more numerous among landlords than among owner-operators, tenants, hired men, or any other group studied. The reasons are rather obvious. They are the older men, who first settled Nebraska, or came fairly soon after its first settlement. We were then drawing very heavily upon the foreign-born for the develop - ment of our farms. Of these foreign-born landlords, 29.4 per cent had native-born sons or sons-in-law as tenants. The percentage of foreign-born landlords will naturally and in - evitably decrease rapidly in the next decade or two. As time sweeps away the landlords we now have, they will undoubt - edly b^ replaced by native-born landlords or owner-operators in practically all cases. In many cases, of course, these will be the native-born sons of present foreign-born landlords. In the Stromsburg area in Polk County there are more foreign-born than native-born landlords, and in the Milligan area in Fillmore County the foreign-born are eleven times as numerous as native-born landlords. These areas suggest what must be true of many others in which the land has been more or less completely settled and retained by the foreign - born and their descendants. In some such areas, the per - centage of foreign-born landlordship and of tenancy are re - duced by such devices as the so-called "Bohemian contract." This contract substitutes ownership for tenancy. It is ordinarily made part of a deed to a son, and binds him to make a rixed annual payment to his parents or otherwise provide for them as long as they live. Occupational Summary. — The landlords studied may be divided into three occupational groups: (1) retired farmers, (2) active farmers, or (3) non-farmers. More than four - fifths are active or retired farmers and some others have had farm experience at some time in their lives. These frac - tions are higher in the southwestern Nebraska areas studied than in the areas farther east. They include only those whose tenants know them to have had such experience, as the tenants furnished all the information. In a number of areas there were practically no landlords whose tenants knew them to be entirely without farm experience, but in all there were some whose tenants were unable to say positively that they had ever lived on farms. Residence. — More than 3 out of every 5 landlords studied live within ten miles of the farms, and another out </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 of every 10 or 11 lives within fifteen miles, while less than 1 out of every 10 lives outside of Nebraska. One out of every 20 or 25 lives on the same farm with his tenant, and another out of every 25 lives within a mile of the farm of which he is the landlord. In Nebraska, non-resident land - lords, therefore, seem to be a very small minority of the total. They are in most cases near enough to be in very close touch with their tenants. This should enable them to take the greatest interest in their farms and in the communities about their farms. In the southwestern Nebraska areas, fewer landlords live within a mile of their farms and fewer entirely outside the state than is the case in eastern Nebraska. Residence: 1900-1920. — Three-fourths of the 495 full - tenant farms studied in 1920 were owned by landlords who lived in the same county with their tenants, as compared with three-fifths in Nebraska in 1900. In 1900 r 1 out of about every 5 landlords of Nebraska farms lived within the state but outside the county within which his farm was located, 6 as compared with 1 out of every 7 or 8 in 1920 ; and 1 out of every 7 or 8 lived entirely outside the state of Nebraska as compared 1 with 1 out of every 11 or 12 (8.7 per cent) in 1920. If the 1920 percentages are not based upon too small a number of tenants to represent the whole, we can conclude from them that non-resident landlords are decreasing in the percentage which they constitute of all Nebraska landlords. Regarding landlordism as a form of credit enabling tenants to use land they have not money to buy leads us to conclude that as the state grows older each county is be - coming better able to meet its own credit needs and less de - pendent upon other counties and other states. This is un - doubtedly true of livestock, farm machinery, and other equip - ment, as well as of land, but we have no such definite data at hand enabling us to state for what percentages of credit for these things Nebraska tenants or other farmers had to go outside their own communities, counties, or state, either at present or at earlier times. In 1900, the Nebraska counties were less completely able to meet such land credit needs than those of either the United States as a whole or the North Central States as a whole, for both were older than Nebraska Kid had higher percentages of the owners of their tenant rmers living in the same counties with the farms) which they owned and much lower percentages living in other • Agriculture, Vol. 5. Twelfth Census of the United States 1900, 310-311. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 21 states. At that time three-quarters of all the tenant farms in the United States and more than two-thirds of those in the North Central States, of which Nebraska is one, were owned by landlords living in the same county as compared with three-fifths in Nebraska. 7 The 1900 figures seem to indicate for Nebraska, the North Central States as a whole, and the United States as a whole, that resident landlords' farm lands have a smaller average acreage value per landlord and that a little greater per - centage of cash than of share tenants' landlords are non - residents. BUSINESS RELATIONS WITH TENANTS The remainder of our discussion will deal with the busi - ness relation of landlords and their tenants. The family rela - tionship between two-fifths of Nebraska landlords and their tenants has already been discussed in another bulletin, 8 which briefly states the effect of family relationship in softening the terms of tenant contracts. TERMS OF LEASES Important. — The terms of 654 leases were fully enough reported for study. Of these, 495 were cases of full-tenant farms, and the other 159 were those of the rented portions of part-owner farms. As the terms of the contract and the spirit in which they are made and met constitutes the heart of the tenancy problem, the practice of farmers on this point is well worth study. A knowledge of the general practice of others who are farming under similar conditions is one of the best guides we can get for our own practice. If we wish to improve that practice, we should first study and under - stand that which we propose to improve. Written contracts. — Written and oral contracts appear to be about equally frequent, with the written contract pre - dominating only among share-cash and cash tenants. Two - thirds of the cash tenants reported written contracts. The principal area peculiarities, in the matter of written contracts, occur in the Walthill area in Thurston County, in the two areas in which farmers of foreign birth or immediate foreign descent predominate, and in the westernmost or Grant area in Perkins County where written contracts are 7 Same. ■ The Nebraska Farm Family : Some land tenure phases. Univ. of Nebraska. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 185. 1922. pp. 32. figs. 8. Lincoln. Out of print </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 22 Table 5. — The written lease, its terms and renewals Unspecified distributed proportionately in computing percentages, but not in stating absolute numbers Tenants All Part- operators | owners Share- All cash Share I Cash Written renewals 143 25.6 I 45 34.3 108 25.2 75J 32.5 19| 12.4 14! 31.1 Length of contract a little more frequent than in most other areas, particularly among part-owners, almost two-thirds of whom have written contracts. This is doubtless because of the large number of non-resident landlords who are renting land in this area. In Thurston County written contracts were found in a high per - centage of the cases because they are always used in case of Indian lands. Written renewals are the exception rather than the rule among both full tenants and part-owners. They are hardly to be expected between landlords and tenants who have no written contracts but are entered into by only about half of those who do have written contracts. Importance of written contracts. — From a number of standpoints it is unfortunate that written contracts are not more generally used. About the only thing that can be said in favor of the oral contract in so important a matter is that it is evidence of the faith of the parties in one another. The written contract, however, need not arise from distrust, but only from a wise and prudent desire to prevent misunder - standing which may arise between the most honest and re - liable men, who may have very different understandings as to what has been expressly stipulated, to say nothing of the Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent] Percent .654 100.0 1S9 100.0 495 100.0 276 100.0 167 100.0 52 100.0 . . 302 49.8 74 50.7 228 46.9 151 55.7 43 26.4 34 66.8 'ot»l number leases Written contract iy»' 2 years 3 years 4 years 5 years Over 5 years Average years . tegin in March . . Other months. . . tenewals by December 1 .... January 1 February 1 March 1 July 1 Other months. . . 322 75.0 71 69.8|251 76.5 158 14 :i.2 1 0.9 | 13 3.9 71 34 7.9 12 11.7 22 6.7 121 4 0.9 1 0.9 3 0.9 01 31 12. 9 8.8 22 6.7 8 25 5.8 8 7.8 17 5.2 6 2.2 ... 2.8 ... 1.9 ... 491 98.9 109 99.0 382 98.8 217 6 1.1 1 0.9 5 12 1 0 0.0 0 0.0 0 0.0 0 24 9.9 11 25.6 18 6.5 4 1 0.4 0 0.0 1 0.5 1 204 84.0 29 67.5 175 87.5 109 6 2.4 0 0.0 6 3.0 5 8 3.3 3 6.9 I 5 2.5 3 \' 83.2 76 3.7 3 6.3 4 0.0 1 42 4 1 2.6 10 ! 1.6 99.5 120 0.5 4 0.0 0 3.3 2 0.8 j 0 89.5 39 •1.1 1 U 2 77.fi 17j 42.5 3.0 3! 7.5 4.1 6 15.(1 1.0 2| 5.0 4.1 1101 25.0 in.'-' ! 2! 5.0 2.2 . . 2.9 96.8 45 100.0 32 | 0 0.0 0.0 0 0.0 4.5 7 20.6 ii.n I' 0.0 88.7 127 79.1 2.3 i (I ll.ll 4.5 (I ll.ll l l i i l ' i l </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 23 things which each takes for granted but which conflict with something the other takes for granted. The custom of the community is some help in determining what should be done, in case all agree that there was no stipulation. Because of some of these sources of difficulty, the laws of the various states quite generally provide that contracts of certain classes, including those for the rental of farm land, are not enforce - able at law unless they are in writing. This is part of one of the provisions of the Statute of Frauds which originated in England in 1676, but which with some modifications is in force in Nebraska and other states. Length of contract. — The one-year contract predomin - ates in all areas, altho there are a few three- and five-year contracts, and a few for more than five years. The average length of contract is nearly three years in case of part-owners, and not quite two years in case of full tenants. These short contracts must not be confused with short stays on the same farm. Many, if not practically all, of the contracts reported as for one year might better be termed year-to-year con - tracts or standing contracts. In landlords' or tenants' meet - ings, there is an almost universal aversion to a contract for a period of years. Long term tenancy and short term con - tracts often go together, contradictory as they might seem. On substantially these same farms on which the contracts ran for an average of less than two years, the average length of time between changes of tenants has been 7.7 years. 0 It is not uncommon in meetings of tenants or landlords to hear statements to the effect that "I am working under a one-year contract, but have been associated with the same man ten (or in many cases fifteen or eighteen) years. We under - stand one another, but if a misunderstanding ever occurs, we are not tied together by a long time contract." Long contracts have been urged by some on the ground that they make it possible for the tenant to make improve - ments, follow good farming methods instead of soil mining, or to equip himself to engage in livestock" farming, dairy farm - ing, or some other type of farming which requires a consider - able period of time on the same farm. Some of these ad - vantages can be attained in part, at least, by a proper under - standing between the tenant and landlord and an agreement in advance that the tenant may make the needed improve - ments and be paid their value at time of moving, if he should ' Nebraska Farm Tenancy : Some Community Phases. Univ. of Nebraska. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1923. pp. 52. figs. 25. Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 be compelled to leave before he has received the full benefit of his expenditures. In other countries, laws have provided compensation for unexhausted improvements, but in this country this matter is thus far left largely to individual agreement. The unavoidable objections to long-term rental contracts appear to be (1) the undesirability of keeping men together after cordial relations have ceased to exist, and (2) the pos - sibility of market changes in the prices of farm products which will greatly reduce or increase the rental value of the farm. This second objection is especially important in case of cash rent and may be very well illustrated by considering what would have happened in case of a five-year, cash rental contract entered into in 1914 or 1919 on the basis of the cash rental values generally prevailing during those years. In the former case the land-owner would have lost, and in the latter case the tenant would have had a contract under which the losses, coming to him from normal farm operations during the depression which followed, would have been greatly in - creased because under a long-time contract he could not com - pel the landlord to share the loss. Possibly we may some time have a sliding rental scale, sufficiently well worked out and sufficiently well understood by all parties concerned, and adaptable to all grades of land, so that we can have the long - term rental contract without this disadvantage, but this prob - lem is so complicated as to be very difficult of solution. In practically every case the contract takes effect in March, but in the winter wheat regions there is provision in most cases for plowing and sowing during the fall prior to taking possession or for harvesting a crop after giving possession, or for both. This is in substantial agreement with 8,000 Nebraska answers to the question, "Letting 100 per cent represent the total number of tenants who moved onto farms in the past year, what per cent took place each month?" 10 Replies to this question indicate that 6 out of every 7 Nebraska farm tenants who moved in 1922, moved during the month of March, 1 out of every 12 or 13 in February, 1 out of every 30 or 35 in April, and 1 out of every 100 in each of the five months of September, October, November, December, and January, leaving only 1 out of every 100 to be accounted for as moving during the months of May, June, July, and August combined. "Stewart, Charles L.. When do farm tenants move? A preliminary statement issued in April, 1923, by the Division of Land Economics. Bureau of Agricultural Economics, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 25 Only in Iowa did even a slightly greater percentage of the year's change of occupancy of tenant farms occur in March. In no other state did three-fourths of the changes occur in any one month, but in all there is apparent the same general basic principle of making the change at a time when (1) farm work is at a low ebb, and (2) one cycle of crop raising or other farm operations is completed and another has not yet been begun. So far as the crops are concerned, Nebraska offers unusually good opportunity for a clean-cut break. Supplies on hand are lower in March. The crop cycle has been completed for some months except in case of winter wheat, and roads are usually in shape to permit moving in time for the beginning of spring work. Date of renewal is also reported as March 1, if reported at all, but the enumerators have apparently construed this as applying to the date when the old contract ends and the new contract begins and not to the date upon which it is agreed that such an extension shall be made. The proper time for making renewals depends upon the crop raised, but should be long enough in advance of the March moving period to enable the landlord to get a good tenant or the tenant to make satisfactory arrangement for his next year's opera - tions elsewhere. In many cases, in the winter wheat belt, this means as early as the preceding June or July. WHAT EACH CONTRIBUTES Real estate. — The landlord contributes all the real estate in case of the full tenant farm and all the land with relation to which he is landlord in case of the part-owner farm. Repairs, depreciation, insurance, and taxes go rather naturally with the land, buildings, and other improvements, which constitute the real estate. They are paid by the land - lord in about 19 cases out of every 20. He also pays the insur - ance in about 3 cases out of every 4, and in most other cases no insurance is carried in any organized company by either landlord or tenant on any part of the real estate. This, of course, means that in fact the landlord is carrying his own insurance, because he suffers any loss or depreciation which may occur. Only about 1 tenant out of every 21 pays the taxes. Operating expense. — Labor is, of course, the main con - tribution of the tenant to the partnership of landlord and tenant, for the relation may be thought of as a partnership of two men to supply the necessary land, labor, capital </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 26 Table 6. — What each contributes Unspecified distributed proportionately in computing percentages, but not in stating absolute numbers All Part-owners Pull tenants Landlords Tenants j Landlords Tenants i Landlords &gt; Tenants goods, and risk-taking. The wealth produced by the enter - prise is then to be divided upon some pre-arranged basis. Nineteen tenants out of every 20 furnished work animals, breeding stock, seed, and binder twine, and paid threshing bills. Siloing, when practiced at all, was usually done by the tenant, but occasionally by the landlord. Tenants also usually delivered crops, and in 19 cases out of 20 paid other marketing charges. Machinery, also, was furnished by 19 tenants out of every 20, — by only 1 landlord out of 20. THE DIFFERENT AREAS Western areas. — In the Cambridge area, mainly in Fur - nas County, there appears to be a much more clean-cut division than in any other area, on the basis of the land - lord's furnishing the land, and the tenant's furnishing abso - lutely everything except real estate, except that in one case the landlord furnished half of the seed and in one case bore half of the threshing expense. In the Grant area in Perkins County, on the other hand, labor and all other items except real estate were contributed jointly by landlord and tenant in greater percentages of cases than in any other area. In this area a quarter or more of the landlords of full-tenant farms bore one or more apiece of the following items: work animals, breeding stock, twine, and threshing charges. Some landlords bore the entire charge and others only a part of the charge. \Percenl\ \Per&lt;xnt\ Pmxnl\ \Perctnt\ \Ptr&lt;xnt\ \Pcrcent 'otal number farms i Repairs I fepreciation I axe. I ns jrancf • .*bor fork animals ! ireediig stock Seed wine 'hrMhing iloing Irop delivery iarketing charge Machinery 654 100.0 i;.".l 100.0 159 100.0 1591 100.0 111.". 100.0 495 100.0 527 94.3 32 5.7 110 91.7 10 8.3 417 95.0 22 5.0 548 96.6 19 3.4 120 94.5 7 5.5 428 97.3 I 12 2.7 540 94.5 31 6.5 116 94.3 7 6.7 424 94.6 24 5.1 400 96.4 15 3.6 66 86.8 10 13.2 334 j 98.5 5 1.5 10 4.0 240 96.0 1 1.5 67 98.5 91 4.9 1731 95.1 33 5.4 571 94.6 2 1.5 128 98.5 31 i 6.6 443 93.4 29 4.8 573 95.2 2 1.5 128 98.5 27! 5.7 445! 94.3 38 6.2 572 93.8 2 1.5 128 98.5 I 36 7.5 444 92.5 24 4.0 575 96.0 1 0.8 128 99.2 ! 23; 4.9 1447 95.1 28 4.6 576 95.4 2 1.5 128 98.5 j 261 5.5 448 94.5 11 2.8 381 97.2 1 1.5 67 98.5 | 10 3.1 314 96.9 10 1.9 5181 98.1 1 0.9 119 99.1 9 2.2 399 97.8 j 21 3.6 1571! 96.4 2 1.5 128 98.5 19 4.1 443! 95.9 28 4.7 571 95.3 j 2! 1.5 128 98.5 26 5.5 1443 94.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 27 Fairfield-Clay Center area in Clay County. — One land- lord furnished all work animals, breeding stock, and ma - chinery, and paid marketing charges. Another furnished half the seed and half the cost of twine, threshing, crop de - livery, marketing charge, machinery, breeding stock, and work stock. A third furnished half the seed and half the cost of twine, threshing, and crop delivery. Walthill area in Thurston County. — Two tenants paid taxes on buildings, and one on eighty acres, of the farm; three landlords furnished half of the work stock; two fur - nished half of the breeding stock; two furnished half of the seed ; one paid half the threshing expenses ; and three fur - nished machinery. Filley area in Gage County. — One landlord furnished half of every item listed in the table, and three furnished half of the seed. Milligan area in Fillmore Cpunty. — One landlord fur- nished half of the seed and threshing expense, but his tenant paid the taxes. Nehawka area in Cass County. — The landlord supplied in 11 cases half the seed, in 9 cases half the work animals, in 6 cases half the breeding stock, in 6 cases half the twine, in 6 cases half the threshing, in 4 cases half the machinery, in 1 case half the marketing charges, and in 1 case half of the work. Summary. — From such a varied showing it is a little hard to generalize as to what each contributed beyond the obviously to be expected contribution of (1) land by the land - lord, and (2) labor by the tenant. Beyond that, it may be suggested that (3) everything else is usually furnished by the tenant, but that (4) the landlord more frequently fur - nishes seed, work animals, breeding animals, and machinery than anything else, not directly connected with real estate, and that (5) these variable items, which depart from the usual custom, result from (a) variations in agreement as to division of product, (b) bargaining concessions, (c) the soft - ening of terms extended to kinsman tenants, and (d) mis - cellaneous, similar considerations. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 28 PERCENTAGES FURNISHED BY LANDLORD AND TENANT The figures of Table 7 show what percentage of the per - sonal property was furnished by the landlord and what per - centage by the tenant. They are based upon inventory values, while the figures of Table 6 are based upon entries indicating who paid each charge but not how much was paid. Table 6, therefore, shows numbers and percentages of landlords and tenants while Table 7 shows percentages of value. All cash includes cash tenants who furnished 100 per cent in alt cases. 90 and 99 per cent. Part-owners' percentages were higher than those of full tenants, as might be expected from the greater age and economic well-being of the part-owners. The principal exception to this statement appears in the land - lords' furnishing four times as great a proportion of the part-owners' work stock as of the tenants'. Table 7 agrees with Table 6 in indicating that the land - lord is more likely to help in furnishing breeding stock than work stock. The term "other machinery" includes the great bulk of the farm machinery — all except automobiles, tractors, ;enants studied f urr isted in Table 7, wl from 70 to 100 per &lt; iish all the operating property of the kinds lile other tenants and part-owners furnish :ent. Most of the groups average between Table 7. — Perce stages furnished by landlord and tenant On tenant farms * if Part-G &gt;wners , i 01 ,11 cattle Milk cows Calves Other cattle ill horses and mules. Work stock Other horses and mules &gt;ther animals Hogs Poultry Miscellaneous i U machinery Automobiles Tractors Trucks Manure spreaders . . Other machinery . . . "unds on hand Tnsold crops i rowing crops 'eed, seed, etc Land- lord 7.3 5.5 4.6 3.1 7.2 4.9 4.5 6.6 5.1 5.5 3.3 5.6 10.9 4.3 1.6 2.3 10.4 18.7 1.6 6.3 2.4 5.3 I iTenant 92.7 94.5 95.4 96.9 92.8 95.1 95.5 93.4 94.9 94.5 96.7 94.4 89.1 95.7 98.4 97.7 89.6 81.3 98.4 93.7 97.6 94.7 Land- lord 5.5 2.9 4.7 4.2 0.8 9.4 10.1 6.7 3.9 2.6 6.7 28.6 6.3 10.0 0.0 0.0 4.9 6.3 0.0 8.2 5.6 6.0 Ml Share-cash j Share Land- Land- Land- Tenant lord Tenant lord Tenant lord Tenant 94.5 8.2 91.8 1.1 98.9 20.1 79.9 97.1 6.9 93.1 1.5 98.5 16.3 83.7 95.3 4.6 95.4 2.4 97.6 10.7 89.3 95.8 I 2.6 97.4 1.0 99.0 9.4 90.6 99.2 10.4 89.6 0.9 99.1 20.5 79.5 90.6 3.2 96.8 1.1 98.9 8.2 91.8 89.9 2.6 97.4 1.0 99.0 6.5 93.5 93.3 6.6 93.4 1.3 98.7 14.0 86.0 96.1 5.7 94.2 1.8 98.2 13.6 86.4 97.4 7.1 92.9 1.6 98.4 14.8 85.2 93.3 2.4 97.6 1.2 98.8 6.1 93.9 71.4 2.5 97.5 2.8 97.2 0.0 100.0 93.7 14.2 85.7 0.7 99.3 85.4 64.6 90.0 1.4 98.6 1.6 98.4 1.4 98.6 100.0 1.9 98.1 0.0 100.0 11.1 88.9 100.0 6.9 93.1 0.8 99.2 | 10.5 89.5 95.1 14.5 85.4 5.7 94.3 I 27.0 73.0 93.7 23.4 76.6 0.6 99.4 46.7 53.3 100.0 2.3 97.7 0.0 100.0 6.0 94.0 91.8 5.0 96.0 2.3 97.7 7.2 92.8 94.4 1.3 98.7 0.0 100.0 2.9 97.1 94.0 5.1 94.9 0.0 100.0 14.7 85.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 29 trucks, and manure spreaders, which are separately enumer - ated in the table. Landlords furnish a larger share of the machinery than of any other property listed in Table 6. On share tenants' farms landlords furnish a fifth of the personal property needed in operating, on part-owners' farms a twentieth, and on share-cash rented farms only 1 per cent. The landlords of cash tenants as already indicated did not furnish any of the operating property in a single one of the cases studied. The differences between the share and share - cash figures may arise in part from the difference in the part of the state to which these terms are attached and suggest that the western part of the state where the share contract is more frequent is also one in which the landlords more frequently aid by furnishing a share of the operating equip - ment and livestock. Perhaps the family relationship between landlord and tenant is still more important, as more than half of the share tenants were sons, sons-in-law, or otherwise closely related to their landlords as compared with less than a third of the share-cash tenants. The related landlord might reasonably be expected to be much more likely, to furnish machinery and livestock for the use of the tenant in operating the farm. Most important of all probably is the fact that the partnership lease under which the landlord is very likely to furnish livestock and machinery is almost sure to fall into the share tenant class. The Milligan area in Fillmore County and the Fairfield- Clay Center area in Clay County are the only two in which the landlords of part-owners furnish any of the cattle. Here they furnish 53 and 69 per cent respectively. The landlords of share-cash tenants share in the ownership of the cattle in only three areas — the Filley area in Gage County, the Fair - field-Clay Center area in Clay County, and the Stromsburg area in Polk County. The landlord owns a larger or smaller interest in the cattle in all areas except the Milligan area in Fillmore County and the Cambridge area largely in Furnas County but extending over a little into adjoining counties. COMPENSATION, SUPERVISION OF FARMS, AND WORK DONE BY LANDLORDS Compensation for improvements and unexhausted facil- ities. — The possibilities of removing some of the causes of frequent change of farms by compensation for improvement and unexhausted facilities has just been suggested. Altho English law and custom provide for these practices, they are unusual in the United States, but not quite unknown in Ne- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 30 braska as indicated by Table 8, which suggests that about 1 Nebraska tenant farmer or part-owner out of every 200 has some provision for compensation for unexhausted fertility, as compared with about four times as great a proportion who have provision for compensation for improvements made by tenants. One out of every 50 or 60 has an agreement under which he is to be paid for work done on the improvements. All three of these provisions were reported by both full tenants and part-owners in about the same percentages of cases. Table 8. — Compensation, trips to farm, and work done by landlord, Unspecified distributed proportionately in computing percentages, but not in stating absolute numbers Not at all 6 1.7 5 1.8 2| 1.2 2 2.3 1 Days work done per year on Day» Days Days \ Dam Days [ 1)&lt; Improvements 26 14.8 25 15.1 14 10.0 | 10 23.3 1 5.0 1 Livestock 7 77.7 7 77.7 2 61.5 I 5 84.2 0 . 0.0 0 Crops 19 39.4 16 40.6 7 13.8 9 61.3 Visits of landlord. — Less than one tenant out of every 50 reports that his landlord never visits the farm altho many ril to give any report at all on this point. One out of every or 7 receives weekly visits, and about 1 out of every 5, monthly visits. One out of every 7 or 8 reported visits only three times a year, and about as many received visits twice a year, but one out of about every 3 or 4 received only annual visits. Part-owners differed from tenants mainly in the much greater proportion who received only annual visits from their landlords. This proportion was nearly half among part - owners, but only about 1 out of every 4 or 5 among full ten- I I Tenants AU I ' , : operators I Share- Part- | All cash Share Cash ! owner? Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Pera 'oUl number 654 100.0 495 100.0 276 100.0 167 100.0 52 100.0 159 100 Compensation for Unexhausted fertility 3 0.5 2 0.4 1 0.4 1 0.6 0 0.0 1 0 Improvements 14 2.1 11 22 6 22 5 3.0 0 0.0 3 1 Work on improvements... 11 1.7 7 1.4 1 0.4 4 2.4 2 3.8 4 2 jindlord'a visits Each day 24 6.8 22 7.8 3 1.9 18 20.5 1 2.8 2 2 Each week 54 155 47 16.7 18 11.4 21 23.8 8 22.2 7 9 Each month 73 20.5 60 21.5 36 22.8 21 23.8 3 8.3 13 17 Every two months 3 0.8 2 0.7 1 0.6 0 0.0 1 2.8 1 1 Every four months 46 12.9 37 13.1 27 17.1 6 6.8 4 11.1 9 12 Every six months 49 13.8 43 15.2 33 20.9 6 6.8 41 11.1 6 8 Each year 100 28.2 66 23.4 38 24.1 14 15.9 14 38.9 34 46 ■ ' </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 31 ants. This doubtless arises in part from the fact that the part-owner usually owns his buildings and the landlord has no occasion to come often to inspect them. Work done by landlords. — As many landlords worked on improvements on their farms as on livestock and crops combined. This work was practically all done on full tenant farms. The landlords who worked on livestock on their ten - ants' farms did five or six times as much work apiece as those who worked on improvements, but the numbers work - ing on livestock were so small as to make chance cases of an unusual nature much more likely to affect the figures. The fact that practically no landlords' work was done on the farms of cash tenants is explained in part by the fact that a large num - ber of these cash tenants were in the Thurston area about Walthill and were the tenants of Indian landlords. It is further explained by (1) the distance of cash tenants' landlords from their farms, (2) the poorer improvements of these farms, and (3) the general lack of touch between cash tenants and their landlords. LANDLORD'S SHARE The landlord's most frequent share is one-third of the product. He practically never receives less, but his share Is not infrequently more than one-third. A dozen corn, oats, ALL PART-OWNERS TENANTS FIG. 2. — THE LANDLORD USUALLY GETS A THIRD OR CASH The tenant curve is doubtless more typical of Nebraska. The part-owner curve is abnormally high in cash and low in the hisrher shares for reasons fully stated in the text. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 and forage crop agreements give the landlord only a quarter of the crop, but only one of all the small grain agreements gives him so low a share. Among the share rentals two-fifths is less than half as frequent and the half -share less than a third as frequent as the third-share plan. Cash is paid about a third as frequently as a share. Of course the choice of cash or share and the fraction paid as share rent are both affected by the crop, the section of the state, local custom, soil fertility, and such individual matters as personal preference, bargaining power and un- Tabi-e 9. — Landlord's share 1 'This table presents numbers of crop agreement? — not numbers of farms. If a given farmer rents corn ground for a third and hay land for half, his contract is counted once under each head. If he rents both for a third, two are added in that line. is counted once under each head. usual aid given by the landlord. Pasture can hardly be rented except on a cash basis and much the same may be said of hay land, altho it is occasionally rented for half of the crop. Alfalfa land is even more frequently rented for a third or two-fifths than for half of the crop. Other hay land is prac - tically always rented for cash or for half of the crop. Some farms are rented for the same share or price per acre without regard to the crop raised, but there were so many cases in which the same tenant paid different fractions of different crops or even different cash rentals on land planted to different crops that Table 9 presents the data by crops rather than by farms, as explained by the table foot - note. Changes in rent. — As prices of farm products have risen and fallen cash rental values have varied accordingly during the past few years. The fraction paid as share rent is thought by some to show a tendency to rise from one-third to two-fifths, but a comparison of the Clay County figures for 1917 and 1920 seems to indicate a change in the other direc- Percent .11 2,436 100.0 i quarter ... 13 0.5 . third 1,037 42.6 'wo-fifths. . . 458 18.8 . half 300 12.3 Sub 567 23.3 ttbar 61 2.5 1 All Part- Tenant* owners ~—^^^— — . —^ —^_^_ j — &gt; — ~ — All Share-cash Share Cash Percent Percent Percent \Percenl\ \Percen 529 100.0 1,907 100.0 1,094 100.0 597 j 100.0 216 100.0 5 0.9 8 0.4 2 H.2 « 1.0 0 0.0 265 50.0 772 40.4 506 46.2 266 \ 44.6 0 0.0 62 11.7 396 20.8 317 29.0 79 I 13.2 0 0.0 9 1.7 291 15.3 84 7.7 207 34.7 0 0.0 181 34.3 386 20.3 176 16.1 0 0.0 210 I 97.3 7 1 3 j 54 2.8 | 9 0.8 39 6.5 | 6 2.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 33 tion. 11 On this point Professor H. C. Filley states that "The share of the crop given as rental in eastern Nebraska did increase gradually from about 1900 during a period of several years," but he doubts whether there was any considerable change between 1917 and 1920. What the landlord supplies may easily vary so as to offset much greater changes in share rental than have occurred. In different parts of the state. — Almost all the quarter - share rents are in the newer areas where land is cheap and labor scarce ; two-fifths and half -share rent are rarer in these regions, leaving the third-share more exclusively the rule than in the older areas where land is higher in price. In the Nehawka area in Cass County in the extreme eastern part of the state the third-share is unusual and cash rental not very frequent, the two-fifths share being nearly twice as frequent as the half -share. In the Filley area in Gage County a little farther west the payment of two-fifths and one-third are about equally usual in case of small grains and in the Milligan area in southeastern Fillmore County there was no renting for half of the crop except in case of one wheat and four alfalfa agreements. There was no renting for a quarter and very little for cash except in case of pasture and hay, leaving one-third as the usual rental for wheat and oats ground and two-fifths for corn ground, altho even corn ground rented for a third of the crop in much more than a quarter of the cases in this area. In the Stromsburg area in Polk County also, practically all rental agreements were for one-third or two-fifths of the crop except that alfalfa and other hay ground was usually rented for half of the crop, altho in two cases it was for only a quarter. The payment of a third was distinctly more fre - quent than the payment of two-fifths in case of wheat and oats land and a little more frequent in case of corn ground. In the Clay County area almost every agreement was for one - third of the crop except in case of hay land which was usually rented for cash but sometimes for half of the crop. The "other" methods were mainly cases of free pasture or the use of land without any payment by the tenant, except that he was expected to pay the taxes. It was largely confined to hay and pasture lands and to the western areas studied. 11 Based on ninety-one 1917 records and sixty-eight 1920 records. The 1917 data are quoted from Booster, E. A., Rent Contracts in Typical Counties of the Wheat Belt, United States Department of Agriculture Bulletin 850, April SO, lKt. pp. 1 and 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 TENURE AND RENTAL TERMS BY CROPS Kinds of tenure. — The tenures or methods of holding the land include ownership, part-ownership, and tenancy. Tenancy may in turn be said to be either part-tenancy (part - ownership) or full tenancy and both may in turn be divided into share-cash, share, and cash tenancy. Three of these four kinds of tenants may pay share rent for all or part of their land, but the cash tenant by definition is a farmer who pays cash rental for all the land he rents and farms. Among all three possible kinds of share tenants the quarter-share plan is about equally rare. It is a little more frequent among share tenants and among part-owners, both of whom are more concentrated in the western parts of the state than are share-cash tenants, but only 1 share tenant and part-owner rental agreement out of every 100 provides for payment of as low a share of the product as one-fourth for the use of the land. The third-share is about equally predominant among part-owners, share, and share-cash tenants, but the two-fifths and half-shares are commonest among share tenants and rarest among part-owners. CORN OATS — •—'— ALFALFA FIG. 3. — RENTAL AND KIND OF CROP Alfalfa and other hay ground usually rents for cash but sometimes for a share. Grain land usually rents for a third but sometimes for a larger share or for cash. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 35 Cash agreements are, of course, universal among cash tenants and unknown among share tenants by our very definition of the terms. They are much rarer than share rent among share-cash tenants who are, therefore, much more like share than like cash tenants. They are usually ordinary share tenants except that they pay cash for pasture or hay lands or both, altho in some cases they pay cash for part of their plow land and share for part of it. The rarity of the half and two-fifths payment by part - owners results from the fact that those studied who fall into this tenure group are so largely (1) in western Nebraska where land is relatively cheap and labor relatively more im - portant, (2) on Indian lands which rent for cash, and (3) part-owners who own their farm buildings and, therefore, pay their landlords a smaller share of the product than they would if the landlord furnished buildings as well as land. LANDLORD'S SHARE OF CORN Of all landlords who rented corn land, two-fifths rented on the third-share basis, nearly one-third on the two-fifths basis, more than an eleventh on the half-share basis, and about a seventh for cash. Among part-owners, cash tenancy was three times as prominent as among full tenants, but almost none were on a half-share basis. Concentration of part-owners on the Indian lands of Thurston County accounts for the prominence of cash rental among part-owners as com - pared with full tenants. Share rental of some kind was, therefore, much more prominent among full tenants' corn land leases. Among part-owners a third of the corn was paid as rent almost three times as generally as two-fifths, but among full tenants it was only one and a quarter times as prominent. Cash rental for corn lands was more frequent than share only in the Walthill area in Thurston County where govern - ment agents demand cash for Indian lands. It was a little more than a tenth as frequent as share rent in the Nehawka area in Cass County, about a tenth as frequent in the Cam - bridge area which lies mainly in Furnas County, and a little less than a tenth as frequent as share rent in the Grant area in Perkins County still farther west. Cash rental agree - ments are about a twelfth as frequent as those for a share in the Stromsburg area in Polk County and the Filley area in Gage County. Cash rental for corn ground is almost un - known in the Fairfield, Milligan, and Stapleton areas in Clay, Fillmore, and Logan Counties, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 Share rental is paid for corn ground in the vast majority of cases in all areas except the one in which cash is demanded for Indian land. The share rent is one-half in a considerable minority of cases only in the Nehawka, Stapleton, Filley, Walthill, and Grant areas in Cass, Logan, Gage, Thurston, and Perkins Counties, respectively. In most cases in all areas studied the share of the corn paid as rent was one-third or two-fifths. The two-fifths share predominated over the Table 10. — Landlord's share of each kind of crop LANDLORD'S SHARE OF WHEAT The landlord gets a third of the wheat in about half of the cases, two-fifths in over one case out of every 5, half in 1 case out of every 10, and cash in 1 case out of every 6 Rent and tenure All crops 1 'orn neat Percent n Percent Al "1 falfa j Percent Other hay Percent ftnseni Perartf Full tenants All rents A quarter .... A third Two-fifths. . . . ttv.:: Other Part-owners All rents A quarter. . . . A third Two-fifths... Half Cash Two-fifths . . Half cash../.;;!;: Other 1,907 8 772 396 291 386 54 100.0 0.4 40.4 20.8 15.3 20.3 2.8 465 2 195 157 55 50 6 100.0 0.4 41.9 33.8 11.9 10.7 1.3 435 0 206 113 61 48 7 100.0 0.0 47.4 25.9 14.0 11.1 1.6 485 2 250 110 62 50 11 100.0 0.5 51.3 22.7 12.8 10.3 2.3 172 1 30 9 35 85 12 100.0 0.4 17.4 5.2 20.6 49.4 7.0 190 100.0 1 0.5 7 3.7 1 0.5 28 14.8 135 71.0 18 9.5 529 5 265 62 9 181 7 100.0 0.9 50.0 11.7 1.7 34.3 1.3 119 1 60 21 1 36 0 100.0 0.8 50.4 17.6 0.8 30.3 0.0 111 0 66 14 2 29 0 100.0 0.0 59.6 12.6 1.7 26.1 0.0 127 1 72 16 1 37 0 100.0 0.8 56.8 12.6 0.8 29.0 0.0 49 0 2 6 0 34 7 100.0 0.0 4.1 12.2 0.0 69.4 14.3 41 100.0 0 0.0 3 7.3 2 4.9 S 7.3 33 80.5 e o.o 2,436 13 1037 458 300 567 61 100.0 0.5 42.6 18.8 12.3 23.3 2.5 584 3 255 178 56 86 6 100.0 0.5 43.6 30.4 9.6 14.7 1.1 516 0 272 127 63 77 7 100.0 0.0 49.9 23.2 11.5 14.1 1.3 612 3 322 126 63 87 11 100.0 0.5 52.5 20.5 10.3 14.2 1.8 221 1 32 15 35 119 19 100.0 0.4 14.5 6.8 15.8 53.8 8.6 231 100.0 1 0.4 10 4.3 3 1.3 31 13.4 168 72.8 18 7.8 •The totals in t oats, alfalfa, and oth as rye, barley, spelt, bis column include not only the ler hay, totaled from later coljm i and kafir. ■ contract agreements covering corn, wheat, OB t but also those covering minor crops such third-share i Cass, Gage, i absent on th&lt; ton, and Fai; Counties, re County, the one-third shs in the Nehawka, Fi and Thurston Counti e farms studied in th rfield areas in Furna jspectively. In the two-fifths share was ire, but the one-half illey, and Walthill areas in ies, but was rare or entirely ie Cambridge, Grant, Staple- is, Perkins, Logan, and Clay i Stromsburg area in Polk 3 almost as frequent as the share was almost unknown </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Landlords of Nebraska Farms 37 or 7. The cash paid was at an average rate of $6.50 per acre. In no case did the landlord receive as little as a quarter of the crop as share rent. These figures include landlords of both tenants and part-owners. Among part-owners the one-third share much more completely predominated among the share agreements, but wheat land was much more fre - quently rented for cash among part-owners than among full tenants, perhaps partly because part-owners were better able to take the risk involved in paying cash rent, but largely be - cause so many part-owners were in the Walthill area with its Indian lands already mentioned as demanding cash rent. The one-third share plan of renting wheat land was fol - lowed on nine-tenths of the Clay County farms studied and on about three-fourths of those in the Fillmore, Furnas, and Perkins County areas. The two-fifths share was not paid for wheat land in any of these three areas last named or in Clay County, except that in the Milligan area in Fillmore County about one wheat rental contract out of every six was on the two-fifths basis. In the Filley area in Gage County, on the other hand, two-fifths was a little more frequently paid than a third for wheat ground, and in the Stromsburg area in Polk County it was about three-quarters as frequent as the one-third share. LANDLORD'S SHARE OF OATS AND BARLEY Oats land has rented more nearly exclusively on the one - third basis than that devoted to any other important crop and less frequently upon the cash basis, except in the Walt - hill area in Thurston County where exceptionally large pro - portions of the agreements are for cash or for unusually large shares of the crops for reasons already mentioned, and in the Nehawka area in Cass County where cash rent or the larger shares are more in vogue than in most other areas for reasons which are not quite so readily stated. In the Stromsburg area in Polk County and the Filley area in Gage County more than a third of all oats land agreements were on the two-fifths basis and in the Stapleton area in Logan County about a third were on the half basis. On the other hand, the general one-third rule applies to about nine-tenths of all oats land rental in the Clay County area, four-fifths in the Millijran area in Fil'more County, three-fourths in the Grant and Cambridge areas in the southwestern part of the state, and important percentages in every other area except that in Thurston County where only three landlords out of </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 202 38 the ninety-nine studied received as small a share of the oats as one-third. The landlord's apparent return on oats land was small whether measured in dollars or in share of the crop, but the acreage per farm was only about half as great as in case of corn or wheat land and the tenant was unable to get as great gross returns from the oats crop as from most others. The one-third share is even more frequent and cash rental less frequent in case of barley than in case of oats. In fact, the cash rented barley land discovered was practically negligible in quantity in the two southwestern areas and entirely absent in eastern Nebraska. The agreements reported were prac - tically confined to the areas in southwestern Nebraska, in the sand hills, and in Clay County. In these areas the larger shares were more rarely received by landlords in case of other crops, so what has been said about size of share of barley paid probably results from its being in these sections rather than from the nature of the crop itself. ALFALFA AND OTHER HAY Both alfalfa and other hay lands are rented for cash in the vast majority of cases. A considerable minority of hay land rental agreements were on the half-share basis and a sprinkling for a third with a very few in four areas on the two-fifths-share basis. The principal exception to this state - ment is found in the Fairfield area in which no cash rental reports were returned and in which practically all hay land appears to be rented on the one-third share basis. S M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>