<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Freezing Injury of Seed Corn</title>
               <date value="1918-04-15">1918-04-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 163 [Popular Edition of Benearch Bulletin Mo. Ill THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FREEZING INJURY OF SEED CORN Distributed April 15, 1918 A Anal general germination test before corn planting LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. Volume XXX, Aktici.k III By T. A. KlKSSKi.mcH and I. A. Ratci.ifk </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY ) HONORABLE E. P. BROWN. I' resident. Davey. HONORABLE J. E. MILLER. Viet President. Lincoln HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER. Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LVI-ORI). Kails City. HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL. Lincoln. HONORABLE HARRY D. LAMMS. Scward. THE STATION OFFICERS •SAMUEL AYERY, Ph. D., LL. 1).. Chancellor, ex officio W. G. HASTINGS, A. B.. Aetimg Chancellor. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. St., Director of Extension Service J. S. DALES. M. Ph., financial Secretary. C. A. LEWIS, B. St., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy. H. J. Gkamluh, B. St., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. I). C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A.. Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. St.. Entomology. M. H. Swenk. A. M.. Entomolotjy. H. C. Filley. A. M.. Earm Management R. F. Howard, A. M.. Horticulture. G. A. Loveland. A. M.. Meteorology. E. Meau Wiuox, Ph. 1). Plant Pathology and Physiology F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S.. Superintendent Experiment Substation. North Platte James Cowan. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Jamks A. Hoi.iikn. B. Sc. Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell tL. L. Z&lt;x)K. B. Sc. Agronomist. North Platte. *J. W. Calvin. B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. tG. K. K. Link. Ph. D.. Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology. **]. Ralph Cooper. M. S.. Associate in Horticulture. F.hwin Hopt. B. Sc. Assistant in Agronomy. W. B. Nevens. M. S.. Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Earm Management •Granted leave of ahsence for militarv service. tDetailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture. United States Depart ment of Agriculture. Washington, D. C. leave of absence. ** Resigned. E. A. BURNETT, 1). Sc, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p003">FREEZING INJURY OF SEED CORN Freezing injury of seed corn has been unusually frequent in recent years. Corn growers have been greatly incon - venienced by such seed injury. Much of this annoyance may be overcome by proper seed corn management. Where injury has occurred, suitable seed may usually be selected if the proper procedure is understood. CAINK OK KKKKZIMi IXJIHY The underlying causes of freezing injury are late ma - turity of the corn and abnormally early freezing weather. Late maturity may result from (1) late planting, (2) plant - ing of unadapted varieties, and (3) peculiar weather condi - tions which do not favor early ripening. Undue early freezing may work similar injury to corn which would pos - sess strong vitality under normal weather conditions. When subjected to a severe frost, immature corn suffers a partial or total loss of germinative power. The germ in a sound kernel of corn is an embryonic liv - ing plant, with stalk, leaves and root. When this living germ contains a large amount of moisture, some physical or chemical change is brought about by freezing which results in death. Following this, the germ usually turns dark in color, which is a fairly safe index as to whether the germina - tion has been destroyed. Figures 1, 2, 3, and 4 show how the germ develops when placed under growing conditions. OttTltllK.M'K OF Al'Tl'MX FRKKZINti IX XKIUIASKA The first autumn frosts in different years occur with great irregularity in Nebraska. As extremes for the vicinity of Lincoln during the last 21 years, the first killing frost occurred on September 12 in 1902 and on October 27 in 1914. Similar variation has occurred in all parts of the State. The average date for the first killing frost at Lincoln since 1897 has been October 11. It varies from about Octo - ber 15 in the extreme southeastern portion of the State to September 21 in the northwest. Frosts sufficiently severe to kill the vegetative part of the corn plant are by no means necessarily severe enough to in jure, the germination of the kernels. The amount of mois - ture contained in the corn, and the duration and degree of By T. A. Kiesselbach and I. A. Katci.ifp </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 163 cold are determining factors. In only very exceptional years is the germination injured by the first killing frost. More depends upon the kind of temperatures following. (2) (3) (4) Fig. 1 — Vertical section of kernel of dent corn. Fig. 2 — Cross section of kernel of dent corn. Fig. 3 — Growth after 35 hours favorable germination. Fig. 4 — Growth after 55 hours germination showing secondary roots. Itl-XATION OK MO1STIRE CONTEXT TO FHKKZIMi IXJl'RY Extensive investigations have shown that a close rela - tionship exists between the moisture content of the kernel and the degree of cold required to kill the germ. As the moisture content of the corn decreases, the injury to the vitality of the kernel from exposure to any given freezing temperature is decreased. To illustrate: Corn samples con - taining various amounts of moisture were subjected arti - ficially for 24 hours to temperatures ranging from 32° to 28° F. with the following results. Corn containing less than 25 per cent moisture germinated 100 per cent; 25 to 35 per cent moisture germinated 80 per cent; 35 to 45 per cent moisture germinated 80 per cent ; 45 to 55 per cent moisture germinated 33 per cent; 55 to 65 per cent moisture ger - minated 28 per cent ; 65 to 75 per cent moisture germinated 1 per cent; and 75 to 85 per cent moisture was entirely dead. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 5 This range in temperature represents that of the first kill - ing frosts in the fall but was of longer duration than occurs under natural field conditions. In the case of immature corn freezing injury at a given moisture content increases as the temperature lowers. For example, for corn containing 25 per cent moisture, the ger - mination percentages were respectively 100, 96, 88, 47, and 0 per cent when exposed for a 24 hour period to tempera - ture ranges of 32° to 28° F., 24° to 20° F., 16° to 12° F., 8° to 4° F., and 0° to — 5 C F. Dry corn containing 10 to 14 per cent of moisture will not be injured by any amount of winter freezing. Air dry corn with a moisture content of 10 or 12 per cent will with - stand the freezing temperature of liquid air or 190° F. below zero. On the other hand corn with 60 per cent moisture may be killed by prolonged exposure to barely freezing tempera - tures. There may be variation in the moisture content of ker - nels on the same ear, which will account for partially im - paired germination of an ear. In 1915 as much as 16 per cent variation was found in the moisture content of such kernels. MOISTIHK CONTENT AND FKKKZIXfi IXJIRY IN 1917 The relation between moisture content and freezing in - jury of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn selected at various dates from the field in the fall and winter of 1917-1918 is shown in Table 1. The selections were based entirely upon the outward appearance and solidity of the ears. But little in - jury resulted from the first killing frost to corn containing less than 47 per cent moisture, even tho the temperature fell as low as 24° F. and continued for a period of 9 hours. On the other hand the prolonged freezing weather follow - ing in October and November materially injured the bulk of the corn. Most of the damage occurred prior to Novem - ber 19. Following this, corn standing in the field dried suf - ficiently to compensate for the lower temperatures and lit - tle additional injury resulted. In general, corn in the field which was sound on November 19, 1917, was also sound on January 15, 1918. The vitality of grain which contained more than 17 per cent of moisture on November 19, was so reduced by the temperatures which prevailed up to that date as to make it unreliable for seed purposes. This includes all corn containing more than 35 per cent moisture at the time of the first killing frost. On the other hand, the dri- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 163 est corn standing in the field and also that from the shocked corn, (Nos. 1 and 2, Table 1) were not injured seriously, giving germination tests of 86 and 88 per cent perfect ger - mination respectively, tho exposed to all the low temperatures prior to January 15. On this date, the field from which the various selections reported in Table 1 were made, tested 31 per cent germination field run. TABLE 1 — Moisture content and germination of corn harvested at various dates during fall and winter of 1917-1918 Moisture in grain of corn gathered on Condition of corn at time of first frost, October 8 Nov. 19 Dec. 11 Dec. 29 Jan. 17 Oct. 8* Shocked corn: 1. Fairly well matured, ears solid :») 1 15 16 14 Corn standing in field: 2. Fairly well matured, ears solid 35 1 16 15 14 3. Somewhat rubbery, ears twist :i!i 21 18 16 17 4. Very rubbery, grain me - dium soft 4:i 26 23 19 19 27 26 21 22 34 28 28 27 36 33 29 28 5. Grain very soft 47 6. Late dough stage 7. Milk stage 60 K:i Pit cent perfect germination of corn Condition of corn at time of first frost, October 8 gathered on Oct. 8 Nov. 19 Dec. 11 Dec. 29 Jan. 17 Shocked corn: 1. Fairly well matured, ears solid 98 85 93 87 86 Corn standing in field: 2. Fairly well matured, ears solid 98 83 87 93 88 3. Somewhat rubbery, ears twist 94 56 79 59 61 4. Very rubbery, grain me - dium soft 92 34 20 14 20 14 17 5 6 5. Grain very soft 92 5 6 6. Late dough stage 82 10 10 0 0 7. Milk stage 44 1 1 0 0 Minimum Temp. Degrees F. . 24 17 -16 IS -21 •The firHt Hclictinn wan made after in the early morning of October 8. thr tiisi killing front which occurred </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 7 kkkkzim; i\.ii m inkvitaki.k in occasional vkaks Experience has shown that the best adapted, highest producing corn for any locality in Nebraska does not mature and dry sufficiently in all seasons to escape freezing injury when left exposed to low temperatures either in the field or in the crib. It would not be practicable to grow corn sufficiently early to escape damage from freezing every year, because such corn would be too small and early to give best results. The best adapted and most productive types appear to be those which utilize nearly the entire growing season of the aver - age year. In the majority of years, such types should ripen fully before the first killing frost, altho in occasional years both the yield and quality may be somewhat reduced. Climatic conditions occasionally combine in such a man - ner as to either hasten or greatly delay the ripening of the corn crop. Seasonal variation in the time of maturity of a given corn in a given locality may be illustrated by the rela - tive maturity of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn at the Experi - ment Station in 1914 and 1917. This is a standard, well - adapted type for conditions prevailing at the Experiment Station. In 1914 the grain of this corn contained only 14 per cent moisture on October 1, while it contained 38 per cent on October 1, 1917. It was well matured on Septem - ber 6, 1914, whereas it was not so mature a month later in 1917. The normal date of ripening for this variety is Sep - tember 20, for this vicinity, while the mean date of the first killing frost is October 11. According to these data, corn which is unsurpassed in average production at the Experi - ment Station ripens, as an average, about three weeks be - fore the mean date of the first killing frost. This seasonal variation makes possible in exceptional years, the growing of late maturing types of corn in locali - ties where they normally are not adapted. But the char - acter of the season and the date of the first killing frost cannot be foretold at planting time. Therefore, unadapted, late maturing types which do not reach their full develop - ment somewhat before the average date of the first killing frost should not be grown. They require the exceptional seasons, in which the first killing frost comes very late. In too great a proportion of the seasons they fail to mature, anO too frequently produce an inferior quality of corn together with a low yield per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 163 SELECTION FOR EAIILINESS Wherever varieties of too late maturity are being grown, this may be overcome in several ways: (1) Securing seed of some earlier type. This may originate in the same locality or be of some previously tried variety obtained from a dis - tance. Before extensive substitution for a new corn, definite knowledge should be had regarding its local adaptation. (2) Field selection of seed from the earlier maturing plants before autumn frosts, while such difference is readily dis - cernible. (3) Selection of the driest and most mature ears later in the season. To a considerable extent, such ears are most mature because of inherent relative earliness. Corn may be made to average a week or ten days »arlier maturity in a very few years by such selection. It is probable that much of the corn grown in Nebraska could be made a week earlier without reducing the average yield, and the quality would be improved. ALTERNATIVES IN SKK1) SELECTION (1) Special early field selection, before any likelihood of frost, may be practiced regularly each year. When such corn is cured and stored in a dry, well ventilated place, good germination without further trouble is reasonably certain. This procedure systematically insures sound seed corn. An essential requirement in this practice is to avoid immediate contact between the different ears so long as they are not well dried out. Corn so gathered should be hung up at once in a dry, well ventilated place. Thus mold and decay will be prevented. By going thru the field with a sack hung over the shoulder, or by some other simple method, the best developed and most mature ears may be readily gathered. Seed selected in the stiff dough stage is sufficiently mature to produce strong vigorous plants. However, seed corn which is much drier when gathered is more easily preserved. (2) Selecting seed late in September or early in Octo - ber, while husking corn in the regular way for early feed, is a safe and convenient manner of obtaining sound seed corn. Precaution should be taken to insure rapid drying and avoidance of mold. This procedure usually requires some husking before the bulk of the corn is sufficiently dry for the general husking to begin. The necessary seed for the average farm may usually be selected from several loads of this early husked corn. If this plan is system - atically followed, a supply of sound corn may be reasonably certain year after year. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 9 (3) Selecting seed at the time of general husking is the most common ot' all methods. Either a box is attached to the side of the wagon into which the seed ears are thrown while husking, or else the seed ears are selected from the wagon while unloading. This method, and particularly the practice of picking the seed ears in the field while husking, has many commendable features in years of early maturity when a large percentage of the ears will possess strong ger - mination even when left exposed in the field to severe freezing weather. In other years, such as 1911, 1915, and 1917, there may be such a small portion of viable ears after sub - jection to freezing weather, that much annoyance and dif - ficulty is experienced in selecting them. If necessary to select seed ears from a field where freezing injury has been severe, the rather smooth, slender, hard, solid ears with relatively shallow grains illustrated on page 15 will be found most likely to give satisfactory germination. For those who do not favor this type of ear, it may be said that it is likely to yield fully as much grain to the acre as the larger, rougher types, even in years when both give equally good germination. Severe freezing destroys the viability of immature seed and this is a factor in the natural adaptation of the crop. It tends to eliminate the later strains while the earlier ones survive. By selecting the ears therefore, which have withstood severe freezing in the field, more consistent earliness is developed. (4) Corncrib selection may be practiced in an emergency as a last resort. If provision for a seed supply by other methods has been overlooked, well-matured and sound seed ears may in most years be selected from the crib during the winter or spring. Such home-grown seed is to be rec - ommended in preference to imported seed whose adapta - bility is not definitely known. The germination of cribbed corn in general deteriorated markedly between November, 1917, and March, 1918. Corn dried more slowly in the crib than when left standing in the field. (5) Old seed. In order to insure against emergencies, it is desirable in years when corn matures well to select suf - ficient seed for two years planting. Especially is this advisable in the extreme northern and northwestern part of the State where early frosts are apt to be especially severe and damaging. It is also advisable in parts of the State where severe drouth or hot winds may almost totally destroy the corn. It seldom happens that two successive bad years occur, and by this practice, much uneasiness and annoy- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 163 ance may be avoided in bad years. Seed corn one year old is entirely satisfactory if it has been preserved in a dry, well-ventilated place. COMHIXAT1OX OK MKTHODS KOIt KKIiKCTlXO SKKD. For many farm operations, the procedure may be varied from year to year according to the seasonal condi - tions or to the individual farmer's fancy or convenience. This holds true in regard to the time and manner of selecting the seed corn supply. The conditions are exceptional in which with care a satisfactory seed supply cannot be selected by any one of the first three methods just described. The relative convenience and practicability of the methods may vary from year to year. In years when corn is back - ward, it is a good practice to select seed from corn husked early before heavy and continued freezing is to be expected. In years of early maturity, when corn is well dried out, it is probably quite as well to pick the seed ears at the time of regular husking. Whether special early selection is prac - ticed in such years may be left entirely to the convenience of the farmer. However, in years when corn is late in ma - turing, early selection and preservation of seed corn may avoid the great annoyance of sorting over a large quantity of corn for the small percentage of sound ears that will give satisfactory germination. Early selection is probably of greater importance in the northwestern half than in the southeastern half of the State. WKICTAIXIXU THK (iKIt.MIXATlOX OK HKKI) COHX After the seed ears are thoroly cured, a general germi - nation test may be made of a composite sample of kernels taken scatteringly from each of several hundred ears at the rate of five or six kernels per ear. The germination may often be improved by discarding the butts of the ears which are more subject to injury, due to slower drying. If the ger - mination proves unsatisfactory, a more severe elimination of unsound ears should be made. Discarding all ears with a discolored germ and making an individual ear germination test are rather effective methods. The making of such tests is generally understood by farmers. Care must be taken to provide uniform and favorable germinative conditions, in order that misleading results may not be secured. The most reliable general test may be made by planting the seed in a box of soil. The number of seeds actually producing plants may thus be ascertained. If the tests are made between moist blotters, cloths, or by any other simi- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 11 Fig. 5 - The individual ear germination test shows definitely which are the unsound ears lar device, the kernels after sprouting may easily be ex posed and the germination counted. In the seasons of 1915, 1916, and 1917, seed of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn was selected at successive stages of ma - turity and tested for germination late in the winter after becoming thoroly air dry. Immediately after harvest, the seed was hung in a dry, airy place and thus cured free from mold or other injury. The results are given in Table 2. Table 2 — Germinative ability of corn harvested at various stages of maturity. Average for three years 1915-1917 Wt. of Ratio wt. Date of Days 100 ker- of embryo Germina - sclci- Condition of gram hi nee fer- ne ] s to wt. of tlon ' l*" r tion tiliiation nrramal kernel* &lt;*nt&gt; tiluatton (p-ams) kernel* •*"* GKIOIIKAT1VE AIUMTY ACgi IHKI) i:\ICI.V ISV ( &lt;IK\ Hug. 24 Milk stage Auk 31 Late milk stage Sept. 7 Roast ing-ear Sept. 14 Late roasting-ear Sept. 21 Denting Sept. 28 Glaxing Ort. 6 Mature •Data fur 11)17 only. 20 27 34 41 48 66 62 12.2 17.0 20.4 24.2 27.9 30.7 31.4 .078 .106 .110 .103 .106 .112 80 92 94 97 97 96 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nrbmnka Agricultural Kxp. Station, Bulletin 163 12 The data indicate that gormlnatlvo ability wan acquired In the milk stage about 20 day* after fertilization, whorum* there were 62 dayi between the time of fertilisation and ripening. However, it would not be considered desirable to HcWt Miu'd before the Mtitl dough xiutfe of development, and preferably not until the com U almost mature. KIHOCI OF TIMK OK NKIIUTION AND I'HKHKHV ATION &lt;»l si.i.k (OltN I I'll N Mill* An experiment wan Htartud in the fall of 1914 to deter - mine the effect of the time of harvesting seed corn upon its yielding power provided care is taken in selection to obtain eiiually high germination. A comparative yield test was made in 1815, 1018, and 1917, of September, November, and March selections from a field of Nebraska White Prize corn. This is a standard variety grown at the Experiment Station and adapted to southeastern Nebraska. The seed was carefully preserved in a dry, well-ventilated place upon being harvested. After danger from freezing injury, only need can* were taken which showed a bright, clear germ. Ears with discolored germs wore discarded because they promised low germination. A composite sample of a large number of ears was used for each selection. TABLE 8 — Relative yield* of seed corn nelected at various da t&lt;x during the fall and winter. 1915-1917 Yltld ptr »crt Diil'ln u tliitm MM*h Dili !• of M»d Ki'lcrilnli 1B16 1MB 1»I7 T) l™ y l* r yt»r •v*r«|» Himhtlii Him/ill* Hunhflii liunhrlii tfeptemlwr 4 :uii :ih.:i 47,0 NovpmtMT 4 &lt;ifii« M7.:i 41.6 41.8 M»rch 4 A4.7 42.1 42.A 4V.H Chwk 4 m:i in i 41.1 4M.2 I. Th« M»4 wan hnrvt-nlftl nhmtl Hi" ir.ili uf tiionlh I, Th. . hi . I, ..I tvn. In. i &gt;. nil it riMin II,. x r n. Id whllr Imxlilna lit Nnv»ftib»f, Ah an average for the three years, 1015-1917, seed corn harvested by xpwlftl wlwtlon fn&gt;ni the ftold In Ht'ptntnbnf, November, and March, and given good care after selection, yielded respectively 47.0, 4M.B, and 49.H bUHhels per acre, white seed Haved from the name field during the regular proceHH of htiftklhg In November yielded 111, 2 lnmlieU per acre, </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Frt$»ing Injury of Seed Corn 13 Illl Vll\ I YIKMIH (IK MMOOTII AMI llui i.ii MAIM During thu four years, 1014 to 1017, four ear-types of NehniMka White Prize corn have Immmi compared in yield with tho original unseloctud corn from which the typw were •elected each year. Thin variety ha* been grown at the Experiment Station many year*. The roaulta are given In TuWe I. TABLE 4 — Yield per acre from different var-typea of Sebranka Ono may conclude that tho long, Blunder, smooth type poi- MMei highly satisfactory yielding qualities, which, coupled with its frequently superior germinativc ability, makes it a very suitable type to grow. This type of ear Is gaining in popularity among corn men of the State. Wherever condi - tions for any reason arc somewhat adverse for corn, this type seems to be especially adapted. I I I I i I III 1 I M Ml i HIM HTAMI (IN Mil It An investigation was made In 1015 and 1016 to deter* mine tho effect of varied distribution of plants upon the yield of com. The number of plants per acre was the mime in all cases, but the number of plants In adjacent hills differed. The purpose was two fold: (1) To learn the effect of varia - tion in stand caused by mechanical variation In dropping by mm planters, when com with perfect germination Is planted. (2) To learn what result mlgnt be expected from planting com. only part of which will grow, but for which the rate of planting has been calculated to seed the desired number of sound kernels per acre. The methods of distribution compared were: (1) All hills with uniformly three plants; (2) alternating hill* with two and four plants; (B) alternating hills with ont, three and live plants: (4) alternating hills with one. two, three, four, and five plants. The results are given In Table R. The average yield for the three varied distributions waa 78 White Pvizv rorn Type of cur lilU ms li 1918 11)17 Av»r»g« Original Hu.ktl. a.7 [64.M HuiktU 66.6 Hu.hrl. 68.6 ItUMhrU 61.1 l.itru'' rough Short rough Short imooth Long illm umiiiii li 80.0 44.4 46.0 41.7 lift..-! AH.U 72.8 M.4 64.4 66.1 80.1 66.2 4ft.li 4B.R 49.2 64.9 61.4 67.1 66.7 68.8 NmnliiT of iluplirui huh 0 H 14 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Silnimlfii \inlriilhmil AV/i, Million, Ihilhlln 1(1,1 IiiimIihIm rniiiimri'il with 71 It IhihIimU for Him milCnim iilnnl lljtf mil' h| Ihi'itH iiImiiIm line hill, A iiiilliiini ■IiiihI nl Ihi'im nlMtilM |n'i hill vii'lilml IN |ii'i i'miiI iiuhm limn Him iiimmii im Him vmiIimI iluliilniliiiix. \ it t in i Mm in mIkiiiI iIiim (n Urn liliilili'i nl In I hi' |iiiimi||H' llf ili'Mil di'i'il III I'lll'll li'nllllM MN IllW M» 7&amp; |(M»' I'Mfll, With M I'lll'I'MHlMltlllllld MllMlnlMII'lll III |||M lilHiillittf imIm, Im Ihm niNi'knil limn Him vmi'IhIIimi Hi Him nImivm ■ lii'iliil iiImiiHiikm, Th" iImIh In Tiililn b miiIihImiiIIhU* mhi'IIit InvtmliKMllu i* Ml Hit' HImIIihi Iiv Miinlti'inii'M III I »••»*/ Mini IIMIM, Ihn i'hnii In iif whirl) him ulvnn In Ttililn •&gt; Tln&lt; msmimum vIuhI nf I n&lt; » mi lm| dull Hull Inn* III IJllft li'«l WMM I " |i"i n'lil hmi'i Ihmi ii iiiiiriiini ilUlillinllnii nf Ihli'M l»i'riinl«. TAMliM f\ Nfti'i't uf vtlihtt tlinhlliiitlint nf iilmit* III iiluiilltui I'linifminl with iiiiiinini illxliiliiiliun im , mm VihIiI |inr m» I'IhiiIi \m hill mm mi« hww I 1 lllllMII k ll IllHIll. A iHHtMi lit) Mini 4 iiIhiiI* A IhmihI ill Ii II Mini X iiImiiI. A INHIHI Hi I, M, », i Hllll * IllHIll. AvHNKKfiir virN ili.ifiiiiiiinii HI II M cm TAMliX N #^/T»'»'^ »/ Wili'il illHhlliliftuil uf mill III [illinium )&lt;u in im 1 14 with niiifiiiiit iiiihiiiiiiiuii unit im* VIhIiI |«r »m IIihIii. iiIhiiIniI |imi hill Mm I Illlll AVNfNM* HuM» Hv*M» I HHihtl I Illllllll It ll JHHlll' » IihimI lilt f Mllll 4 BIHllI" 1 Hi lull III I, II, HHIlA KIMlll- A iMfllHl M|t I HUM It Klillh- 8! 8! II AVKflMH 1 'HC *NI&lt;l»ll lll.lfllllllhll Hl/J^V/^llfiWi'iEP"" 1 MM ! dlii MM U IKIII Mllll III MlMllllIt Hllll 'Him rni'j Ihftt IIim&gt;I» III Im mil mm-mIK imiIiiihiI Iiv mii iininil lilllll lIlnllUlllllllll III' I IM lllllllU IWlllllll |MM«lHMtli|i- llHlll.'l imiH In' i'»|iliillli'il li» I in Idl M*&lt; Ini'illliM Mini nl I lli&lt; I mill nl »i nun |i|)llll A HUH llll I* mil Illiillml III II. HWII II I'll " Hll'llMM llf lilllll Illll Hint IhImhIU ill HH HIIImIiImI'mIiIv lii'»Mliil 81 I Hi *£ Ml 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">t'lTi'tlttii Injury uf Hi'nl Cum 15 IU NlljNI'Mllt lillU fill' wiili'i Mini plMlll ImimI iiiiili'iliil. Hllli i' ll|l"M' Illllli llllU Mil' IHIIMllV llltllllHJf ftlHlll'H, It tfl'MNlMf ttllllll iImih i' mini" ihmIImIiIi' In (HIM nr Mini'i" inU«lli|t |iImiiI« tfim* III Hii'i'i'MM I In 1 ylxlil nl 1 iii'iuliti'iiliitt lillU I'lMHltltl I Ml-lllllil IIMN ul I'MM&lt; HUM -III. nl I ..» Ill IIMI^VIIMS IM I'l^^il'lH l'!s ft y dinner Iim* In jiilml miiiiim ikIIimi iImDiiIIk «|imi&gt;Ihm of (iImiiU In ll|n Ili'lil wllji'll In' ii'MiinU t\« Mil iililliiiiini iiIhiiI Him ihIh rut 1 IiIn iiii'Milly Hi I hi" MVMi'Mtfi" jttwv, VmcIihih m*|mh i MH'iiU Iimvh linlliiili'il Mini Hii'Im limy In' MIMIIM VMI 1 Mlliill III Hi" |i!miiIIii|&gt; mli' ullliniil it nmlMiliil i'ICmi'I ii|iiin lliw vImIiI I'llK Im'IIIM Illl" IH«I', Illllll'l lllMII III III'III'III'M llll|IMlll'l|, III) lll||l|ll"'ll MM Hllll |ll'l ■fl'l'l tfl'lllllllMllllll, |ll VKHt'M llT M'tMJ I'lll'll III Illl Vi lllCMlly MI'OWM MiIhIiJhiI MMMll iHillllM M IllW Nil 7D |l»'l (Mill III' tin |ll'l ll'lll, «||III|||| III* ll«l'l| If Mllllllit"!' »»"Ml| I'Mlllllll In 1 hhIim It'll Wlii'H lilt' li'«l !&lt;" Ill'lllW Mh Nil mIIhWHIIii' |ilnliiilil&gt; alllllllll ill* IIIHlIt" fill Mil' lli'Mll NMMll III lilt' Mill' nl |iImHIH&lt;U NhimI IiinIIiim *n iir Illl |iiii I'Hiil iiIhmIhI nl Din i imlunmiv mli' tlHH &gt; ll'lll HM W»" I ll« HMHll ll'.llliy Illll |ll'l I Mill 'I IH Mil I Illll'll "lii'irml mImiiiU" mm' iimin m |mm iti'lillrHiy Nil) \\W jrl'n iiiinlilly (H'liVM Inn Ihli It In im»" Him «i'it«nii Iniim nil tiiv I (in iliilii III IIiIm liiilli'lin, ImiwmviTi mIiiiiiIiI mil In' ri imlrninl m« miIvmi'mm lii nmlilnit Mil H"m«ihimIiIi' nlhnl In *•»•!*•) I iim •iuhI nf lllHVltH WIlllH 'll#H Mil II 'I'llH NllllMilli lt|IH l» Dll^l !•&lt;) "" HMIHIHl NhlttHxkH HMNlllllMNI ¥\» (I liHIUfi I'tllUll KM! Mllll lull* llPmlM, IIMHHlIt HHt Ml M» </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nilinmhil Siii'li'iillnnil Mi'/i, Mttilttut, llulhliii Hid 16 hltfll urn iiiIiimI lull . NtM'll I'Ml'i'lul niiIhi'IIiiii la iIiiiiIiIIhm ifimil IllHM UtMllllMltl (hi im IHMilln My imlii|i *hni( w h l#'li In In |nii I iiiiMiMinil, m iihUiiiiii mIhiuI fMiiini! (in iiIiIhIiiiuI Illil II Iimm iiMdli uluiwii HimI hIihuIuIc mil mi mil/ In nitl HHi'tiMHiy fill IIIHUlllllllll y IhIiIm All Hli|illiM li.ii) of IIih Inw iif I'liHiii'i* iTmIiIc 7) nIimwm Imiw Him hiihmU Will lit' ilUll'liiillcil wlit'li Nt'oil ImnIIIim 70 |ii*|' ii'lil him) HA |wr ('(•III |M IHt'll Wllll Nil H|l|!MHllfMllc HlllllMlllK'lll III III" |llillil IliM I'Mlc, In ciimi|icihhIc rid III" iciIiii'hH m*** »»i ImmI Ittti II U IHIiIcImIimmI I IimI I||((H»( Otflll'tm WIMllfi MM VMIIcil i(illl«*vliiil In r»n in (IIHI'IIim In Him M4ldl|| Hull Him iiihIimMmiI |.ImiiI.i VMI'Ihm mhiiimwIihI III II* |iIhiiIIiiii IiH' MMflll-H HlllllMlllil (III* IllNHlMC III M Ullt'kff fMlf III HIllMl; Ih (tmiw m imn hhkiI, mhcihIiimIIiiii limin •IhmiIiI Iim vkiiiihI niiiI IIih iiHfHHfiU^ »•' mm •»'i&lt;ii hiiiiwii wllli hmIiHiiIv A (iHiifly hiiiiIiicImiI Im.I miImM IHhmII Ihh lit Id* m MMfi TAWiH 1 Hhtiti'lttjl vhitw't' &gt;h*h iliitliiiu ut filiipf* whm wri pn bill lu bill* M Hii-ht-* uiunl WIlHIl MIMI HHKIllimlW WIlKII HIMI iHMIlKlHlM I If! |(W Will M \M 1*111 »ml i!mi(i|ihiI |iw hill i mi N H*|l| IIIIIII IM» -in li IiIHh hiii.Ii Mill |it»f ttHrx h.lMl -in h hllli -hi I. lilili I itHM 1 1 ThIkI i'ii him nun m\ Mm nun 'Mil </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>