<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00009">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00009</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>GAME AND FISH LAWS OF NEBRASKA, IN FORCE JULY 1, 1901.</title>
		             <date value="1901">1901</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-07</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">GAME AND FISH LAWS 

— or — 

NEBRASKA, 

IN FORCE JVLY 1, 1901. 

6741 Sec. 84. (Killing, etc., muskrats, mink, or otter, on lands 
of another). It shall be unlawful for any person, between the fifteenth 
day of April and the fifteenth clay of February following, to trap, 
catch, kill or to pursue with such intent, on the premises of another, 
any muskrat, mink or otter; and it shall be unlawful for any person, 
at any time, to enter u|K&gt;n the premises of another, without his consent, 
with a view of trapping, hunting, killing, or pursuing with intent to 
kill, any such animal or animals; and it shall furthermore be unlawful 
for any person to enter upon the premises of another, without his 
¦it, and destroy, tear down, or in any manner injure the muskrat 
heaps or houses on such premises; any person offending against any 
of the provisions of this section shall be fined in any sum not exceeding 
twenty dollars for each offense; Provided, This section shall not be so 
construed as to prevent the catching and killing of any animals specified, 
where there is danger of their doing injury to property, either 
public or private. 

K6743g Sec. 86g. (Same) That in all cases, when any person, 
y or officer is convicted and fined for a violation of any of the 
isions of this act, it shall be the duty of the court imposing such 
or fines, to make it a part of the judgment, that such person, party 
licer, stand committed to the jail of the county until. such fine and </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
2 

the fine and costs out of the property of the person, party or officer 
coniieted, and when so made the convict shall be released from further 
imprisonment on that account. (Id., ?'t.) 

t6743i Skc. 8(ii. (Fines, disposition). All tines recovered under 
of the provisions of this act, shall, when collected, Ik- paid into the 
sury of the county for the use of the .school fund, and the corporate 
verities of any county, city or village, within whose territorial 
sdiction such fine was recovered, and (when) collected shall pay to 
complaining witness in such prosecution, out of the general fund &lt;•( 
l county receiving such fine, an amount equal to one half the tine 
lally collected, upon the proj&gt;er application of the party entitled to 
same, in the manner usual for the presentation of claims against 
nties. (Id.. £11.) 

16744 Skc. 87. (interfering with private fish pond). That it shall 
unlawful for any person to catch, interfere with, injure, or in any 
nner destroy, or maliciously disturh, to the damage of the private 
iperty of another, the fish in or work connected with any private lish 
id, not exceeding ten acres, in this state. Any person or person-, 
lating the provisions of this section shall be fined in any sum not 
s than ten dollars nor more than one Hundred dollars; and it shall 
lawful for any person to take up, remove, or clear away any fish 
, fish lines, or fish pond placed or put in the waters of any lake. 
id, or reservoir contrary to the provisions of this act. (Amended S. I'. 
. 8, l&lt;»01) 

6745. Skc. 87a. (Fishing except with hook and line— Free n.i-age 
of fish-Penalty.) It shall be unlawful for any person to catch, 
kill, injure, or destroy any fish in any public water in this state or in 
the Missouri river along the eastern boundary of this state in any 
manner whatever, except with the use of the hook and line. The use 
of seines, nets, and other devices, except the hook and line, being 
hereby prohibited and made unlawful. It shall also be unlawful tor 
any person, association of persons, or corporation to place or establish 
any obstruction across any stream of water in this state that riudl 
prevent the free passage of fish along said stream; Provided, that all 
persons, associations of persons, or corporations, erecting, owning, "r 
maintaining a mill dam across any stream ot water in this state shall. 
at his or its own expense, construct and at all times maintain. Mtbject 
to the approial of the fish commissoti, a suitable and substantial tish 
whereby all fish passing along saiil stream can readily paaa over 
or around said dam. Public waters within the meaning of this - 
shall embrace all lakes, jxjnds, rivers, creeks, bayous, and streams 
except private artificial pond or p:&gt;nds subject to the exclusive dominion 
of a single ownership. Every violation of any provision of this section 
iall be a misdemeanor and every person, association, or corporation 
onvicted of an offense under this section shall pay a line not less than </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
3 

the county jail not less than ten days or until such fine and cost- .ire 
paid. It shall be unlawful for any person to have in his or her 
possession any seine, net or other unlawful instrument or device for 
taking or injuring rish with the intent of using the same in any water 

Eiis state and it is hereby made 
le |KNice, and police judges of 
inst this act. Each day any 
continued without such fishw 
tr.itc offense under this act. 
ce under this act found in 

the duty of all constables, jii 
this state to prosecute all oi 
mill dam or other obstruction sh.ill 
iiv shall be deemed and taken 

Kvery seine, net, or other unlawful 
any water in this state or in the 

possession of any person intend inn to use the same in violation 
of this act may be seized by any person ivith or without warrant and 
deposited with a justice of the peace or police jud^e who shall 
the owner or person having such seine, net. or other unlawful device in 

I possession, if known, to appear 
y such seine, net or unlawful &amp; 
rt shall, upon such hearing, or 
ill cases of condemnation such s 
destroyed under the direction of 
the constable and justice's fees 
misdemeanors. (Amended 1879 

before said court and show cause 
•vice should not be destroyed. &gt;uch 
upon default, enter judgment, and 
eine, net, or unlawful device shall 
said court. In all cases under this 

hall be the tajBC U in other 
71. 1887, Chap. 107. Took effect 

). 

Explanatory net 

prescribes the duty of constructing 
?n declared unconstitutional by the 

So much of Section 87a a 

r maintaining fishwavs has h 
erne Court of Nebraska. (See 

49 Nebr. p. 218. 

the criminal code pertaining to the 
;cifically repealed by the provisions 

The foregoing sections of 

Game and Fish laws were not sp 
of House Roll No. 13-* known a 

the "New Game Law" and still 

tain in force. The new game law referred to was approved by the 
ernor March 23rd, 19(11 and will be in force and effect from and 
r Julv 1st, 1901. 

tGeo. B. Simpkins of Lincoln, Nebraska, has been appointed 
ef Deputy Game and Fish Commissioner, and \V. J. O'Brien as 
&gt;uty Fish and Game Commissioner to have special charge of 
fish hatcheries at South Bend. 

The following is a copy of the New Game Law 

Copy H. R. 138. 

ARTICLE I 

tSicriON 1. There is hereby created a game and fish 
¦tasioa for the State of Nebraska, which shall have the general 
rge of the following named public matters, vi/: 

tl. The protection, propagation and breeding of such tish and 
me, song, insectivorous and other birds as may be deemed valuable 
the people of the State. 

The collection and distribution of such statistics and </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 

propagation of fish and game, song, insectivorous and other birds, and 
to take charge of and preserve all books, records and documents pertaining 
to the subject which may come into the possession of said 
commission, or under its control. 

t3. The control anil management of all state fish hatcheries 
I grounds gMd therefor, together with all buildings, |&gt;onds. 
&gt;aratus of every kind, and all other property belonging to or used 
the state in the propagation of fish. 

The enforcement of all laws of the State for the protection 
ervation and propagation of fish and game, song, insectivorous 
other useful birds. 

§ Section 2. The affairs of said commission shall be 
lucted by a game and fish commissioner and such subordinates as 
provided for in this act. 

The governor is hereby made the game and fish commissioner, 
and he is required within thirty days from the approval of this act, 
and every two years thereafter, to appoint two deputy game and fish 
commissioners, who shall hold office for a term of two years, or until 
their successors shall have qualified, and who may be removed by the 
governor at any time for cause. One of said deputies shall be designated 
as the chief deputy, who shall reside in the City of Lincoln, and 
who shall, under the direction of the commissioner, devote his entire 
time to the affairs of this office. One of said deputies shall be skilled 
in the science of fish culture and shall under the direction of the commissioner 
have the control and management of all fish hatcheries of the 
State and the distribution of fish spawn and fry in the waters of the 
State. Said deputies shall each receive a salary of one thousand two 
hundred ($1200) Dollars per annum, payable quarterly, also their 
actual traveling and subsistence expenses, not exceeding $.S&lt;IO per 
year, when absent from their respective homes in the discharge of 
their official duties. Said commissioner shall also within thirty days 
from the approval of this act appoint, and may remove at his pleasure, 
three deputies who shall receive Seventy-five ($75.00) dollars per month, 
payable monthly, for such time only as they shall be actually employed 
in the discharge of their official duties under the direction of the commissioner. 
They shall also receive their actual traveling and 
subsistence expenses not exceeding three hundred ($300.00) dollars 
per year, while absent from their respective homes in the discharge of 
their official duties. The Commissioner may also at his pleasure in 
writing appoint for special purposes, deputies who shall serve for 
such special purposes without compensation such purposes being 
stated in the written appointment, and who shall have for such 
purpose the same powers as the deputies hereinbefore mentioned. 

i Section 3. The commission shall be provided at the State 
tol with suitable furniture, stationery and other facilities for the 
¦ action of its business. And the commissioner may appoint, and </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
5 

five ($75.00) dollars per month, payable monthly. Provided the 
commissioner may in his discretion require the chief deputy to act aa 
secretary of said commission, in which case said deputy shall receive 
three hundred ($300.m&gt;) dollars, per annum, for such service, in 
addition to the salary herein provided. 

tSKCTioN 4. Said commissioner and his deputies are hereby 
e officers of the State with all of the powers of sheriffs and 
tables, while acting within the line of (heir official duties, with 
ority to make arrests and to serve all writs and processes, civil 
criminal, in the enforcement of this act. and to charge therefor 
collect the fees allowed by law for like services by sheritl 
tables. 

Skction 5. The commissioner and deputy commissioner, and 
every sheriff and constable, in his respective county, is authorized and 
required to enforce this act and seize any fish or game, song, insectivorous 
or other birds taken or held in violation of this act, and he 
shall have full power and authority, and it shall be the duty of every 
such officer, with or without a warrant, to arrest any person whom he 
has reason to believe guilty of a violation thereof; and with or without 
a warrant, to open, enter and examine all camps, wagons, cars, 
stages, tents, packs, warehouses, stores, outhouses, stables, barns, 
and other places, boxes, barrels, and packages where he has reason 
to believe any fish or game, song, insectivorous or other birds taken or 
held in violation of this act, is to be found, and to seize the same; 
provided, that a dwelling house actually occupied can be entered for 

examination only in pursuance of a 

warrant. 

Skctiox 6. Where fish or 

game, song, insectivotous or other 
officer making such seizure shall 
asonable compensation therefor, to 
animals and vehicles used in such 
conveying the fish or game, song. 

E» is seized under this act, the 
authority, upon payment of re 
take iwssession of and use any 
sportation for the purpose of 

|:tivorous or other birds seized to a convenient railroad station or 
e of safe keeping for sale, and also for conveying an}' person 
sted for the unlawful possession of such fish or game, song, insecous 
or other birds to a place of hearing or trial, and no liability 
I attach to such officer by reason thereof, but this section shall 
apply to any animal or vehicle while being used as a public 
eyance for passengers or mails, or to any railroad car. 

t Skction 7. No person shall set fire to any timber or grass 
and belonging to this state or to the 1'nited States, or set tire in 
place where it is liable to spread to such timber or grass, nor 
e an)* camp fire unextinguished. 

I Section 8. The commissioner may, if he so elect, bring and 
tain a civil action in the name of the State for the possession of 
fish or game, song, insectivorous or other birds taken, killed or 
in violation of this act, or for the value thereof, against any per- </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

bond. No previous demand for paaaaaatoa shall be necessary. 
Neither the pendency of such action nor of a criminal prosecution for 
tho same taking-, killing or possession, shall be a bar to the other, nor 
shall anything in this section affect the right of seizure under the 
other provisions of this act. 

Skciion 9. All fish or (Base, mamg, insectivorous or other 
birds now or hereafter within this state not held bv private ovvnershin 

state not held bv private ownership. 

legally acquired, and which for the purpose of this act shall include all 
the quadrupeds, birds and tish mentioned in this act, are hereby 
declared to be property of the state, and no right, title, interest or 
properly therein can be acquired or transferred or possession thereof 
had or maintained except as herein expressly provided. 

Skciion in. As used in this act, and unless otherwise 
•pacifically restricted or enlarged, the word game includes all the 
quHdru|&gt;eds and birds, and the word tish includes all the fish 
mentioned herein and now or hereafter within this state and not held 
by private ownership legally acquired. 

SECTION 11. As used in this act, unless otherwise specifically 
restricted or enlarged, the words herein and hereof refer to the whole 
act: the words person, owner, proprietor, grantee, lessee, or licensee 
include a firm, association, corporation or municipality; the word 

commissioner means the state game 
commissioners provided for herein; 
K^"ii authorized to enforce this act; 
wrtation. transportation, storage, 
tiering or exposing f, )r sale of 

and tish commissioner or deputy 
the word officer includes every 
and whenever the possession, use, 
taxidermy, for millinery purposes, 
fish or game, song, insectivorous 

or other birds is prohibited or restricted, the prohibition or restriction 
shall, where not specifically otherwise provided extend to aud include 
every part ol such tish or game. song, insectivorous or other bird, and 
a violation as to each individual animal or bird or part thereof shall 
be a separate offense, and two or more offenses may be charged in the 
same complaint, information or indictment, and proof as to a part of an 
animal shall be sufficient to sustain a charge as to the whole of it: and 
violations as t.. any number of animals or birds of the same kind may 
be charged in the same count and punished as a separate offense as to 
each animal. 

SECTION 12. The possession at any time of fish or game, 
song, insectivorous or other birds unaccompanied by a proper and valid 
license, certificate, permit or invoice, as herein provided, shall be 
prima facie evidence that such fish or game, song, insectivorous or 
other bird was unlawfully taken and is unlawfully held in possession 
and it shall lie the duty of every person having the possession or coutrol 
of tish or game. song, insectivorous or other birds to produce the proper 
license, certificate permit or invoice, when one is required by this act. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
7 



ction 13. Nothing in this act shall prevent the commiser 
from taking or authorizing- the taking from any of the waters of 

this state, at any time, and in any manner, any fish or spawn belonging 
to the state for the purpose of propagation or stocking other waters, 
or exchanging with the tish commissioner of other states or of the 
United States, but no such fish or spawn shall be taken or used for 
propagation in or stocking of any private lake except on payment 
therefor to the commissioner, nor shall anything herein nrohihit the nnr- 

hall anything herein prohibit the pur- 

Ee, sale and use of small fry 
state, but no small fry or eg) 
ed in public waters where tr 
nissioner. 

and fish eggs for stocking waters in 
s of fish destructive of trout shall be 
¦ut abound without the consent of the 

ISkction 14. In case of 
warrant of arrest may be 

violation of this act by a corporation, 
¦rved on the president, secretary or 
leral or local agent thereof in the 

manager in this state, or any 

n 

Cwatjr where the action is pending 
rant so kervcd, the corporation 
ject to the jurisdiction thereof, and 

, and upon the return of such warhall 
be deemed in Court and subany 
tine imposed may be collected 

» execution against the property of such corporation, but this section 
.11 not be deemed to exempt any agent or employe from prosecution. 

§Skction 15. If the holder of any license, certificate or permit 
11 persistently or flagrantly and knowingly violate or countenance 
violation of any provisions of this act. such license, certificate or 

Enit shrill be revoked by the c&lt; 
alleged violation ar.d an opp&lt; 
M against the same. 

unmissioner after due notice given of 
irtunity afforded to appear and show 

Section lb. The commisst 

&gt;ner shall publish in pamphlet 
: to game aud fish at a cost not 
power to prescribe such rules, 

form for distribution the laws relatin; 
exceeding 53&lt;HI. And he shall have 

regulations and forms as may be required to carry out the true intent 
and purpose of this act and not inconsistent therewith. 

AKTICLK II 

ESkction 1. No |wrson shall at any time of the year, or in any 
nner, pursue, take, wound or kill any elk, deer, autelope or beaver, 
any of the following wild birds, viz.; Turkey, prairie chicken, sage 
cken, grouse, quail, pheasant, partridge, ptarmigan, duck, goose, 
int, swan, crane, waterfowl, wild pigeon, dove. sni|&gt;es, or curlew, 
any sung, insectivorous or other bird, or any trout, white fish grayg, 
sun fish, bass, cattish, wall-eyed pike, pickerel, croppi, or other 
d tish. ship or sell, offer or expose for sale or have the same in pos- 

ion, except as permitted by this act. 

IBKTKM 2. No person shall shoot on or from a public highway 
any game, song, insectivorous or other bird or fish or hunt game on 
y land not public land, without the consent of the owner or person* </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 

preserve without the consent of the proprietor or person in charge of 
the same, and no question of ownership, proprietorship or charge &gt;hall 
defeat a prosecution unless it appears that the accused in good faith 
has theretofore claimed and at the time of the commission of this act 
complained of claimed to be such owner, proprietor or to ha\e MCfc 
charge, or to have had the consent of the owner, proprietor or person in 
charge, and shall establish such claim. 

Section 3. No dynamite or other explosive or poisonous or 
ying substance whatever shall be used in the taking or killing of 
sh, nor placed in any waters containing tish. 

I Section 3 A. (Song, Insectivorous and other birds. Etc.) It 
ill be unlawful for any person in the state of Nebraska to kill, 
ure or harm any robin, lark, thrush, blue bird, king bird, wren, jay. 
allow, oriole, wood pecker, yellow hammer, cuckoo, yellow bird, 
tolink, or other bird or birds of like nature that promote agriculture 
horticulture by feeding on noxious worms and insects, or that are 
ractive in appearance or cheerful in song. Provided, hawks aad 
Is may be killed on one's own premises. It shall be unlawful for 
f person to destroj' nests and eggs or carry away the eggs or young 
any of the birds described in this section. Provided, that schools, 
leges and universities may, when authorized so to do by the game 
] fish commissioner, take or kill for educational or scienti tic purposes, 
to exceed twenty-five (25) in number of any one species or kind of 
ds protected by this section. 

Any person violating any of the provisions of this section 
shall be fined five ($5.00) dollars for each bird killed, injured, or 
harmed, and a like sum for each nest taken or destroyed. 

Section 4. It shall be lawful to pursue, take or kill, during 
the open season therefor, in the manner, of the kind, for the purpose 
and to the number and extent in this section provided, and not otherwise, 
the following fish and game, song, insectivorous and other birds, 
and the open season therefor, in each year shall begin and end as 
follows: 

»1. The open season for deer having horns and antelopes 
¦ing horns, shall begin August 15th and end November 15th next 
uing. Wolves, coyotes, foxes, wild cats, skunks and rabbits may 
killed at any time of the year. 

2. The open season for prairie chickens, sage chickens and 
grouse shall begin October 1st and end November 30th next 
ensuing, and the open season for quail shall begin November 1st and 
end November 30th next ensuing. Provided that it shall be unlawful 
to kill, trap or harm any quail at any season of the year prior to 
November 1st, 1903. 

3. The o|&gt;en season for wild ducks, geese, brants, swans, cranes 
and game water fowls shall begin September 1st and end April 15th </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
9 

next ensuing 

The 

open 

&gt;eason 

on jack 

Wilson snipe, and 

Sill]*' 

yellow legs shall begin September IA and end April 15th next 

ensuing. 

4. The open season U 

¦Id pigMM, do\es and plover shall 
MKh next ensuing. 

The open season lot 

trout not less than eight iiu ! 
end October '1st next ensuing; and 
-,h shall begin April 1st and lad 

Kth, shall begin June 1st ami 
open season tor all other ti 
&gt;ber 31st next ensuing. 

\ ided by this act. the right give* 
uid tab is limited to food purposes, 
twenty-tive gMH birds of any other 

bv this section to take or kill ffaast 
and to ten wild Reese or brants and 

E'ty and twenty-tive tish for each person in any one calendar day. 
no person shall take, kill or ha\e in posstaaioa in any one - 
than one deer and one antelope; or instead of one deer and one 

antelope, he may either have two 
person have in possession at any &lt; 
brants, fifty ducks and fifty other 

deer or two antelo|&gt;e; nor shall an\ 
me time more than ten wild fa 
birds, nor more than fifty tish. 

No or tish shall 

be held in [xissession by any person 
e close of the season for killing the 
ise provided. 

than five days after th&lt; 
:, except as in this act other w 

8. No same shall be pur 

sued, taken, wounded or killed in the 
pointed bullet, nor with any weapoa 

K, nor with a steel or hard 
than an ordinary shoulder 

nil or pistol, nor shall any fi&gt;h Ik" 

taken or killed except in the ordinary manner with a line anil rod. and 
the hook or h«x»ks baited with natural or artificial bait; and Bshiag 
with lines ha\ inn more than five hooks thereon, shall not In- il. 
the ordinary manner of II thing; nor shall any person tish within two 
hundred feet of any fish way; Provided, that dogs, blinds and A 
may be used for hunting birds. 

I Whoever violates any of the provisions of rab-dirisiona 
en and eight of this section shall BBOB conviction thereof, pay a fine 
lot less than ten dollars and not more than one hundred dollars, or 
imprisoned in the jail of the proper county, not exceeding sixty days. 

Section 5. Whoever violates the provisions of section 1 of 
this article by unlawfully pursuing, wounding or killing any elk, deer 
or antelope shall upon conviction thereof pay a fine of not less than one 
hundred dollars nor more than three hundred dollars or Ik' imprisoned 
in the jail of the proper county not exceeding ninety days, or both such 

fine and imprisonment in the di: 
violates said section by pursuin; 
birds or fish of the varieties the 
thereof be fined five dollars for 
taken or wounded, or found in po^ 
of the proper county not exceeding 

icretion of the Court; and whoever 

;, killing or wounding any of the 
-ein named shall upon the conviction 
¦ach bird or tish unlawfully killed, 
session, or be imprisoned in the jail 

sixty day 

Imxui April 15th ami oml Octobt 

Except as otherwise p 
</seg>
            <seg id="p010">
10 

offense or bird so killed or found in possession. 

Whoever violates any of the provisions of section 3 of this 
article shall upon conviction thereof be tined in any sum not less than 
one hundred dollars and not more than live hundred dollars or by 
imprisonment in the penitentiary not exceeding one year. 

KSkction 6. In waters where white buffalo, suckers, gar 
h. carp or squaw tish, abound the commissioner may in his 
discretion issue to any resi&gt;onsible person a permit to take such tish 
at a designated time and place with nets or seines. Provided, that in 
ease any tish of any of the varieties protected by this ait Ik? so taken. 
E shall immediately be returned alive to the water from whence 
shall ha\e U-en taken, which fact shall be stated by such 
er in his said return. And provided that any such permit shall 
ire with the calendar year in which it is issued. 

fSiciiox 7. It shall be unlawful for any cori&gt;oration. earn- 
By, association, person or persons, or its. his or their officers. 
agents, servants or employes, to sell. ex]x&gt;se for sale, or to have in its, 
his or their possession or control, any wild elk. deer or antelope, 
irrouse. pheasant, prairie chicken, quail, wild turkey, wild tfoose. 
rit or any wild duck, or any of the birds, animals or fish protected 
this act. except during the open season hereinbefore denned or 
otherwise provided, and the period of five days next succeeding the 
El such season. Every corporation, company, association, its 
era, agents, employes, and each of them, and any peraoa or 
ons. his or their agents and employes, and each of them violatany 
of the provisions of this section, shall be deemed guilty of a 
lemeanor, and on conviction be fined twenty-Awe dollars for each 
and every such animal so sold. ex|K&gt;sed for sale or so had in its. his 
or their possession or control, and shall on conviction be fined rive 
dollars for each and every such bird sold, exposed for sale, or so 

had in its, his or their possession or control 

BCCTMM S. It is unlawful for any person holding a nonresident 
license as herein provided, to take out of the state more than 
fifty birds or twenty-five fish protected by the laws of this state, in 
any one year. Provided that this section shall be construed to mean 
that when fifty birds and twenty-five tish. of any kind or variety have 
been taken from the state by the holder of a non-resident license 
further rijfht to take any kind of birds or tish by the holder of said 
lie. use shall cease. No transportation company or common carrier 
shall receive for transportation or shipment out of the state any birds. 
fowls or animals protected by the laws of the state, except when the 
same shall be in the personal pnsai aslini of, or carried as baggage or 
express by the owners thereof, and such owners shall have in his 
possession at the time of such taking out of the state a non-resident 
license duly issued to him under the provisions of law, and the number </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
11 

anil kind of birds and fish 30 carried out of the state should be 
endorsed on the license of pefaoa entitled to take them out, and MM 
persons shall accompany the said birds, fowls or animals on the fta«M 
train or other conveyance of the common carrier beyond the border^ of 

the state. Any person who shall v 
section shall be punished by a tim 
more than one hundred dollars, or 
not more than sixty days. 

iol 

:ite any of the provisions at this 
f not less than fifty dollars nor 
imprisonment in the county jail 

by 

BBC rios &lt;». It is unlawful 

for any person a resident of this 
nit this state any birds. fo« U ..r 
state, except when accompanied 

state to ship or take within or « ithi 
animals protected by the laws of this 

by the same and in his prmmic 011 the same train, as provi.l 
in this act. Any person who shall violate any of the provisi. 
this section shall be punished by a tine of the dollars for each bird so 
shipped or taken, or by imprisonment in the county jail not more th.ui 
ninety davs. 

Skciion ID. It is hereby required that any and all packages 
containing fish or ga*M shall be labeled in plain letters on the addres, 
side of the package, so as to disclose the fact 1 that said packat 
tains tish or game, and the amount of said tish or game so contained 
in said package. Any i&gt;er«m who shall deliver to a common carrier 
for transportation any package or parcel containing tish or game, which 
said package or parcel shall not be so labeled as herein required, or 
who shall place upon said package or parcel a false statement 
the contents thereof, shall be punished by a tine of not less than 
twenty-live dollars nor more than one hundred dollars, or by imp 
meut in the county jail not more than thirty days. 

Section 11. Every i&gt;erson 

Jelivering to a common carrier a 
or (fame, shall place upon - u. 1 
own. T or consigner of mM pack- 

package or parcel containing tish 
package the name and addresa ot th. 

th 

age or parcel, and also place upon such package a description of the 

in 

contents thereon, containing the number of birds or animals . 

kind and the number of lish oi ,_¦ 
provisions of this section, shall 

tea variety. Any per— violating the 
upon conviction thereof, be punished 

by a fine of not less than ten dollars nor more than tiftv dollar 

Skciion 12. It shall be unlawful and is hereby prohibited 
&gt;r any common carrier r&gt;r agent, servant or employe of a c..min..n 
nrrier. to receive for transportation or transport any pack... 

parcel containing tish or game unless the same shall be lalx-i 
provided in sections 111 ami 11 of this article. Any person, tirm or 

corporation violating the provisions of this section shall forfeit to the 
State of Nebraska a sum not k*a than twenty-five dollars nor am 
than one hundred dollars, in the discretion of the court. ' 

Skction 13. It shall be unlawful and is hereby prohibited for mv 
person, firm or corporation acting as common carrier. to 
bring into this state any Bah or game fr..in any state during the time 
that such other state prohibits the transportation of such tish or </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

firm or corporation violating the provisions of this section shall forfeit 
t.i the state the sum of not less than twenty-five dollars nor more than 
une hundred dollars in the discretion of the court. 

Skction 14. It shall be unlawful and is prohibited for any 
B, tirm or corporation or common carrier to ship into or 
through this state from any other state any fish or game prohibited 
by the law* &lt;&gt;t said state to be shipped or transported and it shall be 
the duty of the state fish and game commissioner of this state or his 
deputy to seize, hold and dispose of. according to the laws of this 
~tate. any fish or game brought into or shipped into this state, or 
carried through, or attempted to be carried through this state, prohibited 
to be so shipped or transported by the laws of any other 
state, and further to dispose of the same according to the lava of 
•ate. Any person, tirm or corporation violating the provisions of 
thi&gt; act shall upon conviction thereof be fined in any sum not less 
than twenty-five dollars nor more than one hundred dollars, in the 
discretion of the court. 

tSixTiON 15. Any person, company or corporation, or any 
t or servant of the same who shall, for compensation or otherwise, 
sport or offer or receive for shipment or transportation any 
lals. fish, fowls or birds for which a closed season is provided by 
during such closed season, or who shall transport or offer or 
M for shipment or transportation to any place beyond this state 
animals, fish, fowls or birds for which an open season is provided 
iw, during such open season, except as provided in section eight 

(») of this article, shall forfeit not less than twenty-five dollars nor 
more than one hundred dollars for each such violation, to be recovered 
m a civil action brought in the name of the state fish and game com¦iasioacr 
or one of his deputies. The possession of any such animals, 
fowls or birds during the closed season therefor, for a shipment or in 
transit, shall be prima facie evidence of the violation of this section. 
Provided, however, that game and fish lawfully killed or taken 
during the open season may be lawfully carried out of the state at any 
time during the five days next following the end of such open season, 
under the provisions and restrictions hereinbefore provided. It shall 
be the duty of every person, whenever any animal, fish or game of 
any of the kinds the taking, catching or killing of which is prohibited 
by law at any or at all times (except during the period's in which the 
same may be lawfully taken, caught or killed), is offered to him for 
;«&gt;rtation out of the state, to at once notify and give full particulars 
concerning such offer and by whom made, to the state fish 
and game commissioner or one of his deputies. All sections of this 
act relating to the having in possession or under control, or the sale, 
shipment or transportation of any animal, fish, water-fowl or bird, 
shall be construed to include any and all parts of the flesh and meat 
thereof. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
13 

Section 16. It shall be unlawful to store or to receive for 
storage any game or fish within this state, except as follow*, to- 

ll) During the open season for such game or fish, and for 
five days thereafter, when the same is stored for the person lawfully in 
possession thereof. 

(2) At any time of the year when the same has been law 
fully imported into this state. 

Whoever violates any of the provisions of this section ~h ill 
upon conviction thereof be fined in any sum not less than fifty dollars nor 
more than one hundred dollars or be imprisoned in the jail of the proper 
county not exceeding ninety days. 

Section 17. No game or fish shall be held in possession 
of or placed upon the table of any hotel, restaurant, cafe, or boarding 
house, or named on its menu or bill of fare as food for its patrons, 
either under the name used in this act or under any other name or 
guise whatever except during the open season therefor and for the 
period of five days thereafter. 

Provided that game and fish confiscated under the prov 
of this act shall be delivered to one or more of the public institutions 
for the care of the unfortunate or other charitable institutions. 

Whoever violates any of the provisions of this section &gt;h.ill 
upon conviction thereof be fined in any »um not exceeding one 
hundred dollars, or be imprisoned in the jail of the proper county not 
exceeding thirty days. 

Section 18. The naming of game or fish upon any such 
menu as food for patrons shall be prima facie evidence of the poaaession 
of the same by the proprietor of such hotel, restaurant, cafe or 
boarding house. Nothing in this act shall be construed to prohibit the 
stoiage, transportation or use of any fish lawfully imported into this 
state. 

\RTICLE III 

Section 1. Every net, seine, trap, explosive, poisonous or 
stupefying substance or device used or intended for use in taking or 
killing game or fish in violation of this act, is hereby declared to be a 
public nuisance and may be abated and summarily destroyed by any 
person, and it shall be the duty of every such officer authorized to 
enforce this act to seize and summarily destroy the same, and no 
prosecution or suit shall be maintained for such destruction; provided, 
that nothing in this division shall be construed as affecting the right of 
the commissioner to use such means as may be proper for the promotion 
of game and fish propagation and culture, nor as authorizing 
the seizure or destruction of firearms, except as hereinafter 
provided. And, provided further, that it shall be lawful to take </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

minnows of any variety not protected by this act. for bait, in the 
shallow waters of this state with nets or seines not exceedinR twenty 
'i length and throe feet in depth, and nets and seines of such 
description are evecpted from the aperatkM of this section. 

Skction 2. It shall be unlawful for ,inv perm or person-, to 
injure, disturb, or destroy any hatching box, hatching house, or pond 
use.l f.ir hatching or propagating lish. &lt;&gt;r to injure or destroy or disturb 
any spawn or fry, or tish. in any batching box. hatching house, or poad, 
&gt;&gt;r ctream; provided, that the lish commissioners of this state mav take 
or cause to Ik- taken any of the lah named in this section for the pur•f 
propagation, or stocking the waters of this state. Every per-..ti 
violating any provisions of this section shall be fruilty of a mis- 

demeanor, and punished by a fine 
ich fish taken, or held in poai 
section, or by imprisonment in the c 
in the discretion of the court. 

f not more than ten (S10) dollars 
'¦¦too, or other offense under this 
mnty jail not more than ten day» 

Sf.ction 3. All puns, ammunition, dogs, blinds and decoys, 
and any and all fishing tackle, in actual use by any person or persons 
while hunting or fishing in this state without license or permit, when 
such license or permit is required by this act, shall be forfeited to the 
State and it is made the duty of the Commissioner and e\ery officer 

charged with the enforcement of thii 
same in the manner provided for th&lt; 
execution, and to pay over the procc 
for the use of the school fund. 

act to seize, sell or dispose of the 
sale or dis|xisition of property on 

Is thereof to the county treasurer 

Skction 4. It shall be unlawful for any person to catch, 
interfere with, injure, or in any manner destroy, or maliciously disturb 
to the damage of the private property of another, the fish in, or 
work connected with, any private fish pond, not exceeding ten acres in 
this state. Any person or person-, violating the provisions of this 

section shall be fined in any sum not less than ten dollars nor more 
than one hundred dollars: and it shall be lawful for any person to 
take up. remove, or clear away any tish net, fish lines, or fish pound 
placed or put in the waters of any lake, pond or reservoir contrary to 
the provisions of this act. 

ARTICLE IV 

Section 1.— (License) The game and fish commissioner shall 
upon application and the payment to the state treasurer of the fee by 
this act required, issue to any non-resident of this state, a license 
authorizing such licensee, in person within this state to hunt for and 
kill gaaK, and to lish for and take tish. during the o|H-n season for 
such game and tish and to have in his possession and dispose of the 

same subject to all of the restricts 
the commissioner may deliver to 
counties blank licenses bearing his 
and the same may in such case be 
of the Commissioner ujion the term 

ins imposed by this act. Provided 
the County Clerks of the several 
signature or a fac simile thereof, 
issuei by such Clerks in the name 

and conditions above prescribed. </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 

All blank licenses delivered to the several County Clerks shall be 
numbered by the Commissioner anil when such license shall have been 
issued by the County dork of any County as herein provided he shall 
immediately notify the state treasurer by mail atattaK the number of 
such license, the name anil residence of the licensee and the date when 
issued, and shall remit the license fee to said state treasurer, who 
shall keep a record of all licenses issued under this act which shall be 
open for inspection as in case of other public records of the state. 

Skction 2. It shall be unlawful for any person not a bona fide 
nt « &gt;f this stati- to pursue, hunt, kill or wound wiihintlv 
&lt;if the animals, birds or tish, or to tish for, or take out of this state any 
of the birds or tish protected by this act, except in accordance with the 
provisions hereof and without first having procured a license theref' t. 
as in this act provided. Whoever violates the provisions of this section 
shall be punished by a fine not exceeding one hundred (?HK)I dollars 
or by imprisonment in the jail of the proper county not exceeding sixty 
(60) days for each of such offenses. And for the purpose of this section 
every such unlawful .shipment, or offer for shipment and such unlawful 
hunting and fishing in each calendar day shall be deemed a separate 
offense. 

Section 3. Except as otherwise provided in this act. it shall 
be unlawful for any resident of this state without first having- procured 
a license therefor, to hunt or fish within this state, provided th.i 
license shall authorize said person to fish and hunt within any county 
of the state: and provided further, any person may, during ttv 
season as herein defined, hunt and fish within the county of his actual 
residence without such license. Any person offending against the provisions 
of this act shall upon conviction thereof be fined in any sum not 
exceeding fifty dollars, or imprisoned in the jail of the proper county 
not exceeding thirty days. 

Skction 4. The license required by the last preceding section 

Pill upon the payment of the fee h&lt; 
any resident of this state in like 
subject to like condition as in case 

L-reinafter named therefor, be imanner, 
by the same officer and 
! of licenses to non-residents of this 

Section 5. The holder of 

¦ay license authorizing him to ship 
int outside of this state shall upon 

or transport game or fish to any pc 

offering any such game or fj s f, f or shipment to any common carrier 
present to the agent, servant or representative of such carrier a true 
invoice of such shipment showing the number and kind of birds ami 
the number and variety of fish thereof and shall at the same time 
deliver to such agCBt, sonant or representative, his license 
pursuant to this act, and such agent, servant or representative shall .it 
the time of receiving such consignment of game or tish, endorse upon 
such license with ink, the date of the receipt of such consignment with 
the number and varieties of such game or fish, so shipped or offered 
for shipment, -together with the name of the consignee, and the point to 
which consigned. Every person shipping or offering for shipment or </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

receiving as eaaaigl ant or representative of any 
common carrier any fane or fish in \ iolation of this act shall upon conviction 
thereof be fined in any sum not exceed int; one hundred dollars or 
be imprisoned in the jail of the proper county not exceeding sixty days. 
And every common carrier receiving for shipment or transportation any 
gameorfish in violation of this section shall pay to the State of Nebraska, 
not les&gt; than fifty 0SO| dollars nor more than one hundred ($100) dollars. 
All tines recovered under any of the provisions of this act shall, when 
collected. l&gt;e paid into the treasury of the county for the use of the 
school fund, and the corporate authorities of any county, city or 
village, within whose territorial jurisdiction such fine was recovered, 
when such fines are collected, shall pay to the complaining- witness in 
such prosecution, out of the general fund of such county receiving such 
fine, an amount equal to one-half of the tine actually collected, upon 
the proper application of the party entitled to the same, in the manner 
usual for the presentation of claims against counties. 

K SECTION h. The state treasurer shall charge for and collect in 
ance for services required by this act, which shall be disposed of 
as hereafter provided; viz.: For each license issued to a non-resident of 
this state, ten dollars; for each license issued to a resident of this state, 
one dollar; for each and every other license certificate or permit authorized 
by this act. one dollar. 

Sic tion 7. All monies derived from licenses and permits issued 

pursuant to this act shall by the 
use of the school fund of the state 

state treasurer be paid over for the 

Section 8. All licenses 

ued pursuant to the provisions of 


this act shall expire on the 31st d 
date of their issuance. 

ly of December next succeeding the 

SeCTIOS ( t. Prosecutions may be brought by any person or 

I* r-ons in the name of the State &lt; 
parties violating any of the provisi 

if Nebraska, against any party or 
_&gt;ns of this act, before any Justice of 

the Peace or County Judge of the County in which said violation is 
charged to have taken place, or before any Court of competent jurisdiction; 
and it is Blade the duty of all County Attorneys of this State to 
see that the provisions of this act are enforced in their respective 
counties, and they shall prosecute all offenders on receiving information 
of the violation of any of the provisions of this act: and it is made 
the duty of all ifcerifft, deputy sheriffs, constables, and police officers. 
to inform against and prosecute each and every party or parties, person 
or per stum, whom there is reasonable or probable cause to believe are 
guilty of violating any of the provisions of this act. Any county 
attorney, sheriff, deputy sheriff, constable or police officer who shall 
fail, neglect, or refuse to discharge the said duties hereby imposed on 
such officers, respectively, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, 
and on conviction be fined not less than twenty-five dollars nor more 
than one hundred dollars, for each offense. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>