<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of Game and Fish Commission of the State of Nebraska for the Two Years Ending December 31, 1918 to the Governor</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PANORAMA OF THE STATE HATCHERY, GRETNA, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE GAME AND FISH COMMISSION OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1918 TO THE GOVERNOR .^^S Sy^.. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">.a 3 5 I 3 2 "a a o 00 y-t &lt;Si — £ ■* I S u s o ri 55 E^ a ■M i o O </seg>
            <seg id="p004">To His Excellency, Keith Neville, Governor of the Htate of Nebraska : Dear Sir: I have the honor to submit herewith a report of the financial condition of the Game and Fish Commission for the bien - iiium beginning January 1st, 1917, and ending December 31st. 1913. Also a report of the number of arrests and convictions caused for unlawful hunting and fishing; the amount of fines imposed; the number of illegal fishing devices confiscated and destroyed; the amount of game and fish confiscated and disposed of; the amount of money realized for the sale of fish for stocking private ponds and from the sale of licenses during the years 1917 and 1918. Also recommendations pertaining to a few changes desired in our present game and fish laws; supplemented with a detailed report of the State Fish Hatchery by \V. J. O'Brien, Superintendent. Respectfully submitted GEO G. KOSTER. Chief Deputy Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE GAME AND FISH COMMISSION APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENSES Salary of Chief Deputy Warden. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $3,200.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 191S 2,799.99 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 400.01 Salary of Superintendent of Hatcheries, South Bend, Nebr. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $3,600.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 3,150.00 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 f 450.00 Salary of Three Deputies. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $7,200.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 5,378.21 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $1,821.7» Salary of Special Deputies. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $2,400.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 2,042.71 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 357 29 Salary of Secretary. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $1.(80.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 1,470.00 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 210.00 Traveling Expense. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $8,200.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 6,686.04 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 11,513.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 9 Books, Blanks, Postage and Office Expense. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $2,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 1,992.40 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 f 7.«0 Necessary Labor-Hatchery South Bend. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $4,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 3,102.50 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 897.50 Procuring and Transplanting Fish. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $4,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 3,926.57 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 73. 43 New Apparatus and Repairs. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $3,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 2,800.85 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 119.15 Cement Works and Improvements, South Bend Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $1,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 900.00 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 100.00 Seining and Conservation of Fish. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $4,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 3,952.73 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 47.27 Maintenance Sub-Fish Hatchery. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $10,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 7,976.29 Balance on hand December 31st. 1918 $ 2.023.71 For Building Ice-House, Storeroom and Oarage. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $3,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 2,997.2t Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 1.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Bass. Croppie, and Perch, Askey Lake, Marian County. Private Fish Pond. Hon. Sophus, Neble, Springfield, Sarpy County. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 11 For Purchase of Auto Truck and Upkeep of Same. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $1,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 999.92 Balance on hand December 31»t, 1918 $ .08 Rebuilding Flushing System and Excavating Ponds. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $1,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 713.05 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 286.95 Grading Road from East to West Entrance to Park and Improve- ments to Grounds. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $1,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 990.15 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 % 9.85 Appropriation for New Fish Car. Amount appropriated April 1st, 1917 $15,000.00 Amount expended to December 31st, 1918 14,873.81 Balance on hand December 31st, 1918 $ 126.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">- ~ ■ o o r. M g "5 pa 6 PI c a 0 - "^ I "* I ao - m I 3 &lt; - 1 A ■ »♦ . E "V .^ H^ i </seg>
            <seg id="p012">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 13 Money* Paid to State Treasurer for Sale of License** for Wars 1917 and 101N Non-Reident Licenses Conntie.. " "•" Murul mcen.e. Tota , Licenses. Resident Adams * 30.00 11,240.00 $1,270.00 Antelope 60.00 1.405.00 1,465.00 Arthur 33.00 33.00 Banner 33.00 33.00 Blaine 278.00 278.00 Boone 858.00 858.00 Box Butte 10.00 955.00 965.00 245.00 245.00 949.00 1,029.00 1,920.00 1,920.00 546.00 546.00 955.00 955.00 1.384.00 1,384.00 250.00 250.00 52.00 390.00 442.00 1,626.00 1,626.00 Cheyenne I 24.00 725.00 749.00 Clay 811.00 811.00 Colfax 815.00 815.00 Cummings 20.00 646.00 666.00 1,065.00 1.065.00 884.00 1.276.00* 898.00 998.00 882.00 882.00 365.00 479.00 1,336.00 1,336 00 297.00 297.00 Douglas 402.00 12,874.00 13.276.00 Dundy 2.00 120.00 122.00 Fillmore 785.00 785.00 Franklin 82.00 679.00 761.00 •Frontier 538.00 638.00 Furnas 1.080.00 1.080.00 Gage 4.00 1,672.00 1,676.00 Garden 495.00 495.00 Garfield 182.00 182.00 Gosper 90.00 JO. 00 •Greeley 365.00 365.00 Grant 10.00 567.00 577.00 •Hall 200.00 2,048.00 2.248.00 Hamilton 850.00 850.00 •Estimated •Boyd ' _ Brown 80.00 Buffalo Burt Butler I Cass Cedar Chase 52.00 Cherry uster (akota 392.00 •awes lawson (euel 114.00 lodge IJixon </seg>
            <seg id="p013">F •* i 1 1 L 9 ■ ■ ■ E ■ I m ( 4 fj — r ■ 1) /. 5 a \ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 15 Moiw'js 1'nid to Stale Tri'iisuivr for Sale of IJmiws for Year* 1917 ami 1918. — Continued Non-residents | Resident Licenses Licenses Counties. nun-reBiaenu , nes.aem ToU , Harlan 32.00 455.00 487.00 Hitchcock 249.00 248.00 Holt 50.00 1.208.00 1,256.00 Hooker 176.00 176.00 Howard 648.00 648.00 Jefferson 10.00 1.532.00 1,542.00 Johnson 383.00 383.00 Kearney ! 249.00 249.00 Keith 348.W0 348.00 Keya Paha 90.00 90.00 Kimball 8.00 287.00 295.00 Knox 813.00 813.00 Lancaster 6,575.00 6.575.00 •Lincoln 40.00 1,345.00 1,385.00 Logan 121.00 121.00 Loup 49.00 49.00 McPherson 23.00 23.00 Madison 1,929.00 1,929.00 Merrick 1 621.00 621.00 Morrill | 1,284.00 1,284.00 Nance 499.00 499.00 Xemaha 617.00 617.00 Nuckolls 30.00 848.00 878.00 Otoe 710.00 710.00 Pawnee i 310.00 310.00 Perkins 247.00 247.00 Phillips »76.00 976.00 Pierce 1 781.00 781.00 Platte j I 1,161.00 1,161.00 Polk 735.00 735.0* Red Willow $ 6.00 713.00 L 719.00 Richardson 82.00 503.00 .685.00 Rock 60.00 397.00 457.00 Saline 1.345.00 1,345.00 Sarpy 321.00 821.00 Saunders 1,743.00 1,743.00 SCOtts Bluff 188.00 3,231.00 3,4f9.00 Sewal-d 1,493.00 1,493.00 Sheridan 30.00 567.00 597.00 Sherman 265.00 265.00 Sioux 20.00 144.00 124.00 'Estimated </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Morning Shoot, Ericson Lake. Wheeler County. Where the Catfish Play, Beaver Creek, Ravenna, Buffalo County. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 17 Moneys Paid to State Treasurer for Hale of I/.ceimes for Years 1917 and 1»18. — Concluded Non-residents Resident Licenses Licenses Counties. Total Stanton ' 390.00 390.00 Thayer &gt; 22.00 j 867.00 889.00 Thomas ' 10.00 204.00 214.00 Thurston ! 386.00 386.00 Valley ' 775.00 775.00 Washington ' 765.00 7«5.00 Wayne ' .' 275.00 275.00 Webster ' 160.00 763.00 923.00 Wheeler J 59.00 159.00 York ' 1,617.00 1,617.00 Sioux City ' 174.00 174.00 Total ' $2,230.00 $86,680.00 I $90,810.00 Receipts for Scientific permits $ 9.00 •Estimated $90,819.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION II ARRESTS, SEIZURES AND CONVICTIONS During the last biennium the Commission has caused the ar - rest of 748 persons charged with violation ot the Game and Fish laws; 730 of these were convicted and paid fines, in some cases jail sentences were inflicted. The total fines imposed and paid into the various county treasures amounted to $3,842.86. The number of unlawful fishing nets and traps confiscated and found in the streams were 433. All kinds of unlawful fishing de- Vices were destroyed by the local and special deputies. All game and fish confiscated have been given to the State Institutions. The department has found it difficult in many cases to secure convictions on account of the attitude of County Attorneys and judges being too lenient. However, we have had some very hearty co-operation in enforcing the law from the many sportsmen and their organizations in this State. The local and special deputies al - so have done a great deal for the benefit of the game and fish. RECOMMENDATIONS This department now employs three deputy game wardens. I wish to recommend that this number be raised to six and divide the State in six districts, giving each man a district to look after and take care of. During the past six years there have been no setieing licenses issued. 1 wish to recommend a license for the trapping of fur-bear - ing animals. There should be a separate license for this. Reserv - ing the right for a man to trap on his own land without a license. As the law now reads, we have no Jurisdiction over the fishing in the Missouri River and I wish to recommend that a law be pass - ed that will provide that persons must have a license to seine or fish in the Missour River and give this State control over the fishing therein. I wish also to recommend that an appropriation be made for stocking the State with Pheasants. During the past two years this department has turned into the school fund of the state over »90,819.0u from the sale of fishing and hunting licenses. This is a great deal more than is used in the upkeep of the department. CONCLUSION In conclusion, I wish to express my gratitude to the sportsmen, and Rod and Gun Clubs of the State, that have interested themselves in this department; also the special deputy game wardens, through whose efforts a number of prosecutions have been secured. I wish also to thank the press of the state for courtesies extended. Very respectfully, GEO. G. KOSTER. Chief Deputy Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Judge Patterson, Landing Brook Trout, White Clay Creek, Sheridan County. Casting for Bass, Oberfelders Lake, Cheyenne County </seg>
            <seg id="p020">1 liAME AND FISH COMMISSION TO MY OLD CASTING ROD. I will take you out again Dear Friend. To see you once more graceful bend Your agate guides are dearer to me Than diamonds and precious stones would be Every scar on your sides brings happy thoughs Of battles you and I hare fought Among the finny tribes we often have havoc wrought If you have a heart it is true as steel Your will power lies back in the reel. The only time you played, me a Joke Was when you suddenly cracked and broke, Some folks look at you and I with scorn tint they were not for fishing born Even the Holy Bible our cause defends For Jesus Disciples were fishermen. Where they say St. Peter keeps the score If fishing is good you may take to that sphere If not 0 Lord let me stay right here. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">. M s &lt; i 0 ■ E | </seg>
            <seg id="p022">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE STATE FISH HATCHERIES Hon. Keith Neville, Governor: In compliance with the law, I herewith submit a report of this branch of the Game &amp; Fish Department for the years, 1917-18, also a summary of the species, number, and disposition of fish, propagat - ed and planted from the Hatcheries, senied from overflow waters, or purchased from private fish hatcheries for distribution, together with a list of improvements, and betterments, at State Fish Hatch - eries, located at Gretna, Sarpy County, and Valentine. Cherry County. While working with you I often wonder Upon this problem I some times ponder Will there be any fishing on the golden shore SUMMARY OF DISTRIBUTION Nearly all the Pike and Trout, as well as a portion of the Black Bass, were planted in the fry stage from two to twelve weeks old, all other fish were from six months old to adult stock. This summary includes fish secured and planted from all sources; the grand total is somewhat less than the number reported two years ago, this Is accounted for by our inability to secure as many Pike eggs as form - erly, but as the number of Pike taken in our waters has never been commensurate with number of fry planted, this discrepancy does not cut much figure in general results. IVall-eyed Pike fry, (estimated) 9,550,700 Brook Trout fry, (estimated) 969,000 Rainbow Trout fry, (estimated) 899.000 Brown Trout fry, (estimated) 19,500 Black Bass 205,120 Rock Bass 16,100 Croppies 183.250 Striped Perch 172,850 Sunfish 61.700 Channel Catfish 73.200 Bullheads 192,100 Bull Frogs 33,800 Goldfish 3,088 Miscellaneous fish, seined from overflows, (est'd.) 500,000 Total 12.879,403 </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION II IMPROVEMENTS GRETNA HATCHERY Road through grounds from east to west entrance, widened so as to permit the passing of two automobiles at any point, thus lessening the danger of accidents; road to grove and residence graded down and storm sewer to carry off flood waters put in. Building 24 by 26 feet, two stories in height, cement floors and ce - ment block construction lower story, frame second story; lower por - tion to be used for double garage, fish-food cutting and cooking room and for storage of tools .upper story for employees quarters. Ice huse rebuilt of stone and cement, 18 by 30 feet. Double cement block toilet rooms, 12 by 14 feet, with modern toilet facilities; ce - ment block retaining wall along hillside connecting garage, toilet rooms, and ice house, and extending to driveway and to grove. Ground in front of all three buildings graded down and cement walk three hundred feet long built from hatching house to ice house and garage, and two hundred feet of cement gutter put in from grove driveway to ditch along main road; roadway in front of hatch - ing house, 20 by 50, built of concrete, and ornamental cement tank constructed on same; cement retaining wall built across large Bass pond, dividing pond in two parts. Two cement retaining walls re - built in nursery ponds at rear of hatching house; spring house part - ly rebuilt, and new top put on reservoir for house and barn water supply; part of flushing system under trout ponds and to Platte River rebuilt, with new boxes and steel gates at stone dams. This work will be completed in March, 1919. Accumulated mud remov - ed from all trout ponds. Bass, Croppie. and Perch ponds. New fish car house built at Gretna, 16 by 86 and 16 feet high, with cement foundation, 4 by 4 posts re-inforced with 3 inch angle, iron bolted to posts and set two feet in cement foundation, drop siding and shingle roof appropriately painted and lettered. Hatching house, superintendent's residence, two employee's cottages, barn store room, and work shop. Garage, icehouse, light plant building, twine sheds, engine rooms, and spring house all repaired and paint - ed. Mogul mill and pump repaired. Ford, one ton truck, 40 ship - ping cans, 2 seines, 2 boats, 50 new hatching trays, and all other needed hatching equipment purchased and many other repairs and improvements of minor nature made. NEW FISH CAR Owing to the dilapidated conditon of the old fish car "Antelope" which has been in continuous service for 26 years, the last legisla - ture was confronted with the necessity of making an allowance for extensive repairs on the old car or providing for a new car, and $15,000.00 was appropriated for this purpose, immediately after the legislature adjourned the purchase of the car was taken up with different car builders by correspondence, and later a personal Inspection of modern fish cars recently built for Iowa, Minnesota, </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Hackberry Club, Geo. Brandies, Omaha, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 2 7 Wisconsin, Michigan, and Ohio .was made, and plans and specifica - tions of the Iowa, Wisconsin, and Ohio, cars secured and bids asked for on construction of a car of the same character, these bids rang - ing from $26,000.00 to $27,700.00 on account of war prices on labor and materials, these figures were made by the Pullman Car Company, of Pullman, Illinois; Jewett Car Company, Newark, Ohio: and American Car &amp; Foundry Company, East St. Louis, Illinois, through the courtesy of Mr. William Baird. General Superintendent of the C. B. &amp; Q. Coach Shops Plattsmouth. Nebr., we secured the address of a number of car building companies, and in March, 1918, visited the shops of Hochkiss Blue ft Company. Harvey, Illinois. \7e found this concern admirably equpped for this kind of work, they having built or rebuilt fish cars for Michigan. Missouri, and Montana, and many live fish carrying cars for commercial fisher men, and their Superintendent was familiar with fish car construc - tion. I outlined floor plan desired and tank arrangement, and plans and specifications were drawn up and later submitted to Superin - tendent Baird and other competent car builders, and contract let for car fully equipped, including range, bedding, dishes, etc.. at a cost of $14,871.00; this car is strictly modern in every particular, having the heaviest type of steel under-frame, flexolith floor, Davis steel wheels, McCord Journal boxes, Sharon C. B. &amp; Q., standard couplers and draft rigging, steel sheeted exterior, and vestibules, 78 fet long over all, Pratt ft Lambert, steel car varnished and lettered Pullman style, interior finished in plain flush Mahogany, tank room 36 feet long equipped with 20-SO gallon tanks with additional room for 100 8-gallon shipping cans with double air system, from train line, and air pump, electric lighted, train line .and Delco storage battery system with combined electroflater for supplying air to fish tanks, double system of car heating steam heat from train line, and cold hot water heater, office sleeping room, kitchen, dining room and Delco room, giving comfortable accommodations for car crew while car is in service. We feel that in this car this State has the best car owned by any State Commission, and we feel especially Indebted to E. C. Htnshaw. Iowa Chief Game Warden, James Nevin, Chairman Wisconsin Conservation Commission, and General John C. Speaks of the Ohio Fish and Game Commission, for courtesies extended and for pointing out the good and weak points in their car construction and equipment, and furnishing plans and specifi - cation of theri State cars as we have been able to embody the best we found in their cars in the new car. CONSERVATION OF FISH Possibly a half milloin fish of various ages, comprising, Bass, Croppie, Perch, Pike, Catfish, Bullheads, Sunfish. Carp and Buf - falo-fish, have been seined from overflow ponds or drying up pools, and placed in living water during the period covered by this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">— - o U c I ■^ I c »* . J I i = 1 &gt;^ </seg>
            <seg id="p028">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION J9 but owing to the scarcity and the high wages demanded by efficient help, this work has not been prosecuted on as large a scale as it should have been. About one half of the Croppie, and practically all the Bullheads distributed have been obtained from this source; in addition to hundreds of thousands returned to the nearest living water from which they were carried by freshets or high water, while many millions more perished, to become food for the Crows, and a menace to the health of surrounding communities, on account of our inability to cover all the territory. The U. S. Bureau of Fisheries, Minnesota, Iowa, Wisconsin, Michigan, Illinois, and other States are extensively engaged in this fish reclamation work, and in some respects it is more important than the operation of suc - cessful fish hatcheries. SEINING COARSE FISH Soon after the declaration of war, both the State, and Nation - al Food Administrations, urgently requested this department to place as many fish on the market as possible, so as to supply a cheap and nutritious article of food, and a crew of men has been engaged in this work the greater part of the time for the past 18 months. We have found it impossible to make this work pay under war conditions, except in the larger lakes, the high cost of labor, subsistence, nets, boats, tents, and other equipment, eating up all the proceeds, however, this work has been prosecuted vigorously, and about 125,000 pounds of Carp, and Buffalo-fish, have been marketed at from two to ten cents per pound according to size of fish and lcoal demand, and this work when completed for the pres - ent year will show a net profit over expenses of about $1200.00 available for restocking the larger lakes seined with game fish. During the war period many states enacted legislation empowering their game and fish departments, to seine or net and sell practically all kinds of fish except Bass, Trout and Croppie. The South Dakota Warden reports the sale of 140,000 pounds of Bullheads alone. Had we possessed the authority to have carried on the work in this way the seining operations, would have proven very profitable as thous - ands of pounds of adult Channel Catfish, Bullheads, Pickerel, and other fish were returned to waters seined; In some instances these fish could have been marketed with profit to the State and marked benefit to the more highly prized game species. I am also firmly convinced this work can be more economically carried on by hiring a crew on a persentage basis, than on regular salary and expenses; on a percentage basis there is more incentive to push the work. IMPROVEMENTS VALENTINE HATCHERY The main improvements at this hatchery have consisted in changing the course of Minnechaduza Creek for a distance of about one thousand feet, and the construction of another pond covering </seg>
            <seg id="p029">R. P. Holland, Jr., of Atchison, Kansas, With a Fourteen Pound Wild Goose Killed on Missouri River. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION SI about two acres, at the rear of hatching house on the site of the old creek bed. This ground was covered with a dense growth of trees and bushes and underlaid with shale and stone, making it an ex - pensvie and difficult work both in changing the course of creek and the excavation of the new pond, but will when completed add much to the appearance of the grounds as well as adding a fine deep pond for Bass culture. The dams on several of the other ponds have been widened and leveled down. Ground around the new hatching house graded down and driveway and cement curbing put in; a cement walk from the Foreman's cottage to hatching house constructed, two bridges built over storm ditch, about one thousand feet of stone riprapping put In along driveway bordering Bass and Croppie ponds, and considerable riprapping done on banks of all other ponds where needed, a light auto truck, 20 new shipping cans, large heater, seines nets and hatching equipment, including eight new galvanized trout hatching troughs reinforced with angle iron and with angle Iron stands complete. Electric light installed in barn, residence and hatching house, also small garage and other required improvements. STATE FAIR FISH DISPLAY The usual live fish display was made at the State Fair past two seasons, now features at the last Fair being the two acquariums containing deformed fish and the Albino Trout, secured from the Minnesota Fish Commission and shown at our Fair for the first time. With the addition of new buildings and growing beauty of the Fair Grounds, it is only a question of time until these grounds will become a part of Lincoln's boulevard and park system and the fish exhibit could be made a permanent feature the same as in many other cities, as the public is beginning to recognize the educational value of a permanent aquarium. NECESSARY IMPROVEMENTS No new building or new ponds are needed at the Gretna hatch - ery, as expensive buildings do not make a successful fish hatchery and we have all the ponds that our water supply will maintain, in fact more than we can supply during dry seasons without pumping water from the Platte River. Cement bottoms should be put in the Croppie and Perch ponds to prevent seepage and do away with the expense of pumping water, as the spring would be ample to supply all other ponds without pumping in normal seasons. More retain - ing walls and walks should be built, the road from the east to west entrance and to the residence and picnic grounds should be covered with fine crushed stone or macadamized. A cement face should be put on all five stone dams, more ornamental trees and shrubbery planted and considerable blue grass sodding and seeding done. At the Valentine Hatchery, a small addition should be added to the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">a e a £ E - 5 3 ■ - s I i 6 i = O 5 £ S </seg>
            <seg id="p032">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 33 Foreman's cottage and a small building near hatching house con - structed to be used for storing hatching equipment, nets, shipping cans, tools, etc., also a toilet room with modern accessories. A sec - ond pipe line should be laid from the upper Bass pond in the gov - ernment canyon to the hatching house; this would furnish water in case of freezing or other accident to present supply and should be put in so as to furnish water to the foreman's cottage, barn, lawn, and for new pond construction. We should add from five to ten acres more pond surface during the coming two years to provide more room for Bass, Croppie, and Perch rearing ponds. Ol'R FISH LAWS When the State Constitution is revised several changes should he made regarding our game and fish laws. With the almost pro - hibitive price of meat there is a demand that more use should be made of our streams and lakes in the production of food, and the constitution ought to be changed so that fish laws can be enacted to meet local conditions, instead of being uniform for the entire State. No harm would be done by allowing netting or seining in large streams like the Platte River, with large mesh nets under proper supervision and a number of edible fish could be taken from this and other streams without impairing the fish supply in these waters. Most of our streams are now heavily stocked with Carp which now commands a ready sale and are not taken in any quantity by hook and line fishing from streams like the Platte, Loup or Elk - horn. Few Bass. Croppie, or Perch are taken on the lower portion of these streams, and no harm would be done if Catfish, Pike, and other fish weighing more than one pound were taken. Some change should be made in law relating to overflow ponds and cut-offs; high waters in the spring put large numbers of fish in these ponds or lakes, and if the owners of abutting lands are not allowed to seine them in some instances they resent their being seined under state supervision, so it might be well to allow the owners of land bordering these lakes a small moiety from the sale of fish; we would then, in most instances, have the co-operation of these lake owners instead of their opposition and resentment; their principal conten - tion is that they pay taxes on these overflowed lands and should be entitled to some share in the fish, and some have the Hun idea that they own the fish. As a result of the rapid increase in the number of Perch in some of the sand hill lakes, and also the Pick - erel, I would favor allowing these fish to be taken through the ice with hook and line. A more rigid definition of what constitutes public waters should be given, when applied to lakes or cut-offs; while our fish laws define public lakes as any body of water cover - ing over ten acres, many complaints come in from time to time, of landowners fencing in portions of lakes stocked by this Commission, and some law should be enacted to properly punish this brand of fish hog. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">. li — I I B I a t </seg>
            <seg id="p034">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION II CASH FUND $616.20, derived from the sale of fish for stocking private waters has been used for paying hatcheries bills, for which no specific appropriation was made, and there is enough remaining in this fund to take up any small deficiencies we may have in our maintainence fund to April 1st STATE PROPERTY AT FISH HATCHERIES Gretna. Site of 53 acres all fenced $ 8,000.00 Hatching house and aquarium 4,000.00 Superintendents residence 3,500.00 Barn, store-room, workshop and driving sheds 2,500.00 Assistants cottage 1.500.00 Electric light plant and building 1,500.00 Garage, tool house and ice house 3,000.00 Engine houses, gasoline engines, pumps and pipping 1,500.00 Spring house and other outbuildings 500.00 Twenty-five ponds with supply pipes 4,000.00 Fish car "Angler," 15,000.00 Fish car shed 1,200.00 Steel Mogul mill pumps and flume, 500.00 Ford, one ton auto truck 700.00 Team of horses, three wagons, two sets harness 600.00 Hatching apparatus, furniture and shipping cans 800.00 Estimated value of fish on hand 2,000.00 Miscellaneous tools not enumerated 500.00 Total $51,300.00 Valentine Site of 528 acres all fenced $ 5,000.00 Hatching house and hatching appartus 2,000.00 Foreman's cottage 1,200.00 Barn, garage, and other outbuildings 1,000.00 Eleven pounds, including dams and supply pipes 4,000.00 Estimated value of fish on hand 2,000.00 Team of horses, two wagons, one set harness 500.00 Light Ford auto truck 400.00 Miscellaneous tools 300.00 Total $16,400.00 RECOMMENDATIONS First. Permit fishing through ice tor Perch, and Pickerel. Second. Open season for Black Bass, June 1st instead of April 1st. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Pibel Lake, Greeley County. A Few Black Bass Landed by Chris Olsen, Crystal Lake, Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p036">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 37 Third. Impose license on commercial fishermen, operating on the Missouri River, same as the Iowa law. Fourth. Fix a size limit at which Channel Catfish, Croppie, Sunfish and Striped Perch may be legally taken. Fifth. Specifically define, public and private lakes, and fix penalty for molesting citizens fishing legally in public lakes. CONCLUSION Owing to deficient rainfall the past two seasons .many natural ponds and small lakes have either dried up or become so low that the fish in them perished from suffocation during the winter and have diminshed the fish supply to that extent. Black Bass in the sand hill lakes are being taken in small numbers from the lakes that froze out during the severe winter of 1915. As a result of the loss of the Bass, the Striped Perch and Pickerel have increased in these lakes at a wonderful rate and tons of the fish have been taken during the past two seasons. Fishing can be allowed for these fish both summer and winter without diminishing the supply, from a small plant of Perch made in Pibel Lake, Greeley County, in 1912. Mr. James Gilroy. the owner, reports this body of water literally teeming with Perch, and many other instances could be cited of the wonderful increase of this fish in the central and wes - tern portion of our state; while the increase in the catch of Crop - pies has been no less phenomlnal in some waters; hook and line fishing with the exception of the Bass fishing in Brown and Cherry Counties, has been about normal for the past two years; while the weather conditions have not been favorable as a whole for fish life, these conditions have also interfered with agriculture and vegeta - tion as well as fish. The state property at both hatcheries is in fine condition and with the improvements made the past two years, we are in excellent condition to carry on successful work in the future. In closing this report I wish to thank members of the last leg - islature for generaus support given the hatcheries, the press for much free advertising of the activities of this department. Chief Warden Koster for his active co-operation at all times, and the hatcheries employees who have been mainly responsible for results accomplished. Respectfully submitted, W. J. O'BRIEN </seg>
            <seg id="p037">t_ </seg>
            <seg id="p038">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Disposition. Counties. Antelope — Neligh, Mill pond, 900 Clearwater, Elkhorn Slough 900 Brown — Ainsworth, Clear Lake 1,000 Johnstown, Lorenzen Pond 500 Long Pine, Hagans Lake 400 Enderlake, Enders Lake 500 Boone — Petersburg, Beaver Creek iOU Albion, Mill Pond 500 Buffalo — Kearney, Kearney Lake 300 Miller, Spring Lake 2,000 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 500 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lake 500 Custer — Stapleton, So., Loup River 12,000 Stapleton, Uphoff Lake : ..... 500 Stapleton, Spring Lake 400 Callaway, Mc'Connels Lake 1,000 Cherry — Valentine, Canfords Lake 500 Valentine, Mill Pond 20 Newton, Wolfenden Pond 300 Merriman, Arnots Lake 500 Merriman, Goodfellows Lake 400 Kennedy, Buffalo Lake 1,000 Dewey Lake, Marsh Lake 1,500 Kennedy, Buffalo Lake 1,000 Dewey Lake, Marsh Lake 1,500 Dewey Lake, Trout Lake 2,000 Cuming — Wisner, Leisy Lake 1,000 Chase — Imperial, Arterburn Lake 500 Lamar, Spring Lake 500 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 14,200 Dawes — Crawford, Military Lake 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Barn and Workshop, State Fisheries, Near Gret la. Feeding Rainbow Trout, State Fisheries, Gretna. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 41 Disposition. Counties. Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 10,100 Deuel — Big Springs. Spring Lake 500 Dodge — Fremont, Rickey Lake 1,800 Furnas — Cambridge, Crowleys Lake 500 Gage — Beatrice, Grants Pond 200 Harlan — Oxford, Askey Lake tOO Alma, Club Lake 800 Orleans, Mill Pond 1,000 Howard — St. Paul, Chads Lake 500 Hall — Cairo, St. Mcheals Slough 500 Holt — Inman, O'Donnels Lake 1,000 Emmett, Emmett Lake 500 Stuart, Dora Lake 500 Atkinson, Mill Pond 800 Atkinson, Spring Lake 500 Atkinson, Wenner Pond 500 Lincoln — Wellfleet, Opal Lake 500 Hershey, Spring Lakes 500 North Platte, Spring Lake 500 Madison — Battle Creek, Hughes Lake 1,000 BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Disposition. Counties. Morrill — Bridgeport, Irrigation Lake 800 Merrlck— Central City, Mc'Nurlin Pond 100 Otoe — Nebraska City. Park Lake 300 Nebraska City, Youngs Lake 300 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">_ a c IS p .« M </seg>
            <seg id="p042">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 43 Disposition. Counties. Platte— Columbus, Shady Lake 2,500 Columbus, Browners Lake 2,000 Columbus, Club Lake 10.200 Columbus, Ice House Lake 500 Richardson — Humboldt, Club Lake 200 Sarpy — Meadow, Sand Pit Lake 1,900 Sheridan — Gordon, Shell Lake 500 Gordon, Spring Lake 2,000 Sioux Harrison, Wickersham Lake 500 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Lake Minatare 500 Minatare, Bass Lake 500 Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 1,000 Scotts Bluffs, Stewarts Lake 500 Scotts Bluffs, Jordans Lake 500 Seward — Seward, Goehners Lake 300 BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 2,500 Brown — Anisworth, Moon Lake 800 Ainsworth, Long Lake 100 Burt — Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 1,000 Buffalo — Kearney, Kearney Lake 500 Box Butte — Alliance, Krauses Lake 400 Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 1,000 Cheyenne- — Sidney, Irrigation Lakes 800 Lodge Pole, Oberfelders Lake 400 Cherry — Dewey Lake, Marsh Lake 1,000 Irwin, Horseshoe Lake 1,800 Cody, No, Cody Lake 1,800 Oasis, Trout Lake 1,800 Oasis, Dewey Lake 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">A Few Good Ones, From Dewey Lake. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 45 Disposition. Counties Valentine, Minnechaduza Lake 1,000 Valentine, Lovejoy Lake 500 Valentine, Kuskie Pond 200 Valentine, Jeanette Pond 200 Simeon, Mule Lake 600 Simeon, Ell Lake (00 Ely, Rush Lake 800 Cass — Louisville, Sand Pit Lakes 500 Cuming — Wisner, Cutoff Lake 500 Chase — Imperial, Municipal Lake 1,400 Enders, Frenchman River 400 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 13,500 Daves — Chadron, Waterworks Lake 600 Crawford, Mc'Dowell Lake 600 Crawford, Military Lake 1,000 Crawford, Ice House Lake 500 BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 13,100 Dundy — Benkelman, Atkinson Lake 400 Deuel— Big Springs, Spring Lake 400 Dodge — Fremont, Rickey Lake 500 Furnas — Cambridge, Crowleys Lake 500 Frontier — Curtis, Curtis Lake 500 Oreeley — Ericson, Ericson Lake 10,400 Ericson, Van Home Pond 100 Pibel, Pibel Lake 1,000 Gage— Wymore, Indian Creek 500 Grant — Hyannis, Haneys Lake 400 Harlan — Oxford, Askey Lake 300 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Two Favorite Hunting Dogs of Hackberry Club. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 49 WALL-EYED PIKE DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Disposition. Counties. Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 200,200 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 200,000 Platte — Columbus, Loup River 500,000 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Platte River 500,000 Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 500,000 Morrill, Stewarts Lake 200,000 Seward — Milford, Blue River 500,000 Seward, Mill Pond 200,000 Sarpy — Fisheries, Platte River 1,000,000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 750,000 WALL-EYED PIKE DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 500.500 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 500,000 Platte — Columbus, Loup River 500,000 Scotts Bluffs — Morrill, Platte River 500,000 Scotts Bluffs, Platte River 500,000 Seward — Milford, Blue River 500,000 Sarpy — Fisheries, Platte River 1,000,000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 1,000,000 RAINBOW TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Royal, Verdigree Creek 10,000 Boyd — Bristow, Spring Creek 5,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 30,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p047"/>
            <seg id="p048">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 51 Disposition. Counties. Cherry — Kennedy, North Loup River 10,000 Wood Lake, Evergreen Creek 5,00.0 Wood Lake, Fairfield Creek 10,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 10,000 Valentine, Seven Creeks 10.000 Valentine, Minnechaduza Creek 10,000 Valentine, Snake Creek 10,000 Valentine, Canyon Creek 5,000 Dundy — Parks, Rock Creek 10.000 Dawes — Chadron, Big Bordeaux Creek 20,000 Cradron, Chadron Creek 10,000 Chadron, Ash Creek 5,000 Crawford, White River 30,000 Whitney, Indian Creek 10,000 Marsland, Niobrara River 10,000 Garden — Oshkosh, Blue Creek 10,000 Holt — O'Neill, Eagle Creek 20,000 O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 10,000 Dorsey, Steel Creek 10,000 Page, Middle Branch Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Eagle Creek 20,000 Atkinson, Sandy Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Brush Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Spring Creeks 10,000 RAINBOW TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Kimball — Bushnell, Lodge Pole Creek _ 15,000 Keith— Paxton, White Tail Creek 10,000 Morrill — Angora, Willow Creek 5,000 Bridgeport, Lawrence Creek 5,000 Platte — Columbus, Spring Lake 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Pickerel, Fish Lake, Brown County. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 53 Disposition. Counties. Rock — Newport, Willow Creek 10,000 Newport, Rock Creek 10,000 Newport, Ash Creek 10,000 Newport, Sand Creek 10,000 Newport, Oak Creek 10,000 Bassett, Coon Creek 5,000 Scotts Bluffs — Scotts Bluffs, Tub Springs 10,000 Morrill, Sheep Creek 20,000 Sheridan — Gordon, Snake Creek 10,000 Rushviiie, white Clay Creek 10,000 Grayson, Pine Creek 20,000 Hay Springs, Snake Creek 10,000 Sioux — Harrison, Sowbelly Creek 5,000 Harrison, Hat Creek 5,000 Harrison, War Bonnet Creek 10,000 Andrews, White River 30.000 RAINBOW TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Boyd — Bristow, Spring Creeks 10,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 50,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 Cherry — Wood Lake, Fairfield Creek 10,000 Kenned, North Loup River 10,000 Valentine, Schagel Creek 10,000 Valentine, Minnechaduza Creek 10,000 Valentine, Snake Creek 10,000 Dawes — Chadron, Bordeaux Creek 5.000 Chadron, Chadron Creek 10,000 Crawford, White River 10,000 Dakota — So. Sioux City, Spring Creek 2,000 Dundy — Parks, Rock Creek 5,009 Parks, Buffalo Creek 5,000 Garden — Oshkosh, Blue Creek 5,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">- </seg>
            <seg id="p052">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION ..;&gt; Disposition. Counties. Holt — O'Neill, Eagle Creek 40,000 O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 5.000 Dorsey, Steel Creek 15,000 Kimball— Kimball, Lodge Pole Creek 5,500 Rock— Bassett, Coon Creek 10,00&lt;&gt; Bassett, Short Pine Creek 10.000 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare. Seep Creek 5,000 Sheridan — Rushville, Larrabee Creek 10.000 Rushville, White Clay Creek 25.000 Colclesser, Pine Creek 30.000 Sioux — Harrison, Monroe Creek 5,000 Harrison, Sowbelly Creek 5,000 Harison, Hat Creek lo.ooo Glen, White River 20,000 Webster — Cowles, Thompsons Lake 2.000 BROOK TROIT DISTRIBUTION. 191S Antelope — Orchard, Verdigree Creek 15.000 Boyd— Bristow. Spring Creeks 10,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 20,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 Cherry — Cody, Hay Creek 5,000 Wood Lake, Fairfield Creek 10,000 Wood Lake, Evergreen Creek 5,000 Kennedy, North Loup River 10,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 10,000 Valentine, Seven Creeks 10,000 Valentine, Minnechaduza Creek 10,000 Valentine, Snake Creek 10,000 Valentine, Boardman Creek 10,000 Valentine, Sears Creek 5,000 Valentine, Cedar Creek 5,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p053"/>
            <seg id="p054">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 5 7 Disposition. Counties. Dakota — So. Sioux City, Spring Creek 2,000 Dawes — Chadron, Bordeaux Creek 15,000 Chadron, Indian Creek 5,000 r.undy — Parks, Indian Creek 5,000 Parks, Rock Creek 5,000 Parks, Buffalo Creek 5,000 Carden — Oshkosh, Blue Creek 5,000 Holt — O'Neill, Eagle Creek 50,000 O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 10,000 Dorsey, Steel Creek 15,000 Atkinson, Eagle Creek 5,000 Atkinson, Brush Creek 5,000 Knoz — Niobrara, Spring Creeks 20,000 Creigbton, Spring Creeks 10,000 Bazile MilU, Bazile Creek 10,000 Monowi, Spring Creek 5,000 Kimball — Bushell, Lodge Pole Creek 15,000 Morrill — Angora, Willow Creek 5,000 Pierce — Plalnview, Verdigree Creek 10,000 Rock — Bassett, Coon Creek 10,000 Scotts Bluffs — Morrill, Sheep Creek 10,000 Minatare, Seep Creek 5,000 Sheridan — Rushville, Larrabee Creek 20,000 Rushville, White Clay Creek 30,000 Sioux — Harrison, Monroe Creek 10,000 Harrison, Sowbelly Creek 5,000 Harrison, Hat Creek 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">&gt; Prairie Chicken Shooting, Near Valentine, Cherry County. Carter Lake Club House. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION II BROWN TROUT DISTRIBUTION. 1918 Disposition. Counties. Cherry — Wood Lake. Fairfield Creek 5,000 Valentine, Boardman Creek 5,000 Dawes — Chadron, Bordeaux Creek 2,000 Sioux — Harrison, Hat Creek 5,000 Harrison, Monroe Creek 5,000 BROOK TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1917. Antelope — Royal, Verdigree Creek 20,000 Boyd— Bristow, Spring Creek 5,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 30,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 Cherry — Wood Lake, Fairfield Creek 5.000 Wood Lake, Evergreen Creek 10,000 Crookston, Spring Creek 10,000 Merriman, Spring Creek 10,000 Kennedy, North Loup River 20,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 10.000 Valentine, Seven Creeks 10,000 Valentine, Cedar Creek 10,000 Valentine .Minnechaduza Creek 10,000 Valentine, Snake Creek 10,000 Valentnie, Boardmans Creek 10,000 Valentine, Canyon Creek 5,000 Valentine, Sears Creek 5,000 Dawes — Chadron, Chadron Creek 10,000 Chadron, Big Bordeaux Creek 20,000 Chadron, Little Bordeaux Creek 5,000 Chadron, Ash Creek 5,000 Crawford, White River 10,000 Marsland, Niobrara River 10,000 Dundy — Parks, Rock Creek 5,000 Garden — Oshkosh. Blue Creek 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">C Z r » , i f OS i: u X E . i i I 2 i i r •a 5 . «^j ir 7 ft* i 00 J3 I [*i i I n &gt;■ ' o 5 i { </seg>
            <seg id="p058">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 61 Disposition. Counties. Holt- O'Neill, Eagle Creek 20,000 O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 10,000 Dorsey, Steel Creek 30,000 Page, Middle Branch Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Sandy Creek 20,000 Atkinson, Eagle Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Brush Creek 10,000 Atkinson, Spring Creek 10,000 Knoz — Creighton, Spring Creek 2,000 Niobrara, Spring Creek 5,000 Morrill — Angora, Willow Creek 5,000 Pierce — Plainview, Verdigree Creek 5,000 Rock — Newport, Rock Creek 10,000 Newport, Willow Creek 10,000 Newport, Ash Creek .._ 10,000 Newport, Sand Creek 10,000 Newport, Oak Creek 10,000 Bassett, Coon Creek 5,000 Bassett, Short Pine Creek 5,000 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Seep Creek 15,000 Scotts Bluffs, Tub Springs 10,000 Sheridan — Grayson, Pine Creek 20,000 Rushville, White Clay Creek 10,000 Sioux — Harrison, Hat Creek 25,000 Harrison, Sowbelly Creek 5,000 Harrison, Warbonnet Creek 10,000 Harrison. Monroe Creek 20.000 CROPPIE DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Oakdale, Elkhorn Cutoff 500 Neligh, Mill Pond 9,000 Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 1,600 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 1,000 Boone — Petersburg, Beaver Creek 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p059"/>
            <seg id="p060">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION II Disposition. Counties. Brown — Johnstown, Lorenza Pond 500 Long Pine, Hagans Lake 1,300 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 500 Enderslake, Enders Lake 500 Hurt- Lyons, Logan Creek 10,500 Oakland, Mill Pond 3,000 Kuffalo-- Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,000 Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake 1,000 Ravenna, Mill Pond 1,000 Box Butte Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 1,000 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lake 500 Custer — Stapleton, Spring Lake 1,300 Ansley, Mill pond 500 Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond 200 Valentine, Sanfords Lake 500 Valentine, Lovejoy Lake 50t&gt; Newton, Wolfenden Lake 500 Merriman, Spring Lake 500 Merriman, Goodfellow Lake 400 Kennedy, Buffalo Lake 1,000 Wood Lake, Marsh Lake 500 Clay — Sutton, City Park Lake 400 Sutton, Blue River 500 Cuming — Wisner, Leisy Lakes 2,500 West Point, Mill Pond 1,000 Chase — Imperial, Frenchman River 1,500 Lamar Irrigation Lakes 1,000 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake _ 10,000 Valley. Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Dawes — - Crawford, Military Lake 400 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 13,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Ballards Marsh, Famous Cherry County Ducking Ground. Eight Speckle Trout, Sixteen to Twenty Inches Long. North Loup River, Near Kennedy, Cherry County. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 65 Disposition. Counties. Deuel — Big Springs, Spring Lake 500 Dodge — Fremont, Morse Lake 1,000 Fremont, Richey Lake 2,000 Furnas — Cambrdge, Mill Pond 1,000 Cambridge, Mill Pond 1,000 Greeley — Ericson, Simmonsons Pond 250 Gage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 1,000 Beatrice, Grants Pond 500 Harlan — Oxford, Askey Lake 800 Orleans, Mill Pond 900 Alma, Club Lake 800 Alma, Blums Pond 100 CROPPIE, DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Howard St. Paul, Chads Lake 1,000 St. Paul, Devries Pond 500 Hall — Grand Island, Chimmer Lake 500 Grand Island, Prairie Creek 500 Cairo, St. Micheals Slough 500 Holt — Inman, O'Donnells Lake 900 O'Neill, Elkhorn River 1,900 Atkinson, Mill Pond 800 Emmett, Emmett Lake 400 Stuart, Dora Lake 500 Hamilton — Aurora, Blue River 400 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 Madison — Battle Creek, Hughes Lake 1,000 Norfolks, Mill Pond 2,500 Merrick — Central City, Mc'Nurlin Pond 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">One of Nebraska's Pretty Hill Ponds, Near Valentine, Cherry County. Carter Lake, Douglas County. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 67 Disposition. Counties. Otoe — Nebraska City, Youngs pond 300 Nebraska City, Driving Park Lake 500 Syracuse, Eatons Pond 200 Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond 1,000 Pierce, Wagners Lake 500 Platte — Columbus, Shady Lake 1,000 Columbus, Ice House Lake 1,000 Richardson — Humboldt, Spring Lake 400 Rock- Newport, Fish Lake 300 Sarpy — Springfield, Nebies Pond 400 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 La Platte, Trestle Lake 3,000 Chalco, Sasg Pond 200 Fisheries, Sand Pit Lake 10,000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 3,000 Sheridan — Rushville, Bend Pond 500 Rushville, Smith Lake 500 Gordon, Shell Lake 500 Seward — Milford, Blue River 1.000 Seward, Blue River 500 Seward, Goehners Pond 300 Sioux — Harrison, Spring Lake 400 Stanton — Stanton, Lowes Lake 500 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Lake Minatare 500 Morrill, Stewarts Lake 1,000 Morrill, Wilders Lake 500 Morrill, Jordans Lake 400 Saline — Crete Mill Pond 1.000 Wayne — Wayne, Country Club Lake _. 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">r Fish Exhibit Building, State Fair Grounds. Long Pine Creek, Brown County. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 69 Disposition. Counties. York — Mc'Cool Junction, Murkars Pond 200 York, Blue River 1,000 York, Lincoln Creek 600 CROPPIE DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 3,000 Brown — Long Pine, Long Lake 1,800 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 800 Ainsworth, Moon Lake 800 Ainsworth, Long Lake 400 Ainsworth, Enders Lake 800 Burt — Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 1,000 Oakland, Mill Pond 500 Lyons, Mill Pond 1,000 Buffalo — Ravenna, Mill Pond 1,500 Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,500 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 800 Alliance, Krauses Lake 400 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lakes 700 Lodge Pole, Oberielders Lake 200 Custer — Mason City, Muddy Creek 400 Ansley, Mill Pond 400 Cherry — Wood Lake, Marsh Lake «00 Merriman, Spring Lake 400 Cody, Cody Lake 1,800 Irwin, Horseshoe Lake 400 Clay— Saronville, Peterson Pond 200 Cass — Cedar Creek, Sand Pit Lakes 500 Louisville, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Murdock, Spring Pond 200 Cum ing — West Point, Mill Pond 400 Wisner, Cutoff Lake 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">■ </seg>
            <seg id="p068">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Disposition. Counties. Chase — Municipal Lake 900 Enders, Frenchman River 200 Dawes — Chadron, Waterworks Lake 1,000 Crawford, Ice House Lake 1,500 Crawford, Military Lake 500 Crawford, Mc'Dowell Lake 600 Douglas — Valley, Sand Pit Lakes 6oO Omaha, Carter Lake 4,000 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 8,000 Deuel — Big Springs, Spring Lake 400 Dawson — Gothenburg, Lake Helen 1,000 Dodge — Fremont, Rickey Lakes 1,000 Grant — Hyannis, Haneys Lake 800 Greeley — Ericson, Ericson Lake 2,000 Ericson, Van Homes Pond 100 Pibel, Pibel Lake 1,400 Gage- — Beatrice, Mill Pond 500 Wymore, Indian Creek 500 Wymore, Turkey Creek 500 Harlan— Oxford, Askey Lake 400 Howard — St. Paul, Chads Lake 800 St Paul, Devries Lake 400 St. Libory, Spring Pond 500 Hall- Grand Island, Flippin Pond 100 Grand Island, Wood River 1,000 Cairo, St. Micheals Slough l,«00 CROPPIE DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Holt — Inman, O'Donnells Lake 1,500 Hooker — Mullen, Quinns Lake 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">A Baby Pickerel From Crystal Lake, Dakota County. Rainbow Trout, Seep Streams, Scottsbluffs County. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Disposition. Counties. Jefferson — Fairbury, Mill Pond 500 Lincoln — No. Platte, Lamplaughs Lake 500 No Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1.000 Lancaster — Lincoln, Blacks Pond 200 Lincoln, Sand Pit Lake 400 Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond 2,00o Battle Creek, Hughes Lake 800 Battle Creek, Wendts Lake COO Battle Creek, Martins Lake 500 Nance — Belgrade, Bayou Lake 200 Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond 500 Platte — Columbus, Shell Creek 500 Columbus, Loup Lakes 800 Richardson — Humboldt, Club Lake 500 Rock- Newport, Smith Lake 2,009 Pony Lake, Pony Lake 400 Sarpy — Springfield, Nebles Pond 200 La Platte, Trestle Lake 1,000 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Sheridan — Rushville, Selden Pond 300 Antioch, Briggs Pond 200 Seward — Milford, Mill Pond 2,000 Seward, Mill Pond 1,500 Utica, Lincoln Creek 500 Sioux — Harrison, Spring Lake 600 Sherman — Loup City, Conger Pond 100 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Lake Minatare 1,000 Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 1.000 Morrill, Seep Lake 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">.= 0 r -s. •— I a X ii i;ti ii bl 1 '-I - i » &lt; I* M K ■j • </seg>
            <seg id="p072">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 7 5 Disposition. Counties. Saline- Crete, Mill Pond S00 Wilbr, Mill Pond 500 Dewitt, Mill Pond 500 Thomas — Seneca, Railroad Pond 400 Valley — Ord, Bals Pond 400 York- Henderson, Blue River 500 York, Blue River 500 STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 2.000 Neligh, Mill Pond 1.800 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 1,000 Boone — Petersburg, Beaver Creek 500 Albion, Mill Pond 500 Brown — Ainsworth, Enders Lake 1,500 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 1,500 Ainsworth, Long Lake 1,000 Ainsworth, Willow Lake 1,000 Johnstown Lorenzen Pond 500 Long Pine, Hagans Lake 1.000 Long Pine, Chester Lake 500 Buffalo- Kearney, Lake Kearney 2.000 Miller, Harse Pond 200 Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake _ 1.000 Ravenna, Mill Pond 500 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 500 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lake 500 Custer — Stapleton, Brosius Pond 200 Ansley, Mill Pond 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">A Comely Angler With Catch of Pike, Morrill. Scottsbluffs County. A Catch of Croppie, Clearwater, Antelope County. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 77 Disposition. Counties. Cherry — Valentine, Duck Lake 1,000 Valentine, Cottonwood Lake 3,000 Valentine, Mule Lake 6,000 Valentine, Lovejoy Lake 2,000 Cody, Metz Lake 3,000 Merriman, North Lake 3,000 Chesterfield, Chesterfield Lake 2,000 Bailey, Goodfellow Lake 600 Bailey, Spring Lake 1,800 Cuming — Wlsner, Leisy Lakes 2.S00 Chase — Imperial, Municipal Lake 1,000 Dawes — Chadron, Waterworks Lake 1,000 Crawford, Military Lake 1,000 Crawford, Ice House Lake 1,000 Crawford, Swinbanks Lake 800 Whitney, Irrigation Lake 400 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 3,000 Valley, Sand Pit Lakes 1.000 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 5,000 Dodge — Fremont, Richey Lakes 2,000 Fremont, Morse Lake 1,000 Greeley — Ericson, Simpson Pond 200 Gage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 1.000 Harlan— Oxford, Askey Lake 1,000 Alma, Club Lake 800 Orleans, Mill Pond 500 Howard — St. Libory, Spring Pond 200 St. Paul, Chads Lake 500 Hall- Cairo, St. Micheals Slough 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">• • A ■v ~ 1 [ </seg>
            <seg id="p076">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 79 Disposition Counties. Holt- Stuart, Dora Lake 2,000 O'Neill, Elkhorn Ponds 3,500 Atkinson, Mill Pond 400 Emmett, Emmett Lake 400 Inman, O'Donnells Lake 500 STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBl TION, 1917 Knox — Verdigree, Mill Pond 500 Creighton. Mill Pond 1.400 Niobrara, Lutts Lake 1,000 Niobrara, Spring Sloughs 1,800 Logan — Gandy. Burkes Lake 400 Lincoln — Hershey, Spring Lake . 1,000 North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,009 Merrick — Central City, McNurlin Pond 100 Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond 1.500 Otoe — Syracuse, Eatons Pond 200 Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond 1,000 Pierce, Wagners Lake 500 Osmond, Thompsons Pond 200 Platte — Columbus, Shady Lake 2,000 Columbus, Ice House Lake 500 Monroe, Spring Lake 200 Richardson — Humboldt, Club Lake 500 Rock — Newport, Pony Lake 300 Newport, Fish Lake 300 Sarpy — Springfield, Nebles Pond 300 Chalco, Sass Pond 400 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Sheridan — Rushville, Bend Pond 1,000 Rushville, Smith Lake 1,000 Gordon, Shell Lake 800 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">- f J m P r\ ■ ' ' 'Jm^r V^ -., ■- a c &lt; n s I- I : - k </seg>
            <seg id="p078">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 47 Disposition. Counties. Howard — St. Paul, Chads Lake 400 Hall- Cairo, St. Micheals Slough 500 Hooker- Mullen, Quinns Lake 400 Holt — Inman, O'Donnells Lake 800 O'Neill, Golden Pond 300 Meek, Devalls Lake 1,000 Emmett, Emmett Lake 500 Atkinson, Fullerton Pond 300 Kimball — Kimball, Irrigation Lake 400 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lake 1,000 North Platte, Lamplaughs Lake 500 Lancaster — ■ Lincoln, Sand Pit Lake «00 Madison- Battle Creek, Wendts Lake 500 Battle Creek, Martins Lake 500 Nance — Belgrade, Bayou Lake 300 Platte — Columbus, Ice House Lake 500 Richardson — Club Lake 3,500 Rock- Pony Lake, Smiths Lake 300 Sarpy — La Platte, Trestle Lake 500 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Sherdan — Antioch, Briggs Pond 200 Scotts Bluffs Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 11,100 Minatare, Lake Minatare 10,400 Morrill, Seep Lake 1,000 Seward — Seward, Goehners Lake 400 Sherman — Loup City, Congers Pond 100 Thomas — Seneca, Railroad Pond 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Method of Stripping Pish Eggs, State Fisheries, Gretna. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 81 Disposition. Counties. Seward — Seward. Goehners Pond 300 Stanton — Stanton, Lowes Lake 500 Scotts Bluff: Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 1,400 Scotts Bluffs, Ingalls Pond 150 Scotts Bluffs, Bass Lake 500 Scotts Bluffs, Stewarts Lake 1,500 Scotts Bluffs, Jordans Lake 400 Saline — Dorchester, Turkey Creek 500 Webster — Cowles, Thompsons Pond J00 Wayne — Wayne, Club Lake 1,000 York— Thayer, Lincoln Creek 500 STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Antelope — ■ Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 2,000 Neigh, Mill Pond 1,000 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 400 Brown — Long Pine, Long Lake 1,000 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 800 Ainsworth, Enders Lake 800 Ainsworth, Moon Lake 2,000 Ainsworth, Long Lake 2,000 Burt— Decatur. Quinnebaugh Lake 1,000 Buffalo — Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,400 Kearney, Spring Pond 400 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatrick Lake 800 Alliance, Krauses Lake 400 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lakes 700 Lodge Pole, Oberfelders Lake 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Log Pine Creek, Brown County, Rainbow Trout. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION M Disposition. Counties. Cherry — Wood Lake, Kreceks Lake 250 Ely, Rush Lake 1,000 Simeon, Long Lake 1,000 Simeon, Ell Lake 1.000 Simeon, Big Alkali Lake 1.000 Oasis, Watts Lake 1,000 Cody, Quigleys Lake 500 Kennedy, Chesterfield Lake 500 Merriman, Harrington Lake 400 Valentine, Kuskie Pond 200 Valentine, Jeannette Pond 200 Clay— Saronville, Peterson Pond 200 Cass — Cedar Creek, Sand Pit Lake 500 Chase — - Imperial, Municipal Lake 1,400 Dawes — Chadron, Waterworks Lake 1,000 Crawford, McDowell Lake 1,000 Crawford, Military Lake 1,000 Crawford, Ice House Lake 1.000 Douglas — Valley, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Omaha, Carter Lake 23,000 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 2,000 Deuel — Big Springs, Spring Lake 400 Dawson — Gothenburg, Lake Helen 1,000 Dodge — Fremont, Richey Lakes 1,000 Frontier — Curtis, Curtis Lake 1,000 Garden — Oshkosh, Spring Lake 500 Grant — Hyannis, Haneys Lake *00 Greeley — Ericson, Ericson Lake 2,000 Ericson, Spring Lake «00 Harlan— Oxford, Club Lake 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Superintendent's Residence, Gretna Hatchery. Trout Ponds and Assistant's Cottage, State Fisheries, Gretna, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION M Disposition. Counties. Howard — St. Libory, Spring Pond 500 St. Paul, Chads Lake 800 Hall — Cairo, St. Micheals Slough 500 STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Holt — Inman, O'Donnells Lake 1,300 O'Neill, Golden Pond 300 Hooker — Mullen, Quinns Lake 400 Knox — Monowi, Passiaux Pond 400 Kimball— Kiraball, Irrigation Lake 800 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 North Platte, Lamplaugh Lake 600 Lancaster — Lincoln, Sand Pit Lake «00 Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond 1,000 Battle Creek, Hughes Lake 400 Battle Creek, Wendts Lake 1,000 Battle Creek, Martins Lake 500 Nance- — Belgrade, Bayou Lake 200 Phelps — Axtell, Termin Pond 200 Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond : 500 Platte — Columbus, Ice House Lake 1.000 Columbus, Shell Creek 1,000 Richardson — Humboldt, Club Lake 500 Rock — Newport, Smith Lake 2,000 Ponylake, Pony Lake 500 Sarpy — La Platte, Trestle Lake 800 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes 1.000 Springfield, Nebles Pond 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p085"/>
            <seg id="p086">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 87 Disposition. Counties. Sheridan — Antioch, Briggs Pond 200 Antioch, Brice Pond 500 Sherman — Loup City, Conger Pond 100 Scotts Bluffs — Mlnatare, Lake Minatare 500 Scotts Bluffs Lake Alice 1.000 Morrill, Seep Lake «m.:.: 1,000 Thomas — Seneca, Railroad Pond 300 YELLOW BULLHEAD DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Oakdale, Cutoff Lake 1,000 Butler — Ulysuss, Mill Pond '. 1,000 Burt— Lyons, Mill Pond 9,500 Oakland, Mill Pond 4,000 Buffalo — Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,500 Custer — Ansley, Mill Pond 200 Mason, Muddy Creek 200 Clay— Sutton, Blue River 1,500 Sutton, City Park Pond 400 Deweese, Little Blue River 1,000 Cuming — Wisner, Cutoff Lake 1,000 West Point, Mill Pond 1,500 Chase — Lamar, Irrigation Lake 1,000 Dawes — Whitney, Copper Pond 1.000 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 53,000 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 9,000 Dodge — Fremont, Morse Lake 500 Fremont, Sand Pit Lake 500 Garden — Oshkosh, Stephenson Pond 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">•• </seg>
            <seg id="p088">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 89 Disposition. Counties. CJreeley — Ericson, Siraonson Pond 200 Gage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 3,000 Harlan— Orleans, Mill Pond 500 Alma, Blums Pond 100 Hamilton — Aurora, Blue River 1,000 Marquette, Gierstoff Pond 200 Hall- Grand Island, Schimmer Lake 2,000 Holt- Stuart, Dora Lake 2,000 Lincoln- — Hershey, Sand Hill Lakes 1.000 North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 Logan — Gandy, Burkes Lake 400 Morrill — Angora, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 Madison — Madison, Club Lake 2,000 Otoe — Palmyra, Little Nemaha River 2,000 Syracuse, Little Nemaha River 2,000 Sarpy — Chalco, Sass Pond 400 La Platte, Trestle Lake 2,000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 8.000 Saunders — Ceresco, Schultz Lake 1,000 Ashland, Salt Creek 12,000 Wahoo, Spring Pond 500 Sheridan — Gordon, Rutter Lake 3,000 Seward — Milford, Mill Pond 3,000 Seward, Mill Pond 3.000 Sioux — Harrison, Thomas Pond 400 Harrison, Hotz Pond 40a Scotts Bluffs — Scotts Bluffs, Bass Lake 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Where the Croppie Thrive, Near Louisville, Cass County. Bungalow and Grounds, Benkleman Fisheries </seg>
            <seg id="p090">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION •1 Disposition. Counties. Saline — Dochester, Turkey Creek 1,000 Crete, Blue River 1,000 Wilber, Mill Pond 3,000 Wayne — Wyne, Club Lake 1,000 York— Gresham, Lincoln Creek 50« McCool Junction, Markworth Pond 200 York, Blue river 2,000 York, Lincoln, Creek 1,000 YELLOW BULLHEAD DISTRIBl TION, 1918 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Slougbs 2,000 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 1,000 Burt — Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 2,000 Lyons, Mill Pond 1,000 Buffalo — Ravenna, Mill Pond 2,000 Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,000 Custer — Ansley, Mill Pond 800 Cherry — Merriman, Harrington Lake 500 Cass— Louisville, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Murdock, Spring Pond 200 Cuming — Wisner, Cutoff Lake 1,000 West Point, Mill Pond 1.000 Dawes — Chadron, Waterworks Lake 500 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 4,000 Gage — Beatrice, Bear Creek 2,000 Howard — St. Libory, Spring Pond *00 St Paul, Devries Pond 400 Hall — Grand Island, Prairie Creek 500 Cairo, St Micheals Slough 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">1 ■ 1 t I* 1&gt; a I cs s ... 1 I I I f &gt; 1 • I » I ■ ■Ljd </seg>
            <seg id="p092">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 9 3 Disposition. Counties. Hooker — Mullen, Quinna Lake 400 Knox^ Creighton, Mill Pond 80« Verdigree. Mill Pond 400 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 North Platte, Tracy Pond 200 Lancaster — Lincoln, Blacks Pond 200 Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond 1.000 Battle Creek, Hughes Lake 1.000 Battle Creek, Wendts Lake 1.000 Phelps — Axtell, Termin Pond 200 Platte — Columbus, Shell Creek 1,000 Richardson — Humboldt. Club Lake 800 Sheridan — Bingham. Swamp Lake 1,080 Seward — Mllford, Mill Pond 4,000 Seward. Mill Pond 3,500 Utica, Lincoln Creek 1,000 Sioux — Harrison, Coffey Lake 200 Saline— Crete, Mill Pond 800 Wllber, Mill Pond 500 Valley— Ord, Bals Pond 400 York- Henderson, Blue River 2,000 CHANNEL CATFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Oakdale, Cutoff Lake 500 Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 500 Butler — Ulysuse, Mill Pond 500 Burt— Oakland. Mill Pond 500 Lyons, Mill Pond 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Black Bass Taken From Lake Ericson, Wheeler County. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION »| Disposition. Counties. Buffalo — Kearney, Lake Kearney 400 Ravenna, Mill Pond 500 Custer — Mason City, Muddy Creek 200 Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond 200 Clay — Sutton, Blue River 1,000 Sutton, City Park Pond 200 Deweese, Little Blue River 1,500 Cuming — Wisner, Cutoff Lake 500 West Point, Elkhorn River 1,000 Chase — Imperial, Municipal Lake 1,000 Dawes — Whitney, Irrigation Pond 200 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 600 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 2,000 Furnas — Cambridge, Mill Pond 400 Fillmore — Shickley, Matzke Pond 200 Gage- Beatrice, Mill Pond 2,000 Wymore, Mill Pond 500 Hitchcock — Culbertson, Frenchman river 4,000 Howard — St. Libory, Spring Pond 200 Hall — Grand Island, Schimmer Lake 900 Grand Island, Prairie Creek 200 Hamilton — Aurora, Blue River 400 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lake 200 Lancaster — Raymond, Beschorner Pond 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">i r. U z n S£ 3 = - I </seg>
            <seg id="p096">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION »1 Disposition Counties. Madison Battle Creek, Battle Creek 1,006 Madison, Club Lake 44)0 Norfolk, Mill Pond 500 Otoe — Syracuse, Eaton Pond 300 Syracuse, Little Nemaha 300 Palmyra, Little Nemaha 400 Richardson — Verdon, Franenfelter Pond 300 Verdon, Harden Pond 200 Humboldt, Club Lake 200 Falls City, Maust Lake 1,000 Ked Willow — McCook, Driftwood Creek 1,000 Sarpy — Springfield, Nebles Pond 100 Saunders — Ceresco, Schulz Lake S00 Seward — Milford, Blue River l,60u Seward, Mill Pond 1,400 CHANNEL CATFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Saline — Dorchester, Mill Pond 500 Crete, Blue River 400 Wilber, Blue River 2,000 Wayne — Wayne, Club Lake 500 York — McCool Junction, Markworth Pond 2*0 Gresham, Lincoln Creek 200 York, Blue River 1,5*!* CHANNEL CATFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Counties. Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Slough 900 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 400 Brown — Enderslake, Enders Lake 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">Rainbow Trout, Larravea Creek, Sheridan County Private Pish Pond James Terryberry, Louisville, Cass County. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION N Disposition. Counties. Burt — Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 1,000 Lyons. Mill Pond «00 Oakland, Mill Pond 500 Buffalo — Ravenna, Mill Pond 2,000 Kearney, Lake Kearney 500 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 400 Alliance, Krauses Lake 200 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lake 100 Custer — Mason City, Muddy Creek 400 Ansley, Mill Pond 300 Broken Bow, Myers Pond 100 Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond 400 Clay— Saronville, Peterson Pond 200 Cnming — Wisner, Cutoff Lake 800 Chase — Imperial, Municipal Lake 3,000 Enders, Frenchman River 1,000 Douglas — Valley, Sand Pit Lakes 400 Omaha, Carter Lake 500 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake l,40t&gt; P'urnas — Cambridge, Mill Pond 400 Gage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 1,200 Hitchcock — Culbertson, Frenchman River 2,000 Howard — St. Libory, Spring Pond 400 Hall — Grand Island, Wood River 1,000 Grand Island, Prairie Creek 200 Jefferson — Fairbury, Mill Pond 500 Knox — Creighton, Mill Pond 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">.■ I I I ■ I I I if u ) i I I B I </seg>
            <seg id="p100">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 10] Disposition. Counties. Kearney — Axtell, Terrain Pond 200 Lincoln — North Platte. Tracy Pond 100 North Platte, Lamplaugh Lake 100 Lancaster — Lincoln, Blacks Pond 300 Lincoln, Sand Pit Lake 200 Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond 900 Meadow Grove, Williams Lake 400 Battle Creek, Wendts Lake 200 SUNFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Ericson, Simpson Pond 200 Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 2,000 Brown — Long Pine, Hagans Lake 900 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 1,000 Ainsworth, Enders Lake 500 Boone — Petersburg, Beaver Creek 1,000 Buffalo — Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,500 Ravenna, Mill Pond 500 Cherry — Merriman, Goodfellow Lake 500 Kennedy, Buffalo Lake 1,000 Valentine, Lovejoy lake 1,000 Valentine, Mill Pond 800 Cuming — Winer, Leisy Lake 500 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 3,000 Valley. Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Dakota — Laketon, Crystal Lake 2,000 Dodge — Fremont, Richey Lakes 2,000 C reeley — Ericson, Simonson Pond 200 Cage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">Dewey Lake, Cherry County, Noted for Bass Fishing. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 103 Disposition. Counties. Garden — Oshkosh, Stapleton Pond son Harlan — Orleans, Mill Pond Alma, Club Lake Alma. Blums Pond Orleans, Club I.akp Oxford, Askey Lake 1,000 9... i 100 500 50,) Howard St. Paul, Chads Lake 1,000 Holt- Stuart, Dora Lake 1.000 Hall — Grand Island, Schimmer Lake Grand Island, Prairie Creek Cairo, St. Micheals Sough .... 500 500 500 Lincoln — Hershey, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 North Platte, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Logan — Gandy, Burkes Lake 400 Morrill — Angora, Sand Hill Lakes 1,000 Merrick — Central City, McNurlin Pond 100 Pierce — Pierce, Wagners Lake 400 Platte — Columbus, Shady Lake 1.200 Monroe, Spring Lake Richardson — 500 Humboldt, Club Lake 2 0 0 Rock — Newport, Fish Lake (0* Sarpy — Springfield, Nebes Pond 200 Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes Scotts Bluffs — 1.000 Scotts Bluffs, Lake Alice 1.000 York— Gresham, Lincoln Creek 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Brook Tr o ut, Rock Creek, Dundy Countv. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 105 SUNFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Disposition Counties. Antelope — Neligh, Mill Pond 1,000 Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 2,000 Burt — Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 2,000 Lyons, Mill Pond 500 Buffalo — Kearney, Lake Kearney 1,600 Cheyenne — Sidney, Irrigation Lake 300 Custer — Broken Bow, Myers Pond 200 Cass — Cedar Creek ,Sand Pit Lakes 2,000 Chase — Imperial, Municipal Lake 1,400 Enders, Frenchman River 900 Dawes — Chadron, Water Works Lake 1,000 Douglas — Valey, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Omaha, Carter Lake 3,000 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 3,000 Frontier — Curtis, Curtis Lake 1,000 Greeley — Ericson, Lake Ericson 1,000 Harlan — Oxford, Askey Lake 300 Howard — St. Paul, Devries Lake 400 St. Paul, Chads Lake *00 Hall- Cairo, St. Micheals Slough 500 Hooker — Muellen, Quinns Lake 400 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1,500 Lancaster — Lincoln, Sand Pit Lake 400 Platte — Columbus, Shell Creek 1,000 Columbus, Ice House Lake 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">I «' L | I | ■c I i a - Z ■- E u CO s I A I _ J </seg>
            <seg id="p106">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 107 Disposition. Counties. Richardson — Humboldt, Club Lake 1,000 Rock — Newport, Pony Lake 1,000 Sarpy — La Platte, Trestle Lake 400 Meadow Sand Pit Lakes 2,000 Scotts Bluffs Minatare. Lake Minatare 1 400 ROCK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Brown — Long Pine, Hagans Lake 500 Ainsworth, Clear Lake 500 Ainsworth, Enders Lake 500 Boone — Peterburg, Beaver Creek 500 Buffalo — Ravenna, Mill Pond 500 Box Butte — Alliance, Kilpatricks Lake 500 Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond 2,000 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 2,000 Valey, Sand Pit Lakes 1,000 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 3,000 Dundy — Benkelman, Adkinson Lake 1,000 ROCK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Furnas — Cambridge, Mill Pond 500 Gage — Beatrice, Mill Pond 500 Harlan — Oxford, Askey Lake 1,100 Howard — St. Paul, Chads Lake 500 Morrill— Bridgeport, Hedglin Lake 500 Bridgeport, Irrigation Lake 500 I </seg>
            <seg id="p107">Two Pound Croppie, Taken From Mill P o nd, Valentine, </seg>
            <seg id="p108">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 109 Disposition. Counties. Platte— Columbus, Shady Lake 500 Columbus, Ice House Lake 400 Scotts Bluffs — Minatare, Lake Minatare 500 ROCK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond 800 Dundy — Benkelman, Adkinson Lake 200 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 500 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 500 Richardson — Meadow Grove, Williams Lake 1,000 Humboldt, Club Lake 200 BULL FROG DISTRIBUTION, 1917 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 1,000 Neligh, Spring Slough 1,000 Brown — Hagans Lake 1,000 Gage — Beatrice, Grants Pond 500 Beatrice, Bear Creek 1,000 Harlan— Orleans, Club Lake 1,000 Knox — Creighton, Spring Creeks 1,000 Nlobrara, Spring Creeks 2,000 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 1.000 Sheridan — Gordon, Rutter Lake 4,000 Sioux — Agate, Big Springs 1,000 Saunders — Wahoo, Spring Pond 500 Scotts Bluffs — Scotts Bluffs, Seep Lakes 1,300 Sarpy — Fisheries, Platte River 2,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">(Topple </seg>
            <seg id="p110">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 111 BULL FROG DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Disposition. Counties. Antelope — Neligh, Spring Slough 1,000 Burt— Decatur, Quinnebaugh Lake 1,000 Boyd — Bristow, Ponca Creek 1,000 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 1,000 Dawes — Crawford, Swinbank Lake 2,000 Crawford, Military Lake 1,000 Crawford, McDowell Lake 1,000 Crawford, Ice House Lake 1,000 BULL FROG DISTRIBUTION, 1918 Dakota — Ferry, Crystal Lake 3,000 Greeley — Ericson, Lake Ericson 4,000 Holt — O'Neill, Spring Sloughs 2,000 Knox — Niobrara, Spring Creeks 1,000 Lincoln — North Platte, Sand Hill Lakes 4,000 North Platte, Lamplaughs Lake S00 Scotts Bluffs — Morrill, Seep Lakes 2,000 Scotts Bluffs, Seep Streams 2.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">Hatching House and Ponds, Benkelman Private Fish Hitcheries. Tekamah Gun Club. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">• r. [ -*j t i s — 3 = -. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">Yellow Catfish, Platte River, Near Yutan. Saunders County. </seg>
            <seg id="p114"/>
            <seg id="p115">Bass From Brown County Lakes. 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p116"/>
            <seg id="p117">p 1 z, i E ?( •I. X ■ 3 a 5 B E </seg>
            <seg id="p118"/>
            <seg id="p119">c o = I 5 M T. M i e I - «« </seg>
            <seg id="p120">■4 J I .« - -Ji &gt;. k I * T ■ 1 5 53 s I 1 1 i en I I I § • ■ 1 3 i 1 s a k </seg>
            <seg id="p121">A Days Kill of Ducks, Nimord Club. Red Deer, Cherry County. Brown County. </seg>
            <seg id="p122"/>
            <seg id="p123">A Fair Angler, Clearwater Club, Antelope County. </seg>
            <seg id="p124">* </seg>
            <seg id="p125"/>
            <seg id="p126">Crappies Taken Mill Pond. Pierce County. A String of Platte River Wall-eyed Pike. Caught Near Ashland Siunders County. </seg>
            <seg id="p127">Landing Six Pound Black Bass. Ericson Lake, Greeley County. Channel Catfish. Loup River, Co'.umbus, Platte County. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>