<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1925-02">1925-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 205 February, 1925 Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska J. O. RANKIN rassooj wass? DISTRIBUTION OF $47,000,000 IN FARM PROPERTY STUDIED Real estate is, of course, the largest item. It constitutes an especially large percentage of the investment in tenant farms. Machinery and the miscellaneous items, including funds on hand, growing crops, seed and feed on hand, and crops awaiting sale, included a larger percentage of the investment on part-owner farms than on those of either owners or tenants. Cooperating: University of Nebraska U. S. Department of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station Bureau of Agricultural Economics E. A. Burnett, H. C. Taylor, Director Chief </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introductory 3-10 Location and general purpose, 3. The economic unit, 3. The kind of investment, 4. Measuring size of farms, 4. Area peculiarities, 5. Proportional distribution of kinds of pro - perty, 6. Ownership and debt disregarded, 8. The trend, 8. Investment per Farm _ 10 Real Estate Investment 10-12 AH real estate, 10. Land alone, 11. Improvements, 11. Acreage per Farm and Percentage Tilled 13-1G Trend of size of farm, 13. Tenure and size of farm, 15. Percentage tilled, 15. "Tilled" versus "improved," 15. The trend in percentage of land improved, 16. Livestock _ 1 Importance of livestock, 17. Cattle, 18-19. All cattle, 18. Horses and mules, 19-21. All horses and mules, 19. Work stock, 19. Work stock by tenure and section of state, 20. "Other horses and mules," 20. Other livestock, 21. Hogs, 21. Miscellaneous animals, 21. Implements, Machinery, and Vehicles Importance, 1860-1920, 21, 22. Variations by areas and ten - ures in 1920, 23. Operating Funds, Supplies, and Growing Crops 24-2 Funds on hand, 24. Unsold crops, 24. Growing crops, 25. Feed, seed, etc., 25. Equipment per Hundred Acres. Cattle values per hundred acres, 26. Horses and mules, 27. Hogs, 27. Poultry, 28 . General farm machinery, 28. Ready money, 28. Feed, seed, etc., 29. Unsold crops, 29. Tillage Implements and Work Stock. Tilled versus total acreage, 29. Tillage machinery, 30. Value per Animal 31 Animal Units per Farm. •&gt; Tenure and area variations, 32 Animals per Farms: 1870-1920 34 Horses and mules, 34. Cattle, 34. Hogs, 34. Poultry, 34. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska J. O. RANKIN' INTRODUCTORY Location and general purpose. — The new facts pre- sented in this study were obtained by a series of surveys in areas whose locations are shown in Figure 1. In each area an extended study was made comparing owners with tenants in many phases of their economic and social well-being. This bulletin presents only those portions of the data which indi - cate the amount and kind of investment being operated by farmers of the different tenure groups. They deal with the investment per farm or per hundred acres operated by farm - ers, whether the property listed is owned or rented by the farmer. For the other information gathered in these surveys, the reader is referred to other bulletins already published or yet to be published. 2 The economic unit. — The kind of investment and the amount per farm and per hundred acres are determined in part by the types of farming adapted to the various localities and in part by the ability of the farmer to buy or rent the amount of property which he regards as best adapted to his For the new material presented in this bulletin, the author is indebted to the cooperation of Drs. L. C. Gray and C. J. Galpin of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture, who paid the salaries he field men who obtained most of the data. The data were gathered in the mainly as of March 1, 1920. The manuscript was submitted to the i mnii Bureau of Agricultural Economics. Some portions are based in part upon a survey made in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement, but that survey was largely devoted to securing social rather than economic data. Acknowledgments are also due to enumerators who were employed to do the field work, to tabulators, to a number of members of the faculty of the University of Nebraska, and others who have made valuable suggestions at various stages of the work, and to Miss Elizabeth Paschal for final checking and aid in revision. 2 Earlier bulletins published on the basis of this survey are: Reading matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. ISO. IMS. pp. 2S. figs. 8. Lincoln. Out of print, but a digest is available in mimeographed form. The Nebraska Farm Family : Some Land Tenure Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 185. 1923. pp. 31. figs. 8. Lincoln. Out of print, but available in all Agricultural Experiment Station libraries and summarized, together with Bui* letins 191 and 196, in the Journal of Rural Education. Vol. 3. No. 4. December, 1923. 155 ff. and Vol. 3. No. 5. January, 1924. 217 ff. The National Education Association; and in mimeographed form for free distribution from Lincoln. Nebraska Farm Homes : A Comparison of Some Living Conditions of Owners, Part-owners, and Tenants. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. pp. 4S. figs. 19. Lincoln. Nebraska Farm Tenancy : Some Community Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1923. pp. 50. figs. 24. Lincoln. Out of print. Landlords of Nebraska Farms. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 202. 1924. pp. 38. figs. 4. Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 own capacity and to the kind of farming he desires to do. He must operate an investment of about a certain size whether he owns it or not, if he is to get the best results. If it is too small he cannot operate efficiently because he can neither use labor-saving equipment nor keep himself profitably occupied. If, on the other hand, the land and capital goods are more than the farmer can look after properly, his losses are likely to be even greater than if he has too small an investment to handle. The kind of investment. — The most profitable farm in - vestment must be of the right kind as well as of the right amount. The proper economic unit may be of about the same size if measured by dollars whether grain or livestock is to be the principal source of income, but in kind it will be very different. In any case likely to occur in Nebraska, land con - stitutes the principal item of investment, but the distribution of the remainder among machinery, livestock, improvements, cash on hand, and other items depends upon the type of farm - ing to be carried on. The amount and kind of investment in improvements, for example, are different on a ranch for the raising of range cattle from those which are found on the dairy farm or on the farms of those who are raising purebred cattle, even tho all three come under the general head of livestock farms. Altho type of farming largely determines the kind of in - vestment, it is itself determined to a large extent by soil, cli - matic, and topographic conditions. It is also affected by the preference and training of the farmer himself and by the tenure under which he is operating. As we shall see more in detail later, the tenant's farm is likely to differ considerably from the farm which is being operated by its owner in mat - ters of size, percentage of acreage tilled, and amount and kind of equipment. Measuring size of farms. — Farms may be measured in terms of (1) farm acreage, (2) crop acreage, (3) productive Eiimal units, (4) total receipts, (5) total expenses, (6) man bor, — both the mental and muscular effort required to oper - e the farm, (7) amount invested, and perhaps by other eans. Acreage is the usual measure and does reasonably ell in comparing farms of the same type in the same locality, may mean little, however, in comparing farms of widely fferent soil or other characteristics, or used for raising fferent products. Mere acreage tells us little about size of rm until we know, for example, whether it is a truck farm </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 5 near a city, a diversified farm in eastern Nebraska, or a sand - hill or highplains region farm in the north central or western portion of Nebraska. The vast bulk of our statistical data on size of farms deals with acreage, but this study will undertake to supply information with regard to the amount and kind of investment per farm without denying the value of any of the other methods of study. Some might even contend that the amount of man labor the farm absorbs is the best means of measuring its size if it had not proved impossible up to the present to get sufficient statistical data on this point. Perhaps in the future this difficulty may be overcome. Most of the data presented are much more detailed than those of the United States Census, but whenever possible tab - ulations have been made in such a way as to afford some light on the extent to which the farms covered in the survey are average Nebraska farms or typical of the counties in which they are located. The survey data were obtained as of March 1, 1920, while those of the United States Census were ob - tained as of January 1, 1920. In most cases this does not introduce any serious incomparability. Area peculiarities. — Table 1 and Figure 1 show in de - tail where the farms studied were located, and so help in the interpretation of the later tables. The farms of the Geneva area in Fillmore County are not included in most of the later tables. The westernmost or Grant area, in Perkins County, I "able 1. — Number and tenure of farms studio! Tnwn in area _ Tenants V| : U^ County ! A11 Owner* P* 11 " 1 i 1 Mgn,. operator, owner, A)] sh share | Cajih I === == === ""* ! [ Total ...... 1,034 371 159 I 495 276 167 52 9 Siehawka Cam 121 46 10 62 32 26 4 3 Filley Gage 126 44 14 68 54 11 3 10 Milligan Fairfield Stromsburg. Walthill Fillmore 125 59 14 52 37 14 1 0 Clay 110 31 16 63 45 16 2 0 Polk 125 48 18 58 41 14 3 1 | Thuraton . . 127 26 30 69 26 11 32 2 Cambridge. . Grant Furnas 125 64 7 51 32 15 4 3 Perkins 123 27 47 49 8 I 39 2 0 Stapleton Logan I 52 26 3 ! 23 1 21 j 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 is represented by 123 farms, more than a third of which are operated by part-owners and nearly a third by share tenants. The characteristics of this area are more strongly impressed upon the figures for part-owners and share tenants than are those of any other area studied. Part-owners and cash ten - ants are of unusual importance in the Walthill area in Thurs - ton County, because of the rental of Indian lands on a cash basis, and in many cases without improvements. In case of unimproved Indian lands, it is necessary for the tenant to own at least some land upon which to erect the necessary farm buildings. This classes him as a part-owner. The principal peculiarities of other areas arise from the fact that the Stromsburg area in Polk County is inhabited largely by farm - ers of more or less immediate Swedish descent while those about Milligan in Fillmore County are largely Czecho-Slovak. The Logan County area is rather characteristic of the sand - hill region of the state. FIG. 1. — WHERE THE FACTS WERE OBTAINED From 100 to 125 farms were studied in each area except the County. A different schedule was used in the Geneva area which wa cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement. Lovan * Proportional distribution of kinds of property. — Table 2 is made as a percentage distribution of all the farm property of the areas studied rather than in terms of percentages of the property of an average farm to avoid the difficulty arising from the fact that not all the items are recorded from all farms. Seven dollars out of every 8 invested was represented by real estate, 1 out of every 17 by livestock, 1 out of every 30 by machinery, 1 out of every hundred by unsold crops, and another dollar out of every hundred by funds on hand for </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 7 I id* I — .„ .T "I I- t. rt^ — I 0050ii-H^JCOOOC005i-;U3iOi-j dt^»6&lt;Dt^wiHiHCi]ddHH O 00 T r : — S I &lt; os Oi oo oo oo «o tr h oo r* ro tc tp 1- I ot-«on^"«cwi-lnddd6 O 00 CO i-i ■-^ I - i ;!SSSS5S^ TO S§22g L t 5 I en i 1 ill i £ II [I t— QCU5C— »oj;Xi- i c- io ?: j; tj&lt; 1 1 rH I I s I Ofll^iOiOW^HNOo'do' II I li f-c-tctocoi»iont-t-!»iom IM &lt;N IN IM IM IM CJ Wrt — — &gt;, — 3 I i O 00 OT^» i-t = OS CO t— CO t— CN CC 00 CO CD CO tj» tJ&lt; -s* -*f -*jt -^ tJ&lt; *3«CO*-tCMCM 5 II 1 O00 TJICOO) c &lt; &amp; s 1 OdOOUSiOLOCMb-^iCOt-CO^C^ USiOiOiOUS^^iHiOOXXO - 2 d«5^rt^6tidoHi-i6d OX UJNN SJ c i £;2Si2i2"«M=ocgtc5ocn vT CO CO CO CO CO CO CO ?■] — • ~ — — ± I OC^OOiCCW3CC05^«OS*-;CX3tO o^ccwNSJw'dcoo'rHdd . O 00 ■^•CCth «&lt; 1 o^Oi a: ijs a oc as o^so -^t io io _i] 71 ! ! ! ! ! ! ! '. '. '. I I -"S :«s </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 operating the business, while still smaller proportions were represented by growing crops, feed, seed, and miscellaneous items. Among tenant farms the real estate is nine-tenths of the total investment in farm business, livestock only a twentieth, and machinery, funds on hand, growing crops, feed, seed, and such other items are all lower. The tenant is using less be - sides the land per hundred acres altho more per farm in many cases as we shall see more in detail on later pages. Ownership and debt disregarded. — These figures deal with the entire farm investment in each case regardless of who owns it or how much he is in debt. This is a study of the farm and not of the farmer, landlord, creditor, or any of the other persons who might be concerned. No deductions are made from the values involved because the farmer is in debt, or because he rents from someone else part or all of the land he farms. These percentages and proportions are in fairly close agreement with those based on census data cover - ing Nebraska, the West North Central States, and the United States as a whole, except that the livestock percentages are lower on the farms surveyed, particularly the percentage which hogs constitute of the total valuation. This is (1) in part because land values are higher per farm altho not per acre in case of tenant farms because of the greater acreage involved, so that equally high livestock values per farm would appear as lower percentages of the total; and (2) in part be - cause survey figures include some items not included in the census figures. These are funds on hand, unsold crops, grow - ing crops, feed, seed, and a few others, which account for 3.3 per cent of the investment shown by the survey. The live - stock investment percentage shown by the 1920 census is 8.1 in Nebraska as compared with 8.4 in the West North Central States and 10.3 for the United States as a whole. The trend. — A review of the census figures covering the agricultural history of Nebraska shows that the principal change in this percentage distribution has resulted from the rise in land values. In 1860, real estate accounted for about three-quarters of the Nebraska farm investment instead of well up toward nine-tenths (88.3 per cent) as in 1920. Dur - ing the same period livestock fell from 21.6 per cent to 8 per cent of the total Nebraska farm investment, and machinery from 3.9 to 3.6 per cent. This does not indicate so great a change in either acreage of land per farm or number and quality of livestock as might at first glance appear. It does </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 9 .-- « ,1 — -7_r: r . r; -»c — n «e ca 30 t- x c^ S 2li*~ - - i«3s § * • r--s feS- p —I f"i| ' t-aoaocs — sor-rcaie-siot- — ■ g"!.* - - -OOC-iflOSltNiOOlMO ■ P®« ~~ c°* *£ 2 t&gt; a cji — " — " . a e ? a ti y| ii « • : ■ : • ■■&gt; « mm I : .-2 :ii "B. ££ c ■ c _■ s.^ i ai -5 -5 a3 s£scSl i 8&lt;8 Ili "3 I ioe»Vf -" -T ! 8" 4^ i ?n *| I us us xa us to U3C0-I — eo J&lt;js « E « 252ES§S5S§S3S i^Ja «g- * to'ao eo — -^ of — r o— S s "2 s §S2=ii2IiS3SS ! tit g 5 S5- - - °t | .e __ a ° 3 qq (g e - V — ?^g 5-^— "g-S &lt;; MC4NNNMM N— •&lt;-&lt; 3^ io — loo — — naoicnicao tea * t-^-^eJ i-T -# — = _ &lt;— !ll f 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 indicate a considerable increase in the quantity and quality of the machinery per farm or per hundred acres of tilled land. INVESTMENT PER FARM We have just seen the percentage distribution of farm in - vestment among the different kinds of property involved in the farm as a going concern. From this time on we shall deal with absolute amounts of property per farm or per hundred acres. The amounts will often be stated in dollars as in Table 3 because land, livestock, and other property cannot readily be added and compared in any other way. In later tables dollar values will, as far as possible, be discarded and number of acres or livestock stated with such explanations as to comparative quantity and value as can be given. This is especially necessary if earlier periods are being compared with the present, when the value of the dollar is so different. The survey figures indicate greater average values per farm than census figures, in part for local reasons, and in part because tenant farms were the primary object of study and so constitute a greater portion of the farms recorded in the survey than of the total number in the state. Both the full tenant farms and the part-owner farms studied proved larger than the owner-operated farms. Any extended dis - cussion of Table 3 at this point would be very largely a repeti - tion of what has just been said in connection with Table 2 or an anticipation of what will be said in connection with the more detailed analysis of the investment in farm real estate. livestock, machinery, and the other things necessary for the operation of Nebraska farms. REAL ESTATE INVESTMENT All real estate. — In the total investment involved in the operation of farms in the areas studied, about 7 dollars out of every 8, as we have already seen, were in real estate — land, houses, barns, fences, and other improvements. We are now ready to note the chief tenure variations and analyze a little further the investment in real estate. On the tenant farms the investment in houses was only two-thirds as great as that on the farms of part-owners and much less than that on the farms of owners. Of the nearly $41,000 real estate investment per farm studied, nearly $37,000 is in land, about $1,800 in a house, and nearly $2,000 in other improvements including barns, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 11 fences, and everything else attached permanently to the land. The house almost equals in value all other improvements on the farm, but only the part-owner has a house which exceeds in value all other improvements combined. Table 4. — Value of land and improvements per farm 1 Includes no Logan County area data. Land alone. — Land alone was worth nearly $37,000 per farm in the areas studied, or over three-quarters of the entire investment per farm and about nine-tenths of the realty in - vestment per farm. The managers were operating land of greater value per farm than men of any other tenure group, with share tenants only a little behind them. Owners and tenants operated farms of about the same land valuation, with part-owners standing distinctly below both, and cash tenants at the very bottom of the list with land worth only a little over $30,000 per cash tenant. Land value per farm varied greatly from area to area. In the Stapleton area it was a little over $16,000 and in the Nehawka area more than $53,000. Improvements. — Values of houses have already been discussed elsewhere/ 1 The house and other improvements each amount to about one-twentieth, or together about one - tenth as much in value as the land alone. The improvements, other than houses, vary in value per farm from area to area from about $1,100 in the Cambridge area, largely in Furnas 3 Nebraska Farm Homes : A comparison of some living conditions of owners, part-owners, and tenants. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. Lincoln. I I Land Residences No. of operators Land Residences I I Other improvements Ans. Value Ans. Value Ans. Value — !" — All operators Owners 982 345 £65 I $36,976 909 ! $1,801 341 37,347 323 • 2,439 867 $1,981 280 2,601 Part-owners . All tenants Share-cash I 156 472 275 154 I 34,228 145 2,116 461 37,723 432 1,412 273 37,080 253 1,504 142 2,076 436 1,572 256 ! 1,571 Share 146 138 40,946 132 1,421 132 1,724 Cash 51 50 30,322 47 891 48 1,163 Managers 9 9 42,667 9 827 9 1,133 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 RESIDED! IMHtOVEIglffS LAMB FIG. 2. — REAL ESTATE INVESTMENT PER FARM The front pant' shows the amount and percentage which real estate constitute. - of the total investment in all farms studied in 9 areas. Figure 2 analyzes rea estate into land, residences, and other improvements and indicates the absolute and percentage value of each on the basis of the farms studied in the 8 principa areas. Improvements are much less important portions of the investment or tenants' farms than on those of owners or part-owners. County, and the Stapleton area in Logan County to $2,500 per farm in the Nehawka area in Cass County. Improvements constitute a smaller part of total invest - ment per farm in Nebraska than in the West North Central States or in the United States as a whole. Everywhere the proportion is lower in recent years than it was in 1900, if we accept dollar investment as the test. This does not mean that improvements are less good than formerly but that land has risen more rapidly in value than the improvements on it so that the better buildings and fences of today with their greatly increased real and dollar values have been slowly declining in the percentage of total farm real estate value which they con - stitute. In the areas surveyed this percentage was 9.3 as compared with 10.3 in the whole state, 17.1 in the West North Central States, and 17.2 in the entire United States. Perhaps another reason for the apparent gain in the increase of land valuation over that of building valuation is that farmers fail to realize the replacement value of their buildings, or that those who have done no building since the war do not know the present value of a house, barn, or corncrib. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 13 ACREAGE PER FARM AND PERCENTAGE TILLED Trend of size of farm. — The figures just presented on values of land per farm in the various area and tenure groups may be better understood in the light of Table 5, which pre - sents the total, tilled, and untilled acreages per farm in the various tenure groups. In the nine areas studied 1,022 farms, totaling 274,915 acres, average 268.9 acres in size as com - pared with 339.4 acres for all Nebraska farms and 234.3 for those of the West North Central States, and 148.2 for those of the United States as a whole. 4 Includes no Logan County area data. Including managers. The average acreage per Nebraska farm decreased from 226.3 in 1860 to 156.9 in 1880, since which time it has in - creased continuously and rapidly because of (1) the settle - ment of the newer lands of the state in the sand-hill and the high-plains regions where a larger acreage is required to support a family; (2) the increased use of two-row and other larger units of farm machinery; and (3) the decrease in labor per acre needed to farm land after the passage of the earlier period during which it must be broken, fenced, and otherwise improved, altho this decrease is offset, to some degree at least, by the increase of labor caused by more weeds, insect pests, and plant diseases, and the extra tillage required on old land as compared with virgin soil. During earlier Ne - braska farm history these influences were more than offset by the changes from the more extensive grazing to the more 4 Agriculture: Reports for states. The northern states, VI, Part I. 33 and 681. Fourteenth United States Census, 1920. ABLE 5.—. Acres tilled and not tilled per farm 1 ■ft, '&lt;■&lt;&gt; a per /i arm 1 Item Tenants A1P I Owners Part- Mire. owners A11 s £j|™~ Share Cash Total number 982 345 I 156 472 ! 275 146 51 9 Total acreage 261.4 234.2 I 365.8 246.8 208.2 341.5 ! 183.6 I 254.4 Tilled, ■!.■■- Tilled, ;«t crnt 167.6 149.5 212.2 166.0 156.4 193.0 140.3 | 181.1 64.2 63.8 58.0 67 J) 75.1 56.5 76.4 ! 712 Not tilled, &lt;irrr« 93.7 i 84.7 ! 153.6 I 80.8 51.8 148.5 433 73.3 Not tilled, prr rr 35.8 362 1° 42.0 32.7 24.9 43.5 23.6 28.8 O </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 intensive tillage methods. Rising prices of farm products and consequent rise of farm land prices also exerted a power - ful influence during the quarter of a century following 1896, but it was more than offset by the increased use of farm ma - chinery in larger units. These acreages per farm should not lead us to lose track of the relation between our tilled land and the total population which it must support, including country, town, and city people. Improved farm land per capita in Nebraska was 4.1 acres in 1860, 5.3 in 1870, 12.2 in 1880, 14.3 in 1890, 17.3 in 1900, 20.5 in 1910, and 17.8 in 1920. It increased continu - ously from the first settlement of the state until 1910, then decreased. Nebraska is, however, an agricultural surplus state, so these figures can be better understood when com - pared with those of the United States as a whole in which "the acreage of improved land per capita in 1850 was 4.9; in 1860, 5.2; in 1870, 4.9; in 1880, 5.7; in 1890, 5.7; in 1900, 5.5; in 1910, 5.2; and in 1920, 4.8." These figures reflect (1) a rapid expansion of the farm area from 1860 to 1880 or 1890, followed by (2) a rapid expansion of population by immigration from Europe and by natural increase which did not stop when the agricultural lands of our public domain had been largely exhausted. The increase in population con - tinued after the increase in expansion of farm area could no longer go on at any very rapid rate. We have now come back about to the per capita acreage of improved land from which we started in 1850 after passing thru a period during which we had about 20 per cent more tilled land per capita than we now have. The figures quoted for the entire United States are in many ways more significant than those for Nebraska alone. They are less disturbed by such chance matters as the loca - tion of Omaha on the west side of the Missouri River or Council Bluffs and Sioux City on the east side. In comparing the per capita acreage of improved Ian4 in Nebraska with that of the entire country it must be remembered that "small grain farming permits a man to tend a larger number of acres than does almost any other kind of agriculture except grazing." Since 1880 Nebraska has had a greater improved acreage per capita than any other state except North and South Dakota, and occasionally some other state which has equaled or excelled her in this particular for a census period at a time and then dropped back again. Small grain farming </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 15 seems to be the main cause of such great acreage of improved or tilled land per capita in all states in which it occurs. Tenure and size of farm. — Part-owners and share ten - ants operate larger farms than owners or share-cash tenants in most of the areas studied under various Nebraska condi - tions. Cash tenants occupy the smallest farms of all. In no area is the difference so great as the part-owner and the share tenant acreages of Table 5 seem to indicate. The figures of this table tell the truth but exaggerate it. The key to this statistical illusion of Table 5 is to be found in Table 1 which shows that a larger percentage of the part-owners and share tenants than of other tenure groups are in the westernmost area studied. All farms in this area are larger than those of any other area studied, but, in spite of the fact that the farms of part-owners and share tenants are not the largest to be found in the Grant area, their average acreages are more affected than are those of other tenures on account of the large per cent of them in that area. Percentage tilled. — Of all farm acreage studied, nearly two-thirds (64.2 per cent) is tilled. This percentage is highest among tenants, except for the few managers who re - ported 71.2 per cent, and lowest among part-owners, yet the number of tilled acres per farm is highest among part-owners and higher among tenants than among owners. Among ten - ants the share tenants till lower percentages of their acre - ages than farmers of any other group, altho part-owners stand almost as low. Both share tenants and part-owners are tilling less than three-fifths of their total farm acreage, but each of these groups has a higher number of tilled acres per farm than farmers of any other tenure group. These types of tenure are most general in that area in which wheat is most predominant, and the tilled acreage is, therefore, not very intensively tilled. Under most conditions share ten - ancy tends toward the cultivation of a greater number of acres less intensively than cash tenancy.'' Share-renting is most prominent in the small-grain regions of Nebraska in which the type of farming results in large acreages per farm regardless of type of contract. "Tilled" versus "improved." — Tilled land is, in most regions, the most important portion of the "improved land" of the census, which includes all land regularly tilled or mowed, summer fallowed, in gardens, orchards, vineyards, and nurseries, and land occupied by farm buildings. The Taylor, H. C. Agricultural Economics. 1919. 144. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 percentage of improved land is, of course, always higher than the percentage tilled on a given farm or in a given county or state. The areas studied, however, averaged much higher in percentage of farm land tilled than the entire state does in percentage of farm land improved. This, of course, can re - sult only from a large proportion of farm surveys lying in counties which are far above the state's average in both im - proved and tilled land percentages. Tenants operate farms containing lower percentages of untilled and unimproved land than owners, and far less than part-owners. This appears to be true thruout the United States except in Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. Another Nebraska study of about 1,700 schedules, not yet published, shows that these farms, averaging nearly 400 acres apiece, had nearly 300 acres of tillable land each, about one-fifth being in permanent pasture, 5 acres in farm - stead occupied by buildings and lots, and about 7 acres in waste land. These schedules or records were from farms very differently distributed over Nebraska from those which supplied most of the data for this bulletin and whose distribu - tion is indicated by Figure 1. The schedules referred to also show the largest number of crop acres per man in case of part-owners, with other tenure groups ranging downward in the following order: share tenants, share-cash tenants, and owner-operators. The full owners thus have the smallest tilled acreage per man at work on the farm. The order is the same in number of tilled acres per farm except that in this particular cash tenants stand below owners. The trend in percentage of land improved. — In 1860, Nebraska agriculture was very new and the land in farms included a great deal which could not be regarded as im - proved. Of all the land then in farms 18.8 per cent was im - proved, as compared with 48.5 per cent in the West North Central States and 40.1 per cent in the United States as a whole. In each of these areas the percentage of improved land in farms increased until 1890 ; since that timei it has gradually declined, presumably because of the extension of the farm acreage in the regions in which so much of the land taken in the farms cannot be classed as improved, tilled, or tillable. In the particular counties in which the area surveys were located and doubtless in most others of the United States, percentages of land farmed which is improved in - creased rather rapidly following settlement, but since 1910 there had been a slight decrease in the state of Nebraska and in the United States as a whole. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 17 LIVESTOCK Importance of livestock. — The importance of livestock in a system of permanent agriculture needs no discussion here. Table 3 shows that in the Nebraska farm business as organized today livestock stands next to the real estate itself in value per farm. In the areas studied its value averaged nearly $3,000 per farm, — about $3,550 on the farms of owners, $3,350 on those of part-owners, and $2,300 on those of tenants. The average of all the 124,417 farms in the state was $2,704. t; In the Milligan area in Fillmore County, owners CATTIX HOMES HOGS Smm ] ataLumom l FIG. 3. — LIVESTOCK INVESTMENT PER FARM ANALYZED Cattle are much more prominent on the farms operated by managers and owners than or those operated by tenants. They are more prominent on the farms of share tenants than upon those of either cash or share-cash tenants. Much the same may be said of hogs. and pai-t-owners had about the same investment in livestock, — lower than that of owners and part-owners in most of the other individual areas. In the Cambridge and Grant areas in southwestern Nebraska, and in the Stapleton area in Logan County, owners had a larger investment in livestock than part-owners, but in all other areas part-owners had more live - stock per farm than the owners, while in the Clay County area even the tenants had a greater livestock investment per farm than the owners. " Agriculture: Reports for states. The northern states, VI, Part I, 679. Table 1. Fourteenth U. S. Census, 1920. Figures from the Stapleton area are not included in the survey averages as here stated. • </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 CATTLE AH cattle. — Cattle have a greater value than livestock Eany one other kind on Nebraska farms, amounting to nearly ,300 per farm in the areas studied. On the owner-operated rms they represented a little more than half the livestock value; on the part-owner farms much less than half; and on the tenant farms only well over a third. The share tenants have a distinctly greater cattle investment per farm reporting than either the share-cash or the cash tenants, doubtless be - cause share tenants are so much more generally found in the portions of the state in which cattle play a more prominent part in farming. In 5 of the 8 principal areas surveyed, part - owners had cattle of greater value per farm than either owners or tenants, while in the other 3 the owners surpassed Table 0. — Y&lt;ilu&lt;' of cattle per farm reporting Milk cows Calves .Other cattle 'Includes no Login County area data. them. In the Filley area in Gage County and in the Stroms - burg area in Polk County, owners stood below even tenants in value. Milk cows are found on more farms in the areas studied than reported calves. "Other cattle" are found on fewer farms than are calves but represent a much greater value per farm where they are found. The values and num - ber of milk cows should indicate the presence of an ample supply of milk for most households but leave 1 home out of every 12 or 13 failing to report any milk cows from which can be secured any supply of this food which is so important, particularly for the growing members of the household. • Tenure All — ~ farms j r ; Ans. Value Ans. ui Value/ Ans. Value . \11 operators . 982 899 $410 716 $255 i 627 I I $1,098 Owners 345 ; 318 438 : i 257 390 ! 237 I 1,633 Part-owners 156 147 j 550 ' 119 268 106 i 1,044 AH tenants . . 472 426 | 344 334 150 : 281 636 Share-cash 275 258 351 ! ! 208 131 166 J 479 Share 146 126 315 89 202 85 ; 944 Cash 51 42 364 37 130 30 632 Managers . . . 9 8 275 : 6 90 i 3 4,133 i i j j_ </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 19 The "other cattle" reported doubtless include both stockers and feeders on hand and breeding stock not milked for house - hold use, or at least not kept primarily for that purpose. More light will be thrown upon these matters when we con - sider the numbers and values of cattle of different classes. Owner-operators have one and a half times as great an invest - ment in "other cattle" as part-owners and two and a half times as great as tenants. Managers handle lower invest - ments in calves but much higher investments in "other cattle," indicating feeding rather than breeding operations. Only 3 managers, however, are handling these investments so their number is insufficient to constitute a very reliable basis for generalization. Table 7. — Value of horses ami mmha per farm reporting 1 All horses and mules. — Horses and mules show vari - ations in value per farm apparently associated with (1) ten - ure, (2) type of farming, (3) size of farm or tilled acreage, and (4) section of the state. Each of these points should be kept in mind in considering the following paragraphs dealing with work stock and other horses and mules. Work stock. — Work-stock values were reported by about 19 farms out of every 20 — nearly twice as many farms as in case of "other horses and mules." Doubtless practically no farms are operated without some work stock, altho even the census reports domestic animals from only 121,871 of the [ All Work Tenure farms Work stock : st : tock Other horses s ~i — : 1 — Other horses and mules and mu Answers Value i Answers j Value Value : i i ~i ' 11 operators 982 929 $769 469 $370 Owners 345 327 684 160 403 Part-owners 156 148 875 87 458 All tenants 472 446 794 220 310 Share-cash j 275 261 825 136 234 Share 146 135 701 63 444 Cash 51 50 898 21 399 Managers 9 8 656 2 1,100 'Includes no Logan County area data. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 124,417 in Nebraska in 1920. 7 The average value of work stock per farm reporting it was, in 1920, about $769, — $684 on owners' farms, $875 on part-owners', and $794 on tenants' farms. This variation arises from difference in size of farm and type of farming as well as in tenure of farmers. The owner, who has the smallest total and tilled acreages per farm, has also the smallest investment in work stock if we omit from consideration the few managers. He is better able to get and keep all the work stock he wants. Type of farming rather than tenure doubtless brings down the work stock investments of the share tenants who have large total and tilled acreages and small work stock investments. They are more largely western Nebraska small-grain farmers than those of any other tenure group except part-owners. Work stock by tenure and section of state. — Owners had work stock valued at less per farm than either part - owners or tenants. Cash tenants as a group are a little above part-owners with the work stock worth about $900 per farm. The highest average value of work stock per farm was in the Walthill area, in Thurston County. It was $1,034 as com - pared with an average of $770 for all areas. In the sand-hill ar^a about Stapleton the average value of work stock per farm was only about $600. "Other horses and mules." — The variations in value of "other horses and mules" per farm among owners, part - owners, and tenants, and in different areas, sum up the varia - tions in extent to which the stock is young stock or stock kept for breeding purposes or something other than work. Only about half of the farms reported "other horses and mules" and those that did report them had them to an average value of $370 per farm. Here again the part-owner stood above both owner and tenant, but the owner stood a fairly close second instead of at the bottom of the list in this case. In case of work stock the value per farm tended to vary in pro - portion to the tilled acreage. "Other horses and mules," how - ever, show no such variation in proportion to either total size of farm or tilled acreage. It probably reflects rather the per - manence of location and financial ability which enable owners and part-owners to equip themselves for raising horses and mules to a distinctly greater extent than can tenants. The southwestern areas studied in Furnas and Perkins Counties have higher average values of "other horses and mules per farm" than the southeastern areas, doubtless be- 1 Same. 699. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 21 cause the abundant pasture favors horse raising and the keeping of breeding stock other than work stock. The survey returns agreed quite closely with those of the census for the same counties except that the census did not give the data by tenure. OTHER LIVESTOCK Hogs. — Investment in hogs was reported by nearly 9 out of every 10 farms studied, to an average value of about $633 per farm reported, — owners $837, part-owners $765, and tenants $441. For some reason share tenants stood dis - tinctly above the farmers of any other tenant group in their hog investment, which amounted to $660 per farm, while share-cash tenants were far below all other groups, with hogs worth only about $321 per farm. Poultry. — About 9 farms out of every 10 reported the amount invested in poultry, and all taken together show an average valuation of about $100 per farm reporting. Here again the investment was a little lower among tenants than among those of other tenure groups. Miscellaneous animals. — Miscellaneous animals re - ported by 83 farmers were probably mainly sheep and goats. The average value was about $300 per farm reporting — dis - tinctly more for part-owners who were more largely in the western area. IMPLEMENTS, VEHICLES, AND OTHER MACHINERY Importance, 1860-1920. — Implements and machinery, including vehicles, have risen from $74 per farm in 1860 to $341 in 1910 and $1,231 in 1920. While they were thus al - most seventeen times as great in value in 1920, land and im - provements had risen so much more rapidly in acres and value per farm than in 1920 they represented more than twenty times as great an investment as in 1860. Livestock had risen in value per head but fallen in number per farm, with the net result that in 1920 it was less than a twelfth of the investment instead of more than a fifth as it was in 1860 or more than a quarter as in 1880. In 1900 it was still almost a fifth. Implements and machinery have more nearly main - tained their former relative importance. They demanded 1 dollar out of every 27 in 1920 as compared with 1 out of every 25 in 1860. Of course it is well known that the machinery which must be bought for use on a Nebraska farm has greatly increased in quantity, complexity, quality, and price since </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 «im»m»iLr^ TRACTCRS nuus orm ucwmr FIG. 4. — ANALYSIS OF INVESTMENT IN IMPLEMENTS AND MACHINERY "All other machinery" includes the general farm machinery — all other than automobiles, tractors, and trucks. It may be regarded as the most important element of the investment in implements and machinery, varying mainly with tilled acreage per farm. The other elements vary with the purchasing power of the farmer (automobiles) and type of farming in various parts of the state (tractors anil trucks). The share tenants and part-owners who are more largely concentrated in the western areas studied than those of other tenures, have the largest in - vestments in tractors and trucks. Owners have much larger investments in auto- mobiles than part-owners or tenants. Table 8. — Value of implements, vehicles, and other machinery /&gt;&lt; r farm reporting 1 ii i i i Automobiles | Tractors Trucks Manure j Other Tenure All ; spreaders ! machinery l__ . . !„ . . l__ . ITT" I j Ana. Value Ana. Value Ans. Value ■ Ans. I Value Ans. [ Value 1 All operators 982 797 $583 139 $953 i 58 ! $838 j 418 j $70 955 $929 Owners 345 293 743 45 962 19 680 198 . 76 336 858 ■ Part-owners 156 139 565 45 924 j 24 958 75 j 74 153 1.350 All tenants 472 362 475 49 970 15 ] 843 145 59 j 461 j 831 Share-cash 275 216 489 25 792 j 6 592 94 51 269 808 Share 146 109 441 20 1,190 8 1,038; 35 68 141 877 Cash 51 37 488 4 817 1 800 16 72 51 874 Managers 934000 00 000 5 1,441 ■Includes no Loi [an Count: y area data. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 23 1860. Since we have no definite statistical measures of any of these changes except price we can only say that their prices have apparently risen less rapidly than the price of land since they have increased so greatly in quantity but not in relative importance per farm. Variations by areas and tenures in 1920. — The average value of machinery per farm in the areas studied was about $1,600, — $1,605 among owners, $2,464 among part-owners, and $1,325 among tenants. It varied with (1) size of farm, (2) section of the state, and (3) tenure of farmer. Part - owners had a larger investment in implements and ma - chinery, but it will be remembered that they had larger acre - ages to till. Share tenants had larger machinery investments per farm than either the cash or the share-cash tenants when all areas were averaged together, altho in some individual areas they stood below most cash and share-cash tenants. These statements apply with particular force to the machinery involved in raising and harvesting crops, altho based upon values of all implements, machinery, and vehicles, including automobiles, trucks, and manure spreaders. Tractors show about the same value per farm reporting them whether these farms are operated by owners, part-owners, or tenants. Automobiles show no such close relation to the tilled acre - age per farm as general farm machinery does. They are in part production goods and absolutely necessary, or at least extremely desirable, from the purely business viewpoint, in the operation of Nebraska farms under modern conditions, but in part also consumption goods for the satisfaction of the social, recreational, and other needs of the farmer and his family. Part-owners had automobiles worth about one and a fifth times as much as tenants and owners about one and a half times as much. Nearly 4 tenants out of every 5 had automobiles, as compared with more than 4 owners out of every 5 and nearly 9 part-owners out of every 10. Part - owners make this showing in part because a larger percent - age of them than of the farmers of any other tenure group studied lived in the westernmost or Grant area where the greater distances to be traveled make the automobile more of a necessity than in most areas farther east. The values of automobiles show some variation from area to area. Manure spreaders are reported from between a half and a third of all of the farms studied — nearly a third of the tenant farms, nearly half of the part-owner farms, and over half of the owner-operated farms. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 OPERATING FUNDS, SUPPLIES, AND GROWING CROPS We have now considered the principal investments neces - sary to farm operation, but our inventory is incomplete with - out such miscellaneous items as ready money for current operation, crops awaiting sale, growing crops, seed for the next crop, and feed on hand for livestock, listed in Table 3. These items are a minor but not an unimportant part of the total investment the farmer must make. Some of them — particularly feed and growing crops — are present in smaller quantities on March 1 than at most other times of the year. It is in part for this reason that all values were taken as of this date. Funds on hand. — It is always necessary to have some ready money available for household and farming expenses. Funds on hand may be either (1) savings awaiting invest - ment or other use, or (2) borrowings for current expenses. Funds on hand averaged $706 per farm, — $845 among owners, $702 among part-owners, and $609 among tenants, while managers had only $200 apiece on hand. The high figures for owners doubtless result in part from their greater economic resources and in part from the fact that their greater permanence of location enables them to engage in diversified farming of a type which requires a considerable revolving fund. Part-owners cannot equal the full owners because they have neither their economic resources nor the permanent hold on all the land they operate which the full owners enjoy. So far as either total or tilled acreage per farm is any indication, the part-owners' needs are even greater than those of the full owners. Only about two-thirds of the farmers of all tenures reported the amounts of their funds on hand. It is probable that many who failed to re - port on this point could not make so favorable a showing even at this time of greater apparent prosperity (March 1, 1920) than Nebraska farmers have since enjoyed. The manager's operation of a larger farm than that of any other tenure group with less funds on hand seems easily explained upon the supposition that whenever a small expense fund is ex - hausted the owner places additional operating capital at his command. Unsold crops. — Crops on hand awaiting sale are indi - cations of (1) cash income expected from crop sales rather than from livestock to which the crops are fed, (2) economic power to hold the crops thru the winter for the desired price, </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 25 and (3) market conditions and prospects, car supply, and other circumstances which brought these particular results in 1920. Unsold crops differ from feed, seed, etc., mainly in the purpose for which they are intended, altho another pos - sible difference arises from the fact that unsold crops are grown on the farm reporting, while the feed or seed may have been purchased from another source for use on the farm. The value of unsold crops per farm averaged $1,233 in all areas. The figure is about $1,000 among tenants and $1,400 among owners and part-owners. Growing crops. — The only "growing crop" to be report - ed in any considerable quantity in Nebraska on March 1 is winter wheat. The figures in this column are practically an indication of those who grew winter wheat. About one-half of all the farms studied reported the value of this crop and the census indicates that 51.9 per cent of all farmers in the state grew winter wheat in 1919. It gives no figures for the counties in which the areas studied were located. 8 About the same proportion of owner, part-owner, and tenant farms surveyed were included in this number. It included more than half of the share tenants, about one-fifth of the cash and four-sevenths of the share-cash tenants. The value averages $702 per farm reporting, — $745 among owners, $943 among part-owners, and $579 among tenants. Feed, Seed, etc. — The 566 farms which reported the value of feed, seed, etc., on hand averaged nearly $500 apiece for this item, — about $400, $500, and $600 for tenants, part - owners, and owners respectively. EQUIPMENT PER HUNDRED ACRES Thus far we have discussed values and quantities per farm. For many purposes, however, we are more interested in equipment of various kinds per hundred acres of farm land, or in case of machinery and work stock we may wish to know the investment per hundred acres of tilled land and not per hundred acrjes of all land in farms. The value of the land alone per hundred acres averaged $15,440, — $17,657 among owners, $10,485 among part-owners, and $16,234 among tenants. The personal property needed in operating it amounted to about a sixth as much, or $2,432 per hundred acres, — $2,960 among owners and nearly $2,200 among part-owners and tenants. This equipment value in- • Agriculture: Reports for states. The northern states. VI, Part L 68T. Fourteenth V. S. Census, 1920. Washington. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 eludes all livestock, machinery, supplies, and other personal property kept on hand to operate the farm. Three areas had averages rather close to that for the 8 principal areas. They were the Filley area in Gage County, the Fairfield-Clay Center area in Clay County, and the Walthill area in Thurs - ton County. The Nehawka area in Cass County had the highest figure, with equipment valued at more than $3,400 per hundred acres of farm land. It was followed by Stroms - burg with $3,247 and by Cambridge with $3,018 worth of equipment per hundred acres, while the Grant area in Table 9. — Equipment value per hundred acres of land Funds on hand 172 211 ! 128 i 166 j 188 151 j 113 Unsold crops 224 246 199 224 j 112 361 i 211 Growing crops 167 145 144 170 213 139 62 1 25 Feed, seed, etc 103 135 88 83 93 75 66 I 32 Growing crops 103 135 88 83 93 ■Includes no Logan County area data. Jin Table 9 the average value of each kind of property per hundred acres is computed bv dividing the value of all that kind of property luted by the number of hundred acres of land including the acreage m farms which did not report this kind of property as well as the acreage ol farms wnicn did report it. Perkins County stood at the bottom of the list with $1,222. These averages are, of course, almost entirely the result of variation in type of farming, but within each area there is a distinct difference associated with the tenure of the farmer In every area except that about Cambridge in Furnas County the owners and part-owners had a greater and frequently much greater equipment investment per hundred acres of land. •*i£ attle u Va i Ue ; per hundred acres.— All cattle averaged $512 per hundred acres of farm land but varied greatly from Acreage Total valued. Allcattli... Milk cows Tenants All Owners J Part- 1 Mgrs owner. Au Share- shllre Ca8h cash 254,012 j 80.717 56,071 115,094 i 57,624 48,108 9,362 i 2,130 $2,432 ■ $2,960 $2,199 $2,177 $2,133 $2,002 $3,337 ! $2,34(1 r&gt;!2 778 379 386 347 393 588 I 717 149 I 179 146 130 164 i 83 167 109 Calves Other cattla lorses and mulas Work stock Other horses and mul s . logs 'oultry &gt;ther animals 95 268 398 335 63 244 36 8 122 477 ■ M 281 72 411 39 10 62 171 493 431 63 193 92 164 m 327 ' 57 154 j 35 7 511 134 422 372 ! 50 142 45 1(1 118 I 192 j 262 : 203 159 22 I 2 219 202 772 • 681 ! HI 201 45 i 17 u 582 382 .iii.i 28 187 11 utomobiles 'rmctors 'rucks Imnure spreaders ither machinery :::: 183 52 20 10 314 239 SO 19 13 311 141 70 38 x 276 1« 45 13 8 334 ! 180 30 t; 7 338 M 258 n IS 707 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 27 area to area and from tenure to tenure. On owners' farms they have about twice as great a value per hundred acres as on the farms of part-owners or tenants. In the Grant area in Perkins County, the figure was only about $200 as compared with $1,241 in the Cambridge area in Furnas County, which was the westernmost area except that about Grant. Horses and mules. — The value of horses and mules per hundred acres of farm land is much lower in the sand-hill and southwestern Nebraska areas than in eastern areas of the state where a more intensive agriculture is practiced. They range from about $170 in the Grant area in Perkins County and $200 in the Stapleton area in Logan County to $600 in the Walthill area in Thurston 1 County. The tenants and owners had about the same valuation of horses and mules per hundred acres in farm land but the part-owners had nearly one and a half times as great an investment as the owners in horses and mules per hundred acres. Only the cash tenants exceed them in this particular, with an investment per hun - dred acres of farm land in horses and mules more than twice as great as that of owners. The fact that this figure is so much higher in case of cash tenants, who have such a high percentage of their farm acreage under cultivation, suggests that the investment in work stock per hundred acres of tilled land is more important than its investment per hundred acres of all land in the farms. Similarly, figures for machinery values per hundred acres of tilled land are probably more significant than those based upon total land in farms. Hogs. — Hogs vary about as much as cattle from area to area and tenure to tenure in value per hundred acres of land in farms. A glance at Table 9 shows that the average for all tenures for hogs is nearly $250 and that owners had more than twice as great investment in hogs per hundred acres of total farm land as part-owners, and more than two and a half times as great as tenants. Apparently only the owner is able to have the buildings and fences that are neces - sary if the mortgage-lifting hog is to be kept in the larger numbers. The figures for the Cambridge area owners rise to $1,116 because of the presence of purebred herds on the farms of some of the owners, but the part-owners and tenants even in this area are not out of line with those of the same tenure groups in other areas. The census figures in these counties on this point range from $55 in Logan County in which the Stapleton area is located to $382 in Thurston County in which the Walthill area is located. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 Poultry. — There appears to be but little variation caused by differences in tenure in the figures on value of poultry per hundred acres. On this basis owners stand 10 or 15 per cent above part-owners and tenants, but this is because poultry has about the same value per farm in case of all ten - ures and owners have fewer acres per farm over which to distribute the value. In other words, poultry has no particu - larly close relation to the size of farms under Nebraska con - ditions but is more largely a household matter. It furnishes employment and supplies to members of the household, and a marketable surplus is not produced in proportion to size of farm as in case of the major money products. Poultry might well be more fully developed as a factor in Nebraska farm operations but even the increase should probably be on the household basis rather than in proportion to total farm or tilled acreages. General farm machinery. — Machinery needs of most kinds are much more strictly in proportion to acreage of tilled land than to total land in farms. The discussion of such items will, therefore, be reserved until the next table is taken up. It deals with machinery investment per hundred acres of tilled land instead of per hundred acres of land in farms, part of which is untilled and, therefore, not closely related to ma - chinery investment. Ready money. — Current expenses make necessary a re - volving fund of ready money as already explained on an earlier page. It is much greater per farm, as we have already seen, in case of owners and of part-owners. Tenants have only two-thirds as great revolving funds as owners. When we consider the funds on hand per hundred acres, however, we find that the part-owner's combination of larger farms and smaller total funds on hand leaves him with less than two - thirds as much ready money per hundred acres as owners have, and we find part-owners falling far below even tenants. As might be expected, the funds per hundred acres decrease as we go from the more intensively cultivated portion of the state to the westernmost or Grant area in Perkins County where they are little more than half as great as the average for all areas studied. In the Stromsburg area in Polk County, peopled largely by farmers of immediate Swedish descent, the average funds on hand amounted to a little more than $440 per hundred acres of farm land, which was two and a half times the average for all areas. In this area and a number of others, tenants had as much or more than owners, but this was not the rule. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 29 Feed, seed, etc. — The value of supplies on hand for current use is closely but inversely related to the amount of money on hand for expenditures for current needs. It aver - ages a little over $100 per hundred acres in all areas studied. An unusually large amount of feed, seed, etc., on hand seems to have been a substitute for part of the cash that would other - wise have been needed. The areas that stand high in one item almost invariably stand low in the other. The Stroms - burg area for example, just mentioned as standing far above all others in ready funds on hand, stood below all others in vaiue of feed, seed, etc., per hundred acres, averaging only $31 or only about three-fifths as much as even the western - most area in Perkins County, where the extensive agriculture results in low figures per hundred acres. The Milligan area, which has more feed, seed, etc., on hand per hundred acres than any other and about four times as much as the average of all areas, stood lower than any other eastern Nebraska area in ready money on hand per hundred acres. Unsold crops. — The unsold crops on hand not intended for use as feed or seed really constitute a reflection of the marketing conditions preceding the survey and of the eco - nomic ability of farmers to hold their products. They are included here for the sake of completeness, but need no ex - tended discussion from the standpoint of the absolutely necessary investments in operating farm property. They are, however, an indication of reserve power on the part of the farmer. It is interesting from this standpoint to note that the two areas which stand far above all others in unsold crops on hand are those which are inhabited mainly by people of foreign birth or immediate foreign descent. No gradation from east to west is observable in the figures for the various areas, since a Missouri River county stands at the bottom of the list and the Cambridge area, mainly in Furnas County, stands next to the bottom, while at the top of the list, with the exception of two foreign-peopled areas just mentioned, stands the westernmost area studied and another- Missouri River county. TILLAGE IMPLEMENTS AND WORK STOCK Tilled versus total acreage. — Some of the farm equip - ment, as already suggested, is related to the tilled acreage more closely than to the total acreage of the farm. This is particularly true of the work stock and most of the machinery </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 owned by farmers except the automobiles and household ap - pliances. Tillage machinery. — Farm machinery other than auto - mobiles, tractors, trucks, and manure spreaders averages nearly $500 per hundred acres of tilled land ; or, if we include automobiles and all mechanical devices used in farming, the figure rises to over $900. The value of general farm ma - chinery per tilled acre or per hundred acres of tilled land is probably less subject to variations from area to area and from tenure to tenure than any other figure which we have dis - cussed. The greatest variations from the all-area average occur in the Walthill area in Thurston County, where the figure is unusually high and in the Grant area in Perkins and the Stapleton sand-hill area in Logan County. In both the two last-named areas the comparative infrequency of inter-crop - ping reduces the necessity for tillage equipment. Part - owners exceeded both owners and tenants in their invest - ments in tractors and trucks, partly because a larger share of the part-owners were in the westernmost area studied where the investments in tractors and trucks ran rather high. Table 10. — Vain, of implements per hundred acres of tilled l&lt; ■Includes no Lugan County ar -:i data. 'Includes managers except in casa of tractors, truck*, and manure spraadsrs w the 9 managers reported. Owners, part-owners, and tenants had practically equal investments in tillage or "other" machinery per hundred acres of tilled land. The owner figures are probably the re - sult of conflict of two sets of forces — one tending to raise and the other to lower his machinery investments as compared with those of part-owners and tenants. Among the owner's Tenants All= Owners ( Part- owners . I , i All Share- , „. r«h Sh » re ' | Cash i Mgrs All machinery 1909 $993 $954 SMI \ $751 I $770 : $1,655 $546 Automobiles 287 375 253 ■ ; 246 240 175 BSS 49 Tractors 81 78 125 67 i 4. 95 •19 | Tracks 32 31 69 19 K 35 23 Manure spreaders „ 20 15 13 10 11 Other machinery . . . . 4S4 489 492 496 452 &gt; 454 926 497 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 31 tendencies toward a greater investment in implements per hundred acres of tilled land are the facts that (1) he has greater economic resources upon which to draw, and (2) his smaller total acreage per farm with its smaller percentage under the plow gives him less opportunity to get the benefits of large scale operation. He must have at least one imple - ment of each of the principal kinds even if he has not land enough to keep it busy. A binder of the same value, for ex - ample, means a greater investment per hundred acres of tilled land for the average owner than for the average tenant or part-owner, each of whom has a larger tilled acreage than the owner. The owner's tendencies toward low investment in machinery largely center around the fact that he is older than either the part-owner or the tenant. He is, therefore, more conservative. He is less inclined to experiment with new things. He is not providing for as long a stay on the farm. He bought what he had on hand in 1920 before the high prices were in effect and had probably already taken more of the depreciation. VALUE PER ANIMAL We have thus far discussed livestock only as measured by value per farm or per hundred acres, but have had little or no indication of the value per head of the animals owned by owners, part-owners, and tenants. Table 11 shows that ten - ants and part-owners had, in most cases, animals of about equal value per head, but that part-owners exceeded both owners and tenants in value per hog and per milk cow. Own - ers stood above tenants and part-owners in value per head of calves and of mature cattle other than milk cows. Some pure - bred herds in the Cambridge area, largely in Furnas County, account for this difference in favor of the owner. In fact, in every other area the part-owner had "other cattle" worth either much more than those of owners or practically as much per head. Values per animal were generally lower in the sand-hill area in Logan County and in the westernmost area studied — the Grant area in Perkins County. Among the eastern Nebraska areas, that about Walthill in Thurston County had the lowest values per animal. The field work was done in the summer of 1920 but enumerators were instructed to get values as of March 1, 1920. All other data were obtained as of this date as far as possible. This should make the values </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 32 reasonably comparable with those of the census which were obtained as of January 1, 1920. The state average census value per hog was $20.97, and the all-survey average was $21.24. In most other cases the agreement was not so per - fect, but was reasonably close. ANIMAL UNITS PER FARM Table 12 states the number of animals and animal units per farm. As definitely explained in a table footnote, each larger animal is also an animal unit, but it takes a number of each of the smaller animals to make an animal unit roughly equivalent to a horse or cow. Animal units are given in all cases, and numbers of animals are also stated in case of the smaller animals. This method of computation reduces the 165.7 cattle, horses, hogs, poultry, and other animals of all ages found on the average farm studied to 34.4 animal units. The census figures reduce to 34.1 animal units. As just noted, the census figures were taken as of January 1, and the survey figures as of March 1, so the survey figures include a little young stock born in January and February. Tenure and area variations. — Part-owners had more animals per farm and tenants had fewer than owners. Tabi-e 11. — Value per animal 1 Cattle Horses and Mules Hoi Tenure . j , ""Bs Milk cows Calves ! Other i Work stock Other All 4,426 4,644 9,231 6,637 2,586 26,089 Value $108 $42 $80 $114 $68 $21 Owners 1,863 2,031 3,835 2,491 1,014 11,559 Value $96 $53 $112 $111 $65 $19 Part-owners ... | 801 962 1,938 1,133 599 3,531 Value i $184 $36 $57 $114 $66 $31 Tenants I 1,740 1,634 3,307 2,869 967 10,784 Value I $85 $31 $56 $118 $72 $21 Share-cash i 1,087 896 1,343 1,676 518 5,238 Value .... $85 $31 $60 $120 $68 $16 Share . 493 582 1,703 860 375 ! 3,967 Value $79 $31 $51 $108 $68 ! $19 Cash 160 156 261 333 74 | 1,579 Value ... $98 $31 $73 $133 $115 $42 Managers 22 17 : 151 44 6, ?.O6 Value $109 $21 $88 $122 $100 $33 i i i ■Includes no Logan County area data. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 33 Owners stood very close to the weighted average of part - owners and tenants. Part-owners needed more animals be - cause of their greater acreages per farm. Tenants needed them too, as they farmed greater acreages than owners, but they could not keep so many animals because (1) they were younger men, (2) they had less purchasing power, (3) they moved oftener, and (4) they were supplied with buildings that were inadequate for large livestock holdings. Tabu: 12. — Animal* and animal units per farm Tenants All Owners ****■' Kind at animal Mgrs. owners shar e_ g CMh cash I Farms 982 345 34.4 33.0 16S.7 IBM .2 All animal units; Animate Fowls Other-animal animal unite Other animals •"One cow, bull, steer, or horse two years old or older may be called an animal unit. Two head of colts or young cattle may be counted as one. Seven sheep, fourteen lambs, five hogs, ten pigs, one hundred hens may each be called an animal unit." Warren, G. F., "Farm Manage - ment," 210. Perhaps these figures are slightly too high as "swine" were reported without specifying how many pigs, if any, were included, — doubtless not many, as the data are as of March I, 1920. '"Other animals" includes sheep and goats as well as those of unspecified kinds. The areas in western Nebraska and the sandhills had greater numbers of animal units per farm than did the east - ern Nebraska areas in which a more diversified agriculture is practiced. In eastern Nebraska the figures were lowest in the areas peopled most largely by farmers of foreign birth or by their sons. In the westernmost Nebraska and sand-hill areas, tenants had as much livestock as owners, and part - owners stood below both owners and tenants. 105.8 105.4 132.8 100.1 ! 100.3 97.2 ! 109.1 Hi!:; 0.5 0.4 0.8 0.5 0.6 0.5 0.1 0.0 3.4 2.7 5.2 3.4 3.7 3.6 0.7 0.0 56 472 275 146 51 9 38.6 29.1 29.3 38.2 24.5 32.4 !04.6 154.5 147.6 165.7 163.3 112.9 18.5 13.7 12.6 20.8 10.3 19.5 21.6 15.6 12.3 23.3 11.9 18.4 5.1 3.8 4.0 3.6 3.1 2.5 2.8 1.9 3.7 2.5 1.6 0.9 5.6 3.8 3.3 5.0 3.2 1.6 10.6 8.0 4.9 14.7 5.6 16.1 11.3 8.8 8.1 10.0 8.1 6.7 11.6 9.6 8.5 12.3 8.1 6.1 6.7 5.1 7.0 5.9 4.8 5.1 33.4 25.8 22.8 29.3 33.5 24.1 1.3 1.0 1.0 1.0 1.1 I 1.1 Cattle animal units Cattle Milk-cow animal units Calf animal units. Calves Other-cattle animal units Horse and mule animal units . . Horses and mules Hog animal units- Hogs Poultry animal units I" 18.1 j 17.9 4.4 2.3 4.8 11.4 9.0 . 9.7 5.7 28.9 1.1 16.3 19.5 4.7 &gt;M .-..'J M M.I ■1.2 6.2 31.4 1.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 ANIMALS PER FARM: 1870-1920 Horses and mules. — The number of horses and mules per Nebraska farm has increased from 2.7 in 1870 to 3.5 in 1880, 5.9 in 1890, 7.1 in 1900, 8.6 in 1910, and 8.7 in 1920. This has resulted in part from changes in acreage, in part from changes in intensity of cultivation, and probably in greater part from the increase in the size of farm machinery. It has shown about the same general trend in each of the counties in which the areas studied were located, but in some there was little or no increase between 1910 and 1920, or even between 1900 and 1910. Cattle. — The number of cattle per Nebraska farm in - creased from 6.5 in 1870 to 11.9 in 1880, 18.8 in 1890, and 27.5 in 1900. Since that time it has decreased to 22.6 in 1910 and 16.1 in 1920. In the eastern Nebraska counties in which the areas studied were located, the high point was generally reached in 1890 or 1900, and then a decline until 1910 was followed by a rise between 1910 and 1920. The western Ne - braska counties studied have not shown any such decline. Hogs. — The number of hogs per Nebraska farm has fairly closely followed the trend just indicated for cattle. It rose from 4.5 in 1870 to 19.5 in 1880, and 33.6 in 1890. Then it declined to 33.1 in 1900 and 26.5 in 1910, and rose slightly to 27.6 in 1920. Poultry. — The number of fowls per farm can be stated only for 1890 and later census periods. It fell from 65.1 in 1890 to 61.3 in 1900 and then rose to 71.9 in 1910 and 113.5 in 1920. •Agriculture: Reports for states. The northern states. VI. Part I. 681-682. Fourteenth U. S. Census, 1920; Agriculture : Reports by states. VII. 30-38. Thirteenth U. S. Census. 1910: Agriculture: Farms, Livestock, and Animal Products. V. Part I. 458-460. Twelfth U. S. Census, 1900: Agriculture: 297-298. Eleventh U. S. Census, 1890: Agriculture: 162-163. Tenth U. S. Census, 1880. IS M </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska 35 SUMMARY BY LINES Investment in about 1,000 farm businesses was analyzed. Pages 3-6. In 1920, the investment was about 87 per cent in real estate, 6 per cent in livestock, 3 per cent in implements, and 1 per cent in each of (1) operating funds, (2) unsold crops, (3) growing crops, and (4) feed, seed, etc. Pages 6-8. Real estate investment is nine-tenths of the total on tenant farms. Page 8. It has increased greatly in percentage of the total since 1860. Page 8. It included $37,000 in land, $1,800 in a house, and $2,000 in other improvements or, the average farm studied — above the state average. Pages 10-12. Tenant farms have higher percentages of tilled and improved land than owner-operated farms. Pages 13-16. Owners have one and one-half times as great livestock investment per farm as tenants and slightly greater than part-owners. Page 17. Cattle have a greater value per farm ($1,291) than livestock of any one other kind. Page 18. Horses and mules average $938 per farm but vary in value per farm according to (1) tenure, (2) type of farming, (3) size of farm or tilled acreage, and (4) section of the state. Pages 19-21. Implements and machinery averaged about $1,600 per farm but varied about as horses and mules did. For 50 years they have formed about the same proportion of Nebraska farm property values. Pages 22 and 23. Funds on hand averaged $706 per farm reporting them; unsold crops, $1,233; growing crops, $702; and such other items as feed, seed, etc., nearly $500. Page 24. Equipment per hundred acres averaged $2,432, — $2,960 among owners, and nearly $2,200 among part-owners and tenants, — but varied greatly with type of farming. Pages 25-29. The implements and machinery, including automobiles, used per hundred acres of tilled land were valued at $909, — $993 among owners, §y54 among part-owners, and $841 among tenants. Pages 29-31. The value of animals per head was about the same on the farms of part-owners* and tenants. Part-owners had higher-priced milk cows than either tenants or owners, and owners had higher-priced calves and other cattle. Pages 31 and 32. Part-owners had more animals per farm and tenants had fewer than owners. Pages 32 and 33. The number of horses and mules per Nebraska farm has increased continuously since 1870. Page 34. The number of cattle increased until 1900, but since that time has decreased. Page 34. The number of hogs increased until 1890, then decreased. Page 34. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 205 Other Nebraska Tenancy Bulletins Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 180. 1922. pp. 28. figs. 8. Lincoln. Out of print, but available mimeographed as a digest. The Nebraska Farm Family. Some Land Tenure Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 185. 1923. pp. 31. figs. 8. Lincoln. Out of print, but available in mimeographed form, as a digest of bulletins 185, 191, and 196. Nebraska Farm Homes. A Comparison of Some Living Conditions of Owners, Part-owners, and Tenants. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. pp. 48. figs. 19. Lin - coln. Out of print. Nebraska Farm Tenancy. Some Community Phases. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1923. pp. 50. figs. 24. Lincoln. Out of print. Landlords of Nebraska Farms. Univ. of Nebr. Agr. Exp Sta. Bui. 202. 1924. pp. 38 figs. 4. Lincoln. Share-cash Farm Lease. 1922. pp. 5. Lincoln. Univ. of Nebr. Ext. Cir. 803 Stock Share Lease. Univ pp. 7. Lincoln. of Nebr. Ext. Cir. 804. 1923 For copies address College of Agriculture Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>