<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Division of Fire Prevention Eighteenth Annual Report 1926</title>
               <date value="1926">1926</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT 1926 John C. Trouton State Fire Marshal L. J. Butcher Assistant State Fire Marshal Sigrid Rasmussen Secretary E. E. Hayduk Deputy State Fire Marshal Thomas L. Wilson Deputy State Fire Marshal Ray E. Eaton Deputy State Fire Marshal A. F. "Jack" Rhanney Deputy State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">ADAM McMULLEN Governor of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">JOHN C. TROUTON Stats Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT of the STATE FIRE MARSHAL Office of State Fire Marshal State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska. To His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Dear Sir: The law governing this department provides that a report of the business transacted and the acts performed by the fire marshal and others constituting the department be made to you annually, and I have the honor to herewith submit such report covering the work we have accomplished during the past year. Words of Appreciation To you, Governor McMullen, I wish to extend thanks for the interest you have taken in the work in this office and for the help you have given me personally in promoting effective service. For the splendid aid and cooperation the Division of Fire Prevention has received from the fire chiefs and members of the fire departments in the various cities, towns and villages over the state, from the county attorneys, sheriffs, and all fire prevention organizations in the interest of the elimination of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fires, I wish to express my sincere appreciation. We have endeavored to operate the department in an econ - omical and business-like manner. The success of the work is due to the loyal efforts of everyone connected with the de - partment. Assistant Fire Marshal Lynn J. Butcher, Deputy Ed E. Hay - duk and Thomas L. Wilson, and our efficient secretary Miss Sigrid Rasmussen, Ray E. Eaton and A. F. Jack Rhanney, are </seg>
            <seg id="p008">State of Nebraska 8 manifesting a real interest in the department, and are ener - getic workers. With their added assistance we have accom - plished more in the first nine months in 1926 than was ac - complished in any one year during the eighteen years this office has been in operation in the criminal work. We sent eleven to the Penitentiary and twelve were bound over to the District Court. In conclusion, I desire to thank you, Governor, for the con - fidence you reposed in me, and I hope my efforts have met your expectations. I shall endeavor to merit your continued confidence by faithful and honest performance of my duties. Very respectfully, JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">A PROCLAMATION BY THE GOVERNOR Fire continues to take its toll of life and property in in - creasing numbers and amounts. With 14,000 lives lost and 16,000 injured for the year 1925, and a property loss approx - imating $570,225,921 in the country at large, no excuse is necessary for calling the attention of the public to a disaster of such magnitude. In Nebraska 1636 fires are of record for 1925 with an estimated property loss of 2,230,745: and 49 deaths and 56 persons injured by fires. Negligence is cred - ited with a considerable percentage of these fires and the loss of lives and property that follow in their wake. This proc - lamation is to designate October 3 to October 9, inclusive, as FIRE PREVENTION WEEK and I earnestly urge upon the people greater care and vigil- ance in preventive effort. Civic bodies, churches and schools are under special obligations to join in the observance of fire prevention week, and to continue throughout the year their best effort to reduce the number of preventable fires. The generous cooperation of the news papers of the state can be counted on to get added effectiveness to this fire prevention drive. Done at Lincoln, the capitol, this 25th day of September, A. D. ? 1926. ADAM McMULLEN, GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 State of Nebraska FINANCIAL REPORT The law provides a tax to be collected from the fire insur- ance companies doing business in the State of Nebraska "for the purpose of maintaining the department of State Fire Mar- shal and paying all the expenses incident thereto." This tax is defined in the statutes as follows : "A sum equal to three-eighths of one percent of the gross premiums and assessments received for fire insurance, less reinsurance and return premiums." The law states further that "the state shall not be liable in any manner for the salary of the fire marshal, deputies. inspectors, clerks and other employees or for the maintenance of the office of fire marshal or any expenses incident thereto, and the same shall be payable only from the special fund pro- vided for in this section," this "special fund" being the money collected from the fire insurance companies on business done in the state as explained above. The taxes received by the state fire marshal in 1926 are as follows : Aetna Fire Insurance Company $ 925.1)3 Agricultural Insurance Company 145.79 Allemania Fire Insurance Company 7.89 Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia 112.11 American Alliance Insurance Company 41.85 American Central Fire Insurance Company 141.12 American Druggists Fire Insurance Company 6.81 American Eagle Fire Insurance Company 120.45 American Fire Insurance Company 400.18 Atlas Insurance Company, Limited, of London 42.21 Automobile Insurance Company... 241.60 Bankers &amp; Shippers Fire Insurance Company :. 18.00 Boston Insurance Company 91.16 British American Assurance Company 25.00 Buffalo Fire Insurance Company 39.27 British General Limited Insurance Company 6.76 Caledonian Insurance Company 84.26 California Fire Insurance Company 12.41 Camden Fire Insurance Company 2.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Division of Fire Frevention 11 Carolina Insurance Company .47 Central Manufacturers Mutual Insurance Company 4.69 Chicago Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 29.50 Citizens Insurance Company of Missouri 33.05 City of New York Insurance Company 38.11 Columbia Insurance Company 9.50 Columbian National Fire Insurance Company 3.32 Commerce Insurance Company 17.40 Commercial Union Assurance Company 184.16 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company .'. 17.97 Commonwealth Insurance Company 149.69 Concordia Fire Insurance Company 63.32 Connecticut Fire Insurance Company 440.79 Continental Insurance Company 604.03 County Fire Insurance Company 11.58 Detroit Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 6.90 Dubuque Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 96.54 Eagle Fire Insurance Company 2.94 Eagle Star &amp; British Dominions Insurance Company 61.02 East &amp; West Insurance Company... 15.92 Employers Insurance Company 52.68 Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 88.16 Eureka Security &amp; Marine Fire Insurance Company 2.97 Farmers Fire Insurance Company 24.27 Federal Insurance Company 23.21 Federal Union Insurance Company 43.29 Fidelity Phenix Fire Insurance Company 486.28 Fire Association of Philadelphia 148.56 Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 138.08 Fir3men's Insurance Company 234.09 First American Insurance Company 5.55 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company 9.79 Franklin Fire Insurance Company 145.80 Franklin National Insurance Company .19 General Exchange Insurance Company 10.22 General Fire Assurance Company 10.62 Girard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 76.76 Glens Falls Insurance Company 306.06 Globe &amp; Rutgers Fire Insurance Company 1,007.94 Grain Dealers National Fire Insurance Company 147.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 State of Nebraska Granite State Fire Insurance Company 53.14 Great American Insurance Company 527.33 Great Lakes Insurance Company 17.49 Guaranty Fire Insurance Company 5.04 Hanover Fire Insurance Company 160.90 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 122.52 Hartford Fire Insurance Company 1,208.86 Henry Clay Fire Insurance Company 22.53 Home Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 13.87 Home Insurance Company 1,139.27 Hudson Insurance Company 58.23 Imperial Assurance Company 19.62 Importers &amp; Exporters Insurance Company 34.56 Indemnity Mutual Marine Association 6.85 Insurance Company of North America 626.75 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 43.68 Inter Ocean Reinsurance Company 13.41 Law Union &amp; Rock Insurance Company 27.72 Liverpool, London &amp; Globe Insurance Company 356.76 Londoij Assurance Corporation 28.19 London &amp; Lancashire Insurance Company 118.29 London &amp; Scottish Assurance Company 4.09 Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Company 2.81 Maryland Motor Car Insurance Company 7.75 Massachusetts Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company ... 15.27 Mechanics Insurance Company of Philadelphia 77.99 Mechanics &amp; Traders Insurance Company 24.13 Mercantile Insurance Company of America 385.61 Merchants Fire Assurance Corporation 61.05 Merchants Fire Insurance Company 12.43 Merchants Insurance Company 32.62 Mercury Insurance Company 16.90 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Illinois. ... 28.92 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 2.16 Millers National Fire Insurance Company 57.03 Mill Owners Mutual Fire Insurance Company 114.40 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Company 230.26 Minnesota Implement Fire Insurance Company 57.35 National American Fire Insurance Company 544.50 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 103.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Division of Fire Prevention 13 National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford 2,357.25 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company 143.46 National Reserve Insurance Company 37.92 National Retailers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 4.97 National Security Fire Insurance Company 338.31 National Union Fire Insurance Company 158.11 Netherlands Insurance Company 42.86 Newark Fire Insurance Company 32.94 New Brunswick Fire Insurance Company 29.50 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Company 153.81 New Jersey Fire Insurance Company 12.08 Niagara Fire Insurance Company 120.78 North British &amp; Mercantile Insurance Company Ltd. 253.85 North Carolina Home Insurance Company 11.27 North River Insurance Company 126.20 Northern Assurance Company Ltd 53.28 Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company.... 79.64 Northwestern Mutual Fire Insurance Company 11.77 Northwestern National Fire Insurance Company.... 169.91 Norwick Union Fire Insurance Society 55.55 Ohio Farmers Insurance Company 4.88 Ohio Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 30.68 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 34.15 Old Colony Fire Insurance Company 19.79 Orient Insurance Company 106.76 Pacific Fire Insurance Company 20.88 Palatine Insurance Company 39.64 Patriotic Insurance Company of America 12.25 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 198.55 Pennsylvania Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 2.49 Philadelphia Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 40.01 Phoenix Assurance Company, Ltd. of London 57.43 Phoenix Insurance Company 749.00 Potamac Fire Insurance Company 16.48 Providence Washington Fire Insurance Company.... 39.29 Prudential Insurance Company 20.28 Queen Insurance Company 345.99 Reinsurance Company "Salamandra" 171.18 Reliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia 35.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 State of Nebraska Republic Fire Insurance Company 20.15 Retailers Fire Insurance Company 6.64 Retail Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company.... 114.75 Rhode Island Insurance Company 117.99 Rocky Mountain Fire Iusurance Company 1.35 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 45.62 Royal Insurance Company 381.62 Safeguard Insurance Company 18.96 Scottish Union &amp; National 115.67 Security Insurance Company 276.32 Sentinel Insurance Company 8.75 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. 655.52 Standard Fire Insurance Company 4.82 Star Insurance Company of America 93.24 State Assurance Company of Liverpool 14.34 Sterling Fire Insurance Company 7.61 St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 701.45 Sun Insurance Office of London 112.96 Superior Fire Insurance Company.... 4.24 Svea Fire Insurance Company 50.67 Tokio Marine &amp; Fire Insurance Company 12.57 Travellers Insurance Company 40.67 Twin City Fire Insurance Company 162.07 Union Assurance Society 13.59 Union Automobile Insurance Company 42.42 Union Fire Insurance Company of Providence 30.52 Union Insurance Society 66.26 United Firemens Insurance CompanyofPhiladelphia 7.01 United States Fire Insurance Company 283.76 U. S. Merchants &amp; Shippers Insurance Company 1.57 Utah Home Fire Insurance Company 4.62 Victory Insurance Company 29.52 Westchester Fire Insurance Company 119.53 Western Assurance Company 15.02 Western Grain Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co 79.11 World Auxiliary Insurance Corporation 13.45 World Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 2.98 TOTAL TAX COLLECTED $23,418.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Division of Fire Prevention 15 Balance on hand January 1st, 1926, in treasury 17,205.22 TOTAL FUND JANUARY 1st, 1926 $40,623.62 The above figures show the amount of tax money on hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1926. These expendi- tures were as follows : Salaries $11,832.34 $11,832.34 Office Expense Express 0 Printing 313.53 Stamps 220.00 Supplies and Equipment 212.83 Telegraph 3.36 Telephone 113.65 Miscellaneous 43.85 Total $ 907.22 $ 907.22 Inspectors' Expenses (Traveling) Railroad Transportation 1,045.08 Hotel Expenses 3,015.35 Auto Expenses, Taxi and Carfare 2,387.01 Miscellaneous 108.83 Total $ 6,556.27 $ 6,556.27 Expenses Incurred in Investiga - tions of Fires Temporary Services 194.09 Photographs 27.75 Total $ 221.84 $ 221.84 Fire Report Fees Paid to Fire Chiefs for Reporting 1925 Fires $ 496.50 $ 496.50 Total Expenditures for 1926 $20,014.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 State of Nebraska Total on hand January 1, 1926 17,205.22 Fire Marshal Tax 23,418.40 Total $40,623.62 Total Expenditures January 1 to December 31, 1926 20,014.17 Balance on hand January 1, 1927 $20,609.45 SUMMARY OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made ...13,970 Orders issued by inspectors 14,130 Buildings condemned by this department 49 Buildings demolished by order of this department 35 Buildings ordered repaired by this department 480 Buildings repaired by order of this department 81 School buildings equipped with fire escapes, repaired, and otherwise altered, to meet the requirements of the state laws, by order of this department 76 Theatres extensively repaired and altered, to meet the requirements of the state laws, by order of this de - partment 31 Fire escapes installed on apartment houses by order of this department 1( Fire escapes installed on buildings other than school houses and apartment houses by order of this de - partment 3 ■&gt; Fires investigated 115 Persons arrested for arson 27 Persons convicted of arson 11 Persons still to be tried 12 Persons acquitted 3; dismissed 1 4 OUR DOUBLE INSPECTION We wish to call attention to the 13,970 inspections made the past year and 14,130 orders issued. This may look small com- pared to some of the previous reports for past years in this department. But, our new plan of inspecting is as follows: The inspector goes into a town and makes a careful inspec- tion of all public buildings, taking plenty of time to talk to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Division of Fire Prevention 17 the occupant and explain to him the fire hazard and danger of life, owing to conditions found existing there. He tries to instill the fire prevention spirit into him, getting his promise to attend to the orders at once. These orders are given him on a duplicate order sheet and he is advised that the inspector will return before leaving town to see if the orders have been complied with. Where there are bad fire hazzards, the in- spector oftentimes calls three or four times before the con- dition is eradicated. He then marks his order slip O. K. when the order has been complied with. In this way every town has a double inspection and takes double the time to make it, but the towns inspected are in lots safer condition than formerly, because a lot of the business men would forget to comply with orders and the inspector on his return would find con- ditions the same as the last time he was there. In this way we are not able to get as many town inspected within the year, but the benefits to those visited are 90% greater than the old way of going in and making the town as quickly as possible and then rushing on to the next town. We would very much appreciate having your opinion of what you think :&gt;f this new method. CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED DURING 1926 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Unknown causes 97 25 217 339 Sparks from Chimney on roof 313 28 131 471 Defective chimney 24 1 44 69 Gasoline and kerosene stoves 18 0 57 75 Overheated stoves and furnaces 13 2 46 61 Communicated 20 1 43 64 Defective electric wires and motors. 20 2 54 76 Spontaneous combustion 32 0 27 59 Children and matches 45 1 15 61 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 53 1 23 77 Inflammables too near toves and pipes 25 0 15 40 Bonfires and burning grass 14 0 18 32 Incendiarv 19 2 15 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 State of Nebraska Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Gasoline explosion 9 1 28 38 Hot ashes against wood and in wooden containers 16 1 18 35 Oil burners in stoves and furnaces.— 10 5 6 Sparks from engine 0 0 11 Lightning 9 0 15 24 Gas heaters 1 0 0 1 Chicken brooders and incubators 0 0 11 11 Heating oils and greases on stove 2 0 6 8 Defective stoves and furnaces 0 0 11 Miscellaneous 4 0 5 9 Starting fires with gasoline and kerosene 2 0 6 8 Motor backfired 5 0 15 20 Mice and matches 12 0 10 22 Careless use of matches 17 0 7 24 Electric flatirons and curling irons, etc 14 2 10 26 Motor overheated 2 0 0 2 Motion picture films 0 0 8 8 Fireworks 10 2 3 Hot air registers 2 0 0 2 Curtains, etc. set on fire by lamp 0 0 11 Smoking in bed 6 0 0 6 Stove pipes passing thru floors 0 0 6 6 Rubbish against buildings 15 3 0 18 Sparks from stoves and furnaces 8 0 8 16 Overheated smoke stack and fur- nace pipe 17 0 0 17 Filling lamps, lanterns and oil stoves 0 0 0 0 Lamp upsetting 3 0 2 5 Explosion of stills 4 0 0 4 Tar kettle exploded 0 0 2 2 Fire place 12 0 3 Coffee urn exploding 10 0 1 Acetylene tank exploding 0 0 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Division of Fire Prevention 19 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Thawing out pipes with torch and blow pot _... 4 0 0 4 Washing clothes with gasoline 10 0 1 Paper over flue hole 2 0 0 2 Friction sparks 0 112 Blow torch 0 17 8 Total number of fires 852 74 882 1808 Less communicated fires 20 1 43 64 832 73 839 1744 FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Adams $ 299,665.00 $ 234,550.00 $ 18,759.00 Contents 88,075.00 61,200.00 31,466.00 Antelope 23,700.00 10,350.00 8,445.00 Contents 10,780.00 6,750.00 5,260.00 Blaine 2,500.00 2,400.00 none Contents 1,000.00 1,000.00 25.00 Boone 19,100.00 5,200.00 5,215.00 Contents 5,990.00 1,500.00 690.00 Box Butte.... 65,500.00 44,500.00 18,645.00 Contents 34,600.00 16,300.00 9,100.00 Boyd 12,750.00 3,000.00 400.00 Contents 13,600.00 1,500.00 285.00 Buffalo 127,150.00 62,100.00 16,897.85 Contents 77,050.00 24,700.00 9,682.00 Burt 2,515.00 2,000.00 2,400.00 Contents 6,545.00 4,795.00 5,545.00 Butler 64,400.00 51,500.00 17,638.00 Contents 60,240.00 23,450.00 18,200.00 Cass 44,925.00 24,600.00 3,624.10 Contents 6,820.00 4,300.00 1,175.00 Cedar 17,000.00 8,500.00 9,400.00 Contents 27,300.00 20,250.00 8,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Cherry 50,250.00 42,400.00 10,845.00 Contents 25,750.00 24,100.00 4,930.00 Cheyenne .... 7,400.00 2,900.00 893.00 Contents 1,200.00 550.00 450.00 Clay 59,525.00 30,400.00 15,391.80 Contents 39,710.00 27,550.00 10,019.84 Colfax 13,400.00 10,150.00 515.00 Contents 9,300.00 8,000.00 855.00 dimming .... 14,350.00 9,000.00 775.00 Contents 7,400.00 3,200.00 1,000.00 Custer 25,600.00 19,600.00 13,812.00 Contents 31,250.00 21,400.00 19,700.00 Dakota 19,980.00 10,500.00 11,110.00 Contents 7,390.00 5,600.00 4,900.00 Dawes 46,900.00 18,500.00 16,663.00 Contents 39,200.00 29,000.00 14,250.00 Dawson 76,510.00 51,920.00 8,605.00 Contents 62,080.00 41,550.00 8,300.00 Deuel 40,200.00 28,400.00 5,750.00 Contents 8,350.00 2,750.00 2,850.00 Dixon 22,800.00 13,100.00 3,566.00 Contents 28,800.00 18,200.00 9,043.00 Dodge 206,065.00 54,777.69 40,847.69 Contents 151,350.00 67,484.90 65,504.79 Douglas 16,840,423.46 12,262,580.00 656,332.16 Contents 12,099,872.43 9,730,997.00 721,421.30 Filmore 13,550.00 9,600.00 2,527.60 Contents 24,400.00 420.00 2,320.00 Franklin 39,575.00 20,700.00 33,600.00 Contents 24,300.00 14,200.00 21.425.00 Frontier 6,500.00 7,000.00 1,076.29 Contents 2,500.00 2,500.00 898.50 Furnas 22,525.00 14,425.00 3,432.00 Contents 11,275.00 5,900.00 1,382.00 Gage 103,200.00 75,600.00 11,560.00 Contents 49,200.00 18,000.00 4,575.00 Garden 7,200.00 5,500.00 1,450.00 Contents 2,300.00 500.00 625.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Division of Fire Prevention 21 County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Garfield 300.00 300.00 Contents 100.00 100.00 Grant 3,000.00 2,000.00 150.00 Contents 1,500.00 1,000.00 Greeley 11,000.00 5,700.00 7,150.00 Contents 7,100.00 3,300.00 1,900.00 Hall 255,465.00 160,950.00 22,968.89 Contents 182,039.00 100,050.00 44,726.99 Hamilton 23,750.00 19,800.00 10,635.00 Contents 12,200.00 8,250.00 2,267.17 Harlan 40,742.00 28,000.00 11,768.00 Contents 33,162.00 25,343.00 12,055.58 Hayes 20,000.00 12,500.00 50.00 Contents 1,500.00 12,500.00 Hitchcock .... 19,100.00 11,100.00 13,500.00 Contents 32,700.00 14,000.00 14,570.00 Holt 37,200.00 18,100.00 6,718.50 Contents 21,600.00 13,800.00 5,986.00 Hooker 5,700.00 3,400.00 1,037.00 Contents 950.00 250.00 Howard 13,900.00 8,100.00 6,820.00 Contents 8,500.00 3,550.00 7,150.00 Jefferson 194,900.00 148,000.00 4,970.35 Contents 110,950.00 86,200.00 7,925.50 Johnson 51,800.00 27,300.00 30,782.50 Contents 15,750.00 11,500.00 2,540.00 Kearney 23,608.35 21,000.00 18,158.00 Contents 14,800.00 18,500.00 11,300.00 Keith 10,650.00 5,150.00 6,900.00 Contents 12,875.00 11,100.00 7,321.00 Kimball 7,500.00 6,450.00 3,428.37 Contents 16,950.00 15,085.00 15,019.20 Knox 99,175.00 66,275.00 5,364.00 Contents 39,770.00 30,800.00 28,660.00 Lancaster 3,433,375.00 1,244,100.00 37,360.56 Contents 1,528,634.00 700,300.00 37,600.55 Lincoln 111,750.00 63,500.00 9,610.00 Contents 85,040.00 64,300.00 13,915.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Madison 208,320.00 116,000.00 127,800.00 7,820.00 Contents 191,175.00 8,115.00 Merrick 3,100.00 2,000.00 400.00 Contents 1,510.00 5.00 Morrill 12,400.00 1,500.00 5,750.00 14,050.00 875.00 Contents 10,870.00 815.00 Nance 52,550.00 1,972.77 Contents 16,550.00 9,000.00 18,125.00 16,450.00 25,300.00 2,455.10 Neraaha 34,750.00 6,712.75 Contents 26,570.00 2,061.00 Nuckolls 57,000.00 11,275.00 Contents 18,550.00 8,650.00 41,000.00 49,000.00 27,500.00 44,600.00 1,950.00 Otoe 62,000.00 19,869.50 Contents 69,985.00 13,043.50 Pawnee 50,350.00 20,833.00 Contents 72,450.00 34,883.00 Perkins 9,500.00 1,800.00 975.50 Contents 10,000.00 8,500.00 23,300.00 15,700.00 3,000.00 Phelps 45,800.00 30,023.00 16,160.00 Contents 22,400.00 Pierce 228,800.00 116,650.00 1,935.00 Contents 26,500.00 8,750.00 1,773.00 Platte 248,575.00 176,700.00 53,300.00 12,042.00 Contents 111,350.00 12,069.95 Polk 21,860.00 8,450.00 4,100.00 24,400.00 3,300.00 143,700.00 114,950.00 3,810.00 Contents 6,015.00 2,365.00 Red Willow.. 34,500.00 12,250.00 Contents 11,775.00 4,225.00 Richardson .. 196,625.00 40,845.00 Contents 159,250.00 39,210.00 Rock 4,000.00 3,500.00 300.00 Contents Saline 57,550.00 25,175.00 13,950.00 13,000.00 10,901.00 5,015.00 Contents 27,300.00 Sarpy 18,900.00 11,270.00 3,538.00 2,935.60 Contents 7,100.00 6,700.00 13,385.00 3,400.00 Scottsbluff .... 21,705.00 865.00 Contents 6,740.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Division of Fire Prevention 23 County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Saunders 127,000.00 67,832.00 26,677.19 Contents 71,565.00 43,279.00 26,121.25 Seward 71,640.00 41,800.00 5,397.00 Contents 35,365.00 17,400.00 6,595.00 Sheridan 12,000.00 8,500.00 3,242.35 Contents 12,000.00 8,000.00 9,260.00 Sherman 11,500.00 9,000.00 255.00 Contents 11,000.00 7,100.00 450.00 Stanton 28,100.00 16,000.00 1,117.00 Contents 12,010.00 7,800.00 1,000.00 Thayer 11,875.00 3,500.00 2,435.00 Contents 8,460.00 2,500.00 2,858.00 Thurston 19,035.00 4,500.00 1,495.00 Contents 6,500.00 2,200.00 1,455.00 Valley 42,700.00 26,200.00 29,808.00 Contents 29,200.00 18,950.00 14,837.42 Washington .. 62,600.00 37,900.00 13,905.00 Contents 72,800.00 59,100.00 10,175.00 Wayne 36,700.00 26,950.00 1,465.00 Contents 11,050.00 7,000.00 750.00 Webster 30,300.00 19,550.00 13,500.00 Contents 17,380.00 6,820.00 13,780.00 York 124,200.00 65,725.00 3,560.75 Contents 112,381.00 68,625.00 2,598.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 State of Nebraska FIRE LOSS FOR 1926, VALUE, INSURANCE, AND LOSS AS REPORTED BY COUNTIES A WONDERFUL RECORD In looking over the fire report of the city of Lincoln, I am agreeably surprised to see such a marvelous record for a town of about 70,000 population. Under the leadership of Fire Chief Louis Hansen, the citizens of the town may well be proud of their fire department. I believe Lincoln can boast the lowest fire loss for 1926 of any town of its size in the United States. There are always a great many conditions in a town the size of Lincoln which if not eradicated will cause fires. The surprisingly low fire loss is a silent tribute to the work done by the boys of the fire department of Lincoln in the eradication of these dangers. Inspections of a town by its fire department is always a great benefit to the town ; both in the eradication of the conditions which result in fires, and the education given its citizens in fire prevention by such inspec - tion. I sincerely hope that 1927 will be even more successful for this energetic fire department of Lincoln, and that many more towns will profit by Lincoln's experience and be equally suc - cessful in keeping their fire losses down in 1927. Value of Bldgs. Total $ 4,305,980.35 Value of Cont. $ 2,657,096.00 Value of Bldgs. Omaha $16,891,773.46 Value of Cont. $12,250,872.43 Value of B\dgs. Lincoln $ 3,386,150.00 Value of Cont. $ 1,502,065.00 Value of Bldgs. Grand Total $24,603,933.81 Value of Cont. $15,416,223.43 Ins. on Bldgs. $2,628,229.69 Ins. on Cont. $1,624,001.90 Ins. on Bldgs. $12,310,780.00 Ins. on Cont. $9,866,969.15 Ins. on Bldgs. $1,211,400.00 Ins. on Cont. $ 690,000.00 Ins. on Bldgs. $16,160,394.69 Ins. on Cont. $13,184,371.05 Dam. on Bldgs. $ 750,017.96 Dam. on Cont. $ 676,866.34 Dam. on Bldgs. $ 656,219.16 Dam. on Cont. $ 722,746.30 Dam. on Bldgs. $ 32,063.00 Dam.on Cont. $ 36,624.00 Dam. on Bldgs. $1,440,370.72 Dam.on Cont. $1,438,307.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Division of Fire Frevention 25 TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men 13 Women 11 Children 5 Total 29 TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men 38 Women 14 Children 8 60 Injuries from fireworks 11 71 DEATHS FROM FIRE Ainsworth — Margaret Jackson died from burns received when she attempted to light a fire in the school room, using kerosene oil which exploded. Alliance — Frank Moran was burned to death in his home when it was completely destroyed by fire of unknown origin. Bayard — Matt. Thomas, aged 66, died from heart failure, caused by over exertion in fighting a grass fire to protect his home. .- — Bloomfield — Johnnie Hart and Frank Jones were burned to death in a bunk car in which they were sleeping. The fire was of unknown origin. Crawford — Miss Blanch Gill, local telephone operator at Crawford, died from burns received when she poured oil on a slow fire. Carroll — Henry Tietgen, a farmer, died suddenly, after be- ing overcome by the suffocating fumes of a grass fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 State of Nebraska Falls City — Mrs. Joe Doroin saturated her clothing with kerosene oil and set fire to it causing her death, January 5, i Falls City — Radner Worthing of Omaha, died from burns ved when the gasoline tank of his Sedan caught fire. His also received serious burns at the same time. Fremont — Kenneth Howery met a tragic death when in some manner a pan of gasoline which his mother had used for washing some clothing exploded enveloping the boy in flames. Lincoln — Fred Kroeger of Seward, who was a student in the State University, died from burns which he received while sleeping in a building where he worked a part of the time; cause of fire unknown. Milford — As E. Parker was pumping up a hand made tank for a gasoline stock, it exploded, bursting into flames and enveloping him. He was so badly burned that he died a few hours later. Mitchell — Miss Hattie Mildred Richter died in the Meth - odist hospital at Scotts Bluff from burns which she received in using kerosene to hasten the fire in preparing breakfast for a brother who was sick in bed. Mitchell — Mrs. William Charles died from burns received from an explosion of kerosene used to start a partly dead fire. Mitchell — Fay Reef, aged 11, died from burns received while using kerosene to kindle a fire in the kitchen stove. The newspaper in reporting this incident says that this is the third death in this community during the past six weeks from the use of kerosene in starting fires. Newport — Fire of unknown origin caused the death of James Abbott who was sleeping in a room over the stove. Omaha — John Hamilton died from burns received when he poured gasoline on the furnace fire. Omaha — Aaron Weiss, aged 59 years, died from burns which he received while starting a fire in the furnace in the basement of his garage. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Division of Fire Prevention 27 Omaha — William Daly, 52, gave his life in a vain effort to save his brother in a fire at the Commercial Hotel, 2310 M Street. Omaha — Mrs. Katherine Cavanaugh, aged 59, died from burns received when parafine with which she was sealing jelly glasses flamed up, setting fire to her clothing. Omaha — Bror A. Christianson was killed in an accident when two high voltage wires crossed, coming in contact with his body above the waist. Pawnee City — Coal oil, used to start a fire to cook the noon meal, caused fatal gums to Mrs. Charley Spradly and her daughter, when the oil exploded and the farm home destroyed. Pawnee City — Ray Beach, a farmer, died from the re - sults of using coal oil to start a fire in the kitchen stove. Hot coals in the stove is supposed to have caused the explosion. Randolph — Miss Myrtle Chambers died of burns which she received when she upset a can of coal oil onto a red hot stove, splashing the oil over her clothing. The oil had been setting on the warming oven above the stove. Ravenna — Mrs. Pearl Dutton died from burns received when the oil stove on which she was preparing a meal ex - ploded. Rising City — Mrs. Gladys Schrader of Rising City was burned to death at the approach to the Platte River bridge when the car she was driving turned over and caught her underneath. Stratton — Mrs. W. F. Boyle died from burns received a month previous when an incubator lamp exploded while she was filling it. Wymore — Blodwyn Jones, aged eleven, died from burns received when her sleeve caught fire as she was putting cobs in the kitchen stove. Scribner — Edwin Mueller's infant child was fatally burned when another small child pushed the baby buggy up against a hot stove setting it on fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 State of Nebraska INJURIES FROM FIRE Ashland — Mr. Anton Knutson, a fireman, broke his ankle while fighting a fire. Alma — Donald Thompson, son of Mr. and Mrs. Guy Thompson, was severely burned about the face when a celuloid visor he was wearing became ignited from a candle. Ayr — Mrs. William Easter was seriously burned by an explosion of kerosene which she was using to start a fire in the kitchen range. Blue Springs — Glen Dutton, aged 17, was the victim of a very serious accident when he with some others were using a piece of gas pipe for a cannon. The pipe exploded and a piece of the metal was blown through the body of young Dutton. Bridgeport — Jesse Nunn and son, Keith, both suffered badly burned faces and heads as the result of the explosion of a carbide lighting plant which they were attempting to fill by the use of a lighted lantern. Bridgeport — Chas. Hanway suffered severe burns about the face and hands when the tank of an oil stove exploded with which he was working. Chappell — Roy Carter and Fred Thompson were all but suffocated by smoke in the county jail when a lighted match is supposed to have been thrown into some trash outside their cell door. The sheriff, who had come home on a late train, discovered the condition of the men. Clinton — Mrs. J. C. Matz was badly burned when she put coal in the kitchen stove which had been soaked with kerosene oil. Her husband had warned her that he had emp - tied the contents of the oil stove into the coal pile, but she had forgotten the warning. Columbus — Mrs. Gus Edmonston was badly burned about the limbs and on one hand when gasoline which was being pumped into a truck tank exploded setting fire to her clothing. Dannebrog — Harry Lingf ord was struck by lightning and one hand badly burned at Dannebrog. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Division of Fire Prevention 29 Elmwood — Clarence, small son of Otto Flieschman, was quite badly burned when an explosion occurred while the father was pouring gasoline into the tank of a tractor which was still warm from recent use. Elmwood — L. F. Langhorst suffered severe burns in the explosion of the furnace in the basement of his store. The furnace was equipped with an oil burner and when he turned the oil onto the hot plates an explosion resulted. Fairbury — A four-year-old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Mees upset a forge on which her father had been doing some blacksmith work. Her clothes caught fire and she was severe - ly burned. Falls City — Harry Rodewald will probably lose his eye - sight as a result of lighting a match to look at the alcohol anti-freeze solution in his radiator. The alcohol flamed up and burned his face severely. Fremont — Mrs. Fred Reitmueller was badly burned when a gasoline lamp exploded in her home. Grand Island — Mrs. Fred Brown poured some kerosene oil on the fire in the kitchen stove to hurry it along when an explosion occurred which burned her severely over her whole body except her face and lower limbs. Grand Island — Miss Kathe Howk was badly burned when her mother lit a match in the room where the girl had been cleaning a pair of gloves with gasoline. Hartington — Duard Erickson will lose his left hand as a result of an explosion caused by pouring coal oil on the fire in the kitchen stove. Hickman — P. G. Schneider suffered very serious burns as a result of starting a fire with kerosene. Kearney — While working over the kitchen sink, Mrs. Frank Walenta was struck by lightning burning her severely about the arms and legs. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">State of Nebraska 30 Kearney — Charles W. Harper was severely burned by the explosion of a coffee urn in a restaurant where he was em - ployed. Lincoln — W. G. Hall sustained severe burns to his hand during a small fire in the engine room caused by an over - heated exhaust pipe. Lincoln — William Wehrman, a student at the State Uni - versity, was severely burned while cleaning his automobile while it was still hot from recent use. He was using gasoline. Lincoln — Keith Thompson was rendered unconscious from smoke, and when found his clothing was on fire near the furnace. Lincoln — Mrs. E. G. McDaniels and Mrs. Elmer Wilcox were severely burned about the face and arms when a gasoline heater exploded in the Wilcox home. Lincoln — E. P. Feaster and Roy Page suffered slight in - juries in fighting a fire at 1521 0 Street. Lincoln — Eleven persons suffered injuries in Fourth of July accidents in Lincoln from fireworks. Nehawka — Harold Stoll was severly burned about the face and head when the alcohol in the radiator of his car was ignited by a match he was holding at the cap. Norfolk — Alma Hanka was severely burned by the ex - plosion of a gasoline stove. Omaha — Joe Proch was severely burned about the stom - ach and suffered a fracture of the collar bone when sparks from a Roman candle ignited the contents of a box of fire - works and explosives near which he was sitting. Omaha — Nathan Somberg was severely burned when he lit a match in a gas filled room at his home. A gas jet is sup - posed to have been inadvertently turned on during the day causing a slow leak which filled the room. Omaha — Mrs. A. Evans and son Joseph, were severely burned when a pot of gasoline exploded on a gas stove at their home. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Division of Fire Prevention 31 Omaha — Tom Hegarty and Harold Hodder were both ser - iously burned by an explosion in a garage where they were working when one of the boys lit a match. Omaha — Mr. and Mrs. William Meredith were both se - verely burned when a gasoline torch which they were using to solder a radiator exploded. Omaha — Six firemen were injured when two fire trucks going to the same fire collided. Three of the men were severe - ly injured. Omaha — Sparks from a sparkler held in one hand, Tony Gillotte lit a fire cracker held in the other, from which he received a severely burned hand. Omaha — Myrom Parnoff, aged 11, suffered a badly burned hand when he held a fire cracker too long before it exploded. Omaha — Capt. Max Gross, Geo. Powell, John Zick, and Amose Powers, were severely injured, and William Me Wil - liams was overcome by smoke while fighting fire at the home of George M. Seaman, 106 North 54th Street. The fire was started by children playing with matches in the basement. Reynolds — Joseph Nutsch, aged 15, narrowly escaped death and was badly burned about the face, chest, and hands, when a supposedly dead fire flamed up when he poured kero - sene oil on it. Rulo — R. Pahl and Otis Seissong were injured at Rulo while assisting in fighting a fire. When the roof fell in they sought refuge under a pool table and escaped being crushed. Stratton — Mrs. William Boyle was seriously burned while attempting to fill a lighted incubator lamp in the basement of their home. Ulysses — Walter Gitchell and Charles Holderness sus - tained severe injuries when the tank of a Ford coupe exploded which they were filing with gasoline. Wymore — Silas Fax, employed at the Black Brothers' Mill at Beatrice, suffered severe burns on his hand when the feed valve to an oil burner backfired as he was adjusting it. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 State of Nebraska INVESTIGATION OF SUSPICIOUS FIRES During 1926 the Fire Marshal's office made investigations into 115 suspicious fires. Of this number the evidence secured led them to believe that 70 of these fires were of incendiary origin. Twenty-seven persons were arrested and charged with arson. Eleven confessed or were convicted; three were ac - quitted, one was dismissed and the other twelve are awaiting trial. In the remaining seventy cases, up to date, no charges have been preferred as the collecting of evidence still con - tinues. Twenty-five of the fires we decided the cause not to be incendiary, but in most cases to be carelessness on the part of the occupant to allow fire hazards to exist. The other twenty we had to list as unknown or doubtful fires. In the investigation of these fires the utmost care was taken to avoid publicity and reflections being cast on any in - nocent party or parties. It is with greater satisfaction to the investigator to be able to exonerate the suspected ones, than it is to bring charges of arson against them. A BRIEF HISTORY OF THE OUTSTANDING ARSON CASES INVESTIGATED DURING 1926 North Platte, Nebr.— December 30, 1925. The home of Wm. Wolf was on fire three different times between 3:00 p. m. and 4:30 p. m., the fire department being called each time. When the department was called the third time it was dis - covered that oil had been used to saturate the rugs and bed - ding. Therefore, Mrs. Jennie Wolfe (the wife) was arrested, and the Fire Marshal's office called there to investigate the case, and the evidence obtained indicated that the fire was in - cendiary. Mrs. Wolf was tried in District Court on February 1st, 1926. The defense admitted the woman had been drink - ing and, therefore, not responsible for her actions. Conse - quently the jury brought in a verdict of not guilty. Bellevue, Nebr. — January 11, 1926. Mr. J. Cross was arrested because of a second attempt to burn his home. A preliminary trial was held on January 27, 1926, and he was bound over to the District Court. When the case was called </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Division of Fire Prevention 33 for trial the Judge and County Attorney dismissed the action without consulting the Fire Marshal's office. Elkhorn, Nebr. — February 10, 1926. The Union Pacific depot was robbed of mail and express and then set on fire to hide the robbery. James and Charles P. Harmon (two brothers) were arrested and confessed to the robbery, but denied the arson charge. They were released to the Federal Authorities and on confession of the robbery they were sent to the peni - tentiary. Omaha, Nebr.— February 16, 1926. Mike Alexeni, 4541 South 39th Street, was arrested for setting his house on fire, using oil soaked rags. The evidence was not conclusive and he was released by the County Attorney. Maywood, Nebr. — March 23, 1926. Mrs. Sophia Dold was bound over to the District Court on a $2,000.00 bond, April 27, 1926, having been charged with the burning of the school house some five or six miles south of Maywood. The case was tried on October 27, 1926, and the jury brought in a verdict of not guilty. March 29, 1926. Otis and Orville Gaston, aged 15-13, liv - ing on a farm near Howe, Nebraska, were arrested June 4th, 1926, on suspicion of having set fire to the school house in District No. 60, which they were attending. A confession was obtained from the boys who gave as a reason for their actions a personal dislike for the teacher. It was later recalled that two other school houses had been burned in other districts where these boys had attended school, but they denied having set the other fires. The County Judge sentenced them to the Boys Industrial School at Kearney. Pleasant Dale, Nebr. — April 13, 1926. John W. Helm, age 10, had a mania for setting fires. Within a period of eight or nine months he had set six fires, the last fire being on April 13, 1926. The citizens of the town were greatly agitated over the danger of losing their property, so the boy was taken be - fore the County Judge and sentenced to the industrial school for boys at Kearney. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 State op Nebraska Tobias, Nebr. — William Bergman of Tobias, Saline Coun - ty, a bootlegger, had been found guilty on three counts on a liquor charge, and sentenced to serve six months in jail, and to pay a fine of $1500.00. In order to raise the money with which to pay his fine, he burned his shack and a small amount of household goods, on October 22, 1925. The insurance was paid to him. Then his bondsmen withdrew from his bond and he was placed in confinement. Owing to the cruel treat - ment his wife received while living with him, she decided to obtain a divorce. As soon as Bergman learned of her action, he called the authorities and told them that the fire they had was started by his wife and her brother Frank and a sister Rose. He claimed that they had taken their clothing and some of the furniture out of the house and stored it at her brother's place out in the country, and if they would go out with him he would identify the goods. The sheriff, county attorney, the insurance adjuster, and the Assistant State Fire Marshal accompanied him to where he claimed the stuff was stored and did identify quite a bit of the stuff. On making an investigation it was found that Bergman was the one who had taken the goods to this place and threatened all of the others if they should ever reveal this fact to anyone. His case was submitted to a grand jury on September 24, 1926. and Bergman was indicted and tried in district court for the crime of arson. He was found guilty on October 2, 1926, and given a flat sentence of seven years in the penitentiary at Lincoln, on October 28, 1926. Chapman, Nebr. Louis Beehler and Morris Hoier of Chapman, Merrick County, were arrested, having been charged with the burning of a Nash car, six miles north of Chapman on August 27, 1926. The car which belonged to Beehler had been insured by him for $500, it being a 1920 model. Actual value policy, but Beehler thought he would get the entire amount. Beehler was arrested September 13, 1926, and con - »sed that he and Hoier had burned the car. By previous •eement Hoier was to receive an old Chalmers touring car exchange for hia assistance in burning the Nash. Hoier was arrested 10 days later at Crofton and signed a confession which substantiated the statements made by Beehler. Both </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Division of Fire Prevention 35 were bound over to the District Court and on December S, 1926, they appeared before Judge Lightner, each pleading guilty to the charge of arson. Beehler was sentenced to a term of two years in the State penitentiary and Hoier was given one year in the State reformatory. Oakdale, Nebr. Virgil Wagner, living one and one-half miles south of Oakdale, Antelope County, was arrested on November 25, 1925, charged with having set fire to his father's barn, which also partly burned the house, on November 14, 1925. He waived preliminary trial and was bound over on a $1,000 bond to the District Court. He was tried on May 17 and 18, 1926, and after being out ten hours the jury brought in a verdict of acquittal. Omaha, Nebr. Nick Salistean, who was running a three - story hotel at 2623 N Street, South Side Omaha, Nebraska, was arrested on the charge of having set fire to his hotel, this being the third fire in twelve months. Salistean was arrested and at preliminary hearing was bound over to the District Court in December, 1925. The case was not completed at this term of court owing to a death in the family of one of the jurors who asked to be excused from further service at this term of court, June 14 to 16, 1926. He was found guilty of arson and of attempting to defraud the insurance company, and on June 29, 1926, he was sentenced to a five year term in the State penitentiary. The case was appealed to the Supreme Court and was affirmed by them, but owing to an error by Salistean's attorney the Supreme Court agreed to review the case again, and he is still out on an appeal bond. Kenesaw, Nebr.— May 3, 1926. On May 12, 1926, Chas. A. Valkenaar, Adams County, was arrested on a charge of burning his restaurant on the morning of May 3, 1926. The preliminary hearing was held on June 3 and 4, 1926, and he was bound over to the District Court. The trial has not been held as yet. Motive for the fire was to collect the insurance. Crab Orchard— May 16, 1926. Paul Skraback, living four and one-half miles northeast of Crab Orchard, Johnson County, was arrested on May 19, 1926, having been charged with the </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 State of Nebraska burning of a machine shed belonging to Hayes Allen, a near neighbor, on Sunday, May 16, 1926, while Mr. Allen and his family were away from home. The motive given was a desire for revenge, as the evidence showed that he had made threats of getting even with Allen for the testimony he had given against him on a liquor charge that the State held against him. The preliminary trial was held June 1st, 1926, and he was bound over to the District Court. On September 27th, when the case came up for trial, it was postponed until the January 1927 term. Bloodhounds were used on this case. North Loup.— July 14, 1926. Edward A. Knapp of North Loup, Valley County, was arrested on July 22, 1926, and con - fessed to having burned his hardware and furniture store on the night of July 14, 1926, in order to collect the insurance. He was given an indeterminate sentence of from one to five years in the State penitentiary. North Platte, Nebr.— July 27, 1926. Mr. Willard Small of North Platte, Lincoln County, was arrested on July 27, 1926, and confessed to the burning of seven head of horses and a barn, 19 miles north of Stapleton, in Logan County, on May 3, 1926. He was hired by Dick Ross of North Platte to set the fire. Evidence shows that Ross has collected a large number of fire and lightning losses in the last five years. In this particular case Ross stole the horses from two different ranchmen, and with the aid of Small drove them to this old abandoned ranch in the sand hills; having first leased the place, claiming he was going to farm it. Also, he and one other party had three insurance policies on horses that did not exist. Two of these claims were paid. As soon as Ross collected his one claim he disappeared and has so far eluded the officers. Ben Neal was arrested in Oregon City, Oregon, and brought back, and C. 0. Wilson in Omaha. Investigation showed that both of these parties were implicated in the in - surance transactions. They were given preliminary trials and bound over to the District Court, where their cases are still pending, hoping for the capture of Ross. Small was given a sentence of from two to three years in the State reformatory at Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Division of Fiee Prevention 37 An arson ring composed of Wm. Bartlett, Clarence Head - ley, Walter Headley, James C. Sebastian, Mike Toth, Samuel Girt, and Merle Livingstone, all of Omaha, were arrested on August 25, 1926, charged with arson. The crimes committed by them covered seven or eight fires extending over a period of six month. Their preliminary hearing was held on August 26, 1926, and all were bound over to the District Court. Chapman, Nebr. S. P. Banish was arrested November 23, 1926, for the fire which occurred in his cream station on the night of July 29, 1926. This fire was investigated at the time but the proper evidence was not obtained until Louis Beehler confessed to having been hired to set the fire for Banish. Beehler made this confession at the same time he was arrested for having burned his own auto. Banish was bound over to District Court at his preliminary hearing. This case will be tried in 1927. MR. BUSINESS MAN OF NEBRASKA To you business men of this State ; no matter what busi - ness you are in, whether it is merchant, banker, baker, hotel keeper, theatre manager, blacksmith, or any other line of business in which you make your living, we want to thank each and every one of you who has done his part in fire pre - vention this year. We have men from this office who have met you, and you and they have talked over this fire pre - vention question in your own office or shop. It is their duty to inspect your place of business to see whether or not any condition exists where a fire might originate, not only destroy - ing your building, but those adjoining you. These men have often found conditions existing which were dangerous, "ac - cording to statistics," and were not aware that they could cause fire, there were other conditions which you knew might cause fire but you had just grown a bit careless, and needed a little reminder to get you busy. Hundreds of you have cooperated with us to the fullest extent, and have welcomed our coming, while there are a few among you who have re - sented the inspectors' advice and have refused to comply with his instructions. You thereby failed to be a good citizen, for </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 State of Nebraska you are not only endangering your own life and property but that of your neighbor and his property as well. NEBRASKA'S BOY SCOUTS AND CAMPFIRE GIRLS The Fire Marshal's force want to compliment the Boy Scouts and the Camp Fire Girls on the fine teaching they re - ceive in their respective organizations, and the splendid way in which they help the older members of their household to observe the very important teachings of fire prevention. The good that you are doing has been brought to our attention, and we urge you not to be lax in your efforts along these lines. There is so much the boys and girls can do to assist in this great work of combating carelessness. Over five hundred mil - lion dollars worth of property is being destroyed each year, and thousands of lives lost, and thousands injured for life — just because of carelessness, and the time to learn to be care - ful is when one is young, for it then becomes a habit with us and we do it without thinking. Let each of us made a solemn promise to do more good this year than ever before in this particular line of work FIRE PREVENTION TO OUR CHAMBERS OF COMMERCE, COMMERCIAL CLUBS, AND ALL OTHER CLUBS We wish to thank each of you, and each individual mem - ber of same, who has given of his time and money to spread the doctrine of fire prevention in his community. There has been some fine results noted in the towns where the club has put energetic members on their fire prevention committee and where all the other members have made themselves a com - mittee of one, to see that their own business place and home was safe from the causes and defects which might cause a conflagration and possibly loss to life. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Division of Fire Frevention 39 INSURANCE COMPANIES AND THEIR AGENTS We are pleased to extend, "to the Insurance Companies of this State and all others doing business in it as well," our thanks and appreciation of their assistance and cooperation. We also wish to thank all the honest and careful agents who have given us their assistance and who have been cautious and fair in writing the risks. The motive for most of our incendiary fires is to collect the insurance. In some cases where we are called to investigate the evidence is very plain that the party having the loss was heavily insured. CITY COUNCILS AND TOWN BOARDS We wish to extend our appreciation to the members of the city councils and town boards of this state who have assisted in carrying on the fight of fire prevention in their city and town ; first, by giving the proper equipment to their firemen to assist them in the modern way of fighting fires, and, second, to the new fire prevention ordinances passed to safeguard their citizens from careless practices. A great deal of good has been done in this way. Now, a word to the councilmen and members of the town boards who have failed to do their duty in assisting in fire prevention. Gentlemen: It is your duty to see that every safeguard within reason is taken and to supply your town with equip - ment sufficient to fight fires when they occur, and also to pas? ordinances to help prevent fires from starting. Every town is anxious to have their insurance rates lowered and one of the best and quickest ways to get this reduction is to have up-to-date fire fighting apparatus and a well organized fire department — then enforce your ordinances on a clean city — and assist the citizens in getting rid of their rubbish and trash. If you have no funds with which to equip your fire depart - ment, we would refer you to the last page of this annual report where you will find how this money can be procured. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">State of Nebraska 40 TO THE EDITORS OF NEBRASKA To each one of you we want to express our appreciation and thanks for the good and timely advice which went out in your publications on fire prevention topics. The newspaper is the greatest educator of the times and it is through the columns of your papers that more people are reached than any other way. The information on fire is read and a great amount of good is done. We are now earnestly requesting that you all unite with us in a greater effort this coming year in spreading the doctrine of being more watchful against the Demon"fire,"and take the necessary precaution to clean up rub - bish and trash ; to see that safe electric wiring and electrical apparatus is installed ; that furnaces, stoves, pipes and chim - neys are made safe ; that the practicing of starting fires with coal oil and gasoline is stopped ; and that you put up a strong fight in your particular town to see that proper ordinances are passed to make safe the storage and sale of inflammable oils, to see that these storage stations are placed at a safe distance from any building, preferably outside of city limits, as this is one of the greatest hazards. Another thing you should fight for is an ordinance prohibiting the burning of trash in the streets and alleys, unless the same is burned in approved trash burners made of iron, brick, or concrete, so that the fire cannot blow out and the ashes can be easily re - moved. No greater reward can any of us ask, than the peace of mind which we will have in knowing that we have given our time and means in helping to overcome the great loss and injury to life and the stupendous destruction of property and recourses of this country, 80 per cent of which is due to pure unadulterated carelessness. MEMBERS OF SCHOOL BOARDS, SCHOOL SUPERIN - TENDENTS, PRINCIPALS, AND TEACHERS We wish at this time to thank each and every one of you in this State who have assisted and cooperated with us. To you we wish a Very Happy and Prosperous New Year. The School boards that have built their new school buildings with the thought in view as to safety from fire, and have equipped </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Division of Fire Ibevention 41 the same with every safeguard, requested by this office, are deserving of the highest praise, and the same credit is due the school boards that have remodeled their old buildings to comply with existing regulations. These laws were made to safe guard the children, and, oh! how important it is. The superintendent, principal, and every teacher will be honored by the citizens of the state for obeying the law which requires that two fire drills must be had each month, and at least thirty minutes of time devoted during each month to the study of fire prevention. To those others: "Will your conscience be clear?" Members of school boards, school superintendents, principals and all teachers are morally responsible for the safety of the children who are confined to their care for a large part of each day during the early years of their life. We have not yet advanced to the point where we hold those responsible for fire loss to legally account for their shortcom - ings. Maybe we shall some day. But the matter of protect - ing the children is one on which there should be no need for law. Every school house should be properly built and then properly protected with every modern means of fire preven - tion and fire protection. Every school building should be as nearly fireproof as possible. In every school disaster, panic is the principle cause of the loss of life. If people would remain cool-headed they might be easily saved. But, how can you expect children to be cool-headed under circumstances that strike terror into full grown men. Fire drills will help — proper construction will help — but schools should be safe. Then every effort should be made to instill in the child's mind confidence that it can escape regardless of the dangers that threaten, and this confidence can only be instilled through a combination of all agencies: Proper buildings properly protected, and a proper fire drill. It is up to you, Mr. Superintendent, or Mr. Principal, to look into the conditions of your school carefully, to see whether the children really are safe or not. If they are not safe, it is far better to close the school until the condition has been remedied. It is far better to let a child grow up without </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 State of Nebraska schooling, if necessary, than it is to sacrifice that child's life on the fiery altar of your negligence — your carelessness — or your incompetence. Twenty-two little blackened corpses were taken from the ruins of the St. John School at Peabody, Mass. From the Col - lingwood, Ohio School there were recovered the bodies of one hundred and seventy-three victims. Suppose it had been your school instead of that school in Ohio. Suppose you looked down on those rows of little bodies and realized that you were to blame. Do you want that experience? Then take steps to prevent it. Act — Today. Don't continue to think of the dollars, but think of those children. Follow the instruc - tions of the fire inspector and cooperate with us in making your school safe as possible. VOLUNTEER FIREMEN A Word to the Noble Volunteer Firemen of Nebraska We want to extend to you our heart felt thanks, also a few words of appreciation, for your hearty cooperation in as - sisting this office and making it possible to report such a low fire loss for this State for 1926. You are the minute men of the hour who stand ready at all hours of the day or night to answer the call of the fire bell or siren, or even the call by telephone or shouted warning. You drop whatever you are doing, or arouse from your slumbers, jump into a few clothes and hurry to the scene of action — taking your life in your own hands at nearly every call, just to give your services to some neighbor who is burning out, and who may have been careless, allowing conditions to exist around his place that could start the fire, or spread it rapidly after it did start. You not only endanger your life, but you ruin your clothes and shoes — a splendid service ren - dered without a thought of remuneration. We again thank you on behalf of the State of Nebraska and wish you a Happy and Prosperous New Year, and may </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Division of Fire Fbevention 43 the people of your vicinity give you better cooperation and the needed equipment for fighting their fires and also use every precaution in keeping fires from starting. INCENDIARY FIRES Bulletin for Fire Department It is desired to call the attention of the members of the Fire Department to the increasing number of fires of suspicious origin occurring in this city. Some officials have gone on record as making the positive statement that more than 30 per cent of the fire loss is incendiary. This is undoubtedly an extravagant statement, but it is conservatively estimated that 10 per cent of the number of fires show evidence of incendiar - ism. It occurs to me that by cooperating together and by thoroughly investigating every fire of suspicious origin we may materially decrease the fire waste in this state and make the crime of arson so unprofitable and so unpopular that it will be seldom attempted. Arson has always been considered one of the most serious crimes and has been classed with murder and treason, and in some states, even now, a conviction of arson carries with it the death penalty. Incendiary fires can, for ordinary purposes, be separated into five classes, according to motive: 1. To conceal evidence of some other crime. 2. Malice or revenge. 3. Malicious mischief. 4. Pyromania or some other form of insanity. 5. Desire to defraud the insurer. Every fire is presumed to be of accidental origin, and as the firemen are the first to reach the scene of the fire, it is usually within the province of these men to overcome the pre - sumption of accident and to discover evidence to show that the fire was incendiary. One of the first and most important steps in an arson trial is to prove what the lawyers call the </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 State of Nebraska Erpus Delicti," or the body of the crime. In other words, re evidence of a motive, or even a confession, can be in - uced in a criminal trial it must first be proven that the ific crime charged has been committed. In a case of arson specific crime charges is the burning of a building or other In the investigation of a fire care should always be taken to ascertain the character of it, in what part of the building it originated, how it burned, and other facts and circumstances which may be suggestive of the nature of the fire under in - vestigation. The incendiary origin of a fire is sometimes shown by direct and positive evidence, such as the saturation of the premises with kerosene or some other explosive com - pound; it may be shown by the fact that there are two or three separate fires, one having no connection with another. It sometimes manifests itself to the firemen by the manner in which it burns, or by the presence of dense smoke, indicating the use of oil. The appearance of the interior of a building frequently shows whether a fire is the result of accident or design. The articles of furniture may have been placed so as to retard the work of the firemen, or there may be evidence that a con - siderable part of the furniture, fixtures or stock had been re - moved previous to the fire. The Supreme Court of a western state, in commenting on an arson case, said, "Where the same person has a series of fires and collects insurance it furnishes a basis for an infer - ence of more or less strength that the fires are not accidental." In the investigation of a supposed incendiary fire it is frequently thought important to eliminate insofar as is pos - sible all the accidental causes which might possibly be put forward as the probable cause for the fire. It is highly im - portant to inspect the heating and the electrical equipment of the building, to see whether such equipment could possibly have been the cause of the fire. It is thus important to know that the electrical equipment is intact or that there is no electric wire near the origin of the fire, as some of these things will undoubtedly be advanced by the defense as the probable cause. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Division of Fire Frevention 45 Any of these things, and many others not here mentioned, may tend to excite the suspicion of the firemen that the fire was not accidental, and in such a case a thorough investiga - tion as to its cause should be immediately made. If any phy - sical evidences of incendiarism are found they should be im - mediately taken possession of by the officer in charge and held for the Fire Marshal, or his Deputy. It frequently happens that the remains of a "plant" ar - ranged by someone to start or accelerate the fire is found in the building after the fire is extinguished. It is highly im - portant, in the event candles or oily bottles, or things of that character are discovered, that they be left exactly as found until they can be photographed. If the candle is to be picked up. lift it by the wick and turn it over to the Fire Marshal's off.ee for examination for fingerprints. The same care should be exercised in handling any other articles which were plainly used by the incendiary, for their examination for fingerprints. All cases of suspicious fires should be immediately re - ferred to the State Fire Marshal for further investigation, but the members of the Fire Department should bear in mind that, being the first at the scene of the fire, it is their duty, if the fire is incendiary, to collect and develop the evidence to sup - port this fact. Of course it is impossible to properly investi - gate the cause of a fire during its progress, but where the cir - cumstances are suspicious, as soon as the fire is extinguished a watchman should be placed in charge of the building until such time as proper investigation can be made. (Signed) JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal SLOGANS America never has been licked — except by flames A match has a head, but no brains. When you use its head, use your brains. A fire extinguisher on hand is worth two in the store. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 State of Nebraska Fire loves a disorderly housekeeper. A tree will make a million matches, but a match will start a fire which destroys a million trees. Clean property seldom burns. A man steals a few dollars and is sent to prison, but when a man through carelessness and indifference causes a lire which results in the loss of thousands of dollars worth of prop - erty, and sometimes the loss of life, he is not punished. Which is the greater criminal ? Careless smokers burned over millions of dollars worth of property last year. Do not smoke where smoking is for - bidden. Fire prevention protects your home and family. Fire waste is not paid by insurance companies ; they only distribute the money that is paid by the people when they buy merchandise. The cost of fire tax is concealed in the price of the goods. If we all use precaution and teach our boys and girls the hazards of fire, it won't be long until the fires will be reduced to a minimum. Fire is not the only form of waste, but it is the most If we are careful in all things we will avoid waste, and carefulness does not cost a cent. From little sparks may burst a might flame. b Courting Danger. "How'd they come to bounce the fire '?" asked Abe Hinkle, who had been out of town for a le of days. "He took too many dad-blamed risks," ans - wered Joe Mudge. "Why he even wore his celluloid collar to fireo " LUCO. tlf your fire insurance rates are too high, see that your conforms to the state law the state marshall is called lforce and then watch the results. (Kansas State Fire ihal's Bulletin) . A tumbledown wooden building cobwebbed and trash-be - decked in the rear of a block of business houses is a more ex - pensive luxury than a perpetual marble fountain bedecked with vari-colored lights by night, set in the public square. (Kan - sas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin) . </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Division of Fire Prevention 47 SOME OF THE UNDERLYING CAUSES OF FIRE GAS OILS ASHES LITTER MATCHES GASOLINE FIREWORKS EXPLOSIONS ELECTRICITY CARELESSNESS DONTS DONT use make-shifts instead of proper fuses in your elec - trical circuits ; the fuse is the safety valve of the system. DONT leave electric flatirons or other heating devices turned on while attending to something else. DON'T look for gas leaks with an open flame light; you will be sure to find them. DON'T use gasoline or other volatile liquids to remove spots from clothing or for other purposes. It is cheaper to pay for dry cleaning than for a funeral. DONT throw your matches or lighted smoking material where they can possibly start a fire. DONT smoke in bed ; even if those guilty of this practice are too green to burn, the beds are not. DONT let the children play with matches or bonfires. DONT fail to have your defective chimneys and flues mended ; they cause numerous fires in our state. DONT forget to have your smokepipe cleaned of soot; if clogged it may overheat and start a fire when you oper - ate the furnace. DONT neglect to protect walls, ceilings and partitions from the overheating of stoves, furnaces and pipes. DON'T put hot ashes into wooden boxes or barrels. DONT fill oil lamps or stoves by open flame lights ; many lives have been lost by this form of carelessness. DON'T let rubbish accumulate ; uncleanliness and fire go hand in hand. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 State of Nebraska DON'T fail to keep a bucket of water and a bucket of sand in a convenient place for use in case of fire; they may save the lives of your family. DONT fail to purchase a good fire extinguishing chemical (one or more) ) for your home. DONT fail to look after chemical extinguishers ; see that they are immediately charged after being used. A 21/2 or 3 gallon turnover chemical can be used by man, woman or child and one or more should be installed in every home. REMEMBER, IN CONCLUSION, "FIRE IS A DANGER THAT NEVER SLEEPS," SO BE CONTINUOUSLY ON YOUR GUARD FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX "Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DE - PARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metropolitan, first or second class or villages, organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and au - thority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one-half O-Vi) mills each year upon all taxable property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be levied in the same manner as in the case of gen - eral city taxes. Revenue raised by such special levy may be used only for the purpose of purchasing equipment for a fire department of such city or for installing and equipping a fire alarm system, or in payment of bonds as hereinafter author - ized. "Section 4470. BONDS— AUTHORIZED. Any city or vil - lage having levied a tax as herein authorized may anticipate the collection of such tax so levied, and for that purpose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a sum amount - ing to 90 per cent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than five years, and may bear inter - est at a rate not to exceed 5 per cent per annum. Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so assessed and levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax when Kto hold the same as a separate fund to the amount of the s, so issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeeming such bonds." </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>