<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Farm Mortgage History of Eleven South-esstern Nebraska Townships 1870-1932</title>
               <date value="1933-08">1933-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 67 Farm Mortgage History of Eleven South - eastern Nebraska Townships 1870-1932 ELEANOR H. HINIIAN AND J. O. RANKIN Department of Rural Economics 1 1 Location of the 11 townships studied. Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county; Brush Creek pre - cinct m Saline county; and Richland precinct m Saunders county. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA AUGUST, 1933 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Page Summary 4 Introduction 5 Preliminary survey of eleven townships studied &lt;; Farm mortgage filings 12 Summary of filings 12 Class of mortgage filings 17 Interest rates 24 Amount of debt and interest rate 28 Duration of mortgages 30 New and refinanced mortgages 35 Type of lender 37 Residence of mortgagee 43 Land price and mortgage filings 46 Mortgage debt outstanding at specified dates 51 Volume of debt outstanding. 51 First and junior mortgage debt outstanding 57 Indices of farm mortgage debt per acre, wholesale prices, and farm income 58 Total banking and life insurance power compared with farm mortgage debt outstanding 61 Farm mortgage foreclosures 62 The present situation 66 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY A statistical analysis was made of 14,630 farm mortgages filed m eleven southeastern Nebraska townships from 1870 to 1932. The period of greatest activity m assuming mortgages was from 1882 to 1895, but the borrowings per mortgage and per acre m this early period were relatively small. The average debt per acre filed during any particular year rose from three dollars m 1876-79 to $63 m 1920 and then decreased to $26 m 1932, following m a general way the change m land price. The debt outstanding per acre bearing any unreleased mortgage, rose from three dollars m 1875 to $72 m 1923, and has since declined to $61 on January 1, 1933; but this decline was slight m proportion to the re - duction m land values, commodity prices, and farmers' incomes during the same period. Interest rates per mortgage filed were reduced by half between 1887 and 1906, since which period they have remained fairly constant m these 11 townships at about 5% per cent, except m 1920-22 when they were higher. A conspicuous feature of the past 20 years has been the increase m farm mortgage loans obtained from mortgage invest - ment companies and m junior loans obtained from commercial banks. The commercial banks, as a class, usually charged higher interest rates than any other type of mortgagee; the mortgage investment companies, insurance companies, and private investors charged relatively low rates. The proportion of farm mortgages held by local mortgagees increased greatly from about 1890 to 1932. Foreclosures of farm property were less common m the 11 townships studied than m many other parts of Nebraska, but constituted a serious problem m 1896-1900, 1922, 1927, and 1930-32. Voluntary assignments of land title to mortgagees, m return for a release of the mortgage, were commoner than court proceedings during the depression of 1930-32. Twenty-eight such assignments occurred m 1932. The year 1933 commenced with a general level of the prices of farm products as low or lower than at any time m the previous history of the state, while the total mortgage indebtedness outstanding m the 11 town - ships was only slightly reduced from an all-time high. The spectacular increase m the prices of farm products between January and July, 1933, offers the hope of a great improvement m the situation outlined above, if the July price level can be maintained. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven South - eastern Nebraska Townships 1870-1932 ELEANOR H. HINMAN AND J. O. RANKIN • INTRODUCTION The real estate mortgage fulfills three highly important functions m American agricultural history. As capital credit, it is the farmer's chief means of financing his advancement' through the purchase and improvement of his farm. As pro - duction credit, it is one among several means of enabling him to carry on his business when the earnings of preceding years are insufficient for his business needs. As consumption credit, it is a common recourse of farm owners for family mainten - ance m time of personal disaster or moderate economic dis - tress. 2 Data on the total farm mortgage debt outstanding m the United States exist for the years 1880-89, 1910, 1920, 1925. and for alternate years commencing with 1928, but not for the intervening years." 1 The mortgage data presented by censuses subsequent to that of 1890 are confined to owner - operated farms. It is believed that a study of a complete record of all farm mortgages for a typical although very limited Nebraska farming area from 1870 through 1932 may be of interest (1) as a sample of the farm mortgage history of the western part of the corn belt, (2) as a contribution to analyzing some of the sources of agricultural credit and the use made of them, (3) as an illustration of the relation of farm mortgages to land and commodity prices, farm income, and banking resources, and (4) as an example of the mortgage problems of corn belt farmers at the present time and m pre - ceding depressions. 4 'The method of this study was outlined, a part of the data assembled, and tabula - tion commenced m 1922 by J. O. Rankin with the aid of field and office workers, under a co-operative agreement with the Divisions of Agricultural Finance and Land Economics of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The study was completed by Eleanor H. Uinman. "The terms are borrowed and the classification adapted from papers by N. J. Wall and M. R. Benedict, m "Research m Agricultural Credit: Scope and Method", Social Science Research Council, Bui. 3, pp. 8-10. New York. 1931. * Holmes, G. X.. and Lord, J. S. Report on Real Estate Mortgages m the United States. Eleventh Census of the U. S., Vol. 13. 1890. Wickens, David L. Farm-Mortgage Credit. Tech. Bui. 288, U. S. Department of Agriculture. 1931. Home Loan Bank Board figures quoted m The United States Daily. Vol. 8. p. 103. Washington. D. C. 1933. 4 For a specific account of contemporary research m this field, the render is referred to the following publications: Benedict, M. It. A Brief Summary of Research m Agricultural Credit. In "Research m Agricultural Credit: Scope and Method", pp. 13-16. Social Science Research Council, Bui. 3, pp. 13-16. New York. 1981. Jacobs. Katharine. A Beginning Bibliography of Agricultural Credit. U. S. Depart - ment »f Agriculture, Bureau of Agricultural Economics. 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 Scope and methods. — Limitations of time and money confined this study to 11 townships. The factors influencing the choice of the townships were (1) accessibility and re - liability of the county mortgage records, (2) the extent to which they are typical of southeastern Nebraska farming conditions, and (3) relative uniformity of soil conditions within the areas studied. Nine townships in York county - were selected which appeared to satisfy these conditions; these were, namely, Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, Mc- Fadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue town - ships. As a check upon the representative character of the data, two other townships were added, Richland precinct in Saunders county and Brush Creek precinct 5 in Saline county. The cover page figure shows the geographic location of these 11 townships. The mortgage data in these townships were obtained from county records of deeds by field workers familiar with the routine of the recorder's offce. A complete mortgage history of each section of land was obtained separately. It was pos - sible from this record to determine the actual duration of every mortgage for which a release was recorded, and the debt carried at the commencement of each year; also to classify the mortgages as indicated in Tables 5-7. and in Figures 5-15. The county records, while they made possible the inclusion in the data of every mortgage filed in the area under con - sideration, had certain limitations. For example, they gave no information on the costs of placing loans, and very little information concerning amortization payments actually made and arrears of interest. Accordingly these topics are of neces - sity omitted from this study. PRELIMINARY SURVEY OF ELEVEN TOWNSHIPS STUDIED Reasons for preliminary survey. — Some consideration of the type of farming, soil types, and historical background in the areas studied is essential to understanding the sort of countryside of which the mortgage conditions to be presented are typical. The relative uniformity of soil types and land values also, is a problem of some importance in evaluating the significance of the averages to be shown, especially in the absence of land value appraisals which were not given in the records. A brief survey of the areas studied is therefore prefaced to the mortgage data. 8 The minor civil divisions in York county are known hs town3hips ; those in Saunders and Saline counties, as precincts. For the purposes of this study, the terms are used interchangeably. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships fit- '•'*)»•■ *j [» "Ajfk — r ■ 1 $Wi $_m% i t ta u, ' ' W^S. $ " i^k 0 ■* n WELL-DRA1N - &lt;&gt;y. 7§vU . Wg^MMl^ VtasMjl W L - ' H&gt; UPLAND 11 ff rV : i E Uf.'JIIM. _ fflfcVte' "W ssjCLAYPAN II (i IT AT?* SPw. 4* B.w &gt; lSl UPLAND i_WSUM- AA!p' : tA!£&gt;*'_\ RICHLAND PRECT. EXCESSIVELY \Wy~~rU ~-**%*? K !jt SAUNDERS CO. LJ DRAINED \" '^AAsflrs* brush creek prect. ■/St-T 1 *^* y '* jZZAz* saline co Fig. 1. — Soil map of the 11 townships studied. Blue k to™«hW h ?r'v Ha r- Hcnde ™° n . McFndden, Morton. New York. Stewart, and West pi«in t ?t W ?n h S P a 8 un3erY 0 c r oun?r y: V™'™* '" SM ™ C ° Unty ; *' ,d RichW Soil types. — The greatest part of the nine York county townships, and also of Richland precinct in Saunders county, as shown in Figure 1, consists of level, or slightly rolling, well-drained upland. The predominant upland soil in York county is Hastings silt loam, one of the best corn-growing soils m the state. That in Richland precinct is Shelby silt loam, somewhat inferior to the Hastings soil under identical moisture conditions ; but two inches more rainfall in Richland precinct approximately offsets the difference. The alluvial soils of the creek bottoms and benches are second in extent and approximately equal to the best upland soils in value. These two types of soils together make up a very large part of the area of the above ten townships. The breaks between upland and valley are gentle, inextensive, and mostly suitable for cultivation. The only soils of pronounced inferiority are the marsh in the southeastern part of Richland precinct, covering approximately one land section ; and the occasional patches of claypan on the York county upland, shown black on the map. The average annual precipitation is 28 inches in York and 30 inches in Saunders county. Brush Creek precinct in Saline county is characterized by an intricate drainage system of small creeks and gulleys flow - ing into Turkey Creek just east of the precinct line. The soil surface is consequently somewhat uneven, but most of the hills have rounded tops and the valleys have gently sloping </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 sides, while many remnants of the old, level upland remain. The well-drained upland and alluvial soils are similar to those in York county. The fairly extensive claypan soils are much more productive than the patches of claypan in York county, because of extensive surface drainage and uncommonly thick top soils. 6 Table 1. — Land in farms, in crops, and in pasture, in 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1929 1 p_-_„_,.„„ Proportion of all farm land in: .. Approximate Proportion ltem land area ,",«£?. Crops Plowable Other Other in isrms harvested pasture pasture land Acres P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. XI townships studied.... 254,880 97.9 76.9 12.S 7.2 3.6 9 York co. townships 207,800 97.7 77.0 12.9 6.6 8.S Baker 23,010 96.8 76.2 15.7 4.5 3.6 Bradshaw 28,040 97.8 78.3 14.2 4.8 2.7 Hoys 28,040 98.1 78.1 7.0 11.9 3.0 Henderson 23,480 99.1 78.6 10.4 7.9 3.1 HcFadden 23,040 98.9 72.3 15.2 8.7 3.8 Morton 23,040 98.6 80.9 10.8 4.6 3.7 New York 23,040 93.6 77.9 15.7 2.8 8.6 Stewart 23,040 98.3 76.8 14.9 5.1 3.2 West Blue..... 23,040 98.9 74.1 13.2 8.6 4.1 Brush Creek, Saline co. 23,040 98.8 77.2 7.2 11.5 4.1 Richland. Saunders co. 23,040 99.0 75.4 10.9 8.4 5.3 Entire counties York 368,800 97.9 77.0 12.7 6.6 3.8 Saline . 366,720 99.5 72.7 10.8 11.1 5.4 Saunders 483,480 95.6 73.6 12.3 8.2 6.0 1 Fifteenth Census of the U. _., 1930. Agriculture. Vol. 1, pp. 391, 392, and 395. Use of land. — Nearly 98 per cent of the land area of the 11 selected townships is in farms, according to the census of 1930. The range is from 94 to 99 per cent in the respective townships, as indicated in Table 1. The land not in farms consists almost entirely of road and railroad rights-of-way and the sites of towns, schools, and other institutions. From 72 to 81 per cent of the farm land in the respective townships was in crops harvested in 1929. From 15 to 24 per cent of the farm land was in pasture, of which more than half was plowable except in Hays and Brush Creek townships. Number, size, and value of farms, 1930. — The total num - ber of farms in the 11 selected townships in 1930 was 1,370. The average size per farm was 181 acres. Morton township had the largest farms, averaging 204 acres, and Richland pre - cinct the smallest, averaging 151 acres. The real estate value per acre ranged from $99 in McFadden township to $143 in 'Hayes, F. A., and Goke. A. W. Soil Survey of York County. Nebraska. U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of the Soil Survey. Series 1928, No. 10. - Hayes, F. A., and Roberts, R. C Soil Survey of Saline County. Ibid.. No. 12. Meyer, A. H., et al. Soil Survey of Saunderj County, /bid. Series 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships Richland precinct; the value per farm from $18,606 in Hays to $25,764 in Morton township. The high value per acre in Richland precinct was due mainly to more improvements per acre on the smaller farms. Table 2. — Size of farms and real estate value in 11 south- eastern Nebraska townships, April 1, 1930 * „ Number Acres Real estate Value per farm of farms per farm val "e Z ; - — per acre Keal Farm Land ■ estate buildings alone J J townships studied 1,370 181.4 $121 S'l 015 t_ 9BK *i7 0i&gt;7 nlker co - town8hip8 1 -?? 2 « M 5 e,-i "« «:•« ':™ *J 8 :ilI KSE* 118 187 " 9 1Z0 22,567 3.677 18 890 Hav t »} ?02.0 114 2 3 :088 5?20 "Jig „ a^ ""•" }21 186.9 100 18.606 2.982 15 624 MeFadkten Ml J22-2 119 22 - 700 3B8fi 19113 Morton \M ll 8 . 2 . " l"- 666 3 - 547 IS" 8 New York JU KM 126 25 - 764 3 - 505 «KtM |£§£z— — : 111 s ! u En , .ir e 8 coun«« nde " " IM ,6, -° " 3 Z1 - 644 «•"• J "&gt;«« SEjL Mg 180.6 120 21.715 3.700 I 18,015 | alln * 2.087 174.8 122 21.398 3.813 I 17.681 Saunders 2,690 171.3 163 26.144 4 758 I 21887 I •Fifteenth Census of the U. S., 1030. Agriculture. Vol. 1. pp. 391. 392, and 395. Summary of the agricultural history of York, Saline, and Saunders counties. — Agricultural data by townships are not given by earlier censuses, but a brief review of the agricul - tural history of the three counties from which mortgage records were obtained forms a necessary background for the consideration of those records. The first permanent settle - ment in the area now known as York county was made in 1865. The county was organized in 1870. In 1871 the Burl - ington railroad entered Saline county and in 1877 another branch of the same road penetrated York county. Imme - diately preceding and following the entrance of the railroad, these counties were settled very rapidly, so that by 1889 practically all the desirable land was filed upon. Saunders county was filled up a little earlier, having some permanent settlements as early as 1858. 7 Table 3 affords a bird's-eye view of the history of the farms in these three counties from 1880 to 1930, as revealed by suc - cessive United States censuses. The facts of particular sig - nificance in relation to farm mortgages mav be summarized as follows: • 'Hays, T.A.. and Goke. A. V. Soil Survey of York County. Nebraska. U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Soil Survey, Scries 1928' No 10 Hsycs, F. A., and Roberts, R. C Soil Survey of Sal.ne County, Nebraska. Ibid.. Meyer, A. H.. et al. Soil Survey of Saunders County, Nebraska. Ibid.. Series 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 10 Table of the agricultural history of York, Saline and Saunders counties, Nebraska, m census years, 1880-1980 Value per farm I Percentage of total crop »rea» Specified number per farm Tenancy IK::::::::::::::::: :,: • ..?!.. g»Sj g » • g X::::::::::::::: i:S : -• = S s ,i S II 2 « ? S Saline county , &#132;, 52 3 38 40 18 7 27 6 8 20 1000 2.220 162 5,4.4 215 6^ J 14 23 ]2 7 ,g 1^:::::::::::::::: « : }• = g !i g 8 12 1 II »f 0 i'Jg }?i 11:111 1:204 MM 36 30 13 10 26 12 6 85 v ■ j # »v- T-inti, Flnvpnih Twelftt Thirteenth, Fourteenth, and Fifteenth Censuses of the United States. .^rS^W a V^rt^^XTueue^ SSSLTS^ .create In </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 11 (1) The number of farms in these counties was about the same in 1880 as in 1930. It increased slightly up to 1900 and decreased slightly thereafter. The average size of the farms tended to increase somewhat throughout the 50-year period. (2) The value of real estate per farm increased enormously from 1880 to 1920, and decreased from 1920 to 1930, most of this decrease having occurred between 1920 and 1925. (3) The value of farm machinery per farm, known only as far back as 1890, showed only small increases up to 1910 ; but by 1920 it had jumped to three or four times the amount for the preceding census year. It decreased a little from 1920 to 1925 and had regained most of this loss by 1930. The great change between 1910 and 1920 represents partly a rise in farm machinery prices and partly a revolution in farming methods — the introduction of tractor farming. Nineteen farmers out of 20 in York county in 1930 owned automobiles, one in four owned a tractor, and three in eight owned sta - tionary gasoline engines. Saline and Saunders counties had as many farms with automobiles as York county and more with tractors and stationary engines. (4) The value of all farm products sold and consumed by the farm family increased greatly, but not so fast as real estate valuations. The total value of York county products per farm was $532 in 1879 and $3,451 in 1920. But the value of these products for every $100 invested in farm real estate was $33 in 1879, not a prosperous year, and only $16 in 1929. The costs of production have not been deducted in either case. (5) The principal crops are corn, wheat, oats, and hay. During the period studied, corn and wheat competed for the greatest proportion of crop acreage, with corn winning first place. in York county in five census years out of seven; in Saline county in three census years out of seven, and in Saunders county in all seven census years. (6) Swine were numerous in all three counties throughout the period studied, but the number per farm showed pro - nounced and irregular variations, doubtless due in part to changes in the month of taking the census. The 1890 census figures on numbers of swine and cattle appear somewhat questionable. Excepting that year, the number of cattle in - creased from 1880 to 1900 in all three counties, and afterward remained constant. The number of horses increased up to 1910, but decreased slightly following the introduction of power-driven machinery. (7) The tenancy percentage was very high from 1900 on - ward, especially in York county. However, tenant and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 12 owner-operated farms were approximately equal m size and real estate value. In 1925, about two-fifths of all farm tenants m each of the three counties were kinsmen of their landlords. Miscellaneous social conditions. — A perusal of the mort - gage records showed that the names of the mortgagors m York and Saunders counties indicate mainly English, Celtic, or German extraction, except for a considerable number of Swedes m the northern townships of York county. Brush Creek precinct m Saline county is predominantly Czech. This had some effect upon the mortgage data from that township, for subsequent to the early developmental period closing about 1895, the Czech farmers borrowed less frequently and less heavily than the other nationalities included m the sample. The farmers' dwellings m the 11 townships studied are for the most part roomy and m fairly good condition. In 1930 they ranged m value from $1 344 per dwelling m Hays town - ship to $2,673 m Richland precinct. Nearly nine out of ten York county farmers had telephones m 1930; three out of ten had piped water into the dwelling, and two out of ten had electric lights. Saline and Saunders county farms did not have quite as many of the above mentioned conveniences. 8 FARM MORTGAGE FILINGS SUMMARY OF FILINGS Number of filings. — Farm mortgage filings m the 11 townships described, began m a small way with four mort - gages filed m 1870 and none m 1871. From this point the number rose rapidly although irregularly to 676 m 1886, a larger number than m any subsequent year. The primary reason for the large number and acreage of mortgage filings from 1880 to 1891 was the need of constructing improvements on the land settled during the preceding decade. Contributory causes were (1) the brisk speculation m eastern Nebraska lands during 1882-92, indicated m Table 8 of this study, and (2) the custom then m vogue of giving a second mortgage to cover the fee of the agent negotiating the first one. Filings continued numerous until 1894, after which there was a sharp ' drop from 540 mortgages filed m that year to 202 m 1896. This drop coincided with the trough of the great economic de - pression which commenced m the summer of 1893. This de - pression, m Nebraska, was rendered more acute by crop fail - ures m 1893 and 1894, and by the free silver agitation of 1896. Recovery was accompanied by slightly increasing mortgage filings from 1897 until 1899, after which the filings declined to only. 115 m 1907. During this period the heavy •Fifteenth Census of the United States: 1980. Agriculture, Vol. 2, part 1, pp. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 13 indebtedness assumed m the eighties and nineties was being liquidated. Farmers were prosperous enough to pay off their old mortgages, but not sufficiently so to tempt them to assume many new ones. The period from 1908 to 1918 was marked by a slight in - crease m the number of mortgages filed. In 1919 and 1920 this increase became rapid, owing to the considerable number of transfers of farm lands encouraged by the very high prices of farm commodities after the war, and to the heavy invest - ments m modern farm machinery and improvements. Late m 1920 the boom collapsed, and the number of mortgage filings decreased until 1922, since which time it has showed pronounced fluctuations, but no clear tendency to increase or to decrease until the years 1931-32 when it dropped sharply. Acreage covered by mortgage filings. — The total number of acres covered by mortgage filings, as revealed by Figure 2 and Table 4, varied directly with the number of mortgages filed. The greatest acreage covered by these filings was 75,298 acres m 1884. Since 1900 the greatest acreage so covered was 27,047 acres m 1920, and the smallest was 12,279 m 1907. The average acreage per mortgage varied little from year to year. Amount of debt assumed. — Over short periods of time, the total debt assumed by mortgage filings m these 11 town - ships corresponded fairly closely with the number and acreage I I | 111111 JITT +~E : h — g-^piy— : — g— B^ffi:; i./|T — ' . ._ , . . . . ' • ! H i- i a. him *i\ \ I -ji tink\hi \\ thiVxshitHisimitihiiSiituiimminiiiiiiiiiUiiimi Fig. 2. — Number, acreage, and amount of the farm mortgages filed dur - ing each year m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1870-1932; and business annals of the United States. The sraphs are based on data presented m Table 4 of this study. The annals are condensed from Thorp, W. L., "Business Annals", pp. 132-135. National Bureau of Economic Research, Monograph 8. New York. 1926. Data for 1927-32 were added from Thorp, W. L., "The Depression as Depicted by Business Annals", News Bui. 43, p. 1. National Bureau of Economic Research. Sept. ID, 1982. Abbreviations ueed: Dep. — depression Pro. — prosperity Rev. — revival Pan. — panic Rcc. — recession SI. — slight </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 14 Table 4. — Mortgage filings in 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1870-1932 l Year Number of Acres Debt Acres per I Average debt filed mortgages mortgaged' assumed mortgage* I Per Per filed \ mortgage acre a 1870 4 480 Tl 1,835 120 $ 459 $~3.82 1872 6 720 3,372 120 562 ' 4.68 1878 11 1,520 5,686 138 517 8.74 1874 28 3.520 11,102 126 897 3.15 1875 55 6.647 24.467 121 446 3.68 1876 89 10,887 34,315 122 386 3.15 1877 94 11.603 32,355 123 844 2.79 1878 161 16.905 54,090 105 836 3.20 1879 162 18,574 58,228 115 859 8.03 1880 810 34.445 107,132 111 847 4.82 1881 844 36,878 118,410 107 344 8.20 1882 452 61,270 221,482 113 490 4.32 1883 624 67,138 290,125 109 554 5.65 1884 661 75,298 378,702 114 573 5.02 1885 593 64,167 311.230 108 625 4.84 1886 676 74,628 423,097 110 626 5.68 1887 467 52,281 317,663 114 696 6.08 1888 397 43,456 336,914 110 849 7.73 1889 494 54,990 416,186 111 840 7.69 1890 422 46,992 376,046 111 889 7.92 1891 460 51,747 439.543 112 l 956 8.44 1892 398 46.973 472,736 118 1,188 9.90 1893 356 44,988 411,255 126 1,165 9.14 1894 640 60,094 489,862 111 907 8.12 1895 441 52,536 398,799 119 904 7.58 1896 202 25,673 178,771 127 885 6.96 1897 228 28,092 215.704 123 946 7.6S '1898 272 35,276 312,804 130 1,150 8.86 1899 284 84,134 346,331 120 1,219 10.14 1900 219 24,945 265,791 114 1,214 10.66 1901 181 22,400 274,806 124 1,518 12.23 1902 152 19.001 261,962 126 1.723 13.7C 1903 163 19,697 281,608 121 1,728 14.27 1904 134 15,046 237,654 112 1,774 15.80 1905 124 13,952 267,220 112 2,155 19.10 1906 148 16,781 863,607 113 2,423 20.37 1907 115 12,279 287,635 107 2,500 23.43 1908 186 16,608 349,321 122 2,569 20.82 1909 133 16,003 421,445 113 • 3,169 28.09 1910 139 16,820 534,961 121 3,849 31.42 1911 131 15,139 541,059 116 4,180 85.05 1912 138 14,692 501,444 106 3,634 33.49 1913 162 17,943 587,981 111 3,630 32.30 1914 155 16,264 633,371 105 3.441 32.41 1915 159 16,711 497,904 105 8,131 29.00 1916 175 18,766 727,123 107 4,155 32.29 1917 178 18.636 957,506 106 6,379 61.08 1918 161 18,215 1,026,460 113 6,376 55.75 1919 204 22,226 1.379.977 109 6,765 60.76 1920 233 27,047 1.739.519 116 7,466 63.11 1921 206 24,038 1,235,166 117 6.996 60.67 1922 184 22,126 1,067.104 120 6,799 46.01 1923 211 25,836 1.203,625 122 5.704 46.24 •Data were obtained for the following townships: In York county — Baker, township 10 N., range 3 W. ; Bradshaw, township 11 N., range 4 W. ; Hays, township 9 N., range S W. ; Henderson, township 9 N„ range 4 W. ; McFadden, township 9 N.. range 2 W. ; Morton, township 12 N., range 3 W. : New York, township 11 N.. range 3 W. : Stewart, township 12 N., range 1 W. ; West Blue, township 9 N., range 1 W. In Saline count}' — Brush Creek, township 6 N., range 3 E. In Saunders county — Richland, township 12 N., range 7 E. ■These acreages must be regarded as approximate becau:e the records reflect a strong tendency to set down acreages in multiples of forty, omitting small parcels of land (railroad rights-of-way, highways, school yards, etc.) excluded from the trans - action. In 101 cases the acreage was neither mentioned nor deducible from the legal description. * Based upon mortgages recording both the number of acres covered and the amount of the debt. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 15 Table 4. — (Concluded). Mortgage filings m 11 southeastern Nebraska to%vnships, 1870-1932 1 Year dumber of Acrc9 j Acrcßpcr Average debt filed m °V£$ Bea mortgaged 3 assumed mortgage" Per 1 Per """ [ mortgage | acre' }924 212 24,402 1.129,677 115 MM 4T41 1925 200 2G.391 1,276.627 127 6,379 60.18 1926 166 19,892 864,764 128 5,643 43.47 1927 161 18.786 875,263 I 117 5.436 46.59 1928 190 22,678 1,001,295 I 120 5.744 47.82 1929 163 19,966 1,063,855 I 119 6.532 52.81 1980 I 207 23.856 1,134,799 ! 113 6,482 47.35 1931 f 162 17.340 712.601 I 107 . 4,399 41.09 1932 I 112 13.307 I 343.287 | 119 3.065 26.80 of the filings. Over long periods of time, this correspondence was disturbed by the long-term trend toward increase m the debt per mortgage and per acre from 1879 to 1920, and toward decrease m the debt per mortgage and per acre from 1921 to 1832. The greatest debt assumed m any year preceding 1900 was $489,862 m 1894, and the greatest m any subsequent year was $1,739,519 m 1920. Debt assumed per mortgage. — The average debt assumed per mortgage filed during the specified year, as shown m Table 4, rose from $459 m 1870 to $562 m 1872, dropped to $336 m 1878, rose unevenly to $1,188 m 1892, dropped to $885 m 1896, rose first gradually and then rapidly to $7,466 m 1920, and since then has declined irregularly to $3,065 m 1932. These alterations were caused by (1) changes m land values, (2) changes m interest rates, and (3) the effects of economic cycles ; all of which will be discussed m later sections of this bulletin. Individual mortgages ranged m amount from as little as $10 during the 1870's to as much as $40,000 m 1920. Debt assumed per acre. — The debt assumed per acre covered by mortgage filings varied correspondingly to the debt assumed per filing. It decreased from $5 m 1872 to $3 m 1874-79; increased to $10 m 1892; dropped to $7 m 1896; in - creased to $63 m 1920 ; and sank to $26 m 1932. These figures are obtained by dividing the total debt for all mortgage filings recording acreage, by the total number of acres recorded, m each respective year. No allowance is made for cases of two or more filings on the same tract. Seasonal variations. — The figures m Table 4 are all yearly totals or averages. In order to interpret their sig - nificance, a brief consideration of seasonal variations is needed. For simplicity and convenience, the data on seasonal variations are grouped m six periods of approximately ten years each: 1870-80, 1881-90, 1891-1900, 1901-10, 1911-20, and 1921-30. The years 1931-32, for which data were ob- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 16 tained after the completion of the rest of the study, are pre - sented separately. The proportion of mortgages filed in the first three months of the year increased steadily from only 21 per cent during 1870-80 to 58 per cent during 1911-20. and then decreased to 48 per cent in 1931-32. The proportion assumed in the next three months was not significantly altered, while that in the last two quarters of the year decreased markedly during the period studied. During the twentieth century decades, the mortgages assumed in the first three months of the year averaged a little larger in amount of debt than those assumed later in the year. The result of the con - centration in the opening three months of the year was that from about 1900 on, the yearly totals and averages shown in Table 4 and succeeding tables, reflected the economic condi - tions during the early part of the year, rather than those at its end. Cyclical variations. — Figure 2 indicates that the relation - ship between the volume of farm mortgage filings studied and the short business cycle, usually of from three to five years' duration, is slight. A relationship is indicated, however, be - tween the mortgage filings and certain severe depressions especially affecting agriculture, notably those commencing in 1873, 1893, 1921, and 1930. The relationship between these depressions and the average indebtedness assumed per filing and per mortgaged acre, as shown in Table 4, was clear and simple : these amounts declined sharply throughout the course of the depression— in 1873-77, 1893-96, 1921-23, and from 1929 to 1932 which is as far as the data extend into the present depression. From the agricultural point of view it is possible to consider the depression commencing in 1929 as a continuation of that commencing in 1920, since agriculture profited very little from the intervening periods of prosperity. The total number and value of mortgage filings tended to be high (1) toward the peak of a prosperous period and (2) occasionally (as during 1894-95 and 1930) just after the com - mencement of a severe depression. There is reason to believe that capital borrowings — that is, loans for the purchase or improvement of real estate — were the chief component of the high prosperity borrowings; while production and consump - tion loans — that is, loans for the purpose of carrying on the farm business and of maintaining the farm family, respective - ly — tended to increase in time of depression. Mortgage filings tended to fall off in number and total value toward the trough of the depression. In 1893 they declined in the year of crisis also; because of financial stringency, creditors could not find the money to lend. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 17 Long-term trends. — The long-term trend of the number and total acreage of mortgage filings was upward from 1870 to 1884, downward from 1885 to 1907, slightly upward from 1908 to 1920, and slightly downward from 1921 to 1932. The principal factors controlling these trends were (1) the volume of land sales m acres, (2) the demand for farm im - provements, (3) the farmers' demand for operating (produc - tion) credit, and (4) the available supply of credit. The total mortgage indebtedness assumed yearly tended upward from 1870 to 1894, dropped sharply m 1895-96, resumed its upward trend from 1897 to 1920, and declined from 1921 to 1932. This trend was affected by the four factors previously mentioned and also by the value of farm land. The debt assumed per mortgage and per acre tended upward from 1879 to 1920 and downward from 1921 to 1932. CLASS OF MORTGAGE FILINGS Method of classifying. — The county records frequently failed to specify the existence or the number of preceding mortgages resting on a tract at the time of a new filing, so that the classifications shown m Figure 3 were obtained by looking up the previous mortgage history of each tract. While a tract was covered by an unreleased first mortgage, a subse - quent mortgage placed upon it was classified as a second mort - gage. If the tract was covered by a first and second mortgage, the next mortgage placed upon it was classified as a third, and so on. Case 3 were found of seven mortgages resting simul - taneously upon the same tract. For convenience, the fifth, sixth, and seventh mortgages are included with the fourth; and wherever the term "fourth mortgages" is used m the following discussion, it will include all higher denominations. Junior mortgages include all classes except first mortgages. 9 Proportion of first and junior mortgages. — More than half the filings were first mortgages m every year except 1896. From 1900 on, more than 70 per cent of the filings were firsts m every year except 1921 and 1922. All the filings were firsts from 1870 to 1873, for the obvious reason that first mortgages must be assumed before second mortgages can be assumed. The proportion of first mortgages decreased • Several possibilities of error m connection with the3e classifications should be noted : (1) Out of 12,218 mortiraccs filed previous to 1920. only 9,826 had releases recorded. The remainder are assumed to have been released at term, unless the subsequent mort - gage hi3tory indicated that they continued longer. (2) During the first forty years studied, the records leave the date when the release was filed but not the date of in - strument. An attempt was made to allow for discrepancies due to this fact. (3) Occasionally release dates were wrongly recorded. This is proved by several cases where the release date (riven m the county records preceded the date of the mort- KaKe . In spite of these possible sources of error, the classifications made m Figure 3 and Table 5 are believed to be substantially correct, and sufficiently valuable to retain m several subsequent tables. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 18 3B|i||||||i n - fII^BBHSP 30"S^I I IWT? 7-f 7a ai B 4 BT OO ttl OS O« 1002 Off Ofl II (4 17 20 23 26 29 Ig3a Fig. 3. — Percentage of the mortgage filings m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships falling m the specified classes (1872-1932). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Bine townships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; ar.d Richland precinct m Saunders county. rapidly to 50 per cent m 1887, rose to 59 per cent m 1892, and fell to a record low of 47 per cent m 1896. One reason for this relatively low proportion of first mortgages m the eighties and nineties was the custom, already remarked, of giving the mortgage broker a second mortgage on the prop - erty m payment of his fee. This custom was due to the des - perate lack of ready money which characterized both the de - velopmental period and the depression of 1893-96. It grad - ually faded out near the beginning of the twentieth century. From about 1890 on, the proportion of first mortgage filings forms a rough barometer of the farmer's credit diffi - culties. When it commences to go down, difficulties may be inferred. It decreased from 1893 to 1896, or from crisis to trough of the depression of the nineties, from 1907 to 1908, from 1919 to 1921, from 1924 to 1926, and from 1930 to 1932, or coincidentally with a depression m each case. It also de - clined m 1912, when the business annals of the United States indicate general business prosperity, but the corn and wheat crop failures of the preceding year probably account for the increase m second mortgages m the 11 townships at this time. 10 The second mortgage borrowings m 1912, although numerous, were comparatively small m amount, so that the percentage of the debt m first mortgages actually showed an increase over the preceding year m spite of the decrease m the relative number of first mortgage filings. The decrease m the proportion of first mortgages sometimes — as m 1893 and "Thorp, W. L. Business Annals. National Bureau of Economic Research, Vol. 8, p. 141. New York. 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 19 Table 5. — Number and class of mortgages filed m 11 south - eastern Nebraska townships, 1870-1932 x „ Class of mortgage 2 Year filed number j Second j Third j Fourth I I I end ever 1870 i 4 4 i j 1872 ,6 6 .. " 1878 , 11 11 1874 28 26 2 1876 56 60 5 .. .. ■ 1876 89 82 7 ... 1877 94 83 11 1878 161 142 18 1 1879 162 129 27 6 1 1480 310 ' 202 99 7 2 1881 344 211 121 11 1 1882 452 282 166 12 2 1883 | 524 294 199 26 5 1884 &gt; 661 345 264 42 10 1885 693 310 220 I 60 13 1H66 i 676 358 237 66 16 1887 457 230 163 60 I 14 1888 397 219 136 37 6 1839 494 269 162 46 17 1890 422 229 133 50 10 1891 460 26S 142 44 ■ I 11 1892 398 236 113 36 13 1093 356 206 106 34 ; 10 1394 540 801 180 46 13 1895 441 244 129 43 25 1896 202 95 69 25 13 1897 228 131 69 21 7 18118 272 170 80 16 7 1899 284 191 73 17 3 1900 219 161 46 8 5 1901 181 131 39 9 2 1902 162 115 31 5 1 1903 163 126 28 8 1 1904 134 105 26 1 2 1905 124 102 19 2 1 1906 148 131 14 2 1 1907 116 97 17 1 1908 136 106 26 4 1909 133 112 17 4 1910 139 117 19 3 1911 131 112 16 3 . 1912 138 109 26 3 1913 162 128 85 4 1914 165 126 26 3 1915 159 123 24 7 6 1916 176 147 22 2 4 1917 178 148 28 1 1 1918 161 138 20 8 1919 204 160 42 2 1920 238 174 49 10 1921 206 189 63 11 3 1922 184 128 41 14 1 1923 211 161 38 10 2 1924 212 166 46 10 1 1925 200 146 44 7 3 1926 166 110 84 7 6 1927 161 125 30 6 •• 1928 190 146 36 6 3 1929 168 145 20 2 1 1930 207 166 34 6 1 1331 162 126 81 3 2 63-year 93 1 2 otal 14.630 JUSI7 3^916 854 243 &gt; Baker Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden, Morton, New' York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; and BiC Vrhe wOTas Ct rarely a BPec e i™ed C&lt; tho type of mortgHge. While a tract was covered by an unreleased first mortgage, any other mortgage placed upon it was classified as a second mortgage, and so on for third, fourth, and other mortgages. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 20 1919 — commenced just before the crisis. Before 1890, all correspondence of this index to the economic cycle was over- Whelmed by the financial turmoil of the eras of settlement (1870-80) and development (1881-90). The relative decrease m the proportion of first mortgages during 1930-32 was less than might be expected from the seriousness of the depression m those years, probably because small loans during the past decade have been financed increasingly by chattel mortgages m place of junior real estate mortgages. The greatest proportion of second mortgages to all filings was 40 per cent m 1884. Since 1900, the greatest proportion of second mortgages was 26 per cent m 1921, and the smallest was 9 per cent m 1906. Third mortgages accounted for only from zero to 12 per cent of the filings. Fourth mortgages were usually an insignificant proportion of the total filings but rose as high as 6 per cent m 1895 and 1896. Acreage covered by first and junior mortgage filings. — The percentage ratio of the acreage covered by first mortgage filings to that covered by all filings, was slightly lower m most years than the ratio of the number of first mortgage filings to the total number of filings. This was because a farmer wish - ing to borrow a considerable sum on the security of a first mortgage, often found it difficult to obtain the whole amount from a single lender. Accordingly he would borrow from two or more sources and give each creditor a first mortgage on some fraction of his farm. Second mortgages, being com - monly for smaller amounts, were less I often split up as de - 3°~^B I M rin 3T MORTGAGES E%3SCCONO MORTGAGES loStE^I I I^/JTHIHO MORTGAGES BmHapfl Fig. 4. — Percentage distribution, by the specified classes, of the farm mortgage debt assumed yearly m 11 southeastern Nebraska town - ships (1872-1932). Baker. Bradshaw Hays, Henderson, McFad.lcn, Morton. New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships In York county : Brush Creek precinct In Saline county : and Richland precinct m Saundcn county. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 21 scribed. With this exception, the proportion of the acreage covered by first mortgages corresponded rather closely to the proportion of first mortgages to all filings. Debt assumed by first and junior mortgage filings. — The percentage ratio of the amount of debt assumed by first mort - gage filings to the total mortgage debt assumed, as shown in Figure 4, was larger in nearly all years than the ratio of first mortgages to all mortgage filings, as shown in Figure 3. This difference was pronounced from about 1880 to about 1900, but became gradually less after that. The proportion of first to all mortgage debt assumed, had troughs in 1885, 1888, 1896, 1904, 1908, 1913, and 1922, or coincidentally with a depression in each case. It also showed dips in 1879, 1900, and 1925, when either revival or prosperity was indicated by the busi - ness annals. 11 It remained fairly high in 1930-32, probably because of the substitution of chattel mortgage loans for junior mortgages. Debt per mortgage, for various classes of mortgage filings. — The debt assumed per first mortgage filing tended downward at the beginning of the period studied, from $562 in 1872 to $323 in 1878. With 1879, the long-term trend be - gan upward, which finally carried this amount to $8,131 in 1920. From 1921 on, the debt assumed per mortgage grad - ually decreased. Peaks occurred in 1872, 1884, 1892, 1899, 1903, 1911, 1920, 1923. 1925, and 1929. Eight of these ten peaks, or all except those in 1894 and 1911, coincided with the peak year of a short business cycle. Troughs occurred in 1878, 1885, 1895-96, 1900, 1904, 1915, 1922, 1924, and 1932, coinci - dentally with a depression or recession in every year except 1915, a year when farmers found it hard to borrow because the boom in war industries was absorbing most of the avail - able credit, and 1922, which was a depression year for Ne - braska although recovery had started in industrial districts of the nation. The debt assumed per second mortgage showed long-term trends similar to those for first mortgages, but varied from the latter in the following ways: (1) It was less than the debt assumed per first mortgage in every year from 1879 to date. This difference was especially pronounced in the eighties and nineties because of the inclusion of many small commission mortgages. (2) It appeared much less regular, mainly because of the smaller statistical basis. (3) The cor - respondence to the economic cycle was much less than in the case of debt assumed per first mortgage. The annual mort - gage debt assumed per acre increased near the trough of cer - •* Thorp, W. L. Business Annals. National Bureau of Economic Research, Vol. 8, pp. 133, 138, and 146. New York. 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 22 rmTMircMttr ■ :======Z=Z AiF » j if-ii flr — - S MIUOI OCO-\ _^ I *■— »"J [_|^ TTT • • _!l. ; L. I Si i 3 »£ hiSi! Id IS slit I S.ilf »{ |«J » Fig. 5. — Debt assumed per acre covered by mortpaßes filed during each year, m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1870-1932), and busi - ness annals of the United States. The graphs are baaed on data presented m Table 6 of this study. The annals are re - peated from Figure 2. tain depressions, namely, m 1876, 1896, and 1922. This prob - ably represents an increase m borrowings for production and family consumption normally financed from profits of pre - ceding years. The debt assumed per third and fourth mortgage was vari - able m amount and rested on a scanty numerical basis. Third mortgages commonly averaged somewhere between first and second m amount, but were frequently less than either, and rarely more than either. Fourth mortgages commonly aver - aged less than either first or second mortgages m amount, but were occasionally more than second. Debt per acre. — The first mortgage debt assumed per acre, as shown m Figure 5 and Table 6, decreased from nearly $5 m 1872 to $3 m 1876-79, increased by degrees to $75 m 1920, and decreased to $30 m 1932. The cyclical variations were similar m direction and degree to those of the debt assumed per first mortgage. The second mortgage debt per acre fell as low as 95 cents m 1881 and rose to nearly $50 ill 1919. While the average amounts of debt assumed m 1919 and 1920 doubtless seemed conservative when land m these 11 townships was appraised at about $200 an acre, it will readily </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 23 Table 6. — Debt assumed per mortgage and per acre, by class of mortgage, m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1870-1982 » Year I Debt per mortgage Debt per *ere » ""* I First [Second | Third | .^r First | Second | Third | .ffg^ 1870 $ 459* S 3 82* I I 1872 662* 4.68* ....Z '.. ~.Z. 1878 517 8.74 1874 400 $ 857* 3.25 S 2.23* 1876 465 289* 3 93 1 66' 1876 878 688* 3 13 8.85* 1877 342 868 2.77 2.98 1878 323 422 $ 622* 3.12 3.85 * 4.01* 1879 374 281 808* $ 838* 3.12 2.65 1 2.40* $10.48* 1880 405 149 366* 146* 4.01 1.30 I 2.66* 0.78* 1881 489 103 203 600* 4.52 0.95 I 1.64 , 6.26* 1882 653 172 727 937* 5.72 1.67 I 6.30 , 4.89* 1888 80S 198 603 290* 7.37 1.80 | 4.19 | 2.67* 1884 847 214 696 510 7.51 1.88 I 5.10 - 3.27* 1885 748 206 600 724 7.16 1.87 | 4.1C \ 6.1S 1886 911 206 698 I 681 8.40 1.88 I 6.07 ! 4.54 1887 1.028 239 701 618 9.02 2.18 | 6.33 , 4.12 1888 1.089 469 817 905* 10.10 4.13 I 7.71 , B.oB* 1889 1.098 822 1,171 814 9.42 2.87 I 8.98 , 6.41 1890 1,201 410 801 560 10.42 3.77 I 7.40 5.00 1891 1,280 489 524 960 11.32 4.36 | 4.36 . 7.76 1892 1.496 691 929 053 12.66 5.70 7.45 . 5.62 1893 1.410 764 1,058 396* 11.58 5.67 8.26 ! 3.10* 1894 1,169 671 666 | 702 10.68 6.03 4.96 ; 5.11 1895 1.157 51-2 626 576 9.94 5.02 4.73 . 4.09 1896 1,168 693 467 712 1 9.38 5.18 3.69 | 6.94 1897 1,230 686 662 336* 10.28 4.37 4.47 i 5.23* 1898 1.468 564 917 728* 12.09 4.01 5.64 &gt; 4.58* 1899 1,526 676 618 767* 12.91 4.74 4.63 6.75* 1900 1,804 766 1,679* 1,688* 12.03 6.26 11.10* 10.05* 1901 1,814 763 784* 181* 14.95 5.76 6.08* i 1.51* 1902 1,927 1,129 770* 1,600* 15.89 8.72 4.lS* I 9.38* 1908 1,978 802 1,276* 400* 16.92 7.68 10.63* i 2.50* 1904 1,907 1,408 180* 423* 17.16 12.26 o.Bl* ! 3.53* 1906 2,880 1,317 950* 2,617* 20.16 13.35 11.88* I 16.36* 1906 2,543 1,826 2,950* I,ooo* 21.64 11.82 18.44* ! 6.00* 1907 2,742 1,240 700* 25.15 12.96 8.75* | 1908 2,774 1,728 2,500* 23.05 12.91 19.85* | 1909 8,296 2,466 2.650* 29.61 21.14 16.56* I 1910 8,896 2,875 8,214* I 32.06 28.45 51.66* I 1911 4,266 3.669 2.419 36.94 26.96 18.16* I 1912 4,111 1,847 1.767* I 36.49 19.46 1 18.93* I 1918 8.916 2,884 1,775* I 35.68 28.37 I 17.76* I 1914 8.585 2,812 1,988* 36.04 25 28 10.65* 1915 8,485 2,317 I.BBo* 1,384* 33.25 19.12 I 17.85* I 8.34* 1916 4,828 8.666 4,850* I,ooo* 40.74 28.98 88.69* ! 10.00* 1917 6,881 3,040 1,600* 450* 66.18 27.49 18.76* ! 6.63* 1918 6,609 6.893 2,200* , 59.87 40.24 18.33* I 1919 6.888 .6,440 2,760* t 65.21 49.63 22.92* \ 1920 8,181 6,144 7,264 74.54 41.44 29.24 ; 1921 6,028 4,046 4,482 2,783* 67.24 86.04 39.76 20.87* 1922 6949 4 967 7,168 2,000* 60.87 35.90 40.76 \ 12.60* 1928 6,142 4,166 6,245 2,000* 52.65 81.07 29.65 i 10.00* 1924 5659 4 838 4 487 426* 61.47 88.60 28.76 ■ 3.27* 1925 6421 6,226 6.164 7,017* 64.64 42.87 48.95* I 21.93* 1926 6948 4 216 4.269* 7,461* 61.99 28.28 27.08* I 32.16* 1927 6 068 8.845 2.748* 68.85 27.12 16.46* I 1928 6,804 8,796 5.460* 2.812* 66.04 27.23 .28.44* 17.84* 1829 6468 4.929 7 400* 14.040* 56.42 40.40 30.88* 43.88* 1930 5968 8.911 I 1,836* I.ooo* 61.85 84.48 13.11* I 8.83* 1931 4746 8.298 I 867* 4,960* 47.11 24.29 9.28* I 61.88* 1982 8.880 1.'840 I 2.460* 29.74 13.79 16.62* I 1 Baker Bradshaw, Hays. Henderson. HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county ; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county ; and Rich - land precinct m Saanders county. * Based on mortgages recording both acreage and debt. * Average based on less than ten mortgage records. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 24 be understood that farmers who had first, second, and third mortgages outstanding m these years to the amounts indi - cated m Table 6, found themselves m serious difficulties when land values fell to approximately $130 m 1925 and $120 m 1930. INTEREST RATES Average interest rate per filing. — The average interest rate per mortgage filing, as shown m Figure 6, tended down - ward from nearly 11 per cent m 1870-77 to a little more than 5 per cent m 1906, 1916-18, and 1929-30. This decline was %|IIIiIIIIiI I I I I I I I I I I* ii ii iq — I __j L_ o I I— H ua ja_ cyL j » i T2Ts t« *i m •? «o m m m m* es &lt;• ii m n » o a t» mi Fig. 6. — Interest rate per mortgage of the specified class, m 11 south - eastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). Based on data presented more fully m Table 7. "All filings" includes third and fourth mortEageo as well as firsts and seconds. especially rapid during 1878-81, 1897-1902, and 1922-23, or m the years of recovery following certain severe depressions. The chief cause of the general decline m interest rates was the growth of American capital available for mortgage in - vestment. Contributing causes were (1) improved security of Nebraska farms due to better transportation, improved farming methods, and the development of improved crop and livestock strains, and (2) improved facilities for placing and handling farm mortgage loans. The only conspicuous increase m average interest rate which took place during the 63-year period was that from 5.2 per cent m 1917 to 6.6 per cent m 1921^ This increase began m 1918, the last year of the war, continued throughout the post-war boom period, and reached its peak m the depression year 1921. No other economic cycle covered by the period under consideration showed as pronounced a correspondence with the interest rate graph. Slight increases took place from 1893 to 1896, from 1906 to 1908, and from 1913 to 1915, or coincidentally with the depressions commencing m 1893, 1907, and 1913; but these were due principally to the increase m the proportion of junior mortgages, which has already been </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 25 Table 7. —Average interest rate per mortgage, by class of mortgage, m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1870 - -1932 l Year filed IH Clas. of mortgage ~ mortgages I I Fourth First I Second I Third I and more 1870 10.5* uTE* ~ i '. 1872 10.6* 10.5* ... . i 187S 10.5* 10.5* ! 1874 10.0 11.0 10.0* ...... \ 1875 10.7 10.8 10.5* | . ! 1876 10.6 10.6 10.8* I 1877 10.5 10.6 10.3 I 1878 10.2 10.1 10.6 10.0* 1879 9.9 9.9 10.0 | 10.2* 10.0* 1880 9.1 8.8 9.7 I 9.0» I 10.0* 1831 8.7 8.0 9.8 9.9 B.o* 1882 8.5 7.8 9.8 9.2 I B.o* 1883 8.5 7.7 9.7 9.6 9.8* 1884 8.3 7.1 9.8 9.4 9.4* 1885 8.6 7.4 9.8 9.2 9.5 1886 8.2 ' 7.1 9.6 9.3 I 9.8 1887 8.1 6.7 9.7 9.1 I 10.0 1888 8.0 6.9 9.4 9.3 I 9.7* 1889 7.9 6.8 9.6 9.1 9.0 1890 7.8 6.7 £&gt;.6 8.8 8.7* 1891 7.8 6.9 9.1 9.2 I 9.5 1892 7.8 7.0 9.2 8.9 I 8.8 1893 7.8 7.0 9.0 ' 8.8 • 8.8 1894 7.9 7.0 9.2 9.1 9.4 1895 7.9 7.0 9.0 9.4 ! 10.0 1896 8.1 7.0 9.0 9.1 I 9.5 1897 8.0 7.1 9.2 9.4 I 10.0* 1898 7.5 6.6 9.0 8.7 10.0* 1899 6.5 5.6 8.4 8.4 7.5* 1900 6.3 6.7 8.2 8.2* 7.8* 1901 6.1 5.5 7.4 8.3* 8.3* 1902 6.8 6.4 7.3 7.2* I B.o* 1903 6.8 5.2 7.8 7.«* I B.o* 1904 5.7 6.2 7.3 | 10.0* I 7.6* 1905 5.4 5.2 6.6 I 6.8* 1906 6.2 6.1 6.0 I 6.0* 6.0* 1907 5.6 6.3 7.1 5.0* I 1908 6.6 5.4 6.8 5.7* ! 1909 6.5 5.3 6.2 7.1* 1910 6.6 5.3 6.9 6.0* I , 1911 6.6 6.6 6.0 7.0* ] 1912 5.6 5.8 6.6 6.0* 1913 5.6 6.3 6.C 6.4* 1914 5.7 6.5 6.4 6.7* 1915 5.8 5.4 7.0 7.1* 7.8* 1916 5.3 6.1 6.4 7.0* 7.2* 1917 6.2 6.0 6.1 B.o* I B.o* 1918 6.8 5.2 6.1 6.7* I 1919 6.6 6.4 6.4 6.5* I 1920 5.9 6.6 6.6 B.l* I ...... 1921 6.6 6.1 7.6 7.8 9.0* 1922 6.2 6.0 6.7 7.2 ! 7.0* 1923 6.6 6.2 6.2 7.6* 7.6* 1924 6.7 6.4 6.5 6.9* 10.0* 1926 6.4 5.2 6.9 6.3* 7.7* 1926 5.6 5.2 6.6 7.8* 6.8* 1927 5.6 6.2 6.6 6.8* W2B 6.4 5.0 6.2 7.2* 7.0* 1929 6.3 6.1 6.2 7.0* 6.0* 1930 6.8 6.2 6.8 6.4* B.o* 1931 5.4 6.2 6.3 6.0* B.o* 1982 6* SJI 6^2 5.7* I ti simple average —the sum of the interest rates for the year was divided by the number of mortgages recording the interest rate. The Utter totaled 13.871 mortgages distributed by year and class approximately as shown m Table 2. The townships are: Baker. Bradshaw, Have. Henderson. HcFadden. Morton, Now York, Stewart, and West Blue m York county; Brush Creek m Saline county; and Richland m Saunders county. * Average based on less than ten mortgage records. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebe. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 26 described. Although rates on farm mortgages in the 11 town - ships rose sharply during the period of expansion and subse - quent depression in 1918-21, they rose scarcely at all during the expansion of 1927-29, and very little during the subsequent deflation up to the end of 1932. The fall in average interest rate from 10.9 per cent in 1874 to 5.2 per cent in 1917 was no doubt a factor in the increase in mortgage indebtedness assumed between these years, as shown in Tables 4 and 6 of this study. The same interest rate payment will serve for twice as large a debt at 5 per cent as at IO 1 per cent. Under these circumstances farmers are likely to assume much heavier obligations per mortgage at the lower rate. The debt increase, however, was much greater abso - lutely and per mortgage than can be accounted for on this ground alone. Also, rising interest rates in 1918-21 failed to check the increase in debt assumed per mortgage until 1921. Falling interest rates from 1922 to 1929 failed to produce material increase in the debt assumed per mortgage. Interest rate and class of mortgage. — First mortgages bore interest rates conspicuously lower than any other class of mortgage in all years subsequent to the chaotic seventies. 12 This difference, of course, is due mainly to the greater security of first mortgages. The greatest difference between first and second mortgage rates was in 1887, when the former averaged 6.7 and the latter 9.7 per cent. Since then the gap between them has decreased, until, in 1930, it was only from 5.2 to 5.8 per cent. The average interest rates per third and fourth mortgage were so irregular and based on so few instances that they have been omitted from Figure 6. In general, third mortgage interest rates were below second mortgage rates up to about 1908 and above them in most years after this. Fourth mortgage interest rates were generally above second mortgage rates, especially after 1900. Distribution, by interest rate groups. — The interest rate varied from zero — probably on certain loans between friends or relatives — to 12 per cent in years preceding 1882. From 1882 on, no farm mortgage loans in the area studied bore more than 10 per cent interest. Mortgages were strongly concentrated on a few rates, namely, 5, 5y_, 6, 6y_, 7, 8, 10, and 12 per cent. Rates bearing fractions, except 5% and 6V2» "The apparent exception afforded by fourth mortgages in 1881 and third mortgages in 1907 and 1910 was due to the very small number, of third and fourth mortgages in those years, which, furthermore, may have included unavoidable errors in the classifica - tion of the mortgages. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 27 tf ISMTa « (M il ' SO. 3 M M J«02 M M 111417 20 a 2S M li? INTEREST KS»«X'NTe«SnS3| N TD«£3T S^INTOUST Fig. 7. — Percentage distribution of mortgage filings, by interest rate, in 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). 1 1 Baker, Bradshaw. Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships in York county : Brush Creek precinct in Saline county ; and Rich - land precinct in Saunders county. The figure is based on 13,871 mortgages recording the Interest rate and distributed by class and year of filing approximately as shown in Table 5. 'The 5.0-6.9 per cent interval has been split as indicated in order to show the pre - ponderance of a flat 6 per cent interest rate after 1898. were uncommon; and none of these were higher than 8V». Figure 7 shows by years the percentage of first and other mortgage loans bearing (1) less than 5 per cent interest, (2) a flat rate of 5 per cent, (3) more than 5 and less than 7 per cent, (4) 7 and less than 9 per cent, (5) 9 and 10 per cent, and (6) 11 and 12 per cent. Mortgages bearing less than 5 per cent interest formed an insignificant proportion of either first or second mortgages in all years studied. Equal interval groups may be obtained, if desired, by combining the second and third groups, giving 5 and less than 7 per cent; but the group has been split in Figure 7 to show the predominance of a flat 5 per cent interest rate after 1899. This was the commonest rate for the first mortgages during 1899-1910, 1912-18, 1923, and 1925-31. As high as about nine-tenths of the first mortgages filed in 1906 and 1917 bore 5 per cent in - terest, and nineteen-twentieths of those filed in 1928. More than 5 and less than 7 per cent was the commonest interest rate group for first mortgages from 1887 to 1898 and also during 1911, 1919-22, 1924, and 1932. First mortgages bear - ing 7 and less than 9 per cent predominated from 1881 to 1886, those bearing 9 and 10 per cent in 1870-73 and 1875-80, while 11 and 12 per cent was the dominant group for first mortgages in one year, 1874. Slightly lower percentages of the debt than of the number of filings usually fell in the in- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 28 terest rate groups above the mode, and slightly higher per - centages m the groups below the mode. This was because the smaller debts commonly bore somewhat higher interest rates than the larger debts. Junior mortgages fell more frequently into the upper in - terest rate groups. The 9 and 10 per cent group was the mode (the group containing more of the mortgages than any other) from 1874 clear up to 1900, and again m 1903. AMOUNT OF DEBT AND INTEREST RATE i{|72 7-S 7fi 91 ft"T 9O 93 99 99 1908 OJ 09 11 V 417 20 23 ? r a J932 3^ Mt% pyj^ yy^K ijuY/ vjvv pc/Tr jrffij BSS j**^ BUHOtK JljOOO*" 0 *1.000-*4.W» &lt;&amp;~ ffl *S,OOO-U.m □VoOOANOOVtM Fig. 8. — Proportion of all first and junior mortgage filings m the specified value groups m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872 - ----■ 1932). 1 1 Baker, Brndshaw, Hays, Henderson, HcFodden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county ; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county ; and Rich - land precinct m Saundera county. The figure is based on 14,630 mortice records dis - tributed by class and year of filing as shown m Table 5. 'The $1-9,999 interval has been split as indicated above m order to show the pre - ponderance of mortgages under $1,000 m amount m the earlier years. Distribution by amount of debt. — First mortgages of less than $1,000 were the commonest filed from 1870 to 1889, in - cluding as high as 99 per cent of all first mortgage filings m 1878 (Fig. 8). They decreased m importance rather steadily, except during 1893-95, and from. 1907 onward formed a small proportion of first mortgage filings — never more than 8 per cent. First mortgages of from $1,000 to $4,999 formed the commonest value group during 1890-94, 1897-1917, and several subsequent years, notably 1930-32. During 1919-20 and several subsequent years, mortgages of from $5,000 to $9,999 comprised the mode or commonest value group of first mortgages. First mortgages of $10,000 or more formed an inconspicuous proportion of the total before 1917, but in - creased to 30 per cent m 1920, after which they decreased </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 29 again to 2 per cent m 1932. Junior mortgages showed a larger proportion under $1,000 and a smaller proportion over $5,000 than first mortgages. Average interest rates of mortgages of varied amounts. — First mortgages of less than $1,000 bore higher average in - terest rates than first mortgages of larger amounts, as indi - cated m Figure 9, m 44 out of the 61 comparable years. First mortgages of $5,000 and more bore the lowest interest rates ft— AS 7» «l »4 «T &gt;O »» — — ItOt M M II B 17 ID 21 II » HOI J |G- , A XSSH =** - -0 gr. ; cnft laM kirmw' ]jj 3j 1 2 9 Jt uu »»»^i^ft B p c w^^^^j-pte^ _qpjyjQ2_p^LDii_J g5 4 *£ !2°i ••&gt; 95E I. 4 * I 2 1*72 IS 7S SI 84 87 90 93 W 99 1902 05 OB II 14 IT 2D 21 JO 2t~t9X? Fig. 9. — Interest rate per mortgage for first and junior mortgages m the specified value groups, m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872 - ----1932). Baker, Bradshnw, Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart and West Blue townships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; and Richland precinct m Saundcrs county. The ficure is based on 13, 871 mortcages recording in - terest and distributed by class and year of filing approximately as shown m Table 6. of any value group m 28 years out of 44 m which any such mortgages were filed, and tied with the lowest m six more years. Were it not for the very small number of mortgages of $5,000 or more before 1906, and the very small number of mortgages of less than $1,000 after 1906, the tendency for interest rates to decrease as the amount of the mortgage in - creased would probably be more evidenced than it appears m Figure 9. Junior mortgages of each respective value group bore higher average interest rates than first mortgages of the same value group m 51 out of 59 years m which any junior mort - gages were filed. The eight exceptions were due to a small numerical basis — less than ten mortgage records — for one or other of the average interest rates compared. Junior mort - gages of less than $1,000 bore the highest interest rates of </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 30 any value groups of junior mortgages m 45 years out of 53 m which any such comparison could be made. Junior mort - gages of $5,000 and more bore the lowest interest rates m 24 years out of 34 m which any such mortgages were filed. A part of the variation m average interest rate per mort - gage shown m Figure 6 accordingly is due to changes m the distribution of mortgage filings by value group. The slight increase m interest rate per mortgage during the depressions of 1893-96 and 1913-14 was due principally to the accomp - anying increase m the proportion of smaller loans, indicated m Figure 8. This statement, however, does not apply to the depressions of 1907-08 and 1920-21. DURATION OF MORTGAGES Proposed and actual duration.- — The proposed duration of a mortgage is the period from the assumption of the mort - gage until the date when final repayment of the debt is due. The actual duration is the period from the assumption of the mortgage until its release. The proposed duration is empha - sized m this discussion of filings because it has more connec - tion with the conditions upon which the mortgage is nego - tiated. The actual duration is affected, m addition to con - siderations influencing the terms of the loan, by (1) variations m agricultural income during the life of the mortgage, (2) the managerial ability of the mortgagor, and (3) the relative ease or difficulty of refinancing such mortgages as cannot be paid when due. In individual instances a great deal of variation was found between actual and proposed duration. Some mortgages were paid off or refinanced long before they were due, while others continued to run for many years after their legal term. Average duration per mortgage. — Figure 10 presents, by years, the proposed and actual duration per first and junior mortgage, for all filings indicating duration, except 128 long - term amortized mortgages, payable m from 20 to 40 years. The inclusion of a few sporadic examples of extreme range would have confused the averages; therefore, the entire 128 examples of this class were omitted from Figure 10. In addi - tion, 366 mortgages were omitted from the figures for pro - posed duration because of insufficient data. These included a few mortgages payable on demand, a few payable at someone's death, and the remainder payable according to the terms of prpmissory notes not included m the record. Two thousand eight hundred ninety-eight mortgages without release records, including many still m force, were omitted from the figures for. actual duration. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 31 art 7 t» «i »4 «t »o &gt;&gt;»&gt;»» no; ojoan v n 20 n t« tt mx M &#132; p _«£ ["»! _«* "5 t=i I n 68 ""I• f - * *-j ~" ! r-, I&gt;l - * xXdfW 1r- ■ KT\i- j-i. 9 § '■bo &gt;O3« &gt; ou iatk h 1 -•n ,2 lIIII|nIIIII I I I I I I I I 184I 84 71 ~ I F[" fT; ~ ~f» jpos mo Sat sfi= "^ J n Ism * ' I " tma bsy 5H5 m i 6 IP * ■2 i a ■1111111111 I I I I I II I [ »"7J 71 • U IT H U « X 1902 OS 08 II 14 IT 20 23 2« 29 IW2 Fig. 10. — Average duration of first and junior mortgages m 11 south - eastern Nebraska townships, by year of filing (1872-1932). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFaddcn, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Biue townships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; and Richland precinct m Saundera county. The averages are based upon 14,126 cases which re - corded the proposed duration and 11,620 cases which recorded the actual duration, dis - tributed by class and year approximately as m Table 6. Demand loans are omitted; likewise amortized mortgages of more than 20 yeers' proposed duration lire omitted. Average actual duration is omitted for the years 1021-32 because a large proportion of the mortgages filed during these years are still m force. The proposed duration increased from about two years for first mortgages assumed m 1873 to nearly five years for those assumed m 1880. It hovered between four and five years from 1880 to 1893, and about five years from 1894 to 1932. The longest proposed durations — about five and one-half years — were during 1898-99, 1917, and 1919, all years of prosperity or revival marked by increased mortgage filings. The pro - posed duration of first mortgages decreased conspicuously m certain years of severe depression, namely 1873-74, 1896, and 1921-22. In certain other depression years, however, such as 1907 and 1930-32, the decrease was very slight. The actual duration of first mortgages was longer than the proposed duration of mortgages assumed m all years from 1885 to 1896, while from 1897 to. 1919 it was shorter than the proposed duration m all years except 1914. In general, it was evidently easier to refinance mortgages during the past 30 years than it had been during 1885-96, because of the greater supply of capital available and more efficient agencies for the handling of such loans. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebe. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 32 The actuai duration per first mortgage was conspicuously high for mortgages filed during 1873, 1891-95, and 1919-20. In other words, mortgages filed immediately preceding a severe depression tended to remain on the books until better times. During such depressions, diminished farm incomes made it impossible for many debtors to repay their mortgage obligations when due, while contracted agricultural credit made it difficult to refinance them. At the same time, creditors hesitated to foreclose because there was a very poor sale for farm land. The actual duration of the mortgages filed during 1921-32 is omitted because a considerable proportion of such mortgages are still m force. Junior mortgages were usually for shorter terms than first mortgages, except m 1875 and 1880. As shown at the top of Figure 10 the proposed duration of the junior mortgages de - creased from five years m 1880 to only a little more than two years m 1897. The very short term — less than three years of the junior mortgages filed from 1891 to 1897 is a conspic - uous feature of this period. It was probably due to (1) the financial uncertainties of the period which made creditors re - luctant to lend for long periods and (2) to a probable increase m mortgage loans for the purposes of farm operation and family consumption. The proposed duration of junior mort - gages jumped to nearly five years m 1898 and then slowly de - creased. From 1900 to 1919 it varied between two and one - half and four and one-half years ; from 1920 to 1932, between two and one-half and three and one-half years. This graph was much less regular than that for first mortgages, probably because of the smaller numerical basis and more heterogeneous composition of the class. The actual duration of junior mortgages filed during 1875 - -97 was longer than the proposed duration, especially m the depression years 1875-76, 1885-86, and 1894-96. For mort - gages filed m the 23 years from 1898 to 1920, the actual dura - tion was shorter than the proposed duration m 17 years and longer m six years. Distribution of mortgages by proposed duration. — Five years was much the commonest proposed duration for first mortgages filed m all years subsequent to 1875. From 53 to 88 per cent of all first mortgage filings m these years, as shown m Figure 11, were assumed for five years plus or minus two months (58-62 months). This should not be interpreted to mean that all these mortgages were assumed m the antici - pation that they would be paid off m five years. Many of such loans represented capital borrowings which required a much longer period for liquidation. The high percentage of </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 33 five-year mortgages simply represents a preference on the part of borrowers and lenders to renew the loan from time to time rather than to sign obligations binding for much longer periods. The debtor expects to profit by this arrangement because interest rates have, m general, been falling, and he is ordinarily able to refinance his debt at a lower rate. The creditor usually prefers to keep his loan as liquid as possible. n»» n « *• tmummimboso* mw n 20 23 a« » I*l2 BUNOEBI2MOS. QU-IIUOS. 03S-57M03. [gjO-MMOS. (jJeSMOStMOBE Fig. 11. — Percentage distribution of first and junior mortgages by dura - tion groups m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson. HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county: Brush Creek precinct m Saline county : and Richland precinct m Saunders county. The figure is based on 14,260 mortgages which indicated the proposed duration, including amortized mortgages of more than 20 years' duration. During a period of financial stringency, however, the system of five-year renewals may work great hardships on some debtors who suddenly find it is impossible either to renew their obligations to their present creditors or to transfer them to new lenders, and on some creditors who find they must either foreclose on a buyers' market or wait until better times for repayment. First mortgages of less than 12 months' duration formed an insignificant proportion of the total from 1880 to the present. Mortgages of from 12 to 33 months' duration were of the commonest length filed during 1870 and 1873-75, but after 1880 they were of minor importance. Mortgages of from 34 to 57 months' duration were of the commonest length' filed m one year, 1872 ; but m subsequent years they comprised from one to 20 per cent of the filings. First mortgages of 63 months or more m duration comprised from 2 to 24 per cent of the filings subsequent to 1878. The increase m mortgages of 63 months and more after 1922 was due wholly to an increase m amortized mortgages of more than 20 years' duration, which </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 34 are included m Figure 11. Such mortgages, first recorded m 1918, rose to 17 per cent of the first mortgage filings m 1926 and decreased somewhat after that year. In general, a larger percentage of the first mortgage debt than of the first mortgage filings was found m the duration groups longer than five years, and a smaller proportion of the first mortgage debt than of the filings m the duration groups shorter than five years. In other words, the long-term debts were commonly larger m amount, and the short-term debts smaller m amount, than the average debt per mortgage, through the 63-year period studied. This is what should be anticipated, since a mortgagor will venture to assume a larger loan if he knows he will be allowed a longer time m which to pay it off. Junior mortgages showed much larger percentages in the duration groups below 58 months. There was a tendency for the longer-term junior mortgages to be larger in amount, but this tendency had many conspicuous exceptions. Junior mortgages of less than 12 months' duration, for example, com - prised a decidedly larger proportion of the debt assumed than of the filings in the decades 1870-80, 1881-90, and 1901-10. This indicates that a considerable number of fairly large junior mortgage loans were contracted for brief periods. «■« » a u » M W M WIWIU W U W IT » 11 y » l» a ._aL„ JJ ll I — -JLo li SSt Tti r+r L — Ra «=*■* ' — ' LnJT-r4^; ia SL . — h— sX I., 0— J 1 1 M I 1 1 1 1 I ; h U r- «"&lt;-i 4IND 9I JtHORM 8 " n: H3-Z xwi * si momms tg, . _r~ £^z _ -u_. -J3 -p fii _r- D=» _— j^ i2_ »t- — su fc — —t*™t- — 55£=^;3£::52;.t i i z 2*1* b I LirJoisisi icra i* Ji k if » n a a i&amp; Fig. 12. — Average interest rate per first and junior mortgage of the specified duration group in 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson. McFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships in York county; Brush Creek precinct in Saline county; and Richland precinct In Saunders county. The figure is based on 18,680 mortgage records specifying both proposed duration and interest rate. These records are distributed by class and year of filing approximately as shown in Table 6. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 35 Interest rate and proposed duration. — First mortgages of less than five years (under 58 months) in proposed duration bore higher interest rates than first mortgages assumed for five years (58-62 months), and than those assumed for still longer periods, as shown in Figure 12. The five-year first mortgages bore lower interest rates than either the shorter or the longer mortgages in 33 years out of 59 in which any five - year first mortgages were filed. The rate on five-year junior mortgages was lower than that on shorter mortgages in 49 years out of 58 in which any junior mortgages were recorded. Junior mortgages of 63 months or more in proposed duration were so rare that they have been omitted from Figure 12 ; the only year having as many as ten examples was 1898. NEW AND REFINANCED MORTGAGES Definitions. — A new mortgage, as the term is used in this study, is one filed upon a tract which carried no previous mortgage of the same class (first, second, third, or fourth) within a month preceding the date of filing. All mortgages filed at the time when a preceding mortgage was released, or within a month of such release, are termed refinanced mort - gages. The object of this classification, which differs from some other classifications of new and refunded mortgages in contemporary research, 13 is to emphasize the extent to which mortgages on a given tract are merely shifted about from one lender to another, without being paid off. Proportion of filings new- and refinanced. — From 1870 to 1874, all farm mortgage filings recorded were new, for ob - vious reasons. New filings remained a large proportion (more than 80 per cent) of the total number of first mortgages filed during 1875-83, but declined thereafter to only 34 per cent during 1889-90. They increased irregularly from 34 per cent in 1890 to 59 per cent in 1895, and decreased to only 30 per cent of first mortgage filings in 1899, which was the lowest proportion of new mortgages for any year in the entire period studied. Evidently the first effect of the better times from 1897 to 1899 was to enable farmers to refinance a large pro - portion of the mortgages assumed earlier. Between 1899 and 1910 the proportion of new loans increased from 30 to 71 per cent of all first mortgage loans. This period was relatively prosperous for southeastern Nebraska farmers and they were gradually paying off their old mortgages, assumed in the eighties and nineties. During the less prosperous years from "See for example, "Farm Mortgage Loans, 1929", Crops and Markets, Vol. 8, No. 9, p. 894, Sept. 1931. There the classification of "ncfw loans" and "renewals" -was ob - tained from the mortgage bankers reporting to the Department of Agriculture. "Re - newals" there include only loans refinanced Between the same mortgagors and mort - gagees aa the loans which they replace, and probably usually for the same terms; all ohters are "new loans". Those figures are therefore not comparable With this study. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 36 1911 to 1915, the proportion of new loans decreased from 71 per cent m 1910 to 51 per cent during 1914-15. With war - time and post-war prosperity the proportion of new loans in - creased, reaching 73 per cent m 1920, or higher than at any - time since 1884. With the arrival of the depression of 1920 - --21, the proportion of new loans commenced to fall, and kept WTJ 7» II MP* " » " Wj M 06 II 14 17 20 23 2* 29 1032 g§» — I K|j||||jj«j|3|wjjt|flj ■^H so tt ■ nEWFIUNCS gH£TMANCCD-»«UC LCNOEIt OB£WANCEO-NCW L£NMB Pig. 13. — Percentage of mortgage filings new and refinanced, m ten southeastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). A new mortgage, as defined for this figure, is one filed upon a tract which carried no previous mortgage of the same class (first, second, third, etc.) within a month pre - ceding the date of filing. All mortgages filed at the time when a preceding mortgage was released, or within a month of such release, are here classified as refinanced mort - gages. Only 8,045 first mortgages and 4,271 junior mortgages could be classified as described above. The townships are: Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFuddon, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue m York county, and Brush Creek m Saline county. on declining until 1927, when it stood at 36 per cent, or lower than at any time since 1899. Farmers were using the partial recovery during 1922-27 to refinance their old mortgages, just as they had done during 1897-99. From 1927 to 1929 the pro - portion of new loans increased somewhat, probably because a good many debtors were able to repay loans falling due during these fairly prosperous years. It remained high m 1930-32, probably for the reason that reduced incomes forced many farmers to assume new debts. Much of the new debt since 1921 may represent the refunding of short-term personal and collateral loans which farmers could not pay because of falling commodity prices. When such loans are fundamentally sound, although "frozen" temporarily, it is considered advisable to have them refunded as farm mortgages. 14 . : * tti- - 11 Anderson, B. M. Agricultural Credits and Cooperative Marketing. Chase Economic Bulletin. Vol. 111. No. ». pp. 10-11. New York. 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 37 Refinanced mortgages are still further divided into those given to the same lender as the mortgage which they replace, and those witn a new lender. Refinancing to a new lender was much commoner than to the former lender m all years except 1928 and 1931-32. However, the proportion of first mortgages renewed to the former lender tended to increase during the final 13 years of the period studied. From only 5 per cent m 1919, it rose to 30 per cent iri 1928, and remained fairly high during 1929-32. j I? general, a slightly larger proportion of the first mortgage debt than of the mortgage filings was refinanced. In other words, the large loans tended to be refinanced, while the small loans were somewhat more often paid when due. A conspic - uous exception, however, occurred during 1918-20, when the big new loans outweighed the refinanced mortgages. Junior mortgages showed a considerably higher proportion of new loans than first mortgages showed m all years except 1904. The rather extreme variations indicated for junior mortgages from 1901 to 1919 are due to the small number of such mortgages filed m these years. Junior mortgages re - newed to the same lender tended to increase from 1920 to 1931. The distribution of the junior mortgage debt did not differ significantly from that of the filings. Refinanced mortgages usually showed some alteration m the terms of the mortgage. However, occasionally mortgages were renewed on exactly the same terms as those they re - placed. Such renewals comprised nearly 11 per cent of all first mortgage filings m 1928, 5 per cent m 1924 and 1931, and less m all other years. TYPE OF LENDER Sources of mortgage credit. — The sources of farm mort - gage credit for the 11 southeastern Nebraska townships may be divided into six principal types of mortgagees or lenders as follows: (1) individuals; (2) mortgage investment com - panies, including building and loan companies, trust com - panies, mortgage bankers, savings banks, and the like; (3) insurance companies; (4) commercial banks, including na - tional, state, and private banks; (5) the federal farm loan system, consisting of federal land banks and joint stock land banks; and (6) other lenders, including partnerships, educa - tional and religious endowment funds, mercantile companies, and various corporations which could not be identified as to type. Individuals. — Three types of individual mortgagees may be distinguished: (1) private investors interested m farm mortgage loans; (2) former farm owners who, upon selling </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 38 their farms, receive a part of the purchase price m cash and accept a mortgage for the balance; and (3) relatives who re - ceive their share of an estate m the form of a mortgage rest - ing upon it. Upon the death of a farm owner having several heirs, it is a common practice for one of these heirs to own and operate the farm while giving mortgages to his co-heirs amounting to their share m the estate. Again, an elderly - father or mother may deed his or her farm to a son, retaining a mortgage upon it so that the interest payments will con - stitute a retirement allowance. It was impossible m the present study to determine the proportion of loans by individ - uals assignable to the three different types of individual lenders, but it seems reasonable to suppose that the second type would increase m time of prosperity with increasing land sales, while the third type would remain relatively inde - pendent of the economic cycle. miff* S-jiULrSsaSigS 7 — *- ?. Tjis?B. °f 'it JI**J2^.JL^SL, 'S^ff-JS.jiS.t BHmwu BacoMiVkNits ulcounvtits L^uoan system La I*Bo1 * 80 - Fig. 14. — Percentage of first and junior mortgages to specified types of mortgagees, m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1872-1932). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue tovmships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; and Richland precinct m Saundcrs county. The figure is based on 9,601 first and 4,976 junior mort - gages, distributed by year and class approximately as shown m Table S. "Loan com - panies" or mortgage investment companies include building and loan companies, trust companies, and savings banks. The federal farm loan system includes federal land banks and joint stock land banks. "Other lenders" include partnerships, educational and religious endowment funds, mercantile companies, and unidentified corporations. As shown m Figure 14, individuals were the commonest type of lenders of first mortgage credit to farmers m all years studied except 1886-87, 1923, 1926, and 1931. They made as high as about nine-tenths of all the first mortgage loans re - corded during 1873-74 and 1878, and as low as one-third of those during 1886-87 and three-eighths of those m 1926. The general trend of the percentage of first mortgage loans made </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 39 by individuals depended upon the rise and fall of corporation lending. The trend of loans by individuals was downward from 1870 to 1887, upward from 1887 to 1903, and generally downward from 1904 to 1926. First mortgage loans by individuals approached the average for all loans in the amount per mortgage. The interest rate per first mortgage to an individual was usually fairly close to the average rate for all first mortgages filed in the same year, but in 1875-1900 it was somewhat higher than the latter rate while in earlier and later years it was approximately equal to or slightly lower than the average first mortgage rate. In five years (1912, 1920-21, 1924, and 1932) first mortgages to in - dividuals bore the lowest interest rates of any type of mort - gages, and they bore a rate equal to the lowest in seven other years (1917-19, 1926, 1928, and 1930-31). Individuals were the commonest source of junior mortgage loans in all years except 1886, 1917, and 1926-28. They sup - plied a greater proportion of the junior than of the first mort - gage loans in all but 12 years. The interest rates on junior mortgage loans from individuals were, in general, neither the highest nor the lowest. The average amount of the loan was also medium. Investment companies. — Mortgage investment companies placed more farm mortgage loans in the 11 townships than any other type of mortgagee except individuals (Fig. 14). Such corporations first appeared as farm mortgage lenders in 1874, and rapidly gained in importance. They accounted for from one-third to nearly one-half of the first mortgage filings during 1875-76, 1884-87, and 1889, after which they declined in importance up to 1908. Most of these early - loan companies were incorporated outside the state of Nebraska ; many were located in New England and the Middle Atlantic states, and a few were foreign. As a class, these early mortgage companies were not conspicuous for the sound - ness of their financial methods, and commencing about 1887 many of them experienced serious difficulties. However, they continued to be a considerable although decreasing source of credit in the 11 southeastern Nebraska townships included in this study until the depression of 1893-96 put an almost com - plete quietus on their activities in this locality. The propor - tion of loans made in these townships by investment com - panies declined from 25 per cent of all first mortgages in 1893 to 5 per cent in 1898, and after a slight revival during 1899 - 1902, kept on decreasing to only 2 per cent during 1906-08. Shortly after this, however, a new group of investment com - panies, mostly incorporated in Nebraska and much more con - servative in type, began to be active in the 11 townships. The </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 40 proportion of first mortgage loans made by investment com - panies again increased rapidly, from 2 per cent in 1908 to 40 per cent in 1917, and has remained fairly high ever since then. A considerable proportion of the mortgages first held by investment companies in the 11 townships was subse - quently assigned to life insurance companies or to private in - vestors. The average debt per first mortgage to an investment com - pany was usually slightly larger than that per first mortgage to an individual. The marked exception during the decade 1891-1900, when the loans made by the investment companies averaged very much smaller than those from any other source, was probably caused by the difficulties being experienced by the loan and trust companies at that period. Loans by such companies were rather small during 1931-32 also. The interest rate per mortgage was usually lower on loans by investment companies than on any other type of first mort - gage loan, especially up to 1900. Such loans bore the lowest average interest rate of any type of first mortgages in 15 years out of 59 in which any mortgages to investment companies were filed, and bore a rate equal to the lowest in 15 more years. They bore rates below the average for all first mort - gages in 44 years out of 59, equal to the average in eight years, and above the average in seven (1909, 1919-21, 1930, and 1932). The investment companies also accounted for a large but greatly fluctuating proportion of the junior mortgage loans during 1884-91, 1912-18, and several subsequent years. Such loans by investment companies in the eighties and nineties were very small, being mainly agents' commissions which at that period were often financed in this way. Interest rates on junior mortgages to investment companies were relatively high after 1880, except during 1931-32. Insurance companies. — Insurance companies are treated separately from other investment companies because of their distinctive qualities. From 1882 to 1896, they competed with other investment companies for second place in the proportion of first mortgage loans furnished the 11 townships. Subse - quently they furnished one-seventh or more of the first mort - gage loans during 1898, 1906, 1909-11, 1913-14, and 1916, and less in the intervening or subsequent years. The sharp fluctu - ations in the number and proportion of insurance company loans from year to year resulted chiefly from changes in the methods by which the insurance companies placed their loans. Sometimes they negotiated directly with the mortgagor and at other times they bought mortgages from investment com - panies. I </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 41 Loans by insurance companies were commonly larger than those made by any other type of mortgagee. The insurance companies made a policy of lending only on the more valuable and more highly productive farms. Many borrowers prefer to obtain their loans from insurance companies if possible because these companies are not subjected to as great pressure to call in their loans in times of moderate stringency or de - pression as mortgage investment companies and commercial banks. In 1932, however, insurance companies figured prom - inently among creditors instituting foreclosure proceedings in the 11 townships. In general, the interest rates offered by the insurance com - panies in the 11 townships were low, but averaged slightly higher than those offered by the investment companies. In - surance companies' rates on first mortgages averaged below rates on all first mortgages in 29 years out of 56, equal to the average of all first mortgage rates in seven years of the 56, and above it in 20 years. They averaged lower than rates on any other type of first mortgage in seven years (1881-82, 1889, 1907, 1915, and 1929), and as low as the lowest rates in eight more years (1902-06, 1917, 1923, and 1927). The in - surance companies have never made many junior mortgage loans in these 11 townships. The townships studied are near the western border of the territory in which the great eastern life insurance companies place farm mortgage loans. Some of these companies refuse to place loans west of the tier of counties ending in Knox county on the north and Nuckolls county on the south. Commercial banks. — The commercial banks were not an important source of first mortgage credit in the 11 townships studied, although they played a very important part in placing and handling such loans. Previous to the passage of the Federal Reserve Act in 1913, national banks were prohibited from making loans on real estate mortgages. Since then they have been allowed to lend on first mortgage security up to 50 per cent of the appraised value of the farm." The state and private banks made some first mortgage loans in the years preceding this permission. In 1915, one-eighth of all first mortgage loans were made by the commercial banks, this being more than in any other year. First mortgage loans by commercial banks bore higher interest rates than any other type of first mortgage loan in 27 years out of 51, and tied with the highest interest rates in four more years. They bore the lowest average interest rates of any type of first mortgage ' "See Sparks; E. S. Agricultural Credit in the United States, pp. 316, 330-331 Thomas Y. Crowell Co., New York. 1982. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 42 in four years out of the 51 and tied with the lowest rates in three more years. The commercial banks have become an increasingly im - portant source of junior mortgage credit, especially from 1912 to 1928. In the latter year, the banks furnished 55 per cent of the mortgage loans on encumbered property. The interest rate on these bank loans was usually higher than that on the other types of junior mortgages. Inspection of the records indicates that the proposed duration of the commercial bank loans was relatively short. Such loans seem to have been greatly stimulated by the creation of federal intermediate credit banks in 1923. These intermediate credit banks were authorized to rediscount agricultural loans of from six months to three years' duration made on suitable security and terms by state and national banks, and by certain types of invest - ment companies and agricultural credit organizations. 16 Chattel mortgages have been the commonest type of security for such loans, but real estate mortgages are also used. The proportion of junior mortgage loans obtained from banks jumped from 18 per cent in 1923 to 39 per cent in 1924, sug - gesting that local banks in the 11 townships made prompt use of the new facilities for extending credit. Junior mortgage loans by banks were sharply restricted during 1929-32. Federal farm loan system. — The federal farm loan sys - tem was created in 1916 and first became operative in the 11 townships in 1918. It furnished 13 per cent of the first mort - gage loans filed in 1922, 11 per cent during 1926-27, and less in other years. Loans by joint stock land banks were a little commoner in the area studied than loans by federal land banks up to about 1929. The average amount per mortgage was about $8,000 up to 1920, and $6,000 during 1931-32. All these loans were to be paid on the amortization plan in from five to 40 years, 35 years being the usual period in the area studied. The long duration of the loans has en - couraged rather large borrowings per mortgage. The interest rate, however, has not been particularly low as compared with other mortgages in these 11 townships. It was higher than the average for all first mortgages in nine years out of the 15 in which federal farm mortgages have been filed, equal to the average for all first mortgages in three years, and lower in three years. Federal land banks and joint stock land banks are forbidden by law to charge more than 6 per cent interest, which has caused their loans to be much sought after in the western counties of Nebraska where the average interest rate is commonly higher than that. The eastern Nebraska eoun - »Sparks, E. S. Agricultural Credit in the United States, pp. 886-401. Thomas Y. Crowell Co.. New York. 1982. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 43 ties, however, could usually obtain better terms from invest - ment companies, life insurance companies, or private in - vestors. For this reason the 11 townships turned extensively to the farm loan system only in the emergencies of 1922, 1926, and 1932. During 1929-30 the rapid fall of farm land values made the bonds of the land banks a doubtful investment, so that few loans were obtained from such banks in those years. Beginning with 1932, however, the loans of Reconstruction Finance Corporation funds to the federal land banks enabled the latter to become active again in placing and refinancing loans. The amortization feature of the federal farm loans was in - troduced with the object of making repayment easier for the borrowers; but during 1931 and 1932, when farmers found it difficult to pay even the interest on their mortgage debts, the necessity of making amortization payments in addition was sometimes a serious hardship. Recently many agree - ments have been recorded between the federal land banks and their debtors scaling down such payments and extending the proposed duration of the mortgage. The federal land banks and joint stock land banks are allowed to lend only on first mortgage security. Other lenders. — Other lenders than those already dis - cussed furnished a significant proportion of the first mort - gages from 1894 to about 1912. The predominant element in this miscellaneous group consisted of partnerships which sprang up in the wake of the financial disasters of 1893-96. By 1912, most of these partnerships had either incorporated as investment companies or else ceased doing business. Other lenders furnished a significant proportion of the junior mort - gage loans during 1876, 1880, 1896-1900, and 1904-07. RESIDENCE OF MORTGAGEE Significance of terms used. — The locality where the lender resides is not a very good indication of the geographic source of farm mortgage credit, but it appears to be the best available for this study. Mortgagees have been classified in six groups according to residence: (1) those residing in the same county in which the tract under consideration is located ; (2) those residing in other Nebraska counties besides that in which the tract under consideration is located ; (3) those re - siding in any North Central state except Nebraska; (4) those residing in the North Atlantic states; (5) those residing in any part of the United States or its possessions not included among those just mentioned ; and (6) those residing in foreign countries. Corporations were assumed to "reside" where their central offices were located. If locations were not given, the state of incorporation was used as the "residence". </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebb. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 44 wt» « m «4 »T9O p «» »» wm ci cc ii v n ao 2» ** ** **Bp 1072 7 J 78 ftl (^4 ft 700 03 09 00 f^^^ 05 00 1 1 \4 17 20 23 20 29 1932 m%?32? n ®&amp;S2£ ESSffiStt m'SSiS™ 1 a™»»*. E&gt;~«n UOBTCACtD COUNTY NEBRASKA Pig. 15. — Percentage of first and junior mortgages m ten southeastern Nebraska townships given to mortgagees residing m specified local - ities (1872-1932). Baker, Bradahaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county; and Brush Creek precinct m Sniine county. In the case of corporations, the address of the central offices was taken as the mortgagee's residence" if it was recorded; otherwise, the state of incorporation. The table is based on 8,085 first and 4,293 junior mortgages recording residence. Mortgages to local mortgagees. — The proportion of first mortgages made to lenders residing m the same county as the tract mortgaged decreased from 75 per cent m 1872 to 6 per cent m 1887, as indicated m Figure 15. The high proportion of local mortgages during 1872-74 was due to the operations of rather evanescent frontier financiers most of whom disap - peared from the records of the 11 townships after 1879, either because the depression of 1874-79 had broken them or because they had departed, following the advancing frontier. Doubt - less most of these lenders operated with money borrowed m the eastern states at the lower rates of interest prevalent there and loaned m the area studied at from 8 to 12 per cent interest. The proportion of local ("same county") first mort - gages increased from 6 per cent m 1887 to 82 per cent m 1918, after which it remained somewhere between 58 and 83 per cent. Local lenders were the commonest type of mort - gagees during 1872-74 and 1900-32. The very conspicuous increase m the proportion of local lenders since 1887 is to be regarded as a wholesale symptom. It indicates an increase of wealth m the local community. In time of distress, more generous treatment may usually be expected from a local mortgagee than from a distant creditor, because the former has a stronger personal interest m the welfare of the com - munity where he is a citizen. Of course there are numerous </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 45 exceptions to this rule. The local lenders usually furnished slightly smaller loans than the non-resident lenders. The proportion of the junior mortgages given to local lenders was higher than the proportion of first mortgages so given in all except nine years (1875-76, 1907, 1919, 1923, 1925, 1930, and 1932). The proportion to local mortgagees decreased from 71 per cent of all junior mortgage filings in 1877 to 13 per cent in 1884, and afterward increased to 88 per cent in 1918 and 90 per cent in 1926. Since the junior mortgages were usually for smaller amounts and shorter terms than the first mortgages, more of them were obtained locally. Mortgages to other Nebraska mortgagees. — Mortgages to lenders residing in other parts of Nebraska than the county where the mortgaged tract is located, accounted for a fair proportion of first mortgage filings in all years subsequent to 1880. Such mortgages comprised nearly three-tenths of all first mortgage filings during the decade 1891-1900, nearly one-fourth during 1881-90 and 1921-30, and about one-sixth during 1901-10 and 1910-20. They included an even larger share of the junior than of the first mortgage filings during every decade except 1921-30 and 1931-32. First mortgages to Nebraska lenders outside the specified county were equal in amount to the average first mortgage loan, or were very slightly larger, in all decades subsequent to 1880. Junior mortgage loans by such Nebraska lenders, however, were smaller than the average junior mortgage loan. Mortgages to lenders residing in other North Central states. — Mortgages to lenders residing in other North Central states than Nebraska formed a considerable propor - tion of the first mortgage loans up to 1913, but were insig - nificant after that. These states were the commonest source of first mortgage loans during 1881-86, 1888-89, 1894-95, and 1898-99. Most of the loans came from Iowa and Illinois, but there was a scattering from the other North Central states, namely, Minnesota, Missouri, the Dakotas, Kansas, Ohio, In - diana, Michigan, and Wisconsin. The North Central states except Nebraska were also the commonest source of junior mortgage loans during 1874, 1880, 1883-84, and 1888; but the number of such loans from this region after 1908 was insig - nificant. . v Mortgages to lenders residing in the North Atlantic states. — The North Atlantic states consisting of the New England states, New York, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania, ' were the commonest source of first mortgage credit during 1875-80, and furnished as much as 56 per cent of these loans </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 46 m 1879. After that the proportion declined to 4 per cent m 1904. Most of the insurance companies lending to the 11 townships were incorporated m the North Atlantic states, especially Connecticut and New Jersey, and they furnished the bulk of the loans obtained from this district after about 1900. Therefore the percentage of loans obtained from the North Atlantic states after 1900 shows pronounced variations quite similar to those of the insurance company loans shown m Figure 14. Of course these insurance companies drew capital not only from the North Atlantic states but also from other parts of the country. The North Atlantic states were the commonest source of junior mortgage loans during 1875-76, but after 1880 only a very small proportion of such loans came from that district. Mortgages to lenders residing m other parts of the United States. — Other parts of the United States than those discussed m the preceding paragraph never furnished a significant part of either first or junior mortgage loans m the ten townships where the mortgagees' addresses were ob - tained. The largest proportion of first mortgage loans was m 1920, when nearly 3 per cent of the first mortgage loans came from outside the North Central and North Atlantic states. Most of these were from California. Foreign lenders. — A considerable number of first mort - gage loans m years preceding 1883 came from foreign coun - tries. Nearly all of these loans were obtained from mortgage investment companies incorporated m London and Edinburgh, but a few were from Canada and Germany. As many as 16 per cent of all the first mortgages filed m 1881 were obtained from foreign sources. There were no loans from foreign mortgagees later than 1888. This need not necessarily mean that foreign capital had entirely ceased to be invested m these townships by 1888, but after that year any such investments were made through American corporations. The foreign loans were a little larger than the average first mortgage loan during 1870-80. Only four junior mortgage loans were made by foreign lenders and these occurred m 1877, 1880, and 1882. LAND PRICES AND FARM MORTGAGE FILINGS Volume of land sales and mortgage filings. — The number and value of the farm land sales by warranty deed m the nine York county townships is compared with the number and value of the farm mortgage filings m the same townships m Table 8. 17 The volume of land sales was much more irregular than the volume of mortgage filings, especially "Brush Creek rrecinct m Saline county and Richland precinct m Saunders county are omitted because no land sales data were obtained from these precincts. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 47 Mini I I I I I I I I I I I I „, iJ --——————^;—^K—— \v \\ M T^^^- — : _p^^^u;^ X i&gt;» aa •! X OJ noo 01 10 II n «J » I i \ ] s h g £ a % \ it £a S £ ISggSg * gtf i \ s|S g Sty i"" Si* » Fig. 16. — Mortgage debt assumed and total consideration received for farm land sold by warranty deed m nine townships m York county, Nebraska (1872-1932). Data from Table 8 of this study. from 1910 to 1932. Land sales decreased more than mortgage filings during 1911-14, 1920-22, and 1930-32; they increased more than mortgage filings during 1915-19. The number of mortgage filings was greater than the number of land sales m 48 years out of the 62 as shown m Table 8. The exceptions were during 1871-78, before much capital had come into York county, and during 1901-02, 1904-07, and 1909-10, years of prosperity without much speculative expansion m agriculture, during which Nebraska farmers were paying off old indebt - edness. The excess of mortgage filings over land sales was especially conspicuousduring 1884-87, 1894-95, 1913, and 1921-32. Each of these instances coincided with a depression, except that the last one was prolonged over a 12-year period during which land values fell steadily. The reduction m the number and acreage of the land sales m 1920 as compared with 1919 may be ascribed chiefly to the effects of the partial crop failure m southeastern Nebraska m 1918 and 1919. 18 This misfortune had a favorable feature be - "York county corn averaged nine and 21 bushels to the acre m 1918 and 1919, re - •pectively. compared with a ten-year average daring 1914-28 of 80 bushels per acre. Wheat averaged nine and 14 bushels compared with a ten-year average of 17 bushels. The shortage m Saline county waa similar; that m Saunders county was somewhat less severe. Reports of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. 1914-18. Nebraska Agri - cultural Statistics. 1919-28. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 48 TABLE 8. — Mortgage filings and sales by warranty deed m nine townships of York county, Nebraska, 1870-1982 * Year Number of Acreage Total i Per acre ~ I i Con- i j Mortgages | Sales Mortgaged | Sold Debt I federation | Debt | Price 1871 4 400 $ 3.000 ~. $ T. 50 1872 5 10 640 1,200 * 2,872 6,500 $4.49 5.41 1873 9 22 1,200 2,205 3,956 10,015 3.29 4.54 1874 19 49 2,400 5,763 7,117 ' 31,839 i 2.96 5.53 1876 84 41 4,087 3,921 14,467 24,601 3.54 6.30 1876 70 70 9,039 7,725 27,435 45,480 3.03 5.59 1877 67 56 8,885 6,011 24,107 36,593 2.72 6.09 1878 120 126 12,994 18,756 89.615 82,866 3.05 5.99 1879 128 86 14,934 9,810 46,947 79,371 3.14 SJO9 1880 256 98 28,925 10,830 88,346 94,009 3.05 8.68 1881 284 76 31,287 8,135 99,068 85,750 3.20 10.54 1882 363 230 42,865 27.982 184,360 347,535 4.30 12.42 1883 421 198 46,812 21,495 232,244 330,317 4.96 10.81 1884 642 189 64,055 18,640 317,277 824,494 4.96 17.41 1886 497 158 54,968 16,978 268,541 337,908 4.80 19.91 1886 642 180 61,343 17,709 349,152 367,392 6.69 20.76 1887 368 144 43.527 14.206 266.635 282,325 6.16 19.87 1888 310 192 34,897 19,063 268,634 377,358 7.70 19.80 1889 897 177 45,840 15,690 345,282 379,432 7.51 24.18 1890 345 126 39,662 15,033 303.458 397,388 7.67 26.44 1891 364 130 42,317 14.335 334,216 361,746 7.90 25.23 1892 299 207 36,657 22,641 357,836 737,889 9.79 32.74 1893 273 141 35,001 18,526 309,278 597.636 8.84 32.26 1894 441 88 50,114 11,515 377,929 347,057 7.64 30.13 1895 863 91 43,748 13,641 326,031 402,931 7.46 29.54 1896 148 81 20,369 10,199 133,088 281,253 6.54 .27.67 1897 164 91 21,018 11,455 157,140 245,798 7.48 21.46 1898 209 106 28,390 14.608 235,111 839,350 8.28 23.39 1899 223 89 27,414 10,351 272,797 295,570 9.95 28.66 1900 168 122 19,463 16,019 185,676 449,920 9.54 29.96 1901 136 194 17,080 23,806 198.199 774.624 11.61 32.64 1902 113 148 15,351 20,420 208,307 995,900 13.57 48.78 1903 123 99 15,906 12,197 220,615 537,911 14.43 44.10 1904 85 87 10,041 9,956 142,828 505,660 14.22 60.80 1906 87 100 ' 10,480 10,270 191,531 687,232 18.28 57.17 1906 104 116 11,792 12,442 255,107 766,777 21.63 62.44 1907 75 84 8,315 9,465 186,450 682,307 22.42 72.08 1908 90 72 11,692 7,827 242,151 625.641 20.88 67.16 1909 98 99 11,421 10,865 806,807 964,161 26.86 88.74 1910 108 110 13,290 12,668 428,021 1,348,469 32.21 106.44 1011 98 62 12,419 8,022 418,951 863,892 33.73 107.63 1912 106 66 12,039 5,998 425,844 648.815 35.37 108.09 1913 123 39 18,695 3,953 426,606 486,882 31.15 123.17 1914 104 46 11,772 4,352 378.715 446.185 32.17 102.52 1915 126 60 13.209 | 5,238 407,604 482,032 30.86 92.03 1916 128 71 14,030 I 6,850 563.066 766,978 39.42 111.82 1917 182 122 14,177 13,194 701,106 1,690,746 49.45 128.16 1918 126 99 14,335 11,485 794,610 1,724,046 56.43 160.11 1919 150 116 17,130 13,695 1,067,477 2,304,780 62.31 168.29 1920 191 88 23,448 9,934 1,484,519 1,928,762 68.31 194.16 1921 160 64 18.938 I 6,669 970.098 1,217,266 61.22 182.63 1922 149 36 18,187 3,721 832,864 485,682 45.79 130.62 1923 168 87 21,056 3,736 972,954 462,418 46.20 128.77 1924 162 43 19,282 5,165 865,177 639,553 44.86 123.83 1925 169 60 21,491 6,659 1,070,077 679,842 49.79 120.14 1926 124 . 35 16.192 4.285 704,044 601,876 43.48 117.13 1927 124 40 14,636 8,670 710,263 478,237 48.63 ,128.95 1928 145 50 17,059 5.214 831,992 696.668 48.77 133.61 1029 185 60 16,566 7,024 892,80* 881.091 58.89 125.44 - 1980 166 62 19,516 5,851 939,574 646,161 48.16 120.75 1931 117 80 12,440 3,229 513,486 863,669 41.27 112.60 1932 75 20 8.539 1.960 205.660 166,107 24.09 84.76 »The vales tabulated include all bonm fide sales by warranty deed m the nine town - ships, regardless of whether the land was mortgaged or not. The townships are Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden, Morton. New York, Stewart, and West Blue. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 49 cause it doubtless prevented many farmers from attempting to extend their land holdings at the peak of the post-war boom, and thus saved them from serious financial embarrassment during 1921-32. Some credit may also be given to the rather cautious character of the farmers in the area studied. Total consideration received and debt assumed. — The total consideration of the land sold was greater than the total debt assumed by mortgage filings in all years except 1881, 1894, and 1922-32. The wheat and corn crop failures of 1881 10 perhaps account for the drop in sales in that year. The year 1894 was a year of depression in which land prices turned sharply downward for the first time in 20 years. Land sales fell off sharply while mortgage filings still remained high. Falling land values during 1921-32 account for the few sales and the low total consideration during 1922-32. Sales price and debt per acre. — The debt assumed per acre covered by mortgage filings and the sales price per acre of farm land sold, tended to increase and decrease together, as indicated in Table 8 and Figure 17. The lowest values of both occurred during the depression of the seventies: $2.72 in 1877 for debt assumed per acre and $4.54 in 1873 for sales price. The highest values occurred in 1920, when the average debt assumed was $63 per acre and the sales price $194 per acre. Indices of sales price and mortgage debt per acre. — In order to emphasize the correspondence between these two variables, indices have been computed for each, taking the yearly average for the five years 1910-14 as 100. These in - dices are presented in Figure 17. The land price index stood at 177 in 1920, or more than one and three-fourths times its levle during 1910-14. By 1931 this index had sunk to 103, or practically its pre-war level. The index of the debt assumed per acre rose even more steeply, to 192 in 1920, nearly twice its pre-war level. It fell only to 125 by 1931, still consider - ably above pre-war. Both indices fell sharply in 1932, to 77 for land price and 74 for debt assumed, this being lower in each case than at any time since 1908. It must be repeated that the land sold is not identical with the land covered by mortgage filings. However, because of the relative uniformity in land values and in the character of the farms in the areas studied, it seems probable that the average price per acre sold in a given year corresponds fairly closely with the average valuation per acre mortgaged, and that a comparison between sales price and debt is significant. » Thorp. W. L. Business Annals, p. 188. National Bureau of Economic Research. VoL 8, p. 188. New York. 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 50 i«72 w » ii m p ii n ii ii ma qs o« ii v it » n a a i^»2 ~j I I \\ I I I I I__L I I Lr-tl I I I P~ IM IN «X Or DEBT ASSUMED^- so R IACKtW-W-BM I [ I 120 |-J! Lj— j^-b a&gt; ""l" PtBCtNTACt RATIO: D£BT ASSUMED I r-.11 17 | ] •0 -U PER ACRE TO SALES PER ACKE— I 4EPf — INOEX Of SALES PRICE PER ACRES- 90 Hjfl fT 88-WBO 20 — t» — 20 1872 7J 71 II H «T » gj » 81 lory OS OB II M 17 20 23 26 2&gt; 1932 Pig. 17. — Indices of the sales price per acre of farm land and of the mortgage debt assumed per acre, and ratio of the debt assumed per acre covered by mortgage filings to the sales price per acre sold, m nine townships of York county, Nebraska (1872-1932). Computed from data presented m Table 8. For the two indices specified, 'the average for the five years 1910-14 equals 100. Ratio of debt to sales price. — In the seventies the ratio of the debt assumed per acre mortgaged to the sales price per acre sold was very high, reaching 83 per cent m 1872. At that time land was cheap but building was fairly expensive because of the high cost of transporting materials. Relatively high mortgages were placed on nearly raw land m order to erect improvements, because these improvements added to the land value and because a further rise m land prices was ex - pected as soon as the railroad came into the county. From 1880 on, the ratio of debt to sales price was somewhat more conservative, being usually between" 30 and 40 per cent. These ratios make no allowance for the accumulation of several mortgages upon the same property. Price and debt assumed per acre on land sold and mort - gaged during the same twelvemonth. — Table 9 presents the sales price, debt assumed per acre, and debt ratio for all tracts sold within 12 months before or after the filing of a mortgage, m the nine York county townships. Such instances numbered 2,826, or 25 per cent of all mortgage filings m the nine townships. They include principally mortgages assumed for the purpose of buying land, and are more representative of the prosperous periods than of the depressions because land sales were commoner m the former. For example, tracts sold within 12 months before or after the filing of a mortgage numbered 73, or 38 per cent of all mortgage filings, m 1920: but they numbered only seven, or 5 per cent of all mortgage </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 51 Table 9. — Sales price, debt assumed per acre, and debt ratio for land sold and mortgaged during the same twelvemonth m nine townships of York county, 1870-1931 » I When mortgage waa tiled Item and type of mortgage | 1870-80 | 1881-90 |1891-1900|~1901-10 | 1911-20 1 1921-31 Number of cases First mortgages 129 627 S4O 368 870 12S S«ond mortgages SI 835 189 67 81 II Third mortgages 2 100 58 11 6 m Fourth mortgages, etc. 1 20 17 1 V Sales price per acre (dot*.) "" First mortgages 7.16 17.70 27.97 57.66 146.96 130 16 Seconi mortgages 10.71 18.34 28.93 47.05 149 42 12493 Th^ mortgages 6.04 21.85 26.97 66.65 154 85 16308 Fourth mortgages, etc.' 17.32 25.24 25.00 93 75 Debt per acre (dollars) First mortgages 3.41 8.67 12.01 22.74 66.18 60 23 Second mortgages 2.67 2.93 6.00 12.53 37.44 41 21 Third mortgages _ 1.10 7.09 6.52 12.21 28 69 37 44 Fourth mortgages, etc." 3.99 6.91 663 ..'...'. G8 7R Percentage ratio: debt to sales price First mortgages 47.7 49.0 43.0 39.5 46 0 46 3 Second mortgages 26.0 16.0 21.0 26.6 26 0 32*9 Third mortgages 18.1 33.2 25.1 22.0 18.5 230 Fourth mortgages, etc. 1 .... I 23.0 27.4 22.5 73^3 1 Baker. Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden. Morton, New York, Stewart and West Blue townships. The table includes all tracts sold within twelve months before or after the date of the mortgage. 1 Includes fifth, sixth, and seventh mortgages. filings, m 1922. Mortgages assumed for the purpose of buying land are customarily somewhat larger than those assumed for other purposes; therefore the debt assumed per acre and the debt ratio are somewhat higher than m the preceding table. The ratio of first mortgage debt to sales price ranged between 39 and 49 per cent. It was lowest /m the fourth decade studied (1901-10) and higher at the beginning and end of the period studied. The ratio of second mortgage debt to sales price varied from 16 per cent during 1881-90 to 33 per cent during 1921-30. Instances of third and fourth mortgages on land sold within a twelvemonth of filing the mortgage were too un - common to be significant, except during 1881-90 and 1891 - ---1900. The tabla indicates that, m spite of the rather conserv - ative debt ratio shown m the preceding table, a few tracts were dangerously overloaded with debt even at the time of filing the mortgage, especially during the decades 1881-90, 1891-1900, and 1921-30. MORTGAGE DEBT OUTSTANDING AT SPECIFIED DATES VOLUME OF DEBT OUTSTANDING Method of computing debt outstanding. — The discussion of farm mortgage debt so far has dealt exclusively with that assumed by filings during each year or decade. The mortgage debt outstanding on any given date is, however, of equal if </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 52 not greater importance. The farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years m the 11 townships has been computed by the following methods: The acreage of each tract mortgaged and the debt upon it were entered for every January 1 from that immediately following the date of the mortgage to that immediately preceding its release. Where release dates were not recorded, the date when the mortgage fell due wa3 substituted, for mortgages filed before 1920. Un - released mortgages filed m 1920 and subsequently were as - sumed to be still m force unless cancelled by foreclosure or by assignment of title to the mortgagee. The acreage given m Figure 18 and Table 10 is that covered by first mortgages. Junior mortgages, by definition, were placed on tracts already bearing first mortgages. Two sources of error must be noted m connection with the methods just described. (1) No attempt has been made to allow for amortization payments, which tends to make the estimates of indebtedness a little higher than m fact, espec - lllllJlllllTfTfffflff :~zz~t^zi^zzzz~zi-zz~z t * | cms men orr imumtci z mi r 1 I MONTI Ittl XJTiT NOM JtNl j— — i \z — i — ~H — J _^--^=^' i - [- jf^ --- ■ UMiniiiiiiffiffl- Pig. 18. — Mortgage debt outstanding and acreage covered by mortgages m force January 1 of successive years (1874-1933) and the business annals of the United States. Datm on the mortsraires outstanding are from Table 10 of this study; those on mort - gage filing* are from Table 4. The annali are repeated from Figure 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 53 ially since about 1920. (2) The assumption that all unre - leased first mortgages filed previous to 1920 were cancelled at term is doubtless contrary to fact. In general, such mortgages were probably extended for some years after term. In par - ticular, a good many unreleased first mortgages assumed in 1918 and 1919 are probably still in force. This error tends to offset the previous one. Total farm mortgage debt outstanding January 1. As indicated in Figure 18 and Table 10, the total farm mortgage debt outstanding in the 11 townships increased in time of prosperity and kept on increasing in time of depression, with three exceptions. The first of these was the long and steady decline which brought down farm mortgage indebtedness from $2,049,519 in 1896 to $1,282,139 in 1906. Sharply taught by their credit difficulties during 1893-96, farmers reduced their indebtedness as rapidly as they could during the subsequent ten years of relative agricultural prosperity. The second ex - ception was the barely perceptible reduction from $6,105,804 in 1927 to $5,991,920 in 1929, which also occurred in a period of relative prosperity as compared with the years which pre - ceded and followed it. The third exception was the reduction from $6,083,635 in 1930 to $5,622,812 in 1933. This reduction coincided with the greatest depression in the history of the locality and resulted principally from foreclosures and other forced sales. The total mortgage debt rose very rapidly dur - ing 1875-87 and during 1919-22. It more than doubled be - tween 1918 and 1924 and remained very nearly constant at about six million dollars in all years from 1924 to 1931. Forced sales of mortgaged farms were not numerous enough until 1932 in these 11 townships to affect perceptibly the amount of debt outstanding. Acres covered by mortgages outstanding January 1. — By January 1, 1887, the number of acres covered by farm mort - gages amounted to 152,159, which was 60 per cent of the total land area in the 11 townships, and probably about three - fourths of. the land in farms. 2 " The mortgaged acreage re - mained large for the next ten or 12 years, reaching a sec - ondary peak of 58 per cent of the land area in January, 1896. From this point it gradually declined to 56,515 acres, or only 22 per cent of the total land area, in January, 1918. From 1919 to 1931 the acreage covered by mortgages increased rapidly at first, and then more slowly, to 92,518 acres in the latter year. This comprised 36 per cent of the total land area, or 37 per cent of the land in farms. It showed only a slight reduction by January, 1933, although the total indebtedness *■ In 1899. 82.6 per cent of the land area of York, Saline, and Saunders counties was in farms. Eleventh Census of the U. S. 1899. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 54 Table 10. — Farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years, m 11 southeastern Nebraska town - ships, 1871-1933 x Year Acres cowered by SmS^.J-d'to Total debt Debt outatand- mortgaged SSI "rea outstanding ing per acre • Percent JB7l 480 0.2 $ 1.855 * 8.82 J872 480 0.2 1,836 8.82 ' 1878 1.120 0.4 4.607 .4.11 1874 1.920 0.7 7.188 8.73 1875 4,660 1.8 15,682 8.44 1876 8.167 8.2 33,624 4.10 1877 16,682 6.2 69,079 3.T6 1878 22.805 I 8.9 81,514 I 8.67 1879 82,923 12.9 120,887 | 3.67 1880 42,131 1 16.6 155,964 ' 3.70 1881 67.605 22.6 286,992 I 4.10 1882 70,348 27.6 311,648 ! 4.42 1888 92,638 36.4 480,242 5.18 1884 107.729 42.3 677.278 6.28 1885 130.518 51.2 950,271 7.34 ISB6 138,232 54.2 1,136,719 8.21 IKS'' 152,159 69.7 1,359,292 8.92 1888 149,027 68.5 1,448,768 9.67 1889 146,737 57.6 I 1,611,371 10.29 1800 143,272 I 56.2 I 1,579,926 11.00 1891 187.738 '■ 54.0 | 1,629.100 11.80 1892 185.201 63.0 1,691,916 12.47 1893 134,976 63.0 1,794,611 13.20 1894 186.164 63.0 1.840.681 13.53 1896 139,541 54.7 1,941,606 13.87 1896 148,018 58.1 2,049,519 13.82 1897 143,046 66.1 1,982,419 13.83 1898 187,786 54.1 1,898,074 13.76 1890 181,312 51.5 1,806.400 I 13.75 1900 122,960 45.2 1,720.049 13.99 1901 110,089 43.2 1,573.863 14.29 1902 97,260 38.2 1,464,097 15.04 1903 91,697 36.0 1,486,672 16.64 1904 86,519 33.9 1,412.649 16.32 1906 78,181 30.7 1.345,333 17.20 1906 70.28E 27.6 1.282.130 18.21 1907 67,051 26.3 1.349. 1 M 19.87 1908 64,625 25.4 1.411.727 21.68 1909 62,634 24.6 1.467,346 23.10 1910 58,865 23.1 1,546.701 I 25.87 1911 60,686 23.8 1.778,986 ! 28.94 1912 59,991 23.5 1,962,821 I 32.27 1913 60,843 I 23.9 2.176.275 35.24 1914 62,168 ! 24.4 2.389.593 87.81 1915 63,853 25.1 2,459,089 38.51 1916 63,549 24.9 2,617,771 .19.00 1917 63,349 24.8 2.563.628 40.00 1918 66.515 22.2 2,783.084 48.82 1919 57.898 22.7 8.147.306 63.78 1920 63,218 24.8 3.904.210 60.84 1921 69,646 27.3 4.987.723 71.04 1922 77.712 | 3JM 5.605.184 71.40 'The acreage of each tract mortgaged and the debt upon it were entered for each January 1 from that immediately following the date of the mortgage to that preceding its release. Where release dates were not recorded, the proposed release date was used instead, m mortgages filed before 1920. Unrcleased mortgages filed m 1920 and subse - quently were assumed to be still m force except m cane of foreclosures and farms deeded to mortgees. The townships were: Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue m York county; Brush Creek m Saline county ; and Richland m Saunders county. 3 Acreage covered by first mortgages. The second, third, and fourth mortgages were placed on part of the acreage covered by the first mortgages. One hundred and one records did not give the number of acres. "The total debt carried for all mortgages recording acreage was divided by the acreage covered by first mortcaces. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 55 Table 10. — (Concluded). Farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years, in 11 southeastern Ne - braska toumships, 1871-1933 x a _— a. Ratio: acres ~ I ~ — Year Acrra covered by mortgaged to Total debt Debt outstanding morcgagra j^ nd ar^ outstanding ing per acre • ISM SJ'KI to*, 6.741.642 72T32 J ** Oa.,54^ 32.3 K 990 ORO rr. Aa Jfllfi ___% 3Z -« bSKmW 70.11 192? Sa'Sn 8K 6.011.621 70.11 JoSa fS'SSS 33 - 7 6.105,804 70.82 1929 22-2?§ IH 6.097:327 69 88 JS?n SS-iZ? 33 - 9 5.991,920 69.16 l-ll ol"K?o 2H 6.083.636 68 38 IMS nn'Slo «? 6.009,329 64.48 1933 S?'es? $-■! 5.946,896 64.96 1833 91 - 68 2 36.0 6.622.812 60.90 outstanding declined considerably during these years. More mortgaged land and smaller debts per acre were the tendency after 1924. 21 Ratio of indebtedness to value of all farm property, 1930. — The estimated value of all farm real estate in the 11 town - ships on April 1, 1930, was $30,024,020, as given by the census. 22 The mortgage indebtedness outstanding on January 1, 1930, was $6,083,635, or 20 per cent of the total value of all farm real estate. But only about 37 per cent of this land had any mortgage upon it. This ratio of mortgage indebted - ness to the value of all farm real estate was about the same in the 11 townships as that for the entire United States (21 per cent in 1928) and rather less than that for all Nebraska (25 per cent) or the West North Central states (27.5 per cent) as given by a recent Department of Agriculture publication. 23 Effect of mortgage releases. — It may be observed that the debt outstanding sometimes continued to rise evert when the volume of filings fell, for example during the years 1895 - 96 and 1921-26. This, of course, was because the mortgage releases decreased even more than the filings. The amount of the mortgage debt releases declined sharply during certain depression years, namely 1894-95. 1907, 1920-21, and 1931 - 32, because debtors could neither pay nor refinance their loans. Such loans were either extended by agreement, or allowed to run beyond term at a high rate of interest — usually 8 or 10 per cent — or, in a few cases, foreclosed. The amount of first mortgage releases also declined during 1918-19 or be - a Duplications of acreage resulting from junior mortgages have been eliminated from the figures just quoted. Such duplications, however, are included in the figures on acrei covered by mortgage filings presented in Table 4 and in Figures 3 and 19. The fact is helpful in making comparisons. ■ Fifteenth Census of the U. S., 1930. Agriculture. Vol. 1. pp. S91, 392. and 395. « Wickens, David L. Farm-Mortgage Credit. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 288. p. 50. 1932. All three percentages quoted are for 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 56 Table 11.— First and junior farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years m 11 southeastern Ne - braska toivnships, 1871-1988 l Debt outstanding Percentage of total Debt outstanding Year debt outstanding per sere * First || Junior First | Junior First ~| Junicr~ 1871 $ 1,885 100.0 $ 3.82 1872 1,836 100.0 3.82 1873 4,607 100.0 4.11 1874 7,168 100.0 3.11 1875 15.682 ....... 100.0 3.44 1876 32,329 $ 1,195 96.4 3.6 3.96 $ 0.16 1877 56,021 4.C68 93.1 6.0 3.51 0.25 1878 74,831 7.183 91.1 8.9 3.26 0.31 1879 106,485 14,862 88.1 11.0 3.23 0.44 1880 134,482 21,482 86.2 18.8 3.19 0.51 1881 201.444 35,548 85.0 15.0 3.48 0.62 1882 270,176 41,367 86.7 13.3 3.83 0.69 1883 412,378 67,869 85.9 14.1 4.45 0.73 1884 578,552 98,726 85.4 14.6 5.37 0.91 1886 806,146 153,125 84.0 16.0 6.17 1.17 1886 927,549 209.170 81.6 18.4 6.70 1.61 1887 1,108.686 250,657 81.6 18.4 7.28 1.64 1888 1,165,771 277,997 80.7 19.3 7.82 1.85 1889 1.213,688 297,833 80.3 19.7 8.26 2.03 1890 1,261,496 318,430 79.9 20.1 8.78 2.22 1891 1,293,666 335.444 79.4 20.6 9.37 2.43 1892 1.852,844 839.571 79.9 20.1 9.97 2.50 1893 1,460,595 333,916 81.4 ' 18.6 10.73 2.47 1894 1,603,610 386,971 81.7 18.3 11.06 2.48 1896 1.572,C33 869.078 81.0 19.0 11.24 2.63 1896 1,648,867 406.652 80.2 19.8 11.09 2.73 1897 1.588.164 394,255 80.1 19.0 11.09 2.74 1898 1,522,953 375,074 80.8 19.7 11.04 2.71 1899 1,476,552 330,848 81.7 18.8 11.23 2.52 1900 1,482,771 287.278 BS.S 16.7 11.65 2.34 1901 1.818,579 260,284 83.6 16.5 11.93 2.36 1902 '1,248,489 215,608 86.8 14.7 12.82 2.22 1903 1,234,265 201,407 86.0 14.0 13.45 2.19 1904 1.228.967 188.682 86.6 13.4 14.14 2.18 1905 1,160,784 184,549 86.8 13.7 14.84 2.30 1906 1,113,200 162,939 87.3 12.7 15.50 2.31 1907 1,205.146 143,983 89.8 10.7 17.72 2.15 1908 1.281.466 130,261 90.8 9.2 19.56 2.02 1909 1,822.000 145,346 90.1 9.9 20.78 2.32 1910 1,879,778 166,922 89.2 10.8 23.03 2.84 1911 1,571,468 207,518 88.8 11.7 25.52 3.42 1912 1.756,215 206.606 80.5 10.5 28.83 3.44 1918 1.963,491 221,784 89.8 10.2 31.65 3.59 1914 2,116.746 273,847 88.6 11.5 33.46 4.85 1916 2,185.242 273,847 88.9 11.1 33.75 4.86 1916 2,233,686 284,085 88.7 11.8 34.56 ' 4.44 1917 2,279,979 283,649 88.9 11.1 35.5R 4.46 1918 2,494,654 289.430 89.6 10.4 43.70 6.12 1919 2,883,799 318,507 90.0 10.0 48.87 6.41 1920 8,438,011 466,199 88.1 11.9 63.47 7.87 1921 4,285,436 704.267 86.0 14.1 61.01 10.03 1922 4,764,564 840.620 86.0 15.0 60.67 10.73 1928 4,798.712 947.930 88.5 I 16.5 60.70 1t.62 1 The acreage of each tract mortgaged and the debt upon it were entered for each January 1 from that immediately following the date of the mortgrge to that preceding ita relea-e. Where release dates were not recorded, the proposed release date was used instead, m mortgages filed before 1920. Uureleased mortgages filed m 1920 and subse - quently were assumed to bo still m force, except m ca-.e of foreclosure" and farms deeded to the mortgagee. The townships studied were: Baker. Bradshaw. Hajrx, Hender - son, McFadden. Morton, New York. Stewart, and West Blue m York county; Brush Creek m Saline county: and Rich Und m Saunders county. 1 Per acre bearing any sort of mortgage. This acreage was practically identical with that covered by first mortgages. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 57 Table 11. — (Concluded). First and junior farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years m 11 southeastern Nebraska tovmships, 1871-1933 * v Debt outstanding ! Pereentaße of total Bebt outstanding Year | debt outstanding Per acre " First | Junior | First | Junior First | Junior 1024 | 5,028,379 970.706 I 83^5 16^ 60^20 U~29 1925 5.003.427 948.368 84.1 16.9 59 41 1072 1926 4,939.039 1.071,682 82.2 17.8 67 91 1251 1927 5.044.002 1.061,802 82.6 17.4 58.58 1224 1928 5.088.064 1.009.263 83.6 16.6 58 41 1147 1929 6,062,916 929.004 84.5 i 15.5 58.50 1065 1930 6.182.555 901.080 85.2 I 14.8 68.33 10 05 1931 I 5.225,696 783,633 67.0 I 13.0 56.20 828 1932 5.231.126 716.771 88.0 12.0 57.28 768 1933 4.931.625 691.187 87.7 12.3 58.65 7:36 fore the depression commenced. This was probably because of rising interest rates which made borrowers prefer to ob - tain extensions of their mortgages, if possible, rather than try to refinance them at a higher rate of interest. Debt outstanding per acre. — The farm mortgage debt outstanding per acre m the 11 townships on January 1 of successive years rose from nearly $4 m 1871 to nearly $14 during 1894 and remained constant at this point for six or seven years. It rose again during 1901-23 and reached a height of $72 per acre m 1923. After that year it sank grad - ually to $61 m January, 1933. The debt outstanding per acre was usually higher than the debt filed per acre. The difference was especially great dur - ing the depression of 1893-96, and the agriculturally depres - sion period, 1921-33. It was also great m 1915, probably be - cause of war-time conditions. Occasionally, m years marked by considerable activity m farm land sales, the debt filed per acre during the year was larger than the debt outstanding per acre on January 1. Examples are 1905-07, 1909-10, 1912, and 1917-20. FIRST AND JUNIOR MORTGAGE DEBT OUTSTANDING Total first and junior debt outstanding. — The highest peak of first mortgage debt outstanding m the 11 townships prior to 1900 was $1,643,867 on January 1, 1896. Subse - quently the first mortgage debt was reduced to $1,119,200 m 1906 and then rose to $5,231,125 on January 1, 1932, the highest figure m the entire 63-year period. Junior mortgage indebtedness had its peaks and hollows m slightly different years. The greatest junior mortgage debt outstanding prior to 1900 was $405,652 m 1896, after which this debt declined to only $130,261 m 1908. It then rose to $1,071,682 m 1926, and afterward declined sharply to $691,187 on January 1, </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 58 1933. The decline from 1929 to 1932, at a time when first mortgage debt was increasing, is very striking. It was due (1) to a loss of faith in the soundness of second mortgage security, resulting from rapidly falling land values, and (2) probably to the substitution of other forms of security, such as chattel mortgages. The very high second mortgage debt carried during 1926-28 may represent partly a funding, in the form of mortgages, of floating debt of other types in - curred some years previously. First mortgage percentage. — After 1878, the first mort - gage debt accounted for from 79 to 91 per cent of the total farm mortgage debt outstanding on January 1 of successive years in the 11 townships. The percentage in first mortgages was higher for debt outstanding on January 1 than for debt assumed during the year, in all years except 12. This was because the junior mortgages were of shorter duration than the first mortgages. Some of them, assumed for periods of less than 12 months, did not appear on any January 1. Such mortgages were commonly filed in the late winter or early spring and paid in the fall. First and junior mortgage debt outstanding per acre. — The first and junior mortgage debt per acre given in Table 11 is the average per acre bearing any form of mortgage. The greatest first mortgage debt per acre was $61 during 1921-23 ; the greatest junior mortgage debt was $13 in 1926. INDICES OF FARM MORTGAGE DEBT PER ACRE, WHOLESALE PRICES, AND FARM INCOME Wholesale prices and mortgage debt per acre. — All the indices shown in Figure 19 were computed with the yearly average of the data for the five years 1910-14 as 100. From 1893 to date, the general price level, as indicated by wholesale prices, and the farm mortgage debt assumed per acre cor - responded very closely in direction although they differed somewhat in degree. The explanation of this similarity is that the general price level is an important factor controlling national income. When it is rising, profits are made easily and money income normally increases. When it is falling, the reverse is true. This has a two-f o!d effect upon farm mortgages: (1) When the general price level is rising, the price of agricultural products normally rises as much or more than all commodity prices, and therefore farmers have in - creasing incomes. These increasing incomes usually en - courage land purchases and investment in farm implements, which require mortgage loans. (1) When national income in - creases, as it does during a period of rising prices, credit ex - pands and more money is available for long-term investments, </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Farm Mortgage Histor-^op Eleven Townships 59 "4 II I I I \ I I A I 1 :zi: r~ :: \- rARM MORTGAGE DEBT PER ACRE OUTSTANDII.G JAN.I.IINEBR. /'. MO — T*PS. T | ■' \ ,__. ,— WHOLESAl* PRICES OF ALL COUMOOITIES.U.S. V I / —a-^ 220 — REALIZED AGRI. INCOME SIR FARMER, U.5 \ { F I ■St. _- 220 AGM.BALANCE TOU CAPITAL ANO MANAGEMENT f"ER rARuju.S.I / / . * X IMO-M^OO f T/~ 1M \ u_A, — „„ \ ¥/ v/-)£x- - ijo -^Jf - —^^zzA^^'-zzp- : f« ' 40 ;=-— = ;r -*= . A (0 " ■■■"' : *^ ~ » ol — I 1 I I I L ' I I I lo lew ss so as two os io u 20 u raso Pig. 19. — Indices of the farm mortgage debt per acre outstanding Jan - uary 1 of successive years and assumed during the year in the 11 townships compared with indices of commodity prices in the United states (1880-1932), and of agricultural income (1909-32). The index of the debt outstanding per acre is computed from Table 10 of this study and the index of debt assumed per acre from Table 4. Sources of the other indices presented are as follows : Wholesale price cf all commodities: Modified Bureau of Labor Statistics index, as given in Farm Economics No. 72, pp. 1586-1587. Cornell University, Ithaca, N. Y. Sept. 1931. Realized agricultural income per farmer: King, W. I. The National Income and Its Purchasing Power, p. 308. National Bureau of Economic Research. New York. 11130. (Computed.) Agricultural balance for capital, labor, and management per farm : Crops and Markets. Vol. 9, No. 11, p. 440. U. S. Department of Agriculture. Nov. 1932. To obtain this item, farmers' expenditures for operating costs, wages to hired labor, taxes, interest, and rent were deducted from thc gross farm income and the balance divided by the estimated number of farms. The figures for 1932 is a preliminary estimate. including farm mortgages. Exceptions to these statements occur in years like 1907 and 1919-20, when the increased de-&gt; mand for investments described in (1) outruns the increased supply of available credit described in (2). They also occur in years like 1895 and 1931, when the volume of commerce has fallen off so much more than the volume of credit that money is easy. The lack of correspondence between the price level and the debt per acre in the 11 townships previous to 1893 was due to the following factors which for a time overcome the effect of the falling price level: (1) Settlement and development of the country created a great demand for mortgage loans. (2) The construction of new railroads and roads reduced trans - portation costs, and enabled farmers to maintain their in - comes in spite of falling commodity prices. (3) Increased familiarity with the country reduced crop hazards and there- </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 60 fore assisted m maintaining incomes. (4) Speculation boosted farm land prices out of relation to probable income. By the end of 1892 these forces seem largely to have spen* themselves. " The index of the mortgage debt outstanding per acre usually increased when the general price level was rising, and kept on increasing when the price level was falling. The excep - tions were a stationary plateau during 1895-1900 and a de - crease during 1924-33. It was thus conspicuously out of line with the other indices shown m Figure 19. Net farm income and mortgage debt per acre. — Two in - dices of the net income per farm are compared with mortgage debt per acre m Figure 19. One is the "realized income from agriculture per farmer", computed for the years 1907-27 from date given by W. I. King. This figure comprises the receipts of the agricultural industry minus payments to other indus - tries, wages to hired labor, interest on loans, and rent. The agricultural balance per farm for capital, labor, and manage - ment is presented by the periodical "Crops and Markets" for the years 1924-31. The labor and management included here a i r - e ,_i: ho! l e of the farm operator only. Although differing slightly from the index based on King's figures m method of computation and m results, this index resembles it closely m trend and may be used to fill m for the years 1928-31. The index of realized agricultural income per farmer rose from 92 m 1911 to 263 m 1919, or further and faster than any other index shown m Figure 19. It commenced to fall about a year before any of the other indices shown m Figure 19 and dropped to 115 m 1921, or nearer the pre-war level than any other index shown. Recovery during 1922-25 was very pronounced. Later, the index of the "agricultural bal - ance per farm for capital, labor, and management" dropped from 155 m 1929 to 63 m 1931. In other words, while debt outstanding per acre remained at twice the pre-war level and general prices sank to about the pre-war level, the f armers? money income dropped to less than two-thirds of pre-war by 1931 and suffered further drastic declines m 1932. His real income (purchasing power) declined even more than his money income. This decline m income reduced the mortgaged farmer s capacity to make payments on his indebtedness, and therefore damaged his credit so that he found it difficult to refinance his old loans or obtain new ones. The income figures are quoted for the United States as a whole because data on farm income for the 11 townships are not available. Such date would probably show general tendencies similar to those of the entire United States. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 61 TOTAL BANKING AND LIFE INSURANCE POWER COMPARED WITH FARM MORTGAGE DEBT OUTSTANDING Composition of the index of banking and life insurance power. — Reference has been made at times to the amount of available credit as a factor affecting the farm mortgage situation. As a rough indication of this factor, an index of the "total United States banking and life insurance power" for the years 1880-1932 is presented m Figure 20 for com - parison with the index of the total farm mortgage debt out - standing m the 11 townships. The total United States bank - ing and life insurance power comprises the aggregate re - sources of all commercial banks, loan and trust companies, and land banks reporting to the Comptroller of the Currency, and the aggregate resources of all land banks and of all life insurance companies m the United States. These corpora - tions include the chief sources of farm mortgage loans, for even the money lent by private investors will usually be 320 1 I I I I I I 1 I I |»O ~ -^7 C^^~ no +■ f V" no *. : -/ L Lho I 340 f. 240 / / aoo : jj- »o ,„ _ _ 4 ,„ ~ // " 140 1 1 140 I TOTAL FARM MORTGAGE DEBT JS 120 CAI«I«OJAN.IINIITWPS.^ /V^ BO « — jIL T^r 1 1 1 — »&gt; , &gt;* TOTAL BANKING AND UTt ' V-\ -t~T 111 I 1 1 H lUO tS 90 « 1900 OS 10 IJ 2O 2S 1930 Fig. 20. — Indices of the total banking and life insurance power m the United States compared with indices of the total farm mortgage debt outstanding January 1 of successive years m 11 southeastern Ne - braska townships (1880-1933). The index of the total farm mortgage debt outstanding is computed from Table 10 of this study. Total banking and life insurance power consists of the total resources of all national, state, nnd private banks, loan and trust companies, and savings banks reporting to the TJ. S. Comptroller of the Currency on June 1 of successive years, plus the total resources of the federal land banks and joint stock land banks, plus the total resources of the life insurance companies. Data were obtained from the Statistical Abstract of the United States nnd from Reports of the Comptroller of the Currency for various years. The resources of the life insurance companies for 1930-32 were estimates. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 62 handled by one or another of them. No one of these corpora - tions can make loans to the full value of its aggregate re - sources, but as the funds available for lending normally form a fairly constant proportion of the aggregate resources the latter are used since they can readily be learned. Comparison of indices. — The index of the total farm mortgage debt outstanding m the 11 Nebraska townships showed a general similarity m trend to the index of total United States banking and life insurance power after about 1906. Before that date the two indices were divergent. The farm mortgage debt m these townships increased much more rapidly than the banking and life insurance power up to 1896 and then decreased during 1897-1906, when banking and life insurance power was mounting with unprecedented rapidity.* The reasons for the increase and decrease of the farm mort - gage debt have already been presented. From 1906 to 1920 the two indices increased at approximately the same rate Prom 1921 to 1924 the farm mortgage debt m the 11 town - ships increased at a more rapid rate than the banking and life insurance power, but during 1925-30 the latter index caught up with and even slightly overshot that of farm mort - gage debt. During 1928-31 both farm mortgage debt m the 11 townships and general banking and life insurance power stood at approximately three times their pre-war level. In 1932 the banking and life insurance power contracted sharply, and was followed promptly by a somewhat less severe con - traction m the mortgage debt outstanding m the 11 townships. Figure 20 indicates how the tremendous increase m Amer - ican lending power since 1906 has encouraged increases m farm mortgage indebtedness, m the 11 townships studied, until this debt grew out of all normal relation to the farm income shown m Figure 19. FARM MORTGAGE FORECLOSURES Composition of data. — The foreclosures m Table 12 in - clude all sales by sheriffs and special masters m chancery, and all receivers' sales except those m which a bankrupt mortgagee was selling property previously deeded over to him by the mortgagor. Tax lien foreclosures on farm property are in - cluded because they could not readily be distinguished from other foreclosures m the records. From one point of view they belong m a study of farm mortgage credit. When Ne - braska farms free of other encumbrances are foreclosed for taxes, a serious shortage of credit may safely be inferred. Foreclosures constitute only a part of the forced liquidation of farm mortgage debt. During the past decade a commoner form of settlement has been for the mortgagor to offer the </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 63 TABLE 12. — Farm mortgage foreclosures m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships, 1874-1932, and, assignments of title to mortgagees m the same townships, 1920-1932 l Year j No AcreB Consid- JM°rtgage debt outstanding Per acre foreclosed cration Total I First I Junior Consid- I Debt out- ! . * I | eration I standing l FORECLOSURES 1874" 1 161 $ 840 * 2 1876' 1 80 178 2 1877' 1 40 100 i " i Jo™ t I "0 1,296 $ 825 $ 725 % "155 4 $ 1 1810 ' S S6O 1,325 480 480 4 1 1880 3 320 1.400 1.000 1 000 4 3 1881 3*. 400 2.170 2.193 1718 478 5 6 JBB3 1 80 600 274 274 6 3 1884 1 80 800 470 470 10 6 1886 2 160 1,409 728 425 303 9 5 1887 3 400 6.450 6,504 3.500 3,004 16 16 1888 4 401 5.006 5.511 4.050 1,461 7 14 1880 5 640 4.427 9.361 4,749 4.612 7 15 1890 4 400 3.698 16,954 4.436 12,518 10 42 1891 3 400 4.522 6,728 5.228 1.500 11 17 1892 4 480 4.000 7,704 5.600 2.204 8 16 1803 2 160 4,775 3.262 2,365 907 SO 20 1895 3 240 3.280 6.104 4.300 804 14 ■&gt;! 189fi 5 560 11,485 12,527 8,800 3,727 21 22 1897 11 1,125 15,326 23,291 13,600 9.691 14 '0 1898 12 1,438 24,418 22.123 13,750 8.373 17 15 1899 7 680 17.364 16,002 12.150 3.862 26 24 WOO 7 800 16,473 12,445 8.874 3.671 21 16 1301 1 480 15,260 7,000 6.000 1,000 32 16 1912 1 80 6.52S 5,400 4,800 600 69 6H 1913 1 80 900 1,000 1,000 U 13 1918 1 40 775 100 100 22 4 1922 5 1 498 66,180 37,800 34,000 3,800 111 76 1923 1 I 160 26.400 37,725 37.725 165 236 1924 2 | 240 37,600 24,500 17,500 5,000 156 102 1925 2 1 240 12,000 21,000 20,000 1,000 60 88 1926 4 I 440 22,341 61.888 24,133 37.750 51 141 1927 6 1,200 57,741 77.930 62.440 15.490 48 65 1928 3 660 42,801 55,000 60.500 4,600 76 98 1929 3 320 27,634 38,360 24,300 14.060 86 120 1930 4 360 28.955 44,870 27.100 17.770 80 125 1931 5 440 32.340 52,200 36,500 16.700 74 119 1932 | 3 440 18,303 20,500 17,500 3,000 42 '47 ASSIGNMENTS TO MORTGAGEES 1920 1 I 480 88.350 60,000 45,000 15,000 184 I 125 1921 1 160 30,000 30,000 12,000 18,000 188 188 1922 2 240 31,201 31,000 25,000 6,000 130 129 1923 1 160 14,850 14,000 9,000 5,000 93 83 1924 2 240 25,001 26,000 15.000 10.000 104 104 1925 2 120 16,701 14,000 7,200 6,800 131 117 1927 3 240 22,343 28,761 16,860 11.891 93 120 1980 6 760 82,465 81.376 60,000 21,376 109 107 1931 3 620 60,000 69,600 42,500 17,000 97 96 1932 28 4,440 417,978 416,955 361,600 65,365 94 94 1 Baker, Dradshaw, Hays, Henderson, McFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county ; Brush Creek precinct m Saline count? ; and Rich - land precinct m Saunders county. &gt; Mortgage debt unreleased at time of foreclosure decree. No allowance is made for amortization payments or accumulated interest. * Tax lien foreclosures. * Includes some tax lien foreclosures. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 64 mortgagee a deed to the property m discharge of his indebt - edness. Resort is made to foreclosure proceedings only when one or other party to the mortgage is unwilling to agree to a voluntary assignment of title. Such assignments are pre - sented m Table 12 for the years 1920-32, but not for earlier years. There were practically none from 1900 to 1919, but doubtless some occurred previous to 1900. Number of foreclosures and assignments. — The greatest number of foreclosure sales m any year was 12 m 1898. Years having five or more foreclosure sales were 1879 1889, 1896 - -1900, 1922, 1927, and 1931. The year having the greatest number of forced liquidations of any type was 1932, with three foreclosures and 28 voluntary assignments of title. 400.000 -CONSIDERATION. DOLLARS _ f77| 300,000 -M FORECLOSURES | _ 200.000 Efl ASSIGNMENTS _ |ooooQ P 4,000 -ACRES: _ 3,000 -B FORECLOSED ON 'A 2,000 _0 ASSIGNED - P 40 'NUMBER: — 30 B FORECLOSURES 20 YM_ 1020 21 22 23 24 ZS 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 Fig. 21. — Farm mortgage foreclosures and assignments of title to mort - gages m 11 southeastern Nebraska townships (1920-32). Baker, Bradshaw, Hays, Henderson, HcFadden, Morton, New York, Stewart, and West Blue townships m York county; Brush Creek precinct m Saline county; and Richland precinct m Saunders county. The consideration of land foreclosed on was the sales price. For land assigned to the mortgages, the" value of the mortencc plus any addi - tional consideration was used. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Farm Mortgage History op Eleven Townships 65 Foreclosure sales usually lag several years behind the trough of a great depression and are most numerous in the early part of a period of recovery (1879, 1897-1900, 1922, and 1927) partly because of legal delays and partly because mortgagees are reluctant to foreclose until they can expect to obtain thereby the amount of the debt. During the 12-year period 1921-32, 85 farms in these 11 townships changed owners by forced liquidation, 38 of them by foreclosure sales, and 47 by assignment of titles to the mortgagees. Nearly half of these liquidations occurred in the two years 1931-32. At the close of 1932 there were, in addi - tion to anything shown in the table, 18 foreclosure cases affecting land in these townships pending in the district courts. Consideration of foreclosed land, and debt outstanding. The consideration received for land sold under foreclosure, as given in Table 12 and Figure 21, was that named in the deed of sale. The consideration received for land assigned to mortgagees includes the value of the mortgage debt affected by the transaction, and any additional consideration allowed. The additional consideration was usually one dollar, but in several instances was more. The consideration received for this property was naturally extremely variable and bore little relation to its value in normal times. The so-called "debt outstanding" in Table 12 consists of the value of all mortgages unreleased at the time of the decree, in the case of foreclosures, or of the transfer of title, in the case of voluntary assignments. No deduction was made for amortization payments, on the one hand, and no addition for accumulated interest, on the other. Foreclosed mortgage in - debtedness usually carries a 10 per cent interest rate, so that the service charges mounted up rapidly. Failure to record mortgage releases, or delay in recording them, introduces another possible source of error. The figures for debt out - standing on foreclosed property, as given in Table 12, should therefore be considered with this in mind. They are presented as suggestive rather than accurate. The debt outstanding was larger than the consideration of the foreclosed property during 1887-92, 1895-97, 1923, and 1925-32. Apparently during these years the mortgagor com - monly lost his entire equity in the foreclosed property and some of the mortgagees also suffered losses. During certain years (1888-92, 1895, 1923, 1925-28, and 1931) even the first mortgage debt was larger than the consideration received. The problem of deficiency judgments was not investigated in this study. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">Nebb. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 67 66 Debt per acre on foreclosed property. — The debt per acre on foreclosed property, as shown in Table 12, shares the defects already described in connection with total debt out - standing. Nevertheless a comparison with the debt outstand - ing per acre on all mortgaged farms, as shown in Table 10, is. suggestive. The debt per acre on the foreclosed farms was above average in all years after 1887 except 1913, 1918, 1927, and 1932. In other words, except for the pioneer period and a few scattered instances in later years, the farms suffering foreclosures were those which had loaded up with debt beyond what was usual in the localities studied. The large junior in - debtedness on these foreclosed farms is another indication of over-borrowing. The same is true of the farms voluntarily assigned to mortgagees. The farms undergoing forced liqui - dation in 1932, however, were less conspicuously overindebted than those foreclosed or assigned to mortgagees in most earlier years. Fewer foreclosures in the townships studied. — It should be remarked that the foreclosure situation in the 11 town - ships studied, as is generally true in the loess plains region of southeastern Nebraska, was unusually favorable up to 1932 as compared with that in certain other parts of the state, and in the United States as a whole. This favorable condition may be ascribed to the following causes: (1) Highly diversi - fied agiculture enabled farmers to adjust to changing market conditions more readily than in one-crop districts, and en - abled them to obtain a larger part of their living from the home farm. (2) Comparatively low interest rates lightened the jdebt service burden. (3) Farmers were relatively con - servative in assuming mortgage indebtedness, especially dur - ing! 1917-20. The farmer on the western fringe of the corn belt knows that he will have a crop shortage occasionally, which makes him somewhat more cautious about loading up with debt than farmers in regions of heavier rainfall. (4) The circumstance that so many of the mortgages were held locally may perhaps have been another factor discouraging forcied liquidations. THE PRESENT SITUATION i In the trough of the great depression. — In January, 1933, the point at which thi3 study terminates, a profoundly seripus farm mortgage situation existed in the 11 townships studied. The Nebraska price of wheat was lower than in any previous depression on record, while corn and livestock prices were not much better. On January 15, 1933, Nebraska wheat sold at 29 cents a bushel as compared with 40 cents in December, 1895, at the trough of the depression of the nineties. Corn sold at 12 cents a bushel in January, 1933, as compared with </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Townships 67 from 10 to 13 cents during the winter months of 1896-97. Hogs sold at $2.30 per hundredweight m January, 1933, com - pared with $5.01 per animal, or roughly about $3 per hundred - weight, m January, 1896. 24 But the farm mortgage debt out - standing m January, 1933, was 5.6 million dollars as compared with 2.0 million m 1896. It will be remembered that the debt m 1896 was too high for the level of prices then existing and resulted m profound distress and m numerous foreclosures. But the debt is now two and three-fourths times as high while the level of farm prices at the beginning of the year was little if any better than m 1896. Partial recovery m 1933. — A decided improvement m the prospects for the farm mortgage situation m general and m the area studied has occurred since last March, resulting from complex causes among which the following may be noted: (1) The rise m the price of grains, between January and July, offers the prospect of better farm incomes m 192233 which will ease the burden of debt service charges. (2) Farmers m the 11 townships will have grain to sell, for although the wheat harvest m that locality was somewhat spotty, the prospects for corn are good. In addition, many farmers have a carry-over of one or both of these grains. (3) The Farm Mortgage Act of May 12, 1933, has increased the lending powers of the federal land banks. While not many loans have yet (August, 1933) been made m Nebraska under the terms of this act, the anticipation of it doubtless helped to check the flood of forced liquidations of farm mortgages which was such an alarming feature of the late winter and eraly spring of 1933. State legislation passed m March, allowing a two-year moratorium on foreclosure sales at the discretion of the district courts, doubtless contributed to the same effect ; but this law had an unfortunate by-product m making it even more difficult than formerly to obtain new loans from private sources. (4) Recent press releases from the office of the Comp - troller of the Currency show a slight increase m national bank deposits m June, 1933, as compared with those m June of the preceding year. This offers the hope that the period of contracting banking power shown m Figure 20 may have passed its trough. If the hope is fulfilled, the usual non-gov - ernmental sources of mortgage credit may begin to thaw out. The permanency of the partial recovery outlined above re - mains to be demonstrated, since it depends quite largely upon the degree of success attending the federal farm relief pro - gram and the national industrial recovery program now m progress. " Crops and Markets Vol. 10, No. 2, p. 42. U. S. D. A. Fefar. 19SS. Prices of Farm Products Received by Producers. 2. The North Central States. U. S. D. A. Statistical Bui. 15, pp. 178, 180, and 183. 1927. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>