<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Nebraska School for the Deaf Omaha, Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf OMAHA, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF OMAHA, NEBRASKA OFFICERS FRANK W. BOOTH A. JEFFERSON Superintendent Physician A. M1LIN TRENTHAM Matron MARY A. CHRISTOFFERSEN Chief Clerk Miscellaneous Statement Established 1869 ♦Number of employees 49 ♦Number of inmates June 30, 1923 187 ♦Highest number of inmates 187 Per capita cost per month $ 35.53 Number of acres 23 Number of acres under cultivation 12 Value of lands and buildings $325,397.00 Principal industries : Printing, manual training, painting, garden - ing, domestic art and domestic science. Visiting days : Monday to Friday, inclusive. Hours 8 a. m. to 4:15 p. m. The institution is open during the school year to such bona fide residents of Nebraska as are of suitable age and capacity, who, by reason of their disability cannot attend the common schools. Clothing, transporation to and from school, and support during vacation periods must be paid for by parent or guardian. If parent or guardian is unable to pay, or if the pupil is of age and indigent, the county shall pay such expenses. Non-resident pupils may be admitted upon terms fixed by the Board of Control, which at this time is $500.00 per year. ♦Average during school year. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies ; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Some improvements of a permament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska ; a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska ; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Board ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. This land is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1. l l &gt;23) the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4 () S0 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following- table will he found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest bicnnium liiiMinium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) June JO, Ju«e30, time past 1&lt;»21 1923 two years A — Institution for Feeble-Minck-cl (i)7 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 409 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 K— Nebraska Industrial Home*""....!" '. 73 86 99 L— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 722 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R — State Reformatory for Women 9 18 28 S— Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 ■ 53 91 107 T— State Reformatory for Men (b) Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school ; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment. Board of Control, Lincoln — Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble-Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash 27,524.49 Capital Outlay 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash , 4,964.20 Capital Outlay 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett — Maintenance 176,148.28 Cash 67,846.61 Capital Outlay 115,000.00 358,994.89 Capital Outlay.. Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash 99,853.78 Capital Outlay..._ 38,850.25 639,888.49 Capital Outlay. State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,440.24 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay 117,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 375,095,50 Cash 89.072.43 89,072.43 1 Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Capital Outlay.. Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286 28 Cash _ 25.627.53 25,627.53 1 Outlay 4,490,17 152,403.98 Capital Outlay.. State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 229,205.92 Cash 161.633.02 161,633.02 1 Outlay 390,838,94 Capital Outlay.. Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance 61,306.38 Cash _____ 2,57826 Capital Outlay 63,884,64 Capital Outlay- Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance _ 94,406.99 Cash ...„ _ ZZZZ 29,70029 Capital Outlay „... 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City — Maintenance _ _ 57,82522 Cash _ _ _ 3,989.06 Capital Outlay 3,952.01 65.76629 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance — — 321.060.71 Cash 50,535.76 Capital Outlay „ 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance _ _ 137,695.55 Cash 16,819.16 Capital Outlay. 4,500.00 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance _ 28,489.38 Cash ... 2,733.39 Capital Outlay „._ 46,996.15 78218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.53 itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay Grand Total 72,188.46 6,959.45 300,000.00 379,147.91 4,538,783.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 EXPENDITURES FOR I92M922 ®i;&gt;H2, 276.9 H 2,272 ,H65.% SALARIES and WAGES OPERATION and MAINTENANCE FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT 196,093.94 NEW BUILDINGS 6O3.6H9.60 LAND 48.7H8.O8 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID 6.8H8.53 PERMANENT IMP. TO BUILDINGS and GKOUNDS 1 2 1,02570 TOTAL 4,491,102.25 M,H9I,IO2.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 INCOME FOR 1921-1922 STATE FUNOS CASH FUNOS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS 3,84 1,348.13 598,304.90 66,960.00 48,100.56 4,554,713.59 TOTAL *UttfXPEHOED BALRNCE OF CASH .FEDERRL AND TRUST FUNO (CL0THIN6 FUND,1N5TITUTE FOR FEEBLEMINDED) REAPPROPRIATED </seg> 
            <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. lxua f o, o x -n July 1, 1 !1 to June 30, 1 Salaries and Wages Operation and Maintenance Furniture and Equipment Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds New Buildings Land Fixed and State Aid Charges Total for Biennium Per Cent Institution for Feeble-Minded.. .. jirls' Training School soldiers' Home, Burkett rlastings State Hospital state Industrial School _... riospital for Tuberculous -incoln State Hospital...- Drthopedic Hospital state Penitentiary _ Nebraska Industrial Home soldiers' Home, Milford school for the Blind Sforfolk State Hospital school for the Deaf state Reformatory for Women.... Home for Dependent Children state Reformatory for Men (a) .... $ 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410.19 226,534.52 60,739.65 4528120 178,107.10 56,464.88 93,39320 19294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137,841.88 77242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 $ 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,19827 351,306.24 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,86020 42,879.03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,91821 $ 25232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,568.22 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 476.87 38,443.00 7223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28,624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,34827 45,077.86 ... $ 871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 _| 1,091.91 $ ! 375,267,87 158,772.67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63,884.64 140,041.38 65,766.29 431,595.48 159,014.71 78,218.92 72,611.53 379,147.91 8.3 3.5 8.0 14.2 5.1 5.7 12.0 3.4 87 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 i 84.7.^6'... 500.00 ! 24.75 19.00 3.952.01 200.00 i 22;06228"" 7,500.00 2,091,46 50,552.47 '39,052.92" I wj&amp;if' 48.747108 ' Total $1,242,276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,102.25 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Institution for Feeble-Minded...- Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital — State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary . ., , Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the BHnd (a).... Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf (a). State Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (b) Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 Average number Inmates during Biennium 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 Number of employees June 30, 1923, 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 Average number | employees during Biennium 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 Average number Inmates to each employee 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 11 8 5 2 8 4 3 7 6 Average per Capita Cost for Liiennium $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 48427 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 Average per Capita Cost per month $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 35.28 54.23 19.19 69.25 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 6527 31.83 51.22 Average amount Pay Roll per mouth $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total . 5,917 5,876 851 7 -i- 598.15 $24.92 $51,896.46 Averai ;e during school year. (b) Opem &gt;.A October 1, 1921- -21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 t AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FISST TIME Period Ending June 30, 1923 Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs. inc. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs. inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs, inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs, inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total Institution for Feeble-Minded -. GirU* Training School...- Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital. State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital — State Penitentiary ~ _._.. Nebraska Industrial Home .- Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind...- Norfolk State Hospital...- Nebraska School for the Deaf. State Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men 15 ... 6 ... ... - 67 67 17 9 ioo 70 28 65 14 ... 89 38 134 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 11 I 112 63 185 17 223 6 80 28 135 10 61 6 i 36 16 50 3 18 9 59 " 12 70 14 I 16 58 1 8 43 3 n 61 "31 "30 15 . I 2 3 i 1 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 2 I I „_ 7 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 4 27 1 39 ' " "i 6 is 66 a 4 ... 2 26 80 74 36 41 38 .... 34 i 6 5 3 1 I 121 67 """44 180 46 599 581 743 399 172 Total 211 293 324 212 181 271 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 HOSE ADI ITTED PO1 FIRST TIMS Bi« inium Endin, [ June 3ft 19; I. lor IMIt Minded OirU' School Soldiers tndSallon' Home Bnrkett Htatbia? State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penltentiiry Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers and Stum* Home Mill., id Nebraaka School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebnuka School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home (or Dependent Children Reformatory for Hen Total Australia , . Austria Bohemia Bulgaria Canada China . Czecho-Slovakia Denmark — England Finland ._ France Gennanv ._ Cireece _ _ „ Holland Hungary Ireland ..... Italy Japan _.._... Macedonia Mexico _. Moravia Nebraska Netherlands Norway ...„ Poland _ Russia Saxony Scotland a. „, Seria _ Servia _ Sicilia _ _.. Spain ..._ _ Sweden _ Switzerland _ Turkey U. S. other than Nebraska. Unknown Other Countries 1 1 .. . i"" ~i" ... 2 1 __J " " S~ 2 5 ... _. 1 7 6 1 19 1 5 ■■ ... 1 1 _ i l 3 6 , 2 1 1 1 119 1 _... I T 2 17 8 6 2 32 1 pr 4 3 H " L i 1 ; " ~T~ 2 1 3 2 1 ~3 1 1 11 ... .......... "i 2 i „ 2 i 2 i _ i " ■ i" . ... ... 14 3 4 S 1 2 27 _.._ i 3 " 2 - _ " 1 1 1 1 ~ i 2 i i s 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 6 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 30 1 S 1 2 1 2 44 6 1 1564 124 30 ____J — — — — • ... "209 98 ~" 2 vsr 188" 201 339" 74 66 i 12 l'oJ 26 30 232 72 __- 2 3 8 1 "2 1 " 1 • 3 10 ~ ~2 i 2 1 2 5 1 — __ I „ 4 i . 2 _ ] " 2 1 ... ... ... 2 ' 2 13 2 4 2 9 i "i 13 1 i 32 ' 56™ 4 119 205 26 . „„.. ~"76~ 209 42 4 586 ~ 42 1 1 256 5 20 | 116 8 129" 9 29 s 1 116 45 26 i 472 384 369 92 125 4074 Total 246 162 135 333 21 .m 35 62 2.(8 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOB FIRST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. County l—hrntlnn A in— _* Girla' Training School Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital tor Tuberctilotu Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic State Hospital Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford Nebraska School tor the Blind Norfolk State Hospital 5ebraaka School for the Deaf Ritormatory for Women Home (or Dependent Children Reformatory for Hen Total Antelope Arthur Banner __„ Blaine 8 1 I 10 • 5 1 8 3 1 9 3 2 2 97 35 I 2 2 26 20 27 19 85 31 38 46 38 14 19 51 32 19 21 74 23 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 21 110 7 9 5 1 12 112 39 22 4 18 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 46 3 37 7 19 1 2y 21 43 33 49 20 16 22 20 40 12 39 68 8 38 11 39 44 53 28 27 17 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 1 1 55 i l l 2 20 1 5 I " 1 ""' ** _ 1 1 4 1 1 i - 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 f 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 1 6 9 2 1 2 1 6 2 6 1 2 13 125 i i 1 8 1 7 12 3 9 „..._ . " 3 i 4 Box Bntte Boyd Brown Buffalo Burt Butler Cass Cedar 1 I I _ _... 1 12 1 1 9 3 2 1 1 " l 3 1 5 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 1 1 1 1 i I - 2 9 "3 2 "" 6 hr- i i i 2 1 5 2 2 5 10 7 2 2 3 1 2 1 6 1 ... "i » f 3 4~ 2 4 19 " 4 " 4 i i ~ 16 1 6 1 Cherry Cheyenne Clay Colfax Cuming _______________ Custer Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel Dixon Dodge Douglas Dundy Fillmore. Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage Garden _„ . , Garfield ■ Gosper Grant Greeley . _._._..__ ___ Hall Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock iiolt Hooker Howard _..„ .._„. Jefferson Johnson . Kearney _ - Keith ..._ Keya Paha __ Kimball Knox I Lancaster Lincoln Loup Madison McPherson _______ _. Merrick _._ Nebraska Industrial Home Morrill Nance I Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe , Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte. . _ ___ _ PoHc " Red Willow Z Richardson Rock ._ Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff. ocvrsrd Sheridan Sherman "..„. Sioux Stanton __.'._. Thayer Thomas Thurston Unknown Valley Washington Wayne \Viicclcr , M ... , Other States York 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 ... _ i 4 2 i "l — ... — f 16 4 3 2 "~ i 2 2 1 1 6 4 [ 19 4 2 2 4 2 7 14 3 6 « i 2 t l i 8 _ 7 _„ 4 3 3 1 4 2 2 4 1 2 12 3 2 5 i io 1 2 32 ~ 2 2 6 1 3 5 2 1 8 i 5 1 76 i i "i 2 44 2 1 « 5 4 17 13 5 9 7 109 1 2 4 68 18 211 8 27 l 5 _ 68 3 7 9 1 4 2 12 _. 1 1 2 7 1 2 1 1 2 2 5 1 1 1 1 3 1 4 i ■ i 3 1 2 8 —•— — — _ 2 1 2 1 1 2 -• \* 3 1 4 56 1 l l i 2 4 1 "' 3 _i 1 _. i ~~ ™ " i 3 1 2 2 1 1 32 5 5 12 '' 10 2 5 6 3 3 5 2 2 3 3 11 5 1 1 3 5 i l 8 ' 3 , i i_ 2 1 •• 3 • 2 8 2 4 1 2 2 ... ... _ ■ 1 3 —•—•••• •• 1 1 3 2 "8 11 """ 3 1 _. . 1 3 2 2 2 1 3 1 4 1 2 "■ 18 i .... ... ~ 6 2 2 1 i~ 12 " 4 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 2 4 1 i 3 6 2 1 i i 2 ~ 7 i 1 1 4 24 S » l — r* 2 i l i' 49 " 3 1 2 1 3 4 1 2 3 25 3 "■ 145 1 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 38 'i i'6 2 2 i . 15 102 "" 14 9 4 1 3 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 T/; 4 ... "i ... ~~ ~ 3 1 2 i i' "" 4 8 " 1 3 i . ... ■~ I ...... _ ' r -ri ■ *"***"*"**" 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 8 6 2 ~ 8 2 3 I ~ ____ T 1 20 1 1 2 1 3 1 5 1 4 3 1 1 ■ ■■ II ■ «■■■■ m _•*■ ■ , i. ~ is 18 9 4 3 2 7 1 _ 1 6 1 i i i i 2 " ~1 3 8 1 1 1 i i s L_i 2 2 f~r ""if | i ■ 9 14 1 n 2~" 1 "~ i 2 1 1 1 2 2 i -•—— i ; i 10 10 . _ i 3 12 2 5 1 5 3 6 "7" l 3" 7 T is 4 3 2 s 2 '" i 2 i 4 5 15 1 1 1 I ' i 17 6 19 ri 2 " l 3 3 """* 1 7 3 2 4 i i f" "" i * 1 3 3 1 4 1 7 l 4 6 .___„ 5 .„. _h~~ 5 11 ~" 2 1 2 _ i "i 2 1 2 9 6 8 6 11 7 8 5 1 * To" 2 T~ i 2 1 1 4 i __ 1 2 2 _. 1 3 2 1 2 2 2 1 6 ._ _. ... 2 1 17 " '"" 1 2 4 ~ L___._ "i~ HIM ■ &gt; &gt;J 2 6 ii 2 T"' I 16 I " 7~ • • 2 2 ■ T 5 1 1 1 """" 7 , 1 l "*"} r 2 1 2 . '5' 10 1 13~ ""! _ J 2 1 i 1 1 1 H I I i ... . _. _ I -~ T 1 ! ~18~ _-___. .__... ... i J j_. 4 " - .................... Total 162 135 472 333 125 21 344 35 241 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I have the honor to submit to you the Report of the Nebraska School for the Deaf for the period ending June 30, 1923. Statistics show that 51.4 per cent of our pupils are reported by their parents as born deaf, also that the cause of deafness is re - ported as "unknown" in 9.6 per cent of our number. It may safely be assumed that these latter, or "unknown" cases, were also congenital, which would give a total of born deaf pupils in our school of 61 per cent. Similar figures relating to pupils in the school in 1918. or five years ago. show 53.6 per cent of the attendance as born deaf. This does not necessarily mean that congenital deafness in our state population is increasing, but rather that deafness caused by disease is, because of advancements made in medical knowledge and treatment, decreasing. The latest statistics likewise give evidence of an apparent decrease in deafness in the total population, for whereas, for many years the ratio of the deaf to the hearing was commonly quoted as one in every 1,500, the ratio is now, according to census figures, one in every 2,333, indicating a very material change for the better. This school, being considered a part of the public school system of the state, provides free instruction to all deaf children resident within its borders, hence deaf children, if otherwise capable, and of proper age, are admitted to the privileges of the school without charge for tuition or board. Children from other states are admitted upon payment of a sum to cover the cost of tuition and board. Pupils are received in the school at the age of six and remain through a regular twelve years' course. Pupils are, however, admitted if older than six ; but that age, on the whole, is considered the best for a deaf child to begin his schooling for his most rapid advancement, as at that age his mind is at the stage of development when primary foundation work possesses and retains elements of interest that do not exist for him </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 when, later on. such work is presented to his more matured mind. Entering school at the age of fourteen or sixteen, the deaf child may at the best receive no more than the merest rudiments of an ed - ucation, and he is thus handicapped for life because of the delay in starting his schooling. This school was founded in 1869 and in the fifty-four years of its history, 1,083 deaf children have received benefits from the training that it provides. Of this number 172 have completed the full course of instruction, receiving the diploma of graduation, the remainder having attained to various stages of advancement to fit them for life and for the performance of its duties and the bearing of its responsibilities. Of the 172 graduates, 61 have been admitted to Gallaudet College the national college for the deaf at Washing - ton, from which nineteen of the sixty-one are graduates. The course of study of the school covering twelve grades is mastered by the average pupil in twelve years. The course includes all subjects taught in the common schools for the hearing up to and including the first year in high school. Our beginning work is necessarily much simpler and more primary than is the beginning work in schools for the hearing, inasmuch as the un - taught deaf child comes to us entirely without speech or language in any form. But with skillful teaching and proper methods, the work at every stage is educative in highest degree, this doubtless because of the very difficulties inherent in it the overcoming of which gives mental develpoment in direct proportion to the mental effort required of the pupil and put forth by him from the beginning steps of instruction to the end of the course. The 187 pupils in school during the term just finished, were taught in eighteen classes, thus averaging a little more than ten pupils instructed by one teacher. Fifteen of our eighteen classes are taught orally, that is, they are taught speech and by speech. The remaining three classes are taught manually, that is, by writing and finger spelling. The sign language, the language of motions or gestures, is not used. Thus it will be understood that all classes, both oral and manual, are taught exclusively by English language methods. It is held that the best way, indeed the only way, to master a language is through its use, its use upon all occasions and for all purposes. Hence our method of teaching English — through use and absolute dependence upon it — secures thereby the best degree of mastery of it attainable in a given case. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Inasmuch as speech and the reading of speech upon the lips are among our principal subjects taught, parents and the home people generally are asked and urged to cooperate with the school in the use they may make of speech and lip-reading in the home life. Practice is the greatest factor in the teaching-learning problem and this practice can be given as well by parents and the family as by the school. Besides the literary course given our pupils, the school provides training along industrial lines — in carpentry and cabinet making, mechanical drawing, printing, and gardening, for the boys ; and in sewing, dressmaking, fancy work, domestic science, laundrying, and housework, for the girls. The aim is to train both the hand and brain in the handling of tools and in the making of useful articles ; also through the use of technical language of a trade, to teach it, and thus to give our deaf children a complete language equipment for service in all the associations and activities of their after life. In our manual training department, in charge of Mr. Ben. S. Delahoy. the boys are given courses in sloyd, joinery, wood - turning, mechanical drawing, cabinet making, and house con - struction. The shop is well equipped with machinery such as the boys will find and use in shops and factories that they will enter after completing their school training. The printing department, in charge of Mr. F. Arthur Clayton likewise is well equipped with type, presses, a linotype, a paper cutter, and other machinery for the printing of the monthly school paper, and also the large amount of job printing sent to us by the Board for the other state institutions under their charge. This latter furnishes a varied line of work for our boys, besides adding to the revenues of the school a not inconsiderable amount. The department of gardening, with the general care of the lawns and greenhouse, is in charge of Mr. Ralph Neilsen. The boys in this department get practice and instruction in out-of-door work, which is both enjoyable and healthful. The products of the garden, vineyard and orchard are all consumed in the school and they thus are a source of saving in the expense of maintenance. The classes in domestic science, under the instruction of Miss Milin Trentham, and in domestic art, under the instruction of Miss Amelia D. Kuster, are given practical instruction in all branches of cooking and sewing. All our girls in their turn as </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 they approach their graduation take full courses in these de - partments and they attain a high degree of skill therein, well equipping them to become house- and home-keepers in after life. As in former years the school receives books frequently and periodicals regularly from the Nebraska Public Library Com - mission, through Miss Nellie Williams, the secretary of the com - mission. This provision keeps our library up to date in its equip - ment of the latest and best books, studiously selected for us by the commission to fit our special needs. Needless to say our pupils appreciate and enjoy to the full the library in all its broadening and cultural effects, and our teachers likewise value it as an ever active help in their work. I wish in conclusion to express my appreciation of the encouraging interest and helpful cooperation of the Board in the work of our school. Also I desire to thank the teachers and officers of the school for their studied interest and constant effort to advance the work and raise the school's standards. Respectfully submitted, FRANK W. BOOTH, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Movement M. F. Present at the beginning of period Admitted : For first time Readmitted 99 26 13 09 9 8 168 35 21 Total enrollment 138 86 224 ischarged : Graduated •. Honorably discharged Left school for other reasons 5 3 12 4 2 11 9 5 23 Total removals I 20 17 37 Present at end of biennium 118 69 187 TABLE II— SEX AND RACE OF PUPILS DMITTED For 1 ' Period Ending June 30, 1923 Race M. F. T. White _ _ Negro 26 0 8 1 34 1 Totals 26 9 35 TABLE III— AGE OF PUPILS ADM TTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Age M. F. T. 5 years _ 6 years _ 7 years _ _ 8 years - _ 9 years 10 years _ __. 12 years _ ;4 years _ - [7 years _ „ !0 years _ 0 8 5 4 3 2 0 1 2 1 2 3 1 1 1 0 1 0 0 0 2 11 6 5 4 2 1 1 2 1 Totals _ I 26 9 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TABLE IV— NATIVITY- OF PU ■IL For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Nativity of Pupils M. F. T. Nebraska Colorado Idaho Illinois . « * Iowa — Missouri - Nevada - South Dakota 20 1 1 0 1 1 1 1 6 0 0 2 0 1 0 0 26 1 1 2 1 2 1 1 Totals ...- 26 9 35 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF PUP LS ADMITTED. For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Nativity of Parents • M. F. T. United States, both parents Foreign, both parents _ Mixed, on parent United States 18 S 3 8 1 0 26 6 3 Totals 26 9 35 TABLE VI— AGE AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITT D BECAME DEAF. For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Age M. F. T. Congenital — .._. ~ Under 1 year _.^..___ 1 and under 2 years ...„.._ 2 and under 3 years - „_.. 3 and under 4 years _ 5 and under 6 years Unknown _ _.. ... 14 5 0 3 1 0 3 3 0 2 2 1 1 0 17 5 2 5 2 1 3 Totals 26 9 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 TABLE VII— EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED. Totals 9 0 9 TABLE IX— PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME WHOSE PARENTS ARE COUSINS OR OTHERWISE RELATED. For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Degree M. F. T. Cousins 2 0 2 TABLE X— CLASSIFICATION OF PUPILS BY ORDINAL YEAR IN SCHOOL OF ALL PUPILS PRESENT, JUNE 30, 1923. For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Extent of Defect M. F. T. Co hearing 'artial hearing 14 6 20 12 3 IS Totals 26 9 35 TABLE VIII— PUPILS ADMITTED FOR F IRST TIME HAVING DEAF RELATIVES For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Relative M. F. T. Deaf brother (or brothers) Deaf sister (or sisters) Deaf aunt Deaf cousin and grand uncle 6 1 1 1 0 0 0 o 6 1 1 1 Number Year M. F. T. First year Second year Third year Fourth year Fifth year Sixth year Seventh year Eighth year Ninth year Tenth year Eleventh year Twelfth year Thirteenth year 18 10 12 9 11 11 3 11 11 9 5 4 4 7 3 7 S ? 4 8 8 4 7 3 5 3 25 13 19 14 16 15 11 19 15 16 8 9 7 Totals 118 69 187 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TABLE XI— DISTRIBUTION OF ALL PUPILS IN SCHOOL JUNE 30, 1923 Number Grade M. F. T. Kindergarten .. First grade Second grade .. Third grade .. Fourth grade .. Fifth grade Sixth grade Seventh grade Eighth grade .. Ninth grade .. Tenth grade _ Eleventh grade Twelfth grade 17 6 23 17 8 25 11 2 13 11 6 17 15 S 20 6 5 11 4 8 12 8 5 13 5 5 10 6 4 10 9 9 18 5 2 7 4 4 8 Totals 118 69 187 TABLE XII— ASSIGNED CAUSES OF DEAFNESS IN ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM All Pupils in School June 30, 1923 Cause of Deafness Number M. F. T. Abscesses _ Adenoids - ~.~ Catarrh _ Cholera infantum Cold _ Congenital - - Diphtheria _ Fever - — - La grippe , Measles Mumps and measles _ Pneumonia - _ Scarlet Fever _ Sickness .._.«_ _ Spinal meningitis Strangulation «. ~ Taking strong medicine Tonsihtis - Whooping cough _ Unknown „ 3 1 1 0 0 65 1 2 0 2 1 2 6 1 20 0 0 0 3 10 2 1 0 1 3 31 0 1 1 1 0 0 4 4 8 1 1 1 1 • 8 S 2 1 1 3 96 1 3 1 3 1 2 10 5 28 1 1 1 4 18 Totals _ 118 69 187 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 AUL&amp; Alii lUUnil Vt KB,SlUti.n^l&gt;, U* i'Ul'IL.S AilfflliTt FOR FIRST TIME AND ALL REMAINING IN SCHOOL AT END OF BIENNIUM County Admitted for First Time All Remaining June 30, 1923 Nebraska : Adams Antelope Arthur Blaine Boone Buffalo Burt Butler Chase Cherry Cheyenne Cuming Custer Dakota Dawes Dawson ! Dixon Dodge Douglas Franklin Frontier Furnas .' Gosper Gage Greeley Hall ' Hamilton Harlan Hitchcock Holt Howard Jefferson Kearney Knox Lancaster Loup Madison Merrick Morrill Nance Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe Platte Polk Red Willow Richardson Saline Sarpy Saunders Seward 0 U 0 1 0 1 1 1 1 0 0 0 1 1 0 0 1 0 7 2 1 0 1 0 0 2 1 0 1 0 0 0 0 0 2 1 0 0 0 1 1 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 1 1 1 1 1 3 2 4 1 4 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 5 55 .5 2 2 0 5 1 2 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 6 1 1 1 4 1 3 1 1 2 2 4 2 6 4 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TABLE XIII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME AND ALL REMAINING IN SCHOOL AT END OF BIENNIUM (Continued) Admitted for first time June 30, 1923 All Remaining County Scotts Bluff Sherman ... 0 2 2 5 Thayer 0 5 Thurston Valley .. 0 1 1 1 Washington Webster _.. 2 5 0 1 York 1 2 Other States : 0 35 8 Wyoming Total 187 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>