<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00018">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00018</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p005">
INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

389 

The causes »f deafness, as reported by parents, are shown 
in the following table : 

LIST OP CAUSES. 

Apoplexy 1 La Grippe 1 " 

Brain fever 41 Lung fever 


Bronchitis 2 Malaria, 



irrh 12 Measles. H 


Cholera infantum 4 Mumps 1 

Cold 13 Paralysis 3 

Congenital 185 Pneumonia 1 

Cramps. 1 Quinsy 1 

Congestion of lungs 1 Scarlet fever 60 

Diphtheria 9 Scrofula 8 

Dropsy of brain 1 Spasms 1 

Diabetes 1 Spinal meningitis T'.t 

Earache 11 Spotted fever 1 

Fall (in infancy) 9 Sunstroke. 1 

Fever (kind unknown) . . 16 Typhoid fever 1"&gt; 

Fits 4 Tubercular affliction 1 

Head hurt (in cyclone) . . 1 Whooping cough 17 

Inflammation of brain ... 2 Yellow fever 1 

Intermittent fever 1 Unknown 104 

Inflammation of ear 14 

Total 6GT 


Grand total 685 

HEALTH. 

The health of our pupils has been comparatively good. Not 
a death has occurred among the children entrusted to us. 
\&lt;&gt;t only is this true of the past two years, but it is true that 
not a single death has been registered within our institution 
walls during the four years we have been in charge. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
390 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

In the winter of 1903 we had a number of cases of scarletin 
— ail light cases, yet carefully treated. The most serious 
sickness we had were four oases of pneumonia in the 
spring of 1904. Two of these were very critical cases, but 
tender nursing and watchful care brought all through safely. 

aively any accidents have happened, and not a pupil lias 
been maimed or crippled. General good health now maintains, 
and peace, comfort and contentment prevails as a result 
of proper oversight. 

CHANGES. 

A number of changes in the force of employed have taken 
place. Vacancies have been made by resignation or to be 
the service, and such places filled by appointment of persons 
qualified and well recommended for this "work. Lack of complete 
and willing cooperation on the part of any employe toward 
the management transforms his service into a positive 
hindrance, and poisons the atmosphere of efficiency. 

LITKRABY DEPARTMENT. 

The literary department of our institution has advanced 
rapidly under the reorganization of three years ago. 

Kie "combined" system is adhered to. The manual and 
departments both flourish, though the oral department is 
casing more rapidly than the manual. 

All children fitted to receive instruction by speech are 
taught to talk and to read lips. Some are taught by use of 
written language and finger spelling, or the manual alphabet 
None are taught "signs," as is so common an error in belief 
among people in general in regard to the deaf. 

The English language is taught, and our aim is to make 
the child speak, write, spell, and think in English. 

•(•dally prepared graded lessons have been compiled, covering 
each day's work in the schoolroom through the 
n years of the school course. This brings him to the 
sixth grade in onr school. The whole course consists of nine 
grades Each pupil is classed according to his advancement, </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
391 

Bno pupil ma\ be promoted from one grade to the n 
tr without passing a satisfactory test. 

Dmrimg the rammer of 1!K&gt;4 we have sent two claawexhibit 
the work of our school at the World's Fair, St. Louis, 
Mo. Each class remained at the exposition a month, demon 
st rat ing methods in vogue in our school and acquainting the 
public to some extent with the fact that our deaf people 
when educated, are bright, intelligent persons, able to make 
their own way in the world in competition with other work 

Eis display was made feasible by the assistance given us 
the Nebraska World's Fair Commission. That coiumispaid 
one-half the total expense, the remainder being paid 
institution funds. 

The booths where these classes recited were daily surrounded 
by crowds of interested spectators. Besides these 
(lasses, we sent specimens of our school work from both the 
literary and industrial departments. Upon our exhibit as a 
whole, for general meritorious work, our school has been 
awarded a gold medal, and shares with some other state institutions 
for the deaf the award of the grand prize in this 
department of education at the World's Fair. 

INDUSTRIAL DKPAKTMENT. 

(he industrial and domestic departments are in excellent 
lition. Pupils old enough to be admitted to the shops 
instructed in carpentry, printing, shoe mending, farming 
horticulture, painting, baking, free-hand drawing, launng, 
dressmaking, and fancy needle work. 

frerything is taught in a practical way, and practical rei 
are sought, not theoretical knowledge; so that each boy 
girl at graduation is prepared to enter upon some useful 
uit and support himself by his own skill. 

We have just recently installed a bakery with the appropriation 
given two years ago. A class of boys, directed by a 
foreman, is being taught the trade, and, incidentally, they </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
392 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

A regular class is instructed also in painting and glazing. 
This not only helps materially in keeping up conditions about 
the institution, but when these boys leave school they can find 
employment at good wages. 

E?re are still other branches of industry that might be 
L with profit to our pupils, and the branches we now 
can be improved by added investment for equipment to 
i their scope. 

REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. 

Steady, careful push along the line of improvements to our 
buildings and grounds has brought them into very good 
shape, with substantial and lasting repairs as far as our limited 
means permitted us to go. 

B»ors, walls, and ceilings in halls and dormitories have 
renewed in the main building and large boys' cottages, 
rooden floors, where possible, are finished with granite 
varnish, and kept bright and clean by polishing with paraffine. 
A great deal of woodwork had to be patched or replaced 
K;w. A vast amount of paints, oil, and varnish had to be 
id. This renovation adds not only to the permanency 
adornment of the buildings, but provides comfort and 
iure to the pupils and those who have the care of them, 
and increases vastly the sanitary completeness of our institution, 
accounting in part for the general good health of our 
pupils and the fact that no deaths have occurred here during 
the last four years. 

I.th the expenditure of three thousand five hundred dol($3,500), 
allowed us by the last legislature for repairs, 
re safe in saying that double that amount of improveis 
in evidence in and about our institution property 
our last report. This result is possible because we 
turned to practical ends the skill of pupils and foremen in tlie 
Pustrial departments, thus saving for the state large exditures 
for labor. </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
393 

EXPENDITURES. 

All expenditures are made carefully and economically. 
Provisions and paiduMH of all kinds are bought, as far as 
possible, at wholesale prices, and other supplies are con- 
Ited for to the lowest bidder — quality and service consid. 
In all cases the interest of the state is subservnl, 
rdl«- 

I am pleased to report that we expect to have no deficiency 
in any fund during this biennium. 

I lie appropriation of six thousand dollars ($6,000) for 
letting this institution with the city waterworks for fire 
ection lias not been used, because the representatives of 
waterworks declined to make what we regard as a fair 
equitable contract for laying mains and providing hylt 
connections and service. However, the necessity for 
protection still exists. 

NEEDS, 

In the last four years we have increased 34 pupils, which 
is equal to more than two classes. We have added only one 
teacher. At the present time we need another teacher, but, 
for lack of funds, can not employ one. Before two more 
years have passed, at the same rate of increase, we will have 
a second and, perhaps, a third additional class. 

Since our last report we have added two distinct industrial 
branches, those of painting and baking. For each branch we 
have a foreman and teacher under pay. For the above reasons 
we are obliged to ask for an increase in our fund for 
teachers' salaries. 

We are now overcrowded for sleeping room, especially in 
the girls' quarters and in the small boys' wing. W»» are very 
much in need of additional space on this account. We have 
long needed a gymnasium. We also need a library and 
museum room. I ask, therefore, that a new cottage be erected 
about 40 by 70, with a high ceiling in basement for a gymnasium 
room, and two stories above, one floor to be used in </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
394 


part for a library and museum, and the rest of the space for 
dormitories. Such an addition would relieve the overcrowded 
conditions of our dormitories and make space needed for educational 
facilities for years to come. 

We need a general remodeling of the basement of south 
whig of main building, with new washroom, bathrooms, and 
sanitary toilet fixtures. The same is true of the hospital 
building. Porches and approaches to main building, kitchen, 
and large boys' cottage need immediate attention. The large 
l' cottage needs a general overhauling inside. The walls 
of the school rooms need painting. The roofs need repainting 
in the next two years. A new shingle roof is needed oa 
the barn. An icehouse should be built, and many minor 
•ssities are demanded for the welfare of the pupils and 
preservation of institution property. 

A fire-escape should be built to accommodate the third 
floor of the front portion of the main building. About twenty 
pupils sleep on that floor, and only one narrow" stairway 
leading from it. 

Ifter 9:30 p.m. we have no other means of lighting closets 
sick rooms except kerosene lamps. This is dangerous, 
jurse. We need a small electric generator and engine to 
ill an independent all-night system of about twenty-fiw 
:ric lights. The exhaust steam can be utilized for power. 
also advise installing an air com pressure pump. This 
be connected with a well now on the grounds, but unti 
ould be of service in providing water for household needs, 
especially valuable for action in case of fire. 

CHANGE IN NAME, 

Eb again recommend that the name of this institution be 
ged from "Institute for the Deaf and Dumb'' to ' 
ca School for the Deaf." Other states are making this 
ge of name, and we approve of the new title. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
400 


No. Name. Age. Residence. Nativity. Date of Admission. 
234-Whitlock, Blanche. . . 7. .Ong German-Am Sept. 17, 1902 

235- Welch, Maggie 15.. Omaha Irish-Am Sept. 26, 1894 

236-Wiltrout, Ida 8. .Hudson American Sept. 21, 1903 

237-Yelenek , James 9 . . Plattsmonth Bohemian-Am ... Jan. 13, 1902 

Oa-Wilman, Hester 20 .. Nebraska City . . American Sept. 29, 1890 

239-Wright, Chloe 20.. Basin American Sept. 20, 1893 

210-Wessen, Effie 6.. Oakland Swedish-Am Sept 24, 1902 

24 l-Zeiler, Jacob 18.. Hastings Russian Sept. 26, 1894 

242-Zabel, Walter H 12. .Western German-Am Sept. 28, 1904 

ELIGIBLE DEAF PERSONS NOT IN SCHOOL AT THIS DATE 

There are about twenty deaf children of school age knows 
to live in the state, but whose parents do not send them to 
school. We believe the number of such children is even 
larger, and recommend that the legislature enact a law requiring 
parents to send their deaf children over seven years 
old to the school for the deaf; because a deaf person, allowed 
to grow up in ignorance, seldom becomes a self-sustaining, 
law-abiding citizen. 

OFFICERS, TEACHERS, AND EMPLOYES. 

R E. Stewart, Superintendent. Miss Nora O. Johnson, 
Matron. L. A. Divine, teacher. J. W. So well, teacher. 
Charles H. Eldridge, teacher. Nannie C. Orr, teacher. Ida 
G. Hendee, teacher. Mary McNamar, teacher. Alberta Begnier, 
teacher. Ota B. Crawford, teacher. Lillian Bamford, 
teacher. Evelyn Humphreys, teacher. May Autenrieth, 
teacher. Anna Kirkpatrick, teacher. Emma Sitton, 
her. Chas. E. Comp, teacher. J. H. Parry, teacher. 
Samuel Goveia, teacher. Lloyd Blankenship, teacher. Lizzie 
Scherer, teacher. Anna Jansen, teacher. E. N. Reynolds, 
teacher. J. F. Rogers, teacher. Henry B. Rogers, 
tier. John H. Vance, physician. Mary Denehan, nurse. 
T. R. Mackey, clerk. Amelia Gillilan, supervisor. Ann 
Richards, supervisor. Jennie Hambel, supervisor. H. E. 
Iwin, engineer. W. O. Gunn, night fireman. Howard 
Gladwin, day fireman. Minnie Jansen, cook. Carrie Haynes, 
laundress. T. R. Jackson, teamster. Maggie Jansen, second </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
401 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Piry Porter, assistant supervisor. John Opfer, janir 
Myers, janitor. Eva Schiltz, house girl. Amanda 
ing room girl. Lula Schiltz, house girl. Edith 
rase girl.. Kittie Peterson, dining room girl. 

In submitting this report I thank you, gentlemen, members 
of the Board, for your encouragement and kind assistance. 
I wish also to thank His Excellency Governor Mickey 
for his firm, wise counsel and constant interest in the welfare 
of this institution. To all our assistants, teachers, employes, 
and helpers, I extend thankfulness for zeal, efficiency, 
faithfulness, and loyalty in duty. 

{mating that the legislature may be disposed to grant 
•al support and favor our plans by appropriating funds 
needed enlargement and improvements, I respectfully 
nit this report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf 
Dumb for the years 1903 and 1904. 

R. E. Stewart, 

Superintendent 

28 </seg>


         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>