<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Second Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1919-02-01">1919-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1919 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">\ THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, President, Davey. Term expires January, 11)21 HON. JOHN E. MILLER, Vice President, Lincoln Term expires January, 1921 HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln Term expires January, 1923 HON. HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward Term expires January. 1923 HON. JOHN R. WEBSTER, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 HON. FRANK D. JUDSON, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 SAMUEL AVERY. Ph. D.. LL. D.. Chancellor *J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc, Director W. H. BROKAW, Director of Extension Service C. A. LEWIS, B. Sc, Bulletin Editor W. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF L. W. CHASE, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy f . A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy H. J. GRAMLICH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene F. W. UPSON, Ph. D., Chemistry J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology and Hygiene J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology M. H- Swenk, A. M., Entomology R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology E. Mead WlLCOX, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology F. E. MUSSEHL, B. Sc, Poultry Husbandry H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Rural Economics W. P. SNYDER, M. S., St&lt;}&gt;erintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine J. A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimenal Substation, Mitchell **L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry A. W. INGERSOLL, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry P. L. Gaddis, A. B., B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy F. D. Keim, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry John Luithly, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry ***G. K. K. Link, Ph. D., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physvology J. 0. RANKIN, A. M., Assistant in Rural Economics • Bv in »ct of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect Feb - ruary 15 1*99. the State Treasurer became ex offirui custodian of the Experiment Station *ro*m Office'oV Dry Land Agriculture, United State. Department of Agri - culture, Washinuton. D. C. •••Granted leave of alwence. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska: SIR — In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Thirty-second Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, Director. February 1, 1919. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Lincoln, February 1, 1919. Mr. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station: Sir — I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirty-second Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS The Official Roster of the Station Letter of Transmittal 4 Governor's Certificate 4 Director's Review — Experimental Work New Experimental Farms Effect of Past Experiments upon Agricultural Practice 8 Spraying Apple Orchards 10 Potato Investigations 10 Plant Disease Control 11 Seed Corn 11 Winter Wheat Selection 11 Oats Selection 11 Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments 12 Sorghum 12 Sheep Feeding Experiments 12 Pig Feeding 12 Cattle Feeding 12 Cow Testing Associations 13 Cost of Milk Production 14 Protein Requirements of Growing Cattle 15 Poultry Investigations 15 Control of Injurious Insects 16 Farm Management Studies 17 Serum Production 18 The North Platte Substation- Rotation and Tillage Methods 20 Winter Wheat 21 Spring Wheat 21 Pump Irrigation 21 Pork Production 21 The Dairy Herd 22 The Scottsbluff Substation- Rotation of Crops Under Irrigation 22 Time of Thinning Test with Sugar Beets 23 Cultural Tests with Oats and Barley 23 Fertilization Test 23 Grass Pasture 23 The Valentine Substation — Forage Crops 24 Potatoes 24 Beans 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">CONTENTS— (Continued) The Station Staff 2t&gt; Improvements 25 Publications 26 Acknowledgments 26 Annual Report of The Extension Service 27 County Agricultural Agent Work 30 Seed Survey 31 Seed Corn 31 Rodent and Insect Control 31 Increased Production and Conservation 32 Smut Control 32 Live Stock Disease Control _ 32 Labor _ 33 Marketing 33 Statistical 33 Home Demonstration Work 34 Canning, Summer of 1917 35 County Fairs _ 35 Teachers' Institutes 36 Farmers' Institutes and Short Courses _ _ 3C Wheat Substitute Campaign 36 Milk Campaign 36 Food Preservation Campaign of 1918 36 Woman's Clubs 37 Junior Work .37 Conclusion 39 Financial Statement 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT EXPERIMENTAL WORK The work of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion for the current year has been as follows : The funds of the Station are obtained from three sources, namely : The Hatch and Adams appropriations are received from the Federal Government in amounts shown by the Fi - nancial Statement of this Report. In addition, certain funds appropriated for general University maintenance, set aside by the Regents for agricultural departments, are used for experimental work. The last Legislature made an appropriation of $25,000 for experimental work for the biennium ending March 31, 1919. They also appropriated $10,000 for investigation in Animal Pathology; $10,000 for the State Entomologist, who is the Entomologist of the Experiment Station ; $3,000 to the State Rotanist, who is the Botanist of the Experiment Station in charge of Plant Pathology investigation. They also made available the cash received from the closing of the Serum Plant, which fund amounted to approximately $50,000. NEW EXPERIMENTAL FARMS In accordance with the appropriations made by the Legis - lature, an Agronomy farm of 160 acres was purchased one and one-half miles east and one mile north of the present farm campus. On account of war conditions, experimental work has not yet been developed upon this farm but it is being operated as a general farm preparatory to its being laid out for more technical experimental purposes. Thru loss of the dwelling house upon this farm by fire in June, 1918, it became necessary to erect a new residence to facilitate the operation of the farm. The cost of this residence was approximately $6,000. The fruit farm of 80 acres authorized by the last legisla - ture was selected in Cass County, near Union, Nebr., and is described as the west half of the southwest quarter of section number 36, in township number 10, of rane;e number 13. An orchard of 40 acres was set upon this farm in 1918 and the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska farm is being operated in a temporary manner until appro - priations are made available to erect necessary buildings for its operation. The State makes direct appropriations also for the main - tenance of Substations at North Platte, Valentine, and Mitch - ell, Nebraska, and for the Nebraska School of Agriculture at Curtis. It also makes direct appropriations for the Exten - sion Service of the College of Agriculture. Plans of work are prepared by each department at the beginning of the calendar year covering the lines of investi - gation proposed for the current year, so that the work of the Station may progress systematically in accordance with ap - proved plans. EFFECT OF PAST EXPERIMENTS UPON AGRICULTURAL PRACTICE When the Nebraska Experiment Station was founded, spring wheat was almost universally grown in this state. The Sta - tion soon recognized that spring wheat was not well adapted to Nebraska and undertook to extend the winter wheat acre - age in regions where spring wheat had been grown. The growing of winter wheat was at once very successful in most of the state south of the Platte River and practically replaced spring wheat. The production of winter wheat has since extended west and north until about ninety per cent of Ne - braska's wheat acreage is winter wheat. The first introduction of winter wheat brought many varie - ties, only a few of which were hardy. The Experiment Sta - tion after extensive tests recommended Turkey Red type as superior to all others. This type of wheat is now grown almost exclusively in Nebraska. When the Experiment Station was organized early varieties of oats were but little used, the medium and late varieties generally being grown. Experiments proved that early varie - ties were superior to late varieties, so that now the practice is entirely reversed. The Kherson oat was introduced directly by the Experi - ment Station from Russia. This oat has since been improved by selecting a highly productive strain which yields from ten to fifteen per cent more than the original imported oat. This new strain has been increased and distributed. The Kherson </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirty-second Annual Report 9 and other early varieties are now grown quite exclusively in Nebraska except in the northern part of the state and in the irrigated areas where a later oat is in favor. Much experimental work has been done with corn. The danger of introducing new varieties from regions of longer or more favorable growing season has been shown. The most progressive farmers now use locally grown seed adapted and selected to suit their region. Methods of tillage have-Jbeen under investigation for many years. Summer tillage in western Nebraska has received a great deal of attention and is recommended with certain severe limitations as a means of crop insurance by storing water in the soil before the crop is planted. Summer tillage is not recommended for indiscriminate use. Studies of live stock conditions warrant the statement that animal disease has been greatly suppressed and brought under control by the advice from the Experiment Station cooperating with State and Federal authorities. Blackleg and hog cholera have been notably reduced by a study of these diseases, by the use of vaccine and serum, and by police measures. The work of the Experimental Station is studying feeding rations has proved first the high value of alfalfa hay. It has been shown that protein in the ration may be furnished either thru roughness or thru concentrated feed. Where alfalfa hay is used a sufficient amount of protein can be normally secured at a much smaller cost than protein furnished thru cottonseed meal, linseed meal, or other concentrates. The importance of balancing a ration with some protein feed, thru either the grain or the roughness fed, has been demonstrated beyond question. Where alfalfa hay is not available, the use of a high priced concentrate has been justified by experience where the cost of the finished product bears a proper relation to the cost of food consumed. The dairy industry has been promoted thru studies in cost of production and thru cow testing associations, which have furnished a basis for the selection of profitable dairy animals. The average butter production per cow in Nebraska is claimed by statistics to be about 160 pounds annually. This is based on an average of four per cent butter fat. Thru selec - tion, breeding, and good management, the average production </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska of the dairy herd at the central plant is 468 pounds of butter annually per cow. The University owns twenty-five cows whose records exceed 600 pounds of butter annually. Twelve exceed 700 pounds and one exceeds 900 pounds of butter an - nually. The list of 700 pounds cows is as follows : NAME BREED LBS. MILK LBS. BUTTER Kittie Gerben Lincoln Holstein 18,283.4 916.35 Allie Lincoln Holstein 17,070.2 865.87 Roxeva Lincoln Holstein 19,361.3 841.45 Katy Gerben Holstein 19,161.2 831.43 Reba Lincoln Jersey 10.631.8 772.98 LaVerna Lincoln Holstein 17,762.5 768.20 Mesa Lincoln Holstein 16,838.9 793.48 Bonne Jean Ayrshire 13,062.3 723.25 Ula Lincoln Jersey 10,389.8 719.56 Qualla Lincoln Holstein 17,500.0 750.00 Ellen Lincoln Holstein 15,773.2 709.73 Nebraska Girl Jersey 10,666.0 701.19 Spraying Apple Orchards. — The work in fruit production has shown the effectiveness of spraying apple orchards to prevent wormy fruit and to prevent fungous diseases on the foliage of trees. The increased profits per acre under such treatment has frequently been as much as $100 over careless methods of cultivation and management. Studies of the best managed orchards have proved that it is profitable to grow commercial orchards in eastern Nebraska, especially in the Missouri River counties where most of the commercial or - chards are now located. Potato Investigations. — The potato projects have special war time significance in that they have to do directly with increased food production. The results secured this year in our potato selection for seed purposes indicate the possibility of increased yields due to careful selection of seed stock. Our rpsults of this season seem to indicate that potatoes that have been grown for several consecutive years under irrigation contain a high pee* cent of degenerate strains which are wholly unfit for seed purposes. It has been demonstrated from these experiments that it is impossible to select sead potatoes from the bin and eliminate these unproductive strains. The results of this year with dry land potatoes show clearly that they may be grown indefinitely in the highlands of north western Nebraska under dry land conditions and remain in a productive state. The results strongly indicate, however, that even potatoes grown under dry land conditions may con-, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-second Annual Report 11 tain a certain amount of unproductive strains. It would seem from the results secured so far that these unproductive strains may be largely eliminated by selection methods. The Tuber Unit system of selection has demonstrated, however, that bin selection would not be the most practical method of eliminat - ing these weak strains, since one is not able to distinguish between an unproductive and a productive tuber. Our results so far suggest that the most practical method of eliminating low yielding strains is by hill selection or some other method of selection that will take into account performance record. Plant Disease Control. — A study of plant diseases has shown that wheat smut and oat smut can be successfully combated thru the treatment of seed, that the black wheat rust is fre - quently spread from the common barberry and that such bar - berry should not be used for ornamental purposes in the wheat growing regions. A study of the potato diseases has shown that such diseases may be materially decreased by treatment and by the selection of seed, free from disease and degeneration, raised in the high altitudes in the northern and western portions of the state. Seed Corn. — A great deal of attention was given in the spring of 1918 to assisting farmers in securing proper seed corn. The corn crop of the previous season was immature on account of hard early freeze and only a small percentage of it was suitable for seed. A large amount of the 1918 seed supply was secured from farmers who had not sold all of their 1916 crop. The balance was obtained from the 1917 crop thru careful selection and testing. Winter Wheat Selection. — During the past sixteen years extensive wheat breeding experiments have been conducted with the result of isolating several superior strains of Turkey Red, which have been placed in the hands of farmers. Among the most promising strains developed are No. 6, No. 16, and No. 60. Oat Selection. — In oat selection, the Burt, Texas Red, Ne - braska No. 21 (white Kherson), and the original Kherson C911 - linue to be the leading varieties in central and eastern Ne - braska. Great losses in the oats crop are being largely over - come by applying the formalin treatment to seed to prevent smut. Tillage experiments show that the press drill reduces </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 12 the amount of seed required and increases the certainty of a stand to such an extent that it should be universally used. Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments. — Two hundred and twenty-four plats have been set aside for testing various crops and fertilizers to determine what sequence of crops would give the best average yields and what fertilizers, if any, are neecssary in order to produce maximum profits from ordi - nary farm crops. Sorghum. — The use of sorghum as a forage crop is highly recommended thruout all the central and western portions of the state where alfalfa hay and corn fodder are difficult to obtain. Where forage is scarce, the Station recommends cutting corn and husking either with a shredder or by hand in order that the roughage may be used in feeding animals. Sheep Feeding Experiments. — Experiments carried on with alfalfa hay and various grain rations during the winter of 1918-1919 showed that all feeds were relatively too high in price to market them in fattening lambs profitably. The larg - est profit was made upon the lots receiving hominy feed or hominy feed and oil meal as a half of their grain ration, the other half being corn. Previous experiments in using hominy for the production of pork did not show it to be more valuable than corn. The experiments will be repeated to determine whether these results are confirmed by later trials. Com - parisons were made between oats, barley, hominy feed, and gluten feed as substitutes for corn. Pig Feeding. — Experiments were undertaken on a large scale to increase pork production. More than 600 hogs were put upon experimental rations during the winter of 1918-1919 to study the utilization of soft corn, the economy of tankage, the value of semi-solid butermilk, and the use of hominy and barley as partial and complete substitutes for corn. In these experiments self feeders were used and found to be practical, the tankage and other concentrates being fed in a separate self-feeder. Tankage was profitably fed in all instances, in - creasing both the rate of gain and the daily profit per pig. Cattle Feeding. — The experiments in feeding cattle for the present winter are limited to comparisons of different supple - mentary protein rations where corn and alfalfa were fed as </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-second Annual Report 13 standard rations to all lots, both with and without corn si - luge. The addition of 1.71 pounds of cottonseed nut cake failed to increase the rate of daily gain but did increase the feed required per one pound gain by .86 pound and the cost of one hundred pounds of gain $2.16. It also decreased the profit $2.65 per steer. The grinding of corn and alfalfa when fed in conjunction with cottonseed nut cake gave a .32 pound per day larger £ain, at a materially reduced cost per one hundred pounds gain, namely, $2.08, and increased the profit per head from $5.66 to $11.00. It also reduced the pork produced from hogs following the steers from 42.6 pounds to 28.9 pounds for each steer. The feeding of snapped corn, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa hay in comparison with shelled corn, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa hay gave a slightly greater daily gain and a very much cheaper cost per one hundred pounds of gain, namely, $5.55. The feeding of the snapped corn gave, exclusive of pork, a profit of $13.87 in comparison to $1.26 loss where shelled corn was fed, and, inclusive of pork, a profit of $19.85 in comparison to $5.56. The feeding of a heavy silage ration, while it did not pro - duce as much finish as the feeding of the corn in conjunction with cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa, did result in considerable Meshing, and a market price which left a margin in favor of its use. This margin of profit per steer amounted to $1.49 in spite of the fact that the sales price was $1.00 per hundred pounds less than where the steers received a heavy feed of corn. Cow Testing Associations. — Several cow testing associations are in operation in the state, the Experiment Station cooperat - ing with farmers in this work. The result of testing individ - ual herds has been to give the farmer an accurate idea of the value of each cow being tested, enabling him to dispose of such cows as are unprofitable and thereby increase the aver - age profit of the herd. Each cow testing association is gen - erally made up of from twenty to twenty-five dairy herds which are tested once each month for milk and butter fat production and the rations used are determined according to </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska the best dairy standards. Such methods have without doubt decreased the cost of production. Cost of Milk Production. — Under cooperative arrangements with the United States Department of Agriculture, a cost ac- counting study has been carried on with a group of farmers in Sarpy and Douglas Counties in an effort to determine the different elements of cost in the production of milk at differ- ent seasons of the year and the price at which milk can be produced under such conditions. Figures for one year are now available but a second year's data are desired to complete this study. The data gathered show that feedstuffs have advanced in price from 100 to 200 per cent while only recently has milk advanced as much as 75 per cent above pre-war prices. Enough work has been done to indicate that the following formula (M. A. C.)i with prices modified for Nebraska conditions, will give a good idea of the factors that should be given considera- tion in calculating the real cost of milk production. Estimated Cost of Producing IOC lbs. of 3.5 per cent Milk for Winter Months. Modified (M. A. C.) formula and Based on Nebraska Prices. Home grown grains 10.5 lbs. @ $48.00 per ton $ .25 Purchased grains 18.7 lbs. @ 60.00 per ton .56 Hay 46.6 lbs. @ 25.00 per ton .58 Other dry forage 21.7 lbs. @ 12.00 per ton .13 Silage 149.1 lbs. @ 9.00 per ton .67 Bedding 17.6 lbs. @ 6.00 per ton .05 Labor (man) 2.3 hours .30 per hour .69 Labor (horse) 12 hours .15 per hour .02 Hauling milk 25 per cwt. .25 Taxes, Int. &amp; Dep. on Cattle $110.00 @ 12% for 7 mo. .17 Taxes, Int. &amp; Dep. on Buildings 117.38 @ 10% for 7 mo. .16 Int. &amp; Dep. on Equipment 12.09 @ 18.61% for 7 mo. .03 Veterinary Services and Drugs 01 Losses due to death 03 Miscellaneous costs .08 Add 10% for managerial ability, risks and omitted items 37 $4.05 Credit for manure. 230 lbs. &lt;g $1.00 12 Value of calves at birth offset by sire services 00 Winter months — estimated net cost of production $3.93 Sugar Substitutes in Ice Cream Manufacture. — During the sugar famine of the summer of 1918, the Dairy Department conducted many experiments in sugar saving substitutes for ice cream making. Bulletin No. 168 upon this subject was largely adopted by ice cream' manufacturers as furnishing the </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-second Annual Report 15 best available information on this subject. A summary of the conclusions presented in this bulletin are given below. Four formulas have been worked out which save from 30 per cent to 50 per cent of cane sugar in the mix. The ice cream prepared according to these four formulas meets the requirements of good ice cream. Corn syrup dissolves with difficulty in cold cream. When added to cream before pasteurizing, it dissolves readily. In hydrolyzing the syrups excessive heating should be avoided. When invert sugar and corn syrup are used as the only source of sweetening, a rather noticeable syrupy flavor is imparted to the ice cream. When invert sugar, cane sugar and corn syrup are used in the pro - portions indicated in Formula No. 4. no objectionable flavor is noticeable. It is thought that hydrolyzing corn syrup in the presence of an acid will enhance its sweetening properties. In addition to saving cane sugar, all four formulas lower the cost of sweetening per gallon of ice cream. Corn sugar can replace 50 per cent of cane sugar in the mix. None of the substitutes so far tried will satisfactorily replace all the cane sugar in the ice cream mix. Protein Requirements of Growing Cattle. — For the past two years, we have been carrying investigations to determine the protein requirements of growing cattle with a view of deter - mining the minimum protein requirements for the proper development of young animals, and, in consequence, endeavor - ing to reduce the cost of production to the lowest point con - sistent with favorable growth. Poultry Investigations. — An extensive poultry department has been established carrying the leading breeds of fowls adapted to this region. Feeding experiments are in progress to determine the essentials of a satisfactory ration for the growth of baby chicks. Experiments are also conducted to determine the best methods of managing commercial flocks. An outline of the work and results so far secured is herewith given. Breeding Project: 1. Trapnest records of the first year's production of 350 fe - males, typical representatives of five of our most practical breeds (Barred Plymouth Rock, S. C. Rhode Island Red, S. C. White Leghorn, Buff Orpington, White Wyandotte) have been secured. 2. Actual production data have been checked with certain com - monly used capacity tests for selecting good layers. The conclusion is made that altho these capacity tests have some value and altho the "capacity" quality should </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 16 always be emphasized, the use of the trapnest is the only way to get positive data on egg production. 4. The best laying hens as shown by trapnest records have been used for breeding stock for the further study of the inheritance of egg production. 5. The pullet offspring of each mating is being trapnested anil a study of their egg production is also being made. 6. Two pedigree breeding pens of S. C. White Leghorns were used in 1918, each headed by a male with several generations of high egg producing ancestry. It is noted that a large proportion of the pullets sired by one male (109M) are much better layers than the pullets sired by the other male (72M). 7. Breeding stock from these trapnested birds is being dis - tributed to farm poultry raisers and poultry breeders. Feeding Project: 1. As a basis for experimental work to determine the essen - tials of a satisfactory ration for the growth of baby chicks, comparisons of the efficiency of single grains were made. Corn, wheat, barley, oats, millet, and kafir were used for feeding. None of the rations made up of single grains were at all adequate for normal growth but a difference in effi - ciency was noted. The order of efficiency was as follows: Wheat, millet, corn, barley, oats, and kafir. Control of Injurious Insects. — During the year experimental work in the control of several injurious insects has been car - ried on. The most extensive work has been experiments and demonstrations on the control of grasshoppers in western and northern Nebraska. The Economic Entomologist of the Sta - tion cooperated with the County and District Agents in fifteen of the western and northern counties of the state in fighting grasshoppers. Poisoned baits were the chief control methods employed, and in the irrigated district of the North Platte valley alone ten car loads of bran and as many tons of poison were used. The efforts of the farmers to control the grass - hopper scourge were at least partially successful, and efforts are being made at this time to better organize the interested counties so that the grasshoppers will be held in more com - plete control during the coming season. In addition to the poisoning campaigns in the various counties, campaigns to de - stroy the eggs by cultivation were made in several counties during the early spring and late fall, and the use of an im - proved type of hopperdozer was encouraged thruout the in - fested area. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty-second Annual Report 17 Cutworms of several species being injurious in several coun - ties of southwestern Nebraska, experiments and demonstra - tions were carried on in cooperation with several County Agents during the year. The first and second broods of the sugar-beet webworm proved very injurious to sugar beets in certain portions of the North Platte valley and the Station Entomologist made investigations resulting in recommenda - tions for the control of this pest which were carried out in cooperation with several agents of the counties affected. Later in the season injuries by white grubs in the wheat fields of southeastern Nebraska received attention, and an outbreak of the western wheat-head army worm in the Lodge - pole valley counties was investigated. In both cases recom - mendations were made to the County Agents and cooperation to put them into effect was instituted. Other insect pests receiving attenion during the year by the Station Entomologist were the corn-ear worm, the corn-root worm, the corn-root louse, the stalk-borer, blister-beetles, seed-corn beetles, and rield crickets. During the year rather extensive experiments were con - ducted along the line of treating seed corn to avoid attack by rodent pests, and of poisoning and trapping pocket gophers. No definite results were obtained in the first mentioned experi - ments, but very satisfactory results were obtained in the pocket gopher experiments, and campaigns of pocket gopher eradica - tion were carried on in cooperation with the County Agents of four of the most heavily infested counties of eastern Ne - braska. These experiments and exterminative campaigns are to be continued during the coming season. Farm Management Studies. — Studies of different systems of farm cropping and management have been in progress for a number of years, surveys being made of many different farms to determine what general system of management is most profitable in any given region. Farm account books have also been distributed to 15,000 different farmers in the state to assist them in checking accurately the price of farm prod - ucts, the profit per acre upon different crops, and the labor income or profit per farm upon these individual farms. An analysis of these farm accounts is also of assistance in deter - mining what were the profitable and the unprofitable feat - ures upon each farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 18 Studies of direct methods of marketing farm products thru cooperative organizations have been in operation thruout the year and much valuable information has been secured bearing upon this subject. Circular No. 5, "From Car Door to Con - sumer," represents a study of one type of direct marketing mentioned above. Marketing Nebraska potatoes in carlots also constituted one of the studies in direct marketing. Serum Production. — The serum plant was closed about January 1, 1918, upon an understanding with the Legislature, which provided for the distribution of the revolving fund used in the manufacture and storage of serum. During the latter part of the summer of 1918, the shortage of serum and the difficulty experienced by farmers in securing it resulted in a strong demand by the farmers' organizations for the reopen - ing of the plant. The Governor made a special request to the Regents in the matter and arrangements were made to reopen the plant. On November 1, 1918, the Superintendent, Dr. S. W. Alford, who had previously been in charge of the plant, returned to this work and proceeded to put this plant in working order. At this date, February 1. 1919, about four hundred hogs are in use for producing serum, 500,000 c. c. of serum are ready for the final test, and the capacity production of the plant will soon reach 1,000,000 c. c. per month. TECHNICAL INVESTIGATIONS The following lines of technical investigation are in progress at the Station. Some of these lines have been carried for a number of years. Adams Projects: No. 2, A Study of the Stem End Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber. No. 3, A Study of Leaf Curl, Leaf Roll, and Rosette and Relate'! Diseases of the Potato Plant. No. 4, A Study of the Life History and Parasitism of Rhizoctonia as Related to Irish Potato Diseases. No. 5, The Study of Nummularia Discreta, as the Cause of the Blister Canker of Apple. — Its Prevention and Control. No. 6, The Study of the Anatomy of the Potato Plant. No. 7, The Water Soluble Constituents of the Soils of the Transi- tion Region. No. 8, A Study of the Chemical Factors Concerned in the Forma- tion of Pigments in Certain Varieties of Corn. No. 9, A Study of the Formation and Persistence of Prussic Acid in Kafirs and Sweet Sorghums. No. 10, Methods of Determining Humus. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-second Annual Report 19 No. 11, Corn Breeding Experiments. No. 12, Water Requirements of Crops. No. 13, Competition in Cereals. No. 14, Alfalfa Pollination by Insects. No. 15, Food Requirements of Growing Cattle. No. 16, Winterkilling Investigations. No. 17, Heredity Investigation. No. 62, Chemical Studies on Silage. No. 67, The Life-History of Wheat-Infesting Sawflies. No. 69, The Life-History of Several Common Cutworms. No. 72, Physiological Studies in the Formation of Silage. No. 85, Protein Requirements for Growing Cattle. Hatch and State Projects: No. 18, Determination of Experimental Error. No. 19, Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies with Small Grains. Classification of Oats Varieties. No. 20, No. 21, Soy Bean Tests. No. 22, Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments. No. B, Cooperative Fertilizer Tests. Soil Moisture Investigations. No. 24, No. 25, Rodent Investigations. No. 2fi, Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. No. 27, Treatment of Illinois or Blister Canker of Apple Trees. No. 28, Spraying Apples, Pears, Grapes, and Bush Fruits. Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. Principles of Orchard Culture. No. 29, No. 30, No. 81, Hill Selection of Potatoes. No. 32, Home Production of Seed Tubers. No. 33 Fruit Breeding. No. 34, Corn Silage vs. Alfalfa Hay as Feeds for Milk Production. No 35 Corn Silage vs. Alfalfa Silage as Feeds for Milk Production. No. 36, A Study of the Soiling System under Nebraska Conditions. No. 37 A Cooperative Study of Dairying under Conditions of West- ern Nebraska. No. A Study of the Underlying Factors Necessary for the 38 Operation of a Successful Cooperative Creamery. Factors Affecting the Efficiency of Hand Separators and No. :)9 causes of Variation in Cream Tests. No, 40. Forage Crops for Hogs. No. 41 Fattening Cattle. No 42 Farm Survey. Farm Survey. No. 43 No. 44 Handling Silage. No, 45 Hog House Investigations. No, 46 Draft of Wagons. No, 47 Pump Irrigation. Nursery and Orchard and Nursery and Greenhouse Stock No. 48, Inspection, under State Law. No, 49 Serum Production. No, 63 The Organic Constitutents of Soils. No M Sweet Clover Hay vs. Alfalfa Hay as Feeds for Milk Pro- duction. No 65 Rations for Fattening Lambs. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska No. 66, A Study of the Efficiency of Various Types of Cream Cooling Tanks. No. 68, The Relation of the Colloidal Properties of Gluten to Prob - lems of Milling and Baking. No. 70, Plant Breeding. No. 71, Lamb Feeding. No. 73, Farm Survey Based on Agricultural Census. No. 74, Direct Marketing in Car Lots. No. 75, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1917. No. 76, To Improve Dairy Cows by Grading up with Pure Bred Si No. 77, Grasses and Grass Mixtures for Pasture Purposes No. 78, Rations for Fattening Sheep. No. 79, Rations for Fattening Hogs. No. 80, Potato Selection for Seed Purposes. No. 81, Tuber Line Selection of Potatoes for Increased Yields. No. 82, A Study of the Inheritance of Egg Production. No. 83, The Essentials in a Ration for Baby Chicks. No. 84, Cost of Milk Production in Nebraska. THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION The North Platte Substation farm was established in 1903 and was first operated in 1904. It consists of a tract of level bench land of about 280 acres, a tract of high level table land of about 140 acres, and about 1500 acres of canyon pasture, which grows excellent grass in good years and will graze a mature cow on from eight to twelve acres of land. Rotation and Tillage Methods. — About two hundred and sixty plats are devoted to a study of the effect of crop sequence and cultivation. This work has been in progress for about twelve years. It involves comparisons of continuous cropping, rota - tion cropping, alternate cropping and summer tillaee. sprinsr and fall plowing, deep and shallow plowing, and other less common practices. A recent report on rotations and tillage methods indicates the following conclusions: "The weather conditions of the season during which the crop is grown are the greatest favor in controlling yields. "The seasonal precipitation has a much greater influence on crop production than methods of seed bed preparation, crop sequence, or manure. "During favorable seasons profitable crops have been raised by all methods and during specially unfavorable seasons profit - able crops have not been raised by any methods. Summer till - age has been less profitable in producing corn or spring grain than ordinary methods. However, during unfavorable years </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-second Annual Report 21 summer tillage has given a large increase in yields over com - mon practices and thus has served as a partial insurance r gainst entire crop failure. "As a single crop, corn ranks above any of the spring small trrain crops in profit returned where the stover and grain are both used." Winter Wheat. — Winter wheat was mostly killed during the winter of 1917-1918. All plats harvested averaged 7 bushels per acre. A five-acre field following corn yielded 5.6 bushels. An adjoining five-acre tract following summer tillage yielded 19 bushels per acre. Spring Wheat. — The average yield of spring wheat varieties was 8.9 bushels per acre. The highest yields were Marquis and Preston. Under continuous cropping, spring wheat yielded 3.7 bushels per acre. Following summer tillage, the yield was 17.5 bushels per acre. The seven-year average, 1912-1918, of winter wheat was 14.5 bushels per acre and of spring wheat 10.9 bushels per acre. Pump Irrigation. — An irrigation pump is in use upon this station with capacity to water about eighty acres of land. In 1918 dry land potatoes yielded 84.5 bushels per acre while irrigated potatoes yielded 135 bushels per acre. Ensilage corn without irrigation yielded 4.5 tons per acre against 9.1 tons under irrigation. Winter wheat yielded 8.3 bushels per acre without irrigation and 26.2 bushels per acre under irrigation. Pork Production. — Many years of experience in growing and feeding hogs at this station have shown that all standard meth - ods of growing hogs on alfalfa pasture and grain rations are profitable. A medium grain ration fed in summer utilizes more of the alfalfa pasture than a full grain ration fed by use of a self-feeder. Shelled corn and alfalfa pasture have gen - erally produced the cheapest gains. When corn has been ex - tremely high priced, as is now the case, tankage has proved profitable when fed to fattening hogs upon rations of corn and alfalfa hay. In wintering mature brood sows, four years' experiments show that a ration of equal parts of ground corn and alfalfa meal mixed together and fed in a self-feeder has given excel - lent results. Brood sows weighing 387 pounds have gained an average of 95 pounds each in four months upon such rations. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska They have also farrowed good litters following such treatment. Growing sows or young gilts should have about three-fourths of their ration of grain and one-fourth of chopped alfalfa hay. Upon this they will make sufficient growth and produce good litters. The Dairy Herd. — A herd of dairy cattle was established four years ago and at the present time consists of about thirty head of pure-bred Holstein cows and twenty grade cows. The following milk and butter records have been produced by pure- bred Holstein cows in the North Platte herd: Lbs. Milk Lbs. Butter THE SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION Rotation of Crops under Irrigation. — In the irrigated rota - tion experiments there are nine plants of continuous cropping, eleven 2-year rotations, three 3-year rotations, four 4-year rotations, and four 6-year rotations. Three 2-year rotations, one 3-year rotation, and one 6-year rotation receive barnyard manure periodically at the rate of 12 tons per acre. There are eight crops used in this experiment and are arranged in differ - ent combinations. They are alfalfa, sugar beets, corn, flax, oats, potatoes, and winter and spring wheat. Up to date the most striking facts brought out by these rota - tion experiments are: (1) Low yields from continuous cropped plats; (2) poor grade and extremely scabby potatoes from short rotations; (3) fall seeding of alfalfa in grain stubble is better than seeding alone in the spring, except during seasons when grasshoppers are bad, then early spring seeding has been preferable; (4) and the beneficial effect of barnyard manure and the residual effect of alfalfa. During the past season sugar beets grown on manured plats yielded an average of 21.3 tons per acre, as compared with 14.3 tons from plats not manured, or a difference of 7 tons in favor of the manured plats. Potatoes grown on alfalfa land produced more than twice as many bushels per acre as when grown on land that has never been in alfalfa. All other crops show the same marked increase. 1 &amp; B Calamity De Kol Rose 18,241 j &amp; B Becky Blesky Lyons 20,549 Sliza Cornucopia 16,870 Jlothilda Topsy Lyons 14,673 1, &amp; B Re Becky Segis 14,004 847.38 750.00 728.20 625.57 606.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-second Annual Report 23 Time of Thinning Test with Sugar Beets. — The practice of contracting a larger acreage of sugar beets than can be culti - vated and thinned at the proper season often seriously reduces the yield per acre. To determine the effect of this late thinning upon the yield, an experiment was undertaken in thinning beets at different dates, namely, June 8, June 18, and June 28, these dates representing early, medium, and late thinning in the sugar beet region of western Nebraska. The following table gives the average yield in tons per acre from beets thinned at different times: Average of 6 plats thinned on June 8, 19.26 tons Average of 6 plats thinned on June 18, 19.02 tons Average of 6 plats thinned on June 22, 15.83 tons. These results, together with the results secured in 1917. show very conclusively that delayed thinning results in a marked decrease in the yield. Cultural Test with Oats and Barley. — The question is often asked, "Should I plow my corn land on which I am going to seed oats or barley?" To secure information as to the ad - visability of plowing corn stubble land for oats or barley, the following experiment was conducted during the past two summers. The yields given below were obtained in 1918 and are recorded in bushels per acre: Oats Barley Average yield from 3 plowed plats 84.6 79.4 Average yield from 3 disked plats 96.5 80.2 Average yield from 3 spring toothed plats..93.4 75.0 The results from the two years' tests seem to show that plowed corn land has no advantage over disked corn land for oats or barley and disking is much quicker and cheaper. Fertilization Test. — In this test commercial fertilizers — dry blood, ground bone, and a mixture of the two — and barnyard manure were used in different amounts per acre. The ex - periment began in 1917 and was continued during the past summer. Sugar beets was the crop used. As yet the com - mercial fertilizers have not caused any great increase in yield while barnyard manure has shown a decidedly beneficial effect. This test would seem to indicate that the soils of the North Platte valley are lacking in humus rather than in mineral elements of plant food. Grass Pasture. — Experiments were conducted during the </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska summer which indicate that sweet clover is more promising for pasture than the varieties of grasses which were tested. It is recommended that sweet clover be sown in the spring with a grain crop and protected by sufficient irrigation so that it will furnish some pasture during the latter part of the sum - mer. Treated in this way it will furnish a maximum amount of pasture during the second season and will then be plowed up and the land planted to small grain, corn, or sugar beets. THE VALENTINE SUBSTATION The leading lines of work conducted at the Valentine Sub - station are as follows: Forage Crops. — Corn, sorghums, Sudan grass, and alfalfa have been grown as forage crops at the Valentine Substation. Among these, corn has probably been most successful, and is depended upon almost altogether as a crop to be used for silage. Experiments with sweet clover and alfalfa showed that sweet clover is unlikely to suffer from too early seedings. The seedings completed before frost was out of the ground were entirely successful. The first seeding of sweet clover was done on April 7. Alfalfa seeded at this date was a failure, and no successful seeding of alfalfa was accomplished before May 10, after the severe frosts were over. Successful seed - ings of alfalfa were made on light, sandy soil until the sec - ond week in June. No seeding of sweet clover was success - ful after the third week in April. Our experience indicated that early seeding of sweet clover is desirable but that alfalfa in this region should not be sown until the danger of frost is over, and in general should not be sown unless there is moisture in the ground sufficient for germination. Potatoes. — On unmulched, heavy soil, potatoes grown from seed raised under mulch showed an increase of 20 per cent over those from seed grown by ordinary methods. Beans. — Several varieties of beans were grown. Most of these were a failure on account of drouth. The Pinto bean seemed to stand the drouth better than other varieties. No other variety matured sufficiently to be harvested. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-second Annual Report 25 THE STATION STAFF Mr. L. O. Vose, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural-Chemistry, resigned March 31, 1918. Mr. J. R. Cooper, M. S., resigned as Associate in Horticul - ture April 1, 1918, to accept a position as head of the Depart - ment of Horticulture of the University of Arkansas. Mr. R. P. Crawford, A. B., Agricultural Editor, resigned April 1, 1918, to enter the United States Department of Ag - riculture. Mr. E. L. Jenkins, M. S., Assistant Animal Husbandman, v/as granted a leave of absence June 1, 1918, to enter the army, and since his discharge from the army has resigned. Mr. Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy, resigned August 31, 1918. Mr. R. R. Spafford, A. M., resigned August 31, 1918, as Assistant in Rural Economics, to accept a position in the United States Department of Agriculture. Mr. C. A. Lewis, B. Sc, was appointed Agricultural Editor April 1, 1918. Mr. John Luithly, B. Sc, was appointed Assistant in Dairy - ing April 1, 1918. Mr. J. W. Rovner, B. Sc, was appointed Assistant in Dairy Husbandry May 1, 1918. Mr. H. M. Martin, V. M. D., was appointed Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene July 1, 1918. Mr. John 0. Rankin, A. M., was appointed Assistant in Rural Economics September 1, 1918. IMPROVEMENTS Agricultural Engineering Hall has been completed and is ih use for departmental purposes. The laboratory unit for the Department of Animal Pathol ogy and Hygiene is in process of construction. This build - ing will cost about $70,000. A new residence has been built on the Agronomy farm at a co.it of $6,000, to take the place of the one which was burned in June, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 26 PUBLICATIONS The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Thirty-first Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February 1, 1918. bulletin No. 163 (Popular edition of Research Bulletin No. 14) (Volume XXX, Article III). Freezing Injury of Seed Corn. By T. A. Kiesselbach and J. A. Ratcliff. Distributed April 15, 1918. 15,000 copies. Bulletin No. 164 (Report of Experimental Substation, North Plate, Nebraska, Bulletin No. 19). Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran in Grain Ration for Dairy Cows. Distributed July, 1918. 10,000 copies. Bulletin No. 165 (North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 20). Growing Pigs in Summer. By W. P. Snyder. Distributed June 15, 1918. 10,000 copies. Bulletin No. 166. Soy Beans. By T. A. Kiesselbach. Dis - tributed May 1, 1918. 10,000 copies. Bulletin No. 167. Feeding Lambs in the Fall. By H. J. Gramlich. Distributed July, 1918. 8,000 copies. Bulletin No. 168. Susrar-Saving Substitutes in Ice Cream, lly J. H. Frandsen, J. W. Rovner, and John Luithly. Dis - tributed July, 1918. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 169. Forage Crops. By T. A. Kiesselbach. Distributed December, 1918. 10,000 copies. Bulletin No. 170. Fall Lamb Feeding. By H. J. Gramlich. Distributed October, 1918. 8,000 copies. Research Bulletin No. 13. Studies Concerning the Elim - ination of Experimental Error in Comparative Crops Tests. By T. A. Kiesselbach. Accepted for publication December, 1917. Distributed June 15, 1918. 4,000 copies. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly newspapers, especially those papers located within the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-second Annual Report ■21 ANNUAL REPORT OF THE EXTENSION SERVICE The Director's Report for the year ended June 30, 1918. The Extension Service is a joint organization of the Exten - sion forces of the College of Agriculture, University of Ne - braska, and the United States Department of Agriculture. All work in the State is carried on in cooperation with local organiations. These organizations take the form of Farm Bureaus and devote their attention to Extension work with men, women and children. The public school system is an effective cooperator in developing Extension work with boys and girls. The unprecedented demands caused by the world war for the stimulation of food production and food conservation have necessitated unusual development of all Extension work with th^se ends in view. The administrative organization consists of a Director, Ag - risultural Editor, County Agent Leader, Home Demonstra - tion Leader, Junior Extension Leader, an executive Secretary, iii charge of finances, and a Leader of Specialists, who was hader of the "Extension School' project, in charge of all Extension meetings. The office organization consisted of a stenographic office and a combination duplicating-mailing room, in both of which all individual workers were directly responsible to the executive Secretary. The Extension Service has the same relative position as regards the organization of the Agricultural College and Ex - periment Station that existed in past years. There has been no change in relationship involving the Extension Service and the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. War organizations and agencies, such as the State Council of Defense and the State Food Administration, have asked an increasing amount of assistance from the Extension Service. While there was no official relationship between these organizations and the Service, there has been the closest cooperation, and the Exten - sion Service has put out a large amount of material from its multigraph and mailing section at the request of these organ - izations. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 28 The State Department of Public Instruction has from time to time requested articles for publication and has sought as - sistance on agricultural problems from the Extension Service. The State Director of Vocational Education under the Smiih- Hughes Act has negotiated with the Extension Service with the idea of having the supervision of Agriculture in Smith- Hughes schools undertaken by the Extension Service. An agreement has been reached and at the present time the Junior Extension Leader is giving the necessary time to the supervision of the Smith-Hughes schools which have been es - tablished in the State. This relationship bids fair to solve the problem of cooperation, involving boys' and girls' club work and vocational education. Farmers' Institutes have gradually been discontinued in Nebraska and in their place has been substituted the work of the Farm Bureau with its special meetings and definite program of work. Four days' Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics are frequently conducted. A few in - stitutes still survive in some parts of the State, but these are being encouraged to affiliate with the Farm Bureau and to turn their program into its program. The Extension Service has been furnishing specialists to assist dairymen's associations and the Corn Improvers' As - sociation and the various women's organizations of the State. One of the most notable changes in relationship between the Extension Service and the farmers' organizations of the State has been the formation of an Advisory Council to the Exten - sion Service. This Advisory Council is composed of repre - sentatives from the various bona fide state-wide farmers' or - ganizations. The following organizations are cooperating: The Farmers' Union, the Grange, the Farmers' Congress, the Nebraska State Live Stock Breeders' Association, and the State Farm Bureau Association. These five organizations are all of the state-wide farmers' organizations which we have in Nebraska. The Advisory Council thus formed has only an advisory capacity in relation to the Extension Service. It is called upon to assist the Extension Service in formulating plans for new projects, and to help develop the various new agricultural interests that are coming up from time to time. Such a plan brings about a most wholesome cooperation be tween the farmers' organizations of the State and the Col - lege of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-second Annual Report 29 The sources of the revenue which is disbursed by the Exten - sion Service, thru the Finance Office of the University and the State Auditor and Treasurer, are the Federal Srnith-Lever apportionment and the direct State appropriation for Exten - sion work. This State appropriation is in the form of an apportionment from what is known as the State Activities Fund. During the fiscal year ending June 30, 1918, Nebras - ka's Federal Smith-Lever apportionment was $38,575.71. The Extension Service portion of the State Activities Fund was $33,000, of which $28,575.71 was used as Smith-Lever offset. This left a balance of $4,424.29 for miscellaneous expenditures not governed by Smith-Lever account. Actual miscellaneous expenditures were only $2,949.01. The College makes a con - siderable contribution to Extension work by donating the time which is occasionally devoted to Extension work in the field by members of the College and Experiment Station staff. On these occasions the Extension Service pays the expenses only. County funds appropriated to County Farm Bureau for the employment and expenses of County Agricultural and Home Demonstration Agents make a further addition to the actual amount of money spent for Extension work in the State. Counties also make a considerable contribution to Extension work thru the time which County Superintendents of Schools devote to the promotion and assistance of Junior Extension work in their respective counties. Local school districts make contributions in the form of time devoted to Junior Extension work by a regularly paid teacher and in he form of salaries and expenses paid to supervisors of Home work organized during the summer by the Extension Service. To these sources of Extension financial support may be added the membership in Farm Bureaus, Farmers' Asso - ciations, and Home-Makers' Associations, such funds being used to defray the expenses of local Extension meetings. iThe publications of the Extension Service consists of bul - etins, emergency bulletins, the Extension News Service, and i news service for daily newspapers. Six regular bulletins were published during the year endin^ June 30, 1918. They were: No 45. Handling Silage. No 46. Feeding Dairy Cows. No 47. Farm Cheese-Making. No. 48. Well-planned Meals. (Reprinted.) </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 30 No. 49. A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard. No. 50. Home Vegetable Gardening. The emergency bulletins are: No. 15. Controlling Insect Pests of the Garden. No. 16. Home Storage of Vegetables. No. 17. Grasshopper Control. No. 18. Whole Wheat Breads. No. 19. Substitutes for White Flour in Bread Making. No. 20. How to Substitute Other Foods for Meat. No. 21. Economy in the Use of Fats. No. 22. How Can I Make My Clothes Last Longer? No. 23. Saving Beans for Food and Seeding Purposes. No. 24. The Problem of Soft Corn. No. 25. Sugar Conservation. No. 26. Wartime Poultry Feeding. No. 27. Pinto Beans. No. 28. Ration Card. No. 29. The Potato as a Food. No. 30. Substitutes for White Flour in Making Quick Breads. No. 31. Substitutes for White Flour in Desserts. No. 32. Wheatless Recipes. No. 33. Use of Dried Fruits in Vegetables. No. 34. More Wheat for Nebraska. The amount of work handled by the Duplicating and Mailing divisions of the Extension offices is as follows : Stencils cut, 3,423. Pages mimeographed, 4,027,643. Pages multigraphed, 518,826. Pieces of mail received, 84,735. Pieces of mail sent out, 519,441. Total copies mimeographed, multigraphed and printed material in outgoing mail, 2,541,962. COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENT WORK The passage by Congress in August, 1917, of the bill for "Stimulating Agriculture and Facilitating the Distribution of Products" contemplated the expansion of existing machinery, which in normal times had for its object regular Extension work. A conference was held in July to lay plans for ex - panding the work. Nine County Farm Bureaus were then </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-second Annual Report 31 organized and nine agents were at work. In August, the work of organizing other counties to meet the needs for food pro - duction was begun. By January 1, 1918, five additional counties had agents, and organization work was in progress in a number of other counties. On July 1, 1918, fifty county agents were at work, eleven district agents covering two or more counties, three assistant county agents, and ten on the administrative and supervisory force. Three schools for newly appointed workers were held in July, September, and Decem - ber respectively. A conference of all county agent workers was held in March, 1918. SEED SURVEY The spring of 1918 found a very serious shortage of seed corn, and it was known that in the call for more breadstuffs, spring wheat would be much in demand. The State Council of Defense in meeting these needs sought the assistance of the County Agent Section. In the spring wheat regions of the State, the agents have reported a very material increase in the acreage, in some cases as much as 100 per cent. The distri - bution of this seed was almost entirely thru the hands of the agents in organized counties. • The corn situation was similar thruout the cornbelt. This Section threw its whole available force into finding, testing, and distributing seed, as a help to the State Defense Council's efforts. This work was amply justified both from the emer - gency food production point and from that of the Extension Service. SEED CORN Because of the peculiarly abnormal weather conditions in the fall of 1917, most of the corn in the State was soft and very little matured sufficiently to make seed for the 1918 plant - ing. As a result, the seed corn project was adopted by prac - tically all the County Farm Bureaus and the County Agents gave assistance in locating 222,985 bushels of seed corn and distributing 62,298 bushels. The agents aided in establishing 32 testing stations with an average weekly capacity of 44 bushels. RODENT AND INSECT CONTROL As a conservative measure a number of counties inaugu - rated a campaign against rodents, — particularly, pocket go - phers, prairie dogs, and ground squirrels. In this work, the </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Department of Entomology cooperated with the Extension Service. More than 25 carloads of bran and large quantities of alfalfa meal together with 10 tons of poison were used for baiting and poisoning grasshoppers. In the beet growing counties of western Nebraska consider - able attention was given also to controlling the sugar beet webworm by spraying. INCREASED PRODUCTION AND CONSERVATION Farm Bureaus and county agents cooperated in the effort to stimulate pork production for the spring of 1918 and to in - crease the acreage of wheat in 1918 and 1919. In both of these efforts it is estimated that the quota set for the State was exceeded. In seven counties quantities of sorghum cane were raised for syrup to be used as a sugar substitute. A number of old sorghum mills were put in operation and several new mills started on a community basis. SMUT CONTROL A special campaign was put on to control smut in oats and wheat by the formalin treatment. Demonstrations were giver by county agents and by specialists from the Bureau of Plant Industry. LIVE STOCK DISEASE CONTROL As a further means of conserving food, special emphasi&gt; was given to the controlling of live stock diseases, particularlj hog cholera and blackleg. Vaccination demonstrations wen given by the County Agents and as a result of these demon strations 12,318 head of hogs and 29,905 head of cattle wen vaccinated. This work was conducted as an educational fea ture. A number of communities organized to purchase sup plies and to do the work cooperatively in the future. •1 In the hog cholera control work, ten inspectors of th«, Bureau of Animal Industry, located at various points over th&lt; State, have cooperated with the agents. In each instance of ai outbreak, an attempt was made to confine the disease to i limited area. Hog cholera exists mostly in the eastern part of the State while blackleg is more prevalent in the western portion. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-second Annual Report 33 County agents have given a great deal of assistance in the control of other live stock troubles also by advocating sani - tary measures, useful remedies, and the employment of com - petent veterinarians. LABOR The county agent's office has in a large number of counties been the central point for distributing labor within the county. One thousand three hundred fifty-eight farm hands have been distributed during the year thru this medium. MARKETING Each Farm Bureau conducted an exchange of commodities for sale or wanted. An up-to-date list is kept in the County Agent's office and periodically a list is sent to each farmer in the county and also to other Farm Bureau offices in the State. Needs which cannot be filled within the county or articles which find no sale within the county are made known generally thruout the State by means of a state exchange list published from the State Leader's office. Hay, potatoes, and cattle are commodities which have been exchanged widely between Farm Bureaus. The Potato Market News Service was again issued in the fall of 1917 by the Office of Markets, U. S. DeDartment of Agri - culture, from the office of the County Apent at Alliance. Box Butte County. Some 2.200 potato growers were furnished v.ith a daily report of the notato market. This service is very gratefully received by the growers and has a tendency to narrow the margin of difference between the price paid to producers and that paid by consumers. Over 15,000 farmer's account books were distributed by county agents and assistance given many in starting their farm accounts and analyzing their farm business. Records for cost production were also furnished for sugar beets, wheat, and pork. Blanks were furnished to secure the cost of oper - ating tractors. These data are not available. STATISTICAL The work of the county agents, varyincr in number from 9 at the beginning of the year to 50 at the close, is summarized below : Telephone calls 28,464 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 34 Days in field 4,073 Days in office 3,750 Calls on agents at headquarters 40,901 Letters written 34,753 Farm visits made 12,512 Demonstrations visited 1,140 Miles traveled by auto 153,078 Bulletins discontinued 185,271 Number of farms on which hog cholera vaccin - ation demonstrations have been held 357 Number of hogs vaccinated thru demon- Head of pure-bred live stock introduced 36,644 Farm laborers placed 1,355 Number of meetings held 2,290 Aggregate attendance 51,975 HOME DEMONSTRATION WORK Ten home demonstration agents at large were employed. The State was divided into ten districts. Demonstrations were held and talks given where requested and women leaders in the various counties were visited for the purpose of stimulating interest in Home Demonstration Agent work. Thirty-five women were employed during the summer months to do special work under the direction of County and District Agricultural Agents. Three of these were assigned to counties in which were cities. They formed temporary Home-Makers' Associations and carried out projects in food strations 13,717 Number of farms on which blackleg vacci- nation demonstrations have been held.... 390 Number of cattle vaccinated thru demonstra- tions 25,785 Value of live stock bought or sold thru ex- change $418,342 Value of grain, seed, hay, etc., bought or sold thru exchange $262,709 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirty -second Annual Report 35 preservation and wheat substitutes. In the other type of counties the workers spent from one to four weeksjn a co'inty, doing no organizing, but holding canning and drying schools and demonstrations. In all cases every effort was made to interest women in permanent Home Demonstration Agent Work. All during the year cooperative agencies worked with the Food Administration. A special wheat substitute drive was put on. The department has also cooperated with Food Con - servation committees of the Women's Committee of the State Council of Defense. Owing to changes made necessary by war conditions and other intervening conditions, attempts to organize Home Eco - nomic short courses and Woman's Club courses have been dis - continued. All efforts at organization are toward the placing of permanent Home Demonstration Agents and the building up of strong county associations. Conservation has temporarily taken the place of general Home Economics topics. The spec - ialists are utilized to help the agents plan and execute con - servation projects and to assist other agencies, such as Fair Boards, County Councils of Defense, and County Food Admin - istrators, in carrying out conservation programs. PROJECTS Number of homes adopting instruction 542 Number of homes conducting demonstrations. 1,610 Number of people attending demonstrations and meetings 78,639 Canning, Summer 1917. Because the number of trained workers was too small to be able to reach even a fraction of the women of the State, it was decided that the first move neces - sary in the canning campaign was to train teachers. For that purpose forty-five training schools were held at thirty-three different points in the State. Each school lasted two days and a member of the Home Economics faculty of some of the state schools was in charge. The total attendance at these schools was 2,152. This includes only the women who came to get all of the instruction. At these schools the cold-pack method of canning was taught. Those attending these schools of in - struction gave instructions to 33,600 other women. County Fairs. A Home Economics Extension worker was </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 36 sent to each of fifteen county fairs to give demonstrations and individual help. At seven of these fairs University tent ex - hibits were used. Each tent had in it three cases devoted to conservation in the home, including canning and drying and clothing conservation. Teachers' Institutes. Mr. Hoover wrote to each county su - perintendent of the State suggesting that on their institute programs they give food conservation a place. Altho these suggestions came to the county superintendents very late, seven of them asked for speakers. In two cases a whole week's work was given. In four cases only two days were given to food conservation, while in one case the representative of the Extension Service remained only one day. At each of these institutes the teachers were given a chance to obtain copies of the food emergency bulletins. The most valuable thing done was to hold individual conferences with rural teachers who were anxious to start hot lunches. In every case the in - structor showed how each hot lunch could be made a food con - servation lesson. Farmers' Institutes and Short Courses. There was a de - cided decrease in the number held but no decrease in the at - tendance or in the interest shown. The total number of Farmers' Institutes held during the year was 43 with an at - tendance of 5,055. Seventeen Short Courses were held, twelve were combined and five were women's with an attendance of 6,425. Food courses for Short Courses are planned for five consecutive years, clothing for four years, and House Adminis - tration for three years. Wheat Substitute Campaign. About the first of October. 1917, a definite attempt was made thru the County Food Ad - ministrators to place the matter of the use of substitutes be - fore the people. A total of 148 meetings and demonstrations was held with an attendance of 5,064. Milk Campaign. A two months milk campaign was con - ducted during the winter under the supervision of a specialist sent out by the U. S. Dairy Division. Fourteen demonstrations and three schools of instruction were held with an attendance of 570. Food Preservation Campaign. 1918. The Food Preservation campaign was designed to reach the rural districts and more remote towns of the state. A total of 491 schools and demon- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirty-second Annual Report strations were held with an attendance of 13,113. This is a report of the entire work for the season. Woman's Clubs. At the beginning of the year we had a total of 300 woman's clubs mostly rural. In most instances these clubs did not, during the past year, take up regular study along the line of Home Economics, but did some sort of war work at their meetings. Most of the clubs during the year devoted one period of their meetings to Food Conservation, but statistics on results are not available. RELATION OF SPECIALISTS TO AGENTS 1. In organization. They assist in projects initiated by agents, suggest projects to leaders of Agents, and cooperate with Food Administrators and other agencies interested in conser- vation in counties not reached by Home Demonstration Agents. 2. Methods and line of work. a. Methods — Exhibits, demonstrations, and talks at Farmers' Institutes, Short Courses, Woman's Cl.ib Meetings, Fairs, and special meetings. b. Lines — Food, clothing, house administration, dairy, poultry, gardening, and community activi ties. JUNIOR WORK The workers in this department consist of a leader, three assistant state leaders, eight emergency assistant state leaders, ten emergency district club leaders, nineteen emergency county leaders and twenty-five emergency assistant county leaders, a total of 66 people workine on Junior Projects. Besides do - ing the regular club work, these people endeavored to increase the food production and food conservation in Nebraska as much as possible, thru the following lines, namely: the Gar - den Club, the Corn Growing Club. Potato Club, Pig Raising Hub. Chicken Raising Club, War Bread Club. Canning Huh, Drying by Communities and the Junior Red Cross Work. Approximately 24,000 boys and girls enrolled in the different clubs. Twenty-five communities within the State have estab- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 38 lished community drying plants. A state leader was placed in charge of each one of the individual projects and with the assistance of the district, county, and assistant county leaders did all within his power to produce and conserve thru the respective clubs. Altho the junior projects were not primarily demonstra - tions, yet in reality every garden, pig pen, chicken pen, kitchen, or drying plant was a demonstration point. With the enroll - ment of the 24,000 pupils, approximately 15,000 homes were represented. The communities surrounding these homes watched the boys' or girls' plots very closely and in many cases the desired information was carried into homes which other - wise would not have been reached. This is especially true where an antagonistic spirit was shown toward the Home Demonstration Agent or the County Agricultural Agent. During the year 5,774 public meetings were held under the auspices of the Junior Department, with an atendance of 288, - 742 people. Thru the efforts of the Junior Extension Department about $119,213 of garden products were produced, 284 acres of corn were planted, 434 acres of potatoes were raised, 175 tons o pork were produced, 50,000 chickens were grown, 26,250 auarts of vegetables and fruits were stored for winter use 25 community drying plants were established, and aboui 6.000 boys and jrirls were given instruction in Junior Re&lt; Cross sewing. Two hundred finished the cookin&lt;* project 1.800 garments were made in sewing project, while 26 tons o: white flour, 2u&gt; tons of sugar, 6 tons of meat, and one ton o: fats were estimated saved thru the efforts of the war brea&lt; clubs. All circulars and lessons prepared by the Junior Ex - tension Service were approved by the Extension Specialist in Agriculture or Home Economics before being sent to the pupils, enrolled in the rroiectfc The club workers over the Rbtta cp'led to their assistance these specialists in the different lines who gave talks and demonstrations in their territory. The Animal Husbandry Department, used the pic club ant, chicken club as channels thru which they mierht jrive the de ( sired information to the adults of any given community. Thi? relationship was indeed very satisfactory both to the Junior Section and to the Adult Section. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-xecond Annual Report 39 CONCLUSION The general conditions of the outlook for Extension work in the State of Nebraska are very promising. The Advisory Committee for the Extension Service representing the farmers' organizations of the State have agreed to support legislation ?ncouraging Extension work. The State Association of bounty Supervisors and County Commissioners has endorsed he idea of making county appropriation for Extension work :ompulsory provided a reasonable percentage of land owners so petition. With this support, it is likely that a bill proposed n the State Legislature this winter recognizing by law the arm Bureau and requiring cooperation on the part of County Boards when they are properly petitioned will be passed. This will insure the future of the work in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FUND RECEIPTS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1918, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, (Hatch fund) $15,000.00 Financial Secretary. i unrjo Salaries Labor Publications Postage and stationery Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Library Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures $ 6,345.00 3,410.72 2,869.51 213.75 213.41 336.51 1.308.1C 3.2C 194.0C 1O5.8C $15,000.00 $15,000.0C i January 28, 1919. J. S. DALES, </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-second Annual Report 41 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued ADAMS FUND Financial Secretary. lUiVlurlB Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1918, under the act of Congress approved March 16, 1906, &lt; Adams fund) _ $15,000.00 \ EXPENDITURES Salaries Labor v Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Tools, machinery, and appliances Scientific apparatus and specimens Traveling expenses -. Buildings and land $11,615.87 1,460.64 37.12 298.28 228.09 670.26 30.84 569.76 69.14 20.00 $15,000.00 January 28, 1919. J. S. D $15,000.00 $15,000.00 J. S. DALES, $15,000.00 )ALES, </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDS Moneys received by the University (State) treas - urer from other sources than the United States, for the use and benefit of the Experiment Station and Substations, for the year ended June 30, 1918. Balance July 1, 1917 $10,056.01 Sales of stock, produce, etc 63,295.70 January 28, 1919. J. S. DALES, Financial Secretary. rjAriji^ lj Salaries Labor $10,007.63 8,192.55 Publications Postage and stationery Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies... Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Tools, machinery, and appliances ... Furniture and fixtures Scientific apparatus and specimens ... Live stock Traveling expenses Contingent expenses Buildings and land Balance, June 30, 1918 235.56 279.37 639.13 3,977.76 1,534.69 10,967.00 1,789.60 267.55 394.53 15,994.00 157.00 53.60 1,986.17 16,875.57 :73,351.71 $73,351.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Thirty-second Annual Report 43 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATIONS 3alance June 30, 1917, of legislative appropriation from the State general fund for the benefit of the Experimental Substations, for the two years ending March 31, 1919 North Platte $23,086.55 Scottsbluff 2,279.96 Valentine 4,191.72 $29,558.23 Legislative appropriation for two years ending March 31, 1919. North Platte $33,075.00 Scottsbluff 4,200.00 Valentine _ 6,040.00 $43,315.00 Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1918, for su - perintendence, supplies, labor, live stock, feed, seeds, machinery, tools, and betterment of the plants, North Platte $28,362.16 Scottsbluff 3,256.16 Valentine 5,728.05 $37,346.37 Appropriations balances June 30, 1918. North Platte $27,799.39 Scottsbluff 4,503.67 Valentine 3,223.80 $35,526.86 $72,873.23 $72,873.23 Jalance, cash, July 1, 1917 $12,674.88 leceipts to June 30, 1918 45,343.82 Expenditures to June 30. 1918 $36,105.84 lalance. June 30, 1918 21,912.86 $58,018.70 $58,018.70 J. S. DALES, anuary 28, 1919. Financial Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 44 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Concluded \ APPROPRIATIONS BY THH STATE— Concluded AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION Balance, July 1, 1917, of legislative appropriation from the State general fund for maintenance of Agricultural Extension and Farmers' Institutes, for the two years ending March 31, 1919 $28,998.65 Legislative appropriation for two years ending March 31, 1919 _ 39,456.00 Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1918, for su - perintendence, clerical service, labor, lecturers' and workers' services, expenses and printing $33,164.2' Appropriation Valance _ _ _ 35,290.3* $68,454.65 $68,454.6f January 28. 1919. J. S. DALES, Financal Secretary. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>