<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1917-04-10">1917-04-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OK NEBRASKA Volume XXIX, Article III PORK PRODUCTION ON IRRIGATED LANDS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA By James A. Holden Distributed April 10, 1917 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. BULLETIN No. 159 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE KBCBNTS OF THE INIVKRSITN HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, President, Omaha HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln HONORABLE HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary FLOYD WAMBEAM, B. Sc., Bulletin Editor THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry L. W. CHASE, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. Burr, B. Sc., Agronomy T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy Howard J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomology M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology H. C. Filley, A. M., Farm Management R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine James A. Holden, B. Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell *L. L. Zook, B. Sc., Agronomist, North Platte G. K. K. LINK, Ph. D., Associate in Agricultural Botany J. W. CALVIN, B. Sc., Associate in Agricultural Chemistry Erwin Hopt, B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy 'J. A. Ratclift, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy L. B. STURDEVANT, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology E. G. WOODWARD, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management J. R. Cooper, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture 'Resigned 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS PAGE 4 Summary Introduction 1 General description of methods followed 8 Alfalfa pasturing experiments 9 Summary of four years" results when supplemented with a 2 per cent 10 corn ration Summary of two years' results with various grain supplements 11 One-acre pastures supplemented with corn and ground barley 15 Mixed lot of hogs on an acre pasture supplemented with a 2 per cent corn ration 18 Sows and litters on pasture with a grain supplement 18 Corn and pasture versus com in dry-lot for finishing shotes 20 •19. Hogging corn Summary of four years' results on corn without supplementary feed 22 Summary of two years' results with duplicate lots on corn with and without supplementary feed 24 Dry-lot feeding experiments 26 Corn, sugar beets, and mangels 26 Corn, alfalfa hay, and sugar beets 27 Experiments in 1914 27 Experiments in 1915 with the addition of cull potatoes and ground barley 28 Summary of two years' results 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 SUMMARY Because of the relatively small capital and short time required to get a start in the swine industry and because of the high efficiency of hogs in utilizing certain field crops, swine production is a specially promising industry for irrigation farmers. The following statements are based on results from experiments con - ducted at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm in 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, and 1916. In four years' experiments, including ten lots of hogs, in which alfalfa was supplemented with a 2 per cent ration of corn, an aver - age gain of 3,191 pounds per season was made from an acre of alfalfa pasture and 7,752 pounds of corn. It required an average of 2.43 pounds of corn in addition to alfalfa pasture to produce 1 pound of pork. If the gains are valued at 7 cents a pound and corn at 60 cents a bushel, the average annual return was $140.42 per acre of alfalfa pasture. If the corn fed is valued at 60 cents a bushel and the alfalfa pasture at $15 an acre, the aver - age cost of 100 pounds of gain was $3.07. If the average yield of the alfalfa plats in the same field is assumed to represent the yield of the pastured plats, the hogs paid an equivalent of $25.16 per ton of hay. In two years' experiments with alfalfa pasture with and with - out supplemental feed, an average annual return of $45.08 per acre was obtained where no grain was fed, $70.20 where a 1 per cent corn ration was fed, $128.49 where a 2 per cent corn ration was fed, $121.96 where a 2 per cent ration of ground barley was fed, and $168.25 where a 3 per cent corn ration was fed. An average of 644 pounds of gain per acre was secured where no supplement was used, as compared with 1,488 pounds of gain where 3,174 pounds of corn was supplemented, 3,006 pounds of gain where 7,657 pounds of corn was supplemented, 2,776 pounds of gain where 7,236 pounds of ground barley was supplemented, and 4,354 pounds of gain where 12,760 pounds of corn was supple - mented. The rate of gain and the carrying capacity of the pasture increased with the quantity of grain fed. Ground barley appeared to be as good, pound for pound, as shelled corn for hogs on alfalfa pasture. Altho the 1-acre pastures, in 1916, on which corn and ground barley were compared as supplementary feed suffered much from wind and hail storms, the results were fairly satisfactory and added strength to the previous years' data which showed that ground barley is equal to shelled corn as a hog feed. In a mixed lot of shotes, sows, and pigs, 1,029 pounds of gain </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 5 were made from 2,316 pounds of corn and one acre of alfalfa pasture from April 29 to June 29. Sows and pigs on alfalfa pasture, with a 2 per cent ration of grain, made an average gain of 1,516 pounds per acre of alfalfa pasture from May 1 to July 1, or a net return of $63.11 per acre. When corn was used, the return varied from $54.11 to $69.97 per acre, and when barley was used the return was $77.76 per acre. In an experiment which covered a period of two months, where corn and alfalfa pasture was compared with corn alone in dry-lot for finishing shotes for market, one and three-quarters acres of pasture and 10,677 pounds of corn made 610 pounds more pork than the corn would have made had it been fed in dry-lot. During the first month the hogs in dry-lot made a pound gain from 4.55 pounds of corn but during the second month they were fed 5.63 pounds of corn for 1 pound of gain. For the whole period the hogs on pasture made 25.8 pounds of gain and the hogs in dry-lot 19.5 pounds of gain per 100 pounds of corn. In four years' experiments, hogging corn without supple - mentary feed produced an average of 882 pounds of gain, worth $61.74 per acre, or $1.52 per hundredweight of the estimated yield of corn. In two years' experiments, hogging corn without supplemen - tary feed produced an average of 744 pounds of gain worth $52.08 per acre, as compared with 930 pounds of gain worth $65.10 where the hogs had access to alfalfa pasture, and 1,029 pounds of gain worth $72.03 where the hogs were fed tankage in addition to the corn. Where no supplementary feed was used, the hogs paid $1.34 per hundredweight for the estimated yield of corn, as com - pared with $1.55 per hundredweight where the hogs had access to alfalfa pasture and $1.50 per hundredweight where tankage was used. The use of either alfalfa or tankage resulted in more rapid and cheaper gains than were secured where no supplemen - tary feed was used. In a number of dry-lot feeding experiments in which corn, ground barley, sugar beets, mangels, cull potatoes, and alfalfa hay were fed in different combinations, one year's result shows that a 15-ton yield of sugar beets has the same feeding value as a 22.5-ton yield of mangels. An average of two years' experi - ments shows that the net profit from a 14.25-ton yield of sugar beets is the same as from a 60ybushel yield of corn when both are fed to fattening hogs. In this experiment 583 pounds of sugar beets was equivalent to 100 pounds of corn. On this basis corn at $1.07 a hundredweight is a cheaper feed than sugar beets at $5 a ton. In this same test the corn lot paid $8 a ton for alfalfa hay and $1.63 a hundredweight for corn; when the beet lots are </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 charged this same amount for corn and alfalfa hay, one lot paid $5.61 and the other $5.57 a ton for the beets fed. Results from one year's test show that ground barley supplemented with sugar beets and alfalfa hay made faster and cheaper gain than corn supplemented with the same feeds. Cull potatoes made slower but cheaper gain than sugar beets when each was fed with corn and alfalfa hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">PORK PRODUCTION ON IRRIGATED LANDS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA 1 JAMES A. HOLDEN INTRODUCTION The farmer who makes a success on high-priced irrigated land must not only grow large crops but market these crops in the most advantageous way. Most crops grown in localities far removed from the large consuming centers should be marketed in condensed form, so as to reduce the cost of transportation. For example, a hundred pounds of butter can be shipped to market much more cheaply than the hay and grain required to produce this butter. The farmer should take advantage of this fact in organizing his operations. In addition to this saving, the manure resulting from the feeding of the crops makes it possible to produce larger crops in subsequent years. Many of the farmers on irrigated projects are financially un - able at present to secure dairy cows or to get cattle or sheep to feed. There are very few, however, who can not get into the hog business in a very short time. Less capital and time are required in getting into the hog business than in any other live stock industry. With $25 with which to buy small pigs and with very little grain and good alfalfa pasture, the farmer can get well started in the hog business in two years. Horses and cattle increase annually 60 to 80 per cent, sheep a little more than 100 per cent, while hogs should increase 600 per cent or better. The buildings necessary for the housing of hogs are also relatively inexpensive. The hog is a very economical feeder. It takes less feed to produce a pound of pork than any other kind of meat produced on the farm. The hog has the ability quickly to trans - form the products of the farm into a readily marketable com - modity. In the irrigated sections of the West, where alfalfa, sugar beets, and potatoes are the principal crops and where grain crops occupy a secondary position, the farmer needs information on the following points: (1) The practicability of using alfalfa as ■A detailed report of the alfalfa pasturing and corn hogging experiments that were conducted previous to 1916 is given in Bulletin No. 488 of the United States Department of Agriculture, which will be sent to anyone upon application. These experiments were conducted on the Scotts - bluff Experiment Farm. This experiment farm is maintained cooperatively by the University of Nebraska and the United States Department of Agriculture. The primary object of these experiments has been to determine the most efficient methods of utilizing in hog production certain of the crops grown on irrigated lands of the western part of the state. The author desires to acknowledge the assistance given him by Henry Sullivan and A. C. Moore in carrying out the details of the experiments. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 hog pasture; (2) the value of different quantities of grain when fed to hogs on alfalfa pasture; (3) the comparative values of corn and ground barley when fed to hogs on alfalfa pasture; (4) the practicability of hogging down corn; and (5) to what extent can beets, mangels, or cull potatoes replace grain to an advantage in the winter finishing of hogs for market. Some information on these points has been secured from experiments which have been conducted at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm on the North Platte Reclamation Project during the five years 1912 to 1916 inclusive. 1 GENERAL DESCRIPTION OF THE METHODS FOLLOWED It has been the aim of this bulletin to use average prices and to report sufficient fundamental data to enable anyone to apply different prices to the results. The prices used, except where otherwise stated, are as follows: Gains made by hogs, $7 per hundredweight; corn, $1.07 per hundredwieght (or 60 cents a bushel); ground barley, $1 per hundredweight; alfalfa hay, $8 a ton ; tankage, $64 a ton ; sugar beets, $5 a ton ; mangels, $3 a ton ; and cull potatoes, $5 a ton. The data, which usually have been calculated to an acre basis, show the results that were obtained from quarter-acre plats of alfalfa pasture, which, if cut for hay, would have yielded from 4 to 6 tons per acre; and in the case of corn hogged, from one-third or one-quarter-acre plats that yielded as high as 80 bushels of corn per acre. It must be remembered by farmers who attempt to follow these methods of crop utili - zation that the higher the yield of the crop the larger will be the returns. The term "per cent," when referring to rations, indicates the number of pounds fed daily per 100 pounds of live weight. The cost of the condiments fed, sprays used, interest on in - vestment, risk, and labor are not considered in this report. The term "net return," as used in the following text and tables, refers to the difference between the total return and the estimated value of grain fed and is not to be taken as the net return of the land after production costs and interest charges have been deducted. The hogs in these experiments had access to salt, slacked coal, and rock phosphate most of the time. They were also sprayed with coal-tar creosote every two or three weeks to keep them free from lice. In fact, they received the treatment that every farmer should give his hogs. Regularity in feeding, both in time and quantity of feed, clean quarters, and freedom from lice are 'See also Bulletin No. 488 of the United States Department of Agriculture </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 9 three very important factors that are essential to successful hog raising; and these were provided in the experiments under con - sideration. The data here reported are the results of tests cover - ing one to five years. In the alfalfa pasturing experiment, two lots of hogs were used each season; and in the corn hogging experiment, with supplemental feeds, duplicate lots were used. ALFALFA PASTURING EXPERIMENTS The alfalfa pasturing experiments were begun in 1913 and continued in 1914, 1915, and 1916. In 1913, 1914, and 1915 quarter-acre plats were used, while in 1916 there were one - quarter-acre, three-quarter-acre, and one-acre plats. Each plat was divided into two equal parts and the hogs were changed from one to the other as the pasture became short. This allowed the alfalfa to recuperate and at the same time provided fresh, palat - able feed. It was the plan to pasture the alfalfa to its full carrying capacity but not to overgraze. This made it necessary to remove some of the hogs during the latter part of the experi - ment, for as the season advanced and the nights became cool the alfalfa made slower growth and at the same time the hogs were increasing in size, thus requiring more feed. A few times during periods of three or four days of cloudy weather and also during the last month, when alfalfa was making little growth, the plats were perhaps slightly overpastured. As far as could be deter - mined, however, no plat was pastured more heavily than an - other. In most cases the corn was fed on the ear during the first period, and shelled corn was fed during the second period. Ear corn was fed on the ground and the shelled corn in trough. The barley was ground and fed as a thick slop. Grain was fed once a day, in the evening. It is believed that when fed grain but once a day the hogs will make more use of the pasture than when grain is fed both morning and evening, as is usually the case. When not fed until evening, the hogs become hungry and will graze during the cool hours of the evening, even after the grain is eaten. Again, if the hogs are not fed grain in the morning, they will stay out on pasture until the heat of the sun drives them to shade. The method of feeding grain once a day also saves labor. During the pasture season two sets of hogs were used. Fall - farrowed shotes were used during the first period and spring - farrowed pigs during the second period. In 1914 this plan was notjfollowed strictly, as it was necessary to use a few fall-farrowed pigs thruout the season, owing to the loss of spring pigs from </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 cholera. The reason for using two sets of hogs is that fall - farrowed pigs when fed a liberal grain ration are ready for market about July 15, and the April-farrowed pigs are not large enough to utilize the pasture much before that date. SUMMARY OF FOUR YEARS' RESULTS WHEN SUPPLEMENTED WITH A 2 PER CENT CORN RATION To date there are four years' results from pasturing hogs on alfalfa with a 2 per cent corn ration. In 1915 there were two lots, so that during the four years there have been ten lots in all, five in each pasturing period. The results of the four years' tests with these ten lots are summarized in table 1, in which the data have been calculated to an acre basis. Table 1 — Results obtained by feeding ten lots of pigs on alfalfa pasture, supplemented with approximately a 2 per cent ration of corn, at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm in 1913, 191 -4, 1915, and 1916 On an acre basis the five lots made an average total gain of 1,305 pounds during the first period and 1,886 pounds during the second period, or a total of 3,191 pounds for the season. During the first period the hogs were fed 3,613 pounds of corn, and during the second period 4,139 pounds, or a total of 7,752 pounds during the season. It required 2.77 pounds of corn in the first period and 2.19 pounds in the second period, in addition to the alfalfa pasture, to produce 1 pound of gain. For every 100 pounds of corn fed, the hogs made a gain of 36.1 pounds dur - ing the first period, and 45.6 pounds the second period, or an average of 41.2 pounds during the season. With hogs at $7 per hundredweight and corn at $1.07 per hundredweight, the net return per acre of alfalfa pasture was Items of comparison First Second period period Entire season ; l_ Number of lots 5 5 rotal gain per acre Pounds 1,305 i 1,886 Corn fed do 3,613 4,139 Grain per pound of gain do 2.77 2.19 I Sain per 100 pounds of grain do 36.1 45.6 10 3.191 7.752 2.43 41.2 Financial statement: Net return per acre of pasture , $52.69 $87.73 Cost per 100 pounds of gain (pasture at $15 per acre) 3.29 2.86 Equivalent paid for hay, per ton 212.54 27.05 'Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered. $140.42 3.07 25.16 I. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 11 $52.69 for the first period and $87.73 for the second period, or a total of $140.42 for the season. This is equal to a daily net return of 93 cents an acre for a period of 150 days. If a charge of $5 for the first period and $10 for the second period is made for an acre of alfalfa pasture, the feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain cost $3.29 during the first period, $2.86 during the second period, and $3.07 for the season. Alfalfa plats similar to those pastured and in the same field have each year been harvested for hay. The four-year average yield of these plats was 5.58 tons per acre or 2.35 tons for the first period and 3.23 tons for the second period of pasturing. On the basis of this yield, if it is assumed that the cost of caring for the hogs is equal to the harvesting of the hay, the hogs in the first period paid $22.54 and in the second period $27.05, or an average for the season of $25.16 a ton for alfalfa hay. SUMMARY OF TWO YEARS' RESULTS WITH VARIOUS GRAIN SUPPLEMENTS In 1914, experiments were inaugurated to secure information regarding (1) the most economical quantity of corn to feed to hogs on alfalfa pasture, (2) the relative efficiency of 2 per cent corn and 2 per cent ground barley rations as supplements to alfalfa pasture, and (3) the carrying capacity of alfalfa pasture when no supplement is fed. This experiment was repeated on the same alfalfa plats during the summer of 1915, with the addition of one more lot fed 2 per cent corn, which was pastured on a new alfalfa plat. The alfalfa pastured during the two seasons was seeded on April 6, 1912, hay having been harvested from the plats during the seasons of 1912 and 1913. The plat pastured for the first time during the summer of 1915 was seeded in oat stubble on August 17, 1912, and was harvested as hay during the two seasons following. The yields of the different plats during these years were very uniform. Figure 1 gives a view of the alfalfa pas - ture used in this experiment. The results of the experiments in 1914 and 1915 with alfalfa pasture and various grain supplements are summarized in table 2. As two lots of hogs were used each year in each part of the test, the figures in table 2 show the average of the results secured from four lots of hogs in each instance. The figures have been calculated to an acre basis. The results of two years' work show that hogs on alfalfa pasture without grain produced an average of 644 pounds of gain per acre. The same area of pasture, with the addition of 3,174 pounds of corn, produced 1,488 pounds of gain. Where 7,657 pounds of corn was fed, the gain was 3,006 pounds; where </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 12 7,236 pounds of ground barley was fed, the gain was 2,776 pounds; and where 12,760 pounds of corn supplemented the alfalfa pas - ture, the gain was 4,354 pounds per acre of pasture. With this information the farmer can apply prices that suit his own partic - ular condition and determine the most economical quantity of grain to feed. Table 2 — Results obtained by feeding hogs on alfalfa pasture supplemented with varying quantities of grain, at the Scotts - bluff Experiment Farm in 191 k and 1915 Two years' results show that more pasture is required when no grain is fed and that as the grain ration is increased the area of pasture required is decreased. The areas required when nograin, 1 per cent grain, 2 per cent grain, and 3 per cent grain were fed were approximately as 5, 4, 3, and 2 respectively. For every 100 pounds of grain fed, lot 2 made 47.4 pounds of gain; lot 3, 38 pounds; lot 4, 38.3 pounds; and lot 5, 34.1 pounds. The higher the grain ration the lower the gains per unit of grain fed. Also, the lower the grain ration the more pasture was required for 100 pounds of gain. With the prices here used, the two-year average net return per acre of alfalfa pasture was as follows: No grain lot, $45.08; 1 per cent corn lot, $70.20; 2 per cent corn lot, $128.49; 2 per cent ground barley lot, $121.96; and the 3 per cent corn I. . - I. ._-!_ . _ I _ I Lot 1, Lot 2, 1 1 Lot 3, 2 Lot 4, 2 Lot 5, 3 Items of comparison no per cent per cent per cent per cent grain corn corn barley corn Total gain per acre Pounds 644 1,488 3,006 2,776 4,364 Av. daily gain, per acre do 4.1 9.6 19.3 17.9 28.0 Grain fed do 3,174 7,667 7,236 12,760 Grain per pound of gain do 2.11 2.63 2.61 2.93 Gain per 100 lbs. of grain do 47.4 38.0 38.3 34.1 'Financial statement: Net return per acre of pasture $45.08 $70.20 $128.49 $121.96 $168.25 Daily net return per acre of pasture 29 .45 .83 .79 1.08 Net return for 100 pounds of grain (pasture at $45.08 per acre; 1.86 2.16 2.06 2.03 Cost per 100 pounds of gain (pasture at $15 per acre).. 2.33 3.29 3.22 3.14 3.48 Equivalent paid for hay, per ton ; 8.16 12.71 23.25 22.10 :i&lt;l.4H 'Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 13 lot, $168.25. The average daily net return per acre for 154 days ranged from 29 cents, where no grain was fed, to $1.08, when a 3 per cent ration of corn was fed. Fig. 1 — The alfalfa plats used in 1914 and 1915 in the hog pasturing experiments at the Scottsbjuff Experiment Farm, showing the portable houses and the method of dividing the pastures The two-year average net return per acre of alfalfa pasture from lots 3 and 4 shows the sum of $6.43 in favor of corn over ground barley. It will also be seen from table 2 that the corn lot was fed a little more grain than the barley lot. Higher returns would, therefore, be expected from the corn-fed lot, as the results have shown that the net returns for pasture increase with the grain ration. The difference in net returns, therefore, is not enough to warrant the statement that corn at $1.07 per hundred - weight is cheaper feed than ground barley at $1 per hundred - weight. The average of the two years' results, and especially the 1915 results, seem to indicate very strongly that, pound for pound, ground barley is approximately equal to corn as feed for hogs in supplementing alfalfa pasture. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 The two-year average net return for alfalfa pasture was $45.08 where no grain was fed. If the grain-fed lots are charged this amount for pasture, the net returns for each 100 pounds of grain fed were as follows: 1 per cent corn lot, $1.86; 2 per cent corn lot, $2.16; 2 per cent barley lot, $2.06; and the 3 per cent corn lot, $2.03. It appears from this that 2 pounds of corn per day for each 100 pounds of live weight is the most satisfactory ration of corn for hogs on alfalfa pasture in order to get the highest return from both the corn and the alfalfa pasture. This is true Fig. 2 — Representative hogs from the lots fed varying grain supplements on alfalfa pasture at the close of the second period in 1914. From left to right: No grain, 1 per cent corn, 2 per cent corn, and 3 per cent corn when the feeder can get only a limited amount of corn; but when an abundant supply of corn is available at not more than $1.07 per hundredweight, it may be desirable to feed about 3 pounds of corn to each 100 pounds of live weight. Hogs fed a 3 per cent ration of corn will make a faster growth than those fed a 2 per cent ration and hence will be ready for the market earlier. As a saving of time lessens risk and also saves interest on invest - ment, this is a factor to be considered. Figure 2 shows a repre- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 15 sentative hog from the lot getting no grain, and one each from lots getting 1 per cent, 2 per cent, and 3 per cent of corn in 1914. When a charge of $15 per acre is made for the alfalfa pasture, the total cost per 100 pounds of gain was as follows: No grain lot, $2.33; 1 per cent corn lot, $3.29; 2 per cent corn lot, $3.22; 2 per cent barley lot, $3.14; and the 3 per cent corn lot, $3.48. The no grain lot made gains for $1.15 per hundredweight less than the 3 per cent corn lot did. It might appear from this that to pasture hogs on alfalfa without grain is the best practice; but this is not generally true, because of the much smaller returns of pork per acre. Perhaps the most impressive thing shown in table 2 is the amount paid for hay and its very rapid increase with the increase in the grain rations. The 2-year average yield of alfalfa hay from the check plats was 5.52 tons per acre. On this basis and assuming that the care of the hogs is equal to the cost of har - vesting the hay, the no grain lot paid an equivalent of $8.16; the 1 per cent grain lot paid $12.71; the 2 per cent grain lots, an average of $22.67; and the 3 per cent grain lot, $30.48 a ton for alfalfa. It seems certain that it will pay the farmer to feed hogs on alfalfa pasture at least 2 pounds of corn daily per 100 pounds of live weight. By so doing, not only will he get a higher return from his alfalfa, but he may expect also to make a profit on the corn fed. According to these results, it requires less capital for the same net return where grain is fed than where no grain is fed. When a 3 per cent corn ration is fed with alfalfa pasture, 1 acre will produce as much pork as 6.5 acres of alfalfa without grain, or a saving of 5.5 acres of land. Again, when fed a 3 per cent corn ration with alfalfa pasture, 52 pigs will make as much pork as 156 pigs on alfalfa pasture alone. ONE-ACRE PASTURES SUPPLEMENTED WITH CORN AND CROUND BARLEY During the summer of 1916, corn and ground barley, as supplements to alfalfa pasture, were compared on 1-acre plats. At the beginning of each period about a 2 per cent grain ration was fed and this was gradually increased to about a 3 per cent grain ration at the end of the period. During the spring and early summer these pasture plats suffered many disadvantages. The growth was retarded by the cold, backward spring. This was followed by severe windstorms which did much damage to the pasture plats by drifting soil onto them from an adjacent oat field. Particularly was this true of the plat where barley was fed. This plat was so badly damaged that the hogs were kept in dry-lot for six days to give the alfalfa a chance to recuper- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 ate. Again, on June 12 the pasture was so badly damaged by hail that each lot was kept in dry-lot one week to give the alfalfa a chance to start anew. The hogs are charged with the grain fed while in dry-lot. The pasturing season began April 29 and the first period ended June 29. During this period there were 20 shotes in the corn lot with a total initial weight of 1,456 pounds and a final weight of 2,628 pounds, or a gain of 1,147 pounds. This lot was fed 2,834 pounds of corn, or 2.47 pounds of corn for 1 pound of gain. For 100 pounds of corn fed, these shotes made 40.5 pounds of gain. The difference between the cost of the corn fed and the value of the gain made was $49.97. At the beginning of this period the barley lot had 20 shotes, but on May 27 one became sick and was removed. Its final weight was less than its initial weight. The initial weight of the other 19 shotes was 1,456 pounds and their final weight was 2,419 pounds, or 942 pounds of gain. They were fed 2,897 pounds of ground barley, which was 3 pounds of barley for 1 pound of gain, or 33.3 pounds of gain for 100 pounds of barley. When this lot was charged $1 per hundredweight for the barley fed, the dif - ference between this cost and the value of the gains was $38.45. The second period began June 30. There were 40 spring pigs in each lot, 20 of which were removed September 11 and the other 20 October 5. During the last week or ten days, the pastures were rather short. The total initial weight of the corn lot was 1,192 pounds, and the final weight was 3,187. To pro - duce the 1,995 pounds of gain the shotes were fed, in addition to the 1 acre of alfalfa pasture, 5,774 pounds of corn, or 2.89 pounds of corn for 1 pound of gain. For 100 pounds of corn fed, this lot produced 34.6 pounds of gain. This lot gave a net return of $77.87 for the alfalfa pasture. The total initial and final weights of the barley lot were 1,191 and 2,929 pounds, respectively, or a gain of 1,738 pounds. This lot was fed 2.8 pounds of ground barley for 1 pound gain, or a total of 5,000 pounds. A gain of 35.7 pounds was made for each 100 pounds of ground barley fed. The barley lot gave a net return of $71.66 for the alfalfa pasture. A summary of the results of the two periods of 1916 is given in table 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 17 Table 3 — Results secured by grazing hogs on one-acre alfalfa pastures supplemented by corn and ground barley at the Scotts- bluff Experiment Farm in 1916 1-acre 1-acre pasture, pasture, ground barley Items of comparison corn Total gain Pounds 3,142 2,701 Average daily gain Grain fed do 20.4 17.5 do 8,609 7,897 Grain per pound of gain do 2.74 2.92 Gain per 100 pounds of grain do 36.5 34.2 ■Financial statement: Net return for pasture $127.84 $110.11 Daily net return for pasture I .83 .72 Cost per 100 pounds of gain (pasture at $15 per acre) . . 3.40 3.47 Equivalent paid for hay, per ton I 22.15 19.05 ■Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered For the entire season of 1916, as shown in table 3, the gain from the corn lot was 3,142 pounds, and from the barley lot 2,701 pounds. The corn lot consumed 2.74 pounds of corn, and the barley lot 2.92 pounds of ground barley, for each pound of gain made. A gain of 36.5 pounds in the corn lot and 34.2 pounds in the barley lot was made from each 100 pounds of grain fed. When the gains made are figured at $7 per hundred - weight and the lots charged $1.07 per hundredweight for corn and $1 for ground barley, the net returns for the 1-acre alfalfa pastures were $127.84 where corn was fed and $110.11 where barley was fed. In comparing these two lots it must be remembered that the pasture of the barley lot was more severely damaged by the windstorms and that one of the shotes in this lot became sick 28 days after the experiment began, and was removed. In the first period the corn lot was fed 2.47 pounds and the barley lot 3 pounds of grain for 1 pound of gain. During the second period, however, which was more uniform for both lots, the barley lot was fed .09 pound of grain less than the corn lot for 1 pound gain. The results from the second period check very closely with the results obtained in 1914 and 1915, which showed that ground barley, pound for pound, was practically equal to corn as a hog feed. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 A MIXED LOT OF HOGS ON AN ACRE PASTURE SUPPLEMENTED WITH A 2 PER CENT CORN RATION This was a mixed lot of hogs. There were 15 shotes (888 pounds), 2 sows (391 pounds), and 12 pigs (122 pounds), with a combined initial weight of 1,401 pounds. The experiment began on April 29 and continued 60 days. The lot made a total gain of 1,029 pounds, the final weight being (shotes, 1,658; sows, 355; and pigs, 417) 2,430 pounds. In addition to the one acre of alfalfa pasture, this lot was fed 2,316 pounds of corn, or 2.25 pounds for 1 pound of gain. When charged $1.07 per hundred - weight for corn, this lot gave a daily net return of 79 cents for the alfalfa pasture. SOWS AND LITTERS ON PASTURE WITH A GRAIN SUPPLEMENT The following is a brief discussion of the results obtained by pasturing sows and their litters on alfalfa pasture, supplemented with about a 2 per cent grain ration. Corn was fed in each case, with the exception of one lot in 1915 which was fed ground barley. The experiments began in the spring as soon as the pasture would stand grazing and continued 60 days. One lot was used in 1914. three lots in 1915, and one in 1916. In 1914 and 1915 quarter-acre pastures were used, while in 1916 the pasture was three-fourths acre. These pastures were grazed at the rate of eight sows and their litters per acre during the first month and a half. At this date the pigs were old enough to wean; and to prevent overpasturing the plats, some or all of the sows were removed. There are two ways of looking at the results of these experiments. One is to charge the pigs with only the feed, and the other is to charge the pigs with both feed and the loss is weight of the sows. The second method is used here. The data obtained by pasturing sows and pigs on alfalfa pasture and about a 2 per cent grain ration, calculated to an acre basis, are given in table 4. As shown in this table, the net returns were higher in 1915 than in either 1914 or 1916. The average of the five lots shows that it required 2.6 pounds of grain with alfalfa pasture to produce 1 pound of gain, or for every 100 pounds of grain fed the sows and pigs gained 38.4 pounds. The average net return per acre of alfalfa pasture for 60 days was $63.11, or a daily net return of $1.05. The lowest net return for the pasture was $54.11 and the highest $77.76. This highest net return was obtained from the lot fed ground barley. If the sows and pigs are charged $7 per acre for 60 days' use of alfalfa pasture, $1.07 per hundredweight for corn, and $1 per hundredweight for barley, each 100 pounds of gain cost on </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Pork Production on Irrigated hands in Western Nebraska 19 an average $3.24. The gains on the 1914 lot cost $3.83 per hundredweight, while the gains on the barley lot in 1915 cost only $2.76. IO ■*&gt; -*t O IM t- &lt;N CO W Xl'^tOMMX CO ** N ■*• CO &lt;© .- - •» X -1 91M9! SO «D c us « •»- s V £ in •L' Ht- ~. oo OOt-N-^^CC— ■« x rj o co to -T a ■ : fc 7 r "-i Ifc :*- £ ?■• ad o t a So -c ■ 1 s° | 3 £ : Set's : .£ *■•« : » So :.s :o" S«| §4;2 ■ -5 jijjjfi I|iaj] 5 The average yield of similar plats of alfalfa during these pasturing periods was 2.23 tons per acre. If it is assumed that the pastured plats would have yielded the same, the five lots paid an average of $28.74 a ton for alfalfa hay and the hogs did the harvesting themselves. Moreover, by pasturing the alfalfa ,- o 4O 5O « t- «* &lt;&lt;f m m 01 » -h 2^° ! S N S *i S io t- ? i / oi f^ as -£ act^oio^eqco I oi i-&lt; n ec a&gt; I -a «0 W OS W O £ t*; N I U3 G&gt; CO 00 g ! ■*&gt; to &lt;c © co -«j» o lOOSCOlO 1- -7 I- t- C aOooNt-^ooeqeJ t^ ih n t^ « •* C- Vr 01 I </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 it may be assumed that the fertility of the soil was somewhat increased. Fig. 3— |-Sows and pigs on alfalfa pasture in 1914. The little pigs increased in weight from an average of 11.7 pounds to 45.4 pounds in 60 days, almost 400 per cent CORN AND PASTURE VERSUS CORN IN DRY-LOT FOR FINISHING SHOTES In this experiment corn and alfalfa pasture was compared with corn in dry-lot for finishing shotes for market. The experi - ment began on July 7, 1916, and ended September 8, a period of 63 days. The shotes used in this experiment had been on alfalfa pasture and about a 2 per cent ration of grain since April 29. Four lots were used. Two lots, one with 16 shotes and the other with 12 shotes, were grazed on a 1-acre and a three-fourths acre pasture, respectively. Corresponding lots were fed corn in dry-lot. The shotes in dry-lot were given all the corn they would clean up, while the shotes on pasture were fed a limited amount of corn during the first 30 days but during the last 33 days were fed all they would eat. The shotes on pasture had </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 21 an abundance of young alfalfa all the time; in fact the pasture would have carried perhaps a fourth more hogs. The shotes in each lot were weighed at the end of the first month and again at the end of the experiment. The amount of grain fed each lot was also kept separate for each period. If the corn is credited with the value of the gains made, the two dry-lots paid $1.56 and $1.51 during the first period, but only $1.21 and $1.28 respectively during the second period, for each 100 pounds of corn fed. This difference, no doubt, was due to the fact that the hogs had been on alfalfa pasture with about a 2 per cent grain ration for two months previous to this experiment and were in prime condition to make gains when put on a full grain ration, but after the first 30 days, the residual effect of the alfalfa, so to speak, had more or less disappeared. The results for the whole period are summarized in table 5. The shotes used in lots 2 and 4 were smaller than those used in the other two lots, — they were what might be called culls but not runty. Lots 1 and 3 and lots 2 and 4, respectively, are comparable. Table 5 — Results obtained from an experiment comparing corn and alfalfa pasture with corn in dry-lot at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm in 1916 Corn and pasture Corn in dry-lot Items of comparison 1-acre {-acre , . _ -. lot 1 lot 2 Iot 3 lot 4 Number of shotes IK 12 16 12 Average initial weight Pounds 149 119 143 123 do 239 208 218 206 do 1,432 1,065 1,203 999 do 5,556 4,121 6,192 5,108 Average final weight . Total gain Total corn fed Corn per pound of gain ... do 3.88 3.87 5.15 5.11 'Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered, 3ain per 100 pounds of corn do 25.8 25.9 25. 19.4 19.4 19.6 19.6 I - I Financial statement: Value of gains (at 7c per pound) Equivalent paid for 100 pounds of corn when fed in dry-lot .... Net return per acre of alfalfa pasture (corn at $1.36 and $1.37). Net return per acre of alfalfa pasture &lt; corn at $ 1 .07 ) Cost per 100 pounds of gain (corn $1.07, pasture $7 per acre). . . . $100.24 24.68 40.80 4.62 $74.55 24.13 . 40.58 4.72 $84.21 1.36 5.51 $69.93 1.37 5.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 The pasture lots were fed an average of 3.29 and the dry-lots an average of 4.55 pounds of corn during the first month and 4.22 and 5.64 pounds, respectively, during the second month for each pound of gain made. For the whole period the pasture lots made an average of 25.8 pounds of gain, and the dry-lots an average of 19.5 pounds of gain, for each 100 pounds of corn fed. Had the corn that was fed on the pasture lots been fed in dry-lot it would have produced only 1,887 pounds of gain instead of 2,497 pounds. The one and three-quarter acres of alfalfa pasture, therefore, produced 610 pounds of gain, which, with hogs at $7 per hundredweight, is worth $42.70. This is equivalent to $24.21 per acre for alfalfa pasture from July 7 to September 8. Had the hogs in dry-lot been on pasture they would have made the same amount of gains with 2,762 pounds less corn and the gains would have been faster. As shown in table 5, lot 3 paid $1.36 and lot 4, $1.37 per hundredweight of corn. If lots 1 and 2 are charged $1.36 and $1.37, respectively, for the corn fed, lot 1 gave a net return of $24.68 and lot 2, $24.13 per acre for alfalfa pasture for 63 days. When charged $7 an acre for two months' pasturing and $1.07 per hundredweight for corn, each 100 pounds of gain cost an average of $4.67 in the pasture lots and $5.49 in the dry-lots. HOGGING CORN The experiments which have been conducted with different methods of hogging corn fall into two classes, 1 1 1 those in which no supplement was fed with the corn and (2) those in which the hogs were provided with some nitrogenous feeds while they were in the cornfield. Experiments in which no supplements were used have been conducted for five years and the others for two years. SUMMARY OF FOUR YEARS' RESULTS ON CORN WITHOUT SUPPLEMENTARY FEED Each year in the irrigated crop-rotation field, a quarter-acre plat of corn in a 6-year rotation is fenced and the hogs are turned into it to harvest the crop. This experiment began in 1912 and has been continued each year. The hogs are turned into the corn when it is well "dented," usually about September 10. As no supplementary feed is supplied and as the weeds and volunteer alfalfa are kept down, the gains secured are made from corn alone. Each year since 1912 the corn has been grown on land which had produced alfalfa the previous year. This explains the difference in yields, as will be indicated later. The results of the four years' tests, computed to an acre basis, are given in table 6. These results are not strictly com- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 23 parable, as there were two varying factors. The average initial weight of the hogs varied from 117 pounds in 1912 to 63 pounds in 1914, and the number of days that the hogs were on the corn varied from 16 in 1912 to 49 in 1914. Small shotes will make more gain than larger hogs from a given quantity of feed. Hogs that have just been taken from alfalfa pasture will make very good gains for a short period on corn alone, but when fed corn alone for a long period the gains are not so good. In other words, 100 pounds of corn will make more gain on hogs the first week after the hogs are taken off alfalfa pasture than the same amount of corn will when fed to hogs that have been on corn alone for several weeks. As will be seen from table 6, these two variable factors were in direct opposition to each other; that is, the larger the hogs the shorter the feeding period. As the corn crop in 1915 was seriously affected by hail, the results of that year are not included in the average shown in table 6, but they are shown in the last column of the table as a matter of record. Table 6 — Results of hogging corn without supplementary feed at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm from 1912 to 1916, inclusive Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered, A short hogging period is objectional from an experimental standpoint because there are more chances of error. For example, if the hogs are gaunt at either the initial or the final weighing, 20 hogs on a corn plat for 1 week will give a larger error than 2 hogs on the same plat for 10 weeks. The mean weight of three consecutive days' weighings will not entirely eliminate this error, especially if the hogs are left on the corn plat too long and are gaunt at the final weighing. Just how much each of these factors influenced the results shown in table 6 is uncertain. There is 4-year Items of comparison 1912 1913 1914 1916 average 1915 Number of hogs 28 24 24 20 24 12 Number of days 16 28 49 23 36 19 Average initial weight Pounds 117 91 63 94 91 75 Total gain per acre . do 628 1,012 1,048 840 882 212 Gain per 100 lbs. of corn do 20.0 21.8 22.6 22.4 21.7 14.5 . . 'Financial statement: Value of gains per acre $43.96 $70.84 $73.36 $58.80 $61.74 $14.84 Returns per 100 pounds of corn 1.38 1.53 1.60 1.56 1.52 1.00 Cost per 100 pounds of gain icorn at $1.07 per hun- dredweight 5.36 4.81 4.67 4.78 4.90 7.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 little doubt but that the low returns per bushel of corn in 1912 were due to the fact that a larger sow was in the lot. The low total gains and net returns per acre in 1912, however, were due largely to the low yield of corn, it having been estimated at 56.1 bushels per acre, as compared with 82.6, 81.9, and 66.9 bushels respectively for 1913, 1914, and 1916. In computing the cost of 100 pounds of gain, a charge of $1.07 per hundredweight was made for the corn. The results show that this method of utilizing corn has much to recommend it. SUMMARY OF TWO YEARS' RESULTS WITH DUPLICATE LOTS ON CORN WITH SUPPLEMENTARY FEED To secure information regarding the value of tankage and of alfalfa pasture as supplements to corn when hogged off, an experiment was conducted in duplicate in 1914 and 1915. Six lots of hogs were used each year, as follows: Lots 1 and 2 hogged corn alone; lots 3 and 4 hogged corn and had access to an alfalfa field; and lots 5 and 6 hogged corn and had what tankage they would eat. The shotes used in this experiment had been in the alfalfa pasturing experiment and were very uniform in size, as will be seen from the weights in table 7. Each year the yield of each plat was estimated by counting all the stalks of corn and harvesting systematically the corn from 100 stalks; that is to say, if a plat had a total of 3,400 stalks, the corn was harvested from every thirty-fourth stalk. The harvested corn was dried, weighed, and returned to the plat to be eaten by the hogs. The total weight was divided by 100, to determine the average yield per stalk harvested. This average weight was then multiplied by the total number of stalks on the plat in order to determine the yield. As the low-yielding plats became cleaned up, weighed quanti - ties of corn were added, so that all the hogs would be kept on feed the same length of time. Enough corn was added as became necessary so that the hogs had corn before them all the time. When the last lot had cleaned up its plat the experiment was closed. A summary of the two years' results of these experiments, calculated to an acre basis, is given in table 7. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 25 Table 7 — Results of hogging corn, with supplementary feed, at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm in 191 U and 1915 Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered. The data given in table 7 are the averages of four lots in each case and are calculated to an acre basis. The hogs were on the experiment 77 days in 1914 and 55 days in 1915, or an average for the two seasons of 66 days. The average initial weight of the shotes in the different lots was 81 pounds, and the average final weight was 164.4 pounds for the corn-alone lot, 185 pounds for the pasture lot, and 195.3 pounds for the tankage lot, or 1.25 1.57, and 1.73 pounds of daily gains, respectively. The tankage lot made 38 per cent faster gains than the corn-alone lot and 10 per cent faster than the pasture lot. The total gain, on an acre basis, was 744 pounds where the hogs received only corn, 930 pounds where they had access to alfalfa pasture, and 1,029 pounds when fed 300 pounds of tankage in connection with the corn. The net returns per 100 pounds of corn consumed were $1.34 where corn was fed alone, $1.55 where the hogs had access to alfalfa pasture, and $1.50 when they were fed tankage. A 100-pound gain cost $5.61 in the corn lot, $4.88 in the pasture lot, and $5.26 in the tankage lot. From the results of these tests it appears that it would be better to buy tankage at $3.20 per hundredweight and feed it to hogs in connection with hogged-off corn than not to supple - ment the corn, but when the hogs can have access to alfalfa pasture it is doubtful whether it would pay to feed tankage. Items of comparison Corn and Corn Corn alfalfa and only pasture tankage Corn and tankage Number of lota Number of hogs per acre in each test Number of days Average initial weight per hog Pounds Average final weight per hog do Average daily gain per hog do Total gain per acre do Corn consumed (estimated yield plus corn added) do 4 4 4 9 9 9 66 66 66 81.7 81.7 81.0 164.4 185.0 195.3 1.25 1.57 1.73 744 930 1,029 ! 3,900 4,149 I 4,161 'Financial statement: Value of gain (at 7c per pound) Cost of tankage (300 pounds, at $3.20) Charged for alfalfa pasture Net returns per 100 pounds of corn Cost per 100 pounds of gain (corn $1.07) . . . $52.08 $65.10 $72.03 9.60 1.00 1.34 1.55 1.50 5.61 4.88 5.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 The chief advantage of hogging corn is that the farmer is spared the expense of harvesting the crop, hauling the manure back to the land, and feeding the corn to the hogs. A disadvan - tage is the cost of fencing. It seems certain that hogs will make as many pounds of gain from a bushel of corn in the field as they will if the corn is harvested and fed in dry-lot. The question for the farmer to decide, then, is whether it is cheaper to harvest the crop and feed the hogs in a dry-lot or to fence the corn and let the hogs themselves harvest it. DRY-LOT FEEDING EXPERIMENTS In the irrigated districts where potatoes and sugar beets are two of the principal crops, it is important to know the feeding value of cull potatoes and also to know whether it pays to feed sugar beets to fattening hogs. The latter is particularly impor - tant to farmers whose farms are far removed from the railroads so that delivering beets is expensive. It is also important to know the relative feeding value of sugar beets and mangels. To secure information on these points, experiments were con - ducted at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm during the fall of 1912, 1914, and 1915. CORN, SUGAR BEETS, AND MANGELS The hogs used in this experiment were very good, thrifty shotes which had been on alfalfa pasture and about a 2 per cent grain ration during the summer. There were 26 shotes in all, divided into three lots, as follows: 8 in lot 1, which were fed corn only; 9 in lot 2, fed corn and sugar beets; and 9 in lot 3, fed corn and mangels. Each lot was fed all it would clean up twice daily. Beets and mangels were fed about one hour before the corn was fed. Ear corn was used but when referred to in the discussion is in terms of shelled corn on the basis of 22 per cent cob. The average initial weight of these shotes was 105 pounds. The average daily gain per shote was 2.09 pounds in lot 1 ; 2.26 pounds in lot 2; and 2.20 pounds in lot 3. These are exception - ally fast gains. The experiment was conducted only 24 days, which is too short a time to show any very reliable results. Altho these results are not to be taken as conclusive, it is thought that they are of some value, particularly as indicating the relative feeding value of sugar beets and mangels. Lot 1 made 402 pounds of gain, lot 2 made 448 pounds, and lot 3 made 476 pounds. Lot 1 was fed 1,691 pounds of corn, and lots 2 and 3 were fed 1,790 pounds of sugar beets and 2,400 pounds of mangels </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 27 respectively, each receiving 1,590 pounds of corn in addition. For each 100 pounds of gain lot 1 was fed 421 pounds of corn; lot 2, 326 pounds of corn and 367 pounds of sugar beets; and lot 3, 334 pounds of corn and 504 pounds of mangels. If the hogs are charged $1.07 per hundredweight for corn, $5 per ton for sugar beets, and $3 per ton for mangels, each 100 pounds of gain cost $4.51 in lot 1, $4.41 in lot 2, and $4.33 in lot 3. Lot 1 made gains enough to pay $1.66 per hundredweight for the corn consumed. When lots 2 and 3 are charged this same price for corn, lot 2 paid $8.61 a ton for sugar beets, and lot 3 paid $5.77 a ton for mangels. On this basis, if sugar beets are worth $5 a ton, mangels are worth $3.55 a ton; or, in terms of yield, a 15-ton yield of sugar beets has the same feeding value as a 22.5-ton yield of mangels. If lot 2 is charged $5 per ton of sugar beets and lot 3, $3 per ton of mangels, they each paid $1.86 per hundredweight for the corn fed. CORN, ALFAL~A HAY, AND SUGAR BZETS EXPERIMENTS IN 1914 In the fall of 1914 another experiment, to determine the feeding value of sugar beets when fed with varying amounts of corn and alfalfa hay in racks, was inaugurated. The experi - ment covered 60 days. The eighteen hogs, which were divided into lots of six hogs each, were fairly good shotes, having been used during the summer in the alfalfa pasturing work. Each lot was given all the fourth-cutting alfalfa hay it would eat. In addition to this, lot 1 was fed a 4 per cent ration of corn; lot 2, a 3 per cent corn ration plus sugar beets; and lot 3, a 2 per cent corn ration plus sugar beets. Lots 2 and 3 were fed all the sugar beets they would clean up. The total initial weight of lot 1 was 798 pounds and the final weight was 1,333 pounds. This lot made 535 pounds of gain from 2,050 pounds of corn and 344 pounds of alfalfa hay, — or, 383 pounds of corn and 64 pounds of hay per 100 pounds of gain, which cost $4.35. In lot 2 the initial weight of the hogs was 795 pounds and their final weight 1,318, or a gain of 523 pounds. This lot was fed 1,490 pounds of corn, 3,380 pounds of sugar beets, and 250 pounds of hay. To produce 100 pounds of gain this lot was fed 285 pounds of corn, 646 pounds of beets, and 48 pounds of hay, at a cost of $4.85. The hogs in lot 3 weighed 797 pounds when the test began and 1,274 pounds when it closed. To produce this 477 pounds of gain, the hogs were fed 1,025 pounds of corn, 5,530 pounds of beets, and 310 pounds of hay, — or 215 pounds of corn, 1,150 pounds of beets, and 65 pounds of hay, at a cost of $5.41, for each 100 pounds of gain. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 EXPERIMENTS IN 1915 WITH THE ADDITION OF CULL POTATOES AND GROUND BARLEl' The 1914 corn-hay-beet experiment was duplicated during the fall of 1915. Substantially the same methods were followed each year. In addition to these three lots, two more lots were used, in which ground barley replaced corn in one case and cull potatoes replaced sugar beets in the other. There were seven shotes in each lot. The feeding period covered 72 days. Lot 1 made 415 pounds of gain and was fed 1,818 pounds of corn and 506 pounds of hay, or 438 and 122 pounds, respectively, per 100 pounds of gain. Lot 2, which was fed 1,336 pounds of corn, 4,661 pounds of beets, and 489 pounds of hay, made 513 pounds of gain, or 100 pounds of gain from 260 pounds of corn, 908 pounds of beets, and 104 pounds of hay. In lot 3 the hogs made 486 pounds of gain from 1,013 pounds of corn, 5,689 pounds of beets, and 480 pounds of hay, which is 208 pounds of corn, 1,170 pounds of beets, and 100 pounds of hay for each 100 pounds of gain. In lot 4 ground barley was substituted for corn; other - wise this lot was similar to lot 2. Lot 4 was fed 1,224 pounds of ground barley, 5,313 pounds of beets, and 364 pounds of hay, and produced 593 pounds of gain. This lot was fed 205 pounds of barley, 896 pounds of beets, and 61 pounds of hay for 100 pounds of gain, or 55 pounds of grain, 12 pounds of beets, and 43 pounds of hay less than lot 2 for the same gain. The only difference between lot 5 and lot 2 was that cull potatoes were used in lot 5 instead of sugar beets. Lot 5 made 466 pounds of gain and was fed 1,440 pounds of corn, 2,220 pounds of cull potatoes, and 486 pounds of hay. For 100 pounds of gain this lot was fed 309 pounds of corn, 476 pounds of potatoes, and 104 pounds of hay. Only the relative results from lots 1, 2, and 3 will be discussed here; the detailed results will be discussed under table 8, which is the summary of two years' results. The barley and potato lots have each been run only one season. The results are not, therefore, as conclusive as the results from two or more tests would be. It is thought, however, that the results at hand are of enough value to warrant their publication in brief. Of the five feeding lots on experiment in 1915, the barley lot made the fastest and cheapest gains, while the potato lot was second in cheapness and next to the lowest in rate of gain. When the hogs are charged $5 a ton for beets and potatoes and $8 per ton for alfalfa hay, the barley lot paid $2.18 per hundredweight for ground barley and the potato lot paid $1.75 per hundred - weight for corn. Lot 1, which was fed a 4 per cent corn ration and alfalfa hay, paid $1.49 per hundredweight for corn when </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 29 charged $8 per ton for hay. If the barley and potato lots are charged these same prices for the grain and hay, they still paid $8.62 and $8.31 a ton respectively for beets and potatoes. The results of this test again indicate very strongly that ground barley has as high feeding value as corn. With the results from this test and also from the alfalfa pasturing experi - ments where ground barley has been compared with corn, it seems safe to say that ground barley is equal to corn as a hog feed. It must be remembered, however, that in all these tests the barley was ground. By comparing the potato lot with lot 1, which was fed corn and alfalfa hay, it will be seen that 476 pounds of cull potatoes replaced 129 pounds of corn and 16 pounds of hay per 100 pounds of gain. According to this, when corn is worth $1.07 a hundred - weight and alfalfa hay $8 a ton, cull potatoes are worth $6.05 a ton, or 18 cents a bushel. When compared with lot 2 it will be seen that 486 pounds of potatoes and 48 pounds of corn had the same feeding value as 908 pounds of beets. In lot 2 when beets were worth $5 a ton, corn was worth $1.30 a hundred - weight. On this basis, if the value of the 48 pounds of corn is subtracted from the value of the 908 pounds of beets at $5 a ton, it will be seen that 476 pounds of potatoes had a comparative feeding value of $1.65, or $6.90 a ton. In this test 1 ton of potatoes was equivalent to 1.36 tons of sugar beets. It is apparent from this experiment that cull potatoes have some value as a hog feed. This is contrary to the belief of many. It is not uncommon for farmers, when there is no sale for potatoes, to let their potatoes rot in the cellar and at the same time pay out cash for corn with which to finish their hogs or to carry them thru the winter. There is no question that potatoes either with a liberal ration of grain for finishing hogs or with alfalfa hay for wintering old sows have a feeding value nearly equal to sugar beets. SIMMARY OF TWO YEARS' RESULTS The two years' results from lots 1, 2 and 3 are given in table 8. The results were substantially the same each year, except that the corn lot made the faster gains in 1914 and the beet lots the faster in 1915. The cost per 100 pounds of gain was higher in 1915 than in 1914. In 1914 the hogs were fed ear corn, and in 1915 they were fed shelled corn. This difference in corn may explain the difference in cost, for it is generally conceded that ear corn gives a little better results than shelled corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 159 30 Table 8 — Results obtained by feeding finishing hogs corn and alfalfa hay; and corn, alfalfa hay, and sugar beets at the Scotts - bluff Experiment Farm in 191U and 1915 'Labor, risk, interest on investment, etc., are not here considered. By comparing lots 1 and 2 it will be seen that lot 1 consumed 133 pounds of corn and 8 pounds of hay more than did lot 2 per 100 pounds of gain. On the other hand, lot 2 was fed 776 pounds of beets. Therefore, 133 pounds of corn and 8 pounds of hay, had the same feeding value as 776 pounds of beets. To make it simple, 583 pounds of beets replaced 100 pounds of corn. On this basis, when beets are worth $5 a ton, corn is worth $1.46 a hundredweight. If lot 1 is charged $8 a ton for hay it gives a return of $1.63 a hundredweight for corn. When lots 2 and 3 were charged $1.63 for corn and $8 for hay, they paid $5.61 and $5.57 respectively per ton for beets; but when only market prices were charged for the different feeds, lots 2 and 3 paid $9.66 and $7.60 a ton for beets and $1.72 and $1.77 a hundred - weight for corn, respectively. According to these returns, lot 1 paid 48 per cent, lot 2 33 per cent, and lot 3 27 per cent more than market prices for the feed consumed. One hundred pounds of gain cost $4.71 in lot 1, $5.15 in lot 2, and $5.26 in lot 3. According to these results, corn at $1.07 per hundredweight is a cheaper feed for finishing hogs than beets at $5 a ton. It may seem from this that beets have no place as a feed for finish - ing hogs; but look at it from another viewpoint. In lot 1 it required 407 pounds of corn and 89 pounds of hay to produce 100 pounds of gain. At this rate, 1,432 pounds of corn (the Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Items of comparison 4',&lt; corn, 3' t corn, 2', corn, hay beets, hay beets, hay Total gain Pounds Corn fed do Sugar beets fed do Alfalfa hay fed do Corn per 100 pounds of gain do Beets per 100 pounds of gain do Hay per 100 pounds of gain do 475 518 483 1,934 1,423 1,019 4,020 5,610 425 418 395 407 274 211 774 1,161 89 81 81 'Financial statement: Value of gains Return per 100 pounds of corn i Return per ton of beets icorn at $1.63, hay at $8) Return per ton of beets (corn at $1.07 1 Cost per 100 pounds of gain 1 $33.25 $36.26 $33.81 1.63 1.72 1.77 5.61 5.57 9.66 7.60 4.71 5.15 5.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska 31 amount fed to lot 2) and 301 pounds of hay would have produced 350 pounds of gain. Lot 2 made 518 pounds of gain. The 168 pounds of gain can, therefore, be credited to the 4,020 pounds of beets and 117 pounds of hay. With hogs worth $7 a hundred - weight, this 168 pounds of gain is worth $11.76; from this, subtract 47 cents for the 117 pounds of hay, and it leaves a balance of $11.29 for the 4,020 pounds of beets, or $5.61 a ton. It is estimated that it costs $33.10 an acre to grow sugar beets up to, but not including, hauling, and $8.05 for growing an acre of corn up to harvesting. On this basis, and assuming that the hauling and siloing of the beets on the farm cost the same as harvesting of the corn crop, a 14.25-ton yield of beets will give the same net return as a 60-bushel yield of corn. As the farmer in most beet-growing sections can grow $5 beets at a large profit where he is saved the expense of hauling, it appears from these results that it would be a good practice to grow both corn and beets for finishing hogs and to feed them all the corn, beets, and hay they will clean up. </seg>
            <seg id="p032"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>