<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Hog Prices</title>
               <date value="1925-05">1925-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 208 Hog Prices BY H. C. FILLEY DEPARTMENT OF RURAL ECONOMICS Receipts of hogs at 11 markets and average price of hogs at Chicago THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS The Importance of Hog Prices 3 Forces Affecting Hog Prices 3 Supply and Demand 4 Cost of Production 5 Market Strategy S Monopoly 6 Money , 7 Credit , 3 Transportation : 9 Commercial Costs 11 Import Duties '. 11 Corn and Hog Ratios 11 Monthly Variation in Hog Receipts and Hog Prices 15 Yearly Variation in Hog Receipts and Hog Prices 19 Pork Exports 25 Pork Exports and Hog Prices 27 Pork Exports and Hog Prices 27 Cycles of Hog Production 27 The Outlook 28 Safe Planning . 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">H. C. FILLEY THE IMPORTANCE OF HOG PRICES Cost of production and selling price are the two factors rhich determine whether hogs are produced at a gain or at loss. Fortunately, most farmers who produce hogs in any considerable numbers are able to estimate fairly accurately the principal items of cost entering into hog production. Experiment stations have published the results of numerous experiments in feeding hogs, and the thoughtful farmer has supplemented these investigations by keeping records of his own costs. We know to a reasonable degree of accuracy how many bushels of corn and pounds of tankage should be required to produce 100 pounds of pork when the hogs have access to alfalfa pasture. There is ordinarily more likelihood of a wide variation in the price of corn and other feeds from season to season than in the amount of feed consumed in producing 100 pounds of pork. The man who produces pork as a method of marketing corn feels these changes in feed prices less keenly than the man who buys feeds from month to month. Much less attention has been given to studying the forces which control hog prices than to studying feed requirements. This is but natural, since the individual producer can have much more influence upon cost of production than upon price. Profits depend, however, quite as much upon the price received as upon efficiency in production. This bulletin is written to explain the forces affecting hog prices, so thai the individual farmer may regulate his production in accor - dance with the probable price outlook and possible profit. FORCES AFFECTING HOG PRICES The more important forces which determine price are nine in number. They are as follows: 1. Supply and demand 2. Cost of production 3. Market strategy 4. Monopoly 5. The quantity of money in circulation and the rapidity with which it circulates </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 6. Credit 7. Transportation costs 8. Commercial costs 9. Import duties Some of these forces have but little effect on hog prices; others are very important. Following a brief discussion of each of these forces, graphs will be presented showing how the forces have influenced prices in recent years. SUPPLY AND DEMAND Under competitive conditions, the forces which have the greatest influence in determining the price of any product at any given time and place are supply and demand. The supply of any commodity as used in the phrase " supply and demand " is the quantity that will be offered for sale at a given price; the demand is the quantity that will be bought at a given price. If the price of a commodity is lowered, the consumer purchases more; if the price is raised, the con - sumer purchases less. Sellers, if they wish buyers to take more of a commodity, must reduce the price; if they raise the price they will sell less. When hogs are marketed in unusually large numbers, the price is almost invariably low. For example, in 1924 more hogs were marketed than in any preceding year, and prices fell considerably below the general level of production costs. Consumers ate pork, not only because it was good but be - cause it was cheap. European demand would have taken but a relatively small amount of pork at a high price; because of the low price, an almost unprecedented amount was exported. When few hogs are being marketed the price of pork rises. If the demand for a product at a given price is increased, tas for example, the demand for pork was increased during war, — the price rises until some persons necessarily rease their consumption, and demand and supply meet on a new and higher level ; on the other hand, if there is a falling off in demand, as always happens during a period of business depression, sellers must either accept lower prices or put less on the market. Not only do the quantity supplied and the quantity demanded influence price, but price in turn influences the quantity supplied and demanded. When the price of a product is relatively high, producers increase the supply, until because of this increase the price necessarily drops. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Hog Prices 5 For example, hogs were relatively high in 1921 compared with corn and many other farm products, and nearly all Corn Belt farmers were anxious to produce more hogs. The increased number of hogs caused hog prices to drop to relatively low levels in 1923 and 1924. This low price caused many farmers to decrease hog production. A decrease in the number of hogs is logically followed by an increase in price. As a matter of course, the demand for pork is influenced by various factors. More meat is consumed in cold weather than in hot weather. An increase in general prosperity in - creases the demand for pork, but demand decreases during a period of depression. Demand is also increased by adver - tising. An attractive picture of bacon and eggs or nicely sliced ham appeals to the appetite and thereby increases demand. The advertising of meat and lard substitutes de - creases the demand for pork and therefore tends to lower prices. COST OF PRODUCTION The cost of producing any commodity influences price in the long run, because no one will continue to produce goods to be sold for less than it costs to produce them, while if the price is well above production costs, other men will be induced to enter that particular field, and production will increase until the goods must be sold for lower prices if all are to be consumed. Cost of production has little effect upon the price which may be obtained for any product at any particular time. If a greater quantity of any commodity is produced than is demanded at a price which equals cost of production, producers must sell at a loss or else keep a part of the supply off the market. If demand increases or if the supply is short, those who have produced at normal cost may sell for much more than cost of production. Unfortunately for producers, perishable farm products must be sold regard - less of price when they are ready for market. Because hog feeding was profitable in 1921 and 1922, there was a large increase in hog production. As a result, prices fell until a large part of the 1923 pig crop sold for less than cost of production. Under such conditions the most efficient producer has a very decided advantage. He may even secure a small profit when other men are producing hogs at a loss. We may expect the average price of hogs over a long time period to equal cost of production plus a reasonable profit for the efficient producers. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 The relationship between the price of corn and the cost of producing hogs is discussed on pages 12-14. MARKET STRATEGY There are almost always forces at work which seek to fix a somewhat different price than would be established by supply and demand under conditions of absolutely free com - petition. Whenever the run of hogs at any terminal market is far above normal, the market almost invariably drops. The heavy run upon one day or upon every day in one week does not materially change either the number of hogs in America or the supply of pork; neither does it affect the demand for pork and pork products. The increase in supply is a local increase, which may be great enough to tax the facilities of local slaughterhouses. Since there are enough hogs to supply the ordinary needs of all buyers at the market, com - petition is less keen than when the run is small. Under such conditions it is good strategy for the buyers to appear in - different and offer to purchase only at a lower price. The shippers realize the expense of keeping hogs at the terminal market for even a few days, and therefore usually sell. As a matter of course, local supply and local demand enter into the lower price, but market strategy also enters and is a potent factor. MONOPOLY Monopoly has been defined as " that substantial unity of action on the part of one or more persons engaged in some kind of business which gives exclusive control, more par - ticularly altho not solely with respect to prices." The owner of a patent has a complete monopoly, since he has control !f the price at which the patented article may be sold. He an fix his price because he controls the supply. As a matter f course, if he sets the price too high the sales will be so ew that his total profits will be small. On the other hand, if the price is set very close to the cost of production, the net profits will be small even tho the total sales are large. The owners of but few patent rights can actually dominate a market, because there is usually some other article which may be used even tho it does not serve the purpose so well. In other words, the control of any single article or product does not give control of the competitors of that article cr product. It is probable that monopoly power enters but little if any into the price of hogs at the terminal markets. The five </seg>
            <seg id="p007">XT Ti t^ 7 largest packing companies in the United States are in direct competition with smaller establishments and with one an - other. Their united purchases amount to less than one-third of the total number of hogs slaughtered annually. The census of manufacturers reports that there were 1397 slaughtering and meat packing establishments in 1923 that did a business of $5,000 or more. This does not include establishments which slaughter for retail trade only. The Bureau of Animal Industry has published a list of 344 establishments which had government inspection upon January 15, 1925. Most of these establishments do an interstate business. Almost every village butcher shop in the middle west either does slaughter or can easily arrange to slaughter a considerable part of the meat which it sells. Each farmer who produces hogs is a competitor, either actual or potential, of the pack - ing house and local butcher. He usually slaughters one or more hogs each year for home consumption and if prices justify is often willing to sell either fresh or cured pork in the nearby towns. MONEY An increase in the amount of money in circulation causes the general price level to rise, while a decrease causes it to fall. In other words, as the supply of money increases, a greater amount is required in exchange for other commod - ities. Without making an exhaustive explanation it may be stated that " the value of money, under the simplest con - ditions, is exactly inverse to its quantity." ' If the quantity of money in circulation is doubled, other conditions remain - ing the same, prices will be twice as high as before and the value of money will be one-half. It should be remembered that conditions are far from simple and are constantly chang - ing. Changes in the amount of money in circulation have so far been accompanied more or less closely by changes in other forces affecting prices. To the present generation, the prices of farm products of a century ago seem almost unbelievably low. We wonder how a farmer could possibly have obtained sufficient income to pay for even the few necessities of that time until we find that the price of the labor that he employed and the goods that he purchased averaged almost as low relatively as the price of the products that he sold. In 1800 there was but $4.99 — gold, silver, and paper — in circulation for each man, woman, and child in the United States. In the succeeding 1 Taussig. Principles of Economics. Vol. I. p. 2.1.1. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 forty years the per capita circulation but little more than doubled ($10.91), and even at the outbreak of the Civil War in 1861 stood at only $13.98. It is but little wonder that prices were low when there was so little money with which to buy. Prices increased gradually but steadily from 1896 to 1914, while the amount of money in circulation increased from $21.44 per capita to $34.35 per capita. Upon July 1, 1920, our per capita circulation was $50.11 and the general price level was nearly two and one half times as high as upon July 1, 1914. The relationship between money and prices is very apparent if we represent the changes in each graphically. At first, bank deposits and money rose faster but later prices rose faster. Prices also dropped more rapidly. The rapidity with which money circulates is also a factor affecting prices. This is because it is the money which is expended that creates the demand for goods. If everyone spends money as quickly as possible after it comes into his possession, as there was a tendency to do in the inflation period following the war, the price of commodities will in - evitably rise. Doubling the work that a dollar does is just as PELATION OF MONEY, &amp;ANK DEPOSITS AHO W?Ci6 IK UMtTtD SUTE.5 Fig. 1. — Relation of money, bank deposits and prices in the United States, 1914 to 1924. (1910-1914 = 100.) </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Hog Prices effective in raising prices as doubling the number of dollars; conversely, keeping money out of circulation by being slow to make purchases lowers prices as does a decrease in the actual number of dollars. CREDIT The immediate effect of credit sales on prices is the same as cash sales, because credit purchases constitute a demand for goods. This effect is counterbalanced when debts incurred by the purchase of goods are paid, because the money is then used in payment of a past demand instead of being used to satisfy a present demand. A very general granting of credit, such as occurred in 1919, tends to raise prices. When creditors begin to demand payment as they did in the autumn of 1920 prices fall. When credit instruments are used in place of money, as when we make payments by check, the effect is the same as increasing the volume of money. Unquestionably the in - crease of deposit banking and the extensive use of the bank check has had an effect upon prices. The use of Liberty Bonds in place of money also contributed in a small way to the post-war boom, because the effect of using a substitute for money is the same as increasing the volume of money. TRANSPORTATION Transportation charges ordinarily increase the margin between the price received by the producer and that paid by the consumer by the amount of the charge. It is, there - fore, obvious that an increase in transportation costs either decreases the price paid to the producer or increases the price paid by the consumer, or possibly the increased cost is divided between producer and consumer. The Nebraska consumer unquestionably pays the freight upon the coal, farm machinery, and various other commod - ities which are shipped into the state. The increase in freight rates since 1916 has added very materially to our cost of living. Transportation costs have an even greater effect upon the price of most agricultural products than upon the price of manufactured goods, because of their greater bulk in pro - portion to their value. Unfortunately for the grain belt farmers, the transportation charges upon wheat and corn and hogs cannot always be passed on to the consumer. For example, we export wheat to Europe; Argentine also exports </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 wheat to Europe. Nebraska wheat has a long haul before it reaches the water. Argentine wheat has a short rail haul. Our wheat sells in the Liverpool market upon its merits in competition with wheat from Argentine, Russia, Canada, and Australia. The cost of transporting our wheat com - pared with the cost of transporting their wheat is not con - sidered. In the final analysis the Nebraska farmer receives for his wheat the Liverpool price less freight and handling charges. The higher the freight rate, the less he receives. The above example does not indicate that the Nebraska farmer pays the freight on all of his products. Local demand may and often does increase the price, or the demand of a nearby state may raise our price above the price that the sea - board price justifies. It is also true that if because of high transportation charges farmers do not receive cost of pro - duction ,they must of necessity turn to producing some other commodity. Because of the decreased supply, the price of the commodity should then rise until it covers cost of production including transportation. LThe increase in freight rates from 1916 to 1920 has in - enced changes in Nebraska agriculture. It is impossible to ship hay as far as it could be shipped with profit before the raise in rates. The freight rate on corn from York, Nebraska, to Chicago was 20.35 cents per hundredweight in February, 1915. Ten years later it was 31 cents. The freight rate on hogs rose from 37 cents per hundredweight to 50 cents during the same period. Since between 3 and 4 pounds of corn or other grain are usually required to pro - duce 1 pound of pork in addition to other feeds and all other costs, it is very evident that, other things being equal, it is more advantageous for the Nebraska farmer to feed corn to hogs than it was in 1915. It is likewise very evident that the Ohio or Pennsylvania farmer is at a greater disadvantage in producing pork than in 1915. The price of the corn which he feeds has risen more proportionally than has the price of the hogs which he sells. Because of the changes in freight rates 100 pounds of hog flesh, live weight, will pay for more bushels of corn in Nebraska than in Ohio. The tendency is for the production of livestock and livestock products which can be transported readily to shift to the western part of the grain belt. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Hog Prices 11 COMMERCIAL COSTS Trade costs, such as commission or brokerage, inspection, weighing, insurance, yardage, and feeding costs, affect the price of farm products much as do transportation charges. They increase the spread between the price received by the producer and that paid by the consumer. In all organized markets such charges are uniform and regulated by rule. The livestock feeder who ships 20 cars of livestock to a com - mission firm in South Omaha (or any other large market) pays the same selling costs per car as the man who ship? but a single carload. Altho such charges are a relatively small percentage of the selling price, they do constitute a very definite charge which must be paid. The general public is interested not only in the service being performed for the shipper more economically than he could perform it for himself, but in its being performed with the utmost efficiency. In a part of the terminal markets to which Nebraska live - stock is shipped, co-operative commission companies, not members of any exchange, have been able to sell livestock for less than the prevailing commission charge. This decreased cost of service is due in part at least to the large volume of business handled. Some co-operative commission firms charge less than the prevailing rate at time of sale; others charge the regular rate and return any saving at the end of the year in the form of a patronage dividend. IMPORT DUTIES Import duties do not affect the price of those products of which we have an exportable surplus. A tariff on pork, for example, cannot increase the price of the pork which we export and sell in competition with the pork produced in other countries. There is little incentive for importing pork into this country because the United States is one of the largest pork producing and pork exporting nations in the world. If England or Germany or some other country to which we sell large amounts of pork and lard should place a high tariff on pork and pork products we would be affected because the demand of those countries for our product would be greatly reduced. CORN AND HOG RATIOS Cost of feed is the most important item entering into the cost of producing hogs, and in the United States as a whole corn is the most important hog feed. Investigations at the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 Nebraska Experiment Station show that healthy hogs which have free access to tankage, alfalfa pasture, and water will consume between 3 and 4 pounds of corn for each pound of pork. The average for 5 years' feeding experiments at the North Platte Substation ' was 339 pounds of grain, or a little more than 6 bushels of corn for each 100 pounds of gain. Men who are not efficient feeders or whose hogs are diseased or troubled with round worms or other parasites cannot expect to secure such satisfactory results. If the alfalfa pasture is poor or the amount of tankage or other protein supplement fed is restricted, more corn is required. Data obtained by the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture upon 51 droves of spring pigs in Iowa and Illinois in 1921 indicate that on the average 7.4 bushels of corn were required to pro - duce 100 pounds of gain in hogs. At that time corn was relatively cheap compared with tankage and mill feeds, so that most of the farmers made every effort " to use corn up to the maximum and still not injure their breeding stock nor hinder the growth of their pigs." - Feed is the most important item of cost but by no means the only cost to be considered by the hog producers. The total costs include the following : 1. Feed, including grain, pasture, tankage, mill feeds, skim milk, etc. 2. Labor 3. Interest on capital invested in herd and equipment 4. Depreciation on buildings and equipment 5. Veterinary, including vaccines, stock dip, etc. 6. Risk 7. Marketing costs 8. Taxes, overhead, and miscellaneous costs These items vary somewhat with the individual farm, but nevertheless must always be considered. The only way that any farmer can learn the efficiency of his own cost of pro - duction is to keep cost of production records and compare his results with recognized standards. Only those men will continue to produce hogs who receive or believe that they receive cost of production plus a reasonable profit. Altho both the proportion which corn constitutes of the total feed cost and the proportion which feed constitutes of the total cost are variable, farmers have been long accustomed 1 Snyder, W. P. Nebraska Bulletin 147. p. 26. 1 U. S. Department of Agriculture Yearbook 1928. pp. 221-223. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Hog Prices 13 to estimate total cost per hundred weight in terms of corn. The hog producers of a generation ago had little information upon production costs, but reached the conclusion that hogs were profitable only when the price for which they could be sold per hundredweight exceeds the value of ten bushels of corn. If corn were worth 40 cents per bushel the pro - ducer must receive more than $4.00 per hundredweight in order to receive any profit. Since corn was unusually low in price this ratio really allowed a very small amount for the other costs of production. When the ratio fell that low the average producer probably received a very low wage for his labor and nothing for his risk. Most men will decrease hog production when the corn- hog ratio falls as low as ten to one. They prefer to sell their corn instead of feeding it. In only 14 of the 65 years' period, 1860-1924 inclusive, ha3 the average price of hogs per hundredweight at Chicago been less than the Chicago price of 10 bushels of No. 2 corn. The average ratio has been approximately 11.5 to 1; that is, a hundredweight of hog, live weight, has sold for as much as 11.5 bushels of corn. The second column in Table 1 gives the Chicago corn-hog ratio, that is, the number of bushels of corn required each year to equal in value 100 pounds of live hog. The first 60 years are averaged in 10-year periods. Table 1. — Chicago corn-hog ratios, 1860-1924 I860 - 1869 1870 - 1879 1880 - 1889 1860 12.4 1870. 11.9 1880 12.3 1861 14.0 1871 10.2 1881 12.1 1862 10.0 1872 11.1 1882 10.9 1863 7.0 1873 12.3 1883 11.3 1864 7.3 1874 8.9 1884 10.5 1865 16.3 1875 11.8 1885 9.7 1866 16.2 1876 15.3 1886 11.1 1867 „ 7.2 1877 11.5 1887 12.4 1868 9.5 1878, 9.7 1888 12.3 10.3 1889 12.5 1869 14.0 1879 Ten-year average 11.4 Ten-year average 11.3 Ten-year average 11.5 1890 - 1899 1900 - 1909 1910 - 1919 1890 9.9 1900 13.2 1910 15.2 1891 7.4 1901 11.8 1911 11.2 1892 11.8 1902 11.6 1912 10.9 1893 16.5 1903 13.0 1913 13.2 1894 11.6 1904 10.2 1914 11.7 1895 10.8 1905 10.4 1915 9.6 1896 10.7 1906 13.4 1916 11.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 Five-year average 11.8 The Nebraska farmer can doubtless produce hogs at a prof - it when the Chicago ratio is a little narrower than 11.5 bushels of corn to 100 pounds of hog flesh. The reason is that the corn-hog ratio on a Nebraska farm is almost invari - ably wider than it is in Chicago. It costs less to market corn when concentrated into pork than when sold as corn. When from any cause, such as crop failure or demand for local feeding, the farm price of corn rises higher than the terminal market price, the ratio between the price of corn and the price of hogs narrows. It may become narrower than the Chicago ratio. Despite the rather wide variation in the ratio from year to year, the average ratio for 10-year periods is remarkably uniform. When the ratio for the corresponding months of the years are averaged over a long time, it is found that there is a relationship between the ratio and the season of the year. This variation is undoubtedly caused by a variation in cost of production dependent upon the time of the yea:* when the hogs are marketed. For the 10 year period 1907 - 1916, the average ratio by months was as follows: Table 2. — Corn-hog ratio by months, 1907-1916 &lt; Wallace. Agricultural Price., p. 32. O» ( ll.i .898 14.6 899 12.0 lyvi ±i.« 1908 8.4 1909 11.3 ilfl I 9. 1918 10.1 1919 11.: ["en-year average 11.9 Ten-year average 11.5 Ten-year average 11.! 1920 - 1924 1920 9.8 1921 16.0 1922..... 14.9 1923 10.3 1924 8.2 January 11.0 bushels February 11.6 bushels March 12.4 bushels April 12.7 bushels May 12.3 bushels June 12.1 bushels July 12.0 bushels August 11.8 bushels September 11.8 bushels October 11.3 bushels November 10.6 bushels December 10.4 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Hog Prices 15 Fig. 2. — The corn-hog ratio curve, 1910-1924. The curve shows the bushels of corn equal in value to 100 pounds of live hogs at average farm prices. The dotted line shows the average farm ratio for the period, 10.9 bushels of corn to 100 pounds of hogs (live weight) Fig. 2 shows the corn-hog ratio for the United States from 1910 to 1924. Every period when the ratio was narrow and hogs were produced at a loss has been followed by a period when the ratio was wide and hog producers have received adequate profits. MONTHLY VARIATION IN HOG RECEIPTS AND HOG PRICES In the United States more pigs are farrowed between March 15 and June 15 than in the other nine months of the year. Spring farrowed pigs fit well into the farm operations of the Corn Belt farmer. They are ready to be turned on alfalfa or clover pasture in May, and during the summer develop bone and muscle on forage supplemented by grain or by grain and tankage. Some early spring pigs are ready for market in September and October, but a much larger num - ber are fed out on new corn and marketed in later months. Most fall pigs are farrowed in September and are ready for market the following May or June. Fortunately for both the producer and the consumer, the receipts of hogs at terminal markets are much better dis - tributed thruout the year than the time of the farrowing of </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 the pigs would indicate. Among the factors which influence the age at which hogs are marketed the 3 following are most important : 1. Variation in feed 2. Variation in weight when marketed 3. Retention of gilts for breeding A very considerable part of the spring pig crop never reaches the terminal markets. Some are slaughtered by local butchers, and a much larger number are slaughtered by farm - ers. In December, farm slaughter is greater than all other types of slaughter combined. Table 3 gives the monthly rate of hog slaughter and sources of pork consumption during 1922. The first two columns are based on actual records. The second two columns are based on estimates made by the Department of Agricul- TABLE 3. — Monthly rates of hog slaughter and sources of pork consumption Other Uninspected Month " Big Five " inspected local Farm slaughter slaughter slaughter slaughter December 2,138,000 2,056,000 574,000 7,365,000 1 Armour's Livestock Bureau. Monthly Lrtter to Animal Hunliandmvn. February 1. r.t2S. Even with the factors already mentioned working toward equalization, more hogs are received at terminal markets from November 1 to March 31 inclusive than during the remaining seven months of the year. This irregularity in volume of receipts naturally has an effect upon prices. Table 4 shows the relationship between receipts and prices in two different ways. In the first column is given the anuary February ....| if arch ! day I une I uly I lugust I September .. )ctober November ....| 2,342,000 2,100,000 1,716,000 1,554,000 1,642,000 1,944,000 1,288,000 1,216,000 1,061,000 1,154,000 1,890,000 2,482,000 1,562,000 1,615,000 1,383,000 1,938,000 1,796,000 1,573,000 1,174,000 1,270,000 1,692,000 1,459,000 385,000 250,000 165,000 122,000 120,000 117,000 110,000 92,000 92,000 162,000 305,000 3,912,000 2,188,000 1,012,000 522,000 397,000 206,000 237,000 287,000 343,000 878,000 3,320,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Hog Prices 17 actual average receipts of hogs at all public stockyards for the 10-year period 1913-1924 inclusive. In the second column is given the average price of Hogs at Chicago for the same period. It is a little difficult for us to compare large numbers but it is easy to compare any number of two or three figures with 100. In column three the average number of hogs received each month of the 10-year period is represented by 100 per cent. In 9 months the receipts are much more than 100 per cent of the average and in other months much less. In the last column 100 per cent represents the average price for all months. Table 4. — Average hog receipts at all public stockyards and average hog prices at Chicago by months, 1915-1924 Per cent of Per cent Month Average Average I average of average receipts I Chicago price ] month receipts month prices Fig. 3 presents graphically the 10-year relationship between hog marketing and hog price. This exact relationship will probably not exist in any year, but the producer can depend upon this general trend under normal conditions. Hog prices on the average are the lowest during December and January, because more hogs are marketed during these months than during any other two months in the year; hog prices are the highest during July, August, and September, because fewer hogs are marketed during these months. The irregularity in marketing would certainly result in a much greater disparity in price, were it not for the large January February March April May June July August | September ....! October November .... December 5,045 4,138 3,862 3,365 3,666 3,500 3,031 2,617 2,567 3,378 4,318 4,996 i $10.61 11.07 11.83 11.97 11.94 11.70 12.07 12.21 12.34 11.49 10.83 10.51 137 112 104 91 99 94 82 71 69 91 116 135 92 96 102 104 103 101 105 106 107 100 94 91 Average.... 3,707 $11.55 100 I 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 AV.PI?ICE. PER CWT.-DOLLAI?S I?ECEIPT5-THOU5AND5 JAN. FEB. HM?. APP. HAY JUNt JULY AUG. 5WI OCT. NOW. DEC. Fig. 3. — Average receipts at public stock yards (65) and average hog prices at Chicago by months. 1915-1924. consumption of pork in winter, the heavy pork exports at that season, and the ease with which the surplus pork can be cured and carried over to the season of lighter marketings. Cold storage holdings of pork and lard ordinarily show an increase from January to July. They decrease from August MILLION POUNDS Fig. 4. — Quantities of pork and lard held in cold storage upon the first day of each month, January 1, 1920, to December 1, 1924, inclusive. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Hog Prices 19 to November. The amount in storage by months is shown in Fig. 4. The high prices of July and August do not necessarily indicate that more farmers should have hogs ready for market during those months. Hog producers have a greater interest in net profit than in the price received per pound. Their problem is, therefore, not merely a problem of selling at the high market of the year but of selling at the greatest margin of profit. It costs more to produce hogs for the August market than for the December market. Whether the price is sufficiently higher to pay the additional cost is a question that each producer must decide for himself. YEARLY VARIATION IN HOG RECEIPTS AND HOG PRICES The number of hogs produced in the United States in - creased rapidly during the period of agricultural expansion which followed the Civil War. This increase in hog pro - duction is indicated in Table 5, which gives the number of hogs on farms reported by the Census enumerators beginning with the Census of 1870. Table 5. — Number of hogs on farms according to Federal Census Altho the number of hogs reported in 1900 was larger than has been reported in either of the succeeding census years, there has been nevertheless a trend toward increased production during the last twenty-four years. The number of hogs reported in 1900 was apparently abnormally large, while the number reported in 1910 and 1920 was smaller than the number estimated by the Department of Agriculture for every intervening year. Fig. 5 shows the somewhat complex relationships that exist among (1) corn production and price, (2) hog market - ings and price, and (3) the price of corn and the price of hogs. The annual production of corn is the estimate of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. The price of corn is tha average monthly price of No. 3 Yellow corn at Chicago. The receipts of hogs are for the 6 principal hog markets — Chi- 870 June 1 25,135.000 880 June 1 47.682~.000 890 June 1 57,410,000 900 June 1 62,868,000 910 April 1 58,186,000 920 January 1 59,346,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">|J!_ |S On 8? a- I» On Oc- §' p- L . n L 1 rrs X a .i . 2 E 1= 4- t= —^^-^ ! . / / 1_JJV ■». I '•-■. M^+ i I i S r ,^ I 1 w p^- £J= ¥— -h ii _L --: r •--— x- I is £3 4- 4- -t 1 h le 4- - _' c- .Z 2 t I | 4-= ' N N 5L - ?r \- A. I ■ I E ■-... Ji : s i I _ IS i I ISr m^ -r 2 " a l \ "%^ B o a 2 sZ V oo '7\ , I £ r^j tic ■* -I -1 . CO 1 1 • ;r o h 1^ I °°\ ~ be M b 2 « 8 s| II 2° II I? §8 5° Ii P IT §3 I§ </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Hog Prices 21 cago, Kansas City, Omaha, St. Louis, Indianapolis, and St. Paul. The receipts at these markets are a fair indication of the marketing trend for the entire United States. Chicago hog prices are taken as a standard because of the size and central location of the market. The correlation between the detailed study of hog receipts and prices by months and the 10-year average shown in Fig. 5 is surprisingly close. In nearly every year studied, more hogs were marketed in January than in any other one month. Large numbers were also marketed in December and Febru - ary. In every year a second high point comes in May or June, when the bulk of the fall pig crop goes to market. In 1911 the marketings in May and June were heavier than in January. This was doubtless the result of the high price of hogs and the wide corn-hog ratio in the spring of 1910 which stimulated the breeding of sows for fall litters. In nearly every year for which statistics are available, the low hog price of the year coincides with the largest market - ing of hogs, and the high price coincides with the light marketing. An increase in the supply of any product, unless accompanied by a corresponding increase in the demand, almost invariably results in a fall in prices. The price of corn is usually low when the crop is large and high when the crop is small. A careful study of Fig. 5 shows some exceptions to the general rule. The crop of 1903 was smaller than the crop of 1902 but there was no increase in price. The fact is, that the short crop of 1901 helped the price of the 1902 crop because no surplus was carried over. The 1919 crop of corn was larger than the 1918 crop but sold at a slightly higher price. The higher price was due primarily to the post-war boom. The unusually high price of corn and hogs from 1917 to 1920 was caused in part by increased demand for which the war was responsible, but caused also in part by the large increase in our circulating media, and by the unprecedented extension of credit. Fig. 5 also shows an interesting correlation between corn prices and hog production. The country as a whole was prosperous during 1905, 1906, and the early months of 1907. This stimulated the consumption of pork, which naturally resulted in a higher price as hog production had not in - creased. The price of corn was relatively low during all of 1906 and the early months of 1907. Cheap feed and high - priced pork meant good profits for the hog producers, and naturally stimulated production. The 1907 spring pig crop was just ready to come to market at the time of the panic in </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 22 te autumn of 1907. This practically destroyed the market livestock and kept hogs from coming to market in Novem - ber. In January, 1908, more hogs were sold at the prin - cipal markets than in any one month up to that time, and the price dropped to the lowest point it had reached since LOW. The price of corn rose during 1908, due to the heavy temand caused by the large number of hogs produced. The 908 spring pig crop which came to market in large num - bers in November and December, 1908, and January, Febru - ary, and March, 1909, was large enough to keep the price of hogs low and of corn high. Because of the increase in hog production and resultant increase in the demand for corn, the feeding of corn to hogs was less profitable during the latter months of 1907 and all of 1908 than was the selling of corn on the market. As a result of the failure of hogs to return a profit during 1908, farmers curtailed production. Receipts at the principal markets were low during the later months of 1909, 1910, and early months of 1911. The average price of hogs at Chicago rose from $5.65 per hundredweight in December, 1908, to $10.55 per hundredweight in March, 1910. The price of corn at Chicago, influenced by the large yield of 1910, dropped from 80 cents in September, 1909, to 47 cents in January, 1911. The men who were fortunate enough to have hogs for sale in 1910 received an excellent profit. As has been already stated, the high price of hogs in the spring of 1910 stimulated breeding for fall litters with the result that a very large number of hogs came to market in May and June, 1911, at a greatly reduced price. Market - ings were also very large in the following November, Decem - ber, January, and February, due to the stimulus of the big profits of 1910. Hog prices were high again in 1913, low in 1915, and, under the spur of war demands, rose very high in 1917, 1918, and 1919. As indicated in Fig. 5, corn prices also rose very high, so that during the major part of the war period the man who sold his corn on the market received a greater net profit than the man who fed the corn to hogs. Losses were particularly heavy in 1920 and, as a result, hog production was somewhat reduced. Hog receipts at the terminal markets were lower during every month of 1921 than the average receipts for the same months of the three preceding years. In 9 months of the 12, receipts were lower than for the corresponding months of 1920. Decreased pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Hog Prices 23 duction and European demand for pork helped maintain a fair price for hogs in spite of the severe financial depression. The 1920 corn crop was the largest ever produced in the United States and the 1921 corn crop was nearly as large. The price of corn fell precipitately. In December, 1921, the prices offered by elevators in Nebraska were the lowest since February, 1900. The average December 1 farm price for the entire state was but 27 cents, according to the U. S. Department of Agriculture. The average price of No. 3 Yellow corn at Omaha for the entire month of December was 39 cents. While hogs were not high in comparison with the price of furniture, clothing, building materials, and other commodities purchased by farmers, they were high when compared with the price of corn. The bulk of sales at Omaha averaged $6.20 during December, 1921. One hundred pounds of pork was therefore worth nearly 17 bushels of corn. This ratio widened as the distance from terminal market increased, and narrowed as the distance from New York and other eastern markets decreased. The reason for the variation is discussed on page 10. The average for the entire country during 1921 was 14 to 1, the widest ratio for any year since 1910. It was even wider during the first six months of 1922. The ratio by months, 1920-1924, based on average farm prices of corn and hogs is given in Table 6. It is shown graphically in Fig. 2. Table 6. — Corn and hog ratios. United States, monthly. 1920-1924 1920 : 1921 ] 1922 S 1923 ! 1924 Month January February March ! April : May I June I July , August i September ' October November December i 9.3 9.2 8.9 8.4 7.6 7.1 7.8 8.5 10.1 13.0 15.0 13.2 1 13.5 13.5 14.3 13.0 12.5 11.0 13.1 14.8 14.0 15.9 16.0 15.2 15.4 16.5 15.8 15.7 15.0 14.7 14.7 13.7 13.4 13.4 12.8 11.7 11.1 10.9 10.2 9.8 8.8 7.9 7.5 7.7 8.5 8.8 8.2 9.0 I 9.0 8.5 8.6 8.6 8.5 8.1 6.7 8.0 7.7 8.7 8.7 7.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 The result of the profits made in feeding corn to hogs during 1921 and 1922 was a greatly increased hog production. Hog marketing in 1922 exceeded that in 1921 by nearly 3,000,000 head. Altho the corn-hog ratio decreased in the later months of 1922 it nevertheless remained wide enough that hog feeding continued profitable. The 1923 pig crop was far in excess of the preceding year. More hogs were received at public stockyards in 1923 than in any preceding year, the former high record of 1918 being exceeded by more than 10,000,000 head. The crest of the marketing movement did not come until January, 1924. Receipts of hogs at all public stockyards during each month from February, 1923, to Febru - ary, 1924, inclusive, broke all preceding records for the cor - responding months of other years. Because of the unpre - cedented hog marketings the price dropped until in June, 1923, it was at the lowest point in many years. It dropped to an even lower point in November and December, but the ratio was a little wider because of cheaper corn. The production of hogs in such unusual numbers solved the question of the corn surplus that was troubling farmers in 1921. By the latter part of 1923 the surplus had dis - appeared. The hogs had eaten it. Hog producers were again confronted with the problem of how to make a profit feed - ing high priced corn to cheap hogs. The average corn-hog ratio for 1923 was 9 to 1 ; in July it was only 7.5 to 1. Pro - ducers were as anxious to decrease production as they had been to increase it two years previously. During all of 1924 the market receipts contained an unusual number of hogs in poor condition for market. Half-grown pigs and brood sows in thin flesh were sold because producers believed that corn was worth more than the pork that the corn would produce. The number of hogs received at terminal markets in 1924 nearly equaled the record receipts of 1923. The situation was aggravated by the partial failure of the 1924 corn crop over a very considerable area of the Corn Belt. The shortness of the crop practically assured a high price. Feeding demands caused the price to rise until No. 3 yellow corn sold in Omaha during the month of December for an average price of $1.15 per bushel. In January it averaged $1.20 per bushel. The high price of corn acceler - ated the marketing of breeding stock. Producers seemed to have decided that hogs would continue to sell for less than the cost of production. The influence of supply upon price for the three years 1922-1924 is shown in detail in Fig. 6. As has already </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Hog Prices 25 been stated, receipts were below normal during the early part of the period and prices were relatively high. With the increase of receipts in 1923 and 1924 the price of hogs fell. In the meantime the cost of production increased be - cause of the increase in the price of corn. J 13 feO / i / Fig. 6. — Receipts at public stockyards and Chicago prices of hogs: 1922-1924 PORK EXPORTS The United States exports more pork than does any other one country. The explanation for this is found in the Corn Belt. A fertile soil, a favorable climate, and large scale production have enabled the Corn Belt farmer to produce grp.in at a lower cost per bushel than it is produced in any country of western Europe. The world does not demand all of the grain for human food, so a very large part of the corn, oats, and barley is fed to livestock. Denmark and European nations buy some grain from us for feed, but the American farmer has generally found it more profitable to feed the grain and sell hogs and other live - stock than to sell the grain. The cost of transporting pork and lard to Europe is much less than the cost of transport - ing the feed required to produce the pork. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">■a s ■ O C CM 10 o o V ; o o d «- * B - "Cl_ D I -4- c -- 5 a X ■ —| is CM P - — *"* V 2 t» o w S g-j 5 &gt;••§ - 2 IS «r |S — _1 ii I* 2 — c -&lt;-■ p* -c^- 11 h-v -+L =^ r &gt;- 4— t — t _ . lJ&gt;_ 5 3 ml I _ 0) 5 — "Ho, 0 c 2 *■ = — C 8-5 1 II I = : — . 4- --f r _4^ s &amp;b i 8 i I _ 2 as § s^ — - fg a *"! 9 . — — I— o /7 UJ a 4— — sf 2 fer 8 » 8 o CM s 3 N 8 8 s c-" s § in </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Hog Prices 27 PORK EXPORTS AND HOG PRICES Fig. 7 shows the relationship between hog prices and pork exports. Excepting the period of the World War, which rep - resented a very abnormal condition, the experts were low when prices were high and increased when prices dropped. The Europeans are evidently careful buyers who watch our market for bargains in pork and pork products. The fact is that millions of people in Europe are too poor to buy meat except when the price is low. They will doubtless continue to buy our pork when we have a large surplus but cannot be relied upon to furnish a steady market for a large volume at a high price. The European demand for pork certainly helps to maintain hog prices during periods of large marketings. The home demand could hardly have absorbed the enormous market - ings of 1923-1924. It is safe to predict that when prices rise exports will decrease. The American farmer certainly suffers because hog prices are not more stable, but he has reason to be thankful for the elastic European demand which prevents even wider price fluctuations. There is no certainty that Europe will continue to be as good a customer in the future as she has been in the years past. The poverty of the people, the allied debts, and the unfavorable trade balance against nearly every European nation are all factors which will tend to decrease future purchases of pork. Home grown vegetables and bread may of necessity be substituted in part at least for American pork. CYCLES OF HOG PRODUCTION An unusual number of spring pigs were farrowed in 1907, 1911, 1915, 1918, 1922, and 1923. In the months of Decem - ber, January, and February following each of the large pig crops, an unusual number of hogs were marketed and hog prices fell. The number of spring pigs farrowed in 1909, 1913, and 1920 was below normal. The number farrowed in 1917 was much larger than in 1909 or 1913 but was considerably less than the average of the war time period. Each of these small crops sold at a relatively high price per pound. Each period of good prices stimulated production. Increased market receipts were invariably accompanied by lower prices. We may say, therefore, that there is a very distinct cycle of hog production. When the supply of hogs at the terminal markets is small, the price is relatively high. This high </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 208 28 price gives to the farmer a good profit and stimulates pro - duction. Increased production results in lower hog prices. After selling one or two pig crops for less than cost of production, many farmers decrease very materially the num - ber of sows bred. When this decrease in breeding affects the number of hogs marketed, prices rise and the cycle is complete. THE OUTLOOK The United States Department of Agriculture reported that a pig survey made as of December 1, 1924, indicated a decrease of about 30 per cent in the number of sows far - rowing in the fall of 1924 in the Corn Belt states compared with the number that farrowed in 1923. Because of favor - able weather more pigs were saved per litter in 1924 than in 1923 so that the decrease in production was only about 24 per cent. The number of sows bred or to be bred for farrowing in the Corn Belt was reported at about 10 per cent less than the number that farrowed in the spring of 1924. There is, however, almost invariably a slump in the number that actually farrow from the number that are bred. If the shrinkage in 1925 is about what it has been in former years, the number of sows that actually farrow in the spring of 1925 will be between 15 and 25 per cent less than the num - ber that farrowed in 1924. The spring pig crop in 1924 was smaller than in 1923 by about 17 per cent. The total 1924 pig production in the Corn Belt was undoubtedly at least 19 per cent less than in 1923. This represents a reduction from 1923 of between 11,000,000 and 12,000,000 head in total hog production. There was a reduction in the southern states in 1924 and the prospects are for a further reduction in 1925. The indications are that hogs will be very high during the summer of 1925, and well above normal until the 1926 spring pig crop is ready for market in the autumn of that year. The heavy marketings of 1924 and the first two months of 1925 carried to market many sows and gilts that under ordi - nary conditions would have been saved for breeding. With a small pig crop in the autumn of 1924, and the prospects of another small crop in the spring of 1925, the number of hogs marketed between May 1, 1925, and May 1, 1926, will necessarily be smaller than for many years. If the 1925 corn crop is good, the price of corn will un - doubtedly be relatively low, because the demand for feeding </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Hog Prices 29 will be less than normal. Cheap corn and high-priced hogs are an ideal combination for the hog producer. If the history of hog production and hog prices continues to repeat itself, we may expect high hog prices in the autumn of 1925, which will stimulate production. A large crop of pigs in the spring of 1926 would naturally result in low prices in December, 1926, which would continue thru 1927. SAFE PLANNING It is impossible for anyone to predict either hog prices or profits of hog production with absolute accuracy. Too many factors enter into cost of production and price deter - mination. For example, a large corn crop in 1924 would have prevented the rushing of hogs to market in the winter of 1924-1925; a small corn crop in 1925 will decrease hog profits and delay the period of overproduction; a large corn crop accompanied by good business conditions will stimulate hog production. Every Corn Belt farmer can forcast the future hog pro - duction with reasonable accuracy and can plan his pig pro - duction in accordance with the probable outlook. Many farmers now increase the size of their herds when prices are high and decrease when prices are low. A far safer plan is to stay in the hog business all of the time, decreasing the number of sows bred when the outlook is for increased pro - duction, and increasing the number bred at such times as the winter of 1924-1925 when many men are quitting hog pro - duction. Absolute standardization of hog production is impossible under present conditions. It is possible, however, for a farmer to so regulate his own production that he receives the advantage of the recurring periods of high prices. As the number of farmers who study these price cycles increases we may expect market receipts of hogs and hog prices to fluctuate less widely. Wisely regulated production and thoughtful marketing will go far toward stabilizing hog prices. [5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>