<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Methods of Controlling Blister Canker</title>
               <date value="1917-12-15">1917-12-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 161 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA METHODS OF CONTROLLING BLISTER CANKER By J. Ralph Coopri Distributed December IS, 1917 TYPICAL BLISTER CANKERS LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. [ Popular Edition of Kewareh Bulletin No 12| Volume XXX, Article I </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE L'MIVnSITV) HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, President. Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORl). Vice President. Falls City. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN. Davey. HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL. Lincoln. HONORABLE HARRY D. LANDIS. Seward THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D.. LL. D., Chancellor, ex oftic;. E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc, Director. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc, Director of Extension Senice J. S. DALES. M. Ph., Financial Secretary. •FLOYD WAMBEAM, B. Sc, Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. W. W. Bubb, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy. H. J. Gkamlii'h, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. Swenk, A. M-. Entomology. H. C. Fhxey, A. M., Farm Management R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead Wilcox. Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Plata-. James Cowan,. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell tL. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist. North Platte. •J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. tG. K. K. Link, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology. J. Ralph Cooper, M. S., Associate in Horticulture. Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy. H. G. Gould, Assistant in Agronomy. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management. Granted leave of absence for military service. fDetailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart ment of Agriculture, Washington, I). C. leave of absence. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">METHODS OF CONTROLLING BLISTER CANKER Bv I. Ralph Cooper Blister canker, often called Illinois canker, has within the last few years become the most destructive disease known in Nebraska apple orchards. Practically every orchard in the State has more or less infection. It is impossible to estimate accurately the full amount of damage done. Often whole orchards with the exception of a few trees of especially resist - ant varieties are completely destroyed. Orchards which five years ago bore excellent crops have been completely ruined by this disease. A large percentage of this loss, however, can be avoided. Only a few varieties such as Ben Davis and Gano are decidedly susceptible. Even a casual survey of the situa - tion will be sufficient to show that it is the trees of these varie - ties that are being killed in greatest numbers. Orchards on land which has a heavy compact subsoil have suffered a much greater loss than those on deep loose soil. Lack of cultivation and general care is another important factor which encour - ages the advance of the disease. Injudicious pruning — prun - ing too severely and at the wrong season of the year, making large wounds, and leaving wounds uncovered — has a decided influence in spreading the disease. (JKNKKAl. AI'I'KAKAXCK OK THK DISKASK It is not always possible to recognize the disease altho the symptoms are usually very marked and characteristic. In the earliest visible stage the bark takes on a dark brown color and soon becomes shrunken and depressed below the adjoining healthy bark. The cankers are usually several inches in length when they first appear, owing to the peculiar way in which they are formed. Where the surface bark is cut away in these cankered spots or at the edges of old cankers it has a mottled appearance. After midsummer, small, round, blis - ter-like protuberances appear scattered over the surface of the canker, or in the case of large spots, where the center has become hard and dry, only along the margins. Spores form under these blisters. Later the blisters break open and the bark curls back, liberating the spores. This is a brief review of Research Bulletin No. 12. "Studies of the Etiology and Control of Blister Canker on Apple Trees" issued by this Sta - tion. Any one interested in the details of the investigation will be fur - nished, on application, a copy of the complete bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 161 Plate I — Ben Davis tree showing typical cankers at 1. Such a tree will produce little fruit and is a menace to the whole orchard </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Methods of Controlling Blister Canker 5 The cankers increase rapidly in size. Small flat or con - cave spots, sometimes round and sometimes irregular in shape, surrounded by a well-defined dark brown or black ring, mark the points where the blisters were formed. Early in the spring these spots often appear grayish-white but later in the season become coal black. This difference in color is caused by the presence of two kinds of spores which cover the spots at different times. Summer spores (conidia), similar to those found under the blisters, are formed on the surface early in the spring. Later others (ascospores) coal black in color are formed in the interior and forced out upon the surface. Often, especially later in the summer, both kinds may appear at the same time. With age the cankered bark cracks and falls off in irreg - ular patches but the spore-bearing areas (stromata) remain attached to the wood for a long time. When these stromata finally fall off, irregular, dark brown to black rings in the wood show where they had been attached. Often whole limbs and even whole trees are killed in a single season. In the former case the characteristic blisters and stromata are not formed except at the base of the af - fected limbs, and when a tree is killed outright they may not be formed at all. In either case the leaves come out as usual in the spring and fruit may set abundantly. Later in the summer the leaves suddenly begin to wilt and die. The apples shrivel up, or at least cease to grow, and both fruit and leaves remain hanging to the dead branches for considerable time. Injury from blister canker often resembles winter injury and sun scald so closely that it may easily be mistaken for them. HOW THE DISEASE IS SPREAD The disease is disseminated principally by means of the spores already mentioned, which are carried from cankered trees to healthy ones close by. However, it may also be spread by sawdust and particles of wood which are carried from diseased to healthy trees by pruning tools. In culti - vating, pieces of diseased wood or bark containing spores may be carried to other parts of the orchard and infect other trees thru wounds in the surface roots or the crown. Experiments at this Station have proved that infection can take place only thru wounds of some sort. Large wounds are much more liable to infection than smaller ones. Pruning </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 1 61 Plate II — A, canker as it flrat appears. B. canker one year old. C, four - year-old canker producing ascoHpores. D, same as C, but producing summer spores or conidia. E, cankered limb with bark removed show ing attachment of spore-bearingr masses of mycelium (stromata) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Methods of Controlling Blister Canker 7 wounds or wounds of any kind which expose wood which is three or more years old permit infection much more readily than wounds which expose only recently formed wood. In - fection does not take place readily in wounds which extend only thru the bark unless these wounds cover enough area so that the wood dries out and cracks. Wounds made by re - moving one and two-year-old branches are not easily infected. Trees often become infected thru frost cracks which extend deep into the wood in the trunk or large limbs. Mice and other rodents gnaw about the roots and crown of the trees and expose large areas of wood. This wood dries out and cracks, and offers a ready means of infection. After a tree becomes infected the disease may grow for a long time in the heartwood before any cankers are formed on the outside. Owing to this fact the distribution of cankered trees appears very irregular and scattered in an orchard. Even when the trees become infected at the same time, the dis - ease shows externally on some long before it can be detected on others. After a time the disease becomes noticeable on all the infected trees. Cankers appear in various parts of many trees. Trees die here and there thruout the orchard and finally whole blocks of the most susceptible varieties are de - stroyed. TI.MK OF INFECTION Infection occurs most readily in warm, moist weather. There are two reasons for this. Spores are produced abun - dantly at such times, and when a spore lodges on a wound, it germinates much more readily under such conditions. These conditions prevail in Nebraska early in the season (May 1 to June 15), and again often in the fall during the month of September. Experiments at the Station have shown that trees are more easily infected at the time when they are making the least growth. Very little growth is being made during the first part of May and growth has practically ceased by September 1. The disease, after infection has taken place, also advances more rapidly during warm periods when the tree is not grow - ing rapidly. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 161 8 ■a n Plate III — Ben Davis tree sectioned at intervals of about 16* to show ar invaded by canker fungus. A, crown. B, trunk. C, D, and E, ma limbs ##;*«»-• % «6d #€^^ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Methods of Controlling Blister Canker 9 RELATION OF SOIL FERTILITY TO SUSCEPTIBILITY To a casual observer it may seem on first thought that the fertility of the soil bears no relation to the amount of damage done by blister canker. No orchards in the State are free from canker even where the best of care is given. In some cases more cankered trees are found in well-cultivated or - chards where the soil is deep and fertile than in orchards that have been neglected or are on poor soil. When the age and variety of the trees are considered, however, this is usually accounted for. Ben Davis or Gano trees even when growing on rich soil will be found more susceptible to canker than varieties such as Jonathan and Winesap growing on much poorer soil. When the same variety is considered in each case, the trees on rich deep soil suffer less damage than those less favorably located. Experiments at the Station substantiate this statement. A large number of young trees were grown in large jars and half barrels and different amounts of fertilizers were supplied to different groups. A part of the trees in each group were inoculated with the fungus which causes blister canker. The results show that the trees which were properly nourished made a much better growth and were much more resistant to blister canker than those which were undernourished. A trench was dug around two Ben Davis and two Jona - than trees in the orchard, close enough to remove approxi - mately one-third of the feeding roots. All the trees were in - oculated. Several trees of each variety that had not been starved by cutting away their roots were also inoculated. As a result of this ditching and consequent starving, the trees made very little growth and the apples remained small and both leaves and fruit dropped from the trees. The canker was found to have advanced much more rapidly in these trees than in those which had not been molested except to be inoculated. EFFECT OF SOIL MOISTIRE OX SISCEIT1IHL1TY Blister canker apparently spread faster during the sum - mers of 1913 and 1914 than it had ever done before. The ma - jority of the trees which died, however, had been infected for a number of seasons and the drouth encouraged the rapid growth of the disease. Orchards located on shallow soil, or where the soil was underlaid by hard pan or heavy clay, suf - fered the worst. The feeding roots being near the surface of the ground did not receive sufficient moisture to allow the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 161 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Methods of Controlling Blister Canker 11 trees to grow normally, while the growth of the canker was unchecked. In experiments at the Station where young trees were used it was found that canker advanced more rapidly in trees given too little water than in those which received all that they needed for normal growth. VAIUKTAI, SLSCKITIIHMTY Blister canker does not affect all trees alike. In some va - rieties such as Ben Davis and Gano it advances very rapidly, while in varieties such as Oldenburg and Wealthy it makes little headway as long as the trees are growing normally. After carefully observing inoculated trees of different va - rieties in the Station orchard and diseased trees in various orchards over the State the varieties were tentatively grouped as below. The list is necessarily short owing to the limited number of varieties under observation. It is easy to understand why blister canker has done so much damage to orchards in the Middle West. Practically every orchard contains Ben Davis or Gano trees. Often the majority of the trees are of these varieties. These varieties not only die from attacks of the disease but afford such abun - dant opportunities that other more resistant varieties also be - come infected. In the most susceptible varieties of trees under normal conditions the fungus grows very rapidly in the heartwood. When active tissues are encountered the growth of the fungus Very !:■ .-iM.,111 Moderately Moderately Ui'Mixtant Susceptible Very Susceptible ")ldenburg Wealthy Jonathan York Winesap Willow Twig Arkansas Rome Beauty Arkansas Black Maiden Blush Janet Champion Minkler Grimes Fameuse (Snow) Missouri Stayinan Northern Spy Winesap Chicago Virginia Beauty Yates Wolf River King David Northwest Walbridge Greening Malinda Delicious Ben Davis Gano Yellow Transparent </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Ayrirultural Etp. Station, Bulletin 161 12 &gt;■ j-lnu V -tnJiiri«-N which permit i • n&lt;i» InfMtlM, A, i&gt;" xpin •" ff« M, M ■&gt;•■•• t jnii »f tuiiiiiiiu •', •'■•iiittiiin) lull "f min «•■■&gt;• i«i «nd hof»r inju D, li"i»» inJut'Ktl ni th» h«w lir niii'&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Method* of Controllinu Hlitter Canker 13 in chocked but it still advanced slightly fHnti-r th«n n«w wood can be added on the outside. Whan the growth of the trees In milt fi-ifilly i lifiki-d tha fungus jmln* very rapidly, ntitm kill - ing the tr«u«, ThU cxplulnH why mi many lion I)avls tr«t«s died (luring tind «&gt;on »tfter tho severe drouth of 1918. The trees were already infected and were checked by the drouth to such an extent that the fungus was able to Invade the wood more rapidly than new wood could bu formed, Jonathan, Wlnasap, iiini many othttr varieties aliio suffered but to a much less uxtunt. In these varieties the fungus wan found to progress little if any faster than nuw wood wait added when the tree* were in a normal condition. H«nc« even when checked by tht» drouth thawi varieties Htill offered a groat deal of reHiHtancw to iU advance, Ml lllltl.H Ol HIM IIM, III IhI I II . VNKI II KxpurimunU were begun at the Station in 1912 to din - cover Home iiii-iiiih of controlling blUter canker. Two general muthodii weru employed. The nrnt waa to chiael or cut out the canker itself and a* much of the dineaaed wood as poimfblu. The wound was then disinfected and covered. The other method was to remove the limb which was cankered. Those wounds were also disinfected and covered. A number of dif - ferent disinfectants and covers were used for comparison. At the end of the first season it teemed that a high per - ccntuge of the treatments would prove effective since the wounds were healing nicely in tho majority of cases and both trees and foliage appeared healthy. At the end of the second season, however, it was apparent that treating cankers ac - cording to either of the methods used would not prove satis - factory. In many instances the disease soon became visible In the bark at one or more points at tho margin of the old treat - ments. On examining these treatments It was found that the diHOHiw appeared in the bark at points in tho margin where the discolored wood was nearest the surface at the time the treatment was given, or whore for some, reason the tissues had not been sufficiently nourished, as, for Instance, whero the cut was made straight across the top or tho bottom of the wound Instead of being made pointed. All of these places were carefully re-treated but without success in most cases. In all lift trees were treated. The number of original treatments was 341, Of these, 22 were ra-treated three times, 10ft were re-treated twice, and 214 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nrlmmku Aurlrultuml i: , ,,, Station, llulhhn Kit I'lui" VI — I nf noted Bun Ravin tr««. All th« hxttrtwuud and muat of the »p - wimd dlMf»»&gt;-d ThU *h»w( ( h&lt;- futilliy n( irymv to cut nut th* cankir </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Mi Ihmln iif Contmlllnu Illluhr ('unkri 15 wttre r«-tr«»al«d imctt, A notation wm* mad* of twh trwatniunt where lIlM'oloi'fll WOOd WM* U'fl. It WM* found DlWl in i-vi'H ca*« whfi'u th« dl*«w*««l wood wuh not mII ruinovwl, the ranker would contlnuti to grow, Hlnca It I* practically impo**iMti Ui I'umoVM nil iiili'di'd wood, MXcwpt whcti' Km- iiift&lt;clion occur* In ft limb mid Iimh not yul iwhml the trunk, liltl« l»«tu«ftt will (in dt&lt;i'ivt&lt;d from Much tn«HtmtmU, HuMvy pruning ww found to bi InJuriouH i-uIIum Hihh Im&lt;m&lt;- Di ml wlu«rt&lt; tht« trtwH woru htwvily UuwUh\, It Induced m titfor - oum yrowih of wmUt HprouU In th»&lt; tr««H, Htid hImi v%\nmu\ thti furttfUH to thtt Mir wh««r»«v»»r Iwck* 1 woundM w«r« riiHdt-. ('iinki'i'i* iilmoHt lnv»tii»l&gt;ly Mp|u&lt;Mi'nd «t th»«w» prunlnv woihuIh within otic or two mi-ummim. All dnlM hiii! iilmcrvnt loim iihIh -jiIi- thwt mt'thmU of control tor Muti-r cAttlutr muitt bt&lt; pruvcntivti ritthor ihitri curMtlvf, MOW IftfWMOM M4V IIK I'llKI KVH M I'l.AXT IIKMINTANT VAIIIKTI» Oiii- of tin- tfrt'MU'Nt fMctorw in controlling IiIiMit cunki-r Im tli«&lt; tiliinlinv mirmm which tiff known to In- rcKiMUml. Tw» of th« IU«n I)hvIh type should not Ih&lt; plMiiU&gt;d. Th*r« »rw ft&gt;w vnritttimt of npplt«H which nrv not hI Umut mm good, And Km - grout mnjority uro l«ttU&lt;r, It iwitr* h«*vlly butthut »lonn U ■ot dUllU'lttnt nmmm for pluntlng it. Willli Will M Th« importancfl of nvoldlng lurgu wound* of mII kind* Han ulrnjuly lw«'fi «mph»i»l»»d. Thin may iw nccompliithod to «om« d«gr«e by training th« tram whilu young. Km*ll wound* in young true* are not nuitrly m&gt; »«»t*ily infwUid h* wound* in old tree* which expoius wood *everal y««rH old. If a trM i» |iroi&gt; - erly pruned and trained while young, little pruning will w n«ce*»ttry after the trw mnehtm beurfng age. WIII'IN TO I'lll 'NI-; A little pruning will alway* be nec«*»ary even in well trained orchard* but by doing thi* work at a time when it is too cold for infection to take place a great deal of the trouble may be avoided. It certainly in not advUable to prune dur - ing warm, wet weather. Summer pruning in any kind of a season is questionable where wood more than one year old is removed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Kxp. WaHon, Ihdlctin 161 Plate VII — Method* of treating canker. A. limbs removed; wounds at 1 and 2 show that nearly all the wood was diseased. B, canker resulting from removal of cankered limb. C. such a treatment is enough in itself to kill a tree. D, a good Job but canker is "creeping" out at 1 and 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Methods of Controlling Blister Canker 17 TREATMENT OK WOUNDS Pruning wounds, even if made during the winter, may become infected unless protected by covers. AH wounds which expose wood more than one year old should be covered. A number of pruning wounds were made in the Station orchard and disinfected with various substances. Three weeks later spores were spread over them. Similar wounds were made, different covers applied, and spores spread over them six months later. The accompanying table shows the effectiveness of the different covers and disinfectants. The evidence indicates that suitable dressings and disinfect - ants aid very materially in preventing infection. Liquid as - phaltum and white lead and oil appear to be of about equal value. Where either was used there was very little cambium injury and no checking of the wood beneath. In a few cases the covering was raised in blisters which later broke and per - mitted infection. This difficulty can be overcome by making a thin application and later putting on a heavier coat. Both pine tar and coal tar were readily absorbed and much check - ing of the wood occurred. There was also considerable cam - bium injury. Efficiency of various coverings and disinfectants in preventing infection TREATMENT OF WOUNDS COVERINGS Asphalt inn I in gasoline) White lead _ Venetian red Pine tar Coal tar White lead and copper sulphate No cover _ _ DISINFECTANTS Phenol Mercuric chloride 1-500 Copper sulphate saturated so- lution Formalin 20&lt;7r Lime sulphur 32° Baume . Iron sulphate saturated solution Total Num- ber of In- oculations f No. Places Where Infection Occurred I f IVr cent f infected Woundi 39 35 31 16 11 35 51 5 13 5 4 4 49 17.94 14.28 41.93 31.25 36.36 11.42 96.07 15 16 11 4 66.66 25.00 15 12 14 1 1 3 g 6 20.00 66.66 42.85 1£ IK </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 161 Of the disinfectants used copper sulphate proved the most satisfactory. The efficiency of copper sulphate is no doubt due to the fact that the tissues for a short distance beneath the surface of the wound retain the copper for a long time. Tests made over a year after application of copper sulphate to the surface of pruning wounds showed the presence of cop - per in considerable quantities. Practically no injury resulted from the use of copper in this way. PREVKXT DISSEMINATION OF SPORKS By scraping away and burning all cankered bark from in - fected trees or by covering all cankered surfaces with a coat - ing of heavy paint or liquid asphaltum a great deal of infection may be avoided. In the first case the spores are destroyed and in the second they are prevented to some extent from escaping. The masses of stromata which produce the spores absorb liquids very readily. In an experiment at the Station a strong solution of copper sulphate was applied to cankered surfaces and the spores tested afterward. It was found that only 1 to 3 per cent of the spores germinated after such treatment. This would suggest that cankers be thoroly painted or sprayed with copper sulphate at the rate of one pound to two gallons of water, early in the spring before the dissemination of the spores begins. This should also prevent to some extent the formation of new spores. Lime sulphur was also used but with less success. When applying the regular orchard sprays it would be well to thoroly cover all parts of the tree. This would offer some protection from canker infection. Whenever a cankered limb ceases to bear profitably it should be cut off and burned. As soon as a tree becomes so badly diseased that it is no longer profitable, it should be re - moved from the orchard and burned. New trees may be planted to fill vacancies. There is little danger of their becoming infected thru the roots if one or two - year-old trees are used and the roots are not cut back severely. Large quantities of diseased wood were placed about the roots of young trees in the Station orchard but no infection occurred except where the crown or main root was wounded so as to expose old wood. [ll-23-'17— 12M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>