<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00001.00002">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00001.00002</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>JAMES W. DAWES, GOVERNOR, TO THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA. EIGHTEENTH SESION. JANUARY A.D. 1883.</title>
               <date value="1883">1883</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-17</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>

			      <change>
				        <date>2007-02-08</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
      <body>
         <p>

            <seg id="p001">
i v /A I I i I |\ ¦ \ I \ I I I 1 1 \ ri 

or 

JAMES W. DA WES, 

GOVERNOR, 

TIIK 

Legislature of Nebraska. 

EIGJITKKNTIl SESSION. 

LINCOLN, NKli. 

JOUK5AL COMPANY, STATK TRINTERS 


JANUART. A. /&gt;. US </seg>

            <seg id="p002"/>

            <seg id="p003">
INAUGURAL ADDRESS. 

Gentlemen of the Senate and House of Representatives: 

Eaving been called by the people of Nebraska to serve them in 
capacity of their chief executive, it is in obedience to time 
&gt;red custom that I appear before you to-day. 

El entering upon the discharge of the duties pertaining to the 
tion, I am deeply impressed 1 with its responsibilities, and the 
;nitude of the trust placed in my keeping. 

Eis my determination to devote my best efforts to the service 
e people, ami I shall serve therewith all honesty of purpose 
earnest endeavor. 

In obedience to the requirements of the constitution the officers 

I the executive department and of all the public institutions of 
state have severally reported to the Governor. 

En examination of the various reports will satisfy the most 
cal that the affairs of the State are in a satisfactory condition ; 

fthey furnish ample evidence of the fact that the interests of 
state have been in able and trustworthy bands. For a detailed 

tatement of the condition of affairs you are referred to the 

of my predecessor that has just been read to you, and 
to the reports above mentioned, which are full of valuable infor- 
mation concerning public affairs. I would ask for them all a 
careful and painstaking examination at your hands, ami that the 
various suggestions and recommendations therein contained may 

receive the consideration to which their merit entitles them. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
1 


This examination should be early and careful and you will find 
that economy has characterized public expenditures, and efficiency 
and faithfulness been manifest in all the State departments 
and institutions. 

I submit the following suggestions and recommendations: 

IMMIGRATION 

The superior advantages and attractions of soil and climate 
ssed in so high a degree by Nebraska, have been and will 

continue to be the leading influences operating to promote the 

steady growth and development of our Sta 

"&lt; 

It should be our policy to supplement these natural advantages 
in every possible way by wise and liberal legislation, to the end 

that immigrant from other lands, and all who may be looking 
tor homes in the west, may be attracted towards and influenced 
to find homes within our limits. The question of such legislation 
as may be advisable or necessary to enable us to realize this 

policy and reap its certain benefits is referred to you for solution. 

AGRICULTURE. 

The agricultural interests of Nebraska were never more prosu8 
than at the present time. Among the most serviceable 

agi ota in the advertisement of our State have been our agricultural 
and horticultural societies. All reasonable aid that you 
may pee tit to extend them will bring a certain and satisfactory 

return. 

Reports from the various county and State associations 
through out the country afford evidence of progress and growth 
in agriculture that is indeed most gratifying. The exhibitions 
at our own State and county fairs during the past year were the </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
•» 

best ever had in the State. A steady adherence to grain raising 

alone tends to impoverish the soil. That the farmers of our 

State will find it to their advantage to diversify their industries 

there cau be but little if any doubt, and we have reason for con- 

gratulation in the fact that our farmers are devoting more and 

1 breeding of stock, and less to 

more at 

1 an 

:i 

the prow 

ich great expense bo tr 

m 

ported to a distant market. Agriculture is at the present I 

A 

and will.be for years to come, if not always, the leading interest 

of our State, and as such it will no doubt receive at vour h 

i 

m and care as t;. a il importance ot the sub- 

ject de 

SURVEY 

Ti 

he subject of a thorough geological survey of the State is 

leration. It is beli&gt; 


within our borders coal in 


abundance ; and the importance of the fuel question alone would 

i 

are looking to the devel- 


x 

Suchsur. o-n an inter- 


ld examine for themselves, and 

have added largely to their re- 

by 

s 

i 

i 

source 

Und 

ificand thoroughly practical 

B 

ri it would, I 
cause of sci&lt; 

)roductive of great good both to 

1, b 

rial progress of the State. 

1 the r 

If the work should be entered 

upon it i3 highly important that 

it be prosecuted with the greatest economy possible consistent 

with the result desired. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
B 


EDUCATION. 

Our educational institutions, public and private, are making 
commendable progress. It is entirely unnecessary for me to urge 
upon you considerations in support of the proposition that our 
common school system should be carefully and steadily developed, 
to the end that it shall most fully meet the high purpose for 
which it was established; and we can devote our time, or our 
Ingth to no higher purpose than that of devising measures 
ulated to strengthen and improve this sacred interest. We 
agree that upon the wide-spread and thorough diffusion of 
iwledge depends in great measure the happiness of our people, 
the safety of our system of government. Recognizing this 
the nation has made provision for the most generous aid 
q the public property, and this trust will receive conscientious 
rdianship at your hands, that in the end the results righty 
to be expected from a proper use of our educational reources 
may be fully attained. For no other purpose will the 
E'e more willingly and cheerfully give than in support of the 
of education, if they can but have reasonable assurance that 
means so contributed will be economically and wisely used. 

Your special attention is called to the question of text-books 
common schools. The frequent change of books is 
ided with an expense to parents that in many cases is burdensome 
in the extreme, and it is hoped that you may devise some 
plan looking to a reduction of the expense to which parents are 
subjected on this account. 

MILITIA. 

Eit is the policy of the State to maintain its military force, 
e should be ample appropriation made for equipping it in a 
ough and efficient manner. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
While it 13 to be sincerely hoped that the day may never again 
come when the civil authorities of Nebraska will be under the 
extreme necessity of calling for military assistance, yet should 
that time come the most serious consequences might result if 

there were not a well disciplined and properly armed militia to 

answer such demand. 

We can scarcely hope to always escape tumults and disorders 
such as have arisen in other states, tumults or outbreaks that are 

as a rule, or at least in a majority of cases, incited, encouraged 
and led by a lawless and disreputable class of persons, those who, 
lacking habits of thrift and industry themselves, seek, by fomenting 
public disorder and a spirit of discontent among those of 

teadv habits, to reap the benefits that under such circumstances 

inure to them alone, for in the end almost invariably honest labor 
noeeta the expense and is the loser. Our militia is for the protection 
of honest industry and honest labor, whether of high orlow de_ti¦&gt;•. 
It is, therefore, of interest to all, as well as the part of prudence 
and economy, to make such preparation as experience has 
shown to be needed for the suppression of such outbreaks as may 
be too formidable to be controlled by the civil authorities, and liable 
to arise at anv time. You will no doubt take such action in the 

premises as in your judgment is deemed best, tor the interests 

and welfare of the Statt 

PROTECTIVK LB8I8LATI0N. 

There is an evil of considerable magnitude which of late years 

has prevailed in many localities of our State, to the great injury 
of large numbers of our people. I refer particularly to the sale 
of bogus or fraudulent patent rights, and of stock in fictitious 
or pretended corporations, by which unsu&gt;p.Ttiiig persona, </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
7 


* 


through various devices, have been induced to make worthless 
purchases, and give in payment their negotiable promissory 
notes, which by a transfer to iuKWWlt holders they were finally 

compelled to pay 

There seems .to be a well founded doubt in the minds of many 

whether, in the present condition 
ulent practices can be reached 

accounts for the tact that su 

with seerninir immunity from punishment 

Di 

hv ftmeadmi nt or otherwi 

defect. 

RAILBI 

\\&gt; 

1' 

attom on the parr of 

n 

passes to state officials and me 

hi 

standing, Hid I might s; 
While I do not believe that pa 

av 

i\ 

in the nature of a bribe, or for the n 

tion ot improperly influencing 
they have been considered by 

1 

iction ot 

jse wli 

used them a- placing them under any obliga 

rect, the tact vet remains that 

that rapresentatin - of the people may be ei 
the ban nupicion of having been improper!, 

action or in the faithful discharge of their pu 

of our trim 

so frequently 
[ would, there 

r •!!!' 

&gt; 

•t 

i: 

! 

r 

wit 

exi 

ndivii 

i 



IV 

n, direct or 

i 

value and 

r 0 

end 


in tin 

in t 

leir 

)lic duties, it is re( 

of 

i bribe, or tor 

passes to officers of the executive department 

of the state, mem- 

bers of the Legislature, and to any of the class of officials who, 

by reason of their public position, may have it within their power </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
8 


*, 

ectfully suggest the propt 

repr 

oeptance is tor that reason of doubtful propi 

ial law, such t 

and punished, which probably 
les are made so frequent! \ 

ed to avoid 

ommended that a law be enacted prohibiting the grantin 


9 

INAUGURAL ADDRESS. 

either to confer or withhold favors or benefits to railroad corporations. 


RAILROAD CORPORATIONS. 

In this connection I will quote from Article eleven (XI), entitled 

In this c 

from Article eleven (XI), entitled 

Corporations, of the Constitution of the State of Nebraska. 

Corporations, of the Constitution of the State of Nebraska. 

tMMM numbered four (4) and seven (7): 
"Section 4. Railways heretofore constructed or that i 
after be constructed in this state, are hereby declared public 
vays, and shall be free to all persons for tlie transportation 

i : 

instructed or that niav 

" Section 4. Railways heretofore constructed o 


hereby declared public 

r 

highways, and shall be free to all persons for the transportation 

. 3 lor 

of their persons and property thereon, under such regulatioi 

ueh regulations as 

u 

inav be prescribed by law. And the Legislature may from time 

I 


\ 

may from time 

to time pass laws establishing reasonable maximum rates of 

to tim 

charges for the transportation of passengers and freights on the 

i and freights on the 

different railroads in this State. The liability of raiiroad corpora- 


T 

ions as common carriers shall never be limited. 

tions as common carriers shall never be limited. 
"Sec. 7. Tin- Legislature shall pass lawa to correct ai 

ti 

. 7. The Legislature shall pass laws to correct abuses 

nd extortion in all charges of 

and prevent unjust discrimination and extortion in all charges of 
Bxpretm, telegraph and railroad companies in this State, and 

and prevent umust discrimination 

express, telegraph and railroad companies in this State, and 

i 

I 1 

enforce such laws by Adequate penalties to the extent, if neees- 

enforce ,such laws by Adequate penalties to the extent, if neeesibr 
that purpose, of forfeiture of their property and fna 

for that purpose, of forfeiture of their property and fna 

These citations are made for the reason ' ring 

The 

ition 

&gt;r 

eason 

ring 

before your minds directly, and in the most forcible manner. 

before your minds directly, ar 

y, and in the most forcible manner. 

the fact that by virtue of these provisions in our fundamental 

the fact that by virtue of these provisions in our fundamental 

law the people have reserved to themselves absolute power in all 

law th 

i reserved to themselves absolute power in all 
to the correction of abuses, extortions or un- 

matters pertaining to the correction of abuses, extortions or un- 

upon the part of railroads or other corpora- 

just discrimination upon the part of railroads or other corporations. </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
10 

INAUGURAL ADDRESS. 

Railroads may be justly regarded as among the most importt 
factors in the rapid development of our State, and it is of 
ii importance to all interests that they be sustained and encouraged, 
for it must be remembered that such corporations are 
indispensable to the material prosperity of the State. They have 
in the past been dealt with generously by both the Nation and 
the State; and there is to-day no sentiment among our people 
such as demands that the railroads should be either destroyed, or 

crippled to the extent of impairing their usefulness, or so restricted 
as to deprive them of a legitimate return upon capital 
I rested. If the railroads have been unjust, the people will not 
turn be unjust. The people cannot afford to be unjust to any 
erest : but will be careful that the rights of the public as 
against corporations are protected by efficient laws. It is only 
asked that such control and regulation be had as will be just and 
fair considering the respective rights of both the people and the 
corporations. This is no unreasonable demand. It is such a 
demand as keeps steadily in view the important fact that with 
our resources us yet all but undeveloped we must not repel 
Ipital by legislation such as would hazard our best interests. 
legislating it should be kept constantly in mind that corporans 
should have the same protection from the laws that any 
citizen has, and that capital invested in railroads must be protected 
equally with capital invested in any other branch of industry. 
To just that protection it is entitled, and to no more. 

If the railroads have been oppressive it is for the Legislature 

to apply the needed correction 

Whether the railroads are at the present time Managed in a 
fair and just manner is a question for you to decide, and it is 

to be hoped that you may be so guided in your deliberation* that </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
you may be enabled to find the golden mean in legislation, and 
enact such a law as will be not only just to capital, but at the 
same time fully protect the rights of the people. As a guide in 
considering a question of such grave importance, so difficult and 
perplexing, it would seem the part of wisdom to avail ourselves 
of the experience of other states. 

You will find me at all times ready to co-operate with you in 
such action as may be necessary for the protection of the public 
interests. 

UASTY LEGISLATION. 

By the terms of our Constitution it is provided that members 
of the Legislature shall not receive pay for more than forty days 

at anv one session 

The compensation is small at best, and but few can afford to 
remain at their own expense. It is therefore important that 
your work be done within the constitutional limit, as to time 
for which you will receive pay, and for the further reason that 
an undue prolonging of the session is adding unnecessarily to 
the expenses incident thereto, and placing additional burdens 
upon the treasury. 

The interest and excitement attending the election of a United 
States Senator has resulted in times past in the neglect of other 
important business, and to undue haste in the dispatch of business 
in the closing days of the session. 

To remedy this evil of hasty and poorly considered legislation, 
you should, it seem9 to me, apply yourself promptly and vigorously 
to the work before you, and in this way mature and perfect 
the more important subjects of legislation at the earliest practicable 
day. You will by so doing make it possible for all whose 
duty it is to do so, to examine and understand measures thev are </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
11 

called upon to support before acting upon them, and you will 
thus be enabled to best meet the wishes of those you represent. 
To you, coming directly from the people, their immediate representatives, 
this is a consideration of grave mcment. 

Under the guidance of the source of all wisdom, may wo, 

into whose hands the honor of our State has been committed, so 

acquit ourselves of the trust, so perform the work assigned us 

i 

the State, you will have my earnest co-operation, and that in entering 
upon the discharge of the duties of the Executive department, 
it is in the firm belief that you will extend to me your 
generous aid and counsel. 

JAMES W. DAWES. 

Lincoln, January 4, 1883. 

PROGRESS. 

'.u 

In the progress we have thus far made as a State and in the 

at gratifying condition of affairs, as well as in the promising 

DUtlook for the future, we as a people have abundant cause for 

congratulation and rejoicing. 

the good name Nebraska has thus fur borne may receive 

no stain, and that we may in some degree aid in strengtheng, in 

nuking yet more broad and firm, the foundations of her future 

sjreatness. 

CONCLUSION. 

In conclusion, I wish to assure you that in all measures cal- 

Bolated to promote the honor, prosperity and general welfare of </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>