<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Feeding Sorghum Grain to Growing and Fattening Pigs</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">BULIIETIN 323 OCTOBER 1939 Teeding SORGHUM GRAIN To Growing and Fottening PIGS MARVELL. BAKER &gt;__ GLETUSRREINMILLER BULLETIN 43 OF THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION, L.LZOOK.SUPT. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA WW.BURR, DIRECTOR </seg>
         <seg id="p002">3 f» «« *y HE COMING INTO PROMINENCE o£ sorghum grain as a livestock feed has raised the question of the value of this grain in comparison with corn. The follow - ing pages contain a detailed report of four different feed - ing trials in which sorghum grain and corn were com - pared as fattening feeds for growing swine. The feeding trials permitted nine comparisons be - tween shelled corn and sorghum grains. In these com - parisons the sorghum proved to be 89% as valuable as corn, as an average. In some cases it was more and in others less than 90% as valuable as corn. In one case sor - ghum grain that was dry and hard as a result of storage proved only 80% of corn in effectiveness. Differences between varieties of sorghum appeared to be negligible. Grinding the sorghum grain appears to be of doubtful value. Only small differences were noted. Grinding proved advantageous in one trial in which the sorghum had been stored for several months and was dry and hard. The grain sorghums proved to be as palatable as shelled corn and produced carcasses equal in yield, finish, firm - ness, and grade to those produced with corn. -4 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Feeding Sorghum Grain to Growing | and Fattening Pigs '*:.' MARVEL L. BAKER and CLETUSF. REINMILLER 1 BECAUSE OF CONDITIONS unfavorable to the production of corn, trie past few years have witnessed a considerable increase in the acre - age devoted to the production of grain sorghums in Nebraska. This has i been accompanied by an increasing interest in the use of the grain as liyc - i stock feed. The grain sorghums are those that are raised primarily for ~£ grain and are distinguished from the sorgos, or forage sorghums, raised I primarily for their forage. Four trials conducted at the; North Platte Sub- X station in which sorghum grain was fed to growing and fattening pigs are reported in this bulletin. | '."'•'.¦ The objects of the trials were (1) to compare the sorghum grain with j shelldd corn when fed with a protein supplement to growing and fattening /¦ pigs and (2) to study the advisability of grinding the sorghum grain when self-fed to growing and fattening pigs. ..'¦''._ ... ¦. I Purebred Duroc-Jersey pigs produced from the Substation • herd were I used in these trials. They were thrifty pigs of medium type, quite uniform W. in breeding and quality. At the beginning of the trials they averaged I!¦ from about 44 to about 57 pounds in weight. ¦..... ¦. j The grains and mixed protein supplements were self-fed, free-choice, I ; ¦ ¦ in dry lot. The pigs were well housed and were hand-watered twice daily. They also had access to salt. FIRST TRIAL In the first trial two lots of 12 pigs each were fed for 98 days, from December 10, 1935, to March 17, 1936. The average initial weight of the pigs was about 51 pounds per head. The pigs in Lot 1 were fed yellow shelled corn. This corn graded No. 4 and contained 18.5 per cent moisture. The] pigs in Lot 2 were fed whole threshed Wheatland milo. This Wheat - land milo was produced in Frontier county and contained 15.8 per cent moisture. The mixed protein supplement was 75 per cent digester tankage and 125 per cent alfalfa meal. Data for this trial are presented in Table 1. Reference to Table 1 shows that the pigs fed whole milo ate slighdy i more grain, gained slighdy less, and made slightly less efficient gains.than the bigs fed shelled corn. The efficiency of the whole milo and supplement was) 94 per cent as compared with the shelled corn and supplement, based on the amount of feed required per unit of gain. ¦ ¦ ¦ At the close of the trial the pigs averaged a little more than 200 pounds per .head. Both lots were fat enough for market demands, and there was no apparent difference in the finish, of the two lots. 1 {animal Husbandman, North Platte Experimental Substation, and Junior Animal Husbandman. Burefus Animal Industry, United State. Department of Agriculture. The '»'•' »*«*»''. «f^ iunervi«ion of the trial, and direct mpervilion of the first two unit. The ptgs used in »he last wo "wfwere from litter, produced in the Regional Swine Breeding laboratory. Pro,cct In "fPc™™ who! the Bureau of Animal Industry, U. S. Department of Agr.culture. The pig. "«d in these mats w"5 from stock after the litters had been sampled for "litter test lots" and were being grown to obtain growth rates, scores, and other data essential to the project. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 323 Table I.— Feeding Wheatland milo to growing and fattening pigs. December 10, 1935, to March 17, 1936-98 days—l 2 pigs per lot. Lot 1 Lot 2 Shelled corn and Whole milo and supplement, self-fed supplement, self-fed Average initial weight 5150 SH2 Average final weight 206.67 202^0 Average gain per head 155.17 151.08 Average daily gain 1 5g 1^54 Average daily ration: Shelled corn 5 77 Whole milo r'j^ Supplement' 104 t'nj Tot 3' 6.26 6.49 Feed required (or 100 pounds gain: ~ Shelled corn 330 Whole milo ijj Supplement 'gg fi7 „ ,T. otal &#132; . 396 421 Relative efficiency (p.ct.) 100 94 1 Supplement consisted of tankage 3 parts and alfalfa meal 1 part. SECOND TRIAL In the second trial, three lots of 15 pigs each were fed for 90 days, beginning June 16, 1936, and ending September 14, 1936. At the begin - ning the pigs averaged almost 57 pounds per head. The pigs in Lot 1 were fed No. 2 yellow shelled corn, the pigs in Lot 2 whole threshed Wheatland milo, and the pigs in Lot 3 ground threshed Wheatland milo. The milo was the same as that fed to Lot 2 in the first trial, but as fed in this trial it contained only 14.5 per cent moisture and appeared to be much harder than when fed in the preceding trial. The milo fed to Lot 3 was ground as coarsely as possible in a burr-type mill. All three lots had access to a mixed protein supplement consisting of 25 per cent digester tankage and 75 per cent expeller-process soybean oil meal. In addition, each lot of pigs was fed 5 pounds of green alfalfa hay daily. Data for this trial are shown in Table 2. The pigs in Lot 2, fed whole milo, ate more feed in this trial than cither of the other two lots. The pigs in Lot 3, fed ground milo, ate more teed than those in Lot 1, fed shelled corn, and made more rapid gains than either of the other two lots. At the conclusion of the trial they were heavier and fatter than either the pigs fed whole milo or the pigs fed shelled corn. There was no apparent difference in finish between the pies fed whole milo and those fed shelled corn. The pigs in Lot 1 required less feed per unit of gain than the pigs ted either whole or ground milo. Based on the amount of feed consumed per unit of gain, the ground milo and supplement were 89 per cent and the </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Feeding Sorghum Grain to Pics ¦I Table 2.— Feeding Wheatland milo to growing and fattening pigs. I \]une 16,1936, to September 14, 1936-90 days-15 pigs per lot. 'I Lotl Lot 2 Lot 3 '; . Shelled corn Whole milo Ground milo and supplement, and supplement, and supplement, self-fed self-fed self-fed '¦": Average initial weight *6AI , o o nn ™3l AveJage final weight .196.00 . 9«-00 206.6? .[ Avenge gain perhead "?fc "f 7 1 67 | Avcfagc daily gain i-55 '•" Vbl t\ Average daily ration; . ,„, Shelled corn 3.81 ••• :'•'¦¦ jWhole milo ••• 5-3 5 " ! Ground milo : •• • "..'"¦'-¦¦' ¦" ' ft , I |aa—' a &amp; &amp; h. Feed required for 100 pounds gain:' 1 Shelled corn 246 .... I Whole milo ••-. iSZ »;; jli Ground milo ... 'at 58 fl ¦¦ S Cment" :'::-:^y-^^ ¦ .412 369 If Relative efficiency (/&gt;.&lt;*.) 100 80 89 I . -r Supplement consisted digester tankage 1 part and cpejler-process »ybean oil meal 3 parts. In addition, 5 pounds of green alfalfa were fed to each lot daily. whole milo and supplement 80 per cent as effective as shelled corn and supplement. The whole milo was 90 per cent as efficient as ground milo inhthis trial. This places a lower value on whole milo than was obtained W the other trials reported in this publication. Possibly the explanation lies in the fact that the milo fed in this trial had been stored for several I mjonths before being fed and appeared to be harder than that used in the ' other trials. .... THIRD TRIAL ' The third trial began November 23, 1937, and continued until the ¦pcs were removed at a final weight of 220 pounds per pig. Five lots of i 13 pigs each which averaged. 44 pounds per pig at the beginning of the ! trial were used. The grains fed were respectively yellow shelled corn, whole white kafir, ground white kafir, whole Sooner milo, and ground Sooner milo. All of the grains graded No. 2. The white kafir was shipped :''•¦ in from Kansas City, and the Sooner milo was locally grown. Ihe fctfu and milowere ground as coarsely as possible in a hammer-type mill. In tjiiis trial, a mixed protein supplement of 50 per cent tankage, 25 per cent 1 ¦'¦ linseed oil meal, and 25 per cent alfalfa meal was fed to all lots. 1 I As shown in Table 3, which contains the data for this trial, the gams ' made by all five lots of pigs were quite satisfactory, and with one ex - { e'eption were quite uniform. The pigs in Lot 3, fed ground kafir, ate </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 323 Table W«*«* Kafir and milo to growing and fattening pigs. November 2i- m7 &gt; t0 " final weight of 220 pounds—l 3 pigs per lot. Lotl Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Lots ck ii i &#132;,l , Whole Ground Shelled Whole Ground Sooner Sooner corn and kafir and kafir and milo and milo and supplement, supplement, supplement, supplement, supplement, sdf-fcd sdf-fed self-fed self-fed self-fed Average initial weigh, 44.00 44.00 44.00 44.00 44 00 Average hnal weight 220.00 220.00 220.00 220.00 22000 izzzzz mM mm mm mm ™* reach final weight 108.00 109.00 98.00 UO.OO 108 00 Ascragcclsdygam J.6J 1.61 &#132;g0 r. 60 1.63 Average daily ration: Shelled corn 5 08 Whole kafir ' . 557 Ground kafir g ji Whole milo ,- „j. Ground milo ' _' *' Supplement' .80 .97 \ OO lfJ j -° T'"jl 5-88 654 7.13 6.08 6.45 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: ~ Shelled com 3JI Whole kafir 345 Ground kafir 342 Whole nulo '" &#132;, Ground milo ' • • j Supplement' 49 60 55 « M „ ,7- * • 360 m 397 380 395 Relative efficiency (p.cl.) 100 89 91 95 91 1 Supplement consisted 0! tankage 2 par,., linseed oil meal 1 p 3rl , and alfalfa meal 1 part. more feed and gained more rapidly than the pigs in any of the other lots. 1 he whole kafir and supplement were 89 per cent as efficient as shelled corn and supplement, and 98 per cent as efficient as ground kafir and supplement. Who c milo and supplement were 95 per cent as efficient as shelled corn and supplement. Grinding the whole milo did not increase us efficiency in this trial, as the ground milo and supplement were only HO per cent as efficient as whole milo and supplement. Based on the feed required per unit of gain, the kafir proved to be about 97 per cent as efficient as milo, and the sorghum grain averaged slightly more than 91 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. At the final weight of 220 pounds, the pigs fed corn were slighdy fatter than the pigs fed sorghum grain. All five lots of pigs, however, produced carcasses which were acceptable in every way, and carcass grades howed no advantage for the pigs in any one lot over the pigs in the other lots. Ne.ther was there any appreciable difference in the dressing yield </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Feedinc Sorghum Grain to Pics Table 4.— Feeding Early Kalo to growing and fattening pigs. December 13, 1938, to April 13, 1939—121 days—lo pigs per lot. Lotl Lot 2 Lot 3 : Shelled corn Whole Kalo Ground Kalo and supplement, and supplement, and supplement, self-fed self-fed self-fed Average initial weight ' , 56.50 56.50 57.20 Average final weight .: 225.50 222.60 236.80 Average gain per pig 169.00 166.10 179.60 AVerage daily gain 1.40 1.37 1.48 Average daily ration: Shelled corn 4.43 ... Whole Early Kalo ... ¦ 5.16 Ground Early Kalo !» ..'. 5.28 Supplement 1 -A 1 .74 : .69 ¦ .79 .Total- . ¦" v ; .5.17 I 5.85 6.07 Fc:d required for 100 pounds gain: • '.]''.' Shelled corn 318 ... Whole Early Kalo ...-..' 376 ... Ground Early Kalo ¦'.'¦:' ;.... 356 Supplement' 53 - 51 53 Total. 371 427 409 Relative efficiency (p.ct.) 100 87 91 consisted of tankage 2 parts, cxpcHer-proccss soybean oil meal 1 part, and alfalfa meal 1 part, . of the five lots. The pigs fed shelled corn dressed 74 per cent packer style, and the four lots of sorghum-fed pigs averaged 75 per cent. J FOURTH TRIAL In this trial, three lots of 10 pigs each were fed from December 13, 1938, to April 13, 1939, a period of 121 days. The average initial weight ofj the pigs was about 57 pounds. Lot 1 was fed No. 2 yellow shelled corn. Whole threshed Early Kalo was fed to the pigs in Lot 2 and ground threshed Early Kalo to the pigs in Lot 3. The Kalo was ground as coarsely as possible in a hammer-type mill. The Early Kalo was locally grown and of good quality. The mixed protein supplement used was 50 per cent digester tankage, 25 per cent expeller-process soybean oil meal, and 25 per cent alfalfa meal. Data for the fourth, trial are given in Table 4. '/,. The pigs fed either whole or ground Early Kalo ate more feed than those fed corn and those fed ground Early Kalo made more rapid gains than the corn-fed pigs. The pigs fed "corn, however, again required less feed per unit of gain than the pigs fed Kalo. Whole Early Kalo and supplement were 87 per cent as efficient as corn in this trial and ground Early Kalo and supplement were 91 per cent. Whole Kalo was 96 per cent as efficient as ground Kalo. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 323 8 At the close of the trial the pigs fed ground Early Kalo appeared to be somewhat fatter than the pigs in the other two lots. All three lots were well finished, and carcasses produced in the three lots were equally satisfactory. SUMMARY Nine comparisons between shelled corn and grain sorghums were afforded by the four trials. Gains made by the pigs fed grain sorghum were in general as rapid as the gains made by the pigs fed shelled corn. Measured by the amount of feed required per unit of gain, in three comparisons whole milo averaged 90 per cent as efficient as shelled corn; in two comparisons ground milo averaged 90 per cent as efficient as corn; and in one comparison whole kafir was 89 per cent, ground kafir 91 per cent, whole Early Kalo 87 per cent, and ground Early Kalo 91 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. In these nine comparisons, the grain sorghums proved to be 89 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. Differences between grain sorghums appeared negligible although direct comparisons were made in only one trial. In five -comparisons milo averaged 90 per cent, and in two comparisons each kafir averaged 90 per cent and Early Kalo 89 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. In four comparisons between whole and ground sorghum grajn grind - ing proved to be of doubtful economy. In two comparisons whole milo averaged 97 per cent as efficient as ground milo, and in one comparison whole kafir was 98 per cent and Early Kalo 96 per cent as efficient as the corresponding ground grain. In the one case in which grinding proved of material advantage the sorghum in question had been stored for several months before feeding and was dry and apparently hard. The sorghums fed in these trials were fully as palatable as shelled corn and the pigs fed either whole or ground sorghum grain produced carcasses apparently the equal of those from cornfed pigs in yield, finish, firmness, and grade. IWI </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>