<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Raising Dairy Calves</title>
               <date value="1918-08">1918-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">h«i«»*WM Bulletin )l -W.,.1. I'M» Raiting Dairy Cal vet M »m » f I* »»f b »ii» iMf urn 4 (mii^, m A&lt;,MKi/i;n)Mi, IXII,NM(^M,MVUI U, H, MA'AHmJKl Of MM\LU;tUM MMMA1M'* </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Univ«r»ity of N«brMka ColUf« of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE Illl i.OVKIIMM, Mi\U\l I'llif K»v'-"l» "f 'In' I hi\i'i'il&gt; IIumimahi.*. K. I'. Known, PnuliUnt, l&gt;«v*y IIumiKaki.k -I K. MiUKR, l'«' I'limih ill, UikoIm MiiMiWAHi.K Krank L IIam.kr, onmhn HiiMiKAKi.i. Vim. ii (i, I.YKOUD, I 1 nil- ( i': Ho.smIimiii I'iiii.ii' I,, IIaI.I., Lincoln ll&lt;iMiii\iu&gt; IIAKIIY I). I.amiIH, Kfwui'l THK I MVKUHII \ OKH(KHK •Kami ki. Avkkv, I'm. I)., 1. 1.. D.. &lt; W. (i. llAM-riNim, A. I., Acting t% K. A. Hiunktt, l&gt;. H«'., r«//&lt; ,-/•■ i 7/ //.„ \ f/l irul f tl t i I III 1'iliti , K nl / SI ii I inn .1. H. I»aikh, M. I'M., Financial , in KXTKNMION KXKCI'TIVK KTAH (MAN. K OUMMHJ, B. S&lt; l)u rrlnr I! K. II..I.1.A I-, It. Kl., ( 'mini /I Ai/ltlt Limit Mai 1/ Matiikh Wii.hon, Ii. K&lt; ., //((;»«■ l)&lt; ll, utml l ilium l,iiulir I.KW T. KklNNKM, It. Si Strrilm a C. W. Watkoai, A. M., Junior Hyli'imlim I, mil THK KXTKNKION COI \( II, LaWMMCI BBUNM, II. Si h'ntniiKiliif/ii II. C. I M i.m A. M . Fnnn SI nna hi' in tn I •L, W. Chame, M. K., A. E., Aurlculliirnl Kni/uin nun Al.HK M. l.'MlMIH, A. M , 1 1 urn i' Ei'Ovomiet W. W. lii mi B. 8c, K. V. IfiiWAKIi, A. M. llm tirnllnrc (i. A. I.OVH.AVI', A. M Meteorolof/y Animal Hutbandru L Van Eh, M. I)., V. g., K. Mead Wii.ox, I'm. I)., 1'lant I'atlialof/n F. E. MlJNMEHL, B. SC Poultry IliitUiniiii a H. E. Bradford, A. M Principal, School of At/rirulture •Ahuent en leave. C. A. l.nwi», B. He., Atiriniltitrul h'llilur E. A. BuBNtrr, I). He., Dean Cham K. Ut'NNKLlt, B. Sc , Director V. W. UrwtN, Ph. I)., Agricultural ChtmUlry Ai/runotny H. J. Uramlich, I). He, Animal I'utlioli&gt;f/n ami Hi/i/i'iu 3. H. (Jain, M. D. C, Animal f'alholoiiy 3. H. Fkandhen, M. 8. A., Dairy Hunhandrn </seg>
            <seg id="p003">RAIIINO DAISY OALVBi IKIMK I \\V. HKHI &lt; AI.VKM »M,V It U dolllilhil if it pii.vn to i;ii»&lt; /iii.v lull I lii' lii'kl heifer rftlvi'4 if it In tbi plan to have these calves t»ilu- place* in the herd wbwi of milkinu nut', ( 'I'l'ininly it d&lt; &gt;■» not p«y in riiitwt l!i« heifer* from tin- IihhI productive and poorest t ,v j m- cow* if tin- uwimt &lt;|«**ir**w (&lt;&lt; imnHM' ili&lt;&gt; yield &lt;&gt;f milk mid butter fat •ml to improve tint indi- viduality of I Ik- &lt;"»&gt;• in tin* herd lie clfi'Hi'il thru tlic umi of »in'i |iriMlin inif »iiti'k, tin' ini|ii'i'\i'iin Alilm much impr-menu-nt can »|M'cin||y Ki'li'i'ii'il fnin Ihi/Ii it IIMI.V III' l|l'l'OIII|lliiilll'l| Illlli'll it riinlily if tin 1 lii'ifi'i' I'lilti'ft ft in nnlv tlir lii'ot 1'imti Hd' mmi'c.I Tin- ini'i'i'fiM'il 1'imt of nil iii'ii lion, I'hiff mnoiitf which »ru fn-il tin- minimum limito &lt;if milk \tnn\ uliii'h 1'iiiir into milk proilni ni'l li 1 ' r, Iiiin niiiti-riiiliv liiuiil II' iliiriion will Ih- ini'i, With normal dfil \ir\i'p%, i'own |iroilui'inu frmn four to Mm- tin ukhimI |iouii&lt;U of milk miuuiilly pwbtlily iiiinlc ii kliulii prolit foe tlu-ir itwtutnt, Iml nl pr«tM*ii( it i» liki'ly tluit l.iiiin |iuiiiiiU more milk per row |ier year i» Modod to uffni't tin- greater fxinmtu- nl |iro&lt;lui'tiou, TIiih meNint tlmt pown of trentet i'ii|nii'it,v and i'llii'ii'iii',v are nn imperative need if iiii tde&lt;|tuii »op ply of dairy produetN in to lie maintained, Hui'li eowa mn-t In IlliiU'il, Hi. there i» fit |irei&gt;ellt II II illNUtiii'ieut llUllllier of hi|fl|-proilU'' mi; town. To do thin, Helei'tiou muni lie riuiilly practiced, In order to Ki'li'i't the mo»1 deitirable ealveH, it in etwratiftl that production rrionU lie ke|it for ein'li cow iii the herd. TheM Meordi khoulil inelude the amount of milk and butter fut produced iu&gt;l the amount and cont of feed consumed during each ealendar yi-nr. Knirly accurate roeonl* may he obtained by weighing the feed and milk iliirinir one day of eaeh month and by tenting 11 Mnple of milk from both mil king* of tlmt day for butter l'nt by the HhI&gt; - eook teat. It i* well to make these determinationa m&lt; re often if poaaible, but the recorda mentioned are h aatiafaetory cuide in •electing the moat |iro(itnble eowi in the herd. WHKN TWIN &lt; VI.VKS SHOl I.I) HK RAISKII When twin calveN are of the Maine »cx, lioth usually have nor - mal reproductive power, but when of oppoMitc nex the female in iiHually, tli" not alwayM, itterilc. It in, therefore, considered nn profltalile to rHixe, for dairy purposes, a heifer ealf whieh is twin Ilii'll the ''out of |il </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Extension Serf ice to u hull. Twin ealvta arc generally smaller than average calvca of tin- breed, hut when utrong and vigoroun attain us great »ize ax the average. , i CARE OF CALVES AT Bin III III cold weather if a cow will not own her calf and lick it, the cull' nIiouIiI h« dried by rubbing with *traw or cloilm and hy eover- Ing it with 11 blanket which bai been ht-nted. (,'are should be ihIm'ii to avoid eold draftM and to keep hoth the calf and its mother comfortable. It i&gt; itnportiint that the cult' secure MtM of the 1 i i — ■ i milk or colostrum, which is very hcncficial in promoting the proper action of the digestive tract. In cim the cow'a Brat milk in found to he bloody, clotted or otberwiae unlit lor the calf, the milk from (mother cow juit fresh inny he given, or if mich is not avail - able wmic laxative drug miiy he added to milk and given the calf instead of allowing it to nume its dam. For thin purpose one-half ounce to 1 ounce of castor oil or one-half to 1 ounce of Bpaotn ..nits may be given hy mixing with one-half to 1 pint of warm milk and pouring it into the calf* mouth from a bottle. Twelve to twenty-four hour* is usually a wufticicut length ■&gt;!' time for a calf to remain with its dam. Mtrong, vigorouit calve* li(M|ii,.nt|y secure ho much milk thru minting during the lir.st day, especially when their damn are heavy milker*, that ucouring re - sults. For this reason it is often oeceaaary to *cparate ituch calven from their dimis when they are about twelve hours old, or as noon iis they have received one good till of the lirst milk. It ia much easier to teach calve* to drink if Ncparatcd from their dam* at an early age than when they arc allowed to nurse for several days. TEACH THE CALF TO DRINK AT AN EARLY AGE Must calveM cannot be readily taught to drink until they be - come quite hiiungry. The easiest method to follow is to offer no milk to the ealf until it ha* remained tteparate from its dam for 12 to 24 hours. Then a small quantity of the mother's milk at ;is nearly body temperature us poacible may be offered. It is usually necessary to encourage the ealf to drink and to me a considerable amount of patience and perseverance. To get the calf started drink - ing, the attendant may moisten his fingeri* with milk and allow the calf to suck them. The hand may then be slowly lowered into the milk until the calf* none touches the milk. After a few minutes the fingers may be removed from the calf's mouth. It is not r good plan to forec the calf's head into the pail and to hold it there </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Raining Dairy Calves 5 as the calf may choke. With a little patience on the part &lt;&gt;f the feeder, many &lt;hI\cn learn to drink well at thu firm or » ml feed inf. FEEDING WHOLE MILK Whole milk i* the natural feed for young calves and eon - tuiiiH all the element* iii-ci-N»ary for their maintenance and growth. In meeeaaful calf rawing it is abnolutely neceiwary to feed whole milk until nidi time u» the calf in able to obtain it* nouriiihmcnt from other feed*. TIuh mean* that tiNiially whole milk muitt be I'nl for at iciiHt throe, week*, hh at that age calves will cat small quantities of hay and grain. It in generally beat to give t'or the lirst three or four day*. the calf milk from it* own dam After that time the mixed herd milk may be fed. The amount of milk fed xliniild In- in moat I'tiM'N in proportion to the weight of tlie calf, One. pound of whole milk per day to each 10 pounds live weifht of the calf Niifllei(&gt;nt for calve* of the i- Jeney and Guernsey breed*. while to Ayrshire ami HoUtcin calvet* 1 pound of milk to each H pounds of live weight may be fed. When the calf is fed three times a day come what Klu. 1 CiilVDn iiliout two wt-.'k. old wlili'h Iiiivi- n-irlvi'il ■ Kuud mart oo Mlnilf milk They will •noli l&gt;« old i-ii.himIi Io !»!• fi-ii nkliii milk. more milk tlmn this may be given, but care must be taken not to overfeed. When it in not convenient to weigh the calve*, the fol - lowing table may be of uite in determining the amount of milk to feed : Birth weight of dairy calves and amount of whole milk to feed luring p,rs\ weeks of age. Breed Jeriey .... Guernsey Ayrshire Holitein Birth Wt. of Calves Ibt. 45-55 50-60 65-75 80-90 Amt. whole milk per day Its. 4.5- 5.5 5.0- 6.0 8.0- 9.0 10.0-11.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Srhraaku Ertention Service Tlii't'c b eouaiderable variation Imtli in the weiichi and in the lligWtiVf I'll purity nl' i'hIm'N if tile Mllllr lil'rnl, no thai tin* proper ■mount ot' nilk mu«t In* determined from the capai-ity of the in dividual rule rather tluiu by any hard mid I'mM rule, An motioned above, whole milk ulioiild lie IVil for tit leant three week», when it inn.v lie replaced by nkim milk, In oaae •klm milk in nut avuilnldt 1 , ntu-li aa i* often the eMe on limn* where whole milk ix xolil, tin; cuhi'K uui.v lie roared itieeeMfully on u umII (imniiiit uf wlmli' milk supplemented by grain and hay, In !iii»iiik 1'iilvt'N ii iii l&lt;-t- thU inrtlniil, ii full I'rnl uf milk, ilnii In, 1 pound ilinlv fur I'lii'li M |hmiimIm I lie I'llhi") Ill'r I til 'i mitIix (ilil, iii niiMiiiiiiiitf it goodly iimoiint ii'iIiii'imI lit the rule of I pound wi'i'k, For i'miiiijiIi 1 , n I'ulf rci 1 if live Weight, mIumiIiI lie fml until At thai time, |&gt;ri»vliliuir the etlvM of grain uml liny, the milk miiy be per ilny lit I lir lii'iflnnitiK of mtcli t-ivliiK m |miuiiiIn of milk ilnily on full fi'fd would In' fril 7 pound* dully during tin 1 »ixth wm&lt;k, (i poumlN dully iIumiiu tint ni-vciiIIi wi'i'k uml no on until none in foil, Tlnm milk would lu&lt; dUcontliiinid when thi&lt; i-tilf i» ftbottt N dljri of Ntfi', ii total of hImiiii 475 poumU of milk ImvltiK b«i&gt;n ftid. In tin' i'hni 1 of l/ii'tfi', riiKui'd rnlvi'd rm'i'lvliiK 10 to 12 potwda of milk mi full feed, I In' milk tuny li*i Mducnd ul tlm rnin of 2 pouudN daily el tlic lit'iflnniuif of 1'in'li wi'i'li after tlm riilvi'w nri 1 4 u&gt; k&lt; old, Hurli enlvi'x will rvquire n i"inl of from I "»' » to MM) piiuniU of milk mid will Ik* off the milk »i'ln'i|iili- hi mIioiiI 2 uinutliN of atf«&lt;. Wlicii ||u&lt; Hinoiint uf milk i» ri'diti'i«l, Mil fill WHll'l 1 xlllllllll III' Mlipplil'll III IN plni'i', In rnixinu i'uIvmn on wlioln milk, then' ix n ti'iiili'iicy to fi'i'd ton liiilr milk Hiiflli'li'iit milk iniixt In' mipplli'd to ki'i'p tin 1 naive* in tfnod irrnwliitf condltloti, A* n rule, tin' lotiil hi nit of milk fed to » '■nil •Imiilil not lu&lt; li'xx limn I. VI p&lt;iund«. WIIOI.K MII.K W.'iuli tlin milk, TIm&lt; milk • Imiilil he wi'inlii'il for riirli fiu'dliiK if the licxi nnd moMt iM'ouomli'nl ri'Kiilt* are to be hIiImIiii'iI, A uprliitf linlmn'o mioh M th« iiiii' kIiowii III I In 1 ni'i'oiii|inii,vliiK i 1 1 u«t rn tlou, In M'iy iMinvptili'iit for thlM imrpoM, It Ix iii'im idi'd with twir ndjimlnldfl hand*, MM idai'k mid Him other red The Mil I l« V A IHIII) I/IW I'f liillk «tf«l« (in. Imiiif iii.f Iih wl Hi *»tu wlimi ||i» ■•mill* M«ti Iii iiioit It 'hi liillk mil ih.H Ijl fMjl ilf»'H&gt; Tb» itillli 75&gt; Mi'li • »\f »f»*\X (in wnlfliM, VHWAimotiH IN KKKIMNO </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Raining Dairy Calves liaml uiii.v he M't in reud zero when the empty puil i* bung on the Imliuirc mimI tlniM the vMiirlit of milk be ruuii directly. 2, Don't overfeed. It in wonte tluni mteiem to feed more whulu milk than tin 1 culf ran ilitf«*wt, both on account of the \alue of tin- milk iiml on i unt of the probability of emming indige* tion or Mroiit'H, Tin- en 1 1' uliould In* watched carefully In not« i'» condition. :|. Tlir i &lt;' iti| Mi-jit ii r i- nIiiiiiIiI Im&gt; uniform nl nil feeding*, Dur - ing tlir tiist few week* of feeding it in eoeential that tin; tcmpcni - lura of tlir milk be uniform at each feeding. Tin- brut temperature i» t hut of milk ,iii»i tit it in drawn from the row, 4. Too rich milk iiiiiv caiiNc trouble, Milk containing u hiuli pi'i'i'i'iitiiKi' of butler I'hi liiix ii tendency to eauae iniliircation in young i'hIvi'n, Kini'« a larg* i|uantlty of fin in the feed ii-iuU to du - creaae the rate of Momm-h digeation. If tUflfa trouble i» rxperi- I'lirt'il thi' milk miiy In- diluted l&gt;y tidiliiiK »kiin milk or hot water hiuI v\ «i rni i n u to tin- proper li'inpcrHturn, '». CUanlimnw in iwMWtial, J 'mII** In whii'h milk in fi-il Nhould Im&lt; wukImmI with wiirin wntcr iiml Maided with boiling wntnr dally. Whi'ii ii few dropM of milk remain in the puiU from one feeding to Knottier, l he puiU mood become Illthy, «np«i!ially In warm weather, nnd are often the oauee of dl((eittlvi) troubloM, Young I'lilveM lire i|iilte mmi'eptlbl(i to dltfOMtlve dUturbaneeii when unelnan or poor iimiliiy feeda are given them Thny ri*Npotnl nm i|iil«kly to If noil lii'iilini'lll I KKIHNJJ HKIM MII.K Hklm milk U the nnmt Mtlafaetory mipplnment to whole milk .or 1'iilf I'l'i'ilmu Whi'ii a llbernl Nmoiint of frewh Nt-parator Rklin milk In available, enlf riiimiiu U a uoniparnllvitly Nlmple matter, The milk tuny bn fed wnrm from ihn tutpnrator, which untalla sory lltlli&lt; liilior In feeilinif. While cnlve* fed nklm milk do nut becomtt ii« fill iin thorn niiieil on whole milk, they miike n vi«oron», ulurdy ifrowth of body nnd frnine, It i« often HMiimed Hint when whole milk U repbiceil by nMim milk noiiih hl|fh protein feed xnch «n (tan- Need niciil or linaeed nil men I imiinI be fed in order to tukn the place of the butter hil Thin In n mUtiike, nn butter fat Niipplien no pro lelu whnte»er, but Nlmply eneriry, Kneriry enn UNiinlly be Niipplied in bent Mihiinhitfc by corn, oatN, or other Nlmllar «nnn Further, Nklm milk eoutNliiN all Ihe protein of the orliflnnl whole milk, iIhin tii'inu allghtly liitflier In pet'ci'iitiiue of protein than whole milk, and having n much grimier proportion of protein to the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Siinimhu A',w i ■iithni Hvn'H't i I iHli. i •iiliiU iIimii hIhiIm mi ill. Tlic iiiili'lllw ml In nl Hindu milk u nIiiiiiI I -4 4 wlilln HimI nf aklm milk In I ||,A, if mIhmiI Him mhih n« MihI nf Ilimi'ml nil iiimhI Nkllfl mlllt him&gt; Iim M ' »t ' 1 1 1 m 1 1 •i|Ii»IIII||mi| fill' Him hIihIi miIIIi MR ftiiuii M» I Iim iiilf I* mIiIm In tful »ii|||m itf ||* IMMM'ImImmmiiI Iimiii li.ir MM'I tfltilii ll I* i|m»I|'hIiIi&lt; • It m t I Iim ■ .ill Iim Imiii/IiI In Mill NMNM ImKHIIIM till* •Mi'll M* I'llUMI' III' mICmICm, Hi Hit Mlll'l) HM«', •llll'H |||M iMIMin III 1 |||M«|l |l|lllll* I'llllllllll 1/1 III llllltM fllllllll III Illllll'l' t»\, W «&gt;II|I*MIMI' Mllllllllll Illll I tfl'lllll |iIni'I"I kumIiihII&gt; Ii» abllM inllk Him miIm ill 1 I n|' U |iiiMMiU |imi' ilii) Hill |i|iilllllllHM mImIMMIII* •Illllllll IimII il mi'ltn nlil I'lilti* llallttlli Hntl tOmli mill* nhit Iim n IIim miliKllliilliin liMliitf iiimli ill Illllll I In I'llHIItfM I* miiIii|iImIi Tlin iilHHlllil nf xliliii nillli In •tHIIII' IIIIIIMH'I' II* •M|||fM«lMll fill' Will I" i 'I'M fur I'Hi'll ■ |niiiiiiU nl IhM ► limilil Iim Hii'|'hh»miI ii. Him mil i (inillnl- llf mill. || I'll full ilnlli 'I ii In i| unit Iim i|i i|i i niiiM i| in Him linli unlit, Ilitil I*, I iiniiiiil ill unlit it Hi'liilil nf Him i nil Tin 1 NWlfUltl HfllW* U|i lii Him |uiIiiI wIii'Ih I'i Tilt' inn' mil ill null' in i il mil Iim iiiii|ii'ii«i'i| in'&gt;iiinl i lit* iniiiii iihIm Hill Illlll m||MII|I, ll« tfllllll Illlll Inn »niiiiiMt"iM»lt III «ii|i|il&gt; Iiim Him Him «h|i|iI&gt; U i»| i* iliill* iiIhiiiiI unit Miiii'iiill,* Iim iiumiI iiiiii'i' ml iililllliillill Illlll'li'llla ,Sn II I'llli' ■ l-liii Illllk HUM Iim fl'll III HllwillllllfM Illllll rilhi'. mI'm ll hiiiiiHih ii ityt mill »iiiiii'HniM« im I'M u|i lii I I'M r nf mum, ► II I +ll»l»l» KIlMI MM lll»» ll»»H flllM MM lUMl IHHI, Ml »Ht Illlll </seg>
            <seg id="p009">lOll'llIU DlMl/ I lllna 9 Wnill •(•lilt Illllk MMIjf I/I' li.il *}||| tfllllll M.ulU In I'MKn* Hift •i Hir^l»« mIi|, Tm MM* •"•ii mlllt umi'i'mmCiiII^ unpm milal Iim Uh«n IIimI Him Milllt I* lull fnuM; uiuwi mnl Im* wH ItffMM iImmi^miI Iniiii •iNinllHtf »i'Hi|iil iIn^h N»HM' milk •IwiiM Iim (mi »l « unlfiirm '• Hl| M . Ml Nil I HIM.. I'M^'AH'lHiNM IX I MIUNO UMIM Mil t» I, WkImIi Him mill* TIim »ntfui&lt;»ll"n* tflvwii in c hhhI In Him *i&lt;l|fliliilf nf wlinl» milk ii|i|'l&gt; mI«m In rmillnu »kllti milk, TIim ■mhIi'n miii«I In 1 IIMil i nn»liinli&gt; In uiiImp In iicmvi'IiI iivwiCwmiIIiik Mini In MMill'i' ii MiilCniiii iiMinunl ill kmmIi Cui'illlitf, liiMgiiliii Niimiiiil* nl milk ulinn i'NU»ii iIImmkUvm iIihiihIm* y, I Km ri'i'ilmu H »nnri'M nf Cmi'iI Minhi (him milk Himii i» hm ImllMf llnil •klm milk I* "Ililn," Hltlm milk i« ii liilll'lllnil* fi'Mil hi U •nil' In i'iiiivh Irniilili' li'iiilliln Tlii.in )• ii IhiiiImHi'I lit |'mmi&gt; nit iini'inml nl 1 Him iui|iiiImi' HimI )•, Him! II lnnk» turn) viilnn il Hlii'ii li'il III Inn u'"'H iini'iimia I 1 1 ni|ii'MilHli'« nIhhiIiI In Illlllnl III II I* Mill III IlIMM allllll iniini'iiliii'i' l''ni' nnIvm II Minnlli* Illllk I'M tnillitf i ulu. ill limit Ii nlil mnl iMi'i, •klm milk niM,t Im li&lt;i| imlil in whi'IH Wfiihtf, Iml mil'i' uliniilil lit I ii I* in In Iiimh I lie li'iii|M'l'Hlill'M iinlfiil'lii nl i'ii"li fHKlllllH I l'ii»ii'iii 1*1 |iiii'kIim*miI "Ihiii milk, WIimii aklm nilll&lt; I* *&gt;■ illl'Hil 1 1 inn n i ii'iinnu II mIiihiIiI Iim HmiI'iiI^ |ih«Ii*III IdMil licfniH Ih'Iiim fi'il III nrilw lii (iMMi'iil I lie liili'iiiliiHIiin Ililn ijll liMhl til liiCi'i'lliiii. .ll.rn.i.. .iii'ii n« liilii'h'iilnil*, fun! Mini liniiilll iIIki'ikm, fll' I'MKli'lll'Ifllllnn In |i|'i'fi'liilil( lllllll' Ml llll&lt; I'l'l'llllic !')»•, lull n Inn Ilil* lii mil )hi«d|IiIi&lt; II mm In* 'inin nI Immi', I'lioii'iieUHllnii nf milk miIkInN mI hi'iilliii/ lii ii li&lt;iM|n&lt;liilllli&lt; nf l.iii K InililhiM II Nl Mini ll'IM|ii'llllllll' fill' Illl llllMllll'« Hll'l WinllHtf l|llll'ltl», f) I'liiim kIimiiIiI mil In. fml, TIim fiiHIll *illi&gt;li fnCMII nil fn&lt;ili neiiMHili'l' milk &lt;iliiiiilil Iim H'MmmmI ln*fniM I lie inlllt In fm| In Hie wiU»'» hi li'fliitf Inililnk fiiMliiy milk, i'mUh* nfli-n «l|i'k III In him i|IINIilHU&lt;« nf HlK H/llli'li i&lt;NII«Mi HlM»M In IiIiinI MIMl "Ml HMtltl t^N IliM I HH&gt; 'III I||K IHIIfkKl N lllllllIlM nf |'!'|i!lll!ll'l||« Wllll'll Nf» m-hiiik/iiikIiIi Immiii-iI Millk "iiiIihIIIiiIm " TIimh nm iiniinII* ihniIc h|i III Ilic fnnii nf iiii'«l«i wlili'li hih In Im ml«m| wllli |m| *hIi&gt;i mnl Himi iIHiiIhI wllfi m\\k «(■ wnIx^ M»» h*mil, Audi tumit iimiiiMllmiHlilt Iino I'IiiinM^hIiIm Mill* M iiliivMllilM f»^ |MlH, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 I I'll 4 »m imi »\i}ii\i l« iiwiiuiiiiwtih'ii lit i\h&lt; I'tinlm mill Hwhin mi (tfili'li m» \imi im *l!lf mMhuUihi mm, mm lip mi nun in ini»iii\t Iwiui iiimii miif I/* *mhl in miim in) ii Mi; hiiiut Ilimi H ' 'f ""/' ""' ''/""'I. "'"if T ■ hi ii j\n iniiii ul « 0MH »«»"'' '* '"'•"' l *'"' /«'"• '" 'Iic«mi»(I| 111/111 l»»&lt; *fllw '"»'» lllM/lw« wMlit nII^IHH *llf^ iiililH hiiiI liiNi n\\n» 'I" tiii'im in Him! n m l/iji/M mm iniiliiH tn minium ul llm niiixi milliiHinil in 'I hi * iiimim lit ■ mini mm In Inl tt|j(n liii' miliiiHi in linn i» I/I &lt; KHUN m|H miii Hi/ iiiin/iiiii kiii'IiihIIi iMNMdWN '(//III I \nillliii ul mnil mill Uiii'lim Inn hi iDmIhinhI'I mm 4 NMMNIM(iN4lM Mlftfl-Mf 'l|»l»l |« f#Mf###ff» N /-### f«#'«-V h'Ml llfNfl -Ill/I/' ///UN I itHIM Ml»« i-mli i|iiniilllf /////» If/' »i»ImI Ii/|i/ Hi/' Ii f «"*•« !// /!«»■ /■wfl'i limn Ii Immnlhtin, nlln \m\lli\t MM Hliij I if, ««lf Illtfi IKMIIHHVM I// hill I llii Hit il'M lllljll II Illlllllil Hill *iii I'M Mill iiii / 1 1 [nil i il \\ l« ||/i*I# M#-#if#ff#l, full iihm »HiiK» mum \m f ' mikm* fulfil »ll"ll Hi miw null Mini i&lt;Hii&lt;\&gt;hi\ mil h mmi\i&gt; muni mltim ii m&gt;\i&gt;'i\ mm " i'«"« Iff »M*|ii, *lm nm nil mil *\mi mmi '" i/«/i&lt;( «in) ijnmii i\i{ mm &lt;\u imi« "' "»' '/I/// ' 1/ / ii" miibii \ii mini \mi* m *»m I'hImi mm &lt;i mmvM m u*m "'" "»^1 W| '( ¥ If""" fi/n/i /I ml mm m wiki limiili) fm in iiiiuthm&gt;hi\ ml « mi Mil film I nllllllH Hi 1(1-1 1'ilMJ »l«»i&lt;l i/illl ff«f#ilfl#tf Jtf/»«"fitf Miimiliiimiliit \iiiii \ml i/i in /// *m / h ' '/- »♦ ###' l# mi Ullilhll Illl Ilivl "lit In ' /||»/ It I I -HUM Mil flflf MM Html nililinll l'lt»|' M " ""'l : ""' M " |Wil '" j/|li|/llll/l)H I" i i "ll 'III WiHllMl "I mm *m ml wmu""! "" ""( v &gt;wj *mv M \ ii mlf mil iiii hi ilifiiiil mil Ifd liil imlii Un &lt;nl\ inii\i\ mm\i In ml uiiii WiiWi tllm *W ¥ "I "n iw nl ultmil -I WwH 4 1 \w Him will iinii imij \h \'/\ hi mn\] imiif iimb ii in \\n ii*ii\i\t mil' niiiuii \\in» huim \i lammm \h m\ mil ii mtmih h a in a urn i» ' imiH &gt; nhu* miiii *i\h mii\ i ulniii ill in ini in mlili mm lln mini \iiiiim n u^iil imil nj lln liilbii llm &lt;iiiii\lliiii ■M niiiin mill mi llu Will "I iiiililiiiniil niiiliiiiinl Iliim i'lh-1 mil* </seg>
            <seg id="p011">/ / i i i 1 1 mti. mill i l/»/l/'IM/iMNf in mm n»h Hllllll lit I'/'/'M In I I mum I II ///&gt;//» ce Hum I lil'iihiWiluiiHi iiiiiwin ' wiiilm *h in m i mm &gt; \m m in "i" ml nil* ii In Inn hi i I ItmHU I ♦|/H/M&lt;UM »tiii&gt;m timmi* iih mi* imam \iil\'\llmi iilwhnim ml n- i u/ in« Hf&lt;tii /»/ /In i»///|i n||| i,//,//,! ll«&lt; I'liiiliiliN ill nut him a &lt;"'!• I// /!»/ /////i !/ lii»itni in iljiMi l/( flj^fl (l» Ipiftj lUl (((( /| dUL. it /• Ziliiiilh mm mh i» fwi/jwi 11 i^li///i 1/ i( ,M /,,n , V|/ // / IM»»I« Hi mill miNiiini, /„ ( /,|«|« i/, )|,,, w/// | f^ 'i ill m i- ilil Miimiilitl Ihml iiiiiii. linmlmil \\m 111 I fowi, i,l ,,fok Ih/, «|4. f /, //1/( „!„,„ ,i tl , l^L) ,/J mWHIHIimUltMliltlKHIHMM W/i/iH nimhiiliilili i\nmiihiHih m 11* ummi} 111 mum tl\ "III inillllft M VMMM M| r«|[»M ItlJflHMllMi* I I -I !« ihlhl nmulW* Him/ Hi/ i w Imiiih "\ Ji! J'\ </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 HiIiiiihIiii Itiiil nil an Mm h/ll // - -'inum wiiliil in tn ilih mll\ »l/l/ ill i lii n huh iim\ in nit hum iliui minimi hum* limn hunm ihhI* n Hi/; miilli ill tin nun iiiiuium mill iln jnii'i mi iIikIiiiIii H uii\h iiul i nh n» m In Iiii m i\ mil fill i mi 11 i hi mi mill kHlllliI III IHiiliilnl Illllll III! Illlllll »y« I HllillU llhlilh Hln mMnbiiii tlniiii [In; -\iiiii\\in\ii\ hi iliiinhihh mill iiimniim mlllli- mill III uklii llli)lk Ml mi) In mi liiiinkiu i ui ill, t .w {limit Jill- a in, hi ,, III i Jliim i, li I I illll I \ii fill ill §;■;■ Mil I I" 1 ■ |l III /!///) /I II hi || „ I'/) f I W ffi / I itiiiii </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Hiimiiiu Ilium i ah i 13 (I iiullh id film lln mi i Ml //■ I 4 «//l'/H "("'/|l//l "/ '"/If "I////H/I I// i/|'|'M/il Id ill &gt;'« I '« /«f///l 4 III »///i I// lllllll'llil III lln Iml a null i in inlili il m iui imi mum In In III Hi hi II ¥M N^ I M» /' ixf I 'I I Mil «y#W I" I in I ill ili. i i hi In | III I Mnn ill'ii'.M &lt; in Ii! ' r r i,™ MM'/';* &lt;mim humm mm uiii hi'xli n«im »\\mh\ In iimm in i //I In unit mmliH II k null In hi i hi llm Mtfl ilium mil B 10VMX </seg>
            <seg id="p014">II ft I III I ilh I i I i' I bin' at ul» (ntht I'm- ( .1 i&gt;liy»}u 4fi' - ;ili(. .1 a i'ii n i HH»m mmmm m mm ftmn " 'I'hrit ftiUtn- /()&lt; ,,ii,i,;i&gt;i tf( jam), 'I'Ur Hill -UmM l»' * ul 'In* n hi urn- IihK Mir m-nul »in&gt;iiinl tti, &gt;»&gt;n» Minnie &gt;uui&gt;\) d»r nir w i»h (iwl*. l'*m\\ \&gt;\)y*\jn, null no | In 2 awn i» of hhMh¥ nil in it Mnlr « M iiiwH in «»»i»» in n'lwuhitt mty u hint wit iu*i»rih ■Il|/&lt;»IIK ilihl 'llir ft?*! HllUlll l&gt;l &lt;«»!*/* ill 1» lii.il tin II in nun* i I ,1 Inn I linlllili ill lit ■i w! i ■inn 111 ■ 7 "// ii ' mill in* •I In rim) huiH \MfMiH W faillll Mil}) •"))• Hlfil " a rhmiut } 'rm it/ "I III hnliiu mi'iui ) ■ ' • i lnmitli &gt;■» Hlr ('''I 'I &gt;'»n\ I' it hi'tnml »///// m ) &gt;l&gt; /'/.(' n)»r- hihn hi 'lnii lln Unnl'h \UM H»h&gt; ■ I" III II Hill rtn.iini M Himlh "llnnmh lh&gt; i tilHllb hi « ■HUhlr- Hhi'i r,,l&lt;&gt;&gt; nin i»n t,uiu »'niir», tt ion hum »ni*ihif fttfmU "hi lirhmiHir (I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">till It III I II ram ; / hn'um/t »fr»i'h'&gt;l hy riuvwwm. 'fUv 4i*«m »mm &lt;&lt;*&lt;■ \&gt;m i» hit t't Hir rnhir [null »»h # m \ j^ itMiihrhmi wh n» h ■ ) lf r t ,,i K,lMtt,n ,,( +,,„*, m mm Mr Hi h, ih rfwHM i/f ifa- iumrim h wiMMo at hni / n »&gt;. h,.,,,,,, '„&gt;» h»M tifft |« r&lt;,m&gt;n,rh&gt;b'l I" h&gt; m, si, I „,, (L forty, h it »,H hi rrfirnf \h&gt; l»lh n&gt; h *w\ U»» hi Ml -/" *hirh huhli )h Hir nn&gt;»&gt;hn» hi nihl *&lt;•«//„, ..,). mm !w htkr» \&gt;, &gt;h&gt; ihr '«/w &gt;m'kty hmkvttoii, &gt;" bwwmi " m^mmmn hi ««•// m »Am m 1 ln&gt; ilit* »» n»nuHy nut mi ffftnis, IHiHiuurm \hmnu Hn h i/»i»r u lt ii -tmni/ mmlk* viAvm ulUn </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Extennwn Service out in circular patehc* ami thick scaly crust* form on the •kin. Some itching is often present. The i-riistK should be remove. I by washing with soap ami water and the area painted with tincture of iodine, sulphur oint - ment or acetic acid. The painting should be repeated every two or three day* ax long as necessary. To eradicate the disease the stable must be thoroly disinfected and whitewashed to destroy the spores of the disease which become scattered in mangers and ubout the stalls. Care must lie exercised in handling ealve* af - fected with the disease, as it is communicable to man. Mange and Itch — These ailments more commonly aflWt m« - ture eattle but may affect calvex. They are cauxed by Minall mites which tpread rapidly from one animal to another. The treatment pon«igt8 in thoro watthing or dipping in a disinfectant solution and disinfection of the quarters as tueiitiond in the discussion of lice. [7-2O-'l»— KMI |il«irlliui..«l In IMtMM of eo-ofwrallYC Hicriruliurnl nt—Uni wurk. Aeta of May 8 mid June »&gt;. MM, Kxteimlon Kvrvl.c of Tlw I'lilvi-raity of S&lt;Urn*k» 'm° I?"' °f •*'? r l &lt;i " i "" - ' &gt; »"'l I'. «. l»..|.nriin.-in ,.f ,\k rl.-ullur.- to-opcratlnc. ili.n. ■. Ounneli. Director. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>