<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROWING CROPS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXIII, Article III. GROWING CROPS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. Report of Experimental Substation, North Pi.atte, Nebraska Distributed February 15, 1911. GARDEN AND OBCHABD O.N SUBSTATION FARM. Wheat field, No. 19, in the background, 1910. Bench land. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA W. P. Sntder, Superintendent. W. W. Bums. E. A. Burhbtt, Director. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the regent* of the university.) EORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. ORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. ORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. ORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. K ORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. ORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director. B. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. . W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mead Wllcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. J. Alway, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. H. R. Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry La whence Bbuneb, B. Sc., Entomology. E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. •Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry. Ebwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Oeology. G. R. Chatbubn, A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture. O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. G. A. Lovela.-.d, A. M., Meteorology. C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Soil Agronomy. »P. Sntder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. Miss Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Qyi?» K. K. Link, S. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. R. S. Trumbull, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils/. Ellis Rail, B. Sc. A., Assistant in Animal Husbandry. C. B. Lee, B. Sc, Ansistant in Animal Husbandry. T. A. Kiesselbach, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy (Crops) Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. R. F. Howard, B. Sc. in Agb., Assistant in Horticulture. tW. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in Soils and Crops, North Platte; Assistant Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture, U. 8. Department of Agri - culture. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. Fritz Knorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent. t Mas. Nelle S. Scott, A. B., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing. • Deceased. t Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Introduction 5 Soil of Substation Farm 1 Grain Production- Winter wheat History of yields 8 Relation of yield of winter wheat to available water 13 Variety tests 15&gt; Rate of seeding 16 Time of seeding 1* Spring wheat — Variety testa 17 Rate of seeding 18 Time of seeding 1* Effect of previous crop and tillage 20 Oats- Variety tests 22 Rate of seeding 23 Effect of the previous crop and tillage 14 Barley — Variety tests 3« Rate of seeding 3* Effect of previous crop and tillage 87 Spring emmer — Value of J8 Rate of seeding 19 Broadcasting compared with drilling small grain 30 Relative yields of spring grains 31 Corn — Variety tests 32 Manner of seeding 33 Effect of previous crop and manner of preparing seed bed ... 33 Forage Crops — Cane 34 Kafir 37 Milo 37 Brome grass 38 Alfalfa 40 Methods of Tillage- Handling new land 45 Rotation of crops 47 Summer tillage 48 Summer tillage for winter wheat 49 How to summer till 50 Cost of summer tilling 52 Effect of the crop on moisture in soil 62 Subsurface packing 54 The seed bed 66 Climatic Conditions •! Map of Nebraska showing rain belts (2 Record of precipitation by years at North Platte (3 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Pig. 1. Map of Substation farm at North Platte, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">BY W. P. SNYDER AND W. W. BURR.* INTRODUCTION. This bulletin is written primarily for the farmers of west - ern Nebraska and of other regions having similar agricultural conditions. It is, to a certain extent, Bulletin 109 revised and brought up to date. The edition of Bulletin 109 was exhausted within four months of the date of publication. In the present bulletin we have made frequent quotations from Bulletin 109 without using quotation marks, as both bulletins are by the same authors. In the following pages we endeavor to give in as brief form as possible the more important results of crop production on the Substation farm since it was established. In order that the farmer may interpret the results correctly, it is necessary for him to understand the conditions under which each crop was grown. This necessitates our giving in considerable detail the climatic conditions and the manner of handling the soil. The space available does not permit us to discuss the climatic conditions and the methods of tillage in detail along with the report of each crop of each season. Therefore it seems advisable to discuss the "Climatic Conditions" and the "Methods of Till - age" as separate topics following the crop report, trusting that the farmer will read the entire bulletin so thoroly as to be able to use the facts contained under these headings in his KMr. Burr is Assistant in Soils and Crops, Nebraska Agricultural Ex - men t Station; Assistant Agriculturist, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, ;au of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. BUL. 118, AOR. EXP. STATION OF .VEBR. VOL. XXIII. ART. Ill </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Growing Crops in Western Nebraska interpretations of the causes of the various results as shown by the crop yields. The yields obtained in 1910 are lower than for any other year. The cause is not explained in connection with the record of the yields, but when the farmer turns to the record of the precipitation he readily sees that this can be accounted for by the lack of sufficient moisture. In a similar manner he will find the discussion under the heading "Methods of Tillage" of much value when studying the yields obtained under various conditions. Careful attention should be given to the yields secured in 1910 under different methods of tillage as this was the only extremely dry season since these tests were begun. The pre - cipitation recorded at North Platte shows that this season was drier than 1894 and, in fact, the driest since 1874, when the weather record at North Platte began. With ordinary methods of tillage a very few seasons of this sort will greatly retard the development of western Nebraska, but when summer tilling a part of the land has become a common practice among the farmers, such a year will retard the development but little, if any. This statement is supported by the yields of grain this season (1910). In every exact test, summer tilled land gave from two to many times the yield secured from land that pro - duced a crop in 1909. Ordinary methods of tillage on the average did not give profitable returns. We trust that this bulletin will encourage the farmer in western Nebraska, as the results recorded indicate that profit - able crops may be grown during extremely dry years when the proper methods of tillage are used, and that during the more favorable years the returns from similar methods will be correspondingly greater. The development of western Nebraska depends largely on the farmers appreciating the fact that the climate is naturally dry and that the extremely dry years will come from time to time. The only safe way is to farm as if each succeeding year were to be dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE SOIL. The farm lies south of the city of North Platte, parti v &lt;&gt;n the bench and partly on the table-land. In the text of the bulletin, the record indicates whether the crop was grown on the bench or the table, tho the small grains have shown very little difference in yield between the two elevations. This table land is quite similar to the several large tracts of hard, level land known as "divides" or "tables" lying between the streams in the western part of the state. Examples of these are, in the southwestern part of the state, the table-lands between Trenton and Palisade, and between Culbertson and Hayes Center: in the western part, the "divide" land beginning between the North and South Platte rivers west of Paxton and extending into Colorado between the Ix&gt;dge Pole creek and the North Platte river; and in the northwestern part, the tables .about Heming ford. The soil of these and many of the other tables is quite similar to that on the Substation farm in respect to the tillage. the storage of moisture, and the productive capacity. There are slight differences which permit the geologist to classify them in various ways, but so far as the farmer's problems are concerned, all the good, hard soil on these tables is so similar as to permit of practically the same methods of tillage, and will give practically the same yields when the precipitation ;md other climatic conditions are similar. According to the records of the United States Weather Bureau, the average annual pi« cipitation decreases westward in Nebraska, at the rate of about 3 inches per 100 miles. Since the soil is quite similar, we should expect the average crop yield to vary rather closely with the variation in rainfall, just as the carrying capacity of the pas - tures varied and became less farther west in range days. In localities where the soil is more sandy, or where subirrigation causes an excess of alkaline salts, the methods of tillage em - ployed in these experiments should not be expected to give the results indicated in this bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ■ 2 Winter wheat on summer tilled land on table. Yield, 1907, 59 bushels per acre. GRAIN PRODUCTION. WINTER WHEAT. I History op Yields. — Six crops of winter wheat have been wn and a seventh is now in the ground. The crop of 1905 i all on summer tilled land and owing to excessive rainfall h a rank growth was produced that nearly all the crop went ro and was not harvested either on the table or on the bench d. Some late seeding that did not get much growth in the I was cut. This produced over 30 bushels per acre. In 1905, 10 acres in Field 49 on the table was sown to wheat in variety, rate-of-seeding, and time-of-seeding tests. This was on a field that had been planted to trees some years before. The trees had been choked by grass and overrun by cattle until most of them had been destroyed. The field, which was in heavy sod. wu plowed in June. 1905, and cultivated the remainder of the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Fig. 3. Winter wheat on summer tilled land on bench Yield. 1908. 57 bushels per acre. did not give nearly as good a seed bed as regular summer tillage, but might be considered summer tillage. The average yield was 42 bushels per acre, the highest 45.7 and the lowest 31. During the same season, 5 acres of new bench land (Field 21) were broken and sown to wheat, yielding 41 bushels per acre in 1906. In 1907 we harvested four and one-half acres of winter wheat on summer tilled land in the south hnlf of Field 45 and in Field 46 on the table. This waB a test of varieties and rates of seed - ing. The average yield was 59 bushels per acre. The north half of Field 45 which was not summer tilled gave an average yield of 24.4 bushels per acre. This part of the field had been in alfalfa from 1902 to the spring of 1906. It was then plowed and planted to corn. The corn was a very poor crop, making not to exceed 5 bushels per acre, due to lack of moisture. The corn was cut and drawn off the field, the land thoroly disked, and the wheat put in with a press drill, as on the summer tilled land </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 In 1908 we harvested 8 acres of winter wheat in one-half acre plats, testing varieties, rate of seeding, and time of seed - ing, on summer tilled land, in Field 13 on the bench. There were also the same tests in Field 51 on the table. The wheat on this summer tilled land went into a seed bed that contained approximately all the moisture that the soil would retain in the surface six feet. The average yield was ~&gt;7 bushels per acre &lt;&gt;n Field 13, and a higher average on the east half of Field 51, Fig. 4. Turkey Red winter wheat on land summer tilled in 1908. Yield in 1909, 40 bushels per acre. Field No. 50. Table-land. with a somewhat lower yield on the west half. This part of the field is newer land, lying higher up on the slope than the other, and did not respond so well to summer tillage. The highest yield in Field 13 was 66.9 bushels per acre, and the lowest 53 bushels per acre. Field 46, 2\ acres, on the table, which was summer tilled in 1906. and produced an average yield of 59 bushels per acre of winter wheat in 1907, was plowed in the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 fall and again seeded to winter wheat. The yield in 1908 was 20.86 bushels per acre. Field 21. of about five acres on the bench, which was in wheat in 1906, producing 41 bushels per acre, and in oats in 1907, produced an average of 29.6 bushels per acre of winter wheat in 1908. The tests indicate a very marked difference in yield due to Bummer tillage or lack of summer tillage. Fig. 5 Winter wheat on Field 19, summer tilled 1909 Yield In 1910. MJ bushels per acre. Bench land In 1909 there were harvested 10 acres of winter wheat in Field 5 on the bench, and also 10 acres in Field 50, and a little less than one acre in Field 46 on the table-land. Field 5 waa broken from sod during the latter part of May, in 1908. The sod was disked in June, and then packed. Sunflowers and Russian thistles came up on the sod and made such a heavy growth that the disk would not cut thru them. They were </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 mowed daring the early part of August. Near the middle of August the field was backset about 6 inches deep. There was practically no moisture in the soil when the backsetting was done. The soil turned over very dry and lumpy. The field was harrowed several times, and even the disk was tried, but we could not break up the lumps. The soil was certainly in poor condition for seeding. Most of the field was seeded September 21, and contained a variety test and two rates-of-seeding tests. The balance of the field (4 plats) was seeded October 22. During the latter part of September a rain of less than four-tenths of an inch was received, and the wheat which was already seeded began germination and growth. However, the available mois - ture was soon used and a very poor stand of wheat resulted. On the 19th of October a 3-inch rain came. This put the upper three feet of soil in very good moisture condition. The ground froze on the 23d of October and the late seeding did not appear until spring. A very poor spring stand was obtained from the early seeding, but the later seeding gave a good stand. The average yield from this field was 36.9 bushels per acre. Field 60 was summer tilled in 1908, and was in very good condition at seeding time save for the fact that the mulch on the surface was too deep. In order to have the seed in moist soil we were obliged to place the grain beneath the dry mulch. This left the wheat too deep and poor germination was the result. This field contained a rate of-seeding test. The average yield was 37.6 bushels per acre. The highest yield was 42.8 bushels from a seeding on September 14, and the lowest yield 22.8 bushels from a seeding on September 30. Field 46 on the table was summer tilled in 1906 and grew a crop of winter wheat in 1907. It was fall plowed, packed, and harrowed after harvest, and again seeded to winter wheat. This gave a yield of 19 bushels per I The winter of 1909-1910 was unusual all over this state and le others. The winterkilling of trees and other vegetation i severe. Winter wheat suffered very severely in tlie spring. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Isre are many theories advanced to account for this, but none t are entirely satisfactory. There were several plats seeded to ter wheat on the table-land in the fall of 1909. The seed bed i prepared in various ways and good stands were secured on majority of the plats. However, the winterkilling was so »re that all plats were reseeded to spring wheat, excepting ; this was a plat that had been summer tilled. The yield it hardly warranted saving it. being only 12 bushels per acre. 1910 we harvested 10 acres of winter wheat in Field 19 on bench. It contained a rate-of-seeding test of both Kharkov Turkey Red wheats, a variety test, and a time-of-seeding test, average yield of wheat on this field was 30.2 bushels per ?. The highest yield was 37.1 bushels per acre from a seed - on September 15. and the lowest yield was 15.3 bushels per 9 from a seeding on October 16. Relation of Yield of Winter Wheat to Available Water. — We do not have many exact comparisons of yields of winter wheat from fields summer tilled and fields cropped each year. hut have experiments under way that will give these data later. The comparison available now. tho from conditions not so nni form as we should desire, shows the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Tat.i.k 1. — Relation of yield of winter teheat to available water. SUMMER TILLED — #1? *$&amp;? JS5L Year Biitheti Inches Inchest Inches 1907 59.0 13.74 1908 57.0 7.0* 13.65 20.65; 1908 57.0 8.2 13.65 21.85 1906 37.6 7.0 15.80 22. W, 1910 30.2 7 6 10.18 17.68 LAND CONTINUOUSLY CROPPED. 24.4 1 13.74 20.8 1.9* 13.65 15.55J 1908 29.0 2.2 13.65 15.18' 1909 19.0 1.1 15.80 16 90 1910 I , 10.18 * In computing the available moisture at seeding time, we have con- sidered 7 per cent as nonavallable water, and have taken 80 pounds per cubic foot as the average weight of our soil. The hygroscopic coefficient of these soils is slightly above 6 per cent. t In these columns we have considered only the precipitation from September 16, the average seeding date, to July 1, when wheat had tipleted growth, or, in other words, only the entire growing season. t In computing the total available moisture no consideration was taken of the run-off from the surface of the soil during heavy rains. Id publishing the above table we desire to call attention to the fact that the fields were not always adjoining and the rate and time of seeding were not always the same. However, where any advantage has existed it has been to the plat not under summer tillage, and we believe that the table as a whole does not overstate the higher yields that may reasonably be expected from the summer tilled land. We consider well cared for sod plowed at the time of the spring rains about equal to summer tilled land. If the yields on the summer tilled land for the four years preceding 1910 are divided by two, on account of the land being used two Reasons to produce one crop, there will still be 3 bushels per acre in favor of the summer tilled land. The </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 summer tilled land produced 6 bushels per acre more than twice that produced on the land not summer tilled. The seed required to produce two crops under ordinary methods of tillage is twice as much as that required to produce one crop on sum - mer tilled land. The labor required to produce the two crops is much more than that required to produce the one crop. I Variety Tests. — Several varieties of winter wheat have been &gt;wn each season during the past six years. Turkey Bed and arkov have kept at the head of the list for first rank in yield, ese two wheats have proved very similar here. The length the growing season and the time of ripening have been prac - illy the same. Turkey Red has given a little larger yield n Kharkov three years out of the four. Kharkov has given ! highest yield but once. However, the behavior of the two 'ieties has been so similar that we consider them practically ' same for this locality, as is shown in the following table 3 also in Table 3. rs 2. — Variety test of winter wheat grown on summer tilled land. • Average of four plats, with different rates of seeding. ie: per acre Variety 1906 1907 1906 1909 1910 Bushels Buthels Bushel* Bushels Bushel* Iey Red ey Red No. 3 ... ey Red No. 287 .... ey Red No. 48 mm*..!!*.'.'.!'.'..*!!!!!! mm!!!!.'!!!!!!!!!!!! 42.3 58.44 45 7 58 14 58.6 56 6 66.9 53 3 57!6 63.3 57.0 39.7 48.98 50.9d 49.39 37.87 52.07 45 89 42.8 33.6* 39.6 31.3* 39 0 29.6 34.8 32^6 336 30.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 I Kate or (Seeding. — Table 3 shows the results obtained daring five years' tests of different rates of seeding winter wheat. This work has all been done on summer tilled land where the condi - tions were favorable for germination. With the conditions less favorable for germination, so that a lower percentage of seed would grow, we probably should find a greater difference be - tween the various amounts of seed. Where the seed bed is well prepared and there is plenty of moisture in the soil, the plants on the plats receiving the thin seeding have stooled sufficiently to make up for any deficiency in the amount of seed. rm 3. — Rate of seeding and comparative yields of Turkey Red and Kharkov tointer wheat. Yield per acre re of seeding per acre TURKEY RKD 1906 1907 Bushels Bushels 5 42.1 58.4 4 40.0 59.7 3 2 42.3 60.2 Average by years | 42.8 59.4 KHARKOV • Average of three years, two of which averaged low Timb of Seeding. — We have not carried on sufficient tests concerning the time of seeding winter wheat to have results from which we can draw definite conclusions. We think, how - ever, that the wheat should be sown before September 15, or sufficiently early to secure a strong growth in the fall. We have not yet seen too much growth in the fall. The following Average 'nsh«U ' Bushel* Bushels Bushels 55.7 42.6 37.1 58.0 40.2 31.1 67.1 42.0 33.5 56.0 38.2 32.7 56.7 40.8 338 47.2 si 58.1 57.0 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '..'..'..'.'.'. ' ia'.i" .yerage by years 58.2 66.9 58.7 59.2 56.3 60.2 39.6 38.6 39.6 34.2 38.0 31.5 31.6 30.9 31.2 31.3 49.0 46.5 Jr </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 table gives rather conflicting data unless one considers the moisture conditions. The seeding on September 14 and Sep - tember 30, 1909, was on summer tilled land as was also all the seeding in 1910. The seeding on September 21. 1909, was on land deficient in moisture. A heavy rain came on October 19, three days before the late seeding date. The rain seems to have favored the latter seeding. The earlier seeding was badly dam - aged by drouth before this rain came. We have had not to exceed two such rains in October during the past 36 years. Therefore this high yield from a late seeding was under very unusual conditions. Table 4. — Time-of-seeding test of winter wheat. Yield in bushels per acre. t Variety Tests. — Experiments have been conducted with a nber of varieties of both soft and durum wheats. Tests have n made of the manner of seeding, the time of seeding, and rate of seeding. We shall not try to explain the different Iding capacity which is shown by the same variety thru various years that the tests have been carried on. These eats, tho they generally give good yields, are not pure varie - i. The following table gives the results of five years' work testing different varieties. The rate of seeding, date of seed - , preparation of the soil, and all the conditions so far as we ild make them were the same for each variety. In the variety t of 1906, spring wheat was grown in a field which had been winter wheat in 1905, and later fall plowed. Since then the *iety tests have been on disked corn land on the bench: EBod land Sept. 21 Yield, bu 36.8* summer tilled land. . Sept. 14 Yield, bu 40.9* summer tilled Sept. 6 Yield, bu 32.4 ' Average of three plata. Oct. 22 40.5* Sept. 30 22.8 Sept. 15 37.1 Oct. 2 Octll 21.2 15.3 SPRING wi HEAT. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 28.6 32.5 27.2 3.5 29.0 30.8 25.5 2 5 31.4 32.2 28.0 3 4 'I 33.0 30.3 26.5 3 5 Velvet Don, durum, hard . . 23.4 Gharnovka, durum, hard. 22.6 Kubanka, durum, hard 18 . 6 18.6 (Rate of Seeding. — Table 6 shows the results obtained from ir years' testing spring wheat at different rates of seeding, e date of seeding, the manner of seeding, and the preparation the land were the same for all of these plats, the only varying :tor being the amount of seed used. * Figures 6, 7, 10, 11, and IS are used by courtesy of Mr. John Cole, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agriculture. F»F1g. 6. Spring wheat, table-land. 1910. Fall plowing. Yield, Plat A, 1910. Spring plowing. 6 bushels per acre. Yield. 6.8 bushels per acre. Table 5. — Variety test of spring tchcats. Yield per acre Var.ety 1906 1907 1908 1909 1910 rBuBhe Is Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Don, durum, hard ... 22.8 28.6 32.5 27.2 3.5 Red wheat, semi-hard 25.4 22.6 28.2 4.1' White wheat, semi-hard 28.0 25.9 29.1 4.4 Local 10.6 23.4 Durum from Hemingford 30. 1 Velyetchaff 31.3 4.6 Kahla 33.6 4.4 No. 2089, durum 8.0 No. 2247, durum 2.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 tl. Spring wheat on summer tilled land, 1909 Yield In 1910 is 2 bushels per acre. Table-land. Table 6. — Yield of spring wheat from different rates of seeding Yield per acre rot seeding of durum spring wheat 1907 1908 1909 1910 Average Pecks Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Time of Seeding. — The results of two years' work in testing the effects of different times of seeding are shown in Table 7. It will probably be noted that in each of these tests we have obtained our highest yield from the earlier seeding. The weather conditions were unfavorable for germination at the time of the second seeding in 1909. Tho the climatic conditions may occa - sionally be favorable or unfavorable to early or late seeding, yet we feel that the earlier seeding will generally be the safer. «3.U 26.4 Ufa. . %I 31 7 24.6 193 2.9 2 9 216 21.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Table 7. — Time-of seeding test of spring wheat. Yield in bushels per acre. r;. 8. Durum wheat (Kahla). Field 2, 1909. Yield, 33.6 bushels per acre. (Correction. — In some copies of this bulletin, Fig. 9, page 21. bears the date 1910. It should read 1909.) t 'Effect of Previous Crop and Tillage. — It will be noted m the average yields given in Table 7 that, while the yields the spring plowed wheat stubble average a little higher than * The data used in compiling Tables 7, 10, and 14 are taken from the rotation and tillage work in Field 41 which is carried on in coopera - tion with the Office of Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry. United States Department of Agriculture. The results of this rotation and tillage work are given in Bulletin 187, Bureau of Plant Industry, 909 Date Yield . April 1 27 9 April 10 21.7 April 20 266 May 3 24 1 910 Date ... Yield . March 17 14.6 March 30 12 0 April 6 2.4 April 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 on the fall plowed, yet during two years the spring plowed land Kave lower yields than the fall plowed. The low yield given for the fall plowed plat in 1909 was due to the grain being badl.v killed by freezing after it was well up. The conditions for ger uiination were not so good in the spring plowed plat as in the fall plowed plat and as a consequence the grain on the former came Fig. 9. Velvet chaff wheat. Field 2, 1909. Yield, 31.3 bushels per acre I very slowly and escaped the freeze. However, it is only in the results of a longer series of years that we shall be able draw dependable conclusions. We note that in every year, epting 1909, summer tilled land gave larger yields than land : summer tilled ; tho only in 1908 and in 1910 was the differ - e sufficient to be considered profitable. The low yield in # from the plat which had been summer tilled was due to same cause that was given for the lower yield in the fall wed plat. This plat was so badly damaged by freezing that </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 I would probably have been best to reseed it. The yield n summer tilled land in 1910 was three times that on land pped in 1909. During the four years 1907-1910, the spring *at on summer tilled land yielded 8.4 bushels more per acre n the average yield from the three other methods of tillage, summer tilled land produced a crop only every second yeiir. Tabu 8. — Effect of previous crop and tillage on the yields of spring wheat. * The yields on the summer tilled plats should be divided by two in order to represent the annual yield. However, there is twice as much seed and much more labor required to produce two crops by ordinary methods of tillage than one crop by summer tillage. OATS. IVaribty Tests. — Table 9 gives the results obtained from ing different varieties of oats since the Substation was rted. It will be noted from this table that no tests are given the year 1907. The variety test of oats was completely lost t season. The spring was cold and dry. A very severe freeze ight the oats at a critical stage and so nearly destroyed them t the field was disked and sown to cane. Two other fields ich were very similar in their manner of preparation were m to oats, the one a few days earlier and the other a few days er; both came thru with a fair stand. Each year these varie - j have been grown in the same field with the same cultivation 1 same rate, date, and manner of seeding, the only varying tor being the variety. Of all the oats tried, the earlier Yield per acre 1907 1908 1909 1910 | Average Bushels Bushels Bushel* Bushel* Bushel* ipring plowed wheat stubble 24.5 'all plowed wheat stubble . . 26 . 0 Naked corn stubble 24 . 9 Summer tillage alternating with wheat 31.8 22.7 23.0 6.8 27.3 15.3 6.6 25.0 15 1 7.3 40.5 ; 18.0 I 18.0 19.3 18.8 "' 27.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">■ Iieties have given uniformly the best results. Of the varieties en, the Burt oat is the earliest and has made a splendid wing against the Kherson. It is probably 2 or 3 days earlier n the Kherson. The oat obtained from Mr. Olson is perhaps ay earlier than the Kherson, but has not given as heavy yield the Kherson. This may be due to the fact that the seed wan te badly mixed. Kherson and Sixty Ihiy oats have averaged tuning about the same time, their average time from seeding harvest being about 95 days. The Texas Red and the Bi&gt;r ar require a few days longer. The other varieties averaged in ltl to 15 days later than the Kherson. The Kherson oat i given the best results during the entire time it has been Table 9. — 'Variety test of oats Yield per acre Variety Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels I Kate of Seeding. — Table 10 gives the results of different rates seeding oats. All conditions were uniform, with the excep - in of the amount of seed used. On the average, we see that G cks have ghrra better results than either a greater or a less lount of seed. 1904 1906 1906 1906 1900 1910 [herson 48.0 20.0 47 0 60.9 40.0 •exaaRed 29.0 43.3 40.7 38.2 iixtyDay 48.0 20 0 47.8 36.0 Hack American. 40 9 37 0 larly White Champion. 38.0 ted Algerian 27.2 34.2 .ocal. 290 24.0 14.0 : lurt 60.7 38.2 iwedish Select 34.1 23.4 liberian White.. 30.6 Hsen's 28.0 tig Pour 30.0 National 26.0 lidooato , » 6 * The variety test in 1907 was destroyed by freezing. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 I The amount of seed required will obviously vary with the ditions of the soil. If the soil is in good condition for ger tation, more of the seed will grow and less seed will be nired than where the soil is not in good condition. Further re, plants will stool more where the conditions are favorable n they will under less favorable circumstances. Fig. 10 Oats. Plat B, 1910. Fall plowing. Yield Plat A, 1910. Spring plowing Yield, 12.2 bushels per acre. 11.8 bushels per acre. Table 10. — Yield of oats from different rates of seeding. Yield per acre Rate of seeding per acre 1907 1908 1909 1910 Average Peck* Bushels j Bushels Bushels ! Bushels Bushels 8 46 1 50.9 73.0 ! 17.0 46.5 6 48.3 71.0 23 0 47.4 4 46.6 42.6 69.6 i 16.9 43 9 2 1 22.5 I 41.6 I 15.2 26.4 Er of Previous Crop and Tillage. — In Table 11 there are ears' results from four different methods of preparing the It will be noted that the lowest average yield is from </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 spring plowed oat stubble, altho during 2 years this method gave better results than either disked corn stubble or fall plowed oat stubble. The table shows that summer tilled land gave a decided increase during 3 years of the test and an average in - crease in yield of almost 10^ bushels per acre over the highest average given by any other method. During the dry season (1910) the yield on summer tilled land was twice that on land cropped in 1909. • See footnote to Table 8, page 22 11. Oats Plat C. Summer tilled, 1909. Yield in 1910, 23.4 bushels ■g. per acre. Fable 11. — Effect of previous crop and tillage on the yield of oats. 1 1 Yield per acre : , ■ : 1907 1908 1900 1910 Average Bushels Bushels I Bushels Bushels Bushels spring plowed oat stubble 30.0 34.4 31.3 12.2 27 0 Disked com stubble 40.6 43.5 22 5 11.8 29 6 plowed oat stubble... 36.0 68.5 24.1 11.8 35.1 Summer tillage alterna- ting with oats 30.0 82.3 46.3 23.4 45.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Growing Crops in Western Nebraska BARLEY. Variety Tests. — From 2 years' further tests with various varieties of barley it would seem that the common 6-rowed barley is the best variety we can grow. This is in accordant with the report made in Bulletin 109. Table 12 gives results &lt; some tests made in 1909 and 1910. These yields are very low. due not alone to the fact that the rainfall has been insufficient, but also to the method of tillage. During both of these years, the barley has been grown as the third consecutive small grain crop on the field. It has entered into a rotation where winter wheat is followed by oats, and the oats followed by barley. This is, even under the most favorable weather conditions, a very poor practice. A cultivated crop, such as corn, sorghum in rows, or potatoes, or summer tillage should come between the small grain crops. Table 12. — Variety test of barley. Yield per acre Variety 1900 1910 Rate op Seeding. — Table 13 gives 4 years' work in testing the different rates of seeding common barley, and 3 years' work for hulless barley. This indicates that seeding 6 pecks of coin mon barley per acre has given better results than either more or less seed, tho other rates of seeding have given much better results during some years. Four pecks seems to be the best 1 I I I t ft V W II I ' 1 1 \.\f IHJ\JU 1 1 II I I "P*C* I M I I I " V . [anchurian 19.2 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Table 13. — Yield of barley from different rates of seeding. The Effect of Previous Cbop and Tillage. — Table 14 gives the results of growing barley on ground prepared by four differ ent methods, namely : spring plowed barley stubble, disked corn stubble, fall plowed barley stubble, and summer tilled land. Some advantage is shown in the table by fall plowed barley stubble over spring plowed. Either of these methods has given better returns than disked corn stubble. It is a question, how ever, if the average increase from plowing has paid for the extra amount of labor. The results for 1909 show a very low yield on fall plowed barley stubble, and a very little increase on summer tillage over either spring plowing or disked corn land. The freeze that so seriously affected the wheat plats before mentioned badly damaged barley on the fall plowed plat and the summer tilled plat. The conditions for germination were good on both of these plats. The seed germinated quickly, and as a conse - quence the young plants were caught by the freeze at a critical time, while the barley on the spring plowed land and disked corn stubble came up more slowly and the injury was decidedly less. The land summer tilled in 1906 did not give any increased yield in 1907 over the land cropped every year. The average increase in yield for the four years due to summer tilling is 15.4 bushels per acre above the average yield from the other three methods, or 12.5 bushels per acre above the best of the other three methods. This was probably enough to make the summer tilling \ r i . Rate of seeding R . d per acre 1907 Bushels Yield per acre 1906~~ 1909 ~ 1910 Bushels Bushels Bushels m Bushel* Common Common Common Common Hulless Hulless Hulless 40.8 40.1 38.1 34.9 21.9 21.8 18.6 2b.2 17.2 7.4 27 0 19 6 66 23.5 16 0 ; 8.1 17.7 16.8 8.5 12.0 3.5 12.3 4.3 113 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 rl4. — Effect of previous crop and tillage on the yields of barley. Yield p«r acre 1907 1906 1909 1910 Arerage Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Spring plowed barley 39.0 19.6 21.5 13.7 23. ft Disked com land 30.6 . 24.9 21.5 7.9 21.2 Fall plowed barley stubble 40 . 0 'Barley alternating with 43.3 10. 4D 12.5 26.6 summer tillage 39.0 I 67.7 j 23.8!! [ 26 0 39.1 • See footnote to Table 8, page 22. Fig. 12 Barley. Plat A, 1910. Spring plowing. Yield, 13.7 bushels per acre. Plat B, 1910. Fall plowing. Yield, 12.5 bushels per acre. SPRING EMMER. Spring emmer has been grown at the Station as a grain feed each season since the Station was started. It makes a very good feed, and can be fed to horses without grinding. When fed to hogs it should be ground. In an experiment in fattening hogs, where all the feed was ground and alfalfa hay was supplied, one bushel of corn was equal to 1.83 bushels of emmov. &lt;ind one </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 bushel of barley was equal to 1.26 bushels of emmer Stated in pounds, one pound of corn was equal to 1.3 pounds of emmer, and one pound of barley was equal to 1.2 pounds of emmer. It has not yielded as many pounds of grain per acre au common barley or durum wheat, as is shown by Table 17. tl3. Barley on summer tilled land. Plat D, 1910. Yield, 26.0 bushels per acre. The winter emmer so far as we have tested it has not proved hardy for this section. Two very fair crops were harvested in 1907 and 1908, but since then it has not withstood the winter sufficiently to warrant growing it. Rate of Seeding. — The crop of 1907 was on corn land, twice double disked in the spring. The crop of 1908 was on land which had been in rowed cane, and cultivated. The land was double disked in the spring. The crop of 1909 was grown on land which had been in oats the previous year, and was double disked twice in the spring. The table shows that seeding 6 pecks per acre has given the highest yield of any rate of seeding each </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Table 15. — Yield of emmer from different rates of seeding. Yield per acre* Rate of seeding per acre 1906 1907 1906 1909 Average Peck* Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels BusheU * 40 pounds considered a bushel. BROADCASTING COMPARED WITH DRILLING SMALL GRAIN. During the past three years, tests have been conducted to determine the comparative yields obtained from seeding Final I grain by the old method of sowing broadcast and harrowing, and by sowing with the press drill. All conditions were identi - cal for the plats being compared, excepting the manner of seed ing. During each season the grain was sown on corn stubble prepared by disking. The average results of the three seasons, as shown in Table 16, indicate that drilling increased the yield of spring wheat 7.4 bushels per acre, of barley 7.7 bushels per acre, of oats 10.7 bushels per acre, and of emmer 10.8 bushels per acre. Or, drilling increased the revenue $3.57 per acre, considering wheat worth 70 cents, barley 45 cents, oats 35 cents and emmer 30 cents per bushel. According to these results, the increase in the value of 20 acres of small grain planted with a drill over the same area sown broadcast and covered with the harrow would pay for a $75.00 press drill. The results from the tests with winter wheat are not given in the table. There lias not been any winter wheat sown broadcast that has mad&lt;* a crop, while the yields from drilling have been from 20 to 60 bushels per acre. =§=§= 23 5 27.8 23.0 42.9 45.4 35.8 25.1 52.5 52 6 50.8 44 3 33.2 36.6 33.fi 34.2 38.0 38.1 35.8 345 i • </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Growing Crops in Western Nebraska 31 compared with drilling small grain. Table 16. — Broadcasting Yield per acre Method of seeding Crop Year Increase from drilling Broadcast Drilled Hushels Ruthels Bushel* . 1908 Spring wheat ' 1909 20.0 17.0 29.6 9.6 10.2 27.2 / 1910 Failure 2.4 2 4 27.7 17.7 i 1906 iono 17.7 8.8 10.0 Barley \ 1909 1910 8.9 7.4 3.3 4.1 60.6 52.5 1.9 40.0 68.2 28.2 16 3 18.2 1.9 ( 1906 - 1909 { 1910 46.2 52.6 6.4 Emmer 22.0 40.6 18.6 17.2 24 6 7.4 RELATIVE YIELDS OF SPRING GRAINS. For four years, carefully conducted tests have been made to determine the relative yields of the several spring small grains. During each season this test has been on disked corn stubble. The seed has been sown with a press drill on well prepared land. The yield is given in pounds as the number of pounds produced indicates much more nearly the feeding value than the number of bushels. Any of these grains may be fed to any farm stock, but the hulless grains will produce much the best results when fed to hogs. Emmer is a good substitute for oats as horse or calf feed. Wheat has a feeding value about 10 per cent higher than corn per pound. It is probable that the relative feeding value per pound of these grains does not vary greatly if the hull is ex eluded. The results indicate that durum wheat and barley pro - duce more feed per acre than either of the other grains. ( 1908 Oatt ] 1909 { 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 (fTOWtflQ L/T0f)8 ifl W CStd'ti A (sbVOSICQ rant 17 — Comparison of yields of oats, barley, hulless barley, emmer, and durum wheat, grown under similar conditions. CORN. Vakibty Tests. — Variety tests have been conducted during the past six years. The number of varieties or strains grown each year has ranged from 10 to 35. The variation in yield has been from almost a failure to 52 bushels per acre. The rank of the varieties that have been grown each year has not been the same for all years but each season the Substation calico, which is a medium-sized corn, has been among the leading varieties and, on the average, may be considered one of the best. There is no other variety that has proved its superior. From all the results of these tests it seems evident that the varieties which have been grown in the western part of the state for several years and properly selected are superior to those brought in from places having different climatic conditions. I he average yield from the eight varieties yielding the most l season has been as follows: 1905, 37.2 bushels per acre; 5, 48.5 bushels; 1907, 32 bushels; 1908, 31.6 bushels; 1909, bushels, and 1910, 17.3 bushels per acre. The yield of 1909 very low owing to the poor stand obtained by listing. Two s in the same field with the variety test, that were surface ited and had a good stand, gave an averge of 38 bushels per ». The variety test of 1910 was on fall plowed land following ter wheat. The varieties were planted with a lister. They e in Field 5. Field 4, adjoining Field 5, was in cane in 1909. stubble was manured and disked in the spring of 1910 and Yield per acre Crop 1907 1906 1909 1910 Average I Average Average Pounds Iheraon oats 1442 ommon barley . . . 2226 [ulless barley 1436 Imrner 1718 &gt;urum wheat | 1788 Pounds Pound* Pound* Pound* 2044 960 500 1237 2284 1390 886 1697 1658 870 454 1105 2024 1026 828 1399 1772 1192 876 1407 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Grouting Crops in Western Nebraska 33 then listed to corn. The stand was very poor, which was favor able to a good yield in a very dry season. The average yield from Field 4 was 25 bushels per acre, or about 7 bushels more than in Field 5. The variety tests have been on the bench land each season. I Manner of Seeding. — The results of planting corn with a er and with a surface planter are given in Table 18. These s have all been on fall plowed land. Three years out of four e decided results in favor of planting with the lister; the rth year was very much in favor of the surface planting but i was on account of a good stand having been secured by the Dter while a very poor stand was obtained by the lister. A nt of the stalks on the plats showed that the surface planted n had 1,894 stalks to 1,141 of the listed corn. Table 18. — Listing versus surface planting corn. Yield per acre Years Surface T . .. Increase Increase Dlantinc- Ll8tln 8 from from surface planting x planting Hushel* Buthels Buthelt \ Bu thelt I Effect of Previous Crop and Manner of Preparing Sibd d. — During the past four years, careful tests have been made compare the yields of corn on spring plowed corn stubble, fall wed corn stubble, spring plowed small grain stubble, fall ■wed small grain stubble and land summer tilled each alter - :e season. The' corn was planted with a lister. The results ! given in Table 19. The averages of the four years show that these five methods corn following corn on spring plowing has en the highest yields. It was outranked slightly in 1909 by 1 plowing, but no other method, except summer tillage in 1910, lEiiiiiii: 11/ . U 20.7 38.2 16.3 26.7 29.1 24.8 O.O 6.0 "sis JU </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 I a higher yield during any year. A four-year record is fur i being conclusive, and therefore these results, like many r results in this bulletin, should not be considered as final in sense. The yield secured in 1910 should be given special no - as this is the only very dry year in this test. During this an the yield from summer tillage was about four times as ti as the average yield of the other four methods. While wp thought that summer tillage for corn could not be a profit practice, yet the results of this season make it seem profit where it is especially desirable to grow some corn under dry conditions. This work is on Field 41 on the high table, yields of corn should not be compared with yields on Fields d 5 mentioned on pages 32 and 33. rl9. — Effect of previous crop and manner of preparing seeil bed for corn. t Results from one plat only FORAGE CROPS. CANE. I Cane (sorghum) is the most satisfactory annual forage crop t is grown in western Nebraska. It will yield much re on the average than any millet grown, and is a more sat- Yield per ac: 1907 Hushels 1908 1900 1910 Average Bushels Kushels BuaheU El following corn on spring plowing l following corn on fall plowing I following spring grain on spring plowing ! ] following spring grain on fall plowing j i alternating with sum- mer tillage^^^^^^^ t28.7 t27.7 •19.9 •19. 1 t!7.9 38.6 24.6 24.0 29.0 31.6 25.8 8.9 6.2 4.6 ... ... l8 . 27.1 26 1 2.6 18 ., 38.2 25.0 21.9 .. •At&lt; of 9 &gt;lats. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 isfactory forage. It is a good feed for horses or cattle, and is the only forage that many horses on the table-land get during the working season. The only objection is that, like prairie hay. brome grass, and timothy, it is a carbohydrate food and contains only a small percentage of protein. As corn is the principal grain fed to horses, cane docs not tend to balance the ration. Where there is no alfalfa to mix with the cane, it would he well to feed some emmer. oats, wheat, or barley with the corn. The feeding value* of cane may be placed fully equal to prairie hay. other than wheat grass. Cane gives a large tonnage per acre under favorable circuit) stances and will make probably as large tonnage as any other annual under conditions of drouth, unless it be Kafir, which is possibly more drouth resistant than cane. During the past six seasons, cane sown broadcast with a drill on the Substation farm has given an average yield per acre of about five tons. The weights were taken during the winter and probably represent more moisture than weights on cane stacked for some time, yet on these weights it has given better results than prairie hay when fed to cattle. The chief objection to growing cane is that at some stages of growth it is liable to be very poisonous to cattle, killing them quickly. There is more danger of poisoning when the growth is stimted by drouth. A very small quantity will kill a cow. The only safe method is to keep the cattle away from it. This poisonous quality disappears when the cane is made into hay. The cane hay is never poisonous. Cane may be drilled thickly or sown in rows and cultivated. The thick seeding with a press drill has given larger yields than seeding in rows, and the forage has been better because the stems were mnch smaller and consequently there was a much less per - centage of waste. Tf drilled thickly and a good stand is secured, there will be little if any seed. By sowing in rows, a crop of for - age and also a Top of seed may be grown. Tf the stand is thin * See Bulletins 106 and 117. this Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 enough to allow a fair production of seed, the stalks will be too coarse for good forage. If the stand is thick enough to produce go&lt;»d forage, there will be but little seed produced. Besides, to get the best forage, the cane should be cut before it ripens, prob - ably when the earliest heads begin to ripen. If let stand longer, the stems become more woody. For these reasons, we advise sowing two fields, one for seed and one for forage. The best rate of seeding for forage can not always be deter mined, as it will depend to some extent on the season. When seeding broadcast with a drill, from four to eight pecks per acre should be sown. The heavier the seeding, the better will be the quality of the forage, providing there is moisture enough to ma - ture it. The yields from the different rates of seeding in 1908 were larger from eight pecks per acre than from six or four pecks. We usually sow at least five pecks per acre. During tests of four seasons, seeding with a drill gave higher yields than by any other method tried. However, during a season so dry that cane sown as grain would not make any yield, that sown in rows and cultivated might give fair returns. Listing should give good results if a thick stand is obtained, but this is usually difficult, as the cane grows slowly when young and is often covered by the soil being washed over it before it is out of the furrows. W T hen planting cane for forage with a lister the corn plate should be used, allowing the grain to be seeded thickly. It can be drilled into rows quite successfully by using a grain drill in which enough holeR are closed to allow the drill to sow rows at the proper distance apart for cultivating. Where we have allowed the drill to seed a pair of rows together, instead of one row, we have secured a heavier yield of cane, but usually leas of Kafir. When seeding in single rows the drill has been run at 3, 5 and 7 pecks per acre. The heaviest seeding gave the heaviest yield. When planting for seed alone, we think it would be advisable to seed in single rows, setting the drill at four pecks or less per acre. Less seed mav srive better results. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 t Excellent results have been obtained by seeding on new land, ken in the spring. The sod was broken in April and the early part of May. The sod was cut up with a sharp weighted disk. This required from two to three double diskings. The seed wa* sown with a press drill from May 15 to June 15. The yield dur ing four seasons (1904 to 1907 inclusive) was never less than four tons per acre. It is customary to plant about ten days later than corn, but even later seeding may be better, as the ground will be warmer and the cane start more quickly. There is an ad vantage in having it mature rather late in the fall, as in that case it usually will not be cut until after the fall rains. Table 20. — Yield in tons per acre of cane sown broadcast trith Kafir is a very good forage, probiibly fully as valuable per ton as cane. It is usually grown in rows, tho it does well seeded thickly. The chief objection to raising it is that it does not mature seed this far north and the seed shipped in is often low in its germinating power. It is hoped that the date of maturing may become earlier when it is selected with this purpose in view, but thus far there ha« been but little Kafir seed produced on the Substation farm. MILO. Milo has been grown in tests with cane and Kafir, but does not have nearly the feeding value of either of the other two. The seed, however, is valuable as a grain for feeding stock. This character of the plant is being developed with the idea that it may take the place of corn in the extreme western part of the state. press dr*\ .11. i 1906 4.50* 1906 4.60* 1907 6.50* _J 1906 5 33 1909 4.37 1910 3.5 • Estimated. KAFIR. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Fig. 14. Milo, on table-land, 1909 BHOME GRASS. Several grasses have been sown, but none promise as satisfy' lor.v returns as brome grass (Bromns inertiiix). It is difficult to estimate the value of this grass. Tt has been thought that it might supplant the native grasses, taking their place on the ims ture lands. This does not seem likely to occur. It is doubtful if it will be profitable to break native grass for the purpose of seeding it to brome grass for hay or pasture. Brome grass will ■rvt, however, where a grass is desired in a rotation. A hwivv sod of brome grass can be secured on a tilled field with but little difficulty when there is sufficient moisture. So far as we know, it is the only grass that will make a |&gt;ermanent cod when see&lt;1r&lt;! on tilled land in western Nebraska. LFor the first few years after seeding, it may grow thre»- or r feet tall and furnish from one and a half to three tons of </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Iisi v or '{00 to 400 pounds of seed per acre and considerable pas hire. After the sod has become dense the upward growth will Ik* less. This will lessen the production of bay and seed. How fver. the undergrowth will be thick and heavy. As long as there is moisture in the soil, the nroine grass will furnish excellent pasture, but it will not keep free* unless there is sufficient inois lure in the soil. It will probably furnish considerably more pas - ture than the native grass when there is an abundance of mois tare, as it grows rapidly and would naturally produce much more forage thaii the native grasses before reaching maturity. But there is no evidence to show that it will produce more for - age than the native grasses during a period of drouth. Any kind of grass can use only the moisture available and then lie dormant until moisture conies again. The brome grass will re spond very vigorously and quickly when moisture is supplied by rain, but when this moisture is exhausted it will again become dormant until moisture is again available. It has a much longer growing season than the native grasses, beginning early in the spring and continuing late in the fall. This habit, together with its ability to form and maintain a dense sod. gives it a permanent place among the forage crops in western Nebraska. tV thick stand of brome grass is often difficult to secure. The f difficulty is to get it started — the seed germinated and rooted. After it is well rooted it is almost certain to give a thick or fair stand with sufficient moisture. Weeds are the chief dan - ger. They should be kept mowed close to the ground. It matters little whether the grass seed is sown in the late spring or in the fall. If it can be sown during a rainy period in the latter part of August, it will have an advantage over a seeding made in May Ir June, in that it will not have to contend with the weeds. It i customary to sow 20 pounds of seed per acre, sowing it by and and harrowing it in. The main requirement is a proper seed bed. The tillage of the soil is discussed elsewhere in this bulletin. Brome grass requires a seed bed that is flmi. as well as deep, moist, and fine. It will pay well to firm the noil with a </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Growing Crops in Western Nebraska Iurface packer, and may even pay to roll the field. The sur as well as the subsoil must be firm if a stand is to be an i. All grass seeds germinate much better if sown when they receive the benefit of frequent rains while small, allowing i to get their roots down into the deeper soil where perma - moisture is available. Where a pasture is desired, a mix of 15 pounds brome grass and Id pounds alfalfa is said to excellent results. During the season of 1910, the broiue &amp; made but little growth. It produced some pasture but no It probably did not produce as good pasture as the buffalo grama grasses. ALFALFA.* I This is the most valuable forage crop that can be grown in the leys. There is some question as to the profit in raising it on le-land. But where the farmer on the table can not easily alfalfa from the valleys, we believe it will pay him to grow le for pasture for hogs, feed for hogs in the winter, and for for colts and calves. Under the conditions existing on it farms, a ton of good bright alfalfa is worth about the le as a ton of bran or shorts, possibly more, — that is, when fed h the right proportion of corn to hogs, or of corn fodder, e, straw, or native hay to cattle or horses. There is but little doubt that alfalfa will live thru any period of drouth that we are likely to get, after it is well set and rooted. The growth that it will make will depend on the available moisture. When there is sufficient moisture it will make a rapid growth, but as the moisture becomes scarce it will cease to grow and will lie dormant until rain comes again. It is quite likely to give a fair crop from the moisture accumulated during the winter and from the spring rainfall. After the first cutting it may make but very little growth for some time, but * For results of feeding alfalfa to cattle, see Bulletins 106 and 117. For results of feeding alfalfa to hogs, see Bulletin 99 and one that will be published about March, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Growtng Crops in Western \ebraska 41 when the rain comes it will make the best possible use of the moisture. 1 Hiring the five years from 1905 to 1909, we cut at least two crops of two-thirds to one ton per cutting each season on table-land. During the season of 1908, with about a normal rainfall and with no surplus moisture in the soil at the begin uing of the year, a 7^-acre field on the table- land gave an aver - age yield per acre of LtS tons of good hay at two cuttings. The hay was weighed as it was drawn to the stack. In the lower part of the field, which received the surplus water from the higher parts, the yield has been much more. However, during 1910 there was not sufficient alfalfa to pay for cutting excepting in low parts of the field. There was some growth on all the field. This would have afforded considerable pasture for hogs, and might have been profitable in that way on the average farm. During a season when corn, wheat, and oats will give a ton of grain per acre, alfalfa will surely yield much more than a ton of hay — probably two tons. The cost of growing the alfalfa after a stand is secured will be much less than the cost of growing grain. We would recommend that every farmer sow several acres of alfalfa on the best land he has, preferably in a valley surrounded by hills. iln most of the valley lands, where the sheet water is not more n thirty feet below the surface, alfalfa does well, giving from ee to four cuttings of a ton or more each, per season. There 62 acres of alfalfa on the bench land that were sown in 1902. s acreage includes the feeding places and ground covered bv ; sheds. This land is from 20 to 30 feet above sheet water ;re are also ten acres on slightly higher land sown at a later e on new land. These fields have been pastured only lightly I the yield has been light. Twenty-eight acres of the 62 have been pastured by hogs. We keep about 45 brood sows and raise about 275 pigs. The prac - tice is to feed medium or light grain rations, so as to get the largest profit possible from the alfalfa. In 1908 and 1909, 13.3 acres of the remainder of the field was pastured by horses. There w^ere only a few tons of alfalfa cut in the field thus pastured. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 I The yield of alfalfa on the 62 acres for the years 1908, 1909 I 1910 was practically the same, being 157 tons, or 2.5 tons acre. The yield in 1910 from Field 34, which has never been tured, was 2.79 tons per acre ; from the 28 acres in which the fl pastured, 2.59 tons per acre ; and on Field 35, which we pas - ed by horses in 1908 and 1909, 2.63 tons per acre. The horses ed two or three acres in the field. There were two mares I colts in the field during a large part of the season of 1910. i yield in 1908 and 1909 was probably about 4 tons per acre the field not pastured, as against 2$ tons per acre in 1910. t Table 21 gives the results of a test of regional varieties on ch land. This alfalfa was sown in 1905. The weights of first and third crops of 1906 were not taken. The crops were h fully equal to the second cutting and are entered at that in j table. The alfalfa was cut four times each season except 8, when it was cut three times. The fourth cutting in 1910 is included in these figures. It amounted to one-half ton per e. The weights are probably heavier than if the alfalfa had n stacked and weighed some months later. They are of the Ufa in the cock, field dry and ready to be put into the mow. It is probable that a reduction of about 20 per cent to repre - sent shrinkage in the mow or stack should be made from these </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Taiile 21. — Relation of the source of seed to yield. Alfalfa plat* of one-tenth acre area on bench land. Seed furnished by the United States Department of Agriculture. Yield per acre Regional variety I At ■ rveKiunai variety at. 1906 1907 1908 1909 I 1910 for I pa. Ton* Ton* Tons Tona Ton* Tons 1 Montana 3 47 4.65 5.21 7.15 4.17 5.28 2 Nebraska 4.65 7.08 5.26 8.15 4.42 5 91 3 Kansas 3 34 6 85 5.44 7.89 4 62 5.63 4 Colorado 3 52 6.74 5.67 7.35 4.32 5 52 5 Utah non-irrigated 2.90 6 50 4.89 7.05 3 20 4.91 6 Utah irrigated 2.69 6.37 4.74 6.97 4.20 4. 99 IKJ W»U 111 1KIIUOU — ■ V»*/ W.'M -x . ■ ■* \r ■ v w -« . **\S ■» . W9W Molock, Texas 3 46 6 64 5 20 7.33 3.75 5.25 8 Sherman, Texas 3.13 6.12 4.81 7.03 3.97 5.15 9 Germany 3 14 5 83 4.83 6.87 5.15 ' 5.16 11 Poiton, France 3.60 6.36 475 6.90 5.22 5.36 Province, France 3.92 5.47 4 48 6.51 4.87 5.07 13 Italy 3.77 5.76 4 56 595 4.65 4 94 (Peru, S. A Winter killed Afghanistan 3.46 6.40 5.03 7.14 5.30 5.46 Turkestan 3.05 6.18 4.65 6.87 5.62 5.25 Commercial 3 03 5.89 4.71 6.34 4.05 4.80 Minnesota 2 74 6.60 I 4.67 7.58 6.25 5.56 Winter killed 2 74 6.60 i 4.67 7.58 6.25 5.55 19 I Local inoculated 3.18 .5.90 14.73 8.78 6.17 5 75 These figures show that under conditions that have prevailed here during the past six seasons no one regional variety has shown any great superiority over others. Nebraska-grown seed has produced the most alfalfa. The varieties behave differently as regards freezing and recovery after cutting, but. as noted, the yields thus far have been quite uniform. Alfalfa should be sown on good soil. The field should have l»een well tilled previously and should be free from weed seed. The best condition of the soil is that given by summer tillage. If one can not sow on summer tilled land, the next best place is on land that has been in com and well tilled. The field should In- doubled disked early in the spring and every week or two until a favorable time in May or June, when the seed should be sown at the rate of about 15 pounds per acre and harrowed in. The </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 I tow should be used frequently before seeding, in order that ■ seed bed shall be firm when the seed is sown. It is unsafe to &gt;w the land shortly before seeding, as the soil must be firm or ■ seeding will likely be a failure. If a field which has produced all grain is to be seeded to alfalfa, it should be fall plowed as ?p as possible and given the same treatment in the spring as cornstalk land. A nurse crop should not be used on dry land, my farmers sow with a drill with good results, but the seed ist be sown as shallow as possible. I Securing a stand on sandy land seems to be more difficult than hard soil. This is due probably to lack of knowledge as to the •per way to sow it. There are many profitable fields growing the sand hill region on land that is quite sandy. The extreme it generated on the sand during the warm summer days seems kill the very young alfalfa plants even tho there is isture in the soil. It may be best to seed the sandy land early the spring and to permit some weeds to grow with the alfalfa, ere should be manure or stubble on the surface of sandy 'and prevent blowing. I The alfalfa should not be cut close to the ground the first sea - unless it has begun to bloom. The mower should be run r the field a few times during the season with the sickle set h if weeds are bad, otherwise the alfalfa should not be mowed ess it has made sufficient growth to bloom. Pasturing dur the first season, or close pasturing at any time, is very in - ious. Pasturing it short during the fall or winter is especially nrious. The more growth left on the ground during the win - , the more vigorous will be the growth the spring following. Alfalfa should be cut each time just as it comes into bloom, and cut very close to the surface of the ground. If seed is to be produced, the second crop should be allowed to stand for this purpose, on the bench land, or the first crop on the table land. Some farmers in the western part of the state are having good results from growing alfalfa seed on table land. Some growers advocate sowing alfalfa in rows and cultivating it. This method </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 has much in its favor in very dry regions, as the moisture condi tions can be controlled to a large extent by cultivation. The re - duction of the number of plants growing on a given area makes more moisture available for each plant. We believe more atten - tion should be given to seed production, as it promises very profitable returns, especially on land too dry for heavy yields of METHODS OF TILLAGE Handling New Land. — The experience of the old settlers has shown that the sod brakes while the grass is growing rots more quickly than that broken in the early spring. Sod broken late in the summer or in the fall is likely to lack sufficient moisture to promote the rotting. The best time to break is from May 15 to June 15. This period may be extended either way fifteen days, when the conditions are favorable, with prac tically as good results. Breaking done in April is very likely to become quite weedy and the grass may grow again. How ever, if the sod is cultivated sufficiently during the summer to keep the weeds and grass from growing, it will be in good condition to produce a crop. If the field is to be planted to spring grain, then it is necessary to break in March or earlv in April. Where corn is to be planted without disking the sod. the breaking should be done immediately before planting. The ground to be planted to winter grain may be broken at any time before July 15 if it is cultivated and there is sufficient moisture after the sod is turned to insure a moist seed bed. The proper depth to break is about 3 inches. Sod broken to this depth can be thoroly pulverized with a disk and rots much more quickly than deeply broken sod. Where the sod is not cut thru with the disk, there is some danger of hav - ing a mulch established by the grass turned under. This may prevent the plants that germinate in the furrow slice from get - ting firmly rooted in the subsoil. The furrow should be pul verized so that it forms a close connection with the soil beneath. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 It is probable that the winterkilling of alfalfa on sod is largely due to the lack of such connection. Which crop to sow on breaking depends partly on the immediate need of the one interested. If he be the homesteader or the settler who has but little surplus to work with, then it may be necessary to sow some spring small grain on sod. With a favorable season there may be a fair crop, but under ordinary conditions the crop will not be very profitable. In fact we would expect failure more often than a fair return for the cost. Flax often gives good returns when the season is favor - able. As it is sown much later than the spring grains, there may be a period of tillage before seeding the flax, and moisture may be accumulated. Corn is easily planted on sod and may make a fair crop without any cultivation. However, it is be - coming the custom among the better farmers to disk the sod before planting the corn and to harrow and cultivate as the corn grows. It is probably wise for the man who has limited means to plant some corn on sod. It is certainly wise to sow Horghum for forage. The sod should be disked thoroly ami the seed planted with a press drill at about 6 pecks per acre. The yield will be greater if the sod is broken and tilled a few weeks before sowing the cane. Alfalfa may be sown on well prepared sod with good success. Securing a good stand on sod is more certain than on old ground. However, the stand will not be so permanent, as the wild grass will come in again more quickly than when the field has been well tilled for several years. Ten to 15 pounds of seed per acre is sufficient to sow. The man with limited means should retain the main portion of the breaking for winter wheat and the man who has more capital should save all the sod for winter wheat. We are thoroly convinced that, on the average, sod properly planted to winter wheat will give a greater net return than if handled in any other manner. If the seasons are too dry to produce a profitable crop of winter wheat planted on sod, there will </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 I: be any other profitable crops produced. If the seasons are t, then the winter wheat will yield sufficiently more to make the most profitable. The probability is. however, that the sons will be such ;is to give very small yields of the other crops, but a yield of twenty bushels or more of winter wheat. The sod may he broken from April 15 to July 1. or later if sufficient rain follows, ft must be kept free from weeds and should be disked thoroly. Double disking twice and har rowing twice usually puts the breaking in excellent condition. The seed should be put in during the first half of September with a press drill. Ktiox ok Crops.- -After the first crop has been harvested. Is should be brought into a definite rotation as soon ble. The rotation should be planned so that a part of the farm will be summer tilled each year and so that an inter-tilled croj»- like corn or potatoes — will be grown between the crops of small grain. Provision should also be made for keeping tip the fertility. Efeel safe in recommending summer tillage for small es|&gt;ecially winter wheat, but advise that a rotation be J d which will keep up the organic matter in the soil and conserve its fertility. Such a rotation will probably use sum mer tillage on the same field only once during a series of years, and will have a grass, legume, or some green manuring crop which will put back into the soil the organic material taken from it. Where sufficient barnyard manure is to Ik- had. an application of it once during the rotation will prohablv keep up the humus and conserve the fertility of the soil. Where manure is used, it should be applied as evenly as possible on the land, and disked to mix it with the surface. It should be applied at a time and in such a manner as to he a benefit rather than a harm to the succeeding crop. From our experience, we cannot lay down a definite rota tiou for all conditions. The rotations must be worked out to </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 It the farms where they are to be practiced. The proportion the land that should be summer tilled will depend on the ount of precipitation. It may be that it will be profitable summer till one-half of the land each year in the extreme rtern part of the state, and to produce crops only on summer ed land. However, we are inclined to think that summer ing one-third or one-fourth of the farm may give better re - ts. Where one-fourth of the land is to be summer tilled h year, the rotation probably will be summer tillage, winter eat, an inter-tilled crop — corn, milo, potatoes, etc— and ing grain or forage. I A. rotation that seems well adapted to our conditions is follows: Summer tillage, winter wheat, corn, spring grain, e. Summer till and sow winter wheat; disk and fall plow wheat stubble for corn the next year; apply manure during winter, disk the corn stubble for a spring grain— oats, wheat, barley ; disk in spring and plow for cane, which crop com - tes the rotation. To practice this rotation a farm should e at least five fields. This five-year rotation gives winter pat on summer tilled land to be sold as a cash crop, corn I spring grain to be fed or sold according to conditions, and le for forage. If the forage and grains are fed, there will enough manure to apply in the rotation, covering one-flfth the land each year. SUMMER TILLAGE. I By summer tillage we mean the practice of cultivating the an entire season or a large part of the season without a p in order to accumulate the moisture and produce the con - ion in the soil which will force the growth of the crop when nted. In the extremely dry regions this means cultivating land one year to grow a crop the next year. In central I western Nebraska this is equally true except where winter sat or other fall grain is sown, or where grasses are sown the fall, after a period of summer tillage. Where a </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 crop is sown in the fall, the land will have been under thoro tillage from spring until the sowing of the crop in September. Summer tillage differs from the old practice of summer fallow in this, that the old system frequently was to plow the land in July and let it lie bare without working it until near the time for sowing wheat in September, when the land would be put in good condition unless it had been overrun by weeds or become cloddy from excessive drouth. Even the best system of sum mer fallow in the Eastern States did not give so much attention to the accumulation of water in the soil as is done at the present time nnder the hest system of summer tillage. Tn the dry farming region the practice of summer tillnge is followed primarily in order to store water in the soil, and secondly to secure a good seed bed. and to accumulate plant food by securing conditions favorable to the breaking down of humus and the accumulation of nitrates in the soil. The land must be kept thoroly cultivated to kill the weeds and to retain the surface mulch which checks the evaporation and holds the water which accumulates from the rains until it is needed for the use of the crop. In summer tillage the weeds must be kept down, since the growing of a crop of weeds draws heavily upon the supply of water and largely defeats the purpose of summer tillage. Summer Tillage for Winter Wheat. — We recommend sum mer tillage for winter wheat under North Platte conditions nn hesitatingly and we believe that it is even more essential to success farther west. How far east of North Platte it will prove profitable we ilo not presume to know. However, we would advise farmers, anywhere that the rainfall is deficient, to experiment with a ten-acre field, giving it a thoro test. The results to date with spring sown crops do not show that summer tilling is profitable, but neither do they tend to discourage its practice. The winds during the winter and early spring are very unfavorable to summer tilling for spring grain. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Ghrotoing Crops in Western Nebraska Eever, in regions of much less rainfall it is reasonable tc uine that the storing of moisture before sowing any crop be more profitable than to sow without any moisture in •ve. How to Simmer Till. — In central western Nebraska, land which has been in stubble and is to be summer tilled the follow ing year should be thoroly double disked as soon as possible after the grain has been harvested. When there is a consider - ■Me amount of water in the soil this treatment will loosen the surface and prevent the loss of water by evaporation. It will also serve to hold any rain that may come in the fall. Usually the disking will also destroy the weeds that grow on the stubble field after the grain has been cut. When the soil is very dry at harvest time and the weather continues dry thruout the fsili. there may not be any benefit from disking in the fall. Karly in the spring, as soon as the frost is out of the ground, the field should be again double disked. Then the surface should In- kopt lease and the weeds kept down with the disk and the harrow until June, when the land should be plowed eight inches deep. This gives ideal conditions for catching the water which falls, and by proper cultivation to restore the soil mulch the soil becomes a reservoir in which the moisture will be amnnii luted for future use. If this treatment is followed it will be found that the land when plowed contains an abundance of moisture, and that with ordinary rains this moisture penetrates deej&gt;er and deeper into the soil with each successive rain. From plowing until seeding time the weeds must be kept down and the surface loose with the harrow and with the disk. The layer of loose soil on the surface forms a mulch, which protects the moist soil beneath from loss of water by evaporation. It also allows the air readily to pass into the soil and aid in the liberation of plant food. The mulch on the surface should be kept loose and dry. but the granular structure of the soil should if possible be retained. If the soil is pulverized to a fine dust </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 it may blow away or it may pack so firmly as to need frequent cultivation in order to restore the mulch. It is not practicable to summer till soil which blows readily, as the frequent high winds in the region will cause the soil to drift. The depth of cultivation or of the mulch depends much on the type of soil. A fine, heavy soil requires a deeper mulch than a coarse-grained soil, as the finer soils have greater capil lary power and are more difficult to keep loose and open. Deep cultivation may be less frequent tlian where shallow cultivation is used. If we keep a thick mulch it will require more water to destroy the mulch and connect with the water below. A shallow mulch is less serviceable and more readily destroyed l&gt;y light showers. We have found it almost impossible to keep the weeds down and retain a mulch with an ordinary spike tooth harrow and it has been necessary to alternate be - tween the harrow and the disk in order to keep the field clean. A mulch of three or four inches is more effective and can 1m&gt; retained with less labor than one which is but half as deep. The frequency of cultivation dej&gt;euds also em the type of soil and the frequency of the rain. Cultivation should always follow a rain that is heavy enough to wet thru the mnlch and destroy it. A shower packs the particles of the surface soil close together, washing the finer particles down into the open spaces. This restores the capillary connection and the water may be brought to the surface from below and escape. Cultivation should begin as soon as possible after the rain, as the high rate of evaporation quickly draws the water from our soils. During a period of prolonged drouth it may be neces sary to cultivate between rains. When we have a moist soil underneath and a mulch on the surface, there will be some movement of the water from below into the mulch. As this be - comes moister it loses its efficiency in checking the evaporation of the water, and cultivation is necessary to break apart tli&lt; I ■•« ri i ' it^s, \% lilt 1 1 i \ i^«i in (Htmks Til* pv &lt;ipor« t ion . </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 I&lt;3o8T or Summer Tilling. — The cost of summer tilling is excessive. It does not always mean the loss of a crop, ause during dry years there is often no profitable crop hout summer tillage. In such instances summer tilling not y does not cause the loss of a crop but prevents the farmer ing seed and labor in the fruitless endeavor to get a crop hout sufficient moisture. The labor of summer tilling old mnd for winter wheat will consist of plowing once, double king two or three times and harrowing as often. It may possible to lessen the labor by using cattle or sheep to destroy weeds or by using a lighter draft tool than the disk. The uiber of cultivations necessary for the best results will vary :h conditions of soil and precipitation. The labor expended preparing the seed bed for the winter wheat crops on the rotation farm has been as follows: Table 22. — Table showing labor expended in summer tilling land for winter wheat. Year crop harvested Disking Plowing Ha ™ w - P^gg" £^ * The precipitation is given for the year the crop was harvested I Effect of the Crop on Moisture in Soil. — Data have been •lished in the Twenty-third Annual Report which show that isture may be driven fifteen feet or more into the soil. But v many feet of this moisture is available for the use of the in crops is not known accurately. Moisture will move in f direction from a moist soil into a soil containing less isture. Whether this movement takes place with sufficient &gt;idity to make the moisture stored in the soil below the sixth t of use in tiding a crop over a dry period is not known. II =d 2 3 5 2 1 1 1 1 3 3 2 5 Inches 19.61 # 19.96 22.41 10.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 but the following table indicates strongly that the oat crop drew the moisture out of the first four feet of the soil and that the winter wheat drew the moisture out of the first six feet of the soil. Other data at hand tend to substantiate the evidence given in Table 23. This table shows the amount of moisture in the surface six feet of the oat field at seeding and also at harvest time, in 1908. 1909, and 1910. It shows the same for corn and for winter wheat, excepting that it shows the moisture to the depth of eight feet in the wheat field in 1909 and 1910. All this land was summer tilled before these samples were taken, and we find, therefore, that at each seeding time the soil contained approximately all the water that it would retain. The samples taken at harvest time in the oat field show that during each of these years the moisture in the first four feet had been taken out, while that in the lower feet had not been reduced much. The same fact is noted in the corn fields, only not so clearly. The samples from the winter wheat field show that the moisture content of the first six feet was reduced to the point where plants could not take much more. This table certainly shows that the stored moisture is used by the crop and that the reservoir is not the depth of the furrow but is four to six or possibly even more feet deep. A shallow soil cannot be of much use in the storage of moisture, as its capacity if&lt; too limited. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Table 23. — Effect of the crop on the moisture content of tha toil, as shown by the per cent of moisture in the soil at seeding and at harvest time. 1906 1900 1910 Depth Seeding Harvest Seeding Harvest Seeding Harvest OATS 1st foot 19.1 8 3 18.2 8.3 14.2 2d foot 16.1 8.6 16.3 8.0 17.0 3d foot 14.6 i 8.7 15 2 7.5 16.8 4th foot U.2 9.3 15.6 8.1 16.0 5th foot 16.9 ! 15.4 17.2 10.8 17.2 6th foot 16.3 ! 14.9 17.2 14.2 18.4 CORN 1st foot 21.3 7.5 17.5 10.1 180 11.2 2d foot 15.8 ; 9.2 15.9 9.7 16.9 10.1 3d foot 14.7 9.1 14.7 10.0 15.4 10.2 4thfoot j 14.5 I 9.9 14.7 13.1 14.2 12.8 5th foot 15.9 14.9 17.2 16.8 18.6 16.4 6th foot 17.4 15.0 15.7 16.1 17.4 15.5 WOITKI WHEAT 1st foot 18.4 11.4 16.8 15.9* 14.9 n 2d foot 17.0 8.2 17.0 13.9* 15.0 3d foot 15.8 8.3 16.5 8.5 17.6 4th foot 15.0 7.3 14.6 7.8 14.7 5th foot. 13.8 6.9 11.9 7.6 14 6 6thfoot 146 6.9 10.3 8.1 14.5 7thfoot 9.1 8.3 15.6 Sthfoot 1 8.7 8.6 14.9 * This sampling was done about two weeks after harvest and an Intervening rain had moistened the first two feet of soil. SoBauRFACE Packing. — The process of subsurface packing should be emphasized in connection with summer tillage and storing soil moisture. Subsurface packing is the process of firming the furrow slice by packing it firmly against the soil below. This process fills the open spaces that may have been formed by turning under clods, mnnure, or other coarse mate- rial in plowing. It also packs the soil particles closer together and against the soil which has not been stirred. This is essen tial in order to keep the furrow slice supplied with moisture from below. The water in the seed bed is drawn up from below from one particle of soil to the next one. as oil is drawn </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 I thru a lamp wick to the flame. To lift Hk water toward surface the soil particles must be close together so that water may move from one to another. If we do not pack soil after plowing, or plow early enough to allow it to le or to be firmed by rains, the furrow slice will not be in i capillary connection with the lower soil and may dry while there is still an abundance of moisture in the subsoil, evil results from a loose seed bed are often seen where a ;e amount of coarse manure has been plowed under and ire dry weather follows before the land has settled. Another advantage is that stubble, weeds, or manure will decay much more quickly if the soil is pressed firmly around them. Water is required in the process of decay, and the organic material must be in close contact with the soil in order to draw water therefrom. Where the field is rough and cloddy when plowed, the clods hold the soil apart and allow it to I We may employ several methods of firming the soil. There is the market a tool known as the subsurface packer, which is It especially for the work. Most farmers do not have such ool and some feel that they cannot afford one. A disk can used and proves a good substitute for the subsurface packer. i disk should be weighted and run straighter than in regular rk. This will do very little pulverizing, but will firm the I below the surface. Some men hitch an extra horse on the wed side. The horse firms the soil by walking on it. A tion of harrow is hitched to this horse and the surface is de fine by the harrowing before it becomes dry and cloddy, ch furrow gets about three or four harro wings. If the soil i a tendency to blow readily, the surface should not be pul - ized as finely as so many harrowings would do. I No matter what process is employed, the seed bed should firm when the seed is sown. We have noted many cases ?re grain died out and winterkilled much more on loose. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Growing Crop* in Western Nebrtuka 56 ashy-like soils tlian it did where the soil was more firm. This is especially true of grasses. IThi Sbbd Bbd. — A good seed bed is one in which the soil been brought into such mechanical condition as to best it the requirements for germination of the seed. All seeds require water, heat, and air (oxygen) for germina tion and growth. A good seed bed must be fine and firm and must have heat, moisture, and air enough to germinate the seed. It must be loose enough for the air and water to enter from above but firm enough so that moisture may be brought by capillary action from below to the seed which is firmly packed in fine soil. The most common method of loosening the soil is by plowing. When the soil is plowed, it is so loosened and broken that air, heat, and water can readily enter. A loose soil will hold much more water than a hard soil. We can loosen the soil more thoroly with the plow than with any other implement It goes deeper and pulverizes more than any other tool. The plow completely severs the upper surface of the soil and turns it under. Stubble and weeds that are on the surface are turned under and the surface left clean. Every soil should be plowed occasionally. The heavier the soil the more frequently it should be plowed. If a soil is very heavy it should be plowed each time a grain crop is grown. The plowing will tend to free the surface of weeds and incorporate weeds and stubble in the soil, to replenish the organic matter. This cannot be done with a disk, as the disk only stirs the surface. It may cover some stubble or weeds, but not deeply. If the surface is covered with weeds or stubble it is often advisable to disk the soil before plowing. This will mix the weeds and stubble with the soil, and when plowed under they will be less liable to separate the furrow slice from the under soil. The time to plow depends upon the character of the soil, and climatic conditions. Fall plowing is generally considered </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 It when it can be done early, if the soil is of a type that s not blow during the winter. By fall plowing we get soil in shape to catch the rains. The loosened soil has e to settle and become firm again before seeding. There is erally more time for men and teams in the fall than in the ing. The sooner the plowing can be done after the previous p comes off the better. Stubble and weeds are turned under 1 given more time to rot and the growth of weeds is checked that they do not go to seed nor rob the soil of moisture. The depth of plowing depends on the type of soil, the time the plowing is done, the previous handling of the soil, and the crop to be grown. Where the plowing is done shortly before seeding and danger of dry weather exists, the plowing should be rather shallow unless plenty of help is available to work the ground until it is thoroly finned. If the soil is plowed deeply and the seed sown without much working, the furrow slice will be loose and may dry out before the young plants get their roots thru it and establish them in the firm, moist soil beneath. A light, sandy soil need not be plowed as deeply as a heavier soil. The lighter soil is already more open and leas impervious to water, air, and to the plant roots. Heavier soils should be plowed deeper to loosen them and allow water and air to enter and the plants' roots to readily pass torn them. All else being equal, the deep plowing is best if it has time to settle and form a deep, firm seed bed from which the plants may draw plant food and in which they may develop a strong, vigorous root system. Each day's plowing should be harrowed the same day it is plowed. This is especially true where there is an abundance of moisture, as water will be lost very rapidly after plowing. The harrow will level the surface, leaving less of it exposed to the drying action of sun and wind. It pulverizes the sur - face and forms a mulch to protect the moisture below. Where a soil is quite dry and there is danger from blowing, it :s best </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 to leave the soil rough. Some farmers advocate leaving the surface rough and without harrowing to hold the snow better during the winter. This is all right if the «oil is dry when plowed, bat if the soil is moist when plowed it should be worked down to form a better mulch and check the further low of water. Firming the soil is necessary to restore capillary connection between the furrow slice and the under soil. There are gen - erally numerous rather large air spaces formed by plowing under clods, weeds, etc. This gives good conditions for the loss of water and the furrow slice dries out. When we firm the soil we bring the soil particles closer together and fill these air spaces. The furrow slice is also pressed down against the under soil and the water which is there can move upward into the surface soil and supply the young plants. Where the fur - row slice is not firmed before the seed is sown, the plants are dependent upon the water in the surface soil or upon opportune rains. We had just such conditions on certain spring plowed plats during the spring of 1908. There seemed to be plenty of moisture in the soil. However, it was used or lost before the young plants had gotten their roots established in the lower ■oil. The crop suffered severely, even tho there was moisture in the subsoil, and did not recover from the injury thruout the season. If the seed bed has been prepared for some time before seed - ing, capillary connection will have been restored between the surface and the lower soil. This will tend to bring the water to the surface. Surface cultivation will check this loss, as the water cannot readily pass thru the soil mulch produced by cultivation. This mulch not only prevents the loss of water, but is easily penetrated by the heat and air that are required for the germination of the seed. The principles of a good seed bed may be summed up a* including : deep plowing to loosen and pulver ' the soil ; firm- </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 ing the soil again by labor or by natural processes to get a firm, warm, and moist soil area favorable to the retention of moisture and the accumulation of plant food for the use of the crop. I Table 24 on page 60 is a diagram showing the arrangement plats in Field 41. This work is being carried on in co-opera - n with the Office of Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau of Plant lustry. United States Department of Agriculture. The pur - le of the work is to determine the effect of crop sequence 1 soil tillage. The plats are two rods wide by eight rods ig, making one-tenth acre, and are arranged in groups or ations of from two to six each. The number of plats in a ation represents the number of years required to complete &gt; cycle in a rotation. The crop that is shown on each plat in the diagram is the crop that was grown on that plat in 1910. The crops rotate from year to year. Each plat retains the same letter constantly, but the crops move in the rotation from Z toward A. In this ro - tation the oats on plat A moves to plat (' in 1911 and to plat B in 1912, and back again to plat A in 1913. Corn follows the oats and rye follows the corn. All the other rotations follow this same plan. I There are some plats which grow the same crop continuously. • example, in Series 4 there is a plat marked A Barley 8. Barley is grown on this plat each year on spring plowing. s plat above marked B Barley F. P. grows barley each year on plowing. Opi&gt;O8ite these plats in Series 5 are two plats. ? is marked O Barley and the other I), summer fallow. On Be two. summer tillage and barley alternate each year. There also four plats that grow wheat, four that grow oats, and r that grow corn continuously after the same preparation indicated for the barley. LThe rotations are arranged so that met is different from ry other rotation in only one particular. A fair example </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 S e! isiHiinfsififM*!^ i d g I 5 i u I $ t || t i h b 5 a u » a u tl £ a. k &lt;o {2 I I 8 i li : iE;i iiililisii £ — Ib — list — Is — lie — Is I la llw I la lit llo IL Ik m IL I s — Ib — llsi — lie ll» ll&lt; I Is Ik Is Ik IU ll« |[&lt; IL IL | iiiiillii r^ ■ — '■ — 1« — Ik — !■ — IIh— Jk — 1U IL — lit IL IL II* IL IL I 1 1 i 1 1 i 1 1 1 i 1 1 § i i i — IL llv Its — IL — I la — Ib — IU Ik IL IL IL IL IL IL I I 00 I I t ; t i i i i i si i i i i i « lie ||u IL |L Ib lls IL IL lls i a s ■ u I OS 1 3 I g § ? £ to l a i L_ </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 is given by rotations 1, 2, and 3. In these three rotations wheat is grown on fall plowing, spring plowing, and disked corn stubble. Rotation 5 is the same as these excepting that corn is replaced by summer tillage. In rotations 9 and 4 the sequence is changed. These changes permit a perfect system of check - ing thruont all the rotations. IAltho we have at present four years' results and have ?d in this bulletin some of the results, yet we believe that longer period of time is necessary before we can draw de - odable conclusions as to which are the best rotations. From lat has been given it will be seen that certain methods give i best results one year under certain climatic conditions, tile other methods give the best results the following year der different climatic conditions. In Field 49 there are plats d out similar to these, but in this field winter wheat forms ? basis of the rotations. CLIMATIC CONDITIONS. I The climate of western Nebraska is classified as semiarid or humid. It may be better to describe it as changeable, vary from year to year from almost humid to almost arid con - ions, with a mean annual precipitation much below that of tern Nebraska, as shown by Figure 15. With this lower inal precipitation we have a higher rate of evaporation, l to a lower relative humidity and a higher wind velocity n the more humid sections. The higher rate of evaporation kes the loss of water from our soils more rapid than where climate is humid, and consequently we must guard more efully the water which falls.* •The relation of the rate of evaporation to crop production is shown in Bulletin 188, Bureau of Plant Industry, by Dr. L. J. Briggs and Mr. J. O. B*1«. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 ?: ■if 3 I ll £1 s 1 2 ■S H "O Ji _. £ a ■*-* c J JJ * 5 b£ c C •5 ' go c • • {I* w a; o _ r c . 8 g =•2 * S a &gt; ■a — fl 8 — : i '".. ■ 3 s </seg>
            <seg id="p063">I 63 I ! ! : J 2 H I I E It's 7TTi+7Xi= &lt; T?'f &lt; *7i'fV-'f*rT'?T'»T^««-':*«*3 -255 j 5 ° = KS3 83J«6»act?s«w»attw H sa«M|i«ie«a^ttftB 3 5 » * u Si * 5 a :g oj 3Sa9SCsas£St3S8ZB«8S8SSSaa3«3»gg oo at a as NW- » ro £■ S5?S5S8§S8$SSSgE2S 1% 5a iTS*S8S^aSgE2£ga=»S25Si5=3SSS3!5sSf:S s •x «»O N It 9 SSSS2$(esr:2SS « SSS SeSg??°SS?£S=SSg -r M -V OJCOcQ MM ? i 55 22SSE5S!9S?ilS - 3S5Si'»ssgj»3jg 5S2S£?3?a3SSS35S = gESS N-PI«XMWW-M^ « W5D nw «N«NCQciceta is -* ?iiacBCDce«N«m^mm . »..J ■*__* _: • . . 1 i MOJjocr^-H-n.iJ;;,. *5 ?joi^ n II | ssa5aasasssssar:ssesgs5=s25ss?ss8sss!e?!a w — . — M -^t-«"=cWoioJocie»ic«j I&amp;: I S3S2g2£SgSS3;8SSS82Sg5S3gSgg!£SS§f5SP? li JB S SS2S=5SS5$Sg?S?^S2£Sf!g£g;3SSSJ^g2Sj£a82 6 *- ."i I »=B258saj?as5ss6»ss8aassasss«a8a8sjss8 r = ~8?8^S25S22S2SSSigarS3=S;5f:=S25aggsgsa5 = I I iiiliiliillillli|!iifiii|iiii5sgis§i </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 We note from the table showing the precipitation for North Platte (page 63) that four-fifths of the precipitation comes during the six growing months — April to September. The monthly average rises rapidly with April, reaches its higher point in June, and declines to its lowest point in November, as is seen in Figure 17. This distribution is very favorable to crop production. Figure 16 shows a wide variation in the amount of precipitation from year to year. There are years of relatively high and years of relatively low rainfall. The greatest precipi tation recorded at North Platte was in 1883. amounting to 29.88 inches, and the least in 1910, with only 10.70 inches, the difference in the two being about the same as the normal, which is 18.63 inches. There have been twenty years with the pre - cipitation below the average and sixteen years above the aver age. Previous to the year 1892 a year with a deficiency appears to have been followed by a year of more than normal rainfall. In 1893 began a series of dry years with nine consecutive years of deficient rainfall. It is this long series of dry years that played such havoc with the agriculture of this section. Begin - ning with 1904 there were six consecutive years with more than normal precipitation, followed by 1910, the year having the least precipitation of any year in the thirty-six. The five-year period having the lightest rainfall was from 1893 to 1897 inclusive, during which period the total precipi - tation averaged 14.51 inches per year. The five-year period having the heaviest rainfall was from 1902 to 1906 inclusive. Daring this period the average amount of precipitation was 24.52 inches. The average annual difference in the precipitation for these two periods was 10.01 inches. When we consider the ten-year periods, however, there is not so much fluctuation from the normal. The following table shows the average normal precipitation and also the average departure from the normal of two series of ten-year periods, one beginning in 1875 with the first records available for North </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 Platte and ending in 1904; the other beginning in 1881 and ending in 1910 with the last available records. rLE 26. — Record of precipitation at North Platte by ten-year periods, with departure from the normal. Yearly average Departure from Ten-year period for period normal This table shows a variation of 5.36 inches per year between the period of highest and the period of lowest precipitation. If we consider the ten-year period having the least precipitation 1892-1901, with an average of 15.11, and the ten-year period having the greatest precipitation, 1900-1909, with an average of 21.33, we find that the difference in the yearly average for these ten-year periods is 6.22 inches. If we consider the twenty-year periods, we find the varia - tion even less. Prom 1875 to 1894 the average precipitation was 18.44, and from 1891 to 1910 the average was 18.49 inches. If we consider the twenty -year period having the least precipi - tation. 1884-1903, with an average of 17.02, and the twenty-year period having the greatest precipitation, 1890-1909. with an average of 18.59, we find that the variation in the two is 1.57 inches. In summing up these records, we find that the difference in the amount of precipitation between the driest year and the wettest was 19.18 inches; between the average annual precipita - tion of the driest and the wettest five-year period, 10.01 inches; between the average annual precipitation of the driest and wet test ten-year period, 5.36 inches; and between the average annual precipitation of the driest and wettest twenty-year period, 1.57 11884 1894 1904 1890 , 1900 IMO Inehes 19.32 17.57 17.42 19.19 15.81 21 17 Inches + » -1.08 —1.21 + 56 -2.82 +2.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">Growing Crop* in Wetttrn Nebraska 66 I I ' II I I — r^^^^^S S^ </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Growing Crops in Western Nebraska 67 Average Precipirarton by Monrhs tor 35 years ar Morrh Plarre Fig. 17. Arerage precipitation by months A study of Table 25 shows that if we take short periods of time we find a rapid increase or decrease in the annual pre - cipitation, but that if we take longer periods we do not find any marked variation. In earlier settled parts of the country, where the climatic records have been kept for a much longer term of yeare, there is an opportunity to compare longer periods than are given in the records in this table. The comparisons do not show that there is any perceptible change in the climatic </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Growing Crops in We* tern Nebraska fixed and fluctuate below and above the normal, the average remaining about constant. If one studies the history of the precipitation as recorded here and elsewhere he must conclude that the evidence at hand indicates that the precipitation in western Nebraska, in the past thirty-six years, has been much less than in the eastern part of the state (Pig. 15) and that there is nothing to indicate that it is increasing or will increase. If one will also keep in mind that the history of the precipitation of the past centuries is written in the natural vegetation of the country and in the soil, and knows that as we proceed westward in the state there is less vegetation as is evidenced by the acreage of pasture required per head of stock and also that the soil is lighter colored, which means that there has been less organic matter returned to it from the vegetation that it has produced, then he must certainly conclude that western Nebraska has a com - paratively small amount of precipitation. When the farmer has become thoroly convinced that the country is dry and will remain in the future as it has been in the past, then he is in the proper mental condition to succeed in growing crops. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 ; I HH*S i I I ! i I 18 IS M In I Sh* N j « a 1 1 1 1 1 N N ! h I !*•• ! 1 1 1 h* ! ! ! ! [JJJj 1 | h, !«»*»•. | !|ss M*2 ; ; - s :„ q 00 I § 8$ M Mt-8 is3 i;s M^ is M M H i I Jj § ! 15 H SSa8 HH IS I i !88 H S8 H | jt ] S 1 i 1 1 m M ; ■ |8 1^ ;„ g j i^«J|j^ I 1 1 iiihh^iijwji|H|wj&gt;.|sw3 *r | s 5° Mas M i !ss H 8^ H ;$2 I is H s [».3 I f I ||cs fe i H ««^iw»i«iiij!^-!! \ya\\ ihi|s i 1 I § 52 I is^asa | H s j I ! ! i^a i^aa,, is I i Is g a. -&gt; Jl L ; fL__ ; ' i : i ; i ; Lli ». *» S »(-h ! I*? 85 N* i 2 r*r M MSS | H | H 8 U j Is C | «s Isas | I ;ss | ;5 HH [ '[„ |» | j | frj y TO | o - 8 IN iSSSf. 188* i i=8 H 2 j ! H 8S 8 | I | ;«22 | i |i^ :sss i j I j ] j i H ss8 iss Ms is a I ! Mh I ! I i i i Issas M M M M M i i Ms Ms g 35 = = : :; = = = = = • = = = = • = ••;• = ■: ;l | 5 -i»i^w^^^«i«i6 : i^3 2 i ; 5 2 : E ; 52 j S i- a : a ;j s ijjjj; a : g j g jJ o </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>