<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Relation of Environment and Other Factors to Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum</title>
               <date value="1923-03">1923-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE I'NIYERKITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION Relation of Environment and Other Factors to Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum ASSOCIATE PLANT PATHOLOGIST ACCEPTED FOR PUBLICATION NOVEMBER, 19M • 1STRIBUTED MARCH. 192S LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. S. W. (ioss </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS immary 4 lntroducti ■ Prevalence and loss 8 Source of cultureH 10 t'.rowth-temperature relations of Fvxttrium oxtixpot um In pure culture.. 10 Infection experiments . . 13 Fathogenicity tests by direct inoculation of growing plants 13 Review 13 (Experimental data 14 Greenhouse experiments 14 Field experiments 17 Discussion 19 Transmission of Fusarium wilt by infected seed It Review of the literature U Oreenhouse experiments with seed having vascular discoloration. . .28 Field experiments on seed transmission 29 Conclusions 36 Infection from the soil thru the roots or stem 37 Review of literature 38 Field experiments with infested soil 41 (Ireenhouse experiments 42 Relation of soil temperature to infection of roots from the soil 44 Kffect of high soil temperature on the potato plant SI Effect of high air and soil temperature on the disease 61 Relation of soil moisture to infection of roots from the soil 62 Discussion 67 i feet ion from the soil thru the seed-piece 68 Review 68 Creenhouse exi&gt;eriments 69 Field experiments '. 7' Discussion 80 Relation of environment to the disease 80 Literature cited 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY 1. — Ftixoriuiit &lt;ut/x[&gt;oritm is a soil saprophyte capable of parasitizing the potato plant under conditions favorable for the growth of the organism, and the action of the disease after infec - tion has taken place is accelerated by conditions unfavorable for the host. 2. — There are three methods of infection of potato plants with Fiixntfiim oxysporium 1st, infection from the soil thru the seed tuber. 2nd. from the soil thru the roots and stein, and 3rd, infection from the seed tuber. 3. — The initial infection is largely influenced by environ - mental conditions, and the environmental conditions may also cause a considerable change in the latter symptoms of the diseax-. 4. — The complexity of environmental factors influencing the disease results in many inconclusive results from inoculation ex - periments and increases the difficulty of interpreting the behavior of the disease in the field. ."&gt;. — It was found impossible to consistently reproduce the disease under any of the conditions and with any of the methods used in these experiments. 0. — Growth-temperature studies of Fwtariiivi uu-yxponuit in pure culture show that different strains of this s|&gt;ecies vary in their optimum temperature for growth at least '&lt; ( '. These differences were more marked in liquid cultures than in |&gt;etri dish cultures. It was also shown that by the use of different liquid media it was possible to cans*- a lowering of ."&gt; -10° in the optimum temperature for growth. 7. — Pathogenicitv tests of growing plants showed that the potato plant is more susceptible to infection during it&lt; early growth. 8. —^he host plant may often l&gt;e infected without the symp - toms of the disease appearing, under conditions favorable for the plant. 0. — A discoloration of the vascular system of l&gt;oth stem and tabers in the absence of any cau&gt;al organism is often produced under conditions of high teni|&gt;eratiire and low soil moisture. 10. — Soil infection experiments with pure cultures of the organism under a wide range of conditions, in which the tem - perature and soil moisture were controlled, showed the usual </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I "fttttf 1 1 tft t tf it hc tt h tf r ftxtit*tttt)i (sjcyttpopttnt 5 small percentage of infection. The results, however, clearly in - dicated that teni]&gt;eratures of 18°C. and below are very unfavor - able for the development of the disease and that the amount of infection increases with increasing soil temperatures. The dis - ease develops most rapidly when the temperatures are too high for vigorous growth of the host plant. Plants started at a tem - perature of 1* and later changed to higher temperatures showed as much disease as those kept at a constant high temperature. Plants started at a high temperature and later transferred to low temperatures showed practically no disease symptoms even tho the organism was present in small amounts in the finer rootlets. 11. — Constant low soil moisture is unfavorable for infection. After plants have become infected a lowering of the soil moisture accelerates the wilting of the plant. ML — With increasing soil moistures the amount of rotting of the stems and roots of infected plants increases and the wilting symptoms are not as marked. 1:5. — In all the infection experiments with inoculated soil, in feet ion took place thru the roots rather than thru the seed - piece. 14. — Field experiments with seed inoculations under three different environmental conditions showed that the greatest amount of disease developed in the plot having low soil tempera - tures during the early period of growth with a decreasing soil moisture content and increasing soil temperatures in the latter |);ni of the experiment. With conditions very similar except for the application of two irrigations during the latter stages of growth, a small amount of disease developed but the plants were more vigorous. In another plot with the same general type of temperature and moisture curve as in the one showing the greatest amount of disease, but with much higher temperatures and higher soil moistures thruout the experiment, practically no disease de - veloped. IS. — Infection from the soil was found to be the prevalent method of infection in Michigan and Nebraska. Such infection was usually thru the roots rather than thru the seed-piece. 16. — Only a small per cent of tubers having vascular dis - coloration contain Fvxarimn o.ry*por&lt;im and these tubers do not usually reproduce the disease except under conditions very favor - able for this type of infection. 17. — Neither vascular discoloration of the tul&gt;er nor of the stem is a good index of infection with Fmtarium o.ryxpar\&lt;m unless </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Xebranka Agricultural K-&lt;/&gt;. Station, Reneurvh Bui. 23 6 these symptoms are found in connection with a wilted plant. Vascular discoloration can l&gt;e produced in the absence of any organism and can often lie correlated in the field with high soil temperatures combined with drought. 18. — Control of the disease by cutting away the discolored portion of seed tubers is not practicable. til*. — Seed tul&gt;ers showing vascular discoloration, while they ally do not reproduce the disease directly, do produce weak ■ti that niv easily infected from the -oil. Such tillers should be used for pmrpeme*. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Relation of Environment and Other Factors to Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum 1 INTRODUCTION It ha&gt; lieen generally accepted by plant pathologist* that Fumii limn n.r&gt;/x//i&gt;iiiii, Schlect. is a very active pathogene causing one of the ino-t widespread and serious diseases of the potato, commonly known as Fusariiiin wilt or blight. This opinion, however. ha&gt; l&gt;eeii Imsed chiefly upon observations rather than upon conclusive experimental evidence. Many of these observa - ti«&gt;n~ relating to the widespread activity and seriousness of the di*ea&gt;e have Iteen based upon data which have since been proved to be a poor criterion in judging the amount of disease 1 . A critical review of the literature shows t hat much of the experimental evidence is either incomplete or negative. Many of the inoculation experiments reported by various investigators were unsuccessful. Results from repetition of the same experi - ments were often contradictory, and there has been a general failure to reproduce the, disease a&gt; it occurs in the field. Certain lypm of the disease have Ihhmi produced while other types have never U'en produced experimentally. In most of the inoculation ex|»erinient» reported in the literature, the methods used have heea verv drastic and even then a rather low percentage of in - fected plant- ha- Ihhmi obtained. The evidence presented does not justify many of the widely drawn conclusions as to the ex - tremeh active pathogenic nature of Fmniriuni oxifxpornm. but rather points out a lack &lt;&gt;f knowledge of the influence of various factors upon the occurrence of the disea&gt;e. In studying |&gt;otato wilt caused bv Fn*nrinm oxi/xponim undeT widely divergent conditions, it ap|&gt;eared to the writer that tliere were three probable methods of infection: 1. From the mi] thru the seed tuber. From the soil thru the roots and stems. From seed tul&gt;er- having internal infection. These three types (if infection would l&gt;e influenced largely by the following factor-: 1. Soil teni|&gt;erattire. 2. Soil moisture. This paper is based upon experimental work undertaken at the Michigan Agri- cultural Coll -ire in 1914-15. at the I'niv-rsity of Wisconsin in 1916-17 and 1920. and continued at the 1'niversity of Nebraska during 1921-22. The writer wishes to acknowledge his indebtedness to the first two institutions for the privileges and facilities of their laboratories and especially to the members of the Plant Pathology Department of the University of Wisconsin and the Botany Department of the Michigan Agricultural College for their advice, assistance and criticism of this work. R. W. (i&lt;«8 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 _ ' r '/ft " ft If * 1 * f f t * "fff'fftft i j *' M * t • f I' ( f "ff v / 4 ' " % w ' / f i^F f ( C ■ ***■ *' S. Pathogenicity of the strain of Fumirhmt oxyxporum present. 4. Temperature differences with different strains or F. oxyaporum. 5. Differences in susceptibility of the potatoes, both individual and varietal. The disease would also l&gt;e influenced more indirect - ly by atmospheric temperature, relative humidity, sunshine, and other factors influencing the development of the host. This complexity of factors tends to produce uncertain or inconclusive results in e.\|&gt;erimental work and increases the dif - ficulty of interpreting the behavior of the disease in the field. The present work was undertaken to determine the influence of some of these environmental factors on the infection and progress of the disease. The work has not progressed to the point of determining the exact relation of each of these chief factors. However, the results thus far obtained are presented here in order t direct attention to the nature and distribution of the disease relation to the environmental condtions under which certain «*&gt; of infection take place. PREVALENCE AND LOSS It is impossible to determine accurately the actual In-- in yield due to Fmuirium o.ryxjM&gt;mw. The nature of the disease is such that an estimate of the loss in commercial fields is a matter of guesswork rather than of accurately compiled data. It is true of this disease, as of many others, that the estimated losses are often exaggerated, owing to confusion with other troubles, and to the fact that actual losses in yields cannot lx? accurately estimated except in experimental plots or in case:- of epidemics. The distribution of the disease is widespread, as the organism is almost universally present in the soil. Pratt (1916) 1 found that disease-free tul»ers planted on virgin tlesert soil in Idaho produced -Jfi.Z per cent vascular infection as determined by pure cultures. Werkenthin (1916) found Fuxariiim oxysporum to be present in virgin soils of Texas. The writer has isolated the organism from virgin forest soils in the upper peninsula of Michigan, and from fields having l&gt;een in sod for over 20 years. Xo doubt in certain localities the disease has approached epidemic proportions in some years. However, the estimated losses in the United States for three years, as given by the Plant Disease Survey (1019 T 20-21), show a rather small amount of damage. 1 All reference to literature are indicated in the text by the name of the author and the year of publication. For full citations, see the list at the end of this bulletin. Reviews of individual papers are divided into various sections to conform to the outline of this paper. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Potuto Wilt Caused by Fiimrium Oxysporum 9 Year Lou per No. iUte* with No. states with itate 10 per cent loss 5 per rant leas Per cent L»lfl ■_'..". I 14 In the six leading states in potato production for these three years, the highest reported losses are 6 and .") per cent in 1918. In 1!&gt;1!&gt; and 1920 none of these states report more than -\ per cent Id—. Many estimates of the amount of infection have lieen based upon vascular discoloration rather than upon the iniinl)er of wilted plants in the Held, altho we are now aware that vascular discoloration is not a true index of the presence of Fusnrium In 1914, 100 fields in Michigan being grown for seed purposes were inspected by the author. The amount of disease was esti - mated both by counts of the number of wilted plants and by dig - ging ii]&gt; 4 Mr "&gt; lots of 10 hills each in every field and examining for vascular discoloration. Twenty-one per cent of the fields showed Fusarium wilt as evidenced by actual wilting: only one of these fields showed more than 10 per cent infection, and the average amount of infection was 1.5 per cent. If the vascular browning of stems or tubers had been used as an indication of disease, it would have been found that out of the 100 fields in - spected, 5M» showed plants with discolored vascular systems, aver - aging 30 per cent infection per field. In Nebraska, in 1920. the author examined about 900 acre* and found about 82 per cent of the fields infected with wilt, averaging ♦&gt; per cent infection. In 1921 as a result of the seed certification work carried on by the Horticultural Department of the University of Nebraska. 83 per cent of the acreage in - spected was found to contain wilt averaging about 3 per cent infection. These estimates in Nebraska also include a consider - able amount of wilt due to causes other than Fuaarium oxy - npirrum, ■*&gt; that the actual damage due to this one organism is considerably less than the above reports would indicate. Judging from the results of a number of surveys made in different states, the author considers Fusarium wilt to be a wide - spread disease which in some sections may produce considerable injury over limited areas but is usually not serious over entire states. The wide variations in the amount of infection in some states over a period of years indicate that environmental condi - tions play an important role in determining the severity of the attack. The amount of infection in the same fields in successive l!»lf U ■ 14 1915) 1.0 2 7 1020 1.6 2 4 oxyaporvm. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 X, h,&lt;i*l:ti A'/i -ii nit &gt;i ml fi'.i/i. Station. ReHcarrh /in/. years will vary widely, irrespective of the potatoes planted or treatment of cither soil or seed. SOURCE OF CULTURES The various strains of Fwuwium ojryxporiim used in all the following experiments are listed below with their origin. Strain So. 1. — Isolated hv the author from the discolored -- .-— --_- — - - — — vascular bundles of a potato tuber in Michigan. October 15, 1914. This culture was identified bv H. W. Wollenwelier and nuinben&gt;d 3377 by the United States I)epartinent of Agriculture. Strain Xu. S. — Culture obtained from (". W. Carpenter of the fnited States Department of Agriculture a- No. 3395. Strain Xo. -i.i. — Culture ol&gt;tained from (i. K. K. Link of the University of Nebraska as No. 3345a, and obtained bv him from the United States Department of Agricnltnre. Strain Xo. ■!■!. — Culture received bv James Johnson &lt;&gt;f the University of Wisconsin from W. (i. (Jilhert. Unite*! State- De partmeut of Agriculture a- Xo. II. from inoculated plants showing wilt. from the roots of inoculated plants. While these -trains were of greatlv different ages, no dif — ._ .. ferences could U' observed in any of the inoculation experiment indicating a loss in virulence due to the ajre of the cultur GROWTH-TEMPERATURE RELATIONS OF FUSARIUM OXYSPORUM IN PURE CULTURE In studying thi' relation of temperature to the infection and progress of the disease it was also deemed advisable to determine the effect of temperature on the growth of tl rganism in pure culture. While such a study does not necessarily give a true index of disease phenomena under natural condition-, it docs aid mate - rially in interpreting the action of the dix-a-e Im&gt;i1i in the kid and under controlled experimental condition-. In the literature dealing with the growth-temperature reU - tions of Fhmii /in hi o.ri/x/tiiiniii in pure culture- there i- a general uniformity in the hrpe of growth curve. However, the exact minima, optima, and maxima for growth, each varv in the differ - ent papers from •"&gt; to &lt;&gt; C. No attempt has lieen made in the literature to explain thi- discrepancy in the roiilt- of variou - workers. strain Xo. -i't. — Reisolation of Strain So, :*&gt;•"&gt; made in li&gt;-_'0 Strain \&lt;&gt;. ~&gt;(1. — Reisoltition of Strain No. :&gt;:'&gt; made ii </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Potato Wilt (/nixed by F atari um Oxyisponiiit 11 In reviewing the literature on the subject it was found that in all the experiments reported it was assumed that different strains of Fusarium ou-yspormn would react similarly to the same temperature conditions: that is. while the total growth might vary, the cardinal points for growth would remain the same. It was also assumed that the same effect upon the growth-tem - perature relations would 1h&gt; true of the use of different media. 3 10 TCMPERATURC C 35 Fi. —Graph showing the rate of growth of 2 strains of Fusarium oxy - nrum on potato agar at different temperatures. 1 /. Preliminary experiments conducted by the writer indicated tli:it different strains react differently to temperature effects. The media used were also found to cause a shifting of the cardinal points for growth. Further experiments were therefore con - ducted with a numl&gt;er of strains of Fusarivm oxysporum and with several other species of Fusarium. These tests were made on various media both solid and liquid. 1 While lack of space will not permit the publication of the detailed experiments at this time, typical examples of some of the results are presented here. In test tube cultures of Strains Nos. 1. 8. and 32 on potato plugs, submitted to temperatures between 5° and 38° at about 2° intervals, it was found that growth occurred at 9.5° but not at 7°: growth also occurred at 37.5° but not at 38°C. The 1 These rnulti are being published as a separate paper. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Xeliraxhn Agricultural t'xp. Station, lle*ear&lt;h Bui. optimum temperature for growth was Itetween 24 and 28 \ No differences in the reaction of the different strains to temperature were noted. In petri disli cultures on hard potato agar it was found that different strains produced their maximum growth at different temperat tires. In these cultures the daily increase in the diameter of the colony was used as the index of growth. Figure 1 shows the comparative results of 2 strains of Fitaarium oxt/sporum. It is evident that one strain shows greater growth at the lower temperatures and its maximum growth is produced at a point .'&gt; (.'. lower than the other strain. The difference was found in all trials and in all media, being even more marked in liquid media. Fi&lt;;. 2. — Graph showing the comparative growth of Fn.su up after 3 weeks on 2 different liquid media In tests with liquid media, determining ili&lt;- growth by dry weights, it was also found that the use of different nutrient solutions resulted in a shifting of the minima, optima, and maxima teui)&gt;eratiires for growth. Figure 2 shows the average results of 4 trials with Fu*arium osy»por*nu Xo. :52. In these tests the 2 media used were made up n&gt; follow-: Media No. 1 Media No. 2 125 c.c. M/l NH 4 NO-. 20 gin. NH 4 NO-. 50 c.c. M/l KH,PO 4 10 gin. KH.PO 4 20 c.c. M/l Mg SO 4 150 c.c. M/l Sucrose gm Mg 8O 4 S00 c.c. Potato extract from 1 c.c. M/1000 Fe Cl s 654 c.c. Distilled water 500 gm. of potatoeo '.0(1 c.f. Water 1000 c.c 1000 c.c : 4- + i iftj -i- c. Z30 lA 7 r -^ i — K o«J • raw A- ety 7 + T TV ■+- i « w 4 I -4^4 QE Ol hpc c° </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Potato 11/7/ Cmixiil hy F iixii n a id Oxt/*/x&gt;mui 13 It i^ evident that these 2 media cause a considerable difference in the reaction of the same organisms to different temperatures. In Media No. •+ there i&gt; a shifting of the optimum temperature for growth •"&gt; ('. below that for Media No. 1. There is also a greater growth at the suboptimal temperatures and less growth in the supraoptimal region. This difference was also found with ;i number of other strains and species. In liquid media it was also possible to obtain weighable rowth at ."&gt; ('.. while in petri dish cultures no growth was ob- served at this temperature. These data explain to some extent the different results re - ported by various investigators. They also show that in inocula - tion ex|&gt;eriments with controlled temperatures the manifestation of the disease at certain temj)eratures may depend partially at least upon the strain of organism l&gt;t'ing studied. INFECTION EXPERIMENTS It kaa always been recognized that Fusariuin wilt is very irreatlv inHuen&lt;-ed by environmental conditions, chiefly by the temperature and moisture of l&gt;oth soil and air. Just how great a part these factors play in determining the infection and pro - gress of the disease has not previously l&gt;een determined experi - meutallv. In the following work presented in this paper an attempt has l&gt;eeii made to study this disease with various factors under control. The chief difficulties lie in the fact that at present we must of necessity work with maintained conditions rather than with the fluctuating conditions found in nature. The number of individuals in each test is very small under the l&gt;est experi - mental conditions and our knowledge of the reactions of the host to the various environmental conditions even in the absence of di-eii-c i~ fragmentary. The residts. as to the effect of the various environmental factors, are presented separately for the different types of infection. Pathoftenicity Tests By Direct Inoculation of Growing Plants Altho it has been generally accepted that Fusariuin &lt;i.i-i/x/ii&gt;riiin i&gt; the causal organism producing the wilt of the ]&gt;otato vine, until recent years there have Ikhmi practically no in - oculation ex|M'riinents reported, and even in the few experiments reported the result* have often been inconclusive. REVIEW Smith and Swingle (l'.ifM) isolated the organism and de - wrihrd the disease, but no inoculation experiments were reported. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Sehnukti Ayrifultm-al t\r/&gt;. Station. U,s,,,nh But. .'.; Manns (It'll) reported inoculation experiments but he doe&gt; nol give any detail experiments with pure cultures. He states (p. 316) : Artificial infections were brought about in a number of ways. Slight Injuries of the roots or knife incisions in the presence of the organism brought about the most rapid infections. The organism is, however, productive of infection in the absence of any root disturbance or stem injury, as was shown by a number of experiments. Link (1916) reports experimental infections of living plants with Fusarium oxysporu tu . He obtained his largest percentage of infections by smearing the sprouts with rice cultures of the organism as they were just breaking thru the ground. By using inoculated soil he obtained variable results and suggests that this may have Iteen due to a loss in vitality of the organism, or to a gain in the resistance of the plant as the season progressed. Sherbakoff (1915) reports that he was unable to obtain positive infection with cultures of F. oryspomm. He suggests that this mav have been due to a loss in virulence of the culture- These few reported experiments with direct inoculations of growing plants have certainly not produced any very definite or conclusive evidence that Fuaarivm ourysporum is a very active wilt parasite. The inoculations while very drastic in their nature, did not always yield uniform results. The evidence indicates that the organism, instead of being a very active parasite, is rather a weak one and that it is probably greatly influenced by conditions that were not kept under control in these te-t-. EXPERIMENTAL DATA The following infection experiments relate only to artificial inoculations of &gt;tein- and roots, somewhat similar to those re - viewed above. Methods. — In the following experiments only vigorous plants grown from healthy seed were used. The tubers were examined for the absence of any vascular browning, treated with mercuric chloride and planted in sterilized soil. In all cases unless otherwise stated, the stems were in - oculated by removing the soil from around the stem, which was then disinfected, and a small wound made with a sterilized scalpel just below the surface of the ground. A small amount of the inoculum was then introduced into the wound and the soil packed back in position and a little sterile water added. Greenhouse Experiment* EXPERIMENT 1. MARCH. 1916 Plants of the Rural New Yorker variety growing in the greenhouse were inoculated at different ages with different strains of Fusarium orysporum in an attempt to observe any differences in the virulence of the strains or any indications of the plants showing different degrees of resistance as they became older. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Potato Wilt Ciuxrii hi/ Fiimirium Oxysporum 15 Set I. Three plants were inoculated when 2 to 5 inches in height with Fusariwm oxysporum, No. 1, grown on steamed potato cylinders. Plant 1 showed typical wilt and heavy infection throughout the vascular system. In plant 2 the mycelium of the fungus could be seen penetrating the vascular system of the stem for a short distance from the point »t inoculation; no wilting occurred in this case. Plant 3 remained healthy. Set t. Three plants were inoculated at the same age as those in Set 1 with Fusarium oxysporum No. 8. Plant 1 showed a heavy Infection and early wilting. Plants 2 and 3 showed only a slight penetration of the host and did not wilt. M f. Three plants 5 to 10 inches in height were inoculated with Fusarium oxysporum No. 1. None of these plants showed any symptoms of wilt and only in 2 instances was there a slight penetration of the host from the point of inoculation. Sft ). Three plants 5 to 10 inches in height were inoculated with Fuxarium oxi/xporum No. S. No wilting occurred. All plants showed a slight vascular discoloration for about 1 inch from the point of inocula - tion. Set 5. Six plants used as controls remained healthy except in one instance where a wilting of the tops occurred and from which Fusarium nxysporum was isolated. These few tests do not show consistent results, but do indicate that the inoculation of younger plants will give a higher per - i-entage of infection. There was no apparent difference in the _' strains of Fusarium oxysporum used. EXPERIMENT 2. MARCH, 1917 Four plants of the Rural New Yorker variety growing in the green - house were inoculated, just as the shoots were showing at the surface of the ground, with Fuxarium oxysporum No. 8. All 4 of these remained healthy. The previous test was repeated. Seed from the same source was used and inoculations were made with the same strain of Fuxarium oxytporum just as the sprouts broke thru the ground. Three of these plants showed early signs of wilt. The fungus was present abundantly in the vascular tissue, and was recovered in every instance in pure culture. One plant remained healthy. All control plants remained healthy. EXPERIMENT 3, FEBRUARY 21. 192* This experiment was conducted at two different temperatures, half of the plants being placed in a greenhouse maintained at 17°, and half in another house at 27°C. In each house 5 plants were inoculated when they were 10 days old and 4 others were used as controls. Some of the plants at each temperature were inoculated with Fusarium oxysporum No. 33, and some with No. 8. Results. — 17 a C. The plants were all examined May 6. Two plants were inoculated with Fusarium oxysporum No. 33. One stem of plant 1 was inoculated; there was no infection and the wound calloused over; 4 control stems remained healthy. One stem of plant 2 was inoculated, no wilt resulted, the wound calloused over and there was a slight pene - tration of the vascular system for ' 4 inch beyond wound; 2 control stems remained healthy. Three plants were inoculated with Fusarium oxy- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">\,/inix/,,i A;/ri' nl tn nil H.r/i. Station, /t'rxrinr/i Bill. 16 I turn No. 8. All wounds healed over and there was no infection or of wilt. All controls remained healthy. Hi.sultx. — 27°C. Four plants were inoculated with Fusarium oiy - npnrum No. 33. Three stems of plant 1 were inoculated; the tops wilted slightly, the wound on the stem healed over and there were diffuse light brown lesions around the stem but no rotting. Sections of the stem showed invasion of the vascular system and browning extending % inch above the wound. F. oxvxporum was recovered from the vascular system. Plant 2 remained healthy ; the wound healed over,, and there were no lesions or browning of the vascular system. Infection did not progress beyond the wound. Two stems of plant '■', were inoculated, there was no wilt but the organism invaded the vascular system for 1 inch above the wound and below as far as the roots. No external lesions were present. F. MMMM was recovered. Three stems of plant 4 were inoculated. One stem with healthy tops showed a slight invasion of the tissue around the wound, while 2 other stems with the tops completely wilted had the underground stem entirely rotted below ihe wound. One plant was in - oculated with Strain No. ft, There was no infection; the entire plant remained healthy, and the wound healed over. The controls remained EXPERIMENT 4. 1921-2: During the winter of 1921-22 a few inoculations were made on plants in the greenhouse. Tubers of the Bliss Triumph variety were planted in tuber units; 1 plant was used as a control and I others were inoculated, both- by stem inoculations and by injuring a water suspension of spores - on the soil at the same time. The plants were inoculated when they were 6 to 8 inches high. Three inoculated plains and 1 control were kept in a glass incubating chamber where the soil and air temperature was kept between 30 anil 36°C. The other set of 4 plants was kept at a temperature of about 24' The plants were dug and examined 6 weeks after inoculation. In the set at 30' to :S6 . plant 1 had 1 stem entirely dead and the other slightly yellowed. Plant 2 was entirely dead, apparently due to temperature Plant ;'. wilted completely. The control plant was also completely wilted In the set at 21 to 26° all plants showed a slight yellowing of the foliage, there was no complete wilt and no discoloration of the vascular system The control plant remained healthy. EXPERIMENT 5, DECEMBER. 1 Inoculation tests with other organisms to determine the relative values of the methods of inoculation were made in 1921. Cultures of Penitillium sp. and Hhizopux sp. were used in order to test whether the methods generally used in determining the parasitism of Fuxarium oiii - spurn m are so drastic that even very weak parasites would be able to pro - duce similar symptoms. Potato plants of the Bliss Triumph variety grown in the greenhouse at about 24°C. were Inoculated either by smearing the emerging sprout or by inserting into the stem portions of agar cultures of the. organisms to be tested. The plants were dug up and examined one month after being inoculated. limult*. — No wilting occurred in any of the plants. Plants inocu - lated with Penicillium sp. or Khizopu* sp. by smearing the emerging sprout remained healthy and the organisms did not penetrate the host </seg>
            <seg id="p017">r..t,,t» II ilt Cinm-il lit/ F'txtiiltun Oxyttpvmin 17 tissue. When the sprouts were wounded and the inoculum inserted it was found that both organisms had penetrated from 'i to H. inches beyond the point of inoculation. The vascular tissue was discolored, but the infection was not entirely confined to vascular tissue. Rhizopu* sp. was able to cause considerable more rotting than PeniciJHum sp. and produced symptoms very similar to those found in the inoculations with Vapor FieM Experiments EXPERIMENT 1. 1916 Mtlhwix. — Inoculation experiments with pure cultures were made on a large scale in the field in the summer of 1916 in Michigan. Potato plants of the Rural Sew Yorker variety grown from healthy seed were used for this experiment. Some of these plants were inoculated as soon as the sprouts showed thru the ground, others when they were 5 to 6 inches high. Inoculations were made either by introducing the organism into the stem just below the surface of the ground or by soil inoculation both with and without wounding the roots. The inoculum was obtained from HKlay-old potato plug cultures of Fuxarium oxyxporum. also with three varieties of F. ojygporum obtained in 1915 from C. O. Sherbakoff at Cornell (Diversity Altogether, about 1,000 plants were inoculated. The tubers were planted June 14 and 15, the sprouts were inoculated the last week in June, and the final results taken at digging time, September 10. During the experiment air temperature records were taken by means of a thermograph placed in a shelter in the center of the field. Soil tem - perature records were taken with maximum and minimum thermometers placed in the soil at the depth of 5 inches and readings taken every 24 hours. After August 15, a soil thermograph was used. Precipitation rec - ords were obtained from the United States Weather Bureau located about one mile away, and these give a fair indication of the moisture content. The air temperature was very high during the months of July and August. The mean maximum temperature for July was 91.8° (33.2° C.) and for August 84.9° F. (29.4° (\&gt;. The mean average temperature for July was 71. l c (21.7 C.) and for August 72.7° (22.6° C). The highest recorded temperature was 104' (40° C.I the 29th of August. It is worthy of notice that from the 20th of July to the 7th of August the lowest maximum temperature was 92° (33.3° C. 1. The soil temperature from July 20 to August 15 showed a mean maximum of 104° (40° C.) and a mean minimum of 63° (17.2° C. ). The highest temperature. 111* (43.9 C. I. was reached a number of times and was the highest that the only available thermometers at the time would record. Undoubtedly the temperature went higher than this on a number of days. After August 15, the soil temperature dropped considerably, owing to an Increase in the rainfall. The total precipitation for July was only .09 Inch and for August 1.58 inches. Results. — No typical wilting occurred in any of the thousand-odd plants inoculated. Kach hill was examined for infection by cutting sec - tions thru the root and tubers, and also thru the stem. More than 90 per cent of the inoculated plants were found to have a slight browning of the vascular system, and the controls contained a similar amount. A large number of cultures were made in the laboratory in an attempt to isolate the organism from these discolored vascular areas, but without exception they were unsuccessful. The combination of very low precipitation and very hiph </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Xebratka Agricultural Ex p. Station, Mmeareh Bui. JJ temperature during this experiment produced an environmental condition very unfavorable for the growth of the potato. Further - more, these conditions were also unfavorable for infection by Ftuarium oxyspontm even tho Fusarium wilt is usually considered a warm weather disease. It is evident that the low soil moisture content was not favorable for initial infection and therefore high temperatures combined with low moisture have no influence on the disease unless the moisture content has previously been high enough to permit the initial penetration by the causal organism. EXPERIMENT 2. 1921 During the summer of 19-21 a few inoculations of growing plants were made in the experimental potato fields at Lincoln and Mitchell. 1 Nebraska. In the Mitchell fields the experiments were conducted under both dry land and irrigated conditions. The air and soil temperature and moisture records are shown in Figures 3. 4. and 5. Healthy tubers of the Bliss Triumph variety planted in tuber units were used for these tests. Plot 1. Lincoln. — Tubers were planted June 4 and were inoculated June 25. Stem Inoculations were made the same as in previous experi - ments, every stem in each hill being inoculated. The plants were 4 to .'■ inches high at the time of inoculation. Four plants were inoculated with Fusarium oriixporum No. 1. 4 with No. 8. 6 with No. 35, and 8 with No. 56. One hill in each tuber unit was used as a control. Results. — Xone of the plants at any time showed symptoms of wilt - ing. Both inoculated and control plants were small and considerably dwarfed, due to the high temperature of both soil and air. The plants were dug September 2. All Inoculated plants showed a browning of the vascular system from the point of inoculation to the base of the stem, while the control plants remained healthy. Plot 2. Dry Land. Mitchrll. — The tubers were planted May 2&lt;». in - oculations were made June 17. when the plants were from 1 to 6 inches in height. Stem Inoculations were made in the same way as the previous experiments. Five plants were inoculated with Fusariwm nsusporum No. 35 and 5 with No. 56. Results. — On August 16 one plant inoculated with Strain No. 35 showed typical Fusarium wilt. All other inoculated plants and controls remained healthy. These plants were dug September 21. Of the 4 re - maining plants inoculated with No. 35, 1 was perfectly healthy and I showed a browning of the vascular system of the stem. One of these 3 produced tubers showing vascular browning. Of the 5 plants inoculated with No. 56, 2 remained healthy. One plant showed vascular browning of the stem and produced 1 tuber out of 6 showing vascular browning. Plot S, Irrigation. Mitchell. — Tubers of the same lot as those in Plot 2 were planted and inoculated at the same time. The plants averaged about 4 inches in height when inoculated. Six plants were inoculated with Fusarium orysporum No. 35 and 6 with No. 56. Results. — No wilting occurred in any of the 12 inoculated plants, altho when dug September 21, practically every stem showed considerable 1 SeotU Bluff Substation, located at Mitchell, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I'dtnto Wilt Caused by Fu*uriuin Oxytsporum 19 vascular browning: no rotting of the stem was present and no infected tubers were produced. DISCUSSION Tlie&gt;e preliminary tests of the pathogenicity of Fusarium &lt;&gt;j-y*l&gt;orum made in a similar way to those reported in various |&gt;a]&gt;er&gt; on this disease show very clearly that consistent results are not obtained by these methods even tho the methods of in - oculation are drastic enough to permit similar symptoms to ap - pear when inoculations are made with relatively weak parasites. The large number of negative results indicates clearly that F. osi/nponim i&gt; not a very virulent or a very destructive organ - ism. These tests also show that the plant is more susceptible to infection during the earlv growth. It is also shown that con - siderable tissue may be infected and the vascular system distinctly discolored without any symptoms of wilt appearing on the plant. The experiments in the greenhouse indicated that high tempera - tures favor the development of the disease. However, the field experiments conducted in 1916 show clearly that an extremely high temperature and a very low soil moisture content produce conditions unfavorable for infection. Under these conditions a discoloration of the vascular system occurs that is not connected in iinv wav with the disease. TRANSMISSION OF FUSARIUM WILT BY INFECTED SEED Review of the Literature VASCl'LAR DISCOLORATION OF TUBERS Tntil very recently it has l&gt;een commonly believed, as evi - denced by the oft rej&gt;eated assertions found in bulletins, circulars, am) in practically all the information given to the farmers reta - in e to Fusariuni wilt of potatoes, that a plant infected with Fusarium wilt will produce tul&gt;ers showing a brownish discolora - tion of the vascular system, and that a tuber showing vascular browning was produced by an infected plant: further, that a tuber showing such vascular discoloration will, if planted, pro - duce infected plants. Control measures based upon this hypothesis have been rec - ommended extensively in advising remedial measures to the grower for the control of Fusarium wilt. This method of control appears very simple, i. e.. the elimination of infected tubers by discarding entire tul&gt;ers or cutting away the discolored portions of infected tubers. In recent years a number of papers have been published that do not agree with the earlier reports. Never- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 \'i linixhii \ ii in ul t n i at h\rit Station h'l x» ,11 1 h Hill '■{ theless. the popular bulletins on potato diseases still contain this information. Inasmuch as there is this conflict of data and also no published review of the literature, it was thought worth while to present a brief review of the various papers presenting ex - perimental evidence on this point. t Smith and Swingle (1904) were probably the first to draw s conclusion and to recommend such control measures. They te (p. 59) : I The first symptoms in the tuber are nearly always at the stem end the form of browned or blackened vascular bundles. They also report that cultures made from the discolored vas - cular bundles very seldom failed to develop the fungu-. As re - gards control measures, they recommend (p. 80): The greatest care should be taken to avoid the infection of healthy land by the planting of diseased tubers. All tubers designed for seed should be cut at the stem end and carefully inspected before planting. do not, however, give any detailed experiments in ich tul)ers showing vascular browning and from which the sal organism had lx&gt;eii isolated were planted and resulted in ted plants. Manns (1911) report* field experiments in which stvd having \;i-cular discoloration was planted after various treatments, and compared with healthy x-ed of the same variety. It is unfor - tunate that the results arc chiefly based upon yield in bushels rather than upon the percentage of diseased plants. He concludes from his experiments that the percentage of increase in yield obtained from cutting away the infected portion of the combined with formaldehyde treatment varied with the amount of infection in the seed from — 5 per cent to -f-42 per cent. His re-ults (Table 5, p. 3:27) show considerable variation. One of the plots shows a decrease in yield when the infected portion of the seed-piece is cut away: others show variable increases in yield.-. It is noticeable that in the plot showing the greatest increase, 42.^!&lt;&gt; per cent, the total yield is only about 50 bushels per acre, in - dicating that there were probably other factors present not under control that were materially reducing the yield. In many in - stances the variation in yield between plots with the same treat - ment was as great as the increased yields claimed for the treat - nent. showing a considerable experimental error. It is unfor - tunate that while the different experiments were conducted in 5 different counties, no records of environmental conditions are given, it is very possible that the environmental conditions would influence the amount of the disease and the average yields as much as the amount of infection supposedly present in the seed </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum 21 used. It must l*&gt; remembered that in all these tests we have to do with tubers showing internal discoloration and not necessarily with Fusarium oxysporum^ as no isolations were reported from the seed tubers. He also notes (p. 325) in one experiment that: Fusarium symptoms showed up distinctly on 71.1 per cent of the vines, six weeks before maturity, while the non-infected plot showed only 4.7 per cent of the vines infected. And again, (p. 328) ho reports 7(5 per cent of tubers showing internal infection when grown from infected seed against less than 1 per cent in tubers from seed in which the infection had been cut away. As a result of his work, Manns concludes (p. 336) : Internally infected tubers are the chief means of distributing the disease * * * * The infection may be removed from slightly infected Mad by clipping away the stem end and following by external treatment with formaldehyde. Link (1910. p. 188). referring to this method of infection, states: Infection carried over by the mother tuber, which is frequent, rarely permits the growth of stems more than 20 cm. high, and seldom allows the development of tubers. lie does not present any ex|K&gt;iimental data to substantiate this point. If this statement is correct, we should expect that in such experiments as those descril&gt;ed by Manns there would be a more marked difference in yield: in fact, we could hardly expect any yield at all. As far as the author is aware. Bisbv (1910) was the first to siilmiit exj&gt;erimental evidence showing that seed having vascular discoloration and having been obtained from wilted vines often produced normal plants. His data (p. 14) indicate that — serious disease does not necessarily follow from planting seed from wilted vines, and that no more wilt may result from the use of stem ends than frooi the use of eye ends. He mentions, however, the general undesirability of seed from wilted plants and further states (p. 14) : Selecting seed or clipping the stem ends is, however, not alone suf - ficient to avoid loss from wilt. His experiments while not as extensive as those of Manns (1911) were accompanied bv some isolations from the seed to determine the presence of Fuxarium owy*portnn and his results are clear-out. Haskell (1019). working in New York, states: Fusarium oxysporum is undoubtedly disseminated by means of the seed tuber. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Xt hrtlxkit Af/riruftiiral fc'-r//. Station, llcxi-unli /!"/ 22 However, lie immediately qualities this statement in the fol - lowing sentence by saying: When affected potatoes are planted the plants arising therefrom may be diseased provided the proper conditions exist. lie reports exi&gt;erimental plantings of seed showing distiiu-t f?m end hTCunung compared with healthy seed with no vascular scoloration. He bases his results on comparative yields and j&gt;er cent of diseased seed in the resulting crop, and not on per- Itage of wilted vines. His results show that the infected seed lded only !&gt;.&lt;; o/.. |*&gt;r hill against 13.3 oz. for healthy seed. Nn a are given as to the size of the experimental plots or total Id. He also found that in the resulting crop 37 per cent of tubers from infected seed wen- diseased against 42 per cent m the healthy seed. He attributes this large amount of in - tion in the check plot to the fact that infection occurred from soil. He also reports some ex]&gt;eriments with a small number tubers from which in no case were there ."&gt;&lt;l per cent of the re ting plants showing disease. He does not mention any control ntings but nevertheless concludes (p. -240 1 from these experi - nts that : They show that the causal factor may be communicated to some extent at least through the seed tubers. On the other hand diseased seed often gives rise to plants that produce a healthy crop. This may be either because those tubers do not harbor the pathogene or because it is present but conditions are unfavorable for sufficient development. He agrees with Mann.-. &lt;1!&gt;11) and lii-liy (l'.il'.t). however. in concluding that affected seed results in a lowering of the yield. He advises against the planting of seed containing over ."&gt; per cent of "Fusarium necrosis." Seed having less than this amount can be used providing badly diseased tuliers are removed either by "greening' and selection for strong germinating power or by cutting the stem ends and discarding diseased tubers. MacMillan (1910). studying the disease under irrigated con - ditions in Colorado, states in his summary ( p. 301 ) : Vascular infection of the seed is not the starting point of disease. but is one of the conditions assisting in bringing about decreased resist - ance to new infection from the soil. His experiments are more extensive, especially as to the in - spection of individual seed-pieces and cultural studies, than any of the above reviewed work. The results are more clear-cut and are given in percentages of diseased plants rather than in yield. He conducted several experiments where seed having vascular infection and from which Fusarium sp. had been isolated, </seg>
            <seg id="p023">I'nUrt, Wilt (niisxl hi/ Fimirium Oxysporvm 23 yielded results which would support his conclusions stated above. He divided his tuliers in half, and the records of the twins are given from note- taken 4 times during the summer and sum - marized under u different headings, indicating the absence or presence and severity of the disease. There are comparatively few eases in which 2 hills from the same seed-pieces produced similar symptoms of disease, and this percentage was no greater than that found in hill- from healthv seed. He reports experiments where seed tubers of the Early Ohio variety obtained from wilted plants showing vascular discolora - tion and yielding Fusariiim sp. in culture showed less disease than the plots planted with supposedly healthv seed. He found thiit wd of the IVarl variety obtained from wilted hills produced a larger percentage of hills with no germination or seed-piece rotting, and the author accoiints for this by stating (p. 204) : Plainly these plants have been weakened by disease, their power of resistance lessened, and their vigor impaired. Examination showed that soil infection acted here to produce the disease. It i&gt; true that while cultures were made in many cases from diseased seed, the organisms recovered were simply classed as Fusarium sp.. which does not prove that Fumrium orygporum was the onlv organism lieing dealt with. In general, however, it era In- -aid (hat these results distinctly disagree with many previous publications and show dearly that, under the condi - tions of the experiment at least. Fusarium wilt carried over in the seed-piece is not an important factor in transmitting the dis - ease. It is also shown that seed obtained from wilted hills will product 1 weaker plants that are more susceptible to soil infection. Kdson (1020), studying the relation of vascular discolora - tion of the seed to the disease, presents the most extensive ex - periments recorded to date on the relation of vascular discolora - tion to the presence of a causal organism and to the resulting disease in the plants. He used tul&gt;ers obtained from 1'.* different -ources and divides these into 'I groups, obscure disease group. healthy group, ami parasitic disease group. Cultures were made from seed tulters to determine the presence or absence of organ - i-nis. and these tulier- were planted in 2 lots. 1 in Wisconsin and the other in Colorado. Results are presented in nuinl&gt;er and |H*r - centage of diseased plants. lie finds that vascular discoloration is often present in the absence of any organism, and that organ - isms are frequently present when the tissue appears healthy: out of 3.203 cultures, only 1.851 revealed the presence of organ - isms and of tliex- Fusariiim sp. were present only 720 times. His field experiments indicate ( p. 2!&gt;4) — </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Xt-hratka .\&lt;n'« "It'inil Esp. Station, Renearch Bui. 23 that neither vascular discoloration nor fungus invasion of the tissues of the mother tuber is a guarantee of disease in the resulting plants, nor is their absence a guarantee of health. IK' lielieves the soil to be the chief source of infection. De - tailed results are given in a comparison of the plantings at Wis - consin and Colorado. In general there was more disease present in the Colorado plots than in those at Wisconsin, particularly when cut seed was used. He also notes that the plants were often capable of recovery from disease, particularly in Colorado. While these ex|&gt;eriinents afforded an excellent opportunity for studying the effects of environmental conditions on the progre» of the disease, no detailed information as to the environmental condi tions under which the ex|&gt;eri!iieiits were conducted is given except where it is stated (p. -J7!0 that — one lot being planted on a light, sandy soil, under rainfall, at Waupaca, Wts., and the other on a heavy play loam under irrigation at Greeley, Colo. There is no detailed discussion given on the results of these dif - ferent environmental conditions other than that stated above. While the results show clearly that the soil rather than the seed - piece is the chief source of infection, it also appears from a study of the data that diseased seed results in a larger percentage of infected plants from soil infection. This is shown clearly by a comparison of the three different groups. The "healthy group" compared with the "parasitic disease group" shows a small per - centage of diseased plants for both cut and whole seed and under Ixrth Wisconsin and Colorado conditions, regardless of the fact that the healthy seed showed nearly a&gt; much vascular discolora - tion (about A'2. per cent) as compared with 44 per cent for the parasitic group. As regard* the percentage of cultures showing growth, there was 7(i per cent for the healthy and only 72 per cent for the parasitic group, and about '2"&gt; per cent of the organ - isms isolated in both cases were either Funarhim oxy«porum or Fusarinm sp. exclusive of F. iJincnlor far. mlphurem (Schlect.) App. and Wollenw. Thus, the amount of infection that could have l»een carried over would have l&gt;een about the same in both groups, yet the parasitic group yielded about 10 per cent more diseased plants than the healthy group, this being especially true in the case of whole seed. It is worthy of note that in the para - sitic group, more diseased plants resulted from whole seed than from cut seed, while the reverse is ture for the healthy group for l»oth Wisconsin and Colorado plots. As regards the "obscure disease group." he states that a large amount of hereditary disease was present in this group. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 t'otuto Wilt (("/*&lt;&lt;/ hi/ t muiriiiii, Oxysporum and this is clearly shown from the tables presented. The group shows the smallest number of tubers having vascular discolora - tion. the lowest percentage of cultures giving growth, and a very low ]x&lt;rcentage. alnmt &lt;"&gt; per cent, of these positive cultures yield - ing Fuxitrimit oxyn/Htntm or Fusarium sp. ; and yet the largest percentage of diseased plants is found in this group, being about double that of the parasitic group. Here, again, more disease is found in plants from whole seed than from cut seed. Edson concludes (p. 204) that: Stem-end seed-pieces yielded slightly higher percentages of disease than eye-end pieces, evidently because the stem end is endowed with less physiological resistance. McKay &lt;1!&gt;21). studying some wilt diseases of potatoes in Oregon, also takes up the question of the occurrence of Fusarium oxyxporinii in discolored tubers and the amount of disease re - -uitinj: therefrom and draws conclusions similar to those of Edson ( IWft) and MacMillan (1019). The results of his isolations from tubers showing vascular discoloration show clearly that this fac - tor cannot be relied on as a criterion in judging the presence of F. oxyxjiorunt. He isolated F. oxysporum from 205 tubers, or 2.4 percent of all the tubers cultured. His results also indicated that F. oxysporum i* associated with a darker discoloration of the vascular tissues than either F. radiricola Wollenw., or Verticil - lium albo-ntmm Reinke and Berthold. His field experiments also show that F. oxysponnn is transmitted to only a slight extent thru seed tuliers. His results are given, not in yields or percentage of diseased plants, but in percentage of resulting tubers yielding the organism. He obtained from seed known to be infected with F. nxyxporniu only :$.s per cent of /'. oxygpormn infected tubers, while he obtained l.fi per cent from seed yielding no organisms and S.."» j&gt;er cent from seed yielding F. radiricola, an organism that i- not known to produce a wilt. He also found that stem - end seed-pieces of infected tubers do not seem to give any more disease than the eye ends of the same tubers. He concludes that t lie difference in eye end and stem end is so slight that it is not advisable to rely on the practice of discarding the stem ends to avoid wilt. Altho no data are given on the number of wilted plants, his results taken from cultures obtained from the tubers produced would not indicate as great a difference in susceptibility to disease of eye and stem-end seed-pieces as was reported by Edson (1020)." Thus we find considerable discrepancy, not only in the opinion of various workers but also in their experimental data. The preponderance of careful experimental evidence favors the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Xebrnska Agricultural Esp. Station. Research Bui. view that vascular discoloration in the tul&gt;er i&gt; not always a good index of the presence of Fwuiriuw itj-ynporum, or of the fact that disease will result even tho the organism is present. Neverthe - less, such discolored seed appears more susceptible to infection from outside sources. The experimental evidence is rather con - flicting in regard to the value of discarding discolored stem ends of seeil tubers, no clear-cut evidence having l&gt;een presented to show that ii decrease in Fiisariuiu will can In 1 expected by this method of control. \ AStTl.AH DISCOLORATION OF STEMS Very few experimental data have l»een published on the rela - tion U'lween the vascular discoloration of the stein and the pres - ence of F axil rin in iwi/M/Hiriiin. There arc. however, a considerable number of published statements, witli little or no experimental data, to the effect that the presence of the vascular discoloration of the stem at the surface of the ground and below i» one of the lie further savs that culture from wilted plant-, particularly from the interior of the stem near the surface of the soil, ino.-t frequently yielded Funarium iisi/Mpitrmn. However, he readily obtained cultures of F. ojnjxportnn from normal plants killed by frost and showing a browning on the inside of the stems at the surface of the ground. In thi&gt; case it would appear, ;i- Bisby states, that the browning was due to unfavorable environmental chief &gt;i&lt;rn&gt; &lt;»f Fusariiini wilt Mnitli and Swingle t 1:mi4 p. Hi state: Sections cut at the surface of the ground showed only very few hyphae or none at all. There was, however, u marked browning of the tissues, particularly of the vascular ring. '.Ml Manns i 1 '. &gt; 1 1 ) in tI*--«-ril &gt;t n«jr the -vmptnius of Kii.-aiiuin wilt (p. IK* 4 .) -tat.'-: Cross sections of the large roots and the stem at a level with the ground or below show some or all of the \eswls to be of a brown or dull gray discoloration. Ilf further state- 1 1&gt;. .".I.")) : No difficulty is exiwrienced in taking the parasitic organisms from the infected tubers and plants Hisby (1919) discussing the symptoms of potato wilt in Minnesota (p. 8) -ays: A cross section of the lower stem reveals the browning of the vascular system and often of the other tissues as well. This browning may extend to the tips of the plants, though the bundles are often free from hyphae in these upper discolored areas. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Potato Wilt Cnuned hij Fnxarium Oxyxpoi urn 27 conditions and that the organism was present more or less sapro phytieally. In general it may be said that the use of this sign in diag - noMiifr Fusariura wilt has been based chiefly upon observational evidence, i. e.. the presence of a vascular discoloration of the stem accompanying wilt of the plant. It is also based upon the fact that infection obtained by wounding the stem and inserting the inoculum sometime* results in a discoloration of the vascular system by the penetration of the organism. However, as stated by ])isbv. browning of the vascular region of the stem may be brought about by frost injury, and the writer will also attempt in prove that browning may also be brought about by other un - favorable environmental conditions. It i~ also known that Fusarium oxysporum is not the only organism capable of producing this effect. Edson and Shapo - valov ( 1920) found that F. trirhothecioides Wollenw. was capable of invading the vascular bundles. Link (1916) also obtained in inoculation experiments with F. trichothecioides a blackening of the vasmlar bundles extending even into the petiole and leaf veins. The writer has obtained slight vascular discoloration with -iicli organisms as PeniciU'mm sp. and Rhizopus sp., and the browning of vascular elements by V erticillium albo-atrum is a well-known sign accompanying the wilt caused by that organism. While these organisms may produce symptoms typically different from those of F. oxysporum. yet it must be remembered that ....... _ _ . ,7 1 7 *" ~ ™ under field conditions with different environmental factors pres - ent we arc often concerned with what might be termed atypical cases. T'ntil the differences in symptoms caused by environ - mental factors are determined, it is not advisable to use such a triable symptom in diagnosing the disease. It i- also true that plants may wilt and die from infection with Fiixorinm tmftptmm from the soil, due to a rotting of the roota, without any vascular discoloration of the stem being pres - ent. The writer has found this to tie true in inoculation experi - ments as well as under field conditions. Tlic writer is not aware of any single instance in published reports of this disease where a distinct vascular discoloration of the stem, without accompanying rotting of the parenchyma, has ever been produced experimentally by infection with pure cul - tures, except where the organism was introduced directly into the vascular elements. Thus, we may have a browning of these elements not due to FitD/irium oxyttporum, and we may also have a Fusarium wilt pro - duced without any evidence of browning, and under these condi- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Xthraxkii Agru-ultural Kxp. Station, llenearrh Hnl. 28 tions this sign of the disease would not be of value in determining the amount of infection in the field unless accompanied by other symptoms. Greenhouse Experiments with Seed Having Vascular Discoloration EXPERIMENT 1. 1915 Tubers of the Rural Xew Yorker variety were obtained from a field showing a high percentage of wilt on the college farm at Kast Lansing. Michigan. The tul&gt;ers showed a distinct brown discoloration for one-fourth to one-half the length of the tuber, and Fimarium orynpnrum was i-olated from a high percentage of these tulx'rs. Methods. — Tubers were planted February 9 and dug and examined May S. All tubers were treated with either mercuric chloride or for - maldehyde and planted in sterilized soil. The temperature of the green - house was abnormally high for the growth of potatoes, about 85°F. (29.5°C.t, and as a result the yellowing and wilting of the vines could not be taken as a positive indication of infection. Diagnosis was made by an examination of the vascular system of the stem and tuber, followed by cultural work. Results. — SET I. Thirteen plants were grown from seed tubt showing vascular discoloration. The results showed 4 healthy plan 5 with a slight browning of the vascular system, and 4 with a heavy fection of the vascular system from which Funariwm MfiptrM w i\ isolated. SBT '.. — Nine plants were grown from seed tubt colored portion cut away. The results showed ti healthy pUuita, 1 slight infection, and 2 with a heavy infection of the vascular syste SET d.— Eight infected tubers were cut in half, the bud stem ends being planted separately. The bud-end pieces produced healthy plants and 1 slightly infected. The stem-end pieces produced healthy plants and 6 infected. SET '). — Seven tubers were planted showing a slight infection. F of these produced infected plants from which the causal organism was IV covered, while 3 plants remained healthy £ET ■'&gt;. — Sixteen tubers were planted showing a slight infection: i. e., discoloration did not extend 1 inch. The stem ends were cut away to the depth of 1 inch and discarded: the seed was then treated with formaldehyde. 10 of the resulting plants showed infection. Further tests were made in the greenhouse in 1920 Tubers showing vascular discoloration were divided into 2 lots and grown at 17° and 27° C. All plants remained healthy. These few tests proved that the disea.se was capable under the conditions of the experiment of living over winter in the tuber and producing an infected plant the following year. How - ever, the typical symptoms of wilt were produced in only a few cases, altho the organism was present in the vascular system of the stems. The bud end of infected tubers usually produced healthy plants, altho an attempt to cut away the stem end even of </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Potato Wilt ('mixed /,)/ /• 'tixn riii nt O.ri/K/jonim 29 slightly infected tubers for a fixed distance of 1 inch did not if&gt;wlt in uniformly healthy plant-. One plant of this series showed a condition that the author has frequently found in later experiments and in field trials. The seed tuber showed discoloration of the vascular system and F nxii r'i a in oj-yHporum was isolated. The plant produced from this iiiIht ■ppoamn healthy. Upon examination at the close of the experiment the seed-piece was found to be sound, and the causal organism nt again isolated from the vascular system. The vas - cular infection, however, had not progressed far enough to pene - trate the tissue of the buds, and the resulting plant remained ealthv Field Experiments on Seed Transmission EXPERIMENT 1. ISIS 'I'lii- experiment *u conducted on land not previously planted lu potatoes for ;it least 17 years. Methods. — The infected tubers were all obtained in Michigan and were of the Rural New Yorker variety. They were divided into two group?. 1. Slightly infected seed, i. e., seed in which the vascular dis - coloration extended not more than y% inch. 2. Deeply infected seed, 1. e., seed with more extensive vascular discoloration. Most of the seed was treated with either mercuric chloride or formaldehyde, either before or after cutting. In other experiments no treatment was given.' Notes were taken on the amount of wilt appearing in all rows throughout the experiment, and at digging time each hill was examined for vascular discoloration of the underground stem and also of the tubers produced. In all the following tables the percentages of infected plants are based upon the number of hills germinated, rather than upon the number of hills anted. Healthy tubers of the same variety were used for controls. PUt l Four row- of 63 hills each were planted with healthy seed. Four more row- were planted one-half their length with healthy amd and the other half with slightly infected seed. The seed was cut into stem and bud-end halves, the halves being planted in alternate row-. Rex'iltx. — The results of this test are shown in Table 1. The rows planted with infected seed showed considerable wilting and premature dying during August, whereas the healthy rows re - mained green until frost. ' No data are presented in regard to these treatment*, as the results did not show any correlation between the various treatments and the amount of resulting disease, and inasmuch as the data are not presented in yields, they were not considered to be a factor in the results presented here. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Xebraska Agricultural Esp. Station. Research, Bui. 23 30 Table 1. — Percentage of infected plants from healthy seed &lt;i* compared with plants from seed showing vascular disrnloration Field Experiment 1. Plot 1 No distinct correlation i» found lietween tin- number of hills germinated and the vascular discoloration of the seed. The small amount of infected plants present in the control row- «a~ prob - ably due to soil infection but does not materially affect the rela tion between the healthy and disease! seed. The amount of dis - ease present in the progeny from diseased seed was much higher than from the healthy seed. The amount of disease produced li\ stem-end pieces was only slightly higher than from bud-end halves. The presence of the very small amount of disease in the control halves of the infected rows does not show any indication of the disease being spread thru the crop by cultivation, as sug - gested by several authors. In regard to the vascular discoloration of tubers produced, there were more infected tulx-rs found in the rows planted with infected seed than in the controls. The presence of the causal organism was not determined, but there is certainly a distinct correlation between this vascular discoloration and the presence of vascular discoloration in the mother tuber. PM 2 Rows of 65 hills each were planted with deeply infected seed, and these were alternated with rows of healthy seed, the object being not only to compare the two kinds of seed, but also to test the possibility of the disease spreading from row to row. /tesitlts.— Plants from infected seed were badly wilted in August and died prematurely, while the control rows remained Seed Plants wilted Number I or with vaseular of blank discoloration hills of stem Resulting number of tubers with vascular discoloration Per cent Per cent Per cent Controls, 4 rows 4.0 25.4 1.3 infected seed Bud ends four ' •&gt; rows Stem ends 33.8 16.0 45.0 50.0 12.4 19.3 Controls, four }-$ rows 1.6 41.0 .6 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Potato Wilt Vanned by Fumrbim Oxysponim 31 \ tealthy. The results presented in Table 2 again show the much .neater number of diseased plants in the rows from seed with .Hscular discoloration. While the amount of infection was ■ lisrhtlv higher in the controls than was found in Plot 1, it is (Dm /Hirison of healthy seed with seed having deep Tabi vascular discoloration Field Experiment 1. Plot 2 Plants wilted Number Resulting number or with vascular of hills of tubers with discoloration blank vascular discoloration of stem Per cent Per cent 4.S 6.0 68.0 18.1 «J u 24.3 64.0 13.6 v&gt; 10.0 33.0 75.0 21.1 ;«.4 :S.:j 12.1 vo :f.W 13.6 Average of healthy and diseased rows Kov.s Healthy 7.1 12.3 .: Disei.x-.i G9.0 21.1 not probable tiiat it was spread from adjacent infected rows, inasmuch as Rows 1 and :5 show less infection than other control rows farther removed from the diseased seed. There was no correlation between diseased seed and the number of hills failing to gerniiiiitti'. Altlio the averages show greater failure to germi- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Xetfraska Agricultural Etp. Statiot. Research Bui. 23 nate in the rows planted with diseased seed, this does not hold true when the individual rows are examined. As in Plot 1, there was a greater number of diseased t iiIhts produced from diseased rows than from healthy row-. Ptoi 3 This plot was composed of h rows of 65 plants each. All M'fd iixmI in this test war- discolored for a considerable depth. The infected portion of some of the seed was cut away to deter - mine the effect upon the transmission of the disease. The bud and stem ends of tul)ers were kept separate in every case and planted in nlternatr rows. /iixttltg. — The results presented in Table 3 show that in the case of it deep infection it was not possible to remove successfully all the infected portion &lt;&gt;f the tuber. There was also no clear relation between the amount of infection present in plants pro - duced from bud ends and stein ends. Neither was there any relation l&gt;et\veen cutting away the infected portion and the num- r.vBI.K :'.. — (&lt;im /xu-ixDii nf /ihintx ij row ii from bud-end* and gt , mix -if tuber* showing rtmrulor dixcol oration and irfoo of ttiher* with thU discoloration rut &lt;i" Field Experimenl 1. l'U Seed Plants wilted &lt;&gt;r with vascular discoloration of stem Number of blank hills Number of tubers with vascular disroloratior Per rent Per cent Per cent 1 No treatment, bud end 85.0 21.6 37.7 2 No treatment, stem end 50.0 73.5 22.2 3 No treatment, bud end 75.0 41.0 45.0 4 No treatment, bud end 93.0 26.0 47.0 5 No treatment, stem end 87.0 42.0 35.0 • Inf. cut away, bud end '; 75.0 22.0 32.0 7 Inf. cut away, stem end 62.0 33.0 19.0 8 Inf. cut away, bud end . 79.0 53.0 36.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">/' Wilt Caused In/ Futuirium Oxytporvm 33 kt of l&gt;lank 1* i 11- : them was a slightly greater average percentage H.4 |&gt;&lt;r cut ) of blank hills in the "no treatment" seed than in the «eed from which infection was cut away (36 percent). Also, there wa« a difference in the iiiiiiiIht of blank hills planted with stein ends. ;&gt;(;.] avenge per rent, as compared with 28.7 average per &lt;fnt for plants from l&gt;ud ends. In regard to the resulting tubers showing vascular discoloration, there was no relation either ■tween bud and stem ends or between cut and uncut seed. PUt 4 In this plot tubers with slight infection were divided into 2 -•■t-. one-half of tin 1 uiImts having the infected portion cut away. Two row- of ftfi plants each were planted in each Mt. Caulk 4. — Effict of cutting away discolored portions of tubers having only &lt;i flight discoloration Field Ex]M'riincnt 1. Plot 4 Plants wilted Number Number of tubers discoloration than iu found in Plot ■'&gt; with plants from seed with a deep discoloration. It was also noticeable that there were nearly 1"&gt; per cent fewer infected plants when the infected portion of the seed was removed. However, the amount of infection was still x) hijfh that this wa* apparently not a very practical method of controlling (he disease. There was no apparent difference in the amount of •Termination. There were slightly fewer resulting tabm tbowiag diacolomtiaa when the infected portion of the seed wa- removed. EXPERIMENT 2. ltlC Further experiments on the transmission of Fusarium wilt by means of internally infected seed, as well as attempted control measures, were undertaken. The method of work was very simi - lar to that descril&gt;ed in the previous exj&gt;erinients except that it was carried out on a larger scale. Treatment or with vascular of blank with vascular discoloration of stem hills discoloration Per eenl Per cent Per cent nfection not cut away 42.0 37.5 17.5 nfect ion cut away 28.2 35.0 13.5 RctmU*.- -TIh-iv \\a&gt; le&gt;- infection from set*&lt;l showing slight </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Xehiimka Affriciiltural Krp. Station. Research Bui. S3 The results were so uniformly negative that no detailed data will be presented. Very few of the plants in any of the plots showed even slight symptoms of wilt during the summer. At digging time over 90 per cent of the plants, including not only the infected seed both cut and uncut, and with various treatments, but also all controls, showed a browning of the vascular system of both the stems and tubers. Attempts to isolate the causal organ - ism resulted in failures except in a very few instances out of hundreds of isolations. It is interesting to note that most of the infected seed used in this experiment came from a field showing almost 100 per cent wilt the previous season. The conditions of both soil and air thruout the experiment were radically different from those present the preceding year (Field Experiment 1). when such marked wilting occurred. The detailed meteorological data for tins experiment are given on page 17. The weather thruout all of July and part of August was extremely hot and dry in contrast with the moist cool summer of 1915. These con - ditions, which were found to be unfavorable for infection in the inoculation experiments (p. 17), are also unfavorable for the development of the disease from infected seed. The type of brown discoloration present in this experiment was not due to infection with Fusarium wilt, but rather to the unfavorable environmental conditions under which the crop was growing. This non-parasitic browning was also found in in oeulation experiments (p. 17) and is also mentioned by Edson (19-20) as having been ol&gt;served in plots in ilie vicinity of Wash - ington. EXPERIMENT 3 In the spring of V.)-2l a small lot of Early Ohio tubers show - ing varying degrees of vascular discoloration were divided up into three lots: slight, medium, and deep discoloration. Each tuber was cut in half and the corresponding halves planted at Lincoln and at Mitchell. Nebraska. Each tuber was divided into stein-end and bud-end halves. The lot at Mitchell was grown under dry conditions. The weather for both locations i- shown in Figures 3, 4, and 5. The fields were examined several times during the growing season and at no time was there any typical wilt present in any of the lots. The results at digging time showed a considerable number of plants with vascular discoloration in the stems and tubers. The number of plants was too small to draw general con - clusions, altho there appeared no clear-cut difference in the num - ber of stems showing vascular discoloration under the 2 different </seg>
            <seg id="p035">1'otatii ]\'ilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum 35 environmental conditions, or in the various lots of seed. Plants from seed with slight discoloration grown at Lincoln had a smaller number of vascular discolored stems and yet these same plants show the greatest number of tubers having vascular dis - coloration. It was noticeable that the yield was much greater at Mitchell, showing a more favorable environment for the plants. In Table 5 is seen a comparison of the yield of deeply in - fected seed with the other 2 lots. While no wilting occurred and the percentage of plants showing vascular discolored stems and tubers was no greater with deeply infected seed than in the other Fabi.k ."&gt;.- -.1 rerage yield in grams per plant from slight, medium, and deeply discolored seed tubers lata, it is clearly seen that the yield per plant was materially lessened both at Mitchell and Lincoln. This shows further evi - dence that such seed should not be used even tho under certain conditions the disease is not transmitted. The largest yield of healthy tubers was found in the lot planted with slightly infected seed. The yield from bud ends was also considerably greater than the yield from stem ends. CONCLUSIONS The review of the literature shows that in the earlier papers on Fusarium wilt it was generally accepted that a plant showing Fusarium wilt would produce tubers with vascular discoloration, indicating the presence of the causal organism, and that these tubers would in turn produce an infected plant. Recommended control methods were based upon this hypothesis. The later papers show a decided shift in this attitude and clearly state that this hypothesis does not hold and that the seed tuber is not the chief source of infection; further that the cutting away of sup- Fiel M [ Kxp. Experiment 3 &gt;erimi lent A i tmi Yield per plant in grams Yield pi Lincoln Mitchell Slight discoloration ■•■■-■ 143 430 Medium discoloration 154 297 Deep discoloration 71 192 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Xehrwtkit Atiri'iiltmnl Kxp Station, /i'rxmn h Bui. J&gt; posedly infected portions of •the tulx-r may l&gt;e really harmful rather than beneficial. The experimental evidence presented in this pa|&gt;er shows that in the greenhouse, in tests where sterilized soil was used, the disease was carried over in the tuber. The percentage of infection from such tubers was small, but still as high as in the previous experiments where artificial inoculations with pure cultures were employed. Very often infected tubers showing vascular discolor - ation, and also yielding the causal organism in pure culture. failed to produce wilted plants. In many instances, altho no wilting was produced, the causal organism was found to l&gt;e pres - ent in the stem and roots of the plants. Experiments conducted in the field showed that under the conditions of Field Experi - lueiit 1 (]&gt;. ■_".»} Fusarium wilt was transmitted yfiru the seed tubers and that the amount of resulting disease was directly ]&gt;m portional to the severity of the infection in the seed, as indicated by the depth of discoloration of the vascular system. It was also found that in cases of slight discoloration attempts to remove the infected portion of the tulier resulted in a decrease of about 14 [mm- cent in the amount of disease. With deeply infected tuU&gt;r». such attempted removal of infected portion- of the &lt;*•*•([ resulted in no decrease in the amount of disease, and in these deeply in - fected tubers there was no appreciable difference in the amount of disease in the progeny of stem and bud-end seed-pieces. Tt was also shown the following year i Field Experiment ■_'. p. 'XV) that under certain other environmental conditions the dis - ease was not transmitted thru the tuln-rs and that vascular dis - coloration of the stem does not always give a good indication of the amount of disease present, altho. as indicated in Experiment 3 (p. 34). the depth of the vascular discoloration can often be con-elated with a decrease in yield, tlnir- indicating a lowering of the vitality of the seed. Vascular discoloration of l&gt;otli stem and tuber was often found in the absence of any causal organism. This was particu - larly marked in Experiment "2. (p. 33) and Inoculation Experi - ment 1. (p. 17) this appearing to be due directly to the hot. dry weather. The same type of discoloration was observed in 1921 on potatoes grown in western Nebraska under dry land conditions. Hot weather prevailed thruout the summer and there was very little moisture present until late in the season. The crop, how - ever, appeared very thrifty and healthy in the fields and the potatoes were certified for seed. The sale of these potatoes outside of the State resulted in many complaints, claiming that </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Potato Wilt ('iniMtt/ hi/ F iixitriiiui Oxi/xponon 37 the seed was poor in general vigor and was infected with Fusarium wilt. This was due partly to the high amount of vascu - lar discoloration in the seed, altho there was no wilt present in the field. The uiImts were rather badly malformed owing to re - in wed apowth late in the season. Nevertheless, this stock when planted at various points in the South showed the smallest amount of disease and the greatest yields of any of the Nebraska potatoes tested in the same trials. Thus, it is evident that vascular discoloration is not a good ndication of Fiisariuin wilt, altho under certain environmental onditions we do get a considerable amount of wilt by planting li seed, while under other conditions no wilting results. It is to lie remembered that in the plots where the disease resulted from planting seed having vascular discoloration the tubers were ob - tained fro.'.'i stock known to be infected the previous year as indi - cated by the large amount of wilt, and not simply tubers show- vascular discoloration. In other words, vascular discolora- ion is not a good criterion of the presence of Fusarium unless t Ik' produced by a wilted plant, and even then the chances are liat it will not reproduce the disease the following year by means 1 infection. INFECTION FROM THE SOIL THRU THE ROOTS OR STEM It is a well-known fact that Fusarium oxyspontm can live as a soil saprophyte for many years. It has also been claimed by various workers that F. ojrysporum causes a wilt of the potato plant by the entrance of the organism thru the root hairs from the soil. While this method of infection has been generally ac - cepted as one of the modes of entrance of the organism, very little positive experimental work has been published to prove this point. The following work was undertaken in an attempt to tit her prove or disprove this theory, and if true, to determine the conditions favoring such a method of infection. The author has observed many cases in various parts of the Tinted States, but especially in Michigan and Nebraska, where healthy wed planted on land not previously cropped has resulted in a considerable number of wilted plants. These plants appeared to have become infected thru the roots; very often there was only w discoloration of the vascular system without any root rotting and without a rot of the seed-piece. It was this type of infection that prevailed in Michigan in 1014 and 1915 and lead to the undertaking of the present investigation. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Esp. Station. Research Bui. Review of Literature Smith and Swingle (1904) in their early description of the disease state (p. 13) : The disease ordinarily enters the plant through the roots and slowly spreads until the whole root system, a few centimeters of the lower part of the stem, the underground stems bearing the tubers, and the tubers themselves are invaded by the fungus. They present no detailed experimental evidence to support their observations. Manns (1911) also claims that the disease makes its attack thru the root system. This results in the root hairs and smaller secondary roots of affected plants being entirely destroyed and thus causing the premature death of the plant. He found by planting healthy seed on heavily infested soil as compared with slightly infested soil that there was more wilt and i reduction in vield from 125.6 bushels to 90 bushels per acre. He tested the infection powers of "sick v soil by adding a little of this soil to hills of potatoes growing in sterilized soil. He says (p. 317) : The disease came on much more definitely under the sick soil in - fection than it did where pure artificial cultures were used without in - cisions or root injury. The great difference between sick soil infection, and that from pure cultures or even internal seed infection, is that in the use of sick soil the roots are attacked at practically every point, while with pure cultures, or seed internally infected, the fungus attacks only in close proximity to the main root, while most of the secondary roots and the root hairs remain healthy. He does not. however, give any detailed data in regard t infection from the soil by use of pure cultures. Link (1916) does not report uniformly successful re&gt;ujt~ with soil inoculations of Fusarium o.rygporum. He reports one experiment of 5 plants in which the soil was inoculated with rice cultures of F. oxygporum. No plants came up in the inoculated soil, whereas the controls appeared healthy. He states that this experiment was repeated several times, but in no case were the results so striking. In fact, in one experiment no infection re - sulted at all. He stated that plants grown in soil inoculated with F . oxygporum showed severe lesions of roots and stolons. He believed that this root injury is just as important in producing wilt symptoms as vascular mycoses. As to the lack of uniformity in the results, he says (p. 188) : The soil in these experiments surely was more severely infected with the organisms than soil under field conditions can be. yet there were many plants grown in such soil that showed no infection whatsoever. Less success in producing wilt was observed as the season progressed. It remains a question whether this is due to a loss in vitality or to a </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Potato ~\Yilt Conned /&gt;&gt;/ Fnxuriinx O.ryxponim 39 gain in resistance in the plants, due to a change in the soil, tubers, or the organism. Pratt (1016) studicil the amount of disease present when healthy seed was planted on virgin desert soil in Idaho. He found wilt to be present in every plot, and isolated the organism from steins showing vascular discoloration. He also states that SO per cent of the tubers showing vascular discoloration yielded cultures of either Fusarium o.rysporum or F. radicicola. Basing his peiveiii;i&lt;res on this basis, he found on tubers grown on land previously planted to alfalfa and grain 26 per cent vascular in - fection, while on the virgin desert land plots he found 29.3 per cent. Bisbv ( 1919). in discussing the results of attempted infection of potato plants by artificially infected soil or seed-piece, says they were often unsuccessful and concludes (p. 12) : It is evident that F. oxysporum is not vigorously parasitic to actively growing potato plants. He thought that these results may have been due to too low a temperature and made further tests with heavily inoculated soil at soil temj&gt;eratures of 20° to 30° C. with a high humidity, and produced a stem rot or "foot rot" of the plants. He further states that the higher temperatures in the warm chambers were un - favorable to the potato and the plants died sooner than corre - sponding plants left outside. MacMillan (1910) states that in only 6 plants out of many hundreds examined in 1916 and 1917 was root infection deter - mine*! as the probable cause of Fusarium wilt in the Greeley sec - tion of Colorado. He notes that in 1918. when the soil tempera - ture was 6°F. almve the average for the month of June of the two preceding years, plants of the Charles Downing variety were badly diseased by being attacked thru the fine roots and root hairs ;iinl concludes ( p. 284) : Higher temperatures seem to be necessary for root infection Haakell 1 1919) finds that Fusarium wilt in Dutchess County, New York, is primarily a root and stem rot. He was the first worker to report detailed ex))erimental work under controlled temperatures. In 1915 he inoculated sterilized soil with pure cultures of Fhsii riu in oxt/spomw, one plot before planting, an - other when the plants were 6 inches high, and the third plot left as a check: the number of plants is not stated. The results were not uniform and this he attributed to the fact that the greenhouse temperatures were too low for infection. 18°-21° in the day and </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Xebrtui-ti Ayr'uulturul h'jp. station. Uewiinh Bui. 40 13°-1."&gt;.."» ('. at night. He repeated this, using the same soil and growing the plants in the summer when the temperatures wen - higher, and found that many of the new tul&gt;ers showed marked stem-end browning, from which the fungus was isolated. An - other experiment was conducted with *&gt; plants. 4 inoculated with a flask culture of F. oxynponmi No. :WX&gt; &lt; the same as Strain X&lt;&gt;. 8. used by the writer in many experiments). The plants wen - kept in a water bath at SWi (air temperature not given). He found that the root systems l&gt;ecame diseased and that some of the stems showed lesions, and the organism was isolated. He states (p. 237): Although the tops of the diseased plants did not resemble those that are affected with Fusarium wilt as it appears in the field, the affected root system and the lesions on the outside and within the stem were exactly like those that occur in the field. He repeated this experiment, keeping the crocks in the water bath at 5M5 C -39°C'. Again he was apparently unable t-&gt; produce typical Fusarium wilted plants, altho he states i p. S-\~ i : An examination of the xylem of inoculated plants showed it to be badly discolored In most of the stems. In some instance* the checks also showed this condition but not so badly. The writer is in doubt as to just how much of this discolora - tion of the xylem reported by Haskell was due to the extremely high temperatures, as vascular browning can Im&gt; produced by sub - mitting plants to very high temperatures even for short periods, and this diseased tissue becomes easily infected with Fusaria from the soil. It is clear, however, from Haskell's work that even with high soil temperatures it is difficult to obtain 1 « h &gt; jmt rent infection or to produce typical field symptoms of wilt. Haskell also tested soil infection by growing healthy seed in the green - house in soil brought from a badly diseased field. Twelve plant - were grown in this soil and 12 in sterilized soil. Xo typical symptoms of Fusarium wilt appeared. The roots in both plot. - appeared diseased altho Fmuirium ojrynpunnn was isolated only from the plants on unsterilized soil. In regard to soil infection. Haskell further makes the statement i p. -Ji-2) : Land that has produced a diseased crop one year is practically cer - tain to do so the next if potatoes are planted. The writer is at a loss to understand tliis statement in the light of the experiments reported, showing infection to depend upon an extremely high soil temperature. As regards the influence of climatic factors on the disease as observed in the field. Haskell states that hot weather is favor- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">I'ototo Wilt CiKifiil hi/ Fumrium Oxytporum 41 able for the disease ami unfavorable for the host and that it is during the hot weather that wilt develops. How then account for the writer's results in Michigan in 1916 when practically no wilting apjK'ared on badly infested soil during the hottest sum - mer in years. Haskell concludes (p. 252) that — temperature is probably the most important factor limiting the develop - ment of Fusarium wilt in southeastern New York. He believes that the amount of rainfall and hence soil moisture lias very little to do with the prevalence of the disease. He does think, however, that with a low soil moisture diseased plants will wilt quicker. This review of the literature shows a general conformity of opinion among the earlier workers on this disease, who claim that infeetion can take place from the soil thru the roots. There an' some conflicting statements as to whether this type of infection is confined to the vascular system of the roots and stems, or whether it results in a rotting of the root system. It is notice - able that the only writer working under western irrigated condi - tions, MacMillaii (l!&gt;10). claims that only a very small amount of infection occurs thru the roots. It is generally stated that high soil temperatures favor the development of this type of infection. Haskell reports successful soil inoculation experi - ments at soil temperatures of 36" to 40°C. This temperature is i he extreme maximum temperature for the growth of both host and organism. No experimental work is reported regarding the relation of soil moisture to infection. Field Experiments with Infested Soil, 1914-15-16 During 1914 a Held of Rural New Yorker potatoes on the ollege farm at the Michigan Agricultural College showed over 90 per cent of the plants affected with Fusarium wilt. The plants wilted earlv in the year. Fustirium oxynporum was repeatedly isolated from stems and tubers of wilted plants showing vascular discoloration as well as from the soil. In 1915 four rows. 330 feet long, of this heavily infested soil weiv planted with healthy seed. Very few of the plants showed the early symptoms of the disease and very little wilting occurred until just l&gt;efore digging time. The plants in these 4. rows were found to be 47 per cent infected as determined by actual wilting, vjixular discoloration, root infection, and cultural examinations; while the same seed planted on soil not previously planted to potatoes showed only 3 per cent infection. In !!&gt;!•'&gt; four more rows were planted on this land that had </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Xebranka Agrirultxrul Eip. station. Research Bui. 23 been in clover the previous year. A few plants were wilted in August and at the end of the experiment only about 20 plants, or 4.5 per cent of the total number of plants, showed wilting symptom?. When dug. the stems and tubers of all plants showed vascular browning similar to that noted on page 34. but no suc - cessful isolations were made except from the i'O wilted plants. The weather conditions for this year are given on page 17. An examination of the infected plants showed in every instance that infection took place thru the roots rather than thru the sced - piece. The amount of rotting of the root system was very -light. and no rotting of the underground stems was observed except in the few cases where wilting took place early in the season and the plants were not dug until the end of the experiment. The infection in practically all cax's was confined to the small root hairs and the vascular system of the main roots and under ground stem. While this experiment shows at first glance ;i reduction of the wilt, the first year from 90 per cent to 47 per cent, and after one year's rotation to 8 per cent, it must lie remembered that climatic conditions were probably a greater factor than was the rotation used. Greenhouse Experiment* In the following experiments, only vigorous plants grown from healthy seed were used, the s«&gt;e(l tulxTs U'ing carefully ex - amined for the absence of vascular infection l&gt;efore planting. The soil inoculations were made by mixing thoroly with the soil suspension of spores and mycelium in sterile water. EXPERIMENT 1. 1915 Tubers of the Green Mountain variety were planted February 8. The inoculations were made when the plants were about one foot in height on March 1. and the final results were taken May 10. The inoculum was obtained from cultures of Fuaarium oxysporum No. 1. Set 1. — Nine plants were grown in inoculated soil. None of these plants showed typical wilt and at the close of the experiment no browning of the vascular system of either the roots or the stems was observed. s&lt; t 1. — Ten plants were grown in inoculated soil. The roots of these plants were slightly injured, but not enough to impair their vigor. Three of these plants showed a very heavy Infection, the typical Fusarium wilt appeared rather early, and the fungus was found to be present very abundantly In the vascular system. The organism was isolated in pure culture. Four plants showed only a slight Infection, the wilt not belli* serious enough to kill the plants. Three plants remained healthy thruout the experiment. Set 3. — Five plants were grown in soil previously inoculated with Rhizoctonia solani Kuhn, and later with Fiisarium oxysporum. This was </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum 43 done in order to observe the possibility of F. oxytpwum obtaining an entrance into the roots thru the Rhizoctonia lesions. No wilting occurred and no browning of the vascular system was observed. Rhizoctonia lesions were found on 2 of these plants. Set }. — Five plants were grown in soil inoculated by placing pieces of potatoes internally infected with Fusarium oxysporum In the soil clos* to the roots. Three of these plants showed a slight wilt and a slight browning of the vascular system. Two plants remained healthy. Set ■&gt;. — Five plants were grown in soil inoculated as in Set 4, but the infected pieces were placed next to injured roots. Two plants showed a heavy infection of the wilt similar to those of Set 2. Three plants remained healthy. A r ti. — Twelve plants were used as controls. In some a wilting occurred somewhat similar to that of the inoculated plants, so the wilting of the plants could not be taken as a sure sign of the disease. However, no browning of the vascular system was found in any of the controls and careful microscopic and cultural work failed to reveal the presence of the fungus. EXPERIMENT 2, NOVEMBER, 1915 Potato plants of the Russet Rural variety were used in the green - house for inoculation experiments similar to the previous ones. The inoculum was obtained from cultures of Fusarium. oxysporum. No. 1. set i. — The roots of 2 plants were injured and the soil inoculated. One of these plants produced typical wilt and showed vascular browning. The other plant remained healthy. / .' Two plants were inoculated as in Set 1 but the roots were inujred. Both of these plants remained healthy. Set S. — Four plants used as controls remained healthy. EXPERIMENT 3. MARCH. 1817 Fourteen tubers of the Rural New Yorker variety were planted in the greenhouse. The soil was inoculated with Funarium oxysporum Xo. 8 just as the shoots were showing at the surface of the ground. One plant showed slight symptoms of the wilt, and the fine rootlets when observed under the microscope were found to be invaded by the fungus. The other 13 plants remained healthy. Three plants used as controls remained healthy. EXPERIMENT 4. MARCH. 1917 Four tubers of the Rural New Yorker variety were planted in the soil previously used in Experiment 3. All the plants when very young showed symptoms of the wilt. When these plants were dug up and ex - amined, the roots were found to be heavily invaded and the entire under - ground portion of the plant showed the presence of the fungus. Isolations were made from each plant and the organism recovered in all cases. Four other plants kept as controls remained healthy. EXPERIMENT 5. MARCH, 1917 Twelve plants of the same variety as those of the previous experi - ment were used. The soil was inoculated just as the sprouts were break - ing thru the ground. All the plants remained healthy. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. -&gt; EXPBRIMENT 8. 1920 In these tests the soil was sterilized and then inoculated with S - weeks-old rice cultures of Fusarium oxyxporum No. 53. The experiment was started February 21; the results were taken May 5. Two tempera - tures were used. Set 1. — Five plants were placed in a greenhouse having a mean tem - perature of about 17° C. All 5 plants remained healthy. Set 2. — Three plants were grown in a greenhouse with a mean tem - perature of about 27° C. Plant 1 showed no wilt, 2 stems out of 4 had brown lesions at the base of the stem, and there was slight root injury but no browning of the vascular system. Fusarium oxyxporum was re - covered from the lesions. All the underground stems of plant 2 showed lesions, also some of the roots and stolons. There was no wilt or vascular Infection. F. oxyxporum was recovered from the lesions. Plant 3 showed no wilt or vascular invasion, but 2 of the stems showed numerous lesions and considerable root injury. F. oxysporum was recovered from the stems and the roots. In these plants the lesions caused by F. oxyxporum on the underground stems were entirely superficial, while on the roots the pene - tration was deeper and the injury much greater, often cutting off the root. EXPERIMENT 7. 1920 On February 16. 6 pots. 4 with inoculated soil and 2 uninoculated controls were planted with Irish Cobbler seed and kept at 23° C. until March 10 when they were all about 6 inches high with a good even growth and no signs of disease. They were then removed to a greenhouse kept at 30°-33". On March 20 the plants growing in inoculated soil were badly yellowed and wilted. The controls, altho entirely dead above ground, showed no signs of disease in the underground parts, the stem, roots, and stolons being healthy. Fusarium oxyxporum was recovered from th* rotted portion of the stem of inoculated plants. A summary of these soil inoculation te&gt;t&lt; shows that out of 80 plants inoculated in various ways only 14 wilted, 11 were infected but did not wilt, and 55 remained healthy. The re - sults show that the greatest amount of wilt was obtained when the soil was inoculated before planting or when the plant was very young. There was no difference in the amount of infection in the different varieties of potatoes. Injury to the roots re - sulted in a higher percentage of infection. The results also in - dicate that soil temperature and possibly air temperature has a considerable influence upon the infection and progress of the disease. Relation of Soil Temperature to Infection of Roots from the Soil Further experiments under controlled conditions were started to determine the relation of soil temperature and moisture to the disease. Methods. — In these experiments, "Wisconsin soil temperature tanks." previously described by Jones (1917), were used to control the soil tem - peratures. In the experiments at Nebraska slight modifications in these </seg>
            <seg id="p045">I'ntot Wilt Canned by Fwtarium Oxysporum 45 tanks' were made, but the principle employed was essentially the same. In these "tanks" the plants were grown in galvanized iron cans immersed in a well-insulated water bath, 21x39x27'-.. inches in size, heated elec- trically and controlled by electric thermostats. The temperature of the soil in all the following "tank" experiments was taken twice daily at the depth of 3 inches. The soil moisture content was kept approximately constant by weighing the pots and adding the necessary water about 3 times a week, and as the plants grew larger, the water was added daily. In some of the experiments the surface of the soil was covered with min - eral wool and in the latter experiments with crushed stone to prevent a rapid change in the temperature of the surface soil and also to prevent the drying out of the surface soil. Water was added thru a test tubs to an inverted clay pot in the center of the container and was also added to the surface of the soil. With this combination of surface and subsoil water - ing the moisture was found after numerous tests to be very well distributed throut the soil. It is obvious of course that the soil moisture did not remain constant during the experiment, and varied according to the rapidity of transpirtation and the frequency of watering. The soil was only at the specified moisture content immediately after watering and gradually decreased until the next watering. It is also true that during the experiment the soil would settle, and this packing would result in a decrease in the moisture holding capacity. This is counteracted to some extent by the increase in the weight of the plant, this Increase not being taken into account in the weighings. The following percentages show an average of several tests made to determine the changes during the experiment in the moisture content of the soil with growing potato plants. Composite samples were taken from various parts of the con- tan Set 1 Set 2 Set 3 Her cent Pei; cent Per cent Moisture content (dry weight! at start 13.6 20.4 27.2 lloisture content (dry weight) at end 14.0 20.6 23.S Thus we find the greatest change occurring at the higher moisture ntents where the weight of the plant is greater than at the lower soil moistures; the cans at 80 per cent of the moisture holding capacity 1 127.2 per cent dry weight) being 70 per cent at the close of the experi- ment The difference at 40 and 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity was very slight. The plants were watered often enough so that it was never necessary to add more than 200 c. c. of water, and usually only about 100 c. c, so that just previous to watering or when the soil was at the lowest moisture content it was usually not more than 10 per cent of the moisture holding capacity below the desired point. In the late spring or with high air temperature when the transpiration was rapid, the difference was slightly greater than the above. However, as all cans in the experiment were handled in the same way, the differences are relative and do not interfere with tli. interpretations placed upon the results. The moisture holding capacity was determined with the 25 cm. tubes, which were filled with air dry soil and tapped 10 times from a height of S inches, placed in water for 6 to 8 hours, and allowed to drain S to 4 hours. This determination was often checked with the 1 cm. cups, in which filter paper was inserted over the screen, the cups then filled with air-dry soil, tapped on the side 5 times, smoothed off, placed in water for 1 hour, and drained 15 minutes. In all the following- experiments the soil moixture is expressed a» per cent of the moisture holding capacity rather than as per cent dry weight </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Xehrtinkn Agricultural Exp. Station. Re*e&lt;ir&lt;h Kul. &gt; EXPERIMENT 1, FEBKl ARY 1« TO APRIL S. !»»• Method*. — Healthy Irish Cobbler potatoes were treated with for - maldehyde and sprouted for 2 weeks in a cool place. The tubers were cut in half for seed. The soil used was one part leaf mold and 2'.. parts soil sterilized for 8 hours at 2^ pounds pressure. About 3,000 grams of soil, dry weight, was used in each can. The soil had a moisture holding capacity of 40.5 per cent dry weight. During the experiment it was kept at 29.0 per cent dry weight, or about 72 per cent of the moisture holding capacity. The soil was inoculated just previous to planting with a spore suspension in water of a 14-day-old rice culture of Fusarium oxysporum No. 33. Immediately after planting the cans were removed to the de - sired temperature. I Five different soil temperatures were used; 9 plants being grown each temperature, 6 with inoculate! soil, and 3 uninoculated controls. ? temperatures used were 12", 18°, 24°, 30°, and 36° C. Readings ■e taken twice daily and the average thruout the experiment was 11.8°, 5°, 23.8°, 30.1°, and 35.7°. The temperatures did not vary more than on each side of the average. The air temperature was maintained at &gt;roximately 17°. ! Result*. — The ]M&gt;tatoe.- were planted February 16, and bv bruary 23 the sprouts were coming thru at 18'. _H . and 30 = (\ le most rapid growth was at _'4". At 12 C . the plant&gt; wetv iwer in getting started. They were all up on March 3. At 30 the seed-pieces rotted before the sprouts started. The plants 18° produced a very even stand of vigorous, healthy plants d these plants along with those at 12° remained healthy thruout e experiment with no apparent difference between the inoculated ints and the controls. One plant at 30° wu wilted down by irch 10 and the other plants at this temperature all showed yellowing of the lower leaves apparently due to the high soil uperature. The plants were dug on April 8 and the top&gt;. underground stems, and roots examined and cultures made from plants show - ing disease. The results of this experiment are tabulated in Table fi. It is apparent from this table that no infection took place at 12° and 18 C C. At 24^ there was no marked difference in the tops of control and inoculated plants; in only one case were the tops wilted. Three plants had slight root injury and Fnffirium oxyspormn was isolated. At 30 = 5 of the f&gt; inoculated plants showed varying but distinct symptoms of wilt and when examined were found to have vascular discoloration of the stem and in 4 instances the underground stem was rotted. F. oxysporum wts isolated from all roots showing injury and from stems show - ine either vascular discoloration or rotting. It is evident from this experiment that teini)eratures of IS' 1 ■nd below are unfavorable for the development of the disease </seg>
            <seg id="p047">P,,t,it&lt;&gt; Wilt ('mixed b&gt;i Fnxtiiiutn Oxysponun 47 Tabus 6. — Relation of soil temperature to infection of Irish ( nhbler potatoes from soil inoculated with The figures in Tables 8 to 12 represent the degree of infection; 1 = slight, 2 = medium, 3 = serious. In the last two columns the re - ttults of isolations are shown; 0 = negative culture, += positive culture, — = no culture made. 1 The moisture content of the soil was kept as 72 per cent of the moisture holding capacity, or 29 per cent dry weight. and that above 18° the amount of infection in the inoculated plants increased with the increase in temperature up to 30°C. At 36° the temperature was too high for good germination of the seed. It is noticeable that only 6 plants in the experiment Ftisarium oorysporum No. S3. Experiment I 1 Soil tem- perature Symptoms Culto Treatment F. ox% of plants ,— 1— —,— — Culture* of F . oxytporum Vascular Stem Root From Wilt discoloration rot injury roots From stems I ; ; ; : 12 1 ill 6 inoculated plants, 3 controls, all healthy 18 18 6 inoculated plants, 3 controls, all healthy 1 . M (1 - - 1 + 2 — — — 1 + Inoculated J 3 2 2 3 1 — \i - z - • It - 1 - - - • (7 — — — — 0 Control. ..{ 8 — — — — 0 U - - - - - 0 30 13 3 3 3 + 2 2 2 2 1 + Inoculated 3 — — 1 + 4 3 3 3 3 + 5 1 — — 1 + 6 3 3 3 — — + + -t- Control.. \ 8 — 10 (9 ! 1 — 1 — — 0 36 6 inoculated plants, 3 controls, all seed rotted </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Xebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Rexenrrh But. showed positive symptoms of wilt or stem injury, whereas 8 plants showed root injury. The controls remained healthy except at 36° and in the case of one stem of a control plant at :H) -. EXPERIMENT 2. APS1L. 1»2» The methods used in this experiment were similar to those in the previous experiment except that Rural New Yorker pota - toes were used instead of Irish Cobblers. The soil moisture con - tent wa&gt; also lowered. The moisture holding content of the soil used was 4!&gt;.7 per cent dry weight. The sets at the various tem - peratures were divided into two series, one in which the soil was held at 51 per cent of tin* moisture holding capacity (25.3 per cent dry weight) and the other at 57 per cent (28.3 per cent dry weight). The following temperatures were used. Set No. 1: Air temperature 17°C. Soil temperatu 22°. 26°, 30°, and M°C. Set No. 2: Air temperature 27 ('. Soil tempera! and 27°C. The seed-pieces at all the temperatures were completely rotted before the sprouts got above the ground, both in the con - trols and iii the inoculated pots. There were a few weak sprouts appearing above the ground l&gt;ut not enough to continue the ex- \ periment. EXPERIMENT 3. NOVEMBER 5 TO FEBRl'ARY 4. 1*21 This experiment and the following soil temperature experi - ments were conducted at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: and while the same general methods as tho-r outlined in Experiment 1 were used, there were slight differences m each experiment. Tn Experiment 3 an attempt was made to obtain further information in regard to the MM of -oil inoiaturc a - well as temperature upon the disease: 2 different -oil moistures were therefore used at each temperature. Methods. — Owing to the fact that no infection was obtained in Ex - periment 1 at the low soil temperature of 12°. this temperature was omitted in the present experiment and the soil held at 4' intervals in - stead of the 6" C. intervals as in Experiment 1. Six "Wisconsin soil temperature tanks" were used. In each "tank" 8 cans holding about 10 kilos of soil (dry weight) were used. The same amount of soil was used in each can. The soil in 4 of these cans at each temperature was kept at approximately 40 per cent of the moisture holding capacity and in the other 4 at 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity. The moisture holding capacity of the soil was determined to be "8.2 per cent dry weight with the 25 cm. cup method previously described. Six soil temperatures were used. 16°. 20°, 24°, 28°. 32°. and 36°. The averages of the readings taken twice daily at a depth of 3 inches were IT*. 20.3°, 23.5°, 27.6°, 31.8", and 35.5°. These temperatures varied slightly fjiru- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Putilt,, Witt Cmixiil /&gt;!/ F n*&lt;n/ 1/, I, O.i-i/&gt;tpornm out the experiment but the extremes did not overlap and usually the temperatures did not vary more than 1°. The air temperature was kept at approximately 18°, altho during the last 2 weeks of the experiment the air temperature ran slightly higher, averaging about 20°. The soil used was disinfected with formaldehyde and allowed to air out before planting. All the soil was inoculated just before planting with 14-day-old rice cultures of Fusarium osysporum No. 33. Early Ohio tubers were then cut and sprouted in damp excelsior and when planted the sprouts were % to U Inch long. Immediately after planting, the cans were placed at the desired temperature and brought up to the desired soil moisture content, the water being added as in Experiment 1. /.'. *&gt;ilt8. — The plants were examined daily thruout the ex - periment and any symptoms of disease were noted. These along with the results obtained at digging time are presented briefly — „ _- — — — pr? — rr&gt; ~ — r — —--——— — - -— - -j in Table 7. The only temperature at which positive wilting symptoms appeared was 3&lt;&gt; C. At this temperature many of the sproota a|)|M'nred to be killed before they reached the surface of the ground. They then sent out secondary sprouts which pro- duced tops never exceeding 10 inches in height. Both control plants remained healthy. At 32° no wilting occurred, altho most of the plants were considerably dwarfed as at 36°. It was notice - able at these 2 high temperatures, and especially at 36°, that the root itAmm were very small and remained near the surface of i lie ami. Tliw combined with the high soil temperature made it impossible to keep the upper 2 inches of soil at the same moisture content as the rest of the pots, even when insulated with mineral wool. Thus the actual soil moisture surrounding the roots at 36° \\a~ considerably less than indicated in the table. No vascular discoloration of the stems was found in any of the control plants at any of the temperatures. There were no marked differences in the amounts oi vascular discoloration at any of the temperatures between 20° and 36 C C. As regards soil moisture. 10 plants at 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity -liowed vaxnlar discoloration and only 3 at 40 per cent. The amount of stein rot was found to run parallel with the vascular discoloration and in most cases, the 2 symptoms appeared on the same plant. The amount of root injury appeared to be greatest at temperatures from 24° to 36°. altho there was very slight injury to 2 plants at 16°. At the high temperatures the injury appeared greater and isolations from these roots always yielded F •txnr'miit t ,.ii/.«/n&gt;nim. Three control plants showed root injury at J s and •'»_' . and F. ojrygparum was recovered from one of them. The causal organism was also recovered from the stems of 8 inoculated plants showing either vascular discoloration or stem rot. while 2 plants with similar symptoms gave negative results in culture. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Ex p. Station, Research Bui. 50 &gt; Table 7. — Relation of soil temperature and moisture to infection of Early Ohio potatoes from soil inoculated with Fusarium oxysporum X". 33 Soil Soil Tr.-atm.-n! of plants temperature | moisture 1 decoloration Dtgr—t C. Per n*t Control 1 4(1 Inoculated 3 4 16 Control 1 «.. 4 Control 1 Inoculated 3 4li 4 2n Control 1 m. i Control 1 1" 4 24 Control 1 Inoculated S *. I Control 1 t 4(. Inoculated I S 4 2-v Control 1 ■ Inoculated S I Control 1 ■' 40 Inoculated 3 n&lt; germination 4 32 Control 1 2 ■ Inoculated , 3 4 Control 1 2 no termination no termination 4d Inoculated 3 4 1 36 Control 1 [I BO Inoculated 3 1 .1 I 1 Soil moistures are expressed in per cent of the moisture holding- capacity (31 per cent dry weight). Experiment 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">I'.t.if,, Wilt Caused by Fu*arium (Jjcynporum 51 The results of this experiment are not as clear-cut and con - clusive n~ those of Experiment 1. The per cent of infection was not as high: and while 30- was found to be the optimum soil temperature for the disease in Experiment 1, no positive wilting occurred at either 28° or 32° C. in this experiment. It is to be remembered that Early Ohio seed was used in this experiment while Irish Cobbler seed was used in Experiment 1. The results indicated that low soil moistures thruout the experiment were not favorable for the production of the wilt. This experiment was the first one in which plants were grown successfully at 36°, and while the plants grew and the amount of infection was greatest at tlii~ temperature, the appearance of the plants, es - pecially of the root system, was very abnormal and neither the tv]H&gt; of plant growth nor the conditions under which they were grown are comparable with natural field conditions. EXPERIMENT 4. MARCH i TO MAT 12. lttl This experiment differed from Experiment ;$ in that higher soil moistures were used and no plants were kept at a constant temperature of 30 C In the previous experiments the percentage of germination at this high temperature was very low and when germination took place the resulting plants were usually very abnormal and the unnatural growth increased the difficulty of rec - ognizing the symptoms of the disease. In order to obviate this and also to study the effect of changing soil temperatures, the plants •rrowing at 1* and 36° were alternated. Methods— Two different soil moistures were used. The moisture holding capacity of the soil determined by the 25 cm. cup method was 35 per cent dry weight. One-half of the cans were held at 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity (21 per cent dry weight), which was the same as the highest moisture content in Experiment 3. The other half were held at 80 per cent of the moisture holding capacity (28 per cent dry weight i. In order to prevent the drying out of the upper 2 inches of soil, the moisture content was kept constant by both subsoil and surface watering for several days previous to planting. Immediately after planting, the soil in each container was covered with 900 grams of crushed rock. 1 The same soil temperatures were used in Experiment 3 except at 36 °C. One set of 8 plants was started at 18° soil temperature, and when the plants were about 3 to 6 inches tall at the end of 25 days and apparently healthy, they were changed to a soil temperature of 36° and remained at this temperature during the rest of the experiment. In the same way. one set of 8 plants was started at 36° and at the end of 25 days none of these plants were above ground. They were then removed to a temperature of 18° for the rest of the experiment. The soil was prepared 1 This «u found to be a more satisfactory means of decreasing evaporation from the surface soil and keeping the upper layer of soil at a constant temperature than the mineral wool used in the previous experiments. It was also much easier to handle and allowed of some surface watering. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 tie same way as for Experiment 3 and tubers were used from the I source and treated in the same way. Just previous to planting, soil was inoculated with cultures of Fuiarium oxysporum No. 35 n on rice. The containers were placed at the desired temperatures ediately after planting. The soil temperatures were taken at a depth inches 3 times daily and did not vary more than 1° from the desired lerature except in one set. 1 The air temperature was. kept at approxi - rty 18° except during the last few weeks of the experiment, when it itimes rose to 25° during the middle of the day. I/.', stilts.— The plants started at 18° and changed to M C M so badh' wilted that they were dug and examined on May 2: remainder of the plants were all dug on May 1-2. The reMilt&gt; tht experiment are tabulated in Table 8. It was noticeable t at all the temperatures used many of the plants showed a lowing and wilting of the lower leaves at various times during experiment and later recovered and when examined at digging ■ were found to be healthy. Such plants are not listed in the If ;i- diseased. The quick change of soil temperature with the nts started at IK and changed to :ir. resulted in a rapid wilt - • and drying of the lower ha If of the plant. After about one ;k. however, these leaves dropped otf. the plants, apparently oining adapted to the high teni])eratiire, appeared perfectly iltliy. and later the disease appeared and wilting became com - te in some cases. I At 18 r C. no definite wilting wh&gt; observed except in the case one control that wilted from other causes. No wilt occurred 24 except in one control plant. Four plant-. 2 at each soil isture, showed either slight stem rot or slight root injury. At 1 one plant wilted and one other plant showed definite sign&gt; the disease in the underground portion. At -12° the result. - not agree with the previous experiments: practically no in - tion was found, only 2 of the plants showing a slight rotting the base of the stem. The plants started at 18 J and changed 36° showed a marked difference from the plants at the other iperatures. All of these, including the controls, showed wilt nptoms. The vascular system of the stem of both controls s slightly discolored but no root infection or stem rot was ;sont and cultures from the stem were sterile. This slight coloration of the stem was evidently due to the extremely high 1 temperature just previous to digging, as previously men - ned. The inoculated plants started to wilt about April 2~&gt;. d all 3 inoculated plants at 80 j&gt;er cent of the moisture holding 1 In the (18° to S«° i Kt the temperature of the Mil. owinc to mn accident to the regulating device, rose to 45° S nights in succession and was lowered to S6°C. each morning during the last S days of the experiment. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Potato W,lt touted by Fusarium Oxysporutn 53 I'abi.k 8. — Relation of soil temperature and moisture to infection of Early Ohio potatoes from soil inoculated with FuMarium oxysporum No. 35 Experiment 4 Culture, of m soil x™.t— .t , —^^r t-sa-2- Umpsrature wMan' of plants Vascular Stem Root Prom Prom Wilt discoloration rat injury root* Mm " ' I ' " ' ~~ "~~ ~~ — — — ■ ' Degrrti C. Prr &lt;•««( Control 1 — — — — — M Inoculated , I — II - - 1 - - it . ■ _ —I Control 1 » — _ _ _ — ft — — — t — — M Inoeulatwl 1 1 — 1 Coatrol 1 — ft — — 1 — — — 00 Inoeulaud t — — — 1 — — 4 - _ _ _ I + 24 1 Coatrot I * 2 2 i — + fl - — — I + — M Inoculated , S 1 ~ Control I — — ~^ (* — — — — — — M Isoeulatod 3 — t 2 1 + ■j» : Control 1 — — — — — 80 Iaoeaattad j II 11 + 14 — — 1 — i — Control 1 — M boeuartaa- j S — — 5=4-|~§— |-|-|-Ii M. Inorulatvd 3 — [4 — — 1 — — — Control 1 1 1 — — — 0 (t 1 2 1 • + + M inoculated 3 3 t 3 S + -"- 4 1 1 — 1 + — iruM Coatrol I 1 1 — — — 0 (2 * 3 • f I + 0 M Inoculated 11 1 I I I ♦ T [4 1 1 110 0 ~ Cwtnl 1 HU Inoculated 3 no (germination (4 no germination 36 to 18 ■ Control 1 no termination f t no (termination 80 Inoculated j i — — — — 1 Soil moisture! are expressed in per cent of the moisture holding capacity (If per cent dry weight). ■ Final notes on the (18° to S«°C.) plants were taken 10 days before the other plants in the experiment. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">capacity were completely wilted by May 2, while 1 plant was completely wilted and 2 slightly wilted in the set at 40 per cent moisture. All of these inoculated plants showed definite signs of disease below ground and the causal organism was recovered from either roots or stems in all but one instance. As previously noted, the plants started at 36° were not above ground when the soil temperature was changed to 18°. At the latter temperature, all plants that grew remained healthy. The only temperature at which uniform results were secured in this experiment was with plants started at 18° and changed to 36°C. In these plants the wilting symptoms and the vascular discoloration of the stem were undoubtedly due in part directly to the high soil temperature as indicated by the controls. In this set the infection appeared to be greater in soil kept at 80 per cent rather than at 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity. The effect of wilting due to high temperature with subsequent recovery shows that it is difficult to examine a plant having slight signs of wilt during an experiment either in the field or under control conditions and attempt to determine whether these slight symptoms of disease are due to environmental conditions or to some wilt producing parasite. EXPERIMENT 5. NOVEMBER 22. 1*21. TO FEBRIARY it. U22 tThis experiment was planned to test the pathogenicity of irivm oxyspontm as a soil parasite when both soil tempera - 3 and soil moistures are changed during the course or tin* riment. I Methods. — Healthy tubers of the Bliss Triumph variety were used, y were cut and sprouted in moist sand. The sprouts were ] 4 inch long m planted and the cut surface was well calloused over. The soil was ed the same as in the previous experiment and was sterilized for 3 rs at 2V&gt; pounds pressure. It was then inoculated previous to planting 1 cultures of Funarium oxysporum No. 35 grown on Melilotus stems. ' moisture content of the soil at the start of the experiment was 20.4 cent dry weight. This was 60 per cent of the moisture holding capa - , previously determined to be 34 per cent dry weight. The soil was t at the desired moisture content as in Experiment 4. All the contain - were placed atuhe desired temperatures immediately after planting, hty plants were grown in the experiment, 60 of them in inoculated soil 20 used as controls. Forty of these plants were started in a cool ?nhouse at a temperature of about 18° C. Thermograph records of the temperature in the house showed an average mean of 64.7* F. .2° C), an average maximum of 69.3° F. (20.7° C.I, and an average y minimum of 60.1° F., (15.6° C). The other 40 plants were started &gt; soil temperature tanks in the same greenhouse. These tanks war* 1 at 24°, 28°, 28°, 32°, and 36° C. Temperature records were made twice daily in all the tanks and </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 showed the temperature of the soil in the various sets at the depth of 3 inches to average 23.6°, 27.7*, 27.9°,30.6°, and 35.7° C. On January 3 all the plants growing in tanks at 24°, 28°, 32°, and 36° were transferred to room temperature (18° C). Thirty-two of the plants that had been growing at (18°) room temperature were transferred to 24°, 28°, 32°, and 36° tanks. One set of 8 plants was allowed to remain in the second 28° tank thruout the experiment and another set was left at (18°) room temperature thruout the experiment. At the time the temperatures were changed, January 3, the soil moisture of half of the plants in each set, 3 inoculated and 1 control, was allowed to drop to 13.6 per cent dry weight, or 40 per cent of the moisture holding capacity; the other half of each set remaining at 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity. Results. — All plants were examined almost daily and the notes taken are represented briefly in Tables 9a and 9b with the final notes taken at digging time. At the time the temperatures were changed (January 3) all the plants growing at 18°C. (room temperature) were in a healthy, vigorous condition. The plants in the tanks were all healthy and vigorous except at 32° and 36°, where the high soil temperature caused rather small, weak, spindling plants. When these plants were changed to 18° they gradually lost this appear - ance, and at the end of the experiment were apparently not suf - fering from this previous exposure to a high soil temperature. Likewise, the plants changed from 18° to 32° and 30° turned yellow and wilted considerably during the first 2 weeks, but after losing their lower leaves growth was renewed and the controls showed no signs of wilting at the close of the experiment. The effect of the dropping of the soil moisture content from 60 to 40 per cent of the moisture holding capacity of the soil was apparent in a drooping and wilting of the leaves. This was not accom - panied by any yellowing, however, and the plants usually re - covered from the change in the soil moisture in less than 2 weeks. ( )nly 3 control plants out of 20 in the experiment showed any wilt, Isolations were made from both stems and roots of these control plants, and Fnsarium oxysparum was not recovered in anv instance. The greatest amount of infection occurred at the constant temperature of 28 °C. There was severe wilting of all plants, accompanied by a vascular discoloration and considerable root injury and isolations revealed the presence of Fusarium oxy - sporvm in every plant. There was no apparent difference in the amount of wilt at this temperature with different soil moisture contents. The next greatest amount of wilting occurred in the plants grown at 18° and changed to 32° and 36° with 40 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Table 9a. — Relation of varying soil temperatures and moistures to the infection of Bliss Triumph potatoes from soil inoculated with Fusarium oxysporum. No. 35 Experiment 5 JBL Treatment F. oxytporum Temperature of plants Vaacular Stem Root From From WOt oWoloration | rot injury root. Mem. Per ft Ur.,rr,, C. II All plant, he althy Control 1 1 1 1 2 18 to 24 Inoculated 3 4 Control 1 1 2 18 to M Inoculated 3 1 4 Control 1 1 1 • * t 18 to 32 Inoculated III 1 1 i Control 1 1 0 :i :\ 1 t * S S Ml M 18 to M j Inoculated • 3 3 1 • 4 M.O40 Control 1 2 M to 18 Inoculated 3 :! S 1 4 I Control 1 1 I 32 to 18 Inoculated 3 1 1 1 4 I Control... 1 S :t 1 I XS to 18 Inoculated ■ 3 :t 1 4 Control 1 2 24 to 18 j Inoculated &lt; S 4 1 u I Control 1 S I 10 • 1 :l t S — t 28 Inoculated 3 1 3 i » « o 3 I Soil moisturei are expressed in per cent of the moiatur* holding capacity (M cent dry weight). soil moisture. The only other wilted plants occurred at (18° to 28°) and (28° to 18°). All plants held at 18° remained healthy. Symptomi Culture ..f </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Potato Wilt I &lt;t &gt;i»ed by Fusarium Oxysporum 57 Table 9b. — Relation of varying soil temperatures and moisture* to the infection of Bliss Triumph potatoes from soil inoculated 'with Fusarium oxysporvm No. 36 Experiment 5 Symptoms Cultures of P. ojrytporwm From From roots wtmmm Soil Treatment of plants moisture 1 Temperature Vasrular Stem Root •^coloration rot injury Wilt V,' ]&gt;■ It All plants he althy Control 1 1 1 T ■ 3 IS li 21 Inoculated 1 3 4 Control 1 - 1 •1 f 1 &gt; I » to 2k , Inoculated 3 1 If ■1 3 1 1 • 0 Control ! 2 I 4 3 2 I \ Inoculated M t,. ■ Control 1 1 I — I — t ■&gt; M '.. :t« Inoculated .1 4 3 60 t ■ Control 1 1 0 1 I 4 2 Inoculated M to 18 Control 1 X to IM Inoculated S 4 3 2 ♦ + Control 1 2 4 1 ZS to 18 Inoculated 0 0 I 1 Control 1 2 I 4 Inoculated 24 to 18 Control 1 2 4 3 I I 2 I 3 3 — t S 3 t S o + 0 + M Inoculated 0 ♦ ' Soil moutum are expressed in per cent of the moisture holding per cent dry weight i. (34 capacity There was a very slight amount of disease present in the plants grown at (18° to 24°) and (24° to 18°). No wilting occurred 0 • • + 0 + + + 0 0 0 + 0 « 0 — + + </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 \ I) •an/- li/rn ultlir I /• r i Station lirxiiii'l liul ' ' iaiiy of the inoculated plants changed to 18° on January 3 10 vascular discoloration was present in a number of plants I the causal organism was isolated in pure culture. Isolations were made from practically all the plants showing ting accompanied by vascular discoloration or considerable t injury. One plant at (18° to 36°C.) was so badly decayed t isolations were impractical. In most cases 4 tissue cultures *e made from each specimen. If any of these showed Fumrium /.*/&gt; a rum the cultures were marked in the table as positive, na 2* plants with diseased roots. F. oxynparum was isolated times, or 39 per cent. Cultures from the stems of 32 plants lded F. oxysporum 16 times or 50 per cent. Fifteen plants iwed complete or nearly complete wilt. F. owi/xporum was lated from only 7 of them. Two of these l."&gt; plants iwed no vascular discoloration or root injury and the other ielded various species of Fusaria. but not F. oxynporum. Slight lowing of the lower leaves even when accompanied by slight ting appears to have no value in estimating the amount of The chief difference in the effect of changing the soil moisture at the time the temperatures were changed appeared to be in the greater amount of stem rot and the smaller amount of wilt with the higher soil moisture. The extent of root injury was greater on infected plants at the higher moisture content altho there was only one more plant showing root injury than at the low moisture. ,■ i j j — — — There was undoubtedly some vascular discoloration, either accompanying positive wilting symptoms or without any signs of wilt, that was not caused by Fusorium oxysporum. Cultures made from 20 plants showing vascular discoloration accompanied by wilt yielded F. oxysporum only 10 times: and 12 plants show - ing vascular discoloration and with no wilt yielded F. oxysporum only c&gt; times. Thus, the causal organism was isolated from only 50 per cent of the plants. Neither vascular browning nor wilting of the tops is a sure index of the presence of F. oxysporum. EXPERIMENT «. FEBRUARY 13 TO MAY 11. 1K2 This experiment differs from the previous soil temperature experiment in that the soil used was not sterilized and the freshly cut seed tubers were dipped in a water suspension of spores just previous to planting. The soil was also inoculated as in the previous experiments. It was thought that soil sterilization or disinfection might have been a factor in causing the small percentage of positive infections obtained in previous experiments, so this experiment </seg>
            <seg id="p059">l',,t,lt,, Wilt Ctiiixiil In/ Fnxari inn O.ri/K/Hiritiii 59 was planned in order to eliminate such possible injury. The seed-piece as well as the soil was inoculated in an attempt to produce a type of infection similar to that reported by MacMillan i ll'lit). Infection thru the seed-piece from the soil did not ap - j&gt;ear to any extent in the previous experiments when the soil was heavily inoculated, so this experiment was planned with a direct inoculation of the freshly cut seed-piece as well as soil inocula - tion. Mfthtiils. — The soil was mixed as in the previous experiments and inoculated with cultures of Fund riant oxytporum No. 35 grown on boiled rice and Melilotus stems. The seed tubers used were from the same lot H those in Experiment 5. The freshly cut seed-pieces were dipped in a water suspension of spores similar to the inoculum used for the soil. The soil moisture was held at 26.3 per cent dry weight. This was 70 per cent of the moisture holding capacity, previously determined to be 37.6 per cent dry weight. Immediately after planting, all cans were re - moved to the desired temperatures. The cans were watered thruout the experiment by surface and subsoil watering. The surface of the soil was covered with crushed rock. Six inoculated and 2 control cans were used at each of the following temperatures, 18°, 24°, 28°, 32°, and C. Temperature records showed the temperature in the various sets to average as follows: 17.9°, 24.1°, 28.2°, 32.0°, and 34.7". The air temperature was held at 18° at the start, but during the latter half of the experiment it often reached 25° during the day. li'rxulfy. — Altho we would expect a greater amount of infec - tion in this experiment than in Ex|K&gt;riment 3. due to the direct inoculation of freshly cut seed. Table 10 shows a very small per - centage of positive inoculations. The 2 experiments were run for the same length of time and inoculum from the same strain of Fusarium was used. Potato seed from the same source was used in both experiments, but the seed in this experiment was about 3 months older than in Experiment 5. At the close of the experiment, only one typical case of wilt due to infection with Fiixiiriinn ojeysfHtrtim was found. In general, there was consider - able drying and yellowing of the leaves, due to the rather high air temperature toward the close of the experiment. The plants ;it I s ('. were the most vigorous in the experiment. The greatest difference between inoculated and control plants was found in the few plants grown at H2 . The only positive case of wilt occurred at _' s . In general, the controls showed as much infection as the inoculated plants. This was probably due to the fact that the soil was not sterilized. Three control plants and only 2 inoculated plants showed vascular discoloration of the underground stem, altho the infection appeared deeper in the inoculated ones than in the controls. Three controls and 4 inoculated plants showed root injury, and again the injury appeared greatest in the in- </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska At/rii nltuml Es/&gt;. station. Hit, ,i I'h Bui. ~-i r\X 10. — Relation of soil temperature to infection of Blix* Triumph potatoes when both soil and seed were inoculated with Fitsarium oxysporum So. S-'i Experiment f&gt; ' Symptoms Culture, of F. oxyrporum Tern- Treatment perature of plants Vascular Stem Root From From Wilt discoloration rot injury roots stems LJf (jrtps ' ii 2 controls, 6 inoculated plants, all healthy Control 1 Inoculated 5 Control 1 1* Inoculated 5 2 controls and 5 inoculated plants failed to germinate ■il Inoculated 8 ■&gt; 2 3 18- to 32 Control 1 Inoculated 2 •&gt; M 2 controls and 6 inoculated plants failed to germinate 1 TTi« moisture content of the soil wax kept at 70 per cent of the moisture holding capacity or 26.3 per cent dry weisht. § These two plants had been growing at 18° and were placed at S2°C. on March 22 replace seed that failed to germinate. oeii hited ones. Cultures of F. oxytpormn were obtained from all plants showing va:seular browning of the underground stem. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxygprnntn 61 Effect of High Soil Temperature on the Potato Plant Two plants inoculated with Fusarium oxyttpomm and 1 con - trol plant grown in the IN tank with an air temperature of about I8 C C. were found to l*&gt; healthy at the end of the experiment. These plant- were left in the tanks and were submitted to the extreme -oil tem|&gt;erature of about 60' for one hour and then brought back to 18 and left at this temperature for 2 weeks. All 3 plant ~ when dug showed a distinct vascular browning, ap - pearing very similar to the vascular browning caused by F. oxy - uporinn. The tissue of the underground portion of the stem was softened and slightly rotted l&gt;oth in the inoculated and in the control plants. The roots were slightly injured. Cultures from the browned vascular system were sterile. This would indi - cate that we might expect vascular browning from other causes than F. ttsyxponim infection, and that this browning is rather a poor criterion for pronouncing the plant to be infected with F. n.ri/xpiiritm unless it is considered along with other symptoms. While the temperature used was extremely high, it is very prob - able that the same results may be obtained by using a lowei t&lt;'iii|wratiirt&gt; with a longer or intermittent exposure. Effect of High Air and Soil Temperature on the Disease Six jM&gt;ts. 4 with inoculated soil and % 2 controls, were planted at the same time as Soil Temperature Experiment 1. Similar soil and seed and the same methods were used for the inoculations. These pots were kept in a greenhouse maintained at the approxi - mate temperature of 2o°0. until they were all about 6 inches high with a good even growth and no signs of disease. They were then removed to a high temperature greenhouse (30°-33°). Ten days after being changed to this high temperature the infected I ilant - were badly yellowed and wilted : the controls were slightly wilted. Ten days later, all the plants were entirely wilted. The controls, altho entirely dead above ground, showed no signs of disease in the underground parts, the stems, roots and stolons be - ing healthy. Fusarium oxysporum was recovered from the rotted underground portion of the stems of the inoculated plants. It was very probable that infection had already set in before these plants were removed to the high temperature and that this high temperature simply favored the rapid advance of the dis - ease. It is noticeable, however, that altho the roots and stems of the control plants remained healthy the tops wilted rapidly, and the above-ground symptoms could not be used in identifying the presence of the organism. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Xehramku Af/rirultumt /•.'./•/». Station, Rexeitnh Hul &gt; Relation of Soil Moisture to Infection of Roots from the Soil EXPERIMENT 1. DECEMBER 11. 1*1*. TO MAECH 11. 1M1 tin the previous experiments with controlled soil teinpera - es it was found that the soil moisture content was also a factor determining the amount and severity of infection and that a inge in the soil moisture during the experiment affected the ults. The extent of the influence of soil moisture was rather •d to determine, as the soil temperatures won- also varied in se experiments. The following experiment was planned to I the effect of varying soil moisture contents ii|M&gt;n the ili-e;»-e en the soil and air laapemture remained approximately eon - nt. Method*.— The experiment was conducted in a greenhouse maintain - ed at a temperature of approximately 25'C. Seed tubers of the Early Ohio variety were used from the same lot as those used in Soil Temperature Experiment 3, and were treated in the same way. Soil was prepared in the same way as for the soil temperature experiments. Four-gallon earth - enware crocks were used for containers, each holding 16,fi.iO crams of soil. dry weight. The soil was inoculated just previous to planting with cul - tures of Fuxarium oj-iixpurum No. If. Two seed tubers were planted in each container. The soil moisture was maintained by watering methods similar to those used in the soil temperature experiments. One thousand grams of crushed rook was used on the surface of the soil. Tin- moisture holding capacity of the soil as determined by the 25 cm. cup method was 35 per cent dry weight. Twenty-seven containers were used, being divided Into 3 sets, each set composed of :: controls and fi inoculated pots. The soil In these 3 sets of 9 containers each was started at approximately 40. SO. and 80 per cent of the moisture holding rapacity of the soil, equal to 14. 21, and 2S per cent dry weight, respectively. The soil after inoculation wan brought up to the desired moisture content in each set and allowed to stand about 10 days before planting. The soil moisture content in each of these sets was changed on January 8 by dividing each set into -' loU of 1 control and 2 inoculated containers each. Thus, in Set 1. 'ainers (at 40 per cent of moisture holding capacity) were divided into 3 lots. Three containers were left at 40 per cent, 3 changed to 6t&gt; per cent, and 3 to SO per cent of the moisture holding capacity of the soil. In the same way, the sets being held at fi&lt;&gt; and 80 per cent were each subdivided Into 3 lots. In changing the moisture contents, if the desired i&gt;oint was higher, water was added at the rate of 500 c c. per day until the desired point was reached. If a lower moisture content was wanted, the soil was allowed to dry out naturally until the desired moisture content was reached. The maximum change, that is. from 40 to 80 per cent of the moisture holding capacity or vice versa, took place in approximately 10 days. From 40 to 60 per cent or 60 to 80 per cent took about one-half this time. Weighings were made and the moisture contents calculated for each day while changing, but as the slight variation in the length of time nec - essary to change the moisture content did not appear to be correlated with any of the final results, the figures are not presented here. On February IS the moisture contents of the 9 lots were changed back to the original moisture content of the 3 sets. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">r,.t,,tu II iff ('tiiincd by F nxii riii in Oxysponim 63 X ww.v. 11. — Relation of xoil moisture to infection of Early Ohio potato phmtx from soil inoculated with Fusarium Experiment 1 * Symptoms Cultures of F. oxysporum Soil moisture Treatment of plants Vascular Stem Root From From Wilt discoloration rot injury roots stems Per &lt;*» Control 1 Inoculated 2 Inoculated 3 Ki 40 to M to Contral 1 Inoculated 2 3 Inoculated 3 2 1 40 40 to M to Control 1 1 Inoculated 2 1 Inoculated 3 2 •) 3 m :i Control 1 Inoculated 2 Inoculated 3 Hit 1 1 1 SO to 40 to Control 1 Inoculated 2 1 Inoculated 3 — 1 M 1 1 ♦ M la !*0 to Control 1 Inoculated 2 Inoculated 3 :t 1 -t - + HO Control . . 1 1 Inoculated 2 1 Inoculated 3 — Ml ■&gt; 2 1 + Control 1 1 Inoculated 2 1 Inoculated 3 80 to 60 to :t 1 I 80 Control 1 Inoculated 2 80 to 40 to 1 1 - 80 Inoculated 3 2 •&gt; 3 + &lt; Each container represent* 2 plant*, being coniidered her* a* a unit. If either plant in a pot became infected the plant ia marked positive, the decree of infection being baaed on the number of atema and roota infected and the severity of infection. 'Soil moistures are expressed in per cent of the moisture holding capacity (86 par cent dry weight i. o.ri/xporum X&lt;&gt;. -1'j 11 + + 1 1 — ! + 8 3 + + - 1 + -I- 11— — i i — + 3 3 + + </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Xebnuka Ayrio/tuml hx/,. Station. Itrm-nrrh H«\. .'. Result*. — The n'sult.s of this experiment are shown in Table 11. The germination of the seed was very uniform, altho t lit* plants started at 40 per cent of the moisture holding capacity were a little slower in breaking thru the ground. On January 8. when I lie soil moistures were first changed, all the plants were healthy altho the size varied with the moisture content of the soil, those growing at 40 per cent averaging about 2.5 inches in height, those at BO per cent. 4 inches, and those at 80 ]ht &lt;vm. 4.5 inches. The change in soil moistures, when- the moisture content was lowered, was sometimes followed l&gt;\ a drooping of the leaves, but the plants recovered quickly and were apparently normal in about 10 days, the time used in reaching the new mois - ture content. On February 15. when the moisture contents were again changed, no definite wilting hud occurred in any of the plants, nltho there was a slight yellowing of the lower In*M in nil sets, this U'ing more marked in the 40 per cent set than at the higher moisture contents. At the higher moistures, however. the plant- were not as sturdy, the tops often drooping over. At the qIok of the experiment ii was found that the underground stems of the plants at 80 per cent were much smaller in diameter than those at the lower moisture content.*. As shown in Table 11. the sets held at a constant moisture content showed less infection than those in which the moisture content was changed. The smallest amount of infection occurred at the constant moisture content of 40 per cent while the largest amount ocenrred at 80 jx»r cent. The reverse i- true, however, in regard to the pot- in which the moisture content was varied. The largest amount of wilt along with the heaviest infection of stem and root- occurred in the (40 to 80 to 40) jx'r cent lot. and the next in tlie i 40 to •',() to 40) per cent lot. There was not a great deal of difference between the other sets, altho there appeared to Im&gt; slightly more &gt;tem infection in the 80 per cent lots than in the W) \h-v cent lots. Thn&gt;e of the control plants showed symptoms of the clisea&gt;&lt;&gt; lint Fiixiif'mm orygpnnim was isolated successfully from only one of them. Cultures from the inoculated plants showing symptoms of disease yielded F. &lt;xeyspor&gt;im from either the stems or the roots in every instance. EXPERIMENT 2. DECEMBER S, IBI, TO FEBRUARY 2*. 1*22 This experiment was planned somewhat similarly to Soil Moisture Experiment 1, except that a different variety of potatoes was used and the soil moistures were changed once, and were not brought back to the original soil moisture content as in Experi- </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Potato Wilt (anted by Fusarium Oxytpornm 65 Method*. — Tubers of the Bliaa Triumph variety were used from the same lot m those used In Soil Temperature Experiment 6. They were treated in the same way, except that immediately before planting the cut surfaces which had calloused over while the sprouts were starting were freshly cut and planted In soil that had been inoculated at the same time and in the same way as for Soil Temperature Experiment 5. The tubers were planted In 3-gallon stone crocks, one seed-piece to each crock which contained 12 kilograms of soil with 1,000 grams of gravel added to the surface. The soil was watered as in the previous experiment. All the i&gt;ots were filled with soil and allowed to stand for 2 weeks before plant - ing. During this time the moisture content of the soil was brought up to the desired point. Thirty-six crocks were used in the experiment, being divided at the start into 3 sets, each having 9 inoculated and 3 control trocks. These 3 sets were held at 3 different soil moisture contents, as indicated In Table 12. The moisture holding capacity of the soil was 14 iwr cent dry weight determined by the 25 cm. cup method. Set 1 waa held at 40 per cent of the moisture holding capacity (12.1 per cent dry weight) ; set 2 at 60 per cent (20.4 per cent dry weight) ; set 3 at 80 per cent (27.2 per cent dry weight). When the plants were about 6 inches in height, January 9, the soil moisture was changed, so that each set was divided up into 3 lots, each with 3 inoculated and 1 control plant, the same as In the previous experiment. The entire experiment was run In a greenhouse where thermograph records showed the average daily max - imum temperature to be 80.5°F. (26.9°C), the average daily minimum at 71.5°F. (21.9°C), and the average daily mean temperature 75.5°P. 24.2-C). In order to check the possible error in the percentage of soil moisture in the different sets, 2 samples were taken from each of 3 crocks labeled 4n. 60. and SO per cent of moisture holding capacity. These showed the following errors to be present at the end of the experiment In the pots tested : 40 per cent = 12.1 per cent dry weight, at close of experiment was 41.1 per cent or 14 per cent dry weight. 60 per cent = 20.4 per cent dry weight, at close of experiment was 60.5 per cent or 20.6 per cent dry weight. 80 per cent = 27.2 per cent dry weight, at close of experiment was 70.0 per cent or 23.8 per cent dry weight. This showed practically no error in the crocks at 40 and 60 per cent of the moisture holding capacity, but a considerable drop In the 80 per cent set. This was probably due to the increased weight of the plant which was not taken into account in the watering and which in the 40 to 60 per cent sets seemed to be about balanced by the decrease in the moisture holding capacity of the soil due to packing during the experi - ment. Renulta. — All i&gt;limt&gt; were dug and examined February 20, 1022. Notes were taken thruout the experiment. All plants remained healthy except for a drying and slight yellowing of the lower leaves during the latter part of the experiment. No typical Fusarium wilt appeared in any of the plants. The tabulated results in Table 12 do not show any clear-cut results as to the effect of soil moisture on the disease. One plant </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Xebrttxkii A&lt;/riritItural Erp. Station, Research Bui. 23 fsd at 40 per cent moisture in Set 1, but this appeared to be due causes other than Fusarium oxysporum. As in the previous experiment, the plants were about one week slower in breaking thru the ground at 40 per cent than at the higher moisture contents. When the soil moistures were changed, all the plants in the experiment were apparently healthy and averaged about &lt;&gt; inches in height. At the close of the ex - periment all plants showed a slight yellowing and drying of the Table 12. — Relation of soil moisture to infection of Blixx Triumph potatoes from soil inoculated with Fiisariinn Symptom. Culture* of F. uxyiporum Treatment • »f plant! Soil moisture' Vascular Stem Root discoloration rot injury rVom From root* iteaaa Will Prr «M Control I ■1 40 Inoculated 3 * Control 1 1 40 60 Inoculated 3 4 Control 1 I 80 Inorulated 3 4 Control 1 2 40 Inoculated 3 4 Control 1 2 -o M Inoculated. 3 4 Control I 2 80 Inoculated 3 I * 1 Control 1 2 1 40 Inoculated 3 4 so BO 1 control, 3 inoculated healthy »M 1 control, 3 inoculated healthy 1 Soil moiaturn are expressed in per cent of the moisture holding rapacity. 114 per cant dry weight I. oxysporvm So. M Experiment 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Potato Wilt ('mix,;/ hi/ Fimarium Oxi/nponint 67 lower leaves not associated with the disease. There were no marked differences between the various sets. Only one plant showed any wilting symptoms and this was not due to Fusarium infection. It is worthy of note that altho this experiment was conducted at a temperature averaging about 25° and the same inoculated soil, and seed from the same source as that of Soil Temperature Experiment 5 was used, the amount of infection was considerably less than that obtained in the Soil Temperature Experiment at a constant temperature of 28° C, where the greatest amount of infection took place. It is also noticeable that in this experiment where the soil was heavily infested the seed tubers were planted with a freshly cut surface exposed for infection and at a temperature and soil mois - ture higher than that found under ordinary field conditions, and yet no results were obtained that were remotely comparable with those reported by MacMillan (1919) for soil infection thru the seed-pieces under field conditions. DISCUSSION These experiments, conducted with as many environmental factors under control as was possible and with inoculations with various strains of Fusarium oxysporum, show the usual confusion of results. It was impossible to obtain consistent results in con - secutive experiments and in most cases the percentage of infection was rather low. It was evident, however, that temperatures of I s C. and below were unfavorable for the development of the disease and that in general the amount of infection increased with increasing soil temperatures. It was noticeable that under these conditions the disease developed most readily at temperatures unfavorable for the host plant. Plants started at a temperature low enough to be unfavorable for the disease but later transfer - red to a higher temperature showed nearly as much disease as those kept at a constant higli temperature: while those started at high temperatures and later transferred to lower temperatures showed practically no disease, as did those kept at a constant low temperature. Constant low soil moistures were unfavorable for the de - velopment of the disease. However, when the soil moisture con - tent was varied it was found that the disease developed best when the plants were started at a low soil moisture content, changed to high &gt;oil moistures during the critical period in the life of the plant, and later lowered to the original low soil moisture content. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Xebrattka Agricultural h'-r/i. Station. Retearch Bui. 68 It was also noticeable in all these tests that with increasing soil moisture the amount of rotting of the roots and steins increased and the wilting symptoms were not as marked a&gt; at the lower soil moistures. It was also shown that there was often present a discoloration of the vascular system of the main stem, either in the absence of wilt or accompanying these symptoms, that was not caused by Fmuiriinii twy*/toriint. If the plants were sub - mitted to extremely high temperatures for relatively -liort inter - vals, a vascular discoloration was produced that bad all the aspects of Fusarium infection. It is also worthy of note that in all these infection tests no correlation could lie made lietwtfii t lie presence of the disease and the roMing of seed -pieces. Where infection took place, it was thru the roots and not thru the seed-pieces. In all of these tests, the seed-pieces U'haved alike IkiIIi in the controls and in the in - oculated plants. INFECTION FROM THE SOU. THRl THE SEED-PIECE Review III all the published work on Fusarium wilt previous to 1919. the emphasis was placed upon the infection of the plant from the soil thru the roots or by the planting of infected -eed. In - fection of the plant from the xiil thru the seed-piece was not recorded until MacMillan's (1919) publication. This may very probably i&gt;e accounted for as MacMillan sugge-t- i p. _'m)i: Since the part of Fusarium spp. in the creation of disease depends largely on environmental factors, it is important to note that the condi - tions which prevail in Colorado do not exist in the same way in other places. The descriptions of diseases caused by species of Fusarium already published do not. therefore, closely apply to Colorado, because the climate, coupled with the soil conditions and irrigation practice existing there, creates a condition unknown in the East, where mom of the work on Vusarium spp. has been done. The writer has found this statement to hold true not only as regards the different manifestations of the disease in the irri - gated sections of western Nebraska as compared with previous observations in Michigan, but also as compared with dry land sections of western Nebraska. In other words, the type of* infec - tion appears to lie due in a great measure to the environmental conditions and it is impossible to predict what will happen under irrigation in the West from experimental data obtained in the East or from dry land conditions in the West. It i&gt; not necessary, however, to have a different type of infection in order to produce </seg>
            <seg id="p069">I'ottlt Wilt CitiiMttl hi/ FuMiirium Oxyxponim 69 lirtVmii symptoms of disease: it i&gt; only necessary to have present lifferent environmental conditions after infection has taken place. All 3 types of infection discussed in this paper have been found in Michigan :i&gt; well as in the irrigated fields of Nebraska but the mnoimt of each of these 3 types varied with the conditions present. MacMHlan reports experiments in which the seed tubers were inoculated with a spore &gt;uspension of Fusarium oxygporum and then planted either in flats or under field conditions, also by in - oculating the seed-pieces of plants which had already sent up sprout-. He obtained nearly 100 per cent infection with this method of inoculation. He concludes from these experiments i ]). :'.O0) : Two methods of infection are recognized: Infection from the soil of roots and root hairs, and infection of the seed-piece, whereby the plant becomes diseased. The latter method is regarded as the most serious and responsive to environmental conditions in the Greeley district of Colorado. While he does not state the conditions under which his ex - periments were conducted as to temperature and moisture, he ijrs in referring to the relation of soil temperature to infection Seed-i&gt;irre infection will occur at a considerably lower temperature han root infection. The author found that under the conditions prevailing in Michigan during the experiments previously discussed infection from the &gt;oil thru the seed-pieces occurred but rarely. It was found &gt;o seldom that it was not considered of any importance tinder those conditions. It might also be noted that in these ex - |ieriments rotting of the underground stem was very rare, and in general, conditions were not favorable and probably are very sel - ilom favorable in Michigan for this ty])e of infection. In the numerous soil infection experiments conducted under controlled conditions, the seed-piece very often remained healthy thruout the ex|ieriment and in only a fe\r cases could the infection l&gt;e tracd to the -ced tnU'r. Greenhouse Experiments, 1920-21 In 1920 a few tests were made with artificially Infected seed. Healthy Irish Cobbler potatoes were inoculated by placing a few drops of spore suspension in a small hole bored out of the tuber. It was then sealed with a cover glass and planted in sterilized soil. Three seed-pieces inoculated with Fusdiium oxygporum So. 33 and grown in a greenhouse maintained at approximately 17 ('. produced healthy plants with no signs of wilt. One seed-piece had rotted slightly and the base of one stem of this plant was slightly infected. In the other 2 the infection of the seed-piece </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Xebraxku Agrimltural £'j-/&gt;. Station, Renearih /in/. 2i progressed only a short distance beyond the point of inoculation and the seed remained attached to the stem when the plant was dug. Two seed - pieces were inoculated with F. orytporum No. 8 and kept at the aame temperature. Both plants were healthy, the seed-pieces being only slightly rotted. All these plants were duplicated in another greenhouse with a temperature maintained at approximately 27°. All plants remained healthy, and the seed-pieces were still attached, altho they had rotted con - siderably further than in the plants held at 17°. t During 1921, 16 tubers were inoculated in the same way with inrium orysporum No. 35, and kept in a greenhouse at a temperature 25°C. Half of these plants were watered as usual and the other half re given an excess of water. Only 1 plant showed wilt and this was the heavily watered set. The seed-piece had completely decayed and infection of the main stem started at the base and had resulted in a t rot. tThis method of infection was also tried in Soil Temperature Ex - ment 6, p. 58. where the freshly rut seed-pieces were dipped in a e suspension just previous to planting, the soil also being inoculated. bTliis method of infection was tested in l'.t-Jl under field con ons. The experiment was run in triplicate, three plots haviu erent environmental conditions being used. Location of plot*. — Plot 1 was located at the Agricultural College. Lincoln, Nebraska. No potatoes had been grown on this land for 15 years. This plot was used to represent the conditions found In eastern Nebraska, where there is an average annual rainfall of about 30 inches and a high mean daily temperature during the summer months. Plot 2 was located at the substation at Mitchell, Nebraska. The soil was a light sandy loam and was handled as a dry land plot. Plot 3 was located also at Mitchell, but on a heavier soil, and the crop was grown under irri - gation. Plots 2 and 3 were used to represent the dry land and irrigated potato sections of western Nebraska, where the annual rainfall is only about 16 inches, or half that of eastern Nebraska, and where the daily mean temperatures are lower than eastern Nebraska, and the night tem - peratures considerably lower. The meteorological data for these 3 plot &gt; are shown in Figures 3, 4, and 5. Neither Plot 2 nor 3 was under the true typical conditions found in most of western Nebraska, but they approximated it as closely as was practical. t Rainfall — There was considerable difference in the precipitation rds between eastern Nebraska and western Nebraska. During t It* ths that the experiment was conducted, we find the following monthly precipitation records. April May 2.27 in. 3.44 in. 0.44 in. 2.32 in. June July Aug. Sept. 4.95 in. 6.00 in. 3.35 in. 3.63 In. 1.84 in. 2.40 in. 1.79 in. 1.38 in. During the time the experiment was conducted at Lincoln, that is. April 20 to August 8, there were 23 days with more than 0.1 inch precipi - tation, and there were only 4 periods of more than 5 days without measurable precipitation, the longest being 10 days. There were 5 rain - falls of more than 1 inch. Field Experiments, 1921 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">I'otilt Wilt Canned by Fumrium Oxygporum 71 4. and 5. — Graphs showing soil moisture (Pig. 3) (or foot depths Figs a expressed as per cent of the moisture holding capacity, mean weekly air temperature (Fig. 4) and soil temperature (Fig. 5) for com- paratWe weeks of 3 different plots In the 1921 Field Experiments </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 X, IniixLn At/ rir nit ural h's/&gt;. Station, Iletuinth /in/. iJ t During the experiment at Mitchell, May 20 to September 20, a iod about 2 weeks longer than the Lincoln Experiment, there were days with more than 0.1 inch precipitation. There were 6 periods of re than 5 days without precipitation, one being for 15 days and two for During this period there were no raiafalls of 1 inch or more. tSoil moixturr. — The soil moisture of the various plots is represented &gt;hlcally in Figure 3. The soil samples were obtained with a soil ?r for 1 ft. depths. The moisture holding capacity of the various s. obtained by the 25 cm. cup method, was as follows: Plot 1, 50 cent dry weight: Plot 2. 30 per cent dry weight: Plot 3, 3o per cent weight. The graphs in Figure 3 are based upon the percentage of the iture holding capacity rather than upon the actual percentage of moisture by dry weight. It Is clearly seen that Plot 1 had a higher percentage of moisture throughout the experiment. There was a considerable drop In moisture about 3 weeks before the close of the experiment. Plots 2 and 3 bad about the same relative amounts of moisture for the first month of the experiment, after which Plot :! shows an increase in moisture due to irrigation. Two applications of water were made to Plot :!. the first on July 20, the second on August 12. The results of these irrigations are clearly shown in the graphs. Air t&lt; • mperaivre. — In Figure 4 are presented the weekly mean air temperatures for comparative weeks of the experiment for all 3 plots. During the first 4 weeks of the experiment the air temperatures were considerably lower in Plot 1 than in the others; the opposite was true during the latter part of the experiment. The air temperatures of Plots 2 and 3 were about the same since these were located within a short distance of each other; accordingly, only Plot 2 is represented in Figure 4. Soil temperature. — The weekly mean soil temperatures for com - parative weeks of the experiment for all :! plots are plotted in Figure 5. The same thing is found here as in the comparative air temperatures except that the differences are more distinct; Plot 1 had much lower temperatures during the first half of the experiment and much higher during the latter half Plots 2 and 3 had very similar soil temperatures. All seed potatoes used in these plots were of the Bliss Triumph vari - ety grown in the dry land section of western Nebraska, and were very free of all diseases, having been selected from field inspections the previ - ous year. All seed-pieces were cut to approximately the same size. The seed was all treated with mercuric chloride. Stock cultures of Fusarium orynpnrvm No. 8. 35, and 56 were used for all inoculations. Spore sus - pensions for Inoculating purposes were made from 14-day-old cultures on rice and hard potato agar. 1 Three different methods of inoculations were used. In Method No. 1, the seed tubers were inoculated by boring a hole in the tuber 1 to 1.5 cm. deep and 3 mm. in diameter within 1 inch of a sprout. Small glass tubes of 3 mm. bore and with one end closed were filled with 0.5 c. c. of spore susi)ension and placed in the cavity of the tuber. The tubers were then planted immediately. In Method No. 2, the seed tubers were inoculated by immersing the freshly cut seed-pieces in a spore suspension of the organism and planted immediately. In Method No. 3, the cut seed-pieces were allowed to callous over for 3 days before 1 Previous to this experiment these culture, were all tested for virulence by inocula - tion* of healthy tuber, in the laboratory. Complete rot of the tuber, wh obtained at 15°C. in moist chamber.. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">1'ittato Wilt Conned by Fmtnrium Oxyxpontm 73 inoculating as in 2. All inoculations in Plot 1 were made at the same time and with the same spore suspensions. The same was true of all inoculations in Plots 2 and 3. Plot 1 was planted April 20 and dug August .'! to 8. Plots 2 and 3 were planted May 20 and dug September 21. The difference in date of planting was naturally due to the different seasons in the 2 localities. I'lnt I . —Lincoln. Nebraska. This plot contained 9 inoculated rows and &lt;'&gt; control rows, each row having 35 plants. The 9 in - ociilated rows consisted of 1 row each, for each of the 3 methods of inoculation and each of the 3 strains of Futarium oxysporum used. This plot was examined several times a week thruout the period of the experiment and notes were made when any charac - tristii- differences api&gt;eared in the plants. Only 2 plants wilted out of the 813 grown from inoculated seed-pieces. One of these plants was with Inoculation Method 2. Strain No. 56, and the other with Inoculation Method 3, Strain No. 56. All the control |&gt;lant&gt; remained healthy. There was considerable yellowing of the lower leaves and tipburn of all the plants including controls due to the high temperatures. In this plot the characteristic growth thruout the season was considerably different from that fqund in Plots 2 and 3. All the plants were slightly dwarfed, the leaves small, wrinkled, or curled, sometimes with a slight mottling, the appearance being very similar to the usual mosaic symptoms but in this case being due entirely to environmental conditions. The results at digging time are shown in Tables 13 to 18 ami are compared with the results found in Plots 2 and 3. Each plant was examined separately, the stems being examined for rotting and for vascular discoloration and the new tubers for \a&gt;nilar discoloration. Many of the plants were mature and the steins had dried out too much to observe infection accurately; tbeM- are listed in the tables as "dead." Plot ... — Dry land plot at Mitchell. Nebraska. The seed was inoculated and planted in the same way as in Plot 1. except that hills were planted with each of the 3 strains and each of the 3 methods of inoculation. The distance of these plots from the Agricultural College made it impossible to see these fields during the summer more than 3 times. Notes taken at these times were also supplemented by observations made at various times thruout the season by Clarence Harris of the United States Department of Agriculture, stationed at Mitchell. This plot showed the greatest amount of wilt. The results are tabulated in the follow - ing tables. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 23 Strain of Method Plot 1 Plot 2 Plot 3 Funarium oxysporum of inoculation Per ctnt Per cent Per cent Plot 3. — Planted in the same way and at the same time as Plot 2. This plot was irrigated twice. The plants were very vigorous thruout the experiment. Results. — The percentage of germination was higher in Plot 1 than in Plot "2. and Plot 3 showed the lowest percentage of ger - mination. However, as the controls showed a lower percentage than the inoculated rows in Plots 2 and 3. no conclusions can be drawn as to the effects of inoculations upon germination. There - fore, in the following tables and discussion, the actual number of plants is used as the basis for calculating percentages, rather than the number of seed-pieces planted. Considering the actual wilting of the plant, i. e.. wilting resulting either in death or in wilting from which the plant had not recovered before digging, we find the following percentages in Table 13. This shows that practically no wilt occurred in Plot 1. Plot 2 had the greatest amount of wilt. Strains No. 8 and No. 35 appeared more virulent than No. 56 in Plots 2 and 3. In general, the most successful methods of inoculation were Methods 2 and 3. that is. dipping the seed-pieces in a spore sus - pension. Tahi.e 13. — Percentage of plants wilted d.U 1U.U • - 0 78.5 14.2 0 69.6 10.0 1 0 0 3.1 ■ 0 69.6 3.3 3 0 13.7 3.1 1 0 9.0 6.8 ■ 2 2.8 3.5 0 2.8 7.1 14.-J Control 0 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Potato Wilt ('mixed by Fmuirium Oxyxponim 75 Comparing now the resulting tulters from the plants in Plots 2 and :\ where wilting occurred, by examining all tubers at dig - ging time and classing as infected all tubers showing distinct vax-iilar discoloration or stein-end i-otting. we find in weight comparisons, which were found to be more accurate than the number of infected tul&gt;ers. the percentages presented in Table 14. Table 14. — Com /mi rat ire percentage* of infected t niter* by weight, inn, i irifte/f pbtntx mid healthy plantx of inoculated rote* null healthy plantx from control rotrn Thus, the number of iiiIht&gt; having either vax-ular discolora - tion or rotting &lt;-nn lie correlated not only with wilt but also with upjMtrentlv healthy |&gt;l&lt;int&gt; grown from inoculated seed. The amount of infection was also much greater in Plot '1 than in Plot 8. If we now compare the total yield from the rows having wilted |&gt;laiit~ in Plots •! and -\ (a?- shown in Table 18), we find Tabu t Urn jMinitn'i i/ii/t/x in ijniinx /Mr plant of control ,il iriltnl mi,/ healthy phintx in inoculated rov$ Plot 2 Plot 3 Gram* Gntms Wilted plants 134 500 Inoculated row Healthy plants 244 682 ■ Control rows Healthy plants 369 973 Inoculated rows Control rows Wilted plants Healthy plants Healthy plant No. of plants . 79 166 138 •lot I Percentage of infected tuber? by weight 85.9 33.7 5.3 No. of plants 19 220 144 3 lot 3 Percentage of infected tubers by weight 24.4 15.5 0.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Xebraxkui Af/rirultvral Exp. Station. Renearch Bui. .'-, that the total yield per plant can be correlated, not only with wilted plants, but also with healthy plants from inoculated seed. These results are tabulated in Table 15. The higher yields in Plot 3 where the percentage of infection was low was particularly noticeable. However, the cultural conditions must be taken into consideration in comparing yields in different plots, and of course Plot 3 would have a much higher yield, due to irrigation. The comparison between the different lots of plants within Plot 3 is, however, nearly as marked as in Plot 2. tlf we now an for a comparison the number of stems either d or showing vascular discoloration, we find the following per - tage&lt;: Plot 2 Plot 3 Inoculated rows. .. {Wilted plants !&gt;3 per cent (*4 per cent / Healthy plants 88 per cent 83 per cent Control rows Healthy plants 32 per cent 13 per cent The same relation holds here as in the table, where the in - fected tubers were used as a basis of comparison. The percent - iL't--. however, were all higher and the difference U-tween inocu - lated and controls was not a&gt; great. This was chiefly due to the fact that many of the stems necessarily listed as dead had ma - tured normally: also the differences between the plants in Plots 2 and 3 are chiefly due to the fact that the plants remained green longer under the irrigated conditions. Thi&gt; index, therefore, i- not a very reliable one in judging the amount of disease Disregarding wilting as the chief symptom of the disease ami comparing the several experimental j)lot&gt; -imply on the l&gt;a&gt;i - of inoculated seed-pieces as compared with control rows, we find several interesting comparisons. Table lfi shows the percentage by weight of total tubers wing vascular discoloration or rotting in the various plots. This table shows that by far the greatest amount of infection took place in Plot 2. The next largest was in Plot 3. except in case of Inoculation Method 2 with Fuxarium oxynpovum No. 56, which was greatest in Plot 1. However, the total of all three types of inoculation with Strain No. ."&gt;&lt;; was greatest in Plot 2. The amount of infection in Plot 1 was very small, except with Inoculation Method 2. the other inoculations often running lower than the controls, which average well in Plots 1 and 2 and were much lower in Plot 3. It is also seen that with reference to the strain of Funarium oxysporum used more infected tnl&gt;er&lt; resulted with inoculations </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Vnt,,t,, Wilt Canned hi/ Fiimiriiitn Oxynponim 77 Tabus !«'.. — PervenUige by &gt;r&lt;it/ht of resulting tuber* ha ring with Strain No. S extrpt in Plot 1, where the amount of infection «;i- &gt;mall and the probable error would be correspondingly greater, — thi&gt; in *pite of the fact that Strain 8 is the oldest strain of the three. As regards the method of inoculation, there was uniformly more infection obtained with Inoculation Methods 2 and 3 than with 1. There does not appear from these results to be a advantage in allowing the cut surfaces of the seed - pie** to callous over before planting. If, instead of comparing the amount of infection by the total weight of t niters, we compare the number of plants having in - fected tuliers, the following results are found in Table 17. Tli is table shows the same comparative results as those found in the previous tables, the order of greatest infection being Plot 2, Plot 3, and Plot 1 respectively, except with inoculations with No. 56. where there was more infection in Plot 1 than in Plot 3. It was also noticeable that in general the highest percentages were found with Inoculation Method J. as in the previous tables. There was no clear correlation between the amount of infection in the different plots and the strain of organism used. • —^ - -j ;r ■'- — r ;/ - ■ nixritfur discoloration or stem end rot ■'usarium oxytporum Method of inoculation Plot 1 lot Plot 2 lot 2 Plot 3 lot P$r cent Per cent Per cent 1 12 16.1 0.3 8 2 18.2 85.1 35.7 3 0.0 88.1 63.4 1 0.6 11.9 1.3 35 2 10.8 77.6 32.7 3 2.7 62.7 12.2 1 2.3 11.8 3.7 1 2.3 11.8 3.7 56 2 I 34.0 34.0 25.9 25.9 3.7 A *\ 3.7 :t 12.0 29.6 4.0 3 12.0 29.6 4.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Xrhnixl.n Affrirnlfuml Ejrp. Station. Research Bui. ' I Table 17. — Percentage &lt;&gt;f mature plants harinq infected tuber* Strain of Method Plot 1 Plot 2 Plot I Fuaarium oxysporum of inoculation Per eertl Per cent Per cent 18.5 Averaging tin- total niiinher of infected tubers in all :'&gt; nietl)(«l- of iii(K-ulation&gt;. we tiinl that in IMot 1 tlie &lt;rivate&gt;t in - fection. :{&lt;» per peat. «a&gt; with Strain N&lt;&gt;. 5«; m IMot -l. HIA jmt •flit, with Strain No. :\:&gt;; ami Plot :?. ."&gt;O.."&gt; iht cent, with Strain N... I. The etfivt of these inoculation* on the actual yield of tuberx is shown in Tal&gt;le In. the results 1mm n«jr jfiven in wei^lit |&gt;er plant rather than in total weight for the row. hecause many plant.- did not germinate an&lt;l vet this failure to germinate could not lie correlated with the disease. This show- a higher yield from control plants than from any of the rows pown from inoculated M-ed. the averages Ix-injr lusher thruout. and only one row (in Plot 3) yielding higher than the control. In general the lowest yields in each plot were found in the row- having the greatest amount of disease a&gt; indicated liv wilt or hv infected tubers. This doe- not hold true, however, for each individual row when the variation in the amount of di-eiiM is small. At the time this experiment was completed it was impoutUe to make cultural studies from nil the infected tulier-. A repre- </seg>
            <seg id="p079">I'otot,, Wilt C,m*&lt;&lt;\ },,, F&gt;i*tin,tn, Oxi/xpomm 79 Method Plot 1 Plot 2 Plot 3 Futarium oxyaporum of inoculation Cram* Grams Gram* M 723 1 W •&gt; 170 121 m &gt; 200 166 383 I l 175 316 751 169 743 M ■&gt; 161 3 186 ■&gt;i:i 1,133 1 185 302 599 M f S4 318 N6* J9« I It* 582 Average of inoculations 159 234 715 Controls 241 369 973 -t'litative lot of 83 tiiUT* «a». however. selected from the various plots, and isolations were made from these, usually 3 isolations i&gt;eiii&lt;r made from each tuber. Fusavium ojryxpornm was recovered from 11 tubers. Fusarium spp. exclusive of F. oxyapo-rvm from 17 tubers, miscellaneous fuiipi from 3. and 52 tubers failed to yield any organism in culture. From 3(5 tubers having varying degrees of vascular discoloration in the absence of stem end rot. F. ii.ri/xjKirniii was isolated only twice. Fusariuni spp. twice, and 1_'&gt; cultures from the remaining 3*2 tul&gt;ers were sterile. From 4^ tubers showing l&gt;oth stem-end rot and vascular discoloration. F. oxyxptn'inn was isolated from *.• of them. Fusarium spp. from 1-J. miscellaneous fungi from 3. and cultures from 18 tubers re - mained sterile. Five tul&gt;ers of this lot showing stem-end rot but no vascular discoloration yielded in culture Fusarium spp. from '■\. and Imcterial and miscellaneous fungi from '2. While the nuin- Ikt of tul&gt;ers examined was comparatively small, the results were well in accordance with hundreds of other isolations made al various times bv the writer. Tahi.k \&gt;. - A '•I'l-m/r ireiijht of tttherx in t/rinux /»■/■ plant </seg>
            <seg id="p080">DISCUSSION The infection of the plants through the seed-piece from the soil was shown by MacMillan (1919) to be the chief method of infection under irrigated conditions of Colorado. Such infection in the fields in Michigan is not common in the author's experience. It would be assumed that such a type of infection would be more prevalent in the presence of high soil moistures. The results of the field experiments recorded here do not, however, prove this contention to be true. Judging the amount of infection either by the number of wilted plants, the vascular discoloration of the stem, of the tuber, or by comparative yields, it was found that under the 3 widely different environmental conditions present in these experiments the best development of the disease was in the dry land plots of western Nebraska. Comparing this plot ( No. 2) with the other plots as to environmental conditions, we find that the soil moisture was U&gt;» during the entire experiment than that in Plot 1. where the smallest amount of disease developed, and that there was also a much smaller amount of soil moisture than in the irrigated plot (Xo. 3) during the latter half of the ex - periment. The corresponding temperatures both of soil and of air were relatively higher than in Plot 1 during the earlier part of the experiment and lower during the later part. Just what interpretation can be placed on these reMilts i - not entirely clear, as the evidence presented here is only for one year. It is evident in these experiments as in all the other- re ported in this paper that the amount of infection secured by arti - ficial inoculations with pure cultures is so small that it is difficult to make a definite and clear-cut interpretation of the result-. Xo effect was observed on the germinating power of the -4-v.l due t&lt;&gt; inoculation. RELATION OF ENVIRONMENT TO THE DISEASE Fn*nri&gt;im oatyspormti \&lt; capable of living in the soil sapro - phytically or of overwintering in the seed tuber under a variety of conditions. It is only capable of producing severe effects on its host plant when conditions arc very favorable for the infec - tion and progress of the disease. These conditions made up of the complex relation* of many factors may determine not only whether infection will take place, but also the method of infec - tion. Conditions favorable for infection often retard the further progress of the disease, and different combinations of environ - mental factors will cause a marked change in the symptoms. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">I'utut,, Wilt Coaxed by Fusarium Oxy*porum 81 References in the literature on the relation of climatic factors to the. disease, while abounding in incomplete observational data, are rather meagre in exact meteorological records in relation to the various manifestations of the disease. Information regarding soil temperature* and moistures is regrettably lacking. Never - theless many conclusions are set forth as to the effect of different factors upon the disease. Many of these are misleading owing to the incompleteness of the data and to the casual consideration of the disease in tot", rather than to a close comparison of the suc - cessive stages in its development in relation to the environmental factors. Fusarium wilt has always been considered to be a disease favored by warm climates, and some authors have held that a combination of high temperature and drought is particularly favorable for its development. While it is true that the disease i~ not reported as being serious in some of the northern potato producing states, yet considerable infection was found by the writer in the upper ]&gt;eninsula of Michigan in 1914 and 1915. In Nebraska the disease is much more prevalent in the western sec - tion of the Stale with an altitude about 3.500 feet higher and a correspondingly cooler temperature, than in the eastern part of the State Furthermore, we find that such generalizations do not hold when we examine individual fields, experimental plots, or sometimes even potato growing sections of considerable size. Manns (1011) observed that drought apparently hastened the yellowing symptoms of the disease, but he was unable to de - cide its influence upon the activity of the organism. He states ( p. :517) that in the history of the disease at the Ohio station — the severest attack occurred during the most favorable season we have had in a long time, viz., in 1909. The temperature and rainfall that season were very equitable. , He believed (p. 317) that as far as reducing the yields was con - cerned the disease would cans*' — as jrreat a percent in reduction under favorable conditions as under drouth He claimed, however, that the disease would penetrate much deeper into the tubers under conditions of drought. MacMillan (1019) stated (p. 209): Temperatures of the soil are vital as regards infection. The critical temperature for infection has not been determined and it varies for the manner of infection. Seed-piece infection will occur at a considerable lower temperature than root infection. Bifbv ( 1020). ol)serving the prevalence of "foot-rot "' in rela- </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Xfbiiixk-H Aiiiiciiltunil k'.i/i. Station. Iteneurrh Bui. tion to climatic- factors, finds that "foot-rot" develops only when abundant moisture is present, even tho the temperature inav U considerably lielow normal, and that it occurs only late in the -(■miii. irrespective of whether the conditions have la-en favorable from planting time on. tllaskell ( 1919) finds that soil temperature is the chief factor influencing the disease, and states (p. -J.Ys ) that — 1 disease is most severe in places where high summer temperatures wail at the time when tuber formation is in progress * • • Within tchess County there is a distinct correlation between the amount of ease and factors influencing soil temperature such as altitude, exposure fields and shading of plants. He had difficulty in obtaining infection with artificial inocula tion&gt; unless a high x&gt;il tem|M&gt;rature. 'M&gt;- to 40 (".. was used. tKdson and Shapovalov i l!&gt;-jui report an experiment in which 1 tuliers inoculated with Fiixiuiniii oxyitpormn were planted two different dates. The experiment was conducted in the nity of Washington. I&gt;. ('. They conclude that — there were more tubers infected with Fuxarium osysporum in the early crop grown at higher temperature, than in the late crop grown at lower temperature. fc\^ pn no detailed information regarding temperature at sture conditions during the experiment. Experiments made by the author and dix-ussed elsewhere in this paper show results very similar to those reported by Manns (li'll). For instance, in working with infected seed tubers, the disease was reproduced abundantly in Michigan in 1015. a season with low temperatures and high precipitations; while in 1916 similar experiments yielded negative results when the tem - peratures were extremely high and precipitations very low. in fact, one of the hottest and driest seasons &lt;&gt;n record for Michi - gan. Inoculation experiments also gave negative results during this season. t Experiments with inoculated seed in Nebraska have shown it the disease i* favored by the environmental conditions found the dry land sections of western Nebraska more than in either 1 irrigated fields having a higher soil moisture or the fields of eastern Nebraska with both higher temperature and moisture during the entire season. In the experiments under control run tions. low soil moisture during the early growth of the ]&gt;lant&gt; s unfavorable for infection. However, high soil moisture fol - ed by drought resulted in an increase in the amount of wilt, ile continued high moisture decreased the percentage of wilt even tho the extent of rotting of the stem and roots was increased. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Potato Wilt I'miMfd by Fimarimn Osyxponnit tt In the temperature experiments, plants infecteil at high tem - peratures and changed to lower temperatures recovered and showed no wilt symptoms even tho the organism was present in the hosl tissue. Plant &gt; started at low temperatures and later changed to higher temperatures showed as much disease as fhose grown nt a maintained high temperature. Soil moisture may act in a variety of ways, determining the distribution of the organism thru the soil, and by its effect on the hosl plant determining the entrance of the organism. Later changes in moisture not only would have a profound effect upon the type of injury, i. e.. rotting of the stem or roots, but would : 1 1 — &lt;• an eel the symptoms of the disease by bringing about condi - tion enabling the host plant either to counteract the detrimental effects of the organism or to accelerate the action of the parasite and weaken the host. Temperature would affect not only the growth of the organ - ism but also the growth of the host and determine the ability of the organism to enter the host. The conditions favorable for this infection may not l&gt;e favorable for the further progress of the disease within the host plant and the susceptibility of the host in -iiiciinili to the attack of the parasite. Because of these complex reactions we often find conditions during a greater part of the season that would be, favorable for the progress of the disease, but unless the conditions had been favorable for the inital infection, these later environmental con - dition- would have no effect. Conditions of drought, while favoring the later stages of the disease, are apparently not favor - able for infection. Drought combined with high temperatures may cause a browning of the vascular system in the absence of the parasite, a condition often mistaken for Fusarium wilt. Thus it i- dear that observational data on environmental conditions to I*' of value must take into consideration all condi - tion- influencing the disease from the time of planting until maturity. It is only by the accumulation of data from all potato growing sections, combined with a careful examination of the plants as regard* the method of infection and resulting symptoms, that we can come to a clear understanding of the action of this &lt;li-&lt;&gt;a-*. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Xehntxkn A&lt;/ri&lt; ultnml Exp. Station. litx,,ir&lt;h Finl. .'.; LITERATURE CITED Bisby. G. R. 1919. STUDIES ON FUSARIUM DISEASES OF POTATOES AND TRUCK CROPS OF MINNESOTA. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bu! 181, 44 pp., 30 figs. Edaon. H. A. 1920. VASCULAR DISCOLORATION OF IRISH POTATO TUBERS In Jour. Agr. Research, v. 20, no. 4, pp. 277-294. Edaon. H. A., and Shapovalov, M 1920 TEMPERATURE RELATIONS OF CERTAIN POTATO ROT AND WILT-PRODUCING FUNGI. In Jour. Agr. Research, v. 18, no. 10, pp. 511-524. Haskell. Royal J. 1919. FUSARIUM WILT OF POTATO IN THE HUDSON RIVER VALLEY, NEW YORK. In Phytopathology, v. 9, no. 6, pp. 223-260, pig. 13-15. Jones. L. R. 1917. SOIL TEMPERATURES AS A FACTOR IN PHYTOPATHOL - OGY. In The Plant World, v. 20, no. 8, pp. 229-237. Link. Geo. K. K. 1916. A PHYSIOLOGICAL STUDY OF TWO STRAINS OF FUSAK - rUM IN THEIR CAUSAL RELATION TO TUBER ROT AND WILT OF POTATO. In Bot. Gaz.. v. 62. no. 3, pp. 169-209. Reprinted as Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bui. 9, 1916. McKay. M. B 1921. TRANSMISSION OF SOME WILT DISEASES IN SEED PO TATOES. In Jour. Agr. Research, v. 21, no. 11. pp. 821-848 pis. 138-141. MacMillan. H. G 1919. FUSARir.M-BI.KiHT OF POTATOES UNDER IRRIGATION In. Jour. Agr. Research, v. 16, no. 11, pp. 279-303, pla. 37-41. Him Thomas F 1911. THE FUSARIUM BLIGHT (WILT) AND DRY ROT OF THE POTATO. Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 229, p. 299-336. Plant Disease Survey, U. S. Dept Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. 1919. The Plant Disease Bulletin. Supplement no. H, pi ( mimeographed ) . 192*. The Plant Disease Bulletin. Supplement no. 12. pp. 319-32C (mimeographed ). 1921. The Plant Disease Bulletin, Supplement no. 18, pp. 330-331 ( mimeographed ) . Pratt, O. A. 1916. EXPERIMENTS WITH CLEAN SEED POTATOES ON NEW LAND IN SOUTHERN IDAHO. In Jour. Agr. Research, v. 6, no. 15, pp. 573-575. Sherbakoff, C. D. 1915. FUSARIA OF POTATOES. N. Y. Cornell Agr Exp. Sta. Mem 6, pp. 87-270, 7 pis. (col). Smith, Erwin F., and Swingle. Dean B 1904. THE DRY ROT OF POTATOES DUE TO FUSARIUM OXY - SPORUM. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. Bui. 55, 64 pp., 8 pis. Werkenthin, Frederick C. 1916. FUNGOUS FLORA OF TEXAS SOILS. In Phytopathology, v. 6, no. 3, pp. 241-253. SMI </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>