<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIFTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT AND BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB FOR THE YEARS 1905 AND 1906 TO THE GOVERNOR HON. JOHN H. MICKEY</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FIFTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT AND BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE EBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB FOR'.THE YEARS 1905 AND 1906 TO THE GOVERNOR HONSJOHN H. MICKEY </seg>
            <seg id="p002">i ITl/TE FOR THE DEAF AND D! OMAHA. XEB., DECEMBER 1", in II. Mick ernor: R-. 12, chap. 22, of the I T the Nebraska Institute i dumb have the honor to transmit herewith the miiiil report of this institution, embracing tin - nd work lished durinir the period ending Decem- Eully, J. (&gt;. Detweiler, John W, Steinhart, ! M III. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">BOAKI) OF TRUSTEES. tweiler, President Omaha. Nebraska John W. Steinhart. Secretary Nebraska City, N'ebr I Windham Plattsmouth, Nebr OFFICERS. l;. E Stewart, M. A. Superintendent and - ' Johnson TEACH I R. I it, M. A., Principal J \V. Sowell, M. A. Manual De] - H. Eldridge .Manual De] Harley I). Drake, 1'.. A. Manual Depart) np Manual Departi .Manual Depart! Ma &lt;i. Ilcinlir - .Marion Finch Manual Dep - Marion Finch .Manual Dep Emma Anderson Manual Dej Harriet E. Yoe Manual Depart! Alberta A. Regnier. head teacher primary. Oral Depart] Emma Anderson Manual Dep Harriet E. Yoe Manual Depart! Alberta A. Regnier. head teacher primary. Oral De] Miss Lillian Bamford Oral Dej Miss Lillian Bamford Oral Dej t Lillian Humphreys, M. A Oral Depart! Anna B. nirkpat rick. M. 8 Oral Depart: Miss Edith R&lt;&gt;ss Oral Depart] Lillian Humphreys, M. A Oral Depart 1 Miss Anna B. rCirkpatrick, M. 8 Oral Dei impbell Oral Depart) Minnie M. Rupley, B A Oral Depart) </seg>
            <seg id="p004">INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT. TS, ETC. .11 Carpentering up Printing ■ I Blankenship Art J P Painting i. Reynolds Horticulture 1a Shoemaking Miss Anna Byrne . Baking Lizzie Scher&lt; r . Sewing Miss Margaret Schwake Ironing John H. Vance, M. D. Physician Miss Agnes Brown Nurse Miss Audrey Holsclaw Tlerk Miss Mary Woodson s ipervisor of Girls Mrs. Ann Richards . Supervisor of Large 1 Miss Jennie Hambe! Supervisor of Small i H. E. Gladwin Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. OMAHA. XEB., DECEMBER 10, 1906. To His Excellency. Governor John EL Mickey: The Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf end Dumb has the honor to submit the following report: CHANGES OF OFFICERS. Jan. 27. 1905, the board lost in the death of Hon. Clinton Orcutt of Omaha, one of its oldest, most energetic, and faithful numbers. Mr. Orcutt had been president of the board since 1902 :md took a deep interest in the op-building of this institution. To till the vacancy thus caused. Mr. .f. (). Detweiler of Omaha was appointed, Feb. 8, 1905, a member of this board. In May. 1005, Mr. J. W. Steinhart of Nebraska City was re - appointed to succeed himself and continues secretary of the board. ■ay, 1906, Mr. K. B. Windhani of Plattsmouth was appoint - takint.' the place of Mr. Charles Nownes whose term pired. May 22, 1906, ..I. O. Detweiler was made president of the board. Pie following table shows status of appropriations made by legislature for the biennium. 1905 and 1906: Approp. Expend. Bal. Salary of superintendent $:{,&lt;»&lt; »0.00 $3,000.00 $60000 Salary of matron l.ti(&gt;0.00 Employes' wafM 11,000 of teachers, etc. 27,000.00 Fuel and li«rhts 7..")(M).(i(l lfmintenai 18,500.00 Furniture and bedding 1,800.00 Supplies for industries 1.200.00 Office expensec, etc. 1,000.00 Telephone -S0.00 Drills and medicine 2~&gt;&lt; 1.00 1,333.34 2.16 20,061.42 fi.UO.'tl 14.624.21 1,61! l,l&lt;)0.92 672.93 160.45 125.23 266.66 1,537.84 6,938.58 1,370.09 3,875.79 187.05 9.08 327.07 89.55 124.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">498 improvement and equipment 100.00 70.49 29.51 300.00 256.62 43.38 of hoe Improvement on farm and improvers Water Hipply 3,500.00 2,947.11 552.89 1,000.00 1,000.00 iX) 126.00 124.00 15(1.00 134.78 15.22 Fir- ric lights INSTITUTION CASH ACCOUNT. in hand from last report $ 704.30 from the sale of fruit, vegetables • ipts from industrial shops 1,289.36 Total $1,993.66 ,nt exp&lt; 1,713.86 $ 279.80 Balance on hand &gt;IATED EXPENDITURES FOR BIENNIAL — FROM APRIL, 1907 TO MARCH 31, 1909. Salary of superintendent $3,600.00 try of matron and housekeeper 1,600.00 Salary of teachers, physician, nurse, supervisors, sten- ipher, and all empl&lt; 4o.(n : light, maintenance, furniture and bedding, drag* and medii id water supply 30,050.00 plies for industries 1,500.00 Incidentals 1,500.00 Office expenses, - stationery, and postage 1,000.00 Repairs and improvements 3,500.00 ;hone 225.00 Improvement on farm 300.00 For Gallaudet students 300.00 SPECIAL APPROPRIATIONS. r include num, library, mu - seim n, and don $35.0i' We fully endorse the above recommendation for appropriat ns made by our superintendent for the rapport of the school dur- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">499 E&gt;e hindered or checked, and invite the inspection of the same iv time by yourself &lt;&gt;r the coming legislature so soon to n believe the management of the school to be in good h;i the work of its superintendent, teaehen and officers to be able ;ind efficient. Bthe judgment of this board that additional ground for ■ and expansion of the school is now needed and as oppor - presents itself and before adjacent land is taken up for this land should be purchased. A request for an appro - n for purchase of land will for above reasons be made. J. O. Detweiler, Jno. W. Steinhart, R. B. Windham, Board of Trustees. SUPERINTENDENT'S KEPORT. To the Honorable Board of Trus Gentlemen 1 respectfully submit to you the fifteenth biennial it of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, cov - t-rini.' the period from December 5th. 1904 to December 10th, (During this biennial we have enrolled 242 pupils. Of these 2 were boys and 110 were girls. Forty-five new pupils have en admitted since our last report. Present enrollment is 191. This institution was founded in 1869 and since that time pupils have attended the school. Of this number 68 per - have been awarded diplomas of graduation. Twenty-seven Is have Lrraduated since \'H\2, and six of these are now at t 1 .iillandet College, Washington, I) C. This is the on] in the world where the deaf can get a higher education. It is supported by the national government as our institution is sup - 1 by the State. t Pupils from the state institutions, who pass a satisfactory amination. are admitted to Gallaudet College, but each pupil ust pay for his clothing, transportation, and incidental ex - penses while there. This amounts to about $75.00 a year. Some pupils who graduate here have bright minds and could pass the college examinations but they cannot afford the expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LAND COMMISS1 500 I would recommend that our state legislature appropriate $300.00 biennially as a fund to encourage worthy deaf pupils btain a higher education and afford an allowance toward their support while in college. This is done by other states. LIST OF GRADUATES. Ella M. Rudd LSI tided Gallaudet college two years : taught in her alma mater, married L. A. Divine in 1897; died in 1898. Louis A. Divine _ 1889 Graduated from Gallaudet college in taught in the Montana and Nebraska Schools for the Deaf in the Tw &lt;hool at Knoxville. Married Belle Stout of Philadelphia. Penn. Etta Stewart . 1889 Married James Cain, an ex-pupil of the Nebraska School, who is said to be prosperous cotton grower and night nd citizen of Osceola. Oklahoma. Butterick Taught several years in her alma ma- \t. Coulter, an ex-pupil of the Missouri School — a suci •■ ranchman in Redington. Nebraska. Ella Cornish . 1891 Was hoys' supervisor for several years in the Colorado School. Married Al- vis L. Hurt, an ex-pupil of the Kan- sas and Colorado Schools, now en- gaged in the cattle business 111 nal, Utah. Ida Kerr 1891 Married Arthur Boatright, who is an industrious, frugal farmer in Osce- ola, Nebraska. Alfred Waugh 1891 Living somewhere in Chicago, 111.; do- ing well at his trade. Married an ex- pupil of the Illinois School. Edward Higgins 1891 Is in California making a name for himself as an artist; unmarried. Ota B. Crawford 1891 Attended Gallaudet College two years; for several years a teacher in her al- ma mater. Married Lloyd Blanken- ship. her in the Nebraska School. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 501 Name. Class. Ella Ream 1891 Married Abraham Gardner, a graduate of the New York City School for the Deaf, who is one of the successful. hard-working farmers of Arapahoe, Nebraska. Henry Porter 1893 For several years assistant boys' super- visor at the Nebraska School. Now at his home in St. James, Nebraska, doing carpenter work. Unmarried. LeRoy Johnson 1893 A tonsorial artist in College View, Ne- braska. Married Amelia Miller, former pupil of the Nebraska School. Asa Beahm 1893 In Montana in the cattle business — sup- i to be doing well. James Boggs 1^93 Photographer in California. Charles Kluge 1893 A successful farmer in Saltillo, braska. Married Emma Luhn, an ex- pupil of Nebraska School. Parli 1893 A well-to.do farmer living in Pawnee City, Nebraska. After his graduation he attended Kendall Green School, a preparatory school, but did not ter college. Fred Beck 1891 Self-sustaining; married Belle Fitch, an ex-pupil of the N'eBraska School. Harry Mercer 1893 Married a hearing lady; is a master of the printing trade. ;a Forbes tided Gallaudet College. Taught for one year at her alma mater. Married Clyde Jones, an ex-pupil of the day school for deaf at St. Louis, who is an employe in the East St. Louis, 111., postofflce. Mary Donnelly 1895 Attended Gallaudet College. Is now in Colorado Springs, Colorado, working a3 seamstress. John Flood . 1895 A government employe in Washington, D. C. Married an ex-pupil of the Missouri School. Cora Rexford 1896 Soon after graduation married B. P. Round, a graduate of the Wisconsin School and of Gallaudet College, who ably edits a newspaper for the hear- ing. Nettie Burrows 1896 Living at Ord, Nebraska, with her par- ents—busy with her art work. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">502 LAND COMMISSIONKirS KKI Class. Lloyd Blankenship 1897 Art instructor in hia alma mater. Mar- ried Ota Crawford, a graduate of the Nebraska School. Wayne Thierman 1897 Master carpenter in a door, window. sash factory in Portland, Oregon. Married Margaret Turner, a gradu- ate of the Colorado School. C P Jen.-' l 1897 For several years an employe in the Grand Island, Nebraska, Creamery How farming for his widowed mother. John Zadina 1897 An employe in a packing house in So. Omaha. Married Jennie Prentice, an ex-pupil of the Nebraska School. Martin Kennealley .... 1897 Farming in Crookston, Nebraska. Lit- known of him since his gradu- ation. William Kiper . 1897 Is MM to make a successful living from poultry in Portland, Oregon. Married Daisy Joy, an ex-pupil of tho Oregon School_ Jane Lockhart 1897 Marriied John Bauman of Concord, Ne- braska, a prosperous deaf farmer, who invented a hay stacker. Marion Hall 1897 In Pfttsbarf, Pennsylvania, in the ca- pacity of housek&lt;- Bertha Baumai. 1897 Married an ex-pupil of the Wisconsin School, an employe in a packing house in So. Omaha. John O'Brien 1898 Works in a box factory in Nebraska City. Nebraska. August Koberstein __ 1898 Said to be in Alaska digging for gold. Married Maud Jenkins of the same class Patrick Regan 1898 A successful farmer in Platte Center, Nebraska. Emma Morse 1898 Graduated from Gallaudet College in received the degree B. A. Married Perry Seely, a graduate of the Nebraska School. Effie Goslin 1899 Graduated from Gallaudet College in 1904, receiving a B. A. Now at home at Havelock, Nebraska, keeping house for her father. Married John Zadina of the class of 1897. Died 1906. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">INSTTTTTK FOR THK DF.AF AND Dl 503 \ii nit'. Kathrine Peterson 1900 Employe in her alma mater upon grad. uation. Married Bert Ellis of Okla- homa, an ex-pupil of the Iowa School. Mary Smrha 1902 A junior at Gallaudet College. Her par- ents reside at Milligan, Nebraska. Maude Marshall 1902 Of Lincoln, Nebraska. Makes money from her art work. Resides with her mother. Clara Truhlar 1902 Married a hearing man. Little ia heard of her since her graduation. Hester Willman 19":; Attended Gallaudet College two years. Now at home in Nebraska City with her parents, keeptr.g up her art studies. Dean W. Smock 19" 2 An employe in the l\ P. Ry. shops in Omaha Eud Zweifel ... ttie Bell Ren •ry Seely 190 2 Married Dean W. Smock 1903 A junior in Gallaudet College. Attended Gallaudet College two years. married Emma Morse of the cUss Ol' ! Frances Davis 3 Married an ex-pupil of the Texas School. John Opfer I employe at his alma mater a year. Now farming in Kansas. diehard Bingham 1904 Works for Contractor Harte, Omaha, and is giving satisfaction. I!to4 A swift and sure hand at carpentry. Harold Lee Resides in Council Bluffs, Iowa. Iraac Wittwer 1904 A graduate from the college of barbers. Now engaged in the tonsorial artist's line, Council Bluffs, Iowa. Bert Pilsbry \ssistant boys' supervisor in his alma mater. Maudie Roath 1905 Freshman at Gallaudet College. Home, Lincoln Anna Johnson 1905 Freshman at Gallaudet College. Home, Minden, Nebraska. Earl Haller 1905 Grand Island — farming with his father. 1905 At her home in Friend, Nebraska, do- I -a ura Peterson ing housework for her mother. She takes pleasure in fancy work and painting. Harry Myers 1905 A rising young farmer of ability. 1905 Wayne, Nebraska. Junior at Gallaudet 1905 Keeps house for her father, Syracuse, Helen Northrop _ Margaret Stillahn Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">504 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Nan Eth Marshall 1906 With Miss Bamford, Omaha, ra Jensen 1906 Assistant girls' supervisor at alma mater Charles Macek 1906 Assistant boys' supervisor at his alma mater Eph MorehouM . . 1906 Student at Oallaudet College. &gt;er Stichker _ 1906 Printer in Lincoln, Nebraska, olph Schupbach .. 1906 Works in his father's lumber yard at Columbus, Nebraska The several counties of the state have sent pupils to this school u follows Adams 14 Furnas 11 lop« . I &lt;;;il'.- 11 Banner 1 Qosper 4 e 16 Qreeley Buffalo U Hall 14 Burt 12 Hamilton 7 Butler 12 Barlaa I 2 1 1 ayes | 2 Hitchcock . 4 ■.„ 1 Holt Cam 16 Howard iar 13 Jefferson ■* . 1 Johnson r-rv 2 Kearney 10 enne 11 Knox ("lay 8 Lancaster 40 12 Lincoln. | Coming 0 Ma&lt;lison . 6 Merriek 11 MePheraon :\ Xiinc.. ; 7 Xcin.iha IT) 1 Xnckolls 5 11 12 &lt;&gt;toe 19 E13 Ptwnet . 6 trlas 125 Perkins 1 2 | 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND D' 505 Polk 11 Sherman Willow 3 Stanton Richardson 20 Thurston Hock 1 Thay.-r 10 Saline 21 Valley Sarpy S Washington Brandon 18 Wayne Seward - 8 Webster 7 Sheridan . 5 York Total From other states 7 (irand total 732 The causes of deafness, as reported by parents, are shown in the following table: LIST OF CAUSES. Apoplexy 1 La Grippe 17 Brnin fever 43 Long fever Bronchitis 2 Malaria Catarrh 12 Measles Cholera infantmn 4 Mumps Cold 13 Paralysis genital 1"1 Pneumonia Cramps 1 Quinsy creation of lungrs 1 Scarlet fever . 62 Diphtheria 9 Scrofula Dropsy of brain 1 Spasms I Diabetes . 1 Spinal meninpritis - 80 .•he 12 Spotted fever Fall (in infancy !) Sunstroke 1 Fever (kind unknown) 16 Typhoid fever Fits 4. Tubercular affliction Head hurt (in cyclone) 1 Whooping cough .. 19 Inflammation of brain 2 Yellow fever Intermittent fever 1 Unknown Inflammation of ear 1"&gt; Total Mutes 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">506 LAND COMMISSIONER'S KKPOUT HEALTH. The general health n fairly good. We had a number of cases of scarlatina during the term of 1905-1906. Two cases had diphtheritic complications and were very severe. One child was taken home by her mother and has since recovered. The other was nursed through her sickness at the institution, regaining l&gt;erfect health. There have been many and varied ailments com - among children, bat none dangerous or incurable. En six years of our management, not one death has taken place our institution. Xo serious accidents have happened, and not &gt;upil has been maimed or crippled in all these years. (Vs the school •_ r ro\' leniatif phys - 1 training iiinasium should be provided and mod&lt; equipped to furnish regular, &gt; tie drill and amusement en outdoor sports cannot be indulged. This could be arranged a new building and is much needed. LITERARY DEPARTMENT. Ehe literary department progresses in a very satisfactory con - on. We use the ■"combined" system with a manual and department. 11 our policy heretofore, all children capable of re - og instruction by speech are taught to talk and read lips. • are tauyrht by use of written language, finger spelling and lanual alphabet. ne are taught "signs". They are taught the "English Lant: and how to use it. After they have learned the it will not injure any deaf person to know how iga. re have nine grades which require a child eleven years to meeting of the America: ition to Promote the Teach - h to the Deaf was held in August last at Edgewood, Pa. At this meeting, the importance of oral instruction and speech for pupils in schools of this kind was fully demonstrated^ The use of electrical devises for aids to partially deaf people and bearing was discussed. While no great amount of proof was given as to the real worth of these instruments, nevertheless I recommend that this school install a set of elec - 1 aural developers in &lt;&gt;&gt; Irooni to test their value as who an ;if. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">INSTITl'TK FOK THE DKAF AND D&lt; 507 There are children in attendance too deaf to catch the tones of the human voice in ordinary conversation who might hear t by means of an ear tube or other mechanism. Much aimed by agents of certain electrical inventions now used by semi-deaf and hard of hearing people, for restoring defective i ng- and overcoming its inconvenience. While the introduc - tion of these into our school would be largely an experiment, I recommend the trial. Kof four where four pupils at the same time can listen instruction from one teacher — may be installed for about THE LIBRARY. To the deaf do adjunct to our institution is of greater value imparting information than books suited to capacity and of learners. Our library is not well enough stocked with suitable literature and is so hampered by insufficient quarters that much good is lost to our pupils. E recommend that room be provided in a new building with the iinasium for a library, reading room, boys' study room large ngh to a mmodate seventy-five or one hundred boys for Ding study, and a museum hall where specimens ■.: all Id be collected and exhibited. DEAF-BLIND. I There is one deaf-blind child in Nebraska. .Miss Ethel Hill of nth Omaha. She is thirteen years old and should hav&lt; i\ instruction either in this school or the school for blind. I.-itic appropriation should be made by this legislature to ovide education for her. Such children require a S| icher and caretaker who should become a constant eompan - 1. It would require at least $1,500. for the biennion to thus re for her. INDISTR1AL DEPARTMENT t Pupils old enough to be admitted to the industrial shops are itructed in carpentry, printing, shoe-mending, farming ami rticulture, painting, baking, freehand drawing, laundering, diking and fancy needlework. We advise the immediate installation of a cooking school. Ev - ery girl should I table housekeeping, and the art </seg>
            <seg id="p016">508 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT of preparing and serving a good, plain, substantial meal. A room ehould be provided and furnished for this purpose and a domestic ice teacher employed to conduct the work. SALARIES Et has been customary with us for years to employ teachers ler a gradually increasing scale of wages. Experience counts much in teaching and caring for the deaf; Even the most 1 1 teachers in public school work are helpless among the f. It rt'&lt; j i ral years mingling with the deaf and work - with them to make of them real successful teachers. There - '. it dues not pay the State to train new teachers annually. chers of ability and experience ar e sought by institutions of : kind all over the continent. I We have gathered a very excellent OOrps of instructors into ? Nebraska institution but in order to keep them we must pay in proportion to other states. I ask for $2,000 more in propriation lor salaries of teachers than we had two years lering the number of pupils in school and the num - r of industries taught our scale of wages is low. Watris of employes all over the country have increased nia - lly in recent years. We must pay more for nearly every class of labor than we did three or four years aim. We need a lar night watchman to truard the buildings and prei [leers demand more wages than we have been able to pay. In the office, expenses have been light and in the last five years I have personally saved the state at least $5,000 by assuming ward, a position which formerly carried a salary &lt;&gt;&lt;) h year. MAINTENANCE. Our appropriations for fuel and liyht may be deficient by five hundred dollars for the biennium. There will tie a deficiency in fund of perhaps one thousand dollars. This M an item of fifteen hundred dollars — "Incidental Fund" — was cut out of our list of appropriations two years airo. This was done by error or oversight in copying as the legislative com - mittee had approved Ike amount. All expenditure* are made in the interest of the State with and economy and supplies are utilized without wastefulness </seg>
            <seg id="p017">INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DIM! 5 509 REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. Our buildings are in very good condition. Excellent impr merit has been made in the basement of the small boys' wing: cement floors in halls, trunk rooms and toilet: new bath rooms and wash rooms with tile floors and tile wainscot and metal ceilings. The hospital building is undergoing repair at this time and when finished will he a neat, convenient, substantial building. It will contain wards for ordinary sickness and wards entirely ■- for contagious diseases. It will provide apartments for a\ and have tile lined bath and toilet rooms on two floors. The floor will be finished with metal eeiling and new hard pine floors. All plumbing has been put in new, and new joists, and brick piers in basement. tnew roof was put on the barn, atul all floors and int&lt; h throughout the institution has been kept in good form. I fire escape was placed on the north side of the main build - so that now no dormitory is without adequate prota hat kind. fnew ■"Steam Heater"' system was placed in the boiler r pumps and machinery kept in repair. NEEDS. E'e need above all more room. As has been suggested, a ° ew ding should be erected furnishing a gymnasium, library, euni. study room and dormitory. Ie need more land. Our boys have not a good ball ground. ground is as necessary for growing child 'en as food. There tracts of land joining the institution which may be bought, city is fast absorbing these tracts for building purposes and it will be impossible to buy advantageously. fe have '25 acres rented. This provides us with grain and ender for all stock. The State has not been called 01 feed for this institution since 1901. We need new steps and approaches to our present buildings. These should be iron. The large boys" cottage needs overhauling and its steam-heating system re-arranged. Some cement pave - ment ought to be put about the buildings. There should be a large cistern constructed for receiving rainwater for laundry The laundry will need a new cylinder washer and the floor in </seg>
            <seg id="p018">510 LAND COM M It'S UKI'OKT Fit department Mi V tile floor is needed in the and ilish wash room. Some new roof may be necea old build an ice house. MANNERS AND MORALS. Eime is good. 1'upils are taught to respect hority and a re encouraged by wholesome advice from teachers like in right ways of living and nobility of character. I rally our pupil* respond willingly so that by kindness (1 fir; leldom need for punishment. We insist at pupils remain in the institution continuously through the h-&gt;ol term as home goers disturb the discipline and order of hoolroom work and endanger the whole institution to conta- CHANGE IN NAME E'lnmend that the name of this' institution be from ••Institute for the Deaf and Dumb" to 'N'ebraska ool for the I Mates have mad.' 1 his chang ii'. and we approve the new title. In submitting this report I thank you all for that encoir which yon have given to our work. I wish to specially our governor, Hon. John II Mickey, who has ",d for the principles of honesty and good by which this institution has prospered. To all teachers. id helpers, I extend thanks for faithfulness and ! in duty. I thank the parents and friends who have given me •ir moral support in enforcing good rules; and acknowledge iiitiide the kind Providence that lias led us and guarded ty and welfare of our school. E rusting that this legislature may appropriate liberally for •nding and carrying on the good work, I respectfully submit report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb for years 1905 and 1906. STEWART, Superintendent. RULES AND INFORMATION. 1. The institution is open to all the deaf of the state free of charge, provided they are of suitable age and mental capacity, , _ j •••p tf\f\ &lt;lpfl f tn lip pHnpstpH in +Tip pATnTnnn Qplinnl c </seg>
            <seg id="p019">[NSTITUTE FoK THK I.»l 511 _' Pupils will Ik- considered eligible between the ii and twenty-one. Children should by all means be brought chool soon after they arv seven years old. Applications for the admission of pupils mm ide upon liar blanks, which will be furnished by the superintendent. 4. Pupils are admitted &lt;&gt;"■ the following conditions: They must be rovided with clothing and trans- portation. (b) They must rem . i in school through the full term an till June each ; reai v — the annual session being a con - tinuous one without a vacation. So parent or guardian will be allowed to take a pu - pil out of school during tl □ without some urgent reason. When a parent or guardian is unable to furnish clothing Mid incidentals for any child, the superintendent may provide that which is needed, according to Section 15, Chapter 26, ' tral Laws of Nebraska, 1897. The superintendent shall have the power at any time to &lt;liseharge a pupil from the institution for inability to re&lt; an education, for lack of progress or non-attendanee, for viola - tion of the rules of the institution, or where his retention w e a detriment to others or the school. And such action shall be reported at the next meeting of the board of trustees lor their consideration. K Visitors to the institution can not be entertained for meals lodging. All business letters. (l r letters of inquiry in regard to pi (concerning their progress in school, health, financial matters, for purchase of supplies, instructions, etc .) must be addressed he superintendent. He will at all times take pleasure in giving information about the institution and invites correspon - dence from parents of deaf children not attending school or un - der school age. </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">Appropriations, l!Mtr&gt;-»; 11 Appropriation, estimated. 1 !•" H in Asylum for the fneurab I i Boards and dates of Board of Public Lands vV Smldi ' COUnty contest 15 (''■in a interest ai ■ mentc on intere I Comparison of inter. :il collected yearly &lt; oncl union 46 rtmeni of surveying national lands mated expenditures next biennium relative to deerea* -i on sale contracts 12 collected 12 Field work, surveyor Figured biennium 1897-98 to 1905-06 (Seneral comments on lease contracts (ieneral commenta on sal« &lt;iirl," Industrial School. Geneva Home for the Friendless, Lincoln Interest and rental \'&lt; Inieresi on sale contracts decreasing rapidly -1 Itemized work of the biennium Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, Omaha institute for the Blind, Nebraska City '.ands sold, appraised at 12, 1t&gt;. I s . ■". ■i- of Transmittal : Lewis A Clarke Kx posit ion ition oi institution and superintendent in charge Louisiana Purchase Exposition S'ehraska Ilospitnl (or tin 1 [n««ne, Lincoln Nebraska Institute for Heebie Minded Youth. B Nebraska State Hospital for Crippled Children, Lincoln 41'. Nebraska Industrial Home. Milfonl </seg>
            <seg id="p022">&lt;&gt;lk II"S|&gt;it;il for In L'l 1 r. land office r, state 7 itetitiary land, funds received ;md expended 1 t •hool fund, how secure I isfiiient lauds held under iJLse contrail 14 d and interest ;' lit al on lease contracts ii: 14 iniiiendatiiiii as commissioner 13 ion an |iresident of t'ue Hoard of I'. L t l'&gt;. l»itol. dai lins.' • [M'nitentiary 47 in N'ebnuika and Sailors" Home, Grand Island iers' and Sailors" Home. Milford 4.~&gt;1 Industrial School. Kearney penditarea 11 I colled - 24 i rentals collected on lease contracts L' 1 i\ collected on sale contracts Table securities permaaeni school fund -■'. Temporary school fund l':'. Table, state educational land 24-2H Table, work of the biennium </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>