<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Eighth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1915-02-01">1915-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA 1'WENTY-EKIHTH ANNUAL REPORT rut Agricultural Experiment Station &lt;&gt;K NEBRASKA Febri ai:y 1. 1915 LINCOLN. NEBRASKA 17. S. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">// s ii 88*. mill t pro vt i lllh &gt;\ Xefoi s !!■! ual Ut-pori of Mr. //. I. Hit Slut ion LKTTKR &lt;&gt;F TRAXSMITTAL The University of Nebraska &lt;■/). John II. itorchead, Governor of Xrbntxku: rdanee with the aet of Congress approved March • act of tlic genera] assembly of the State of Xe - 1 March 31, 1887, establishing and regelating ex his. 1 have the honor herewith to submit the Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment raska. E. A. Burnett Director. (iOVKKNOK'H CKRTIFK'ATK vtt, Director Xebraaka Agricultural B&amp;periment liv acknowledge receipt of the Twenty-eighth An the Agricultural Kxjierimeni Station of Nebraska John H. Mokeiieai), Outer nor Auuiri j.ti it-u. Experiment Station ,vtk ok Nebraska, Executive Dki-aktmext, Lincoln, February 1, 1!)1~&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD. THE RCGCNTS OF THC UNIVERSITY HON. WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Pres., Valley .. Term expires Jan., 1917 HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln Term expires Nov., 1916 HON. FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha Term expires Jan., 1919 HON. VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City Term expires Jan.. 1919 HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey Term expires Jan., 1921 HON. JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln Term expires Jan.. 1921 SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary/* THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE. WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. SAMUEL AVERY. E. A. BURNETT THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director; Animal Husbandry C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc, Director of Extension s&lt; m W. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. Upso.n, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemittry L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. tR. K. Buss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gai.n, M. D. C, Animal Pathology J. H. FRAND8EN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandi Lawrence Bkinkr. B. Sc, Entomology T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agrun H. C. Fiixey, A. M., Farm Management W. J. Mokkii.i,, M. For., Forestry. tR. A. Embbso.n, D. Sc'., Horticultnn R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology W. P. Snyder, M. S., Supt. of Experimental Substation. North Plat C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry Howard j. Ghamlich, B. Sc, Associate in Animal Husbandri, M. H. Swexk, A. M., Associate in Entomology George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botan J. W. Calvix, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy I Soils/. Erwix Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crop*) J. A. Ratcuff, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy L. B. Sturdevaxt, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pmthology E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry W. M. Osborx, B. Sc, Assistant in Crops and Soils. North Platte; A**t Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture. V. s. Dept. o) Agriculture. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. Fraxk C. Deax, A. B., Bulletin Editor. C. A. Helm, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy H. E. Vasev, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany Florence A. McCormick, Ph. D., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. H. A. McComb, B. Sc, Horticulturist Erp'l Substation, North Platte James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz Knorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. H. L. Nyb, Foreman Demonstration Farm, Culbertson. * By »n act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15 1899, the State Treasurer became ex offlcio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and •fterJuly 1, 1899. t Resigned </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTEXT* PAGE Letter ok Trankmittal Hi Governor's Certificate ill The Official Ro.ster ok the Station Iv Director's Review — Experimental work vii Plant diseases vill Silage investigations viil I'russic acid in sorghums and kafirs vili Soil solution lx Corn experiments lx Table showing effect of different degrees of soil fertility on plant growth and water requirements of corn ix Table showing effect of variety and adaptation on water re - quirements of crops. 1914 x Table showing effect of the degree of exposure of the pc - tometer upon the growth and the water requirements of corn. 1914 xi Table showing effect of size of potometer upon the growth and water requirements of corn in unmanured and ma - nured soils. 1914 xi Improvement of varieties of grain by selection xli Table showing average yield of digestible nutrients of corn, wheat, oats, and soy beans at the Nebraska Experiment Station during the six years. 1909-1914 xiii Table showing average yield of nine varieties of soy beans tested at Nebraska Experiment Station. 1903-1904 xiv Table showing the effect of distance between rows and of rate of planting soy beans xiv Table showing summary of hay yields in 1912 and 1914 xv Table showing summary of variety tests of soy beans for six years. 1909-1914 xv Table showing summary of comparative yields of corn, wheat, oats, and soy beans at Nebraska Experiment Station for last six years. 1909-1914 xv Beef production xvi Feeding wheat to hogs xvi Lamb feeding experiments xvl Experiments in milk production xril Hog cholera serum production xvii Experiments at the North Platte Substation xvli The Valentine Substation xviii The Scottsbluff Substation xix The Culbertson Demonstration Farm xx The Station Staff xx Improvements xxl Improvements at the central plant xxi Publications xxi Annial Report Aiiriciltiral Extension Service xxiii Acknowledgments xxxii Financial Statement xxxiii </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">TWENTY-EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT EXPERIMENTAL WORK The work of the Nebraska Agricultural Exj&gt;eriiiient Station for tlic current year has been as follows: The funds for the Station are secured from three source, namely: The Adams and the Hatch appropriations are received from the Federal Government in amounts shown l»y the financial statement of this report. The Kxperiment Station also uses cer - tain other funds appropriated from general University mainte - nance and set aside by the Kegeuts at their annual meeting for the maintenance of departments in the College of Agriculture and the Experiment Station. Direct appropriations are also made by the Legislature for certain specific purposes, such as hog cholera investigation and the work of the Slate Entomologist and State Botanist, who are respectively Entomologist and Botanist of the Kxperiment Station. These appropriations are under con - trol of the Kegents of the University and are expended for the purposes authorized by the Legislature. The State makes direct appropriations also for the mainte - nance of Substations at North l'latte, Valentine, Mitchell, and Culbertson, Nebraska. An appropriation is also made for Agri - cultural Extension work of the Experiment Station and the Col - lege of Agriculture. The farm of the Nebraska School of Agricul - ture at Curtis is available for demonstration pin-poses. Under the law, the Adams funds must be expended strictly for original research and cannot be used for general administration, for printing, or for farm demonstrations. The Hatch appropria - tion may be and for general administration purj&gt;oses and for investigation. It is no longer used to print bullet ins of a popular or demonstration character. State funds which come thru ap - propriation by the Kegents to departments in the College of Agri - culture doing experimental work are available for purposes of investigation or demonstration, but these funds must largely be used in carrying on routine work of instruction within the de - partments. The larger demands u|k»ii the departments caused by </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska the growth of the Agricultural College leaves less and less money from State appropriations available for experimental purposes. I'hms of work are prepared by each department at the begin - ning of the calendar year, covering the lines of investigation proposed for the current year. Plans are made for the utiliza - tion of all the funds available to the* department, so that the work of the Station may progress in a systematic and orderly manner to accomplish the largest results, and practically no funds remain unappropriated for the pursuance of new lines of work. Hucli lines of work can only be undertaken when the projects now under investigation have been completed. Most lines of work continue for a series of years before their final completion. Problems requiring original research are always pressing for investigation, but funds for taking up new lines of work have been so limited that very few new projects have been undertaken in the last six years. Plant Diseases. — The leading lines of investigation during the year have had to do with certain potato diseases and with the Illinois apple canker. The selection experiments carried on in the North Platte Valley MM Mitchell. \'eln\. have clearly demonstrated the ]&gt;ossi bility of securing a strain of potatoes with a high degree of resist ance or possibly one which is immune to the leaf roll disease. Apple Canker. The study of apple canker in various orchards in the State has been continued. Investigations have shown that where the canker is removed with the knife and the surface thoroly painted with aspha!tum. trees may continue to grow and largely overcome the damage wrought by the disease. Where canker is not treated, it very soon kills the tree. Silage In\ estimations. — The Station is carrying on investiga - tions with silage made from alfalfa mixed with other green crops. Indications are that excellent silage can lie made with mixtures of alfalfa and sweet sorghum. Such mixtures containing one - half alfalfa and one-half sorghum cane, put up on a small scale, give perfect silage three mouths after siloing. The acidity is some - what lower than normal silage hut this does not seem to impair the keeping qualities. Further investigations of this subject are in progress, but the present results would indicate that a farmer might safely put equal parts of alfalfa and well -matured sorghum cane in his silo with exj&gt;ectatio!i of securing a good quality of silage. PRU88IC Acid in Sorghums and Kafirs. — A stndv of the condi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Twenty-eighth Annual Report 9 lions u tnlcr which prussic acid in produced in sorghums and katii-s has been continued. A large number of varieties have lieen planted, with the hope of securing varieties of sorghum whicli do not develop prussic acid. The investigation of this subject is incomplete. Son. Soi.itiox. — A study of the water soluble plant food in soils of the loess region is continued. It has been shown that the amount of plant food soluble in water is greatest in soils that are most fertile as shown by their crop history. It has also l»eeii showu that the amount of plant food recoverable in the water solution can Ik* increased by the addition of manure or fertilizers lu the soil. Corn Experiments. — Exj&gt;erinieuts with corn have shown con - clusively that inbrteding tends rapidly to dwarfing and steriliza - tion of the plants, altho some seed is produced. Cross-breeding, on the other band, between different strains which have been inbred for a nuiiilu'i- of years restores vigor and vitality, resulting in a normal or increased yield of corn. In the study of the water requirements of crops to determine the relationship of water transpired to plant characters and en - vironmental factors, extensive data have been secured and are be - ing prepared for publication. The following tables summarize a portion of this work: ai:i.k Kffert of differn f/nnrth and im tit degree* of noil fertilit ter requirement* of corn. ty on p&lt; an I Average of tw «&gt; years, 1911 and 19U.) Fertility of soil Dry wt. of ear Total dry wt. of plant ToUl water transpired Water used pergr. dry wt. of ear Water used per gr. dry wt. of plant Infertile soil Infertile soil with manure . . . Intermediate soil Intermediate soil with manure . Fertile sojl Fertile soil with manure Gram* 54 192 121 219 181 246 Gram* 128 370 257 426 345 4t;o Kilogi ami 57.76 119.63 91. 87 130 44 107.51 137.83 drums 1,223 623 861 599 634 563 Qratnx 463 323 383 308 327 299 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 «/'■» •i/ ittiiral E, &lt;peri7nent Station of \ebru* iJta ■ 1 E |*G«:M05Q0Ot^t~.INOINlM»&gt;nO ■ I 5?§ ? - 2 5 12 5 N rt - * «? *im 3C^,^,^,^, : ,^,^,^, 3 1 i ■ri a 1 I ■o 1 : : : : : : : '. :8 : \ ! \ \ liiilijIjiNU; I fc&gt;«| j*j|aiS i • : : •: |lll^ll|p I lii^liiljljti tjifjlilfiljfii </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Tireuty-rifjhth Annual Report 11 T.w.i. k 4. — Hfffct it] size of potometvr upon the BfOWth and wmter ifuirrmenta of eon in ummmmured and manured soils. 1914. (Hogue's Yellow Dent Corn.) r.viti.K :!. — Effect of the degree of exposure the growth and the water requireinei ' of the poti nt» of corn. l omcter upon . 1911,. 1 xpoeure of potometer Dry wt of ear Total dry wt . of plant Total water transpired Water used per gr. dry wt. of ear Water use 1 per gr. dry wt. of plant dlUIIIS (/raws Kilograms (irams Grunt* Potometers fully exposed in pit to atmosphere Potometers buried in soil Potometers in pit surrounded by four-inch water jacket . 287.5 257.7 557.9 .545.4 151.7 152.7 527.8 6003 272.0 279.9 293 0 602.5 162.6 555.0 270.0 Size Weight Manure of of soil added po- (mois- (mois- toin- ture ture eter free) free) E ii 6% Dry wt. of Total dry wt. of plant Total water trans- pired Water used pergr. dry wt . of ear Water used pergr. total dry wt. Heig't of plant ear In Piitimls Pcxmds 12x12 32.5 0 12x12 32 5 175 12x24 85 0 12x24 85 1.75 16x24 150 0 16x24 150 1.75 16x36 239 0 16x:«i 239 1.75 21x36 583 0 21x36 583 1.75 30x36 MM 0 30x36 956 1.75 4 4 4 4 4 4 :&lt; s I I :i 4 dram* 10 sj 113 180 ION 270 242 387 299 :ui 405 416 drams 98 269 206 402 316 525 443 558 628 708 728 781 Kilograms 40.0 86.7 74.6 125.0 107.7 162.7 122.7 151.7 182.3 190.5 175.1 196.4 drains 4.009 1,067 1,180 673 995 603 507 528 610 558 432 472 dram* 412 325 363 •11 Ml 304 277 272 290 269 240 252 n 1(12 100 106 110 112 llti 114 112 114 108 114 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Agricultural Experiment Station of \ebraska Improvement of Varieties ok Grain by Selection. — A largo number of varieties of winter wheat and oats have been grown in nurseries for the purpose of selecting the best individual plants and propagating them to produce a selected strain. The average yields of the best selected strains of winter wheat would indicate that they are somewhat superior to the original Turkey Red from which they were selected. In the selection of oats it is apparent that the early varieties are superior to the late varieties and that the selected strains are somewhat superior to the original strains. Tests have been made to determine the yield of digestible nu trients per acre of corn, wheat, oats, and soy l&gt;eans at the Ne braska Experiment Station. The following table gives a ship inary of the results of six years" work from UKtfl to 1!(14. in elusive : </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Iff/1 ty-eightl \nninil Rep &gt;ort xiii b 5 =2 £J SS "" «5 ■* 1 i "3 • H i i i j II .2 £ C -?.£* "OxsaCNiNoo jg IN — «(N • as a * I I r. a « a B I ■3 — ac — — to SORtfN •s *s II 8 Ex i s = ■ 3 -= =31 &gt;§ "NPOCDt-. C -HodoJcoio a si&gt;.SN3: ©5 e £1 •^j b-; 00 tt -^ = roN oi oi ■* 3 j I I 1 I ! DC _ ■I 2 a. ec •3 . I •s 1 -a i 3 M 3 &gt; II 1&amp; J&amp;Jl • ■♦— c S i — - II 0 &lt;5 x 2 10 w5 00 V 2 J ■it « -S : : : : 8 ... .-3 1:1 Z : if ij i{ l| 3 sl 3Jj£ feg C 3i d &gt; Z- a i _: 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Agricultural Expcrimnit Station of Nebraska Kx|ieriuieiit8 have also Ikhmi made to determine t lie yield ol nine varieties of soy iK'iins; also the effect of different rates of planting, ;is follows: AI'.l.K ». — Average yield &lt;&gt;j nnii Xebranka Exiterimen ■ niricticx of * t Station. liH Olf UVilHX M- 190.',. en 1 1 a Yield of Variety Date planted Date ripe No. days required to mature beans per acre ( bushels ) Early Yellow American Coffee Berry Early Black ItoSan Wisconsin Black Medium Early Yellow Medium Early Brown Medium Early Black Medium Green May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Oct. 4 112 112 112 112 115 115 115 115 124 15 10 12.72 21.88 12 44 30.96 18.86 M M 11.95 15.04 16.17 Average all varieties ABLE I. — . ff PC- I) IX un&lt;r between ing 8(ii/ bea i pmn ami uj ratr of plant nx. 1912 II 13 1914 Average Variety Dist ince r* tween rows 35 in. 28 in. 35 in. 28 in. 35 in 28 in. 35 in. 28 in. Bus. Habaro 12.30 Shingto 13.50 Chernie 14.25 Haberlandt 11.45 Nuttall 10.15 Cloud 7.90 Amherst 10.05 Meyer 11.00 Bus 13.50 12.40 11.25 12.45 8.60 9.45 7.80 8.40 Bus. 7.25 7.58 7.67 5.54 5.98 3.30 2.81 5.70 But. 8.39 8.66 10.23 6.37 6.11 4.00 2.43 4.48 Bus. 15.72 14.42 14.25 21.82 18.42 15.83 17.18 16.15 Bui. 17.85 17.12 18.84 21.15 14.17 12.75 17.61 16.32 11.76 11.83 12.06 12.94 11.52 9.01 10.01 10.95 Bun. 13.25 12.73 13.44 13.32 9.63 8.73 9.2S 9 73 Average all varieties.' 11.33 1048 5.73 6.33 16.72 16.98 I 11.26 11.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Tiniitf/tifihth Annual RejMjrt 15 Tests have Ihhmi made with citwjteaN and soy I&gt;eaii8 to determine their relative yields of hay daring two yean, as follows: Tabu 8. Bmmmmrf of hay yieldn in 1912 and l'Jl'f. Air-dry yield per acre — bushels. Year Crop Yield of cured hay per acre Yield of cured hay per acre 1912 Whippoorwill cowpeas Amherst soy beans 1914 Whippoorwill cowpeas Pound* 2,729 2,856 2,900 Tom 1.37 1.43 1.45 Tahi.e !t. — Kummary of variety tests of soy 1909-191$. beans for six years. Variety 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 6-year average Habaro Shingto Chernie Haberlandt Nuttall Cloud Amherst Meyer But. 8.65 9.37 8.37 11.57 7.12 12.40 14.40 10.32 10.28 Bus. 20.30 20.00 20.10 19.70 24.30 22.30 29.90 26.10 22.84 Bus. 15.26 15.81 14.88 22.71 22.14 18.79 21.96 21.03 19.07 But 12.90 12.95 12.85 11.95 9.39 8.69 8.93 9.70 10.92 Bug. 7.82 8.12 9.38 5.95 6.04 3.85 2.62 5.09 Butt. 16.78 15.78 16.54 21.49 16.29 14.29 17.39 16.24 Bus 13.62 13.67 13.69 15.56 14.21 13.39 15.87 14.75 Average 6.11 16.85 14.35 Table 10. — Summary showing co, oats, and soy beaux at Xebra nix year*. 1909- HU',. mparatire yields of corn, wheat, ska Experiment Station for last field ler acre Average for 6 years Crop 190!) 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 Bug. But. Bug. Bus. Bug. Bug. Bug. Hogue's Yellow Dent corn Turkey Red wheat Kherson oats Average of 8 soy bean varieties Haberlandt soy beans. . . 41 27 67 .-&gt;s 4S 412 43 51 38 48 9 37 s 50 45 .53 :« 42 36.5 49.5 9 11.5 23 19 23 11 12 t&gt; 0 17 21.5 14 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Agricultural Experiment Station of Xebrtutka Bkek Pbodixtion. — Exjieriinents have been continued to de - termine the value of different rations in fattening cattle. In the year 1912-1:?, six lots of steers with eight in each lot were fed &lt;m different rations for this purj&gt;ose. In the year 1913-14, eight lots of steers with eight in each lot were again fed; ami in the year 1914-15, six lots of steers with eight in each lot are lieing fed. in determine the relative values of different rations. In this experi - ment, attention is given to the use of silage in fattening cattle and also to the different commercial foods which may be used to supply protein in the fattening ration. A bulletin on bmf pro - duction covering the tirsi two experiments is ready for the priater. Feeding Wheat to Ho»;s. — An ex|&gt;eriiiienl was conducted for the purpose of securing daia on the value of whole wheat and ground wheat, fed both with and without tankage, in fattening pigs. Forty pigs were used in this experiment. They were divided into four lots of 10 pigs each. The follow ing rations were fed : Lot 1, soaked whole wheat. Lot 2, soaked whole wheat 111 parts, tankage 1 part Lot 3, soaked ground wheat. Lot 4, soaked ground wheat 1!) parts, tankage I part The feed required for KM) pounds of gjiin on the different ra tions was as follows : Soaked whole wheat. 591 pounds. Soaked whole wheat, lit parts: tankage. 1 part i4K.~&gt;.n pounds wheat and 24 pounds tankage). Soaked ground wheat. 443 pwnds. Soaked ground wheat, 1!» parts: tankage, 1 par! 1 421.7 pounds wheat and 20.7 pounds tankage I. Figuring the farm price of jKU-k at $7 ]&gt;er hundred, soaked whole wheat was worth 71 cents jm-i- bushel when fed alone and 79 cents per bushel when fed with one part tankage to 111 part* wheat. Soaked ground wheat was, after paying 4 cents per bushel for grinding, worth 90.8 cents per Imshel when fed alone. When fed with one part tankage to 1!&gt; parts wheat, it was worth !»2.28 cents per bushel. The complete results of this experiment are published in Itul letin 144. Lamb Feeding Experiments. — Experiments are in progress at the central Station and at the North Platte Station to deter mine the relative value of different rations in fattening lambs. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Tirvntji-eiqhth Annual Report 17 Shelled com uud alfalfa hay are l&gt;eing compared with shelled con, alfalfa hay. and silage. Choice alfalfa hay is also being compared with first cut tin}; or second quality hay, fed in connec - tion with sln-lled corn. Ten per cent cottonseed meal is being used in connection with corn and alfalfa hay to determine whether there is any advantage in feeding cottonseed meal with alfalfa hay. Uroand corn and ground alfalfa hay is being fed to one lot to determine whether there is any advantage in feeding alfalfa meal over feeding ■ straight alfalfa hay ration. Two hundred and fifty western lambs and 2K native lambs are being fed at the central Station, and :?20 western lambs at the North Platte Station. The ex|»erinients are not yet completed. KxrKiti.MKN is in Milk Pmnhictiom. — Two yearn' exiierimental work in coin] aring corn silage versus alfalfa hay as feeds for milk production where a grain ration is fed indicate that the alfalfa ration favors a slightly heavier yield of milk than the corn silage ration. The corn silage ration as fed has been found to l»e cheaper. The experiment is not yet complete. 1I(h; Choljou Skkc.m Production. — During the past year the capacity of the serum plant has been increased by the erection of a new barn in which to house hogs which are being used for seruir purpose*. For the year 1914, more than 8,&lt;KH),000 cubic centi - meters of serum was produced. The inventory of the plant January 1. 1915, was $57,181.19. This is somewhat in excesss of the $50,000 total appropriation made by the State during the last three bienniums. During a portion of this time, serum was sold at 2 cents per cubic centi - meter, and later at 1.5 cents per cubic centimeter. Still later, the cost of serum was reduced to 1 cent per cubic centimeter, but an accurate cost accounting now shows that this price is below the cost of production, and the price of serum is being raised to 1.25 cents per cubic centimeter, beginning February 15, 1915. EXPERIMENTS AT THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Lines of investigation include crop production under both dry land and irrigation, variety tests, methods of tillage, and crop rotation. The work in irrigation is confined to the irrigation of a 10-acre tract by (lumping water from a well about 40 feet in depth with a 4-inch rotary pump and a 20 horse power gasoline engine. These experiments indicate that there is an abundant supply of water available for irrigation, and we wish to recom- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 [grieultwnl Etitcriment Station of \rhranku mend that provision be made to establish an irrigation plant which will have capacity to irrigate 4(1 MM of land which will be put under a regular cropping system. Experiments in growing trees are being continued. These in - clude the testing of different species, the enVct of pruning and of cultivation, and the effect of different spacing and different varie - ties of trees. Fruit trees are being grown on a limited scale, and ornamental shrubbery is lieiug tested to determine what varieties are hardy in the region. During the past year a dairy barn lias been completed, 72 feet by 40 feet dimension, with a milk room 24 feet by ,'50 feet. This building is built of hollow tile, with cement stucco exterior finish and cement plaster for interior finish. The cost of the barn was f 10,500. The dairy work is under way but is not yet started on an extensive scale. We have purchased the nucleus of a pure-bred Holstein herd, which it is expected will be increased in number in the near future. Experiments are in progress with 14 lots of pigs to determine the value of different rations and different methods of feeding. The results of previous experimental work with similar rations is l&gt;eing printed as Bulletin No. 147. S|K'fial attention has been given to the cost of predating t lit 50-pound pig and the cost of wintering brood sows. The chief value of the work of the Substation, on the whole, is to disprove the theories thai extreme drouth conditions can l»e overcome either by adapted varieties or kinds of cropa or by special methods of tillage; that while these assist in making the crop more certain to reach maturity and increasing the yield, weather conditions may be so adverse as to destroy the crop in spite of all modern methods of seed selection and tillage. These facts have a hearing in emphasizing the importance of making the production of live stock the chief end of farming in this region and in discouraging attempts to grow large fields of grain for market. In addition to the dairy barn above mentioned, a new office building was completed within the bieuuium, at a cost of $7,500. Mr. H. A. McComb, a graduate of the University of Nebraska, who has been engaged in commercial horticulture for some years, was added to the force as Horticulturist. The cooperative work in dry land farming investigations with the United States Department of Agriculture is continued. THE VALENTINE SUBSTATION During the past year a dairy herd has Ikhmi established upon </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Twvnty-eighth Annual Report 19 the Valentine Substation farm, for the purj&gt;ose of demonstrating the practicability of dairying as an industry in this region. A pure-bred herd of Holstein cattle has been purchased. A dairy barn and silo have been erected, and sufficient corn has been raised to till a 100-ton silo and furnish a limited amount of fodder corn iu addition. Experiments have been continued with sweet clover and alfalfa to determine their suitability for pasture in sand hill regions. Potato experiments have beeu continued to determine the best method of growing potatoes for seed for the region and to find some variety which might take the place of the old Early Ohio, which is the potato now grown almost exclusively for commercial purposes. Experiments would indicate that the Irish Cobbler is ■ variety raparior to the Early Ohio, having yielded 15 per cent more than the Early Ohio and ripening 10 days earlier, which is considered an advantage. Potatoes grown under a mulch in 1912 produced :\2 per cent larger yield, and in 1913 produced 27 per cent larger yield, while in 1914 they produced 18 per cent larger yield than potatoes grown in the ordinary way. When the rain - fall was deficient, the advantage of mulching showed to a larger extent than when the rainfall was normal or nearly normal. Potatoes growa under a mulch also showed an advantage when used for seed, by producing a larger yield per acre than seed growa iu the ordinary way. In 1913 this increase amounted to 7 per cent in the yield ; in 1914, to 3 per cent. In testing the various sorghums to determine which varieties are superior, dwarf milo is recommended above larger and later maturing sorghums. Feterita is rather late in maturing, but has shown valuable drouth resistant qualities. Plants grown from seed raised in the region mature earlier than plants raised from freshly imported seed. Sudan grass promises to become one of the most valuable sorghums yet tested. All the sorghums grown at this Station have been iu cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture, which furnished the necessary seed. The most important practical result of this Substation has shown itself in the increase of acreage planted to alfalfa and the number of silos that have been built as the result of the showing made on the Substation farm. THE SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION Work is continued at the Scottsbluff Substation along the lines previously undertaken. This includes rotation of croj* under irrigation, a study of the varieties of wheat, oats, barley, corn, and potatoes. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Agricultural Experiment Station of Xebraskn Experiments have beeii undertaken to determine the value of forage crops for pasture of swine and the value of unmarketable potatoes in fattening hogs when used in connection with grain rations. A dairy herd haw l&gt;een established at the Station, to OMMraffe dairying in the region. It is proposed to add to this herd hy the purchase of pure-bred Ayrshire cows, so that a pure-bred Ayrshire herd may l&gt;e developed. The Station is cooperating with the fanners in the region to determine the most profitable use of alfalfa, beet pulp, and low grade molasses in connection with the grains produced. The Station recommends the keeping of larger numbers of live stock upon irrigated farms, and especially commends the growing of hogs on alfalfa pasture with a small grain ration in summer. the keeping of dairy cows to consume the alfalfa and other rough ness on the farm, and the feeding of cattle and sheep in winter, so that a home market may be supplied for the hay which is prodsci c! 1: 1 &gt;• hi all irrigated farms on this project. The Station has published ISulletin No. 141. •Irrigated Field Crops in Western Nebraska." and Bulletin No. 142, '•Vegetable (iardeus on Irrigated Farms in Western Nebraska." THE CULBERTSON DEMONSTRATION FARM Plats have Iteeu laid out upon a portion of this farm to com pare dry land methods with irrigation, to test different varieties of corn and small grain, and to develop different varieties of sorghums with a view of determining the sorghums liest adapted to the region. THE STATION STAFF Within the past year the following changes in the Station stall have taken place: Professor R. K. Miss has resigned to accept a position as In ;i&lt; of the Extension Service at the Iowa State College. Professor R. A. Emerson has resigned to accept a position as head of the department of Plant Breeding at Cornell University. Ithaca, New York. This position was filled by the selection of Professor Robert F. Howard as head of the Department of Horti culture. Mr. H. B. Carpenter, Assistant in Animal Husbandry, died .March 7. 1914. Professor H. Clyde Filley has been placed in charge of the Farm Management investigations, the Department being sepa - rated from Agricultural Extension when this Department tn reorganized into the Agricultural Extension Service. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Twenty-eighth Annual Report 21 IMPROVEMENTS Mince the l«ri Annual Report, addition* have been made to the Serum Plant costing aliout Xtl.OOO. The North Platte fhrpcrif atal Suhstatiou has completed its laboratory and ottce building, at a cost of f7,500, and its dairy barn al a cost of #10,500. Imi'kox k.mknts at TiiK Central Plant. — The results of the recent election have placed at the disposal of the Regents a sum of over $2:50.000 as a portion of the proceeds of the three-quarter mill lax which the University Farm is to receive during the six years from 1913 to 1919, estimated at #700,000, for agricultural improve - ments, to Ik' used liy the College and the Station. The plans for the new Dairy Hall are practically completed. and it is estimated that this building with its equipment will cost 9125,000. Plans are also in progress for a new horse barn, which will cosi approximately X20.000. The lines of expenditure for the balance of the appropriation have not yet been determined, but it is expected that greenhouse facilities for investigation will be largely increased and the laboratory equipment of the various Station departments will l&gt;e very greatly improved. PUBLICATIONS The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Twenty seventh Annual Report. Presented to the Governor January 31, 1!M4. ."..000 copies. Bulletin No. 141 i Volume XXVI, Article III) (Scottsbluff Substation Bulletin No. 1). Irrigated Field Cropit in Western \ebraxka. By Fritz Knorr. Distributed May 1, 1914. 5.000 copies. Bulletin No. 142 ( Volume XXVI. Article IV) ( Scottsbluff Hub - station Bulletin No. -). Vegetable Hardens on Irrigated Farm* in Western \ebraska. Bv Fritz Knorr. Distributed April 27, 1!»14. 5.000 copies. Bulletin No. 14:5 (Volume XXVI. Article V) (North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 15 1. Feeding Baby Beef. By W. P. Snyder. Distributed June 22. 1!U4. 15.000 copies. Bulletin No. 144 (Volume XXVII, Article I). Ground Wheat ttrmu Whole Wheat for Fattening 1'igs. By R. K. Bliss and C. B. I-.ee. Distributed August 15. 1!H4. 20,000 copies. Bulletin No. 145 (Volume XXVII. Article II). Handling Silage. Bv L. \V. Chase and Ivan D. Wood. Distributed Septeiu ber 1, 1914. 20,000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Agricultural Experiment Station of Xebraaku Bulletin No. 146 (Volume XXVII, Article III). Emme Mulched rx. Xorthcni Seed I'otatoi'x for Haxtern Xebraxka. By K. A. Emerson. Diatribated December 24, 1!&gt;14. 12,000 copies. Bulletin No. 147 (Volume XXVII. Article IV) (North Platte Substation Bulletin No. M). Pork Production. By W. P. Knyder. (In press.) 20,000 copies. Bulletin No. 148 (Volume XXVII. Article V). 1 Hmmdbook of Xebruxka Ora **&lt;•*. By K. Meml Wilcox. George K. K. Link, and Venus W. Pool. (In press. I 10,000 copies. Press Bulletin No. 45. How to Combat the Hixxinn /•'///. Bv M. H. Swenk. Distributed August 1".. l!»U. 20,000 copies. Extension Bulletin No. 2.'{. What it &lt;i Farm Demonttrmtorf By V. \\. l'unsley. I»isiril)ute&lt;l March '.). l'.tU. S/inu/inii Fruit in Xcbraxka. Bv •June L'4.'l!»14. Extension Bulletin No. 24. .1. Ralph Cooper. Distributed The Habcock Text und itx I xc in Prandoen. I&gt;istribute&lt;l September Director!/ of Xebraskn Dairy Cut tic Hrccdcrx and Itcaler*. By J. H. Frandsen. i In press, i Extension Bulletin No. 27. h'irxt Annual Report of Count i Cooperative Farm Demonxtration Work. .January 1. 1!»14. By (' W. Pugsley and A. E. Anderson. Distributed July 10, I!tl4. Extension Bulletin No. 2S. Feeding Alfalfa to Hone*. By II J. Gramlich. Distribuled August 27. I!tl4. Extension Bulletin No. '27&gt; Herd I miironinriit. Bv J. II. 1(1. 1!)14. Extension Bulletin No. 2(i. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Tin-nfi/rii/nth Annual Report 23 ANNUAL KEPOUT A&lt;il{ICII/n UAL EXTBN8IOU BEBVICK Tin- KxteuMuu Service «&gt;f the College of Agriculture of the rniversity of Nebraska is carrying on the following Hues of ex - tension work : 1. Fanners' institutes. I'. Extension schools. :!. Demonstration work. 8. Women's clubs. 7. Extension news service. .S. County fair exhibits, '.i. Correspondence courses. 10. Extension bulletins and 4. Hoys' and girls' chilis. ~&gt;. Home economics work. circulars. In conducting this work U."&gt; people are employed by the Service for full time, 5 for part time, and 15 for sj&gt;ecial lecture work as I he occasion demands, making a total of 45 workers. In addi- tion to this the faculty of the College of Agriculture and the staff of the Experiment Station, members of the State Board of Agri - culture, the State Horticultural Society, the Live Stock Sanitary Board, and other state associations give much of their time. The farm demonstration work, the boys' and girls' club work. and certain phases of work in connection with dairying and hog cholera problems are carried on in cooperation with the I'nited States Department of Agriculture and local rural organizations. The following is a statement of the clerical work necessary in conducting the administrative work during the past year Total personal letters — pages l'0,li5 I Miplicate letters — pages 184,660 Duplicate instructional material — pages 689,698 Extension bulletins sent on request 68,850 Bulletins published — copies 110,000 In addition many letters of a technical nature were written by workers in the various departments of the College aiid Station, to which such inquiries are always referred. The Extension Service of the College of Agriculture in organ izatiou is coordinate with the Experiment Station, and has an Extension Council composed of the heads of the various depart ments in the College. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Agricultural Experiment station of Nebrutkii 24 MEETINGS HELD AND PEOPLE REACHED Following is a statistical report of the uumlier of meetings held himI the attendance at each during 1!»14 Total separate points MMW 4!»2 Total meetings held 77.'! Total sessions held 2,051 I !■• Total sessions held The attendance at these meetings was as follows: Meetings Attendance Farmers' institutes lSli 10:«.74o Short courses 20 21.414 Special demonstration meetings 24."» 2&lt;&gt;,"&gt;sl Special women's club meetings INK 4.5(M» Special junior meetings 1 14 Ht, 147 County fair exhibits 7 .".."i.OOO Miscellaneous meetings 18 1,784 Totals 77:: 212. His The distribution of all meetings is shown by the following map: The above map shows the location of the meetings. Several of the points indicated were visited more than once, but this is not shown on the map. The counties holding the most meetings have a county agricultural agent, an interested county superintendent, active granges, or farmers' unions. • • • • • * * 1 • • . • • • • • • ii • !.. "- • • • • • • •• ,&lt;:• • • • • * • k± .' • • • •• . • • .' ••• • • R 5^ • • • • • • tlsA • • :• :*i ft ,.*. • LOCmtiO"! AT AoMia/i. nMH •• .1 • o F L_ • • ■ • • *N r^ V: u. t- • </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Twenty-eighth Annual Report 25 EXTENSION NEWS SERVICE The weekly News Service is used by Nebraska papers having a combined circulation of 1,295,949, practically equal to the popu - lation of the State. Papers using the service have 97 per cent of total number of subscribers to all Nebraska newspapers. In ad dition it is known that papers outside Nebraska using the service liriiiH the total numlter of subscribers up to 2,725,889. FARMERS' INSTITUTES I Miring the past year there has been a decided increase in *ke attendance and interest at farmers' institutes. It has been the policy of the Extension Service to make the farmers' institute as nearly a short course in agriculture as possible. For this reason an effort is being made to secure enough specialists at the College and Station to fill all institute dates. These specialists are used in the summer months when institutes are not held, and also to address special meetings for which there is always a demand. We find this method of hiring specialists by the year more satisfactory than to employ lecturers for a few weeks at a time who do not have special training. In this way we are able to get men who are well trained along certain lines and to hold them in the work because they are employed by the year. At all farmers' institutes an association of farmers and inter - ested people is required, and local arrangements are made by the executive committee or officers of the association. All local ex - penses, such as halls, advertising, speakers, local expenses, etc.. arc provided by the association. One hundred and eighty-six institutes and similar meetings were held with an attendance of 103,740. SHORT COURSES The Extension Service is encouraging the short course idea. A short course is merely a school of agriculture held for a week ai one town. A crew of lecturers is sent to talk upon the subjects desired. Illustrative material, often including laboratory ap - paratus is furnished by the Service from the College. Sessions of the school are held mornings, afternoons, and evenings. The schools are growing in popularity, and the Service is not able to suppiy the demand for short course workers. There were sufficient applications to have kept two crews busy during the past year, but funds permitted the employment of only one. It is a more expensive method of work than the farmers' institute but is productive of a great deal more good. As with farmers' insti - tutes, all local expenses are provided by a local association. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska During the past year, 20 schools were held, including adult and junior schools, with a total attendance at all sessions of 21,444. r COUNTY AGENT OR FARM DEMONSTRATION WORK County agricultural agent work lias l&gt;eeii in progress in eight counties this year. Four of the work under way last year. Four this season at various times, county, March 10; I&gt;awes county. and Kimball county, July 1. counties organized and had the • new counties look up the wort They are as follows: Madiso' April 1 : Dakota county, .Inly 1 : The eight counties, together lows: * Resigned. CouNT/fS AiKIHC FipLMAmRY frrr t*ngi The demonstration work is undertaken by an organization of farmers in a county cooj&gt;erating with the Extension Service of tin- College of Agriculture of the I'niversity of Nebraska and with the United States Department of Agriculture. The United States Department of Agriculture contributed f8,100. and |600 of Smith with ilie county agentx, are ;is M Merriek Couniy I Jage County Fhui'ston County Reward OmhMj Madison County Dawes County Dakota County Kimball County V. S. Culver* (&gt;. II. [Jeter* I. F. Oovpe V. II. Beckkuff Val Kuskn' C. S. Hawk illicit KaymoiK (it-o. &lt; &gt;. 1 'nruli </seg>
            <seg id="p027">TirrntH-eii/hth Annual Report 27 Lever funds was used in the maintenance of county agent work in the counties now organised. It is the plan of the Extension Service to secure $1,200 per year from Federal or State funds for each county if $1,200 or more |km- year is raised by a county farmers' association, either by membership dues, subscriptions, or by appropriations of the county commissioners or supervisors. lielow is a statistical summary showing some of the demands upon their time: SI MMAKY OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF COUNTY AGENTS Farmers visited on their farms 2,817 Total 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i »«- 1- of farm visits made 4,038 ( mice calls 4,720 Telephone calls 4,804 Letters written 6,240 Circular letters and bulletins distributed 21,365 Meetings addressed 406 Attendance at such meetings 26,581 Community clubs organised 9 Total membership of such clubs 308 Agricultural articles published in county papers.... 387 Local short courses conducted 3 Attendance at short courses 725 Schools assisted in developing agricult'l instruction !&gt;4 I'upils reached 2,915 Agricultural observation parties conducted 11 Total persons in such parties 767 Fanners cooperating in demonstrations 350 Meetings held to ins|&gt;ect demonstrations 47 Attendance 1,526 Total members in county farmers" associations 2,012 Farm buildings planned or improved 42 Silos constructed 66 Water supply systems introduced 9 Drainage systems planned 10 Irrigation systems planned 4 Registered stallions secured 4 Registered bulls secured 56 Registered boars secured 71 I &gt;airy cows purchased 142 Heef cows purchased 31 Purchasing and marketing associations formed 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">xxriii Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Business done by farmers' exchanges in buying and selling live stock, seed, hay, etc $41,141 HOME ECONOMICS WORK The record of women's meetings during the } - ear 1914 shows ;i decided increase in number over those held during the year 1913. Two hundred and fourteen points thruout the State have been visited by women sj&gt;eakers and 461 meetings have been held for women. The demand for short courses is steadily increasing; 10 tirsi year, 6 second year. 1 third year, and 3 junior short courses have been held, making a total number of 20. The average attendance per session has been 72 and the average total attendance per week has been 515. The total nmulier of women who have been reached in the morning and afternoon sessions of the short courses is 10,246, while the number attending the evening session amounts to 3,448. This makes a total of 13,649 women reached thru the short course work Home Economics extension workers have come in contact wilh 4. 506 women thru talks given along various phases of club work and have met with 25,207 women in farmers" institutes and other similar meetings. The number of women in attendance at various evening meetings thruout the year is 11,883. The total number of women in attendance at all meetings during the year is 51,842. WOMEN'S CLUBS During the past year 247 women's clubs have asked for our outlines. This means that these clubs are devoting their time either wholly or in part to some kind of home study work. A very few have a membership of less than 20. Many have a mem bership of 30 or 40, while several have as many as 100 members. Averaging them at 45, which seems conservative, their combined membership may be estimated at 10,935. These clubs are located in 6!) different counties. We have visited 32 clubs, assisting in planning their work or helping in any way we could. (Mub talks have been given at 45 different points. The number of women reached by speakers, who presented the club work, was 4.506. [ 'ows tested for milk production Animals tested for tuberculosis Hogs vaccinated for cholera Well hogs in infected herds saved Fotal hogs in infected herds saved Blackleg vaccination 575 u« 2:5,605 nils'-; 4f&gt;4 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Tirrttty-riyhth Annual Report 29 We have ■ list of 70 purely rural clubs. Many of these are doing very little work, hut all are doing something. We heartily encourage them regardless of the amount of work being done, for in the thinly settled districts the club is the center of the social life. WOMEN'S MEETINQS DURINQ THE YEAR I9N BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUB WORK The Boy*' and (Jills' Club Work is a National movement and is fostered by the United States Department of Agriculture. The work in Nebraska is carried on by the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture. One club leader has devoted her en - tire time to the club work during the past year, and she will have two assistants during 1915. In the club work special emphasis is placed upon the work for the entire year, and monthly lessons are sent to each club member and reports required on each lesson. The bo\ or girl who enrolls as a club meiulter decides to carry out daring a period of at least one year some home project work and submit a definite report at close of the j'ear showing results. The following club projects have been promoted in Nebraska during the year 1014: Corn, potato, gardening and canning, sew - ing, and cooking. Two thousand two hundred boys and girls were enrolled, en - rollment closiug June 1. Eight hundred thirty applied for mem - bership in the com club, 150 in the potato club, 245 in gardening </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Agricultural Experiment tSation of Nebraska 30 club, and 975 in the sewing and cooking clubs. Tliiss membership is from 76 counties in the State. UMVUSITyKMASU eoLLECc or abricuuurc C1TU1SO. HKVC • CUBMUMUI • «TWCS 01EMB • am mtrnx BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS 1014 EXTENSION NEWS SERVICE The total number of subscribers of Nebraska publication using the News Service and special articles furnished is 1,29a 'M'K or almost e«|ual to the population of the Htate. iwvfKiTi of hum i - COUECE OF ICIICUUUIE EITCISIOK SEtVICE OSEEXTOfiOlinsSFJWC USC SKDA. MTIOiS ONLV MIT USING NCWS SERVICE NOT KFOITIK CMIMTEK IEWESEIT LK1TI0I OF E«EIT lEHiSU ICWSHHI PAPERS USING EXTENSION NEWS SERVICE IN I9U. COWIIEI CIICUUTiOl 1.295.949 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Twenty-eighth Annual Report 31 COUNTY FAIR EXHIBIT During the year 1!U4 the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture slatted a county fair exhibit. A tent measuring 30 l&gt;y 40 feet housed the exhibit. The interior of the tent was lined with glass and oak cases 6 feet high containing exhibits of the latest experimental work of the Experiment Station, and the re - sults of certain tests being made among the farmers in the State. Twenty-eight applications were made for the exhibit for the season. Only seven of these requests could be granted because of the shortness of the county fair season. The assignment of the exhibit was made by a committee ap - pointed by the Association of County Fair Managers working in rooperation with the Extension Service. The county fair exhibit was displayed at seven county fairs liesides the State Fair. The demonstrators in charge of the ex - hibit make the following estimate of attendance at the county fairs: i lay Center, Clay County 3,100 Wahoo, Saunders County 4,800 &lt; Jeneva. Fillmore County 6,300 Nelson, Nuckolls County 8,800 Auburn, Nemaha County 3,800 Beatrice, (Jage County 3,500 In addition there were thousands of visitors who saw the ex - hibit at the State Fair. CORRESPONDENCE COURSES Correspondence courses in agriculture offering college credit are off ere* 1 thru the University Extension Department in coopera - tion with the Agricultural Extension Service. These courses are especially prepared to meet the demands of the high school teachers of agriculture, but may be taken by any - one having a high school education or its equivalent and who desires some knowledge in agriculture. C. W. Pugsley, Director of Extension Service. February 1, 1915. York. York County 4,700 Total 36,000 KesiKMtfully submitted </seg>
            <seg id="p032">tfxxii Agricultural Experiment Station of Xcbraxka ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural praw and the daily and weekly newspaper*) eHpwially those papers located within the Stale, have showi their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by ff'v ing liberal space to experimental work reported anil in every \va.\ facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Tin ntji &lt;i&lt;ihth Annual Report 33 FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FUND Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1914, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887 (Hatch fund) $15,000 00 THK ACiUKMmKAL KXPKUIMKNT STATION OF XKBKASKA RECE1ITS RXPBND1TUKH Salaries $6,325 00 Labor 3,616 88 Publications 671 43 Postage and stationery 973 86 Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies 3 30 62 55 699 02 Feeding stuffs 951 45 Library 11 85 Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures 133 14 1,453 09 Scientific apparatus Traveling expenses 37 50 60 93 15,000 00 15.000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Agricultural Experiment Station (if Xvhraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued ADAMS FUND UHrEIITS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1914, under the act of Congress approved March 16. 1906 ( Adams fund ) Salaries Labor Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies. Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies. Library Tools, machinery, and appliances. . Scientific apparatus and specimens Traveling expenses $15,000 00 $15,000 Oi EXI'KNIHTtKES </seg>
            <seg id="p035">igktk I a n mi I Report Tu ii tit 35 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDS RECEIPTS M ys received by the University (State) treas - r from other sources than the United States, versity (State) an the United : le Experiment S or the use and benefit of the Experiment Station ind Substations, for the year ended June 30, 1914. year ended Ju lance August 1, 1913 $9,858 07 ales of stock, produce, etc 41,507 54 EXPENDITURES ries $975 00 Jr 9,043 58 Postage and stationery 449 08 Freight and express 967 23 micals and laboratory supplies 467 80 plants, and sundry supplies 8,229 68 Feeding stuffs 13,312 87 ibrary 20 58 Tools, machinery, and appliances 1,191 55 Furniture and fixtures 383 34 Scientific apparatus and specimens 257 50 Live stock 5,955 92 ling expenses 1,089 99 Uingent expenses 95 59 Buildings and land 273 71 Balance, July 1, 1914 8,652 19 $51,365 61 $51,365 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Agricultural Experiment Station of Xebraska 36 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Concluded APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE EXrEKI MENTAL BIB8TAT1ON8 Balances, August 1, 1913, of legislative appropriation from the State general fund for benefit of the Ex- perimental Substations, for the two years ending March 31, 1915, Culbertson $7,094 01* North Platte 41,330 38 Scottsbluff 3,865 46 Valentine 12.061 00 $64,350 K Expenditures 11 months ending June 30, 1914, for superintendence, supplies, labor, live stock, feed. seeds, machinery, tools, and betterment of thf plants, Culbertson $6,567 87 North Platte 25,438 84 Scottsbluff I Valentine 9,725 41 $44,086 49 Appropriations balances July 1 1 m. Culbertson $526 15 North Platte 15,891 Scottsbluff 1,51109 Valentine M 1.:; t AUBICI I.TI KAI. EXTENSION Balance, August 1, 1913, of lei islative appropriatioi from the State general fund for maintenance &lt; farmers' institutes, for th»- two years endii March 31, 1915 I Expenditures, 11 months ending June M, 1914. for superintendence, clerical service, labor, lecturers. and workers' services and expenses printing 8U PP»es $25,288 95 Appropriation balance July 1. 1914 21,044 36 $46,333 29 4&gt; January 31, 1915. J. S. DALES. Financial i </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>