<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the State Reformator for Women York, Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE State Reformatory for Women YORK, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies ; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Some improvements of a permament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska ; a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska ; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska ; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Board ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. This, jand is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1, 1923) the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4980 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 fur the biennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest biennium biennium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) j une j une 3Oi time past 1921 1923 two years A— Institution for Feeble-Minded 607 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 409 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 K— Nebraska Industrial Homt'ZZZL. 73 86 99 L — Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 733 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R— State Reformatory for Women 9 18 28 S— Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 T— State Reformatory for Men (b) Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months ; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment. Board of Control, Lincoln — Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble-Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash 27,524.49 Capital Outlay '. 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash 4,964.20 Capital Outlay 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett — Maintenance 176,148.28 Cash 67,846.61 Capital Outlay 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash 99,853.78 Capital Outlay 38,850.25 639,888.49 Capital Outlay. State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,440.24 230,986.02 Capital Outlay. Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay 117,826.18 254,696.76 Capital Outlay. Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 375,095,50 Cash 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Capital Outlay. Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash _ _ 25,627.53 Capital Outlay 4,490.17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 229,205.92 Cash 161,633.02 Capital Outlay 390,838,94 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance 61,306.38 Cash _ 2,57826 Capital Outlay 63,884,64 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,406.99 Cash „ _ 29,70029 Capital Outlay 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City — Maintenance 57,82522 Cash 3,989.06 Capital Outlay 3,952.01 65.766.29 Capital Outlay.. Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance ...„ 321.060.71 Cash 50,535.76 Capital Outlay...- 59,999.01 431,595.48 Capital Outlay.. School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance 137,695 55 Cash 16.819.16 16,819.16 1 Outlay „ 4,500.00 159,014.71 Capital Outlay.. State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance 28,489.38 Cash 2.733.39 ,-•"- •• 2,733.39 1 Outlay 46,996.15 78218.92 Capital Outlay </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Grand Total. At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERIXE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYX, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. 4,538,783.65 Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.5; itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 72,188.46 6,959.45 300.000.00 379,147.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1922 PERMANENT IMP. TO BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 1 1 1,02570 TOTAL M,M9I,IO2.Z5 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 INCOME FOR 1921-1922 *UNEXPENOED BALANCE OF CASH ,FEDERRL «ND TRUST FUNO FUNb,lN5TITUTE FOR FEEBL^IINOEO) REHPPROPRIATEO </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. [TUBES, STATE I July 1, 19; 11 to June 30, 1923 Institution for Feeble-Minded.... Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous...- „.. Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital...- State Penitentiary. Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital School for the Deaf. State Reformatory for Women.... Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (a).... * 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410,19 226,534.52 60,739.65 45,28120 178J07.10 56,464.88 93,393.20 19,294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137,841.88 77,242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 Salaries and Wages $ Operation and Maintenance 186.411.64 82,797.68 155,198.27 351,306.24 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,860.20 42,879.03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,918.21 Furniture and Equipment $ 25,232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,568.22 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7,223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 *•- 10.72 2,124.19 28,624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 New Buildings $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,34827 45,077.86 Land $ 871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 Fixed and State Aid Charges $ Total for Biennium 375,267,87 158,772.67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63,884.64 140,041.38 65,766.29 431,595.48 139,014.71 78,218.92 72,611.53 379,147.91 Per Cent 8.3 3.5 8.0 142 5.1 5.7 12.0 3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 l~09L91 847.26" 500.00 24.75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 22,06228" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 39,08242 90^»J5 48,747"08 ' Total . $1,242,276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,10225 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">i.L POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1923, Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inmates to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Biennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary — Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind (a).... Norfolk State Hospital... Nebraska School for the Deaf (a). State Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children Slate Reformatory for Men (b) 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 66 20 72 160 40 7,6 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 12 9 6 7 S 3 7 2 11 8 5 2 8 4 3 7 6 $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 484.27 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 35.28 54.23 19.19 69.25 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 65.27 31.83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total 5,917 5,876 851 $ 598.15 $24.92 $51,896.46 (a) Average during school year. (b) Opeai :d October 1, 1921—21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period Ending June 30, 1923 Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs. ine. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs, inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs. inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs. inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total n for Feeble-Minded State Hospital luitrial School. for Tuberculoui. — ............... « 67 70 28 38 134 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 11 H2 6 80 6 i 36 • ■ •••... •••..............• 9 59 16 58 —-— 79 61 30 15 j 2 " 3 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 "- "6 17 9 65 14 63 185 17 223 28 1.15 10 61 16 50 3 18 12 70 i 1 8 43 "■ 31 ( t^ntnnBfl wF j^i^rwPaTwTi aaawj lllttttttaaaammm mtm9tmmmm Nebraska nduitrial Home Soldier*' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind. Norfolk State Hospital.. ........ Neiragu School for the Deaf State Reformatory for Women...- Home for Dependant Children State Reformatory for Men 67 ido 89 14 2 "'" 3 " ..... 6 •• 15 ..... "" 66 31 4 2 7 26 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 j 27 1 39 80 •■ 74 36 ............ 38 ""W" i 44 6 5 .......... i" 121 67 180 46 j i Total ' 211 293 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 181 271 76 4074 I </seg>
            <seg id="p014">M :vity op 1 HOSE ADI ilTTED »O1 FIRST TIME Bie miuni P'ridin I June-30, 19; I. IttbU lining aohooi Soldl.ni tndS-Uon' Home i Burkott Hutlnfa BtaU Hospital Isdastrial School Hospital tor Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthoiwdic State Penitentiary Nebraska IndtutrUl Home Soldiers -DdSkUon* Home MlUord Nebnik- School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebraaka School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home tor Dependent Children Reformatory for Men Total ... 6 7 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 .30 1 8 1 2 1 2 44 6 1 1564 124 30 .1 ■■»..■■ .»■■■■ m.,.n I i" .. - -" I 14 "'■ r - ...„ i J ... _ 2 2 i -"*— — — *- "TH i f~ ■■"-T-- 1 _-___._ 12 3 i" "awfcs gTuuiiiiii3."Z.".r"r Dmautrk Puund .z.'.zzrzzrz. Praaee _ Germany ~ wm^* m t •••••••«•_•••_■•••••••••••••_ Greece _ Holland Hungary Ireland lUly Japan Macedonia Mexico IT Usraria ______ Nebraska Netherlands Norway Pound ..._ : ::: n Russia ...„ Saxony _ _ Scotland II. Seria ir 1 *!* — - - Sicilia .... _ Spain _ Sweden " Switzerland ; _.. Turkey U. S. other than Nebraska. Unknown __ _ Oifcer Countries...- _. __ 1 7 6 17 8 6 2 1 ■ I „ 1 "4~ 1 4 S 1 2 27 _ T" 3 2 1 1 _ ~" !S s 1 19 1 _J 1 1 „ "" 2 2 32 1 tl 1 3 2 1 _ 1 ~" ' 1 2 _.._ _ _ i" 2 i " 1 ~"T 7 _ _ 1 3 2 — . .__ ._.._.. .. ""■■■"■■"i "1 3 1 1 _ 1 , _ " 4 2 , I !______ 1 11 ' ... -.._.-..._....._. 1 1 119 1 vi ™" 2 i" i _______ 209 ■"" 98 ■~"""T~~\ -arH " " jgg 201 '339 74 66 " 1 12 103 26 30 232 72 _ 2 3 8 1 I 1 2 1 2 5 """l 2 1 3 10 " T I . , "4 l . „ 1 _ i 2 — i 2 " 1 -_— • ■ . ; 2 9 . 2 2 13 2 „ _j . „ — l 256 5 i i' _ 13 1 _.._ "i 32 K 4 ~ii9~ 205 26 "~ l"37 "76 209 42 4 42" 20 l 116 n 129" ' 9 29 5 1 116 45 26 Total 162 135 472 333 384 369 125 92 21 344 35 62 238 241 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 I CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOB FISST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">17 STATE REFORMATORY FOR WOMEN YORK, NEBRASKA OFFICERS ALMA J. CHAPMAN, M. D. LEO ROSE, M. D. Superintendent Physician MINNIE CAMERON Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1920 Number of employees 7 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 25 Highest number of inmates 28 Per capita cost per month $ 65.27 Number of acres owned 119 Number of acres under cultivation 119 Value of land and buildings $ 89,951.00 Principal industries, farming and stock raising. Visiting days, fourth Thursday of each month. A female of fifteen years or upwards (who is not feeble-minded or insane), convicted by any court or magistrate, on charges of petty larceny or immoral conduct, may be sent to this institution for indeterminate sentence and is subject to parole by the Board of Pardons ; provided that no such parole may be granted while the inmate is afflicted with venereal disease. When the crime committed is a felony, the convicted women may be sentenced to the Reformatory, but is subject to transfer to the State Penitentiary for infractions of the rules in incorrigibility. </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. It gives me pleasure to present the first biennial report of this institution, which was opened in May, 1920. The Legislature had appropriated $50,000 to establish this institution, and 120 acres of land were bought at $300 per acre. The rest of the money was expended in building barracks to house and care for the inmates. In 1922 the Legislature gave us $40,000 for a new building, which is known as the West Hall. It contains twenty-five single rooms for the girls, a lobby, sewing room, school room, laundry, store room, and four "thinking" rooms ; also quarters for the em - ployees. Up to this date we have had seventy-six girls here. A number of the girls have attempted to run away during this time, but we have never lost but one girl and she had outside assistance. The officials of York County have been a great help to us. The ministers of York have taken turns ■ in conducting the Sunday afternoon services until February, 1923, when Reverend Carney became our chaplain. His work has been excellent. The inmates of this institution are many of them mentally subnormal. We receive here those suffering from venereal diseases, drug addicts, drunkards, prostitutes, thieves, and others that are mentally irresponsible. We have a schoolroom and each girl goes to school for one hour each day. Most of the girls have had very little schooling. They come to us pallid and sickly and in a short time become brown and rugged. The new girls are put outdoors to work and the regular hours, outdoor work and treatment have their effect, and the girls gain from ten to forty pounds while here. Most of these girls come from broken families or are of foreign parentage. We have a sewing room in which the girls make their own dresses. We also make shirts for other institutions. We raise our own potatoes and butcher some of our stock. The West Hall is fitted with three shower baths for the use of the girls. The good food and personal cleanliness help to make our girls healthier. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">20 The manner is which we punish rule-breaking girls is to lock them up in the "thinking" room until they can see the error of their ways. We have 120 acres which are in corn, oats and garden. Our herd has increased until we have fifteen head of cattle at the present time. We have fourteen hogs and one hundred ten spring pigs. A cement hog house and a cement chicken house have been erected. The Nebraska Public Library Commission has furnished us with a traveling Jibrary and we also have a good many books that have been given us. Our girls are fond of preparing programs and at Christmas and Easter we invi.ted some of our friends from York to attend these entertainments. The girls are also fond of dressing up and having parties, which are their very own. The costumes that they prepare are remarkable considering the little that they have to do with. They have outdoor games such as tennis and base ball. We feel in this work that we are going forward and the insti - tution is shaping itself to do the most for the girls placed in our charge. Much of this is due to the excellent group of women who are co-workers with me. I appreciate very much the help given me by the Board in the many problems that I have had to solve since coming here. ALMA J. CHAPMAN, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p020">21 Remaining at end of period I 29 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 14 and under 18 8 18 and under 21 , | 23 21 and under 25 j 10 25 and under 30 .'. i 6 30 and under 40 i 5 40 and under 50 3 50 and under 60 , ! 1 1 Total I 62 TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 e 30, IS •30 2 Single ,30 Separated Married 29 Widow 1 Total 62 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Present at beginning of period Admitted : For the first time 14 02 Total 76 ischarged : No longer requiring institutional care Transferred to other Institutions Died Escaped Paroled, or on visit home and not returned during period... Discharged while on parole 9 3 1 1 23 10 Total 47 lotal </seg>
            <seg id="p021">22 Total 62 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 than the 8th Grade Ith grade 0th grade High school lollege _ 22 26 10 2 2 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Jnited States ! Alabama California Colorado Illinois I Iowa Kansas Kentucky _ Minnesota Missouri Nebraska North Dakota South Dakota _ 59 1 1 2 2 6 5 2 2 6 30 1 1 Total 59 Canada Mexico _ Russia 1 1 1 Total 62 TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE DMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Both native born _... Both foreign _ Mixed Unknown _ 15 2 5 40 Total 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">23 P DEA For Period Ending June 30, 1923 ronchial pneumonia after influenza .. 'eriod of residence in the institution of those who died during period ige at death 9 months 5 days 43 years TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF YEAR Those admitted \ I° tal . during period Tl^ m ?™ June 30, 1923 Boyd I 2 0 Buffalo I 2 1 Burt ! 1 1 Cedar I 1 0 Cheyenne I 1 0 Clay 1 1 i" A. t 1 Custer I I Dawes 2 0 Dixon I I Douglas ' 9 6 Dundy I I Furnas | 2 0 Hall ; i 3 I Jefferson : I Keith I I I Keya Paha I Knox 0 I 0 Lancaster ; 15 Madison ! 1 Morrill J 6 0 ? 0 -*iui l ill *» V Nemaha ' 2 0 I -. iv -" iu "" - Otoe ! 1 piatte ;.;.. 1 1 0 Richardson i 2 0 Saline ...ZZ..Z..ZZZZ.ZZ.Z. 1 0 Scotts Bluff ........ZZZZ.ZZ.ZZZZ... 3 1 Seward .....~.J.'.Z.'.'..ZZZZZ. 1 0 Thomas i 2 2 Total | 62 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">24 TABLE IX— PHYSICAL CONDITION OF THOSE AD DURING PERIOD ENDING JUNE 30, 1923 ADMITTED Girls committed during period with syphilis Girls committed during period with gonorrhea Girls committed with both syphilis and gonorrhea. 17 24 15 Total 56 Well girls committed during period Total girls committed during period 62 TABLE X— PHYSICAL CONDITION OF THOSE DISCHARGED For Period Condition at discharge Ending June 30, 1923 All girls discharged during this period were free from diseastij TABLE XI— INMATES NO LONGER REQUIRING INSTITUTIONAL CARE For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Discharged 9 Paroled from institution ' 23 Total 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">25 PRODUCTS OF LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY tattle: 9 cows 1 male 2 heifer calves 2 male calves . 1 red calf Total Hogs 23 sows 1 malt 110 pips Total Horses 4 work horses 1 colt Total Total Poultry 160 chickens 42 ducks 7 geese 7 turke Total Total value of live stock and poultry $4010.00 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>