<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Study of Selected Types of Domestic Gas Stoves</title>
               <date value="18??">November 1936</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">A Study of Selected Types of Domestic Gas Stoves COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA^ AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 86 ¦ ¦..¦...-¦ '¦: .¦¦¦"...-¦ ... ¦....:. . ¦ . ' -.\ ¦ / •. Arnold E. Baragar I | Department of Home Economics - :.. ¦".'¦¦¦¦"¦.¦¦¦¦ '¦¦':¦¦¦'.¦¦'-¦'. '&lt;'¦¦ ¦¦'•¦¦¦ :¦ ¦ ¦.- '¦,¦¦¦ i: . ¦¦' 'r ¦ - .'.'¦¦ ¦~:'4-i:'=- :;: . = ¦¦."¦'¦'¦•¦•-¦¦¦ ¦-¦¦. ¦¦ '¦¦ : ¦¦ V ¦ ¦.'¦''¦• , . i i ¦.-¦•¦ ¦'¦:': . . - ¦'¦-¦ : ¦.'¦¦ ' ' '.¦."•'- ¦.'¦ ¦ . '" -¦:¦- '¦¦'..: '..¦•¦ ¦:- ¦¦ - ¦.".¦¦¦¦•'¦¦•.. ¦!¦ ' ¦'¦¦'¦¦. '.¦-¦¦¦.: '¦':'¦- ¦"¦¦:¦. V-'-'-'fc.' : ¦/'¦¦ ;/: ¦ '... ¦¦; ¦¦ ¦¦¦¦";¦¦;,'..-:¦¦: ¦ - '. ;' ¦¦''.'¦'¦ ¦¦¦:'¦.¦ ¦ ' •¦• i LINCOLNj NEBRASKA NOVEMBER, 1936 1 ¦.",-.-¦ .-¦•¦-, ¦.- ¦ ¦ ¦¦ : ¦." ¦ j ~ ¦ ¦ ¦' -' ¦ ¦'" ¦ . ¦ ' ¦ . i ' . ';'""¦. </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Summary 2 Introduction 5 Type* of .Surface Burners Studied 5 Utensils Used on Surface Burners 9 Ovens Studied 10 Broilers ]] (/as Supply J1 Type of Measurements Involved . . 12 Setting tht- Orifice for Propt-r das .Rate and the Adjustment of the Burner 13 Tests with Surface Burners 16 Short-time Tests (Thermal Efficiency) 16 Heat Distribution of Burners 30 Long-time Tests (Thermal Kfticiency) 28 Flue-gas Analysis . . 32 Automatic Lighters 34 Boil-over Tests 36 (^inclusions from Surface-burner Tests 37 Tests with Ovens 3&lt;S Method &lt;,t Procedure 3H Calibration of Hum lost at 39 ()\cn Heating ('ap.iciti -42 Rate of Cooling "45 Kmptv (Hen lhat Loss. Temperature Distribution, and Surface Temperatures 46 Open-door Loss 58 Changes in Design which Improve Performance 60 (^inclusions fur Oven Vests 62 Performance of Surface Burners and Ovens in Actual Cooking 63 Appendix I —L.ihoraton and i-.quipment 68 Appendix II —Meter Calibration 69 Apix-ndix lll— Test Box 69 A/&gt;j&gt;cnd'\ IV—LKtfcct of Temperature on (Jas Rate f&lt;ir Type A Burner 70 MKNOWLfcDOMENT the 4u'hnr wishes tn cv'iresi hu .guilesMtioti to the foMowinj*' for iheir coopcranon and assijianee: the Amrricin (,j* Jinoti.num Tetnii)* (..iha'ir.nnrv. the low*-Nebraska Light and Power Company, and ihe Vmhrrn Viitir.il (...-. t ..m|M.n. SUMMARY Seven domestic gas stoves representing several types ot surface burners and burner assemblies and various conditions of oven construction have been studied to determine their performance, primarily from the point of view of a comprehensive set of technical tests. Finally, the performance as determined by the technical tests was compared with the performance obtained from a scries of cooking tests. The stoves were operated on natural gas of average heat content of 1,009 B.t.U. /x*r cubic foot, average specific gravity of 0.72. and at normal pressure oi 7 inches oS water. Gas volume was measured with a 10-light wet test meter; temperatures were measured with coppcr-constaman thermocouples connected to a Leeds &amp; Northrup portable potentiometer, and gas analysis was determined with a Rurrell Orsat apparatus </seg>
         <seg id="p003">¦ ; Selected Types of Gas Stoves : -....-¦ ¦;;. : ¦-¦¦ ¦¦ .: ¦ '-&#132; ¦/¦ ¦ ¦ 1 ; for CO2 and 0 2 , and with an iodinc-penloxidc apparatus for CO. A\\ Mats were per- , j formed in a tcmpcrature-conuollcd room. ¦ : , • Cooking Top Performance , I. 1 the following tests were used to analyze performance, thermal efficiency and time , I of heatins for both short and long periods of heating, heat distribution of the burners, ; flue-gas analysis, automatic-lighter tests, boil-over tests, and actual cooking. . I The efficiency was determined by heating water from an initial temperature of 75 ;i Fto a final temperature of 200" F. Six aluminum and two enameled utensils varying . i in capacity from 1 quart to 8 quarts were used in the efficiency tests. With the weight , , ;; and specific heat of the pan and the water known, the amount of heat necessary ( to [ ¦ raise the temperature from 75° F. to 200° F. could be computed. This was the out - put From the volume of gas used to raise the temperature through the 125 degrees IV of change, the input was calculated. For the short-time tests the ratio of these two ii quantities was taken as the thermal efficiency. For the long-time tests the radiation I and convection loss at the boiling point of water was included in the output, the input ' being calculated as for the short-time tests. _ '. i . / Because of the effect of temperature on gas rate the periods of heating for all burners were corrected to a common basis, the distribution of heat from the burners was determined from scorch patterns / produced on white blotting paper which covered the bottoms of iron and aluminum skillets. From a practical point of view, the distribution was observed by the pan broiling of steak. . ¦¦'-¦¦ ¦'¦¦¦ ¦ Samples of flue gas were removed from a suitable hood placed over the burner, on which was placed a 7 Vi-inch-diameter pan containing water. The gas was analyzed for COi, 0% and CO. The CO content was computed on the basis of the percentage of CO in a 1,000-cubic-foot room by the method presented in American Gas Asscciation "Approval Requirements for Gas Ranges." From the gas analysis, the excess air and heat loss through the flue were computed. ' ' \ • ¦ .. ¦' .; .' , i Automatic ignition tests were conducted according to the specifications ot the ; American Gas Association laboratory. Pilot lights; were adjusted according- to. manu- II : faciurcrs' recommendations and then the pressure was reduced to 3!4 inches of water. ¦I At this pressure the times for ignition and re-ignition were recorded. ... ¦I Boil-over tests consisted of attempts to dog the burners and lighter assemblies at . • ¦I- the burners with cither a soap or a starch solution. When the soap solution failed to ¦I' clog, starch solutions were used. : ; . , ¦ i ,;, . ¦ . The results-for" the efficiency-tests showed that efficiency depended upon the size ¦I and kind, of utensil, upon the construction of the burner in the stove, and. upon the '&#132;.¦ | ,yp c of stove top and grate construction. It was found that efficiency could be changed I by modifying any of these factors. The efficiency was found to be independent of the j quantity o/ water used, the length of the injector tubej and the gas rate, provided all ¦¦ V factors other than gas rate were kept unchanged. Furthermore, efficiencies determined V for the long-time tests were comparable with the average efficiencies for the short-time , 1 tests. Averages of all the short-time efficiencies for pans 1 to 6 (3-quart to 8-quart capacity) showed that the burner assemblies for stoves A to F ranked in the following order, ivith the following efficiencies: 1 . &#132; : Burner Efficiency Burner Efficiency I; Rank assembly [Percent) Rank assembly j (Percent) j -': Ist F 44.49 sth :'...- A 39.65 ! ~ 2nd 834 : . 41.89 Gth / ;C -37.50 ( i I-' 3rd 835 4U2 7th ' E 35.52 j i! ;; •¦ . -ith :¦¦• d 41.09 . ;¦¦ .- ¦ ¦:. 'i ¦.;-.-. .-¦-. | ! ) These nay be considered aj the general efficiencies to bei expected from these .burner i A ''-¦¦ assemblies. The results of the cooking tests produced an identical ranking. , ' % 'A Time of heating was found to be a function of the gas rate and the efficiency, the V \ ' most rapid heating was accomplished with the highest gas rate and the most efficient j ¦ &lt;-\ ¦ ..¦ . .. ¦ ¦:.-.-.¦ ¦ / ..'. ¦ - - .' i ':- .¦¦¦.¦.--¦"¦ :...¦¦¦.•¦.-¦¦.-..¦•.¦ . ¦ ¦ -¦' - ¦'.':''.. \ '; </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 burner assembly. Care, however, must be exercised in choosing the gas rate in order that the burner will not produce carbon monoxide. For the ordinary burner, an input of 9,01)0 B.t.u. per hour may be used. The heat distribution from the burner as determined by the scorch-pattern method was a function of the skillet as well as the shape of the burner. In general, the distribution is fairly uniform for an aluminum skillet, because iron is a poorer con - ductor of heat than aluminum, the iron skillet best revealed the areas of high temperature. From the practical point of view the heat distribution for both skillets was uniform enough to produce well browned and evenly cooked steaks. The principal conclusion to be drawn from the automatic ignition tests was that automatic lighters were not always successful in lighting the burners. Assembly types A, C. and F had the best lighters. The boil-over tests on burner assemblies showed that types C and F were the only imrs that could not be clogged. The remaining assemblies cither clogged in the burner or in the tighter tube at the burner. In general, given technical data regarding the performance of the surface burners 'it the types studied, the /vrformance of similar types can be predicted. These data will also furnish a basis fur predicting the cost of operation for actual cooking. Ovens Chen tests consisted of a calibration of the thermostat, a determination of the oven he.it capacity, a determination of the rate of cooling from an initial temperature of SS(| S X.. .i determination i»t the empty-oven heat loss, surface temperature distribution, internal temperature distribution. &lt;i[icn-do&lt;jr heat loss, and finally an analysis of ihc tlui- gas. After all the tests were performed, attempts were made to improve the oven (K-rtormaiKe on ovens U '35 and F by modifying the burner design. In order to check the perform jnee under practical conditions, bread, butler cake, sponge cake, custard, apple pie, and biscuits wen- baked »n the oven. To observe the performance for long - time cooking, rolled rib roasts were roasted. (Ken dial settings at 400° F. were adjusted to agree with a -100° F. average men temperature measured b\ rive copper-constantan thermocouples connected in parallel ant) arranged &lt;&gt;n the fJijgcmaJs in the mid-plane of the oven. After adjustment, temperatures wire checked tor interval* of 50 degrees, starting at the 250° F. mark. Results shown) thai if an cinpt) oven could be maintained at 300° F., a loaded oven could be maintained at approximate!} 250° P. Whenever low temperatures could not lx- maintained, the Jault was usually found in the burner design and not in the thermo - stat. In general, thermostats were found reliable. The American (las Association requirement tor the oven heating capacity was followed and all of the ovens were round to fulfill the requirement. The thickness oi insulation seemed to Ik the criterion for rate of cooling. The thicker insulation produced a slower rule of cooling. A qualitative measure of heat !&lt;»*( through the- flue was shown In oven X, which had a damper in the flue. The damper closed automatically when the gas was turned off. The heat-loss data revealed that although all of the ovens were insulated, some rather hcavih. much heat was Infct. A great amount of the heat loss could be accounted tor as passing through the flue and the poorly fining dooTS. The effectiveness of the insulation in keeping the exterior surfaces at low temperatures was shown by the surface temperature:.. The heat distribution within the oven could be considered as quite uniform. The baking and roasting tests showed that good products could be obtained from all ovens. According to the amount of heat required to perform the various operations, the ovens ranked in the following order: £. B, D, C. A, F, the first letter denoting the oven ranking in first place anil the last letter the oven in sixth place. It is concluded for ovens that the data obtained for the six ovens studied do not form a basis for predicting the performance of other ovens. The performance of an oven seems t«» dcfiend on the variable factors of construction. In order to measure performance with certainty, each oven should be tested. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">A Study of Selected Types of Domestic , Gas Stoves : ARNOLD' E. BARAGAR . . ) - During recent years several detailed investigations have, been made concerning the proper design of domestic gas burners, 1 but there seems f to be a need for information as to the performance of the burner when used in the modern gas range. Fortunately gas equipment must pass a set of exacting tests performed in the American Gas Association Testing Lab - oratory before being placed on the market as approved equipment, but as is emphasized in the preface of the A. G. A. "Approval Requirements for Gas Ranges" these are a set of minimum requirements. To the general public the great need is a knowledge of the maximum performance and not the minimum. Since there was nowhere to be found literature which would give such data, this investigation was designed to study the mechanical and technological features of various types of gas stoves operating on natural gas with emphasis on the performance of surface burners and ovens, and to determine what the optimum of requirements must be to meet standard cooking practices most satisfactorily and economically. . ( During the period from September, 1933, to June, 1934, six stoyes representing various types of surface burners and ovens were purchased for testing purposes. 2 Two of the stoves were table-top models and four of them were console models. The stoves were purchased from open stock either through a local dealer or direct from the factory. Since the primary interest is type of burner, burner application, and type of oven, and not the testing of any particular brand of. stove, all designations will be made by letter. The essential variable characteristics will be.enumerated as needed throughout the bulletin. . ¦. :, ' '-¦ TYPES OF SURFACE BURNERS STUDIED During the period of this study there were six types of surface burners being used on gas stoves in the United States. They were (1) the eight - arm or, as sometimes called, the star burner, (2) cast-iron round burner, (3) die-cast round burner, (4) Y-type, (5) daisy, and (6) continuous or ribbon flame. These various types of burners and applications are shown in Figures 1 to 7. . . 'Burner-and.application Type, G is art eight-arm, double-duty burner built in a test box for laboratory investigation. The burner was covered by an open grate and there was no burner pan or bowl surrounding the burner. Type H burner and application was similar to Type G except 'Design of atmospheric gas burners, bureau of Standards Tech. Paper 193, 1921; Design of gas burner*- for domestic use. Bureau of Stamfords Circ. 394, 1931; A method of determining the mast '. favorable design of gal burncri. Bureau.of Standards lournal of Research, Research Paper +46, 1932; Domestic gas burner tlcsinn and application, K. M. Conner, American Gas Association Monthly, Feb., 1934; chapter on burner design in "Comlnmion" published by A.,G. A., 1932. .'. ¦ ¦"' j'' 3 During the testing period, icver.il manufacturers introduced burners of the types considered but varying in construction and application from those used on the six stoves. Hence in order to com - plete the study, seven more stoves containing features not already tested were purchased. The results '¦" for these stoves will l&gt;c published in a later bulletin. ': . . I </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 '"' "'' t * '¦'.:^F'»^^^M -'-,&gt;¦ V»MJHF*' Hip' 4 f- ss j.( _J ¦ F.c. 1.-llurncr and a |.pl.c a .i,,n , y|K A. showing eight-arm burner and air plates Small utinsil is pan 1 and large utensil is pan 6. Fig. 2.-Burner an&lt;l application type B, showing round cast-iron burner, drip m n ) open Rratc, and pan 2. 1 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">i r I : ... Selected Types of Gas Stoves ¦ ¦' ' ¦'.'••¦..¦¦ '¦¦' ¦'.'.¦¦¦¦ ¦ - I¦¦¦. . - ¦ ¦ ?1 Fie. 3.—Burner and application type C, showing round die-cast burner, drip pan, ;1| open grate, and pan 5. ?! ¦' Fig. 4.—Burner and application type D, showing round, die-cast burner, solid top with | :ii-i , . burner bowl, open grate, pan 7 next to oven, and pan ion outside grate. • -iv/i .' - ¦ . . ¦ - ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p008">| Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 I; . .! I 11. i.—llurntr ;incl applicatinn type E, showing daisy burner with drip ring. Top is ht.\\\ cjm \ron. Front »raic referred to as open grate and left rear grate as solid (!ra(r. Ih&lt; rich! rear n|K-nini: is a ihermowell. Fw.. fi.—Burner and app\ic;uinn ivjw F. showing conunuous flame burner, burner j bowl, ami nrattL- Larjjc utensil is pan 4 and small utensil is pan 8. I </seg>
         <seg id="p009">I • ¦ Selected Types of Gas Stoves 3 ? : sj'pi '''"' ' ¦'¦ ¦'¦¦•.'''¦¦ ¦¦'' ¦ ¦.¦'¦¦- ". ¦ ¦ -y., '-?'-l^'V^i-j^^^'^!sj}s£j&amp;s§b?*^H II J Fie. 7.—Grouping of various types of burners. The three burners on the left arc round I! die-cast; the first and third burners on the right arc round cast iron; two styles of I! ... .-¦ continuous flame burners are behind the gas cocks and the front round cast-iron I ¦ . burner; the right rear burner is the V type; while the center rear is a double-duty I eight-arm burner, and in front of the eight-arm burner is the daisy type burner. I ' The gas cock in the left front is a double-duty cock, while the right front cock is jBI a single duty. ¦I that the Y-type burner was used. The Y-type turner is shown in the ¦ I upper right-hand corner of the burner group in Figure 7. Before the stove Ml : having Type E burner was purchased, this burner and its application were ¦I studied in the test box. In references to the data covering these tests, the ¦¦I burner and application will be designated as.type J. Types G, H, and J ¦I ¦ are not shown by figures, but the construction of the test box is described B' in Appendix 111. . . 111: ¦ I" order to evaluate the various types o£ burners, the following tests W were outlined: (1) short-time test to determine efficiency and time of l| heating, (2) long-time test to determine the efficiency when evaporation II:; of water is considered, (3) the heat distribution from the burner, (4) flue - l.\ gas analyses for excess air, carbon dioxide, and carbon monoxide, (5) 1;V automatic lighter tests, (6) boil-over tests to determine whether or not a I?v : burner would clog, and (7) actual cooking tests to correlate the technical I * : tests with practical tests. ¦, .¦;'.' .: IV . UTENSILS USED ON SURFACE BURNERS I p,\ In determining the efficiency of a surface burner, not only must the ,1 burner application be noticed, but the size and kind of utensil used must |! ?Vi be considered. Table I lists the essential characteristics of the utensils. 1i | ' Each of the pans used for efficiency tests is shown in one of the Figures | J; 1 to 6. The skillets listed in Table 1 were used for scorch patterns and ¦ pan broiling of steaks, while the drip-drop roaster was used for surface S '-'] meat cookery. ¦¦...-:¦ . ' vv; - "".¦'.- ¦'¦ . : l "..'.' ". '¦ ' - - \; ¦ ' . -'"...'.¦ ¦'¦ '. ¦ " " ' ¦ '" . ; .. ;¦ . . ¦ ¦¦ ¦ . ¦ ¦ .¦¦.... ... ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 1. — Essential characteristics of utensils. Uiens.l I _ ~\ ~ ! i Diameter 1.. . , V~l ¦ I Radiation and ,Vo I T«« [ Mttcrul ( 0 ( bottom I H «Shl I | convcaion loit titthct Inchet Quun B.t.it./min. 1 Sauce pan Rolled aluminum 7.000 -U5O 3 5.12 2 Sauce nan Cjsi aluminum 7.575 4.750 ¦) 6.77 3 Sauce pan (ireen en.imel 7.250 4.250 3 7.60 4 Sauce pan White enamel 8.250 5.000 5 11.00 5 Siock leir/e Kol/eil aluminum 7.575 6.875 6 5.92 6 Sioct keltic Rolled .ihiminum 9,Wf) 6.875 8 7.60 7 Saucepan RnMe.l aluminum 5J75 4.250 2 ft Sauce run Roiled aluminum 4.375 3.250 1 I Sirl/et Cm jluminum 9.250 2.000 10 Skillet Cast iron, black 9.500 1.870 U Drip-drop roaucr [..in iron 9.000 4.250 5 .._ "~ L . lrnlll Wriishi " ! o Without . Wiih j Condition of horrom Lill /its pan cover cuier I «.¦ Ibi I O.")'ll \.l\" Recessed Tijlitly .* 1.672 2.273 Concave upward, jltghi Tightly, vapor seal * l sn* :.ii*i" Concave upward, great Poorly 4 1922 2.5 W. Concave upuanl. great Fairly well l 0.»2l 1.0.11 Concave upward, great Tightly, clamped (. 1.571 1.922 Recessed Tishtly It 554 n.tt&lt; Concave downward, ilishv Tightly v ri4in D.s:^ Hcccsscil Tightly 4 2.02 i Concave downward, great 11l 4 7V* Concave downward, great II 5»2» IT Flat Tightly OVENS STUDIED The essential features of the ovens studied are listed in Table 2. It will be noted that the ovens varied sufficiently in construction SO that several contrasting features could be investigated. In order to estimate the performance of an oven the following tests were made: (1) calibration of the thermostat, (2) preheat tests to determine the energy and time neces - sary to preheat an oven to a predetermined temperature, (3) heat loss of empty oven, (4) heat loss when oven door is opened, (5) rate of cooling of oven from an initial oven temperature of 550° F., (6) temperature distribution in the oven, (7) surface temperatures, (8) flue loss, and (9) actual baking, roasting, and broiling. Table 2. — Oven dimensions and essential features. Interior dimensions | Thermostat ) J Racks—all non-tilt type . V * * V Ij ' ' 1 ;i| i i is. s 5 = ?!¦§,* a¦ 4 ;1 Tv i"- Locauoi. £¦! j*-a »*¦; Ss-*s = c: g z¦- ¦ &gt; '-*- ; I ' pis \2l zjiz gjgjj In in. I* Cu. ft. h, ft'a. In. In. A Ift U 19 2.29 T"|&gt;—2 Carbon rwl. Lower led Fjir 5 I'A 2'i Side*— I «-nppcr (übe lidc it fronc B 16 I! 2ii 2AO II 16 &lt;:arl&gt;on rod. Back. Fair \M-VA \\i copper lube nenr (op 2W l C 16 14 IH'j 3. ,9 I 1 « Porcelain rod Top, at Fair 4 2fS I.i topper tube (rom D 16 M IN 1 1 2.21 I. Ri-mciallic Lower left Fjir VA IV* sirip side at from t IR 12 la 2.25 2 Cn-lxin rod. Top— % Excellent 8 9/16 &gt; I*B copper tube from front F lf&gt; IV, W, 2.W IS C.irl&gt;on roil, Boiiom. Poor 5 2ji VA copper lutic ai back 1 Intervals mcjturetl from ihe bouom between succestive rack positions roward the lop. 7 Bcrwcrn rhc fourth and fifrh nek position ihcrc is an interval of I*4 inches. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Selected Types of Gas Stoves ¦¦..'. broilers Although no technical studies were conducted upon the broilers in the various ovens studied, the broilers were given consideration. Such items as spacing of broiler racks, type of broiler pan, interior finish, ease of cleaning, and performance of broiling burner were observed by broiling large sirloin steaks. The essential dimensions of the broilers are given in Table 3. Broiler E had a separate broiling burner with the broiling com; partment over the oven. Broilers B, C, D, and F were built with drawer - type broiler compartments. In broilers A and E the broiler side walls and racks were stationary so that only the broiler pan was removable. It is obvious that the drawer-type blotter is more convenient to use. Table 3.- -Broiling compartment dimensions. I Interior dimcMioni ~~ ~~ Rack i n , cr »a, . Broiler ' j T ~ area 1 poiitions between Width I Height |. Dcpih ¦ rack! In. ';". In. In. Si.in. No. la. A 16 9 19 106.4 5 11/16 B-34 J 16 8 20 112.0 5' &lt;A C ¦ i 16 7 W/i 103.6 5 W D J 16 : 6&lt;/ 4 18(4 103.6 A 1 E =18 7. 18 113.5 .. . ¦ 6 9/16 F 16 W, K'A \M3 5 ?} 1 Drolling area—3s per cent of the cross-sectional area of broiler compartment in the broiling plane. 1 The data for B '35 were identical with thoie of B '3-1. . All of the broiling compartments were finished with porcelain enamel. The broiling trays varied from enameled pans with ordinary wire racks to aluminum and chromium finished pans with special types of racks. THE GAS SUPPLY USED IN THE TESTS The gas used for the tests was supplied by the lowa-Nebraska Light and Power Company. It was natural gas o£ heating value approximately 1,000 British thermal units per cubic foot and average specific gravity of 0.72. The gas comes to Lincoln from a mixing station at Clifton, Kansas. At this station the heating value is recorded continuously by a Thomas recording calorimeter. Since the heating value of the gas remains essen - tially constant, it was found that the daily average reading of this calorim - eter was sufficiently accurate for the computation of results of tests per - formed in the laboratory; A daily record of the heating value was kept and the average heating value over a period of one year was found to be 1,009 B.t.u. per cubic foot, with a variation amounting in some cases to about plus or minus one per cent. 3 This value of 1,009 B.tu. per cubic foot was used for the computation of results. 4 In the gas distribution system in Lincoln each consumer has a pressure regulator controlling the gas supplied to his equipment. The average 1 The daily average heating value was furnished through the cooperation of. the lowa-Nebraska ¦ Light and Power Company. ; ¦' ¦ ; _ * With a change of ±1 per cent in the* heating value the thermal efficiency mult* are affected by about only +0.5 per cent. - • '¦ ¦ : . .¦¦;¦¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 pressure used is about 4 inches of water. For the testing in the laboratory, however, a pressure of 7 inches of water was used. This follows the specifications of the American Gas Association Testing Laboratory. 0 In order to complete the analysis of some of the tests performed, it was necessary to know the composition of the gas. The composition does not remain constant, since it is necessary to change the mixture at Clifton, Kansas, with gases from different fields in order to maintain a gas of Fie. H. —A scctinn o( the laboratory showing the pressure regulator (extreme right), the mrtcr calibration tank, and the wet test meter. The hood and bottles at the stove were used to obtain samples nf flue gas from the surface burners. about constant specific gravity and heating value. However, for the com - putation of results it was determined that an average composition would ser\e the purpose. From the records at the meter testing station of |the Northern Natural Gas Company it was found that an average composition was 69 to 70 per cent methane (CR,); 16 to 17 per cent ethane (Q.H O ); about 1.5 psr cent oxygen (Qz); a trace of carbon dioxide (CO2); and about 12 per cent nitrogen (Nn)." The specific composition used for calculation of results is given later in the text. THF TYPE OF MEASUREMENTS INVOLVED An analysis of the surface burners and ovens requires three types of measurements, i.e., the measurement of gas volume, the measurement of 'Approval Requirements lot On Rancct. A. (&#132; A.. Cleveland. Ohio, 1931 and 1936. • The perecnliee tor elhane also include) mac of the lusher hydrocarbon!, principally propane (CsH«) anrl hmmc fC.Hio) </seg>
         <seg id="p013">; Selected Types of Gas Stoves a. w ¦ V. f f; Fig. 9.—A section of the laboratory showing the gas-analysis apparatus and the ¦V: cooling system. . V: temperatures, and the measurement of flue-gas composition. The apparatus !; used for the testing is shown in Figures 8 and 9. Briefly, the gas volume was measured by a 10-light wet-test meter operating at the normal pressure &gt;;; . of 7 inches of water. Changes in the specific gravity were obtained with ;;';¦ a calibrated fixed orifice. Barometric pressure was observed with an aneroid ;¦ barometer set to agree with those in the United States Weather Bureau 'i- ¦¦ office at Lincoln. All temperatures were-recorded with copper-constantan couples connected to a Leeds &amp; Northrup portable potentiometer. A Burrell Orsat apparatus was used to analyze the flue-gas samples for CO 2 v and 02,O 2 , while an iodine-pentoxide apparatus was used to determine the .;. CO content. All weighing was done on a Fairbanks beam-balance with : ; standardized weights ranging from 5 pounds to 1/16 ounce. A complete ¦ description of the laboratory and apparatus is given in Appendix I. ! I •¦;'&gt; SETTING THE ORIFICE FOR PROPER GAS RATE AND THE ADJUSTMENT Ij3" ; OF THE BURNER - ¦Ml Domestic gas burners are built to operate at a definite B.t.u. input and ;&gt; • as pointed out in the papers on burner design, the burner must be flexible ¦';&gt;./¦ ¦- enough to allow for various operating conditions and service. In this ::; investigation the essential dimensions of a correctly designed universal ;:J atmospheric gas burner as listed in Conner's paper in the A. G. A. ¦ Monthly have been used as a basis for all burner computations and analysis. These specifications are listed for reference in Table 4. Figure </seg>
         <seg id="p014">NtBRAsKA Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 10 is supplied as a further reference for the various burner terms used in Table 4. It is evident that the amount of gas consumed and the amount of. an required for complete combustion must be considered in the adjustment of the burner. In the laboratory the orifices were adjusted first to comply with the recommendations of the A. G. A. Testing Laboratory, namely that a regular surface burner shall be adjusted for an input of not less than 9,000 B.t.u. per hour, an oven burner for not less than 8,000 B.t.u. per hour for every cubic foot of oven space when the oven volume does not exceed 2.4 cubic feet, and a broiler burner for not less than 140 B.t.u. per hour per square inch of broiling area. Table 4.— Essential dimensions of atmospheric gas burners. Si. 'lem -;. „ 77^1 ~.M "" 20,000 \ Capacity H.i.u. s»i. in. |ion jic.i .... 3C (Vifl J (.ipactti- H.i.ii. m. in. cMi-wctianll am Iwrner head »,uuu i. Suggested port sue M. T. I). 3j K.,.liu! ul mixer (arcduincler in inches) * t. Sin ol ihroat (per cent Icilal pan area) ™ 1,. M«pc of .lie mixing lutie. degrees r i.myth ol mixing tul&gt;c (umei throat diameter) " H. t'rou-wiluHul J'« of ntiKE chamber (limti area th(oul) */» I) J'ort spacing ccnlrr H) cemcr (times diameter of" port) * ID. \rca i&gt;t mixer opening, times tma\ port area Ordinarily the adjuster of an appliance in actual practice considers the rate of gas consumption as being only a function of the orifice area but in the laboratory adjustment the effect of change in specific gravity was also taken into consideration. The relation of pressure, specific gravity, and orifice area to gas rate is given by the usual hydraulic equation of discharge.' i| = Hi 50.5 Ka y h/tl 0) where q = the gas rale in cv. ft./hr. a = ihc orifice area in sq. in. h — the meter pressure in inches of water tl = specific jjravity (air = 1.000) X = the discharge coefficient It is evident then that a standard specific gravity must be chosen if a check of the gas rate should be desired under different conditions from those existing during the period at which the orifice was adjusted. For this work the standard chosen was the approximate average value 0.72. The orifice area was adjusted by timing the passage of one cubic foot of gas under the conditions given by the equation: time in scc./cu. ft. t.f ca s burned = 3600/q X corr. factor (2) By this method the gas rates were adjusted to within 0.5 per cent of the values given in Table 5. This is quite in contrast to the A. G. A. require - ments which allow a variation of plus or minus 5 per cent. TThe more eiact equation for the efflux of gaiej through small orifices is treated Extensively in Bureau o( Standard. Scientific Paper 359. but since the differential pressure at the orifice is small and .he pipe diameter larue compared to the orifice diameter, the hydraulic equation instead of the liliahmic equation of discharge may be applied with very little error. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Ii ':¦-¦'..' Selected Types of Gas Stoves Finally one more factor had to be Considered in adjusting the orifice -.; for the proper gas rate. It was discovered early in the experimental work c that the gas rate was affected by a change in the temperature of the gas. This, of course, can be accounted for by the effect of temperature upon ; the viscosity and the density. 8 As far as efficiency is concerned, this : decrease in gas rate does not alter the calculation but a comparison of the S time of heating of one test with another can not be made unless the gas &gt; | rate remains the.same for each test. It was found by experiment that it i- ¦ ¦ Table s.—Bj.u^inputs used for surface and oven burners, ¦:.. Type Risht front Left front Left rear Right rear Oven Broiler ¦i burner burner burner ' burner burner burner liii KY~m | . G w v ,«".-.¦.. ..coo ,5,000. &amp;y -^SSL. .: ¦ ' H 9,000 . 9,000 . '.'.'.'. '"¦". ; f . ) 9,000 ..... .'.'.'.'.' r would be easier to correct the times of heating to some common base than •;• to attempt to keep the gas temperature 1 constant. Since room temperature g; .was maintained at 75° F. during the surface-burner tests, this temperature V was chosen as the base for calculation; Thus, during the adjustment of ¦jl the orifice area care was exercised to maintain the orifice at 75° F. ;; In all cases the air shutter was opened wide enough to produce a hard sg.; flame without causing lifting from the ports. - 1 : Table 6.—8.U1. rating of surface burners computed from dimensions ;: ¦ of burners. 1 .,. •&gt;« I -lag I I g [,&amp; '. . »¦•"" ¦ . ¦' ' i! ' In. ¦ tn. In. Sq.in. Smi!'" 1? Circular 46 ¦ N0.38 .... ... 03721 7743 y ' circular 2,° 6 %^, ¦•......:::&gt; SiSI lf&lt;[ .; -' c Di«-a,t Rwtaneular M' i' 9/32 5/« '.'.'.'. 0.4W5 9,950 ¦4 2 Die-ait Reconguiar « ."'... 3/32 7/M !!.'.' 0.4512 - 9024 ' I ?S V » S. reul":. 71 3/32" ••• ¦ 0-&lt;9°B 99JS \ . -P; Ribbonflame Slit 5/12S 1 I3'i 0517fi iS G 8-arm rcdlar Circular .47 ' NoVi* '!. "' 0' v S»6 . G B ;a rm B ian, Circular ' H No. 36 ........ ' " I"; o.SlfiS 10.M6 ; . 11— J Circular 61 No. 36 0.5435 10,870 :¦? The slit height varied between 1/32" anil 3/64"; the average ij used in the table. It was found during the study that some burners would not operate I satisfactorily on the gas rates specified in the A. G. A. approved require - : ments. Using the data supplied in Table 4, the burners were analyzed y and the B.t.u. rating determined from the dimensions of the burner. The v results of this analysis for both surface and oven burners are listed in Tables 6 and 7. This analysis proved very helpful when studying low : ; oven temperatures. .-...¦ I LiS^fAt-SSSS^n £ ; h«£ A"b^er! Kharw CKfficicnt btauK of *= «""" </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 7.-8.1. U. rating oj oven burners computed jrom dimensions oj burners. —— —¦ ¦ ; Rating—B.l.u./hr. Interior dimension! ; Measured T°"' Computed Computed 1 1 ' i Volume ' • 'drill ,i« P°" foe from Type- i I | P°™ area normal oven Width ; He.k-hi | Depth i b uin cr tin , '; ','i ',"., '&gt;j«r &lt;h s,,v, im«h I7JM HUM ! No. « „ „, h jii :.«.; l« N°'.M I.«H M.«» IM* &lt;- „, n is', 2w ii 4" "V'u" n.nm w.*B 19.112 „ ,„ m ia .. :.i!T i* nS'.'lj i.w a*»° IWM f &#132; |. I, &gt;J« l"i No.j!' 1.(1692 «JW "¦OM F „, ,} , vr, &gt;.«&gt; .'« NVW IJJM .«.7»6 19.136 ' lh» &gt;jlw imlafc." 6« l«*i« •hKh mm climawl ¦« I" kli&gt;&gt;»Jb« i» ¦¦ 'lit in 'I" 1"-"1"- TESTS WITH SURFACE BURNERS THERMAL EFFICIENCY AND TIME OF HEATING FOR SHORT-TIME TESTS Method of procedure.—Covered pans 1 to 8 were used for these tests, with 4 pounds of water in each of pans 1 to 6. Since the capacities ot pans 7 and 8 would not permit the use of 4 pounds of water, pans 7 and 8 were used with 3 pounds and \'/ 2 pounds of water respectively. The tempera - ture change of the water was taken from 75° F. to 200° F. Thus any oss due to evaporation near the boiling point of water could be disregarded. These temperatures were recorded by a copper-constantan thermocouple in - serted through the plug in the cover and projecting to within one-halt inch II \iwer Head vjjr--—'gurner FVirta Fig. 10.—Domestic-type atmospheric burner. from the bottom of the pan." With the operating pressure at 7 inches of water, the volume of gas needed and the time required to br.ng about this 125° F temperature change were recorded. This procedure was repeated for gas pressure one-half normal, and 1% normal, namely 3.5 inches o£ water • Finerimtim ihownl thai ihe tcmpcrarorei mawrcd by one """pit were the lame as time m a,ureT.T"nree copies connected in parallel when the three couple, were arranged » that one wm nea he oum.le one in ihe cen.er. and one between the center and oulude wall of the pan. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">¦¦¦' Selected Types of Gas Stoves and 8.75 inches of water respectively. These tests were all performed with the burners secured in.the stoves )ust as the stoves were received;from the ¦ manufacturers. ¦ I :-v- Since evaporation was neglected, the efficiency was calculated by the I 1.; simple formula :¦".' . ! j ; pc.cn.aKc of thermal effiaency - 8 , t . u . /cu , f t . XQ X c(. ./ .! ¦•¦¦¦' where W = weight of water in pounds . ' ¦•' ...''• . w = water equivalent ofutensil 10 : '",•' Ti = initial temperature of water, degrees Fahrenheit Ta = final temperature of water, degrees Fahrenheit i ¦ Q '= gas consumption as shown by meter, cv.ft. , j :¦" c.f. = correction factor to reduce observed gas volume to 30 inches , ..-'¦ '..-.;¦ ot mercury pressure at 60° F. . ¦'. After determining the efficiency in the above manner, modifications ; were made in the burner application to increase the efficiency and still i ;'¦ have a safe burner with respect to the formation of carbon monoxide. ;,/'¦' In order to compare the time of heating of different burners it was necessary to reduce all time data to a common basis. By inserting two thermocouples in the gas manifold and securing one couple to the orifice ; cap of the gas cock, it was found that comparable readings were obtained -on all three for any one condition of heat in the burner box, thus showing : j that the temperature of the orifice cap represented the temperature of the ';, gas in the manifold within the burner box of the stove. The position of these couples is shown in Figure 11. Thus, to obtain the necessary data for the temperature correction the method was adopted of fastening a thermo - couple, by means of a narrow strip of electrician's tape, to the orifice cap I of the burner valve. An open pan having a bottom 9 inches in diameter i . ! V—— Thtrmocoufkt ¦ y if¥^ : \ ifil Thti Ikrmouufk. .-¦ - fap^^J . \ ||/»cureJ to (of harm 7 Fie. ill.—Position of thermocouples for temperature correction data. "The value 0.124 for ihc specific heal of ihe enameleil pans was determined by experiment.. Sec Ncbr. A(!r. Exp. Sla. Bui. 68, A study of five commercial electric stoves, 1933. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 and containing about 5 pounds of water was placed over the burner. When the gas was ignited the heat reflected from the bottom of the pan was sufficient to cause the gas in the manifold to become heated. The time for successive passages of one cubic foot of gas through the burner was recorded, together with the rise in temperature of the gas-cock orifice cap, these readings being taken at two-minute intervals. From these data a gas-rate-temperature curve could be plotted showing the decrease in gas rate with increase in orifice-cap temperature, i.e., with increase in gas temperature. Since the curve was found to be rectilinear, it was extended until it intersected the 75° F. abscissa and the correspnding gas rate was read from the graph. Each gas rate was divided by the gas rate at 75° F., thus giving a series of values for the correction factors to be used to reduce the time to the basis of a gas temperature of 75° F. By plotting these correction factors against the corresponding orifice-cap temperature, the correction factor for any orifice-cap temperature could be read from a graph. Results.—lt has been pointed out earlier in the paper that the burners tested were chosen particularly because of their design and application. These surface burners fitted into the original plan of investigating as many factors as possible which might affect the efficiency of the burner. Before efficiency tests were started the following factors were enumerated as possibly having some influence on the efficiency: (1) the quantity of water heated, (2) the size and the material of the utensil, (3) the use of long and short injector tubes on the burner, (4) the distance between the grate and the burner, (5) the type of grate, (6) the control of excess air by using air plates, fire bowls, and burner pans, (7) the use of gas rates varying from 5,000 B.t.u. per hour to 12,000 B.t.u. per hour, and (8) the construction of the stove top. A few preliminary tests showed that with gas stove burners the efficiency would be the same whether 1 pound or 4 pounds of water were used for the test. The latter quantity was chosen because the longer time involved would tend to decrease errors produced by small differences. The fact that efficiency is independent of the quantity of water is due to the fact that a gas burner may be considered as operating from a hot start almost immediately, in contrast to an electric unit which requires a pre - heating of the unit before much heat is delivered to the pan. 11 Before continuing with the remaining factors, the characteristics and dimensions of the various cooking tops and the efficiencies of the burners should be considered. These are listed in Tables 8, 9, 10, and 11. The averages of all these efficiencies are shown in Table 12 and the averages for pans 1 to 6 are listed in the last column. These values would indicate what efficiencies may be expected in general for each type of burner and 11 Recently it has bern pointed out to the author by a member of the research staff of the A. G. A. that although the gas burner docj operate almost immediately from a hot start, it is their laboratory practice to initially heat the burner and grate with an auxiliary pan of water before starting efficiency tests. This practice was not followed in the tests performed in this laboratory and may account for part ot the small variations in efficiency found for the same pan when used on front and rear burners adjusted for the tame conditions of operation. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Selected Types of Gas Stoves • S.Sggt BBS So 0888 . a s.a"l ¦ . ..' ¦;."•. BJitsl 4-s 5:.*.'.» s **** 2~0.a5 ¦ - " """ Sl* -8 ¦-.;. . -•¦; ¦.¦¦•.; ¦.-.¦ f j:.s IS v ¦sr ¦¦«¦ •¦ -|i ¦--.¦¦¦ ¦,¦¦-.•¦ '¦ ¦; • -- tN OO O OS :A S?Ot W • a — "- ¦" ¦ ¦¦¦' ¦'. ' ;/ n» s ':¦¦¦¦¦' ¦'¦"-¦ '¦ ¦¦¦¦¦ "i .5 „ c- c ~ g s^s v O 2'^ ___ ¦¦¦-.. .. _ o 8f B £ ¦¦¦¦¦ ..¦.-¦..¦ -....¦' S Ji " 5.« :S " ¦ ¦'.« : S . -.¦JS.X 3 ¦•§ ¦ - s- i,J5' S ¦ S ¦ S s*» : S Tr ' ¦ ¦ '¦!&gt; ' S ° H ¦ ¦ i - .8' c ¦ ¦ 3 -.8 fi ¦ ¦;i g^ I •¦ ! •§ 1 ' I • .•s'. -51 -5 ¦ £ \.JL ill i P jlilj I- |«a. ; fi« ¦;.«,:¦ «-.; -• • s S I . s i.-2 5 SI S :8, -..-a : : .S •I "-: » : S S"- .' - g&gt;. is/g' ..;•¦ "2 T I • r'-1-1* viy^Ml : J ft!!, If 1^ :¦ j • I] I! I:¦ f fi X iff! • : I I", li :.;. .« « X « 'Q o o&lt;&gt;"O -3^ g, . &lt; a O Q w v. UK— P - ¦¦¦' ' ¦ ¦ ¦ " •' : .&lt;¦"¦' ¦¦.':'¦ 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 9.— Percentage efficiency for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,000 8.t.u./hr. and operating at normal pressure, 7.0 inches water. , Position i I I 1 T&gt;(* | of j Pan 1 i Pan 2 Pan 3 I Pan -I P.in ¦&gt; I Pan 6 !&gt;.in 7 Pjn 8 burner ' ; : ¦ i I'.tt. I'-tl f-tt f.tl. t'.tt. Pxl. i'.tl. l'.ct. A 1.. R 15.20 40.80 10.25 44.75 37.15 44.40 29.40 21.05 A I. F. 37.20 36.10 37.80 40.40 39.50 43.80 .... B 14 1. R. 411.4 D 40.20 41.40 44.75 39.80 41.75 H 14 I R 41)00 41.45 41.00 45.50 41.50 47.20 [I 15 R K. i8.!0 59.90 39.50 42.40 38.70. 44.00 29.E0 27.00 C 1.. R 14.20 W. 50 37.40 40.M) 34.40 36.11) C. 1. f 16.18 18.60 35.84 36.58 35.22 40.20 31.25 22.90 1&gt; R R 35.01 40.10 40.10 45.35 37.57 42.70 I) X F. 35.90 m.70 37.80 45.10 37.70 43.31) 33.1)0 29.00 X » c. 29.911 11.20 31.90 35.50 34.10 38.80 20.20 15.W F S I. 32.112 37.2(1 32.80 33.40 35.60 39.30 F R f. 41.r,i 42.45 47.42 44.85 41.60 44.00 (. R f&gt;(&gt;s 16.25 18.96 42.50 33.95 38.40 (. f (1 :ci »« X..50 W.dO 31.40 34.M II » 15.i1l C.25 17.40 37.10 35.40 37.50 If I- Ivin (1.2H 17.60 37.40 36.90 36.60 I i) (. 12 4' l"»l 16.110 40.60 3&lt;&gt;.»o ¦(1.00 " .... I S (. U7II W.WI 11..511 17.76 34.70 39.00 t R Irtt TiMr. I I~- led Irnul. (&gt; (&#132;= op-t&gt; nr.tlc. R.= tear. K. R.= nß^r tc.it. R. F.= nj;ht ;r.,ni S (, - ...lul cr.iic. I — mmi -Humrr .iiliii^tnl h.f I2.'»i" H-i v prr h.mr uipilt Table 10.— Percentage efficiency for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,001&gt; B.t.u. hi: and operating at one-half normal pressure, 3.5 inches water. I'uMt &lt;.n I l\|&gt;r i&gt;i l'.,n I ['.in? I.in 1 Km 4 I.m 5 I'.tn 6 ! Pan 7 ! Pan 8 hiirnrr /',; /¦,/ /',/ /'./ /'../ /'.(/. I.a. ;¦.,;. \ I. R 1! Til KI.WI 17 4(1 45 2i 42.50 45.3! 33.17 32.20 \ I. f. 14 5(1 41 «li 4(1.0(1 45.K1 14,l»l 41.00 B 14 I. R 414" h.Ki 41411 45.211 411.20 43.20 B 14 I. I- IV4II 4(14" &lt;•) HI 42.611 19.211 44.50 C 1. R *Tln I&gt;*.Wl IC&gt; wi 1'1.9*l 36.111 42.fi0 C I. X CWI 42 2H 16.2(1 4(1.5(1 16.1 d 44.70 0 R R 16 Ml 42.1K1 41 111 46.911 14 411 43.40 I) H ¥. 1" In 4145 41l'i 45.611 411.40 45.60 E II (. ii.li W.lll 14.*( 16.7(1 16.65 36.60 E S (&#132; 11 H5 411.411 17 51) 16.90 15.3(1 38.60 F R.F. 471K1 4T.4H 49.25 50.25 44.10 51.25 (, R. IMHI 17.3H 16.25 19.55 15.75 411.20 G f.' 11.611 111" 16.i1l 16.25 34.15 15..95 H R. 14.411 14 15 16.1' i 11.42 33.75 37.00 H l; 11411 17 m 16.Ml 19.55 14.75 37.10 I Cl (&#132; 34.211 i'MII 13-MI .19.6(1 34.W1 39.40 1 Hiirncr .i.ltuMr.l fur I2.'M'i Bin per hour nipui </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Selected Types of Gas Stoves " . -V. .' ': ¦¦ .-.•; I ¦••.." - Table 11.— Percentage efficiency for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,000 8,t.u./hr. and operating at I'A normal pressure, 8.75 inches ; water. .'..'.-... ¦..' ' I Type Poiiuon p, n i T , nl Pan 3 I Pan* PjnS Pan 6 of burner | ¦- ¦- " |- j P.cl. i&gt;.«. ' f.rt. Pet. ¦ P.tl. P.cl A L. R. 32.00 38.55 40.25 45.42 34.20 39.42 A L.F. 34.00 38.90 38.20 • 45.50 36.50 41.90 IH L. R. 42.00 ¦¦¦ 43.80 &gt; 13.90 &lt; 45.60 34.40 35.45 834 L.F. 35.80 3«.«0, «.7O ¦ ¦ 48.40 42J00 47*1 C ' L:R. 29.90 37.00 34.63 i 39J0 37J0 40.00 C L.F. 32.40 37.00 35.C0 | 41.25 34.03 ' 40.43 D . R. R. .32.55. 39.201 39.60 45.00 38.50 43.50 I) ¦ R.F. 35.00 40.30 41.40 : 45.10 37.55 43.70 F. O. G. 32.30 37.40 32.20 | 37 JO 35.90 37.15 E S.G. 31.55 36.40 32.65 ,38.00 . 34.75 39.65 F R. F. 42.00 - 44.50 45.40 , 43.80 : 39.00 3950 G R. ¦ . Would not operate at this prewurc O F.» 32.75 36.00 35.75 , 36.90 31.40 3250 H. . R. 34.60 36.70 37.30 I 37.90 35.20 36.10 11 F. 34.20 37 JO 35.35 ' 39.10 35.60 37.30 I O. G. 32.65 3«.90 37.60. . 37.50 35.80 40.30 1 {turner adjusted for 12,000 B.t.u. per hour input. , . , .... application when using pans varying from 3 to 8 quarts in capacity. From the efficiency tables it is immediately' apparent that the efficiency is a function of the pan used, the highest efficiencies being obtained with the 5-quart pan 4 and the 8-quart pan 6, and the lowest with the 1-quart pan 8. Further, these tables show that a consideration of the effect of long and short injector tubes upon the efficiency may be eliminated because a higher efficiency is obtained with a rear burner as often as with a front burner on the same stove. Variations in efficiency must be accounted for by other means than the difference in length of injector tubes. The other principal factors which cause this variation are the distance between the burner and the bottom of the pan, the type of grate, the kind of stove top, and excess air. ' :.'."¦;','' This.may be exemplified by comparing different types. For instance, type B and lype F. list ¦ the highest. efficiencies and types E and H the lowest. From Table 8 it is evident that the burners on types B and F are closer to the pan than those, of types E and H. However, the dif - ference in distance between the pan and burner does not entirely account for the variations in efficiency. Other items of contrast are the type of grate and the stove top. The type E top is of very heavy iron (enameled finish) with rather heavy solid and semi-solid grates, while the type F top is a heavy-gauge, enameled, sheet steel with burner bowls and a rather light-weight grate. It seems that much more heat is absorbed by the type E top than by the type F, and this, of course, reduces the efficiency, since not as much of the heat delivered,by the burner is available to be absorbed by the pan and water. Variations in efficiency between one stove and another must be analyzed by considering compositely all such factors as distance between pan and burner, the type of grate, the use of fire bowls and burner trays, and the construction of the. stove top, including the •¦ ¦¦¦ .¦; ¦ . :¦' i ¦ .. :';¦". '. :: /.: -: ...¦¦..- ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agr. Exp. St.i. Research Bulletin 86 Table \2—Average percentage efficiencies for Types A to ], with pans 1 to 6. __ =zt^ - -= i | I Average T &#132;„, Pan 2 Pmi Pan 4 Pan 5 Pan 6 for pans 1 1 MOO 77, I.i P.ci. Pa. I'M. /'.«. I'" , M &gt;&#132; i 9 21 M.IK 44.38 38.36 42.64 39.65 fi-N iViilP 4(1.44 41.511 48.00 J9.52 43.81 41.59 835 W.6S 40.40 40.60 44.20 39.65 43.80 41.22 r 14.29 I*Bl 15% .19.72 35.55 40.66 37.50 y, ".,' 4029 4(1.51 4X.17 38.52 43.70 4\.09 t ,;¦.«, «,9S 31.64 36.30 35.38 38.34 35.52 F jV,-5 44.7* 47.15 44.72 41.53 45.03 44.49 , &#132;«, V, »i if, 77 17 60 4\.n2 34.H5 39J0 3/.56 ,'.l2m, HJS wSI &lt;6.25 37.23 MJJ 3456 34.79 &#132; MM «,&lt;)( W..66 .17.41 55.26 36.93 36.28 I uu «;« J5.97 M.87 35.52 39.92 36.99 weight and kind of material. To produce the highest efficiency, the loss of heat by conduction, convection, and radiation in the stove itself must be reduced to a minimum. The effect of change in gas rate upon the efficiency is not apparent with the efficiencies arranged in their present order. The percentage efficiencies for type F surface burners adjusted for gas rates of 5, 6, 7, and 9 cubic feet per hour and operating at normal, one-half normal, and 114 normal pressures are listed \n Table 11. The average for all the efficiencies for each pan arc listed at the bottom of the table. Similarly, in Table W are listed the percentage efficiencies for type B surface burners adjusted for gas rates of 6, 7. «, and 9 cubic feet per hour and operating at normal pressure. It will be noted that the right front burner was operated for one Table \S.—Percentage efficiency for Type F surjace burners adjusted for gai rates oj 5, 6, 7, and 9 cv. It., In: and operating at normal, one-half normal, and /'&lt; normal pressure. tw.nti i..i»"&gt;ic. ' VroMirc, |&#132;,, | p..,,, J ]'&#132;„&lt; l'.,n 4 Pan 5 ' I'jn d &#132;„.,. i.in v, l&lt; hr in. U..HT /',.• .". /',: /'-./ /'.«. I'll X l „ , ,"! -Tiki 44.5 m 45 4n 4i.SO 39.00 39.90 J j „,», "Ml 41 (.5 42 41 47 42 44.H5 41.60 44.C0 I, p &#132; If, Isn 47I«1 47.40 49.25 50.25 44.00 51.25 , . ; m 5.75 X 2ii 47.40 43 60 511.40 MM 50.60 if : (HI -in 4;-II 41 i«l 47 00 4G.70 42.00 48.50 I l i.. H lin 41V m «.in 49.M1 53.70 48.30 47.30 i r (.-2 ».:i 41.M1 45.10 45.50 51.20 45.70 49.60 I v (, in", 7mj Jj ')D 46 Tti 44.«" 46.«0 44.75 46.70 ," V 4J5 -1511 4.1.1(1 41.B" 48.70 46.50 45.00 49.80 J R sJ/l n;s 42 00 41.40 43.40 48.20 42.00 50.30 KR SJ» 7"" 4MH 45.40 46.70 52.40 40.60 48.70 RH jK 111' 45 40 41.811 511.70 51.40 48.40 42.10 Vrr«f ¦"'" 4'('" '•"-20 '"iB ¦(3''s '*'¦'"' set of tests at 6 inches of water pressure. This happened by accident, but since the results are as valuable as the others, they are included. From these tables the most obvious conclusion to be drawn is, that if no mechan - ical change is made in the construction of the burner in the stove, the efficiency will be the same whether a high or low gas late is used. What, </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Selected Types op Gas Stoves then, is to determine the choice of gas rate? There are two important factors, time of heating and safety. Table 14.— Percentage efficiency for Type B surface burners adjusted for gas rates of 6, 7, 8, and9cu. ft./hr. and operating at normal pressure. |SE, ta%.|jK£J 1 I &gt;"» 1 r*°3 *"&lt; I »«» I*ZI M I Pans l.a. Pei. i:a. P.,i. p.ii. r x ,, /..„, Pet ¦"*• W.? 38.10 39.80 41.20 45.70 38.80 43.00 37 10 35 60 ¦£•£• ™ J 38.40 41.20 39.00. UM 38.50 42.80 35.0 29$ S-E- ™ * •¦" «•«&gt; 1030 44.40 42.60 45.50 » 30.90 28.50 ?•£• »° I 39.90 40.60 43.40 45.30 39.80 44.40 3020 26 70 "•"¦ 9.0 7" 38.30 39.90 39.50 42.40 38.70 44 00 2980 27 90 A""EC - -, . 38.65 40.40 40.60 44.20 39.65 ti.gQ liTl BSS 1 Tan not centered on burner. . ~ ' ¦ : The time o£ heating for type B burners is shown in Table 15. These are the time-of-heating data corresponding to the efficiency tests listed in Table 14. The results are obvious and need no explanation. Table 16 is a table for type F burners corresponding to Table 13. All'of the corrected time-of-heating data are listed in Tables 17, 18, and 19. These tables are significant, for they show that when burners are adjusted for the same input, those having the highest efficiency willdo the same amount ot useful work in the least time. ¦ '. . . Table 15.-^-T,ime of heating for Type B surface burners adjusted for 6, 7, 8, and 9 at. ft./hr. operating at normal gas pressure—time shown in minutes and seconds. 1 . : Burner Gai rate, Pressure, „ . . i n' , „ . ¦ position cv. ft./hr. in. water ' ™"2 P4n 3 Pan"( Pa"s Kn6 i r«7 . ?»» \"f fa 7 }?'?•* m" 8 13' ° ""54 13.-t7.6U-0 10-44 5-39 8 ;•£•.:.- 10.I 0. "¦•?..: "-s:&gt; "-'-I 12-2-8 10-59.5 12-7.4 11-15 9-55 6-12 If' io ¦¦¦*'"¦ "- 1(M" 10J7(i W0 '-18-8 9^&lt;?"o-8.6 5-39 R« 9 0 ¦¦-"•.?¦ SSI o\U 8M BM-2 9-14 1 9"12 w7-8 5-36 i "•"¦ 9-° ¦' 7 9-14.4 9.27.2 9-4 8-38.2 9-20.4 8-36 8-59.8 4-53.6 'Miniiics io-the left of hyphen, iKondi to the* rii-hi. " ~~ ~~- ! 3 Pan not ccntcretl on. burner. . ¦ . '. . Previously it was shown that the factor for correcting the time of! heating was dependent upon the gas-cock temperature and the gas rate It_is evident that if no other factors are modified, a decrease in gas rate will increase the time of heating of like thermal masses through the same Table 16.— Time of heating for Type F surface burners adjusted for 5 6 7, and 9 cv. ft./hr. operating at normal gas pressure—time shown in minutes 'and seconds. ; . . . Burner Gat rate. i&gt; i I n i ~ ¦ ~ po.ition ai. ft./hr. .n-' | ''"2 p *n 3 Pan 4 Pan 5 Pan 6 Pan 7 "' ' ''" «5 !iS !!JS E \ii | </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 17 .—Corrected time for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,000 8.t.u./hr. and operating at normal pressure, 7 inches of water— time shown in minutes and seconds. Typ«!Bu'ncl P"l I""3 Pa"&gt; Pa"4 Pa"s Pjn6 T"'7 T'Oi pot 11 io ii —— , L „ &#132;49 9- 0 8-42 7-58 9-19 7-15 8-37 4-10 B t? "-50 9-44 MJ «¦&lt; 9-M W6 n RR 915 8-W 8-29 7-41 8-59 8-20 B .3 .« a s ii "-251 8-36 E S.C. 11-JH 9M 10-41 IOHB 9-56 9-15 .. a r »°' 10-2 10-27 9-12 8-34 10-26 9-40 0 "&gt; 7.56 «-l. 7-20 6-57 8-32 8-0 ° , ,il 1,17 9-35 9-40 10-2 9-58 " F Oil 10.10 9.2. 9-45 10-25 10-10 , o.C. 10-45 9-21 9.53 8-56 9-37 8-59 I S.G. 10-32 9-27 9-47 9-41 10-16 9-54 ' (irait coM. J Grate healed 'Burner idjusied /or jai rale of 12.1X10 8.i.u./hr. Table 18.— Corrected rime for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,000 BJM./hour. and operating at one-half normal pressure, 3.5 inches of water—time shown in minutes and seconds. Twc »u, TC . ' &#132;,„, | P,r,2 Par, 3 P." 4 Par, 5 Pan 6 &#132;.,, p 6 12-H I"'" 13"1(i l2'lo • ;- W ' H J» " i b ss r, :| C '¦„ f; M 113 10-IS 12-28 IM6 » J l « JW f I I | I I I • Pini 1 Jnci 4 were rcpeatej with the B "'e healed. • Burner a d;u..cd for E« ra.e of 12,000 8.1.v. per hour. temperature change. The following explanation is presented as the reason for the change in gas rate with increase in gas temperature. As heating is continued on the surface burners, the gas manifold in the burner box increases in temperature. Because of the heating of the gas, the viscosity is increased and the density decreased, so that the complete effect is to decrease the discharge coefficient of the orifice. For Urge on&amp;ces such as are used in commercial metering of gases, the orißce is operating in a region of turbulent flow and a change in viscosity has no effect, but for </seg>
         <seg id="p025">/: '; i Selected Types of Gas Stoves small orifices such as are used on gas cocks on ranges, any change in the viscosity of the gas will affect the rate of flow. An analysis of data for a type A burner showed that the orifice was operating in a region of viscous, turbulent flow where a change in viscosity has an effect on the discharge coefficient; This region of flow was determined by comparing the "dis - charge coefficient—Reynolds number" curve obtained with that of Hodg - son. 12 These data are presented in Appendix IV. : From the time-of-heating data in Tables 15 and 16 it is evident that heating can be accomplished in the shortest time with the highest gas rate. The final choice of gas rate, however, should depend primarily upon safety. It; will be noticed from Table 23 that the type F construction operating at a gas rate of 9 cubic feet per hour at normal pressure pro - duced carbon monoxide in excess of what was assigned as allowable. With a decrease in the gas rate to at least 7 cubic feet per hour the burner was safe to operate. Thus in determining the proper gas rate a compromise must be niade between time of heating and safety. In making the final choice rapid heating must be sacrificed for safety. . After completion of the tests on the various types as received from the manufacturer, attempts were made to improve the efficiency by modifying certain constructional features. In some cases conditions were modified to show that the type of burner and application as tested were best. The whole question of improving efficiency revolves around the use of small utensils such as the 3-quart pan 1, the 2-quart pan 7, and the 1-quart pan 8. The data in Table 9 show that the efficiencies for these pans are very much lower than for the larger pans. Much of the work on the improvement of efficiency was conducted with the larger-sized utensils. The reason for this was the fact that pans 7 and 8 were purchased for testing after most of the efficiency data had been obtained. It would seem, however, that if the efficiency were greatly improved for the large pans it would also be improved for the 1-quart and 2-quart pans. To show the effect.of excess air upon the efficiency, types A and G were chosen, and to show the effect of modifying grate construction, types . E and F were used. The results of these tests are listed in Table 20. It is evident from the data for types A and G that the efficiency is improved when excess air is controlled. This has been recognized by many manu - facturers so that most of the recent range constructions embody some form of excess air! control. However, not all of the construction controlling excess air improves the efficiency, because much of the heat from the burner is conducted to other parts of the stove by the burner pans and burner bowls; thus in reality the efficiency is decreased. To offset this it must be noted that!,burner pans and burner bowls serve another function and that is to improve the ease of cleaning. Perhaps for this one feature alone a slight sacrifice in efficiency is worth while. An example of the change in efficiency by removing the burner bowl is given in Table 20 under P ap m\°l92s. * * b"" °l *". mcaiuremcllt ' J- !•• Hodemn, In.l. Civ. Ei^. Sefcctai Entering </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agr. E.vp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 T,ble W.-Corrected time for surface burners adjusted for an input of 9,000 8.t.u./hr. and operating at PA normal pressure, 8.75 inches of water—time shown injninutesandjeconds. - ;" Bu;,, " " w " 1..U | F..1 j *•« ! *"5 | Pan&lt;i . illll I 1 | | l «•«¦ «•" J-'S f.* i-M 8-17 7-17 " X f !w I'll ?¦* »¦!« 8"57 8-2? k &lt;&gt;&lt;¦¦ 'V "Ji 9. 2 i W« 8"58 B's « ,L] 5 S 1 Si • Burner ..liu.ir.l I"' (J&lt; ¦•'« "' l!-'"" "'" '"" '""" ,vneV With the type F burner it is more economical to remove the grate 5 set pans of jjjan or smaller capacity directly on the burner. Th.s vp t o burner was constructed so that this could be done The effect of changing the distance between the grate and burner is .Iso shown n Table 20 under type F.» k was necessary to change the dis^ce Ween the burner and pan because of the production^c *CQ ,o. been 3 These blocks acted as insulators between the grate and Itove to P ,To that the conduction loss through the cooking top was dCCTt awill be noted in Tables % 10, and 11 that the efficiency oi: the type E b mi wls the lowest of any of the types as received from the manu - facturer The data in TaWe 20 sUow how tms type of bumev and appli a ion an be improved by merely changing the grate. With the cooking op a" constructed much "of the heat delivered by the burner ,s aborted by the cooking top. Naturally this type of top is very rugged, but .dfc icncy has Wen sacrificed for rugged construction. In a region where gas s inex- Insw th aenfice may not be important but where the gas rate ,s high, efficient operation should be given preference to extremely rugged con- StrUFina nily there is the problem of improving the efficiency for small pans. This may be accomplished by decreasing the gas rate and raising the Ju er nearer to the bottom of the pan. In all cases where this was tried ih efficiency was greatly improved. Where other changes such as chang - ng o\ghte yr-we,ght grates was incorporated with the above Ganges he efficiency was further improved. Two examples o such changes are shown in Table 21. Type A was chosen because the burner had such a wide "~^Wto (he era* »,, r.i.ed (hrcefourth. of »n ,nch .he burner » a! »(c .. opera,,. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Selected Types of Gas Stoves - . . . •» .- :¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦ • ¦¦&amp;¦¦¦-¦ ¦':''¦. ¦ 4 ¦ ¦ •¦' I .So ¦¦; S ' ¦¦ : J ¦--,¦;¦ '¦£ : .i I! 'p ,i . - % It -IB} lIjO 111-i! .I 1 :: ti.M lillf lilui % * bSS S§ :' ; : :?S H¥??2 s — ¦¦ ;¦"/ ..V ;-.: ¦•: .. i ,*j ¦ ¦ ... ¦ . ¦ ' jE. ~^~ " '' '¦'¦"'¦ : ¦ Z tSS j : :SS 8BSS? I l — . ,;: . ;:-.:: ;.. | '1 iks %%.% '¦ '¦ :~' 2RS2iq.' ••*"¦¦• '..¦.¦' -I -¦:'¦' (3 ¦..¦¦' ; " - ¦¦¦¦'' "5 ¦-¦"¦¦• .--:•;¦ '-, • ho 5 t: SS. =.&lt;-;§ Sr,T»n "it.S 1-.". ii? £ £*i^-r ot-m, »^ff&gt;n —O *^«**l^lSEf §— — . • ¦ :.'.. '¦¦ ¦: . . o . j ..¦'.'¦:¦.. .-¦¦¦¦ % ii ¦ ¦ . ;¦.' . |, i H;.** ""'¦"•'¦"fr:'f^..-- CM W ¦ :• •¦. . ¦...:.¦¦... ¦ti s§ .. .'¦. .. .;... . ¦:¦ H So . a- a; JJ J: uJJcfiK htuKKCtf '¦ I .¦¦¦ ¦¦¦¦;¦ ." y ¦ ¦¦&#132;¦-;¦: ¦¦-.¦¦ St &lt;&lt; uuu u.o.'u.u.u. uuuou ¦ r- ¦, ¦. 27 </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 21.— Modification of efficiency by changing grate construction \or low gas rates. Type : X"""' ie " nK &lt; l\in I i Rin 7 Pan 8 Remarks l&gt;&lt;mll'in jcu. ft./nr. P.rl. Pxl. P.O. A I R. 4 36.40 Rq:uhr condition]. A Auxiliary 4 43.75 . . .... Grate similar to type A, yi inch from ports. table A Auufiary 4 48.10 . ... Type D grate, VA inches from ports. table A Auxiliary 4 51.50 . .. Light-weight wire grate, 15/16 inch from ports. table F 1.. F. r . . 28.30 Regular conditions. F 1.. V. : 37.00 32.40 Without grate, f 1.. R. 6 27.66 Rr^uJ.ir conditions. f 1.. R. 6 3K.70 33.40 Without K rate. F K. R. =) 29.50 Recul.ir conditions. F R R i 3HJ4 M.OO Wtthotn crate. burner-head area. Of course the results shown are a combination of change in distance between burner and top of grate and change of grate from heavy to light-weight type. The most remarkable change is shown in the type F burner. At present it seems that the most efficient operation is produced with this type of burner. The idea suggested by decreasing the gas rale and raising the burner closer to the pan bottom is to produce a burner on the gas stove similar in efficiency to the 1,000-watt unit on the electric stoves. Perhaps here again such a change is only vital in a region where gas is rather expensive. THERMAL EFFICIENCY FOR LONG-TIME TESTS For the long-time tests the 3-quart pan 1, the 5-quart pan 4, and the 8-quart pan 6 were used with the thermocouple adjusted as for the short-time tests. Four pounds of water was heated from an initial temperature of 75° F. to the boiling point with the burner operating at the full gas rate. After the boiling point was reached the flame was turned to such a height that the water would continue to boil gently, i£ possible, for the remainder of the hour test period. For those stoves having a simmer burner, the simmering flame was used whenever practicable. The usual data for gas consumption were recorded. Save for one or two exceptions, the gas burners were flexible enough in operation to maintain temperatures low enough to keep the water gently boiling. Thus the evaporation was reduced to such a minimum that this heat loss was neglected in computing efficiency. However, since the utensils were not perfect heat retainers, the heat necessary to maintain boiling was partially used to compensate the radiation and convection loss of the pan. In computing the long-time efficiencies this radiation and convection loss was included in the output. This loss for pans 1 to 6 was determined during a previous investigation by means of an immersion heater." The loss in B.t.u. per minute is given in Table 1. " A srudy of five commercial electric stoves, Ncbr. Agr. Res. Bui. 68, 1933. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">I; Selected Types of Gas Stoves ' The following formula was used to compute the long-time thermal efficiency: Percentage of thermal efficiency = p, tv /cv ft *X QX cf *"" \V = weight of. water, pounds . • ; w = water equivalent of utensil ' Tl = initial temperature of water, degrees Fahrenheit : T2 = final temperature o{ vraier, degrees Fahrenheit a = radiation and convection loss in B.tu. per minute ; . . t ¦== rime; in minutes that water boiled : : ; ;Q == gas consumption as shown by meter, cv. ft . . .. c.f. = correction factor to reduce observed gas volume to 30 inches : o£ mercury pressure at 60° F. ' The percentage efficiencies for the long-time heating ate listed in Table 22. A comparison of the efficiencies in Table 22 with the corresponding efficiencies in Table 12 will show-, that-the values are similar. ! The important feature to observe in long-time cooking tests is the use V of the simmer burner. Types 835, F, and G were equipped with simmer burners, with the simmer flame in the center of the burner for types B '35 and F and in one arm of type G. The advantage of the simmer burner is greater for small pans such as the 2-quart pan 7 and the 3-quart (¦: ¦ pan! than for the large pans such as the 5-quart pan 4. This is shown Table 22.— Percentage efficiency for long-time heating with surface burners ; operating at normal gas pressure. Type Burner G""l'- Pan I ' ftn-J Pan 6 . . .. ' location ¦ cv. ft./hr. . . ¦/,.... / /&gt;.«. P.ct. P.rt. A iL.R. ¦-. 9 34.60 «.9O 38.20 A L.F; 9 32.40 44.25 45.50 I: B-34 L.R. 9 33.90 «.85 B-34 L.F. 9 35.60 45.70 .... 835 'L.F. :':.:'¦', 7 '¦.;'¦¦ 41.80 40.75 1 .... C ..-¦.- : iL.R. • 9 30.30 37.20 •. C ¦¦' L.F. ;. 9 3010 36.70 D R. K. ,:¦¦¦.. 9 25.75 45.90 .... D : R.F; 9 . 30.40 34.80 31.10 •':¦" D R.R. - 9 30.50* E :O.G. 9 2«50 . 35.50 3UO E :S.G; 9 : 25.80 36.65 33.80 F L.B. 6 .... 44.75: 52.70 «.6O I.-.-.' F . R.R. 5 ¦¦;..¦- 41.80 50J0 14.60 'I ¦ P ¦"-..'.¦ L:F. 7 37.40 . 53J0 10.40 ! - G ¦¦-¦'¦¦¦¦• R. 9 ' .... 41.90 O ' - ' . ¦ R. ¦ ' ¦.-¦. 9 . : ¦ . .... 48.50' ;, -¦ O : ' ;P. ¦'-.- : ; 12 ' ...:"¦'- 48J0 g f. 12 :..;¦ 51.70' .... ,¦¦ '¦ H R. 9 21.40 3030 H F. 9 ¦.¦¦. 30.00 ¦ 32.60 : J O.G. 9 20.15 .... I S.G. 9 :... 35J0 :¦' . IThe simmer flame alone would not keep the water at the boiling point. . ' 3 Fhmc set so low h had to be watched constantly; violent boiling. ¦ .' ¦ . 'Uied air. plate from type A. ¦ . - -. -. by contrasting the values for type B '34 with type B '35. It is to be noted - that the simmering flame was not enough to keep the water in pan 4 at </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 |j [he boiling point on type B '35. Occasionally the entire burner had to be ;J turned to its lowest flame position. Considering the type D burner, it is | evident that higher efficiencies could have been obtained with pan 1 if j this burner had been equipped with a simmering flame. With the name : , set as low as possible, so that it had to be watched constantly, the water . | boiled violently. . , , ... \\ The inability of the simmer burner to maintain the water at the boiling ; point was demonstrated by actual cooking tests. As will be shown in a ; | later section, when whole potatoes were cooked in the enameled pan 4 the &#132; simmering flame was not enough to maintain a boiling temperature. This ;,. case was the only exception found. :&gt; HEAT DISTRIBUTION OF BURNERS ! j] The heat distribution of surface burners has been observed in such j various ways as the use oi sheet-iron plates, thermocouples, and baking 1;| griddle cakes, but the following method was found quite satisfactory and ;.; simple. A piece of blotting paper was cut to fit the bottom of the skillets &#132;- - listed in Table 1 and a wooden block three-fourths of an inch thick and ; ¦ j covered with asbestos paper was placed over the blotting paper. With both | burner and skillet initially cold, the gas was ignited with the burner 1 operating at the full gas rate. The iron pan was heated for four minutes ,| and the aluminum pan for live minutes and then the blotting paper was j removed." The scorch pattern formed furnished data both jfor the con- j ductivity of heat by the pan and —_^^ . | lor the heat distribution from the /"^i,*,^ I 1 burner. This method of obtaining / N. ' . | a scorch pattern was adopted, he- / / \^ \ | cause it was subject to the minimum / *"¥&lt;" *«'¦¦• s *"V" \ | amount of variation in the materials / / /" "s. \ \ i u::cd. / / /sniifiA \ \ \ i Before an analysis of the scorch 1 H J ¦ ' | patterns can be made, the types of I I V J J j . .|| skillets used must be considered. An V V / / "o aluminum skillet will produce a \ «"\^ y*" I \S\ much more uniform scorch pattern \ __^/ / ¦ than a cast-iron skillet for the thcr- \v / |&gt; mal conductivity of aluminum is ' %\ about four and one-half times as . ¦ : |; l c ¦ V*U , ,U» Fui 12.—Division of scorch pattern for 3 great as that of iron. Further, the ~ ftom of bumcr . ,|; thermal conductivity of aluminum . |: increases as the temperature of the aluminum increases, the thermal con- | ductivity at 1,112° F. being 206 per cent greater than that at 212" F. Thus | the heat distribution pattern must be considered as a function of the skillet | as well as a function of the type of burner. 1 "In „„, ca.ti it w.ii n«Mury to mcrt.is&lt;r the heatinß pcrio&lt;l, li«.m!c periods of i and 5 j mintnci produced link or no icorch. ; </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Selected Types of Gas Stoves The scorch patterns were divided into three areas —A, B, and C—by concentric circles whose radii were in the ratio 1:2:3. Next, a line was drawn through the star, which denoted the front of the burner, and the center of the disk from which the circles*were drawn. A second line through the center and perpendicular to the first line divided the pattern into quadrants. This division of the scorch pattern is shown in Figure 12. The following degrees of scorch were used in analyzing the pattern: no scorch, very light brown, light brown, brown, dark brown, and black. The results for the scorch patterns for the various types of burners are summarized "in the following form: - Type A.— Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. The scorch was unifotm for all quadrants. The scorch was brown lor sections A and I) and dark brown for section C ¦-...! i... .-¦ - Iron pan, heating period A minutes. A dark brown scorch was produced in sections A and B with the scorch" shading from a light brown to no scorch in section C. The position of each arm, of the burner was dearly shown by a black scorch. ¦ Type B.—Alumhjum pan, heating period 5 minutes. When the burner was centered in the burner tray, the scorch was a uniform brown over all sections. However, when the burner was not .centered, a black scorch was produced above ihc narrow opening between the burner and burner tray. This black scorch appeared in section C. Iron pan, heating period 4 minutes. The scorch was almost uniformly black in section A, shading to a uniform brown in section B and to a very light brown in section C. ¦¦¦.'.".¦¦'..".- , Type C.—Aluminum pan, hearing period 5 minutes. A uniform brown scorch was produced over all sections. Iron pan, heating period 4 minutes. The scorch pattern in this case was uneven. A light brown scorch was produced in sections A and B in quadrants 1 and 4, while the scorch in sections A and Bin quadrants 2 and,3 varied from brown to light brown. In section C no scorch was found in quadrants 1 and 4 and a -very light brown scorch in quadrants 2 and 3. Type D.—Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. The scorch pattern was un - even. In quadrants 2 and 3 a brown scorch was produced in sections A and B, while the scorch in section C was dark brown. In quadrants 1 arid/fa light brown scotch was found in sections A and B, while the scorch in section C varied from a very light brown to no scorch. "".;'¦ . . • Iron pan, heating period 4 minutes. Here again the scorch was uneven. There was no scorch in section A, a brown scorch in section B and part of C, and no scorch in the outer portion of section C. '.'-¦¦ Type E.—This burner was operated with two types of grates, an open grate and a closed grate. Scorch patterns were made using both grates. Open grate: Aluminum pan, heating period 6 minutes. A uniform light brown scorch was produced in quadrants 1 and 2 over air sections, while the scorch in quadrants 3 and 4 for all sections was a uniform brown. Iron pan, heating period 6 minutes. The scorch was uniformly brown over all quadrants and sections. . . ; ' ' .Closed grate: Aluminum pan, heating period 6 minutes. The scorch was a very light brown in section A and in the outer portion of section C, and light brown in .section B and the inner part of section C. : Iron pan, heating period 6 minutes. The scorch was uneven over all sections, shading from a. light brown to a very light brown. Type J. —Type J is presented here because it was the same set-up as Type E except that it was built in the test box. The scorch patterns for Type J were made before those for Type E which accounts for the greater number of patterns. </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Open grate: Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. There was no scorch in • section A and a very light brown scorch in sections B and C. Iron pan. heating period 4 minutes. No scorch was produced. W pan, heating period 5 minutes and 30 seconds. The scorch was a un.form brown over sections A and B and very light brown in section C. Closed grate- Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. The scorch in section B was a very light brown, while no scorch was Sound in sections A and U Iron pan, heating period 4 minutes. No scorch. Iron pan, heating period 5 minutes. Over all sections there was a light, brown scorch in quadrants 1, 3, and 4, and a very light brown scorch in quadrant 2. Type F.—Right front burner, set for an input of 9,000 B.t.u. per hour. Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. A uniform brown scorch was produced '""iron paThcating period •) minutes. The scorch varied from a light brown to a very light brown in section C and no scorch was found m sections A and 13. Left front burner, set for an input of 7,000 B.t.u. per hour. Muminum pan. heating period 6 minutes. There was a uniform brown scorch over sections A and B with the inner portion of section C showing as a dark brown ring and the outer jwrtion of section C showing as a light brown ring. Iron pan, heating period 5 minutes. Except for a small, very light brown spot about one inch in diameter at the center of section A, there was no scorch in sections A and 11. The scorch in section C varied from very light brown to no scorch. Type H.—Aluminum pan, heating period 5 minutes. There was a uniform brown scorch over sections A and I) and the inner portion of section C. The color shaded of! lo a light brown in the outer portion of section C. Iron pan. heating period 4 minutes. The scorch in section A was dark brown; a brown scorch was produced over section B. and there was no scorch in section v From the analysis of the patterns it was evident that the scorch pro - duced in the iron pan reveals more about the spread of heat from the burner than does the scorch produced in the aluminum pan. It is ot interest, however, to note the scorch for the aluminum pan on the type B burner. No other test that was performed showed the hot spot above the burner on the side where the burner was dose to the burner tray. Probably what happens when the burner is not centered in the burner tray or burner bowl opening is a greater influx of cold air from below, through the larger opening, and this cold air spreads under the pan and cools the pan more on the side abo\e the large opening. Type B assembly was the only one which had off-center burners.' 0 FLUE-GAS ANALYSIS Of equal importance to efficiency, or perhaps more important, is the question of safety, that is, the safety against carbon monoxide. Although these stoves carried the approval seal of the American Gas Association Testing Laboratory, it was thought advisable to check the carbon mon - oxide produced by the respective burners. This can be accomplished by analyzing the products of combustion. Further, by an analysis of the com - bustion products an estimate may be obtained of how much heat is lost in flue products. i« , fmlht , « u d, of oficenlct bu.ncn will be made wilh the Moves recently purchased, of which four of rhe surface cooling assemblies have burners not centered in Ihc burner bowl* and graic. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Selected Types op Gas Stoves : . . -..• -¦¦.;¦¦••¦ . ¦'• ¦ ' ¦....'.'¦ .¦'.¦¦.'¦¦. ¦ • ¦ i.l; The method used for the analysis follows closely that employed by the !' A. G. A. A suitable hood, shown on the stove in Figure 8, was placed j over the pan and burner to allow a flue sample to be obtained. For some tests utensil 5 was used, while for others pan 1 with the handle removed Table 23.— Results forflue-gas analysis for surface burners operating at '.'• normal gas pressure. . „ ¦ Flue . . CO CO in _ " Flue lots Type Bu'"« temper- c 0» air-free in I,ooocu. **?•' perm. ft. Floe , poiilion , mc air-free Mmpk ft; room a" pi burned '¦&gt;'¦ . ¦ * -; .DegMetP. P.ct. '. P.ef. . P.ct, P,a, B.f.H. P.cr, A,-" L.F. 336 11.70 0.05950 0.007490 46.0 185.13 18.40 i A L.F. 340 12.86 0.03980 0.005000 48.5 190.40 18.90 A L. R. 346 14.96 0.08690 0.010900 45.S 187.98 18.50 A L.R. 3-19 12.90 0.06860 0.008620 49.J . 195.00 19.30 . B "34 L. F. 340 13.20 0.06850 0.008610 66.0 232.65 23.00 B '34 L. F. 336 13.18 0.05020 0.006300 692 231.76 2330 834 L. R. ; 336 12.82 ' 0.05160 0.006500 5G.0 101.00 10.C0 834 L. R. 336 12.61 0.05200 0.0065-IO 60.0 212.32 21.00 I D '35' L. F. 358 15.61 0.03530 0.0M430 66.9 239.51 23.80 B-35 R.F. 337 14.25 0.01100 0.001380 62.9 216.22 21.50 B'JS R. R. : 358 15.14 0.05230 0.006560 62.1 224.30 22.20 B !35 L. R. 295 16.00 0.06080 0.007600 77.3 261 27 25.90 C L.F. 353 12.40 0.07950 0.010000 74.0 278.82 27.50 C L.F. :. 401 13.22 0.W660 0.005850 74.0 263.73 26.10 C L. R. 386 12.94 0.04800 0.006030 63.8 237.62 23.50 C . L. R. 408 13.80 0.05840 0.007320 64.2 260.19 25.80 D R.F. 270 12.77 0.01850 0.002320 39.0 166.64 16.50 D R. F. 333 12.21 0.02720 0.003420 40.8 177.96 17.50 D R. R. 349 12.81 0.02840 0.003570 53.0 200.39 19.90 . D R.R.; 340 12.55 0.00000 0.000000 55.1 200.64 19.90 E O. C. 439 14.90 0.03580 0.004500 48.4 226.23 22.50 F. O. G. 417 12.58 0.01730 0.002170 39.0 201.90 20.00 E ¦¦'•¦¦ S.G. ' 408 12.61 0.01600 0.002100 46.7 209.40 20.75 E S.G. 408 12.86 0.00604 0.000758 50.8 218.05 21.60 F R.F. 430 12.18 0.26600 0.033300 45.0 215.55 21.40 ¦¦¦... F 1.. F. 317 12.63 0.05600 0.007030 58.2 199.82 19.80 F L.F 302 12.83 0.04290 0.005380 56.2 189.67 18.90 F ¦ I. X. 307 13.30 0.06225 0.007820 59.4 : 198.56 19.70 f! L. R. .282 12.34 0.00000 0.000000 57.8 183.72 18.10 F X. R. 227 12.70 0.06740 0.008460 64.4 171.45 17.00 F R.R: Ml 13.35 0.07880 0.009900 64.2 176.05 18.50 i G F. 393 9.90 0.09620 ' 0.012080 73.5 ¦ 301.42 29.90 . ,' C F. 398 13.61 0.06950 0.008740 70.2 282.35 27.90 . O R. 344 9.49 0.01700 0.002130 75.7 283.93 28.00 G R. 317 13.43 0.03180 0.003980 72.4 240.60 23.80 H F. 300 12.63 0.06450 0.008090 78.8 275.32 27 JO H F. 322 13.22 0.10230 0.012840 78.8 292.90 29.00 H R. 325 14.40 0.01636 0.002050 69.6 238.73 23.70 ¦ H R. 342. ' 14.56 0.00980 0.001230 70.0 251.36 24.90 ; 'Operating pressure for type 835 was lA normal. - -•. .... ' ¦ " * was used, since;either pan had about the same diameter of bottom. About five pounds of cold water was contained in the utensil. After the burner . had been operating for five minutes, two samples,were drawn off. One sample was used in the iodine-pentoxide apparatus to determine the carbon monoxide in the combustion products, and the other sample was analyzed for carbon dioxide and oxygen in the Burrell-type Orsat appa - ratus; these were the only two constituents necessary to complete the com - putations. All of the flue samples were obtained with the burner operating at normal gas rate and normal pressure. 17 ir Type B "35 was the last stove tested. Experience gained from the'other tests showed that it only one operating pressure was to be used, pressure should be 1% normal. </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 The flue loss was computed by the same method as outlined by Conner 18 and the carbon monoxide computed by the method as outlined by Vandaveer and Gregg." The Approval Requirements for Gas Ranges states that "A gas range shall produce no carbon monoxide. This require - ment shall be deemed met when a concentration not in excess of 0.01 per cent is produced in a room of 1,000 cubic feet content with four air changes occurring during the combustion of an amount of gas liberating 60.000 8.t.u." Analysis in each case was reduced to air-free basis and the CO concentration in a 1,000-cubic-foot room calculated by the formula:'-" Cr = (C.V/4 X 1,000) (1 —l/c-&lt;)6O (5) where Cr = concentration of CO in room atmosphere, per cent C -- CO in air-free products of combustion, per cent V = volume of combustion products per 1,000 B.t.u (exclusive of water vapor), cubic feet c — Napcrian logarithmic base (2.7ISJJ This formula may be simplified to read (&gt; = O.OH7CV (6) The results for the Hue analysis are listed in Table 23. The ]mportant columns to note are the flue loss, the percentage of excess air, and the percentage of CO in a 1,000-cubic-foot room. For a burner to be designated as giving off no carbon monoxide, the percentage of CO must not exceed 0.01 per cent. It will be noticed that only one burner greatly exceeded this amount, the right front burner of type F. About eighteen different analyses were made on this burner and the data listed represent one typical set of results when the burner was used as built in the stove. It is because of this excessive CO that this burner should be operated with an input of 7,000 B.t.u. per hour or less, at least with natural gas. A consideration of the flue-loss and efficiency data will give some esti - mation of how much heat is lost by conduction through the stove top. For instance type F burner had an efficiency of about 45 per cent and the average flue loss was approximately 19 per cent and thus about 36 per cent of the heat delivered by the burner was dissipated through the stove and around the burners. Finally, a glance at the excess-air column will show the advantage of the air plate, such as that used on type A. Again, type C has a burner tray which controls the air around the burner but by the use of the open-type grate, cold air is drawn in from the surrounding area above the burner tray. This cooler air furnishes excess air and at the same time must be heated, which, of course, lowers the efficiency of the burner. AUTOMATIC LIGHTERS Automatic lighters were not considered as being essential to the study ot the surface burners but since all of the ranges were equipped for auto - w .Approval Requirement*. ,\. (&#132; \. </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Selected Types of Gas Stoves made ignition, the lighters were tested according to the A. G. -A. specifications. With the burners operating at normal gas rate and pressure, the pilot flame was adjusted to the proper height and if equipped for a Bunsen flame, the air shutter was set. The gas pressure was then reduced to one - half normal and the gas turned off at the burners. Before the tests were started, the gas line was tested to make certain that the line was full of gas. Utensil 5, containing a quantity of water, was placed over the burner to be tested and the gas cock turned on to the full position. The period of time between the opening of the gas cock and the ignition of the gas was recorded with a stop watch. Similarly the flames were blown out and the time between the extinguishing of the flame and reignition was measured. : ,; . Table 24.— Time required for ignition and reignition oj burner flames by automatic lighter. ¦ __ ¦¦•-,-* i . : Ay. lime Ay. lime . . . " Type of Burner r or f or Remarks aiscrobly | position igßilipn' ; re-ignition . ¦. Saonih : Secondi .--¦'¦¦ A All burners 2.0 ; 1.0 '.; B '35 L. F. 1-8 i 1.0 Would not always relight. 835 ' 1..R; 1.0 !.¦ .. Would not rclicht. li'3s it F. 1.1 1.0 .Would not always relight. 835 R.R. . . 1.7 IS C L.F. 2.0 2.0 C L.R. 1.8 M- C . R.F. 2.0 2.1 ¦¦ ..V. C . R. R. -2.4 :. Would not relight. ¦" ; D L.F. 5.0 : 3.4 :..... n L.R. 4.0' 3.0 : D , R.F. . 2.0 ¦ 3.0 ..' •¦ •••••• t&gt; R.R. , 2.6 . 2.4 ...i.I E L.F. 4.5 ' 3.0 E . 1.. R. . 2.0 .. Would not olirayj lighl—would not relight. F. R.F. 4.0 3.0 .:..... . . F. L.F. 3.0 2.0 .;...... F L.R. 3.0 2.4 : F R.R. 2.2-2.0 ; . ..:...;.¦¦ ....... . :...¦¦¦¦¦. The time required for ignition and reignition of burner flames by. the automatic lighter is presented in Table 24. As stated in the Gas Associa - tion requirements the ignition time must be within 4 seconds for ignition or reignition if the lighter is to pass. From Table 24 it is evident that the automatic lighters did not always work successfully. The assembly which gave the greatest trouble was type E. This stove was placed in actual service after the laboratory tests were completed. Complaints were soon received that the lighter functioned only occasionally. The lighter was removed and returned to the laboratory for investigation, where it was observed that because of the long lighter tubes used and also the mode of construction of the tube adjacent to the pilot light, a flash was not always produced at the burner end of the tube even when the end of the lighter tube at the pilot was slightly higher than the end at the burner. The tubes were rebuilt so that the end at the lighter was not constricted </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 and two more holes were drilled in the side of the daisy burner so that when the flash was received at the burner the flame would travel up to the ports. After these changes were made the automatic lighter functioned properly. . The lighters which proved the most successful were those on types A, C, and F. Type A was the most positive of all, for the pilot light was only about V/ 2 inches from the burner, thus having a very short flash tube The flash tube on this lighter forms part of the air-plate and may be seen on the left burner assembly in Figure 1. Type C lighter tubes were integral with the burner tray and had openings large enough to produce a good passage through which the flash must travel. All three of these lighter assemblies were protected so that they were not affected by boil-overs. BOIL-OVER TESTS With regard to the safety of the appliance this set of tests was more important than first thought would suggest. The burners and automatic lighters were set to operate at the normal gas rate and pressure, and then pan 8, containing either soap solution or starch solution, was placed over the burner and the gas cock turned on full. After the solution began to boil over, conditions affecting the normal operation of the burner were observed. The boil-over was continued until either the flame went out entirely or else it was certain that the flame would not extinguish. The solutions were made as follows: Soap solution.—Pan S. three -fourths full of water, to which was added two table - spoons of bead soap anil a small amount of water softener. This solution produced a very frothy suds. Starch solution.—Pan S. three-fourths full of water, with enough rolled oats, petti- John, and graham flour added Mi make a thick mixture when boiled. Boil-over tests revealed features of construction about the burners and lighters that might otherwise have been missed. In some cases only the lighters were clogged and in other cases only the burner was affected, while occasionally both were clogged by the boil-over solution. A discus - sion of the results of the boil-overs is presented for each type of burner assembly in the following. Type A.— With the map solution \iart &lt;ii the burner ports were, filled, but the flame was not rYrineimhetl. Because of tfic filling of part of the ports, the gas came out of the remaining ports with such a velocity that a floating flame was maintained im - mediately under the pan. When the starch solution was used, the outer ports were clogged but the flames continued to burn in inner ports. The automatic lighter was not aftcctcd by boil-overs from either solution. Type B.—Only the soap solution was used because the flames were completely extinguished in all tests. The results arc as follows: Right front burner—all flames extinguished in 15 seconds. The burner would not relight with automatic lighter nor when a match was used. Right rear burner—flames extinguished in 5 seconds. Could not be relighted with automatic lighter or matches. Left front burner—flames extinguished in 2 seconds. Would not relight with lighter but could be ignited with a match. Left rear burner—flames extinguished m 5 seconds. </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Selected Types of Gas Stoves Part of the ports relighted with automatic lighter. The refusal of burners to relight with the lighter was due entirely to the clogging of ports. The lighter was unaffected by the boil-overs. Type G—This burner and burner assembly was unaffected by the soap solution. With the starch solution the flames from several ports were extinguished temporarily but re-ignited in less than one second. Type D.—The soap solution clogged the ports near the lighter tube. The flames were not entirely extinguished. The automatic lighter would not function because the slit in the lighter tube adjacent to the burner became filled. The burner could be relighted with a match. With the starch solution, the flames were extinguished in one minute. The lighter tube also became filled with the starch solution so that it refused to rcignitc the gas, but the burner flames could be relighted in some places with a match. &#132;.'•-;¦ ¦ '¦'.;¦¦ ¦ ¦ . : - . _ ; Type E.—The assembly was unaffected by the starch solution but was clogged with ¦'the soap solution. The open grate was used for all tests. With all of the burners in this assembly the heads next to the lighter were clogged and also the air adjustment brcamc so filled that a yellow flame was produced. The right front and left front burners refused to light with the automatic lighter. The left front burner could be lighted automatically, but not immediately. -:¦.¦'¦• Type p.—Neither the burners nor (he lightcts were affected by boil-overs. Aside from the hazard of having unburned gas given off, the most disagreeable factor is the cleaning of the stove after the boil-over. Since it was necessary to put the burner in working condition again, the ease of cleaning the burner and cooking top,was.noted. .Types A, B, C, and D were easily cleaned, especially types C and D, which have removable heads as shown in Figure 7. In all of the burner-clogging tests on type E, the greater portion of the liquid fell into the drip rings, but some of the liquid fell into the storage compartment. Because of the construction of the burner head, unnecessary labor was required in cleaning and restoring the burner to satisfactory working order/Type F compartment was the hardest to dean, for although the burner bowls collected most of the liquid, that portion which fell into the burner compartment was difficult to remove. Both type E and type F assemblies should have removable drip pans below the burners. ¦ CONCLUSIONS FROM SURFACE-BURNER TESTS The thermal-efficiency tests show that the efficiency of a burner iVa function of several factors, the principal ones being the size of the utensil, the distance between pan and burner, the type: of top, and the grate con - struction. The results indicate that there is a need for a change in burner application so that efficiency will be increased when small utensils are used. One way of accomplishing this would be to raise the burner nearer to the bottom of the pan. This would, of course, necessitate using a lower gas rate in order to remain within the limits of safety. Still another way would be to thermally insulate the grate from the stove top. This would decrease the conduction of heat through the stove and thereby make avail - able more heat which could be applied to the pan. If one compares the present burners and burner applications with those in the past, it is evident </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 that efficiency has been increased but there is still too much heat lost that could be used to do work. In general, the heat-distribution tests and gas-analysis tests showed that the burners studied were satisfactory. From the results with boil-overs, however, it is apparent that improvement is needed. The tests showed that if a burner is to be free from clogging because of boil-overs, the burner must have some form of protected ports and lighter system. Although automatic lighters are a great convenience, there is need for improvement (drastic improvement in some cases) if they are to be con - sidered entirely dependable. It is the experience of this laboratory that automatic lighters work most of the time but in some cases they are failures. The principal value of these surface-burner tests should be that of a measuring stick for judging similar types of burners. That is, knowing the thermal efficiency of, for instance, a type B burner it should be possible to predict the efficiency of a burner of similar type and construction. 21 Of course, in making such predictions, all factors affecting efficiency must be considered, for slight changes in application sometimes make quite a difference in the efficiency. When choosing a stove there arc certain tests that anyone can make, namely, heat distribution tests, automatic lighter tests, and boil-over tests. If these tests are performed and then the efficiency judged on the basis of known data, a fairly comprehensive idea of what a particular burner will do may be obtained. With regard to safety from poisonous gases, however, one must rely upon the manufacturer, unless one has available suitable apparatus for analyzing the flue gas. TESTS WITH OVENS METHOD OF EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE FOR OVENS In setting up the oven for tests, three things had to be done: the burner orifice, the by-pass valve, and the pilot had to be adjusted in the oven; and the outside oven surfaces had to be divided and marked into the proper number of areas for surface temperature measurements. The burner orifice was adjusted according to the method previously outlined, so that the inputs agreed with those in Table 7 under the head - ing, "Rating computed from oven size." The by-pass valve on the oven heat regulator was adjusted so that the burner flame due only to the by - pass flow of gas was about the size of the head of a match or about one - eighth of an inch long. The pilot flame was usually about three-fourths of an inch in length. In setting the pilot and by-pass flames, the recom - mendations of the manufacturer were followed. Fifteen couples were used to measure the temperature within the oven. The couples were arranged in three planes, the upper plane being about n The me of the existing ibla From these burners has been tried in predicting the efficiency o/ some of the burners fin ranges yet to be lellcd. It was found tlm efficiencies couid be predicted to </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Selected Types of Gas Stoves 2 inches from the top of the oven, the mid-plane halfway between the top and the bottom, and the lower plane located at about 2 inches from the bottom of the oven. On the diagonals of these planes five couples were arranged so that the four couples at the outer corners were about 2J4 inches from the side walls with the fifth couple at the center. Average oven temperatures were measured by the five couples in the mid-plane, the couples being so wired at the switch that they could be connected in parallel. The couples were supported in a strip of heat-resisting pressed asbestos. This strip also served as an electrical insulator between the couples and the supporting rack. A sketch of this support is shown in Figure 13. Unless some peculiarity in design made a change necessary, each of the exterior sur- 1 • faces of the'top, sides, and back of the oven (f ¦ was divided into sixteen areas. The oven l] door and broiler door were divided by a n^T\ horizontal line through the middle and by T"Y three equally spaced vertical lines, thus divid- ing the surface into eight areas. For measure- /^ ments around the rim of. the oven door, a . &amp;*/jK^^. strip about 1 '/z inches wide was taken as -*O^ the door frame, and this strip was divided I^^T^ © f V into areas having lengths ranging from &lt;fe approximately 4to 5 inches, depending upon r \ q the size of the door. These divisions are \ vP shown in Figures 21 to 27, where the results \\ y^ for surface temperatures-are presented. The L. temperature at the center of each area was , &gt;vf measured with a copper^constantan couple which had sufficient length of the couple at the hot junction spiraled in the face of a VA- • inch cork with the tip of the junction at the center. This arrangement allowed for : —»..*..!«. the minimum conduction'of heat away from '?l°- 13.—Sketch of thcrmo - the tip. of the! couple and also, since the cork . couple $uppoU in mca - had a very low thermal capacity, successive readings could be taken rapidly. | CALIBRATION OF THERMOSTAT The first test performed was. a comparison of the dial settings with the actual oven temperature, as measured by the five couples in parallel. 22 With the thermostat set at the 400 mark, the average oven temperature was read after, the oven temperature had attained the steady state and had remained constant for at least 30 minutest If the difference between dial setting and actual temperature was more than two degrees, the dial was adjusted. Whenever an adjustment was necessary, an attempt was made to have the average oven temperature agree with the dial setting. After " The -100 mark on ihc dial is usually used as ihc calibration point by manufacturers and testers. </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 « S «•» "¦- -r -r w C _____ |! jl^ iiii I _J ¦ "^ "s "", "1 * \^ i s ' ' I iii .-.=.".-.-:=. 5 ; 5 ' J; .-. v t ¦ j«; c cq x « * ° i'li'^l SI IS S 1 "l" 1 5 I ? - ¦a " I -.pea c q q a - 0 0' i s s — ! ' 5 ,- ' S Si . "j -¦*¦**"¦¦" s ¦^ - jjS ) z —I S" I/. £ -S l/&gt; _' f „ rS 3t J* 1 . "*.'*.*. "' '"¦- "l °. "= -y, !d ~ 11' s 1" 5S ? t X E 1 m 'Xi ,j :U = 5?,-. S -r n - ll^ J! ¦^5 .3xriq *r Or '-^ j "ss* * "¦ ' sil H gi||SSS Ph 40 </seg>
         <seg id="p041">&#132;. ¦¦. Selected Types of Gas Stoves the 400 mark had been checked* and adjusted if necessary, dial settings o£ 250, 300, 350, 400, 450, 500, and 550 were compared with average oven temperatures. For each of these settings the oven temperature was brought to the steady state and then held there for one hour. Since in most cases these data could be used also for heat-loss data, the gas volume, the time, the barometric pressure, and the meter pressure and temperature were recorded, i . The first test showed the following agreement: Oven A, 397.7° F.; oven B '34, '446° F.; oven 835, 399-2" F.-, oven C, 460° F.; oven D, 414.7° F.; oven E, 3995° F.; and oven F, 400° F. It is evident that ovens A, 834, C, and D had to be adjusted in order to fulfill the A. G. A. requirement. After adjustment the agreement for these four ovens was: oven A, 402° F.; oven 834, 399.5° F.; oven C, 400° F.; and oven D, 402° F. It should be noted that with all the thermostats tested except the bi-metallic strip regulator on oven D, the temperature was maintained constant; that is, there was no fluctuation of temperature as there is with electric stoves. With gas-oven regulators there is always a constant amount of heat being applied in contrast to the off and on periods of electric ovens; for this reason any wide change in temperature should be investigated. In Table 25, which lists the agreement between dial settings and oven temperature, it will be noticed that there are two calibrations for ovens A and F and three tests for oven D. ¦ . After the first adjustment of the dial, calibration 1 was obtained for oven A and the agreement was considered good. Later while obtaining heat-loss data it was observed that there was discrepancy between dial settings and actual temperatures. At 400° F. this amounted to between 30 and 35 degrees,* that is, to obtain an actual oven temperature of 400° F., it was necessary to have the dial set between 430 and 435. When a re - calibration was started this discrepancy had changed to 25 degrees and no adjustment of the dial could be found for which the temperature would remain constant from one day to the next, that is, between successive daily tests. The trouble was finally located at the valve seat, where a piece of dirt was alternately being drawn in and ejected. With the removal of the dirt, calibration 2 was performed and good results were obtained for all succeeding tests. ; . ¦ The heat control on oven D presented a different problem. As men - tioned before, this regulator was an exception. It did not keep the oven temperature constant but fluctuated between a high and a low value. In this case the average temperature between the high and low value was used as the comparison temperature. A portion of the calibration curve for this thermostat is shown in Figure 14. The data for this curve were taken during the adjustment of the dial at .400° F. Calibration 1 was made with the adjustments set as the stove was received from the manu - facturer. After adjustments were made, calibration 2 was started at the 550 mark and the temperature decreased for each successive lower dial setting until it was found that for the low dial settings of 300 and 250 </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Acr. E.xp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 the by-pass flame was so low that some of the ports were not ignited. Great difficulty was experienced in setting the by-pass valve on this regulator because the ad- 410, r 1 1 1 s 1 justing screw made such a snug fit with the regulator M ./ _S. that it was almost impos- / \ / sible to turn it. For the ad- | ( \ / \ / justment before calibration J \-^ 3 the by-pass flow of gas 0 was increased slightly. The g"° 1 oven was heated l'/i hours I I and then the dial was :¦&gt;** T changed. The final setting j- / gave a high value of 404.2° — I F. and a low value of j / 393.4° F., the average be- * jn \J. ing 398.8° F. It is the opinion of the author that 1 - c 1 ¦ "d JtJ 75 JS Jd Sb oo &gt; this type 01 thermostat is r,mt ,n m™»« not as successful a regula- , _ ... , _ " . Fig. H. —Calibration curve for oven D. tor tor gas ovens as the copper-tube, carbon-rod regulator, or the pressure-thermometer regulator. The first calibration test for oven F was discontinued at 350° F. be - cause at this dial setting the temperature decreased from the previous temperature for dial setting 400 until the oven temperature reached 319° F. and then the temperature began to increase until one hour later it had become 405° F. The by-pass was readjusted to make the by-pass flame as low as possible and with the dial at 400 the temperature obtained was 398.4° F. Calibration 2 was obtained after this adjustment. There was considerable back-lash in this dial, so that a variation of at least five degrees could be obtained while moving the dial from one setting to another. OVEN HEATING CAPACITY The essential feature of this test was to determine the time and energy necessary to heat the oven from room temperature to 500° F. Two sets of data were obtained, one set with the thermostat at the 550 mark and the other set with the thermostat at the maximum position. The necessary data were secured by recording gas volume, time, average oven temperature, and the correction factor to reduce the gas volume to standard conditions. The oven heating capacity is represented by the time necessary to heat the oven from room temperature to 500° F. The requirement of the American Gas Association for 1936 for these ovens is as follows: "Ovens and their controls shall be so designed that the oven temperature can be increased from room temperature to 500° F. at an average rate of at least 21.5 degrees per minute." </seg>
         <seg id="p043">':/'¦• Selected Types of Gas Stoves | '¦• " :.' • ¦' - ¦•'•'. ' ¦¦" . '' '. • I While this test is in operation the gas rate should be adjusted so that the input is 8,000 B.t.u. per hour per cubic foot of oven space. The pre - heating curves for the various ovens;are shown in Figure 15. The curves show that all of the ovens fulfilled the American Gas Association's requirement. ;¦.;. : ¦ .. ¦ ' . .! 600 — -:— — . '.'.'• SSO — — —. — — i.i— /L, -* 3QV .1 '$%&gt; ¦'".'. \ 600 ' • \ff\r . 7 j£/,' ' — :— J/f Iff . ; I ¦J/f'// ' ' ——-- . I : 'I I ¦-...huo'—4LUl—^ ¦ '¦'¦ i l/$" - ¦ ' ¦ ¦¦ ¦:.¦'¦¦ \IOOW — ; iQ4 a it v to I* ta : ..;¦::¦ Time in Minutes &#132; Fie. 15. —Preheating temperature as a function of time. Not only is it important to know the time necessary to heat to 500° R, but the energy consumed should be considered. The gas rate did not remain constant, as is shown in Figure 16. The rate became less at higher temperatures and this is to be expected since the orifice was heated as time increased. The amount of energy in B.t.u. necessary to heat the oven to any desired temperature is shown in Figure 17. -. '•¦ For all the curves shown, the thermostat was set at the maximum position. However, the effect of having the regulator set at 550 is shown by the dotted lines on ovens 834 and E in Figure 15. With the regulator </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 /_ 8000 -/--/¦ _ OvnlfM ¦$ / ZZZZZZ / ' ~ i -Zrzzrzz#zzzzz r J Z liooc Wh--- 1 JZ jEZ * _w_ jBJ JjL_ 1000 -jf- -2—__-11111111 A\ 1111111 IF — 0 10 20 j) Time in Minutes l-'ii,. lA.—f'rrhcatinj: i-ncrK)' as a funclitm n( time. set at 550 the closing action of the valve began to take place soon after the 500° F. temperature was reached. A similar action would be found for other dial settings; that is, the gas control valve would begin to operate before the temperature indicated by the dial had been reached. Thus the curves in Figure 15 represent the minimum time necessary to preheat to temperatures below 550° F. </seg>
         <seg id="p045">: :. Selected Types of Gas Stoves ' ' ; : 7r/ r&amp; ¦- — '¦ : ~~7^t/'y^ "~— ¦¦¦•• jr—Mr——————— ¦.: \sao — «wo —jmo jw *w -JKi» i#ss we eooo foot ;.' v Prctiuiiaj Cneyy m&amp;tu Fig. 17.—Oven temperature as a function of preheating energy. ; '¦ ' RATE OF COOLING ; One simple method of studying the construction o£ an oven is to observe the rate|o£. cooling. Immediately after preheating the oven to 550° F. the gas was turned off and the rate of cooling was determined. For the first 20 minutes, average temperature readings were taken every two minutes; for the next 20 minutes the interval was increased to 5 minutes; and for the remainder of the test the readings were recorded every 10 minutes. ..;¦;. .: , .. In order to observe the effect of bringing the oven to a steady state, before starting the cooling test, the oven was preheated to 550° F. and maintained at this temperature until the temperature had remained con - stant for 20 minutes. The gas was turned off and the data were recorded as in the above outline. , ' All of the ovens had about the same size flue opening and with the exception of oven E the doors did not fit tightly. The principal difference in construction was the thickness of insulation. The condition of the ovens for the cooling curves was that of an unsteady state so that the rate of </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 cooling should be principally a function of the thickness of insulation. From the insulation thickness given in Table 2, it would be expected that oven E would have the lowest rate of cooling and the greatest rate would be had with the ovens having the least insulation. "°T 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i — soo vX ¦—¦ ¦ — i"°-w\ —n I »V t&lt;»"f w /OCS h 75 JO 40 SO 60 70 Bo 73 X&gt;o to liO Time &lt;n Minyfea In.. iS. -'I line r.Ui ul ciK&gt;linj! Iroin SSo° }¦'. titr ovens. This is vcriricd by the curves in Figure IX. which show the rate of cooling tor the various ovens. The slightly lower rate of cooling for oven H 35, in contrast to the rate for oven 834. was probably due to the increased thickness ot the right side wall. On oven B '35 the thickness had been increased to l' 4 inches. The flue passage of oven E was constructed with a small damper that closed when the gas cock was turned off. The oven was designed to bake on retained heat. The contrast between the cooling curve when the damper was closed and the cooling curve when the damper was open give a measure of the amount of heat that was lost through the flue opening. EMPTY OVEN HEAT LOSS, TEMPERATURE DISTRIBUTION, AND SURFACE TEMPERATURES The rate-of-cooling data give some information about the heat-retaining properties of the oven, hut in order to know the actual number of British thermal units necessary to maintain an oven at a desired temperature it is necessary to determine the heat loss of the oven. Besides the heat-loss data computed from the calibration tests, tests were performed to obtain data for heat loss when the average oven temperature was constant at 300°, 400°, and 500° F. The temperature was considered constant if the tern- </seg>
         <seg id="p047">¦ -¦-¦¦- - ¦ " ¦¦ ¦ - I -. : " ; &#132;-. Selected Types of Gas Stoves : perature variation was not more than ±1 degree. After the condition o£ the oven had reached the steady state, the average temperature was watched constantly and readings were recorded at 5-miriute intervals. Gas-volume and correction-factor data were taken every 15 minutes. The total time for a test was one hour or more. At the same time the heat-loss data were being obtained, the tem - perature distribution in the oven vvas recorded. ; Every fifteen minutes the temperature at each of the fifteen couples was obtained. The average of the readings for each couple was used for the temperature-distribution data. After the heat-loss tests had been in operation for 30 minutes, surface temperatures were recorded. Usually readings were again taken at the end of the test period. For this set of data the only computation necessary is the conversion of gas volume per unit of time to energy per unit of time. The most con - venient unit would be B.t.u. per hour, tor when a comparison between the KOOOi 1 j I I I I I I I II I - ¦-•¦'¦••••• :I~ti// -¦¦¦ w- {I 9000 ; H—l :¦¦¦ *wea —JEzZ /aY/ ;^,*«_ —__— —M' — — — r- Oven C o\ A I I I 111 I I • - SO- - 100 ISO 200 ZSO 300 . JSO 400 4SO JOO JSO ¦".. ¦" ' -'..'¦¦ Oven Timptttiwt in Otfrcfa rchrenhvi Fie. 19.—Empty-oven heat loss as a function of oven temperature. </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 heat loss of gas ovens and the heat loss of electric ovens is desired it is only necessary to multiply B.t.u. per hour by 0.2928 to obtain watts A quantitative measure of the heat loss for the empty ovens is given in Hgure 19. The experimental points for these curves clustered very closely about the curves At 300°, 400°, and 500° F. at least three points were used to locate the curve and at least one point was obtained from the calibrate data for points from 250° to 550° F. A substitute burner using an input of 9,000 B.t.u. per hour was installed in those ovens with which it was impossible to obtain temperatures around 300° F with the regular oven burner. b The empty-oven heat loss in B.t.u. per hour per cubic foot of oven space is shown by the curves in Figure 20. In this set of curves it will be noticed that ovens B 35 and E have changed places; otherwise the location of the curves remains essentially the same as in Figure 19. ASOC . / £«* I r r~i-+ \ Oven O'M- p-V' J jjoo I Oven C—f- T~y/ | cvLc-yt-j// i TN W~ My 8 f/ * ,*o yZ_ \, soo j, &lt;f I MM) "" "° lo° M» So 310 400 4S S3 Oven Temperature //? Dtyreet fZhrcnhtit Fig. 20.—Empiy-ovcn heat loss in B.t.u. per hour per cubic foot of nven space as a function of oven temperature. </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Selected Types of Gas Stoves In conjunction with the heat-loss curves, the flue loss should be con - sidered as determined from the gas-analysis test. The flue analysis is listed in Table 26. Samples of the flue products were taken at the flue exit of the oven and analyzed for CO 2 , 02,O 2 , and CO. The flue loss was computed in the same manner as for the surface-burner analysis. The thermostat was set at the maximum position and the oven burner was operated for 15 minutes before the samples were withdrawn. The flue temperature was taken at the place where the flue box was connected to the oven. It will be. observed that the flue loss for oven F was rather low and yet its heat loss as given in Figure 18 is one of the highest. This oven seems to be ¦ ' Table 26.— Flue-gas analysis forovens. ¦ Flue CO air- coin I ' Flue loss : . Oven tempera- :, a free in 1,000 eu. ft. "«" percu, ft. pluclou ture air-free lample room ™ pal burned • DeermT. P.et. P.O. P.el. PM. 8.1. U. Pxl. X 272.6 15.08 0.00000 0.00000 77.78 245.376 24 JO 834 353.8 12.34 OMOOa ' 0.00000 73.00 269.755 26.70 835 370.2 14.40 0.01610 0.00210 60.50 230.445 23.25 C 318.5 , 1154 0.00000 0.00000 77.78 279.865 27.70 D 235.2 12.35 0.02360 0.00296: 54.20 157.600 15.62 E 328.6 11.88 0.00000 0.00000 . 78.20 290.090 J8.75 F ."•¦. 288.0 12.80 0.00581 0.00073 61.30 190.Z60 18.88 a good example of the amount of heat lost through a poorly fitted door. Beginning at the upper left corner and extending to almost the lower right corner of the door there was a space varying from 1/16 to 3/32 of an inch. This crack always appeared with a normal closing of the door. This poor contact is also shown by the surface temperature in Figure 27. It is the opinion of the author that the lower flue loss of oven B '35 in contrast to the flue loss of oven B '34 is explained by the change in the method of exhausting the flue gas from the top of the oven. It appears that the baffling of oven B '35 is improved so that more of the heat in the flue products can be utilized. : The temperatures obtained at the fifteen places in the ovens indicate that the temperature distribution, and thus the heat distribution, in the oven may be considered as quite uniform. The distribution of temperatures is listed in Table 27. ; The heat-loss curves show that a definite amount of heat is necessary to maintain ah oven at a required temperature. The flue-analysis data show that part of the heat put in was lost through the flue. The heat lost through cracks in poorly fitting doors was not determined and a quantitative measure of the heat lost through the side walls and top was hot obtained, but a qualitative measure was obtained by observing surface temperatures while the ovens were in the steady state. These surface temperatures for ovens A to F are given in Figures 21 to 27 and Tables 28 to 33 respectively. For each area in the figures the upper value denotes the temperature when the internal j temperature of the oven was 500° F. </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 /• N o o IsilL^Jld o o 001 o o o ° is! sk! hu is/ ° ° oo I ! ¦— o o 0 o iUH'liiU 1S ° !&lt;SS- o o H &#132; «5J «7* itll i/ti \y V ent&gt; 1 1 ) «&lt;"' _ii i i A." ! " A"• I'" Mi "i-i v" ' " /,, 7 UsSi SM S«UIiL jj urIKC ]""' | " " ¦X"'''"* bvrvn ,nt ' ,?jj /jro «« btrners f ' ! |S eg) In I ' i-H-OKI-g) , ?(J «{.! ,«, «gl —i—i —| — 81 va i ' m m —; —'—— »i w; !«&gt; 3- yigleferarl lltr ? I A»^ ¦ vrf» . —2 ¦ -^— t—Z—L_o— Q-«^ w^ I IMS -W5 /!»&gt; '«a "*B tG) U46 1201 &#132;4 3 , f49 &#132;St US* &#132;40 "40 1140, •'3l ,0U 'OH 10% it'i '34* I*™ 'ill l\t «» "« »f-5 *?J t,o 9i liwo ' wo , - byafritdbQf 1 I 1 —— ISHft $jsliM '111 »J TX^^UT V V. V.\ 'I/IP^ 11^—^-^—"-^—^—L^ -"I "'j **| "* Fie. 21 -Surface temperature fur ..»!&gt;¦ »&gt;de». ami front of own A. In each area the upper mkldle. anil lower numbers denote surface temperatures for oven air tem - peratures of 51)0° 4011°. and 300° F. respectively. This applies to Figures .1 to II inclusive Surface temperatures »f the Hack of oven A shown above. </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Selected Tvp£S of Gas Stoves ' - Hit 133* I3*-I *f JJ ." "- ' j|A ..V 3$ !»l 5 IS wT „ -j— -7-—j —— »3 «".» «'» "¦&gt;' ; I ttu nat 1740 ms ' ¦¦¦'. {'•?,'. 'if ff4 f«i OVM ! . ¦ door . . ¦¦ . ." - - - BSi Wi W '&amp;', "it.' fi!--M--il--^) I FlO. 22,-Surfacc temperatures. t^lbSllgJlWiiigUl ! : oven B '31 ;¦¦;'¦¦¦[»'» % % :¦¦.:¦: '. ¦;¦;., ¦ m m 'S&amp; ss' ¦¦;..¦ //« «« '«» *•-• . . ¦ ¦ i ¦j bach ¦ :-. ¦¦.. - i . L I ' rijhtink ¦ | ! "¦¦g|tf|g|it¦¦¦¦ff:|-ffi|».|iß f H4i iljj 1(3.7 l£B7 ' ¦ "" ""¦ &amp;l w "™ 'a* aij -m m %\ ¦ ¦ - m fc g/,/ ; /;a^ //*^ /'" ;¦;¦-¦ si »$ 1? ~^~~s»~i&gt;r~®r ! J?!» «'J '«Z /»-« i , . 9 XJ // IC \ I I ¦ ' int mt not ntt ¦ '¦¦.'¦'. - --.! it If aa sjs ¦•¦¦¦.; , ¦¦¦¦¦'-': : oven __ ; ___ ¦. ¦. '¦';-' door : . : I rali MO Z146 lUi - ¦ ll'.* in* Alt HJ-f ¦ .; :¦ j B« isoL&gt; moj i»»j . . -. ¦ Moor [M ,U:S S« U] Fn. 23.—5-irfccc tcm - ] 1 |fa&lt;r |/gj \iuj \au£\ pcraturcs, oven II "35. 51 </seg>
         <seg id="p052">Nebraska A™. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 | II tot* { I fli; «« ;sj ::; ' i *""H----| ——r l"¦ 1-»i «»' "« «k [-Mli/lif lw !'"' ® ™ ""' p IG 24.—Surface icmpcraturcs, oven C. )' 52 </seg>
         <seg id="p053">. Selected Types of Gas Stoves J Kit "4* if'i. I'M? ! ¦ hoi uos ho 5 \\fii • ¦¦¦ ¦i • ¦ til nz nt lISiJ . . .. . ':'-:¦ ¦ • I ¦ .. :¦¦¦ 'XI 'Hi •&amp;' '«s . .. .: ku ml mi isu : . btTk ¦ '¦¦' ¦': ¦. ' ¦ . ¦ IM2 till t 1437 ISOJ ' ¦ '¦ ¦ 114$ tljr 1161 IMJ ¦ . ml Bio Mil iim ' 1544 I 1 tSBS ' ¦ ¦ ¦ w fi&lt;* m . m ',?,! mi ats ¦ma j«s VSS USS net M 74 IH4 "tc !«5 S» ',',% 'UK ;&gt;&lt;&gt;', ft&gt;, . ii*4 U44 hi.4 f os7 /a7 j iara -trns&amp;- - : -ii -_ . . 'IS M '&lt;'&amp; "" '"''' W "" "" HOI ICI.T 101* UU % %£ 'ttt ;m isi im .'¦'. . I «7J ICtJ lU.T KJ7 1 ««• "'• «5J '»«! vss 'Mi '4?a '4i' 131* 1Z9.7 11741 Ilia lv* lIO£- lI4A /«• . Hit Kft »«.&gt; W . I ,ffi 5!» B« ,-S , w, , , ®?_ Sii £&amp; ISil —— — y«. "Sml^"^ ilii (iff «i i»2 F ; Jim m -II ;ia *" *" ™ »* Fie. 25.—Surface temperatures, 'oven D. 53 </seg>
         <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agk. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 ..» , *fr , ..... I in ° I ——1 in.i 1070 1070 lira U6.7 m Hi lil.t ""' ,341 fit 9 119 4 f46 O 107.9 3QQQ QQOQ (Stirs (jjjX /M-0 /OJ-S «/ 7 1070 lOi 7 lOS 5 lOJ.J /OJ J 962 fOO-8 990 100 8 lOOS 1008 900 9l O 100 9( t 9J4 9/0 101 7 103 S 7&lt;* ? &gt;M' »Ji 94 1 « &lt;• 99 0 97 t tS S 95 S 94 6 90.0 91 0 90.0 08* 38 3 S6J -left Ude top IQZ S I6t S *J 6 94 A ' 9C.7 91 O 99 o 9tf Z fj t *J * 9i 6 ?r 1 90 O 90 O At, S 06 3 09 S 856 1043 101 1 910 917 117 91 0 99 9 VO I 9? 7 9? ? 94 6 946 91S 900 Si 6 SS.o 8* S 056 'nil «7d 'IQ%I /OJ'I I I I II i \ fa* 914 \ 9M&gt; &#132; 'Sis 'P7 %\l ¥,l , 936 917 910 914 * broiler door ~IO4J IOZS 99 9 ?9P N 99 9 9&amp;! 97 3 99.0 //[ 910 \ 900 9QQ \ 9O.Q)t HU , e7£ , 070 IQ4J _",j I , 4 , 3 It 6 __ IQS.I 105 2. 9*A tAJ, ,J it I IS — li \la "1 *J* ' J* 91° 90° _ n 130.3 II9S UTB 1310 ', „ fight j^fc 1174 f/S4 UU ' -iiyw m*k 9 1070 107 0 1031 105* 4 //f&lt; JM&lt;J /0?^ /J4J _ oven door #«.e /w"i&gt; &gt;os.s 99.0 .m&gt; ,™?U** isoj I *" *" 'J&lt; "° 8 «/«* its.s ass mo . s lO7A 1078 1071 1076 _ 7\- It .1 M if I .LI )h /O jj ( &#132;m to7a /o3S -U4 c r ' -1 «j*_ iosj toys 100.0 95.S Ul6 ISTI-TTse,* '261 *' 0 910 91.0 90.0 lOHS HI S IC7A 10? &lt; I I (Q{ .1 \ lOt S \ I I I | | Ki&lt;-. 2f&gt;.—Surface temperatures, oven E. 54 </seg>
         <seg id="p055">,' ¦ ' . ¦¦-.'¦ -¦ '¦ ¦¦" I Selected Types of Gas Stoves j - I :. '".."'¦ .¦¦'-' .f. ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ;¦¦ ¦ ¦.- ¦ "-'¦ ... ¦"" '.'¦¦"¦ I: . ¦ ¦: --¦¦'¦ ¦ . 1344 Hit 137 A UfJ - . . - IttJ ItU ttlJt 111 6 , ;.. :. . ¦ 0O&amp; tec a toil usa ¦¦ '¦'¦-. . •-: \ ! —— . ; , - !8I 35J JBJ iffi | MS lUS Ml 1161 ¦¦". I" ' ' : ¦' ' ' ¦: ' ' •;'¦ )si 'ffri !t% ifi ' mi nil nil i3jj f«f f?I! iffl f?« ¦ ' . IStO ISJty*^^4S 1410 ;¦;¦¦.¦¦ [flufl " . ¦ . . {54.6 IStZ 130,3 I4fj /fft lil.T ¦ fin* i**s "'•* li9i (J7* "•' i - . ' - " tOTO 106.1 168.7 1070 117.1 116.6 i 14X7 1334 1311 1378 Ut.7 155.1 ¦..--¦ fISI 1174 /ISO U44 IJTJ 14t2 : . Wtf^ ?t.f 3i,Q ictS not IiOJ. ¦': ¦ . ' '.. . : — top --nahtsidc — ¦¦ ¦ 1411 1370 tilt I4ZO H76 146-0 IZS.S mi U7.t lU3 UtO 1411 . ¦ ' , io&amp;.o loi s toes io*.o itu no i ' ¦ '¦ ' 169Z tS7.t I74J&gt; 1737 1749 - Itt.O ¦ ' /jjj mo* mo U6.e ufa /4/e . ¦ ¦ ItiO 1246 lilt 130 J U9S lU9 139.4 IS7» 1544 1704 \ U~*^ | "" "'• "" "" $!?#!&gt; mm, ]— " "TcT/ side- — Ljj— ¦¦ l&amp; ... -^_ —3^L iil.7 1544 &gt;S3* 146T 'M ¦¦ i^— —« ¦»" /«.&lt; //i^ //M /*7.# /m , t7oa \\niA ,74* 1*9.7 M*.?Y/4SJ 1470 -. — i U4.4 ICtA I MA Uto ' . -— -broiler door /JOJ 130.7 134.5 /34J 150 J U7B !3t t IXt 133.6 125 J MO 111.9 119.S 1141 lit A tilt 109.7 IO3S to/7 101.7 1079 K&gt;4 3 1033 lOXS ; • ¦ , '.:¦**. :¦¦'¦- ;¦¦.- ¦; | Fig, 27.—Surface temperatures, oven F.i : ¦ .'.¦-. ¦¦- '¦;¦ -. ¦ . ¦ ¦- '.'-':"..¦ I ;"' . ¦ - ¦ '"-.'¦' ¦'¦'¦ "¦ '¦¦ .¦¦;.'¦¦: \ ; '¦/,.(¦ . ,- ¦!.-";:¦¦. ¦' ' " ¦ ( '¦ ¦''¦ 55 </seg>
         <seg id="p056">.'- - - , •-' l_ ¦ Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 \ , , -r *r o f o q c = q c -r c — x -r I/; i -1 i*isigi§ s i * s § s § s,: - -o q&gt;O»**One«;"i O m Oh O; O q ll w I o [I l c O ,OM/MOO'rr-ioc*N 1*00; C; i }I) 1 = giilssl S I 5 5 5 « S § I „ , C 1* C 5&gt; N fl O OOO'O-r — o%^©**" I'll illliiiillililii i a a a ;l '- -!• iSI i 13 issl f 3 i I I '3 il lii; i 11 i 1 1 11111 la - f-- =: . &#132; -, T . -c- ~ — a-. &lt;c &lt;-t ac — ¦ «*| .S = l^ - r-l " = :ia-r t t - :ni; :« « = tSSi ; - ca = - L_ *xq.,.&gt;qq * 0 5. i; «"."! 2 5 = £. 0 s-rcCir rr C *~l = ? &lt;~t t- ©= C O i{ .. J "*" *¦ **¦¦ ~&gt; &amp;\ -r t **¦ fi "*¦ ft t tt ""• *r *r »— £ ' 0 x l^. i/~ ac » ir; *^ "". — * '"^ &lt;~) 5" ** c. *^ ' ' 1 S Si3SF-'-jSS 3 S i ? S? 5 8 "5l !| , ''iMfl(n",M'l fl *. fi "' Nn m fj • [I |oj, w o««=*= -: r c =. 9 ST-' [; I&lt;l 1 — t 1 1 = o.^ocr-o^O'vs — — 00-ro ..T. {¦: I :|i i ¦'; , i .If 56 </seg>
         <seg id="p057">Selected Types of Gas Stoves Table 28.— Surface temperatures for small areas of oven A. Tmc" 1 2 3 4 5 «. 7 [ 8 9 10 11 11 500° 221.2 219.6 210.0 217.2 243.2 243.2 278.8 283.4 283.4 269.0 257.4 260.8 400° 191.5 190.0 183.0 186.1 2063 205.5 2035 221.2 222.0 218.8 214.0 214.8 300° 157.0 156.2 151.2 . 150.3 160.3 165.1 166.7 166.7 167.6 167.6 166.0 167.6 Tj™?"' 13: 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 500° 142.0 1345 1255 122.0 121.1 112.6 125.5 132.0 136.2 i' 41.2 158.6 1615 400° 121.11 112.2 108.7 103.5 102.5 103.5 1043 111.4 116.6 121.1 133.6 1345 300° 111.4! 103.5 '¦ 99.9 98.2 973 1035 102.5 107.0 107.8 1W.6 116.6 1103 TS'"' tf-j ;¦'¦-» 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 loo°~ 126 J' 133.6 133.6 133.6 1453 1W.4 HU 111.1 . 11U IH.I 1W.6 1102 400° 115.8! 121.1 121.1 120.2' 120.2 102.5 105.2 105.2 105.2 1035 1025 1043 : 300° 101.7; 107.8 107.8 107.0 1043 783 96.4 955 94.6 94.6 94.6 94.6 Table 29.—Surface temperatures for small areas of ovens Bs4 and 835. :fZf \\-'i V 4 s 6 7 a ¦.-/»; w un 500° 174.0 i 162.7 157.8 170.8 195.4 201.6 201.6 196.2 151 2 151 2 151.2 1503 400° 133.6 133.6 1303 137.8 162.7 168.4 170.8 166.7 132.8 133.6 132.0 132.8 300° 125.0 118.8 118.0 127.1 139.5 143.6 146.2 142.8 114.9 114.0 114.0 1145 Table 30—Surface temperatures for small areas of oven C: ' "¦¦¦(¦¦¦_ 2 . 3 ¦:¦ 4 1.. 6 X, 8 ! .". 9 ' 10 11 12 500° 167.2 183.1 187.9 188.3 193.2 192.6 1965. 222.0 214.4 1973 150.3 1745 400° 152.7 160.1 160.5 157.7 1573 1573 161.4 180.6 172.8 158.6 133.7 144.1 300° 144.1 146.1 145.7 154.6 152.4 151.1 152.4 161.1 1503 1395 109J 117.0 T17,1" 13 14 15 16 17 18 .19 20 21 22 23 24. 500° 1810 171.2 168.7 167.5 1655 165.1 166.7 177.7 1773 164.7 202.0 187,2 400° 1525 148.2 149.5 148.6 . 147.0 .144.0 146.1 151.5 151.5 140.7 170.8 1643 300° 127.4 127.4 1283 127.9 127.0 127.9 129.1 132.4 128.7 116.1 139.9 136.6 Table 31. — Suijace temperatures for small areas of oven D. "2T 1 7" 3 4. 15 &gt;f \i, -if .':-»"'; io 11 '2 13 ,M ~soo^ 195.4 195.4 197.0 197.0 193.8 193.8 2063 226.0 229.7 23U 240.0 237.6 214.0 210.8 400° 162.7 162.7 162.7 162.7 159.5 160.3 179.0 193.8 193.8 1985 203.2 197.0 179.8 1745 300° 132.8 132.8 133.6 132.0 1303 1295 140.4 15U 153.0 152.0 157.8 154.6 142.8 14U </seg>
         <seg id="p058">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 32.— Surface temperatures for small areas of oven E. Temper^ I | j I | jcurc ] j 2 I 3 ! 4 1 5 6 7 8 9 10 II 12 113 H L ' i ' I I sl»° Vfl.lt 116.1 122.il 12.5 Hlt.7 H2.1) 150.3 150.3 H9.5 116.2 110.4 129.5 137.8 H2.0 1(Xl= 102.5 1D2.5 112.2 111.1 121.1 121.1 125.5 128.7 126.2 126.2 120.2 112.2 121.1 121.6 «»r 11.(1 H. 6 16 4 98.2 99.0 99.0 105.2 107.8 108.7 107.8 103.5 99.0 107.0 107.8 Temper- " | "i I "' i lure | 15 , 16 17 | 111 I 19 20 21 22 23 21 25 26 27 28 500= m.5 112.0 147.8 152.8 119.5 119.5 150.3 157.8 171.0 183.0 183.0 178.2 170.8 163.5 ( *«' 126 2 121.6 IJ6.H 132.H 1J1.2 137.8 132.8 111.2 150.3 151.6 J51.6 151.2 117.0 H1.5 &lt;(«!= UI7» iih.s 112.2 H3.l 111.1 H1.4 109.6 109.6 113.1 116.6 117.6 118.4 117.6 117.6 Table 33.— Surface temperatures for small areas of oven F. !wl? 1 ' 2 &lt; 1 ¦ 5 ! 6 I 7 8 9 I 0 II 12 13 14 sui: II*: ITM r!4 ITiI.K 170.11 170.8 186.1 207.1 222.8 229.0 230.5 214.8 198.5 193.8 mi' I12(i IK. 2 1415 111.5 Nil 116.2 155.6 171.0 186.8 195.4 194.6 183.0 170.8 166.0 n«i' 1211 I22ii 122H 1214 12! 1 122.1) 131.2 141.2 149.5 153.6 153.6 144.5 137.8 137.0 Similarly the middle value denotes the temperature for 400° F., steady state, and the lower value for 300° F., steady state. Temperatures could not be suitably placed on certain areas which were too small and so the temperatures for these areas have been given in Tables 28 to 33. OPEN-DOOR LOSS During the investigation of electric ranges the loss of heat due to opening the oven door was determined. A similar test was performed for gas ovens so that a comparison could be made. The oven was first brought to the steady state for the desired test temperature, the loss being deter - mined at 300°, 400°, and 500° F., and then the input was increased slightly and the open-door test started. The door was opened for 20 seconds at 5-minute intervals. Obviously the temperature would not re - main constant as in the case of the empty-oven heat loss, but the average temperature was kept as nearly constant as possible. The heat loss due to opening the door was computed as follows: Let A equal the total heat loss in B.t.u. per hour at the oven tem - perature T°, as determined from the test data. This total heat loss is composed of two parts: first, the empty-oven heat loss at T° F., and second, the open-door heat loss for the 20 seconds opening at 5-minute intervals. Designating the empty-oven heat loss as B B.t.u. per hour, the difference between the total heat loss and the empty-oven heat loss, when both losses are observed at the same oven temperature, will be (A —B) B.t.u. per hour. During a one-hour period the door would be opened twelve times at 5-minute intervals; hence the heat lost every time the door was opened was (A. — B)/12 B.t.u. This represents the quantity of heat lost during </seg>
         <seg id="p059">I Selected Types of Gas Stoves «« -jr~~ -^ =- t^— t^— 7 t^ 7^= 7*= -r^ 7*= -r == I: L ¦ s JM : " ' : — — I : ¦ . ¦ ' ' I* I H I I I I -HL- L-L-^-H- O 10 Hi Zi JO J* . 40 M -SO 35 4O ¦ ' ; ¦ ¦ Time tri Htnotci . -..¦¦[. Fie. 28.—Variation of oven temperature when door is opened, oven C, average I; : . .'¦ temperature -fOO" F. . ¦*fr —T" —I 1 1 1 I.'.' I I 1 71 ¦••¦ • \ I too -»— : —j ~w~ i— ———-7^f i ta ______4^ 7 z- ¦;¦¦¦¦' ;¦¦*" z 7^/ ...— — -^y"— — ¦;¦¦'¦ - yg-^r I I I I ' I---. II . -JO 100 ISO ZOO tSQ JOQ JSO 400 4SQ 3OQ 350 QvtnTcmpenflvre m Oyrees Fahrenheit ; Fie. 29. —Open-door loss in B.t.u. per minute as a function of oven temperature. .- </seg>
         <seg id="p060">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 J 20 seconds, so the heat loss per unit time would be (A. — B)/240 B.t.u. per second or (A — B)/4 B.t.u. per minute, or 15(A — B) B.t.u. per hour. j For plotting the results, the unit used was B.t.u. per minute. While obtaining the data for the open-door loss, the oven could not be kept in the steady state. During the 20 seconds while the door was open the temperature dropped sharply about 200 degrees and during the first 40 seconds after the door was closed the temperature recovered almost as rapidly. An example of the fluctuation in temperature is shown in Figure 28. All of the ovens acted in a similar manner. The amount of heat lost in B.t.u. per minute is shown in Figure 29. No open-door loss data were obtained for oven F, but the curve for this oven should agree very closely with that of oven B '34. Since oven A had one of the highest heat losses and was the most rapid in cooling, it would be anticipated that the open-door loss would be in the same region as oven B '34. All of these ovens had the same area of door opening, as is shown in Table 2. It was noticed during the opera - tion of the open-door test for oven A that the thermostat began to operate as soon as the door was opened. This thermostat was located at the bottom and rear of the oven, in contrast to the other thermostats which were either at the mid-plane or the top. Evidently the cold draft of air sweeping in at the bottom affected the thermostat quickly enough so that an increase in heat was obtained earlier than in the other ovens. This seemed to be enough to lower the open-door loss for this oven. CHANGES IN DESIGN WHICH IMPROVE PERFORMANCE The technical performance of an oven must be considered in terms of all the aforementioned results, for a consideration of only one or two factors might lead to a distorted view. A discussion of one or two of the ovens should help as an example. Jf temperatures of 250° and 300° F. are considered as low baking temperatures it is apparent from Table 25 that with three of the ovens low temperatures were not obtained. The fact must not be ignored that these ovens are to lie used for actual baking and roasting. There is at present a demand for a controlled temperature of 300° F. for meat roasting, and some foods, such as fruit cakes, require a temperature of 250° F. The tests performed revealed that ovens B '35 and F obviously would not fulfill these requirements. Consider first oven B '35. What changes could be made so that lower temperatures could be obtained? The preheating time is controlled by the gas orifice adjustment, and the heat losses are a function of the oven con - struction. If orifice adjustment and oven construction are not modified these factors will remain unchanged. Low temperatures depend upon the ability of the burner to maintain a low by-pass flame and since the by-pass flame on the burner was adjusted to be as small as possible, no further adjustment here could be made. The trouble lay in the burner itself. Assuming from Table 4 that the input for a universal burner should be </seg>
         <seg id="p061">Selected Types os Gas Stoves 20,000 B.t.u. per hour per square inch of port area, the analysis as listed jy in Table 7 shows that this burner was designed to operate with an input of 28,428 B.t.u. per hour. Evidently there was too much port area. The I' next step was to compute the required port area according to recommenda - tions for proper burner design. This was done as follows: On the basis of an input of 8,000 B.Lu. per hour per cubic foot of oven space, the proper input for this oven should be 19,256 B.t.u. per hour. (The preheat curve in Figure 15 shows that with this input this oven heated to 500° F. quicker than any of the other ovens, the rate of heating being almost 32 degrees per minute.) Allowing 20,000 B.t.u. per hour per square inch, of port area, the required port area should be 05628 square inch. This burner was drilled with a No. 34 drill, and thus the • total number of ports necessary would be between 99 and 100. Allowing for the four small ports as indicated in Table 7, 24 ports on each side of the burner were closed with brass plugs so that 96 ports of No. 34 drill size and four ports of No. 42 drill size were left. With this decrease in the number of ports it was possible to decrease the by-pass flow of gas. The thermostat was then set at 400 and found to check. Next, the dial was set at 250 and the empty oven was maintained at a temperature of 3oo° f. :- ¦;;•.•; ¦:¦¦• ¦ ' ••.;. ¦¦¦:• .¦" .-.¦:¦¦ ' - .. At this time it would be well' to discuss some cooking tests that were conducted with this rebuilt oven. First, two fruit cakes having a total weight of 4 l/ 2 pounds" were baked at a temperature of 250° F. These cakes were baked in two long pans so that all fifteen couples could be used. The baking was started in a cold oven and in 10 minutes the temperature registered by the five mid-plane couples was 253.2° F. In the next 10 minutes the temperature rose to 261° F. and then gradually dropped to 255° F., where it was maintained for two hours. The tern- i; perature again began to rise until the maximum of 264° F. was reached at &gt; the end of 210 minutes. The total baking time was 240 minutes, during which time the temperature never went higher than 264° F. The cakes were excellently baked. ¦ Experiments were carried further by substituting wet sand for the fruit cake. The sand was baked in four oblong tin pans having dimensions of 3% by 7J4 hy 2 inches. Two pounds of the sand-water mixture were ;: contained in each pan, the sand and water being mixed in the proportion of 10 pounds of sand to l l/ 2 pounds of water. With the thermostat set at 250 the oven was maintained at!an average temperature of 251° F. for 3 hours and 15 minutes, the maximum being 258° F. and the minimum being 245.6° F. The first 30 minutes were used to bring the oven ter- j perature to 245.6° F. At the end of the period the sand was removed and weighed and it was found that practically all of the water had been ; evaporated. The sand could be considered as almost dry, since only 1/16 of an ounce of water was left in the 8 pounds of mixture. This test was repeated with the dial set at 300 and 400 and the results showed that this ! ..¦-'¦ .i/ ¦'¦----.".• ¦ ¦'.'¦.'. '.-..'"'. - . - i </seg>
         <seg id="p062">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 oven could be maintained at a temperature which corresponded exactly to the dial settings. Finally, this oven was used to roast six standing rib roasts, four of which weighed 10 pounds each and two weighed 8 pounds each. The roasting temperatures were 300° F. and 450° F. Again by using a couple in the center of the oven at trie top, trie oven temperature was checked during the roasting and every check showed that the oven air temperature around the thermostat agreed with the dial setting. It will be noticed that a similar situation arose with oven F. Reference to Table 7 shows that the burner in oven F should be used in an oven requiring an input of approximately 36,800 B.t.u. per hour. In contrast, the input required as determined from the oven size was 19,136 B.t.u. per hour. On the basis of the latter input, 128 ports of No. 40 drill size would be sufficient for this burner. The first experiment tried was a modification of the burner by plugging half of the ports in the oven burner. With the thermostat set at 250, temperatures slightly below 300° F. could he obtained, but such a burner would be unsatisfactory because the spacing between successive ports was too large. Thus, with the port spacing more than four times the diameter of the port, the flame would not travel readily from port to port. The next experiment tried was to drill a new burner. An undrilled burner was purchased from the manufacturer and drilled in the laboratory. The burner was drilled with a 7/64-inch drill, this size being only slightly smaller than the No. 34 drill recommended for a uni - versal burner. The burner was first drilled for 86 ports and although a temperature as low as 280° F. ivas obtained, the burner was not entirely satisfactory because there was a tendency for the flames to blow from the ports. With the 102 ports, the lowest temperature obtained for a dial setting of 2^o was 300 c F. This burner proved satisfactory since each port was carrying about 18H B.t.u. per hour. CONTUSIONS FOR OVEN TESTS The most evident conclusion to be drawn from the data obtained for ovens is that it is not possible to predict the performance of an oven in terms of known factors from other ovens. With regard to any one oven, certain (actors must be assumed unless tests ate performed to obtain reliable information. First it must be assumed that the actual oven tem - perature will agree with the dial setting. The calibration data showed that this assumption was invalid at the 400 mark for 43 per cent of the ovens tested. The calibration showed further that after the thermostat was adjusted so that the dial setting of 400 agreed with actual oven temperature, only 14 per cent of the ovens would have temperatures as low as 300° F. Secondly, no assumption that will give any clue relative to preheating time and heat losses can be made from the construction of the oven. It will be noticed from the preheat curves in Figure 15 that the fastest - heating ovens were A and B '35, which had insulation about half as thick as that of oven E, which ranked third. Likewise, where it would be </seg>
         <seg id="p063">! Selected Types of Gas Stoves j expected that the oven with the thickest insulation would have the lowest heat loss, the heat-loss curves in Figures 19 and 20 show that an oven , having only VA inches of insulation had the lowest heat loss. The manufacturer should recognize the importance of building a good ¦ oven. because the consumer must depend upon him for quality of oven in a stove. A good oven should preheat rapidly, it should have a low heat loss, it should have uniform temperatures within the oven, and the thermostat dial readings should agree with the oven temperatures. These factors are not difficult to obtain if care is used in construction. All the tests showed ;that the thermostats were reliable; that is, when-properly adjusted correct temperatures could be maintained. It should be the duty of every manufacturer to ascertain that each thermostat is properly cali - brated and adjusted before the stove is placed on the market for sale. Finally, the experiments performed on ovens B '35 and F definitely showed that ovens can be constructed to maintain temperatures of 250° F. Thus, more, attention should be given to burner design, for it is.in this sphere that most of the trouble rests. .-'. . : . THE PERFORMANCE OF THE SURFACE BURNERS AND i OVENS FOR ACTUAL COOKING 23 During the course of the investigation of these ranges, emphasis has been placed upon technical tests. The fact must not be forgotten, how - ever, that the primary purpose of cooking equipment is that of actually cooking food. Thus, in order to observe the performance of. the surface burners and ovens from the housewife's point of view, actual cooking practices were performed. It was felt that the one who did die cooking should know inothing of the results of the technical tests, so the only in - structions given were to perform the tests in the manner that the average housewife would do the cooking, placing emphasis upon the use of as little gas as possible to acquire the desired product—in order words, good cooking done as economically as possible. . • ;r ¦ The important features of these tests were to determine the amount of heat required; and the variations in the finished products. The important data for these tests are summarized in Tables 34 and 35. There was practically no: variation in the finished products cooked on the surface burners. The following comments were made on the baked products: The butter cakes were nicely browned. The custards were soft and smooth. The sponge cakes from ovens A, B, and E were evenly browned, the cakes from ovens G and F had a perfect brown and texture, while the cake from oven D was slightly cracked and rather brown. The thermostat for oven D should have been at 325° rather than 350° F. The apple pies were nicely browned, the ones from ovens B, C, and D being superior in color to those from ovens A, E, and F. The bread was about the same from each oven. The biscuits from ovens B, C, and E were nicely browned 33 All cooking operations were performed by Mrs. Edna B. Snyder of the research staff of the Home Economics Department. " ". . . </seg>
         <seg id="p064">Table 3*t. — Gas consumption tn B.t.u. for foods cooked on surface burners. mrmhly | &#132; Ni| j g,,.,,,,, ly Turn- j (..., ii.r.l ' I.m N,, (Ju.,rii,,, ;In f;j, ¦¦«¦,( I'jn N« &lt;.&gt;u..nt,, v Time j c; a . v, c ,l 5 A 1 li -I" 1.2564 I I .'I I Wi-. - &#132; 15 v 187H6 £ II 7 I', M l.m» &lt; " 11, .'i I.JMH 7 ', If,. 45 1.646! (J 1 B 4 I &lt;1 l.« 2« I 1 .' &lt;" 1,6X1.6 1 I 19-21 IMB2 B II 2' J « I .Sill I' 4 I W 2.SIH.H 4 2 14.(1 U11; C 7 I'j 21 1.4"&gt;2." " 11, 24 1.555.7 1 I 21 II 2 615 9 ? C4i 2" 1.'144 2I ' _¦¦; 1.7»5.(, 4 2 2&lt;i II I 2~2 4 " II I 11-I 1-- 211 1.2411.2 1 1 21 1.121.1 O 1) 7 1' j 22 1.227.6 " 11,I 1, 2" 1.17!/, 7 i, 15-22 I 717 8 * II 4 I 21 1.7' U." I -' 26 1.K112.S I I |g. I) 2.«12» PO I) 4' 2 U 1.7W.2 4 .&lt; )ll 2,141.2 4 2 24-11 J.514.S fl X 1 I'j &lt;ll 1.84».3&gt; I 1 26 2.014.9 r" E 7 I'j 27 2.010.7 7 I', II 2,605.8 7 V 4 21-0 2,»«3 5 S3 X -I 3 M 2,'»1.6« I 2 .12 2.757.3 1 1 21-0 2,-52!2 S E4»^ 2 _V) 2.729.0 4 i .V) 3J93.fi 4 2 22- 0 3.M4.S X I I'j 2.1 1,1&lt;)5.« 1 1 20 865 5 C*\ F " 11-I 1-- 23 1.365.5 7 11, 28 1.401.8 7 ij IK. 0 1.585 7 P 4 I 27 1,581.6 I 2 25 1.422.0 I I 20-0 1/J77 5 F 4 1 2 3'J 1.729.0' 4 3 40 2.156.3 4 2 25-0 2.408.8 64 </seg>
         <seg id="p065">l'anliroilcd itcak ; . Pot roast .;¦¦ Micmkly skil|ec | Weight | Shrinkage ] Time , | Gal vied Weight | Shrinkage | Time | Gas used [ pcHl.'.'m'c.n TTi, Os. . Os, ,\lin. Set. HIM. /&gt;.'. Or. lin. «./.&lt;/. . B.IM. ¦a" Aluminum ' 155/116 3 l/l* 11-!' 'S 4.039. 17 &gt;/» HI . 5.W15.5 1,390 c ;.: .'.. ¦ -iron 1 C 3/8 4 5/8 14-0 .' 1,660.5. 5.318 •' 29 5/8 I7fi '¦ .8.009.3 . . 1,498 C Aluminum I 4 1/8 . 4 1/2 . 14-0 • - 1,571.5 „ Iron 1 59/16 ¦ 57/16 .12-0 . . 1.4695 ¦..-.¦ 4.406 313/8 . 136 9.090.0 2,060« CO ."¦•-. I&gt; ¦•• Aluminum 1 2 1/16 3 1/2 ! 9-50 1,296.8 g! F Iron . I 115/16 3-3/4. : .14-10 1,903.8 3.336 215/16 -141 6,181.2 1,840 .W ; ¦ .. E'• '¦"¦ Aluminum &#132;- 1 1 9/16 4 7/8,. 14-7. 1,850.4 : . U :,.»:. i ron .'.;. 1 69/16. 4 1/16 14-47 . 1,347.3 / 3.855 207/16 - 148 4,868.2 ' 1,263 g 1 .. P . Aluminum 1 '69/16 ¦ 5 5/16 16-4 1,414.0 .¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦•¦¦..¦.• ¦- ' .• ¦ ¦ '•.¦¦': ¦—— — r-i ::'¦:—:: — " ¦ ¦. ~ ....... ~~ 3 iDeholcs whole potatoes.. ... .¦': . - - ¦ . ..'¦ .:. . »5 ¦¦'.'¦ ¦ 'Simmer used —evenly cooked. . ' .'¦¦. . ¦ ¦ P* * Simmer vied— water would not boil around outside. ¦ • ... .. .'¦¦¦.¦ ;, . V —- .— *Low flame usetl^cvenly cooked. .- - . . &#132;:' , ¦¦¦ O ' sMore water would be needed if not carefully watched. , : . .... ¦ • Some water left on potatbei at end of cooking but they were burned on bottom £» .-.-.¦¦• 'Water could not be kept boiling with limmcr— low flame uicil. ' . J- 1 - •Temperature too high. Flame coald not be-torncd low enough. . .: :.....-¦ "&gt; 65 </seg>
         <seg id="p066">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 Table 35.— Gas consumption in 8.(.v. for foods coo\ed in ovens and broilers. ' I Brcjd Buncr cake Own 1 No. l mvf 7.nd _V^^L_ »»"»« W.- id ) Ca , u&gt;c d 1)1,1 1 fc-n,"! 6" "'"* Itind of p»n Dill Time 1 Dal Time bred I Preheat 1 Balunt I i/, n i/,,, /!». r« /;./.«. ¦"'»¦ •"'"¦ B.iJi - &gt;. - U.,m,n,,n, 450 li' 450 15 3-4 9.817.2 350 10 60 8.120.0 JW X \ i r, m 45(1 1" 4511 15 3- 1 9.«8.9 15(1 .Ml A &#132; Tin 4511 15 45(1 45 111- tl' 12.645.2 _____ ~B 35~2 ~Miimmum «fl IS 450 22 !¦ li 9.625.3 U35 2 Pvret 45:. 15 45(1 15 2 4 9.191.0 .Wl 10 SO' 5.524.0 150 JO B!5 (, Tin 45" 15 450 15 111- 4 11.190.0 )511 !5 t ! Aluminum 4511 15 45(1 15 i- 'J 10.100.0 c ; f- m 450 15 450 15 J- 3 9,453.0 350 15 66 8.393.0 350 30 r 6 Tin 45" 15 450 15 10" ' 11.9 M.0 JM 55 ~D .' tlummum 45., 15 4511 15 !- 9 9..112.2 n ; &#132;v , ., 45ii 15 451' l 15 15 9.170.1S fiO 12 73= 5.%8.0 ill [, &#132; |-, n 4vi 15 45ii 45 111- s', 11.1911.» t I Mmmmim 450 15 45(1 15 i- II X.610.2 X ; &#132;„„ 4in |? 45M 14 14 8.645.6 350 10 77 ' 8.655.0 15(1 t! t -],„ 45ii ',5 45" !5 7 d 11.H09.0 .150 )5 ' Aliiinir.uni 45" I' 45" 45 1- 1 12.019.0 h ' [i ur , 4Sci IS 45" 45 &lt;•(,', 11.8574 .150 14 82 11.334.-l [. i, tln 45ii 1^ 45u 1,0 ln-14 15.3*1.8 S| ,,. nt ,. , jk , I ii.ur.l Apple pit -r Ti™T~j: , ,„,, T-"?£Z_l t " &#132;,C , |",."i^."' ' '''--""¦ .| Ca ,used c ""' itehc«-«3i!jl &#132;rr l ,,.l , li..kmß | (" ""°' liul'Time | Dial I Tim. I „„ ¦./,„ /;¦„ »"&gt; «¦•• '""¦ ¦"'"¦ "'"¦ "'•"¦ „,-.. &#132;= 1,, ifl 11 151 4 450 15 450 V) 9.645.5 , UJ, I' • '¦" '¦ ' j;o ](, „.„ ,J, „ 5,. M,4,., 05 ,„ |..l 1...11».'&gt; «. 15 4» W ».«" ,„, ,= „, &#132;|:, P5 15 H5 H.f.754 450 15 450 2(1 9.393.0 1 U" .^ "¦ - 350 , 5 '&#132; „„ 15 45 :.»75.0 125 1" &gt;5 1(1.650" 450 15 45(1 20 9.100.1 r i; 5 15 Wl 7.635.6 W 10 125= 10.706.0 45(1 15 «n 18 8.918.3 f 325 15 30 11.958.4 325 10 90 12,301.8 ¦ISO IS W 45 11.312.0 </seg>
         <seg id="p067">: Selected Types of Gas Stoves c Biking powder biscuit! ' Rolled rib roan ' Cmuk4 r? ni,l I Time lr.iu.nl U-Juht I *&gt;&gt;"•&gt;*¦ I T"'al I ?'chc* I KM"'"g I Gai P""1 - -° D'al iT^aOgJV.ngr"'"'" 1- '8l"l age I Time |pial I TlrTeJDiat) T.me I imd ""*' M.'v. Mm. 8.1.v. I&gt;j. Or. : 0:. Mm. Mm. M/n. B.MI. B.«j(. . ' 500 20 A 450 ..« 14 . 6,610.4 5- 3/8 23 5/8 169 500 22 350 125 23,785.5 4,730 ¦(00 122 835 450 15 12 5,736.8 5-2 7/» 17 1/2 175 500 20 500 20 21,750.0 1,200 350 135 ¦C 450 15 11 7,191.2 5-2 161/2 162 500 20 500 20 19,008.2 . 3,710 I) 450 15 15 6,524.6 350 122 I) 500 15 '12 8,484.0' 6- 1/8 17 7/8 192 500 20 500 20 21,008.0 3,500 . . . ¦ . 350 152 F. 450 15 12 6,140.8 5-i 19 1/4 203 600 30 600 17 21,210.0 4,195 ¦ - 450 19» F 450 15 18 7,837.6 4-35/16 19 3/16 155 500 20 500 20 23,785.5 5,650 ..: ¦ . . 350 115 - [ . : - Broiled lirloin slcak . ¦ I ' s Broiling I Gal Uic&lt;* Broiler Weight Shrinkage, Thickneu ' I Gal uicd per Ib. ' ¦ -|-'¦¦;¦' Dial ] Time I meal Lbi.Oz. Os. In. Mm. 8.1.8. Bl.il. A 3-13 5/16. tin 11/2 550 22 5,858.0 1,530 B -35 4-3 111/2 1 1/2 broil 261/4 7,878.0 1,880 C 2-13 1/8 15 11/16 1 broil 22 6,413.5 2,275 D 3-11/8 17 1/8 ¦' 1 550 25 ¦ 6J53.0 2.070 E 2-113/4 16 1 : .-• 27 .7,494.2 2.900 F 4-1-/8 17 9/16 I 1/2 broil « 11,473.6 2,785 1 Flame extinguished al 70 minutes. • Preheat encrey calculated. 3 Flame extinguished at 64 minutes. T Repeated—not browned at 450 —see text. ,&lt;. ' 3 Flame extinguished at 74 minutes. * Part of the roasting was done on retained heat. 1 Flame extinguished at 50 minutes. . •Separate broiling compartment —no heat control. 5 Flame extinguished at 105 minutes. . . ' , on both top and bottom and while those from oven F were quite evenly browned, the quality would have been better i£ the thermostat had been set at 500° F. The biscuits from oven A were not as brown in the center of trie sheet as those around the outside. With the thermostat o£ oven.D set at 450° F.jthe biscuits were not evenly browned, those on the left side of the oven being browner than those on the right. With the thermostat set at 500° F. a good product was obtained. The rolled roasts were nicely browned but rare inside. The steaks from broilers A and B were very rare inside, nicely browned outside, and slightly burned near the bone.; The other four steaks were broiled medium rare. " . The final question to be considered is, How do the results of the cooking tests compare with the results of the technical tests? Analyzing the surface burner and oven cooking tests on the basis of first, second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth place for each similar set of tests and then finding the average for each burner assembly and oven, the final ranking is as follows: ¦. . ¦ \ '_. • i - Surface . '.; ¦." ' ¦..'..¦ .-..'.. ' Place burner Rank Oven Rank Ist \ F 1.78 , E 1.88 2nd - B ;:.;. 2.21 , B 2.66 3rd D 3.43 D 3.00 4th A 5.91 C , i.77 sth . ' C 4.H ' A 4.11 6lh E ¦"• . 5.50 , F 5.77 </seg>
         <seg id="p068">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 according to the cooking tests. AP?ENDK 1 LABORATORY AND EQUIPMENT P* experience fad UW - k fet't &amp;X Kmprwit as nearly constant as poss.blc dunng men tests Jl cotlswlctc(l&lt; rm pl.shc.l by ,h, use ofj&gt;«™ f»»^ [- f n ° d X £^ S C W?I&lt;: conned by a s^ss few £ •« * * ™adiustcd Sorthmp portable po en »'™^" "^ '^ , made by tw i stin g together ,o within approximately 0., le E e&lt; X me P M Milgsfiilsipp value used as the oa«s K a x/h/d Usin K this method the orifice tem - perature must be kept «^ 75 F h.s kng "^ dctcrmi dat the 7^ZZ^TtrZ^ n Natural Gas Company, the, va.ues be,n S determined by a density balance. by </seg>
         <seg id="p069">Selected Types of Gas Stoves Chemist's Handbook (3d cd.) A. G. A., 1929; Sampling products of combustion from gas appliances, F. E. Vandavecr, A. G. A. Mo., October, 1929;, Carbon monoxide in the products of combustion from natural gas burners, Bureau of Standards Tech. Paper, 212, 1922; A method for testing gas appliances to determine their safety from pro - ducing carbon monoxide, Bureau of Standards Tech. Paper 304) 1926; Sampling and examination of mine gas and natural gas, Bureau of Mines, Bui. 197, 1926; and Bureau of mines Orsat apparatus for gas analysis, Bureau of Mines, Tech. Paper 320, 1925. ;.¦'." ;., ,¦_."; ¦'/:/ appendkh ,¦¦¦¦!. "/¦ ''¦ METER CALIBRATION : The displacement method as outlined in Industrial Gas Calorimitryl was used to calibrate the meter. A copper tank having a capacity of 1.8 cubic feet was equipped as an aspirator bottle. The volume of gas drawn through the meter was calculated from the corresponding weight of water displaced from the tank. Before measurements were taken, the water in the tank was thoroughly saturated with gas. Jn. making the tests, the water in the meter and tank and the gas passing through the meter and the tank were kept as near room temperature as possible. In most of the tests this was | accomplished so that no temperature correction had to be made. Corrections were \ made for buoyancy, density of water, pressure difference of gas in meter and in tank, and temperature difference of gas in meter and tank. A sample data sheet for one test is given in Table 36. ! , A total of fourteen tests were made, covering full revolutions and quarter rcvolu - i. tions. The average volumes of gas passed as determined from the tests were as follows: for one revolution, 1.0032 cubic feet; for the first quarter revolution, meter reading 0.00 to 0.25, 0.2535 cubic foot; for the second quarter revolution, meter , reading 0.25 to 0.50, 0.2554 cubic foot; for the third quarter, meter reading 0.50 to 0.75, 0.2441 cubic foot; and for the fourth quarter, meter reading 0.75 to 1.00, 0.2505 cubic foot. ( '¦ .;-'¦ ""'.¦'' The results of the calibration show that each quarter did not deliver the same volume of gas and the volume of one revolution was slightly greater than one cubic toot. However, since in most cases the volume of gas consumed was very small, ho: corrections on meter readings were made for the experimental tests. ¦ .' Table 36.— Sample data sheet for meter calibration. Time. ." .-.; ¦ •¦•••. 4 minutes, 12.4 seconds Meter reading cubic feet.. ;....Start 3802.9, end 3803.9 Room temperature, degrees Centigrade 25.0 Meter temperature, degrees Centigrade • 22.5 Botilc temperature, degrees Centigrade '. . : . 22.0 Barometric pressure, millimeter of mercury.... ....; 7i02 Total gai pressure at meter inlet, millimeters of mercury......'... . 759.45 Total gas pressure in bottle, millimeters of mercury.... ....'. 753,85 Weight of water, grams .-........;. ...........; 28,511,00 Computation: . . . ¦ ' .*. v . ' Weight of water, grams ..: .;...... ... 28,511.0 Correction for buoyancy ......'........... ;. 4" 28.8 Correction for density of water... ..; &#132;. + ".0 Correction for difference of temperature of gas in meter and.in b0tt1e...;....:... —21017 Correction lor difference of pressure of gai in mcterand in bottle.... -f 45.47. -Volume o£ gas passed into meter, cubic centimeter 5................ 28,441.00 Volume of jps passed into meter, cubic feer— ... .*— IJIO4O .-¦-. ¦'.'•¦ ¦:¦ ¦;¦:.-.¦.¦:¦;¦¦¦.¦.¦:¦".lEsr'-Bbx.: ¦;'¦•¦,¦..¦¦..- .. .-¦ ¦ .;" :¦¦ When testing' o£ the surface burners was started, the plan was adopted to build several types of burners in an auxiliary burner box, thereby reducing in quantity the number of stoves necessary for testing. This was thought advisable since the number 'Bureau of Standards Tech. Paper 36, 1914. . • : '.. " ¦¦ ' . ¦ ' </seg>
         <seg id="p070">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 of types of surface burners was greater than the number of types of ovens. The burner box was constructed of 10-inch white pine having a thtckftCSS of 13/16 inch. Its width and length was sufficient to accommodate the stove top of Type E assembly and for those assemblies where only one-half of the top was used .the other half was filled in with wood. The burner box was equipped with a metal drip pan below the burners. The entire box was built on a üblc; the gas manifold ,wa^s placed inside the box so that the burners were protected from drafts. In all cases the assembly of burners was made to duplicate the assembly in the stove. A diagram of the box showing Type C grate is shown in Figure 30. Ik., iu.—Dwfjr.im of test box. Alter the preliminary experiments iuul been conducted on the Type 0 assembly, tests no the burner box assembly were performed. Early in the tests it became evident that this plan would have to be discontinued, for the wooden box did not react in the same manner as the metal box of a stove. Since the grate rested on asbestos laid between the metal and wood, it is obvious that the first thermal insulation between grate and box started here. Next, heat could not be readily passed from the interior of the box to the exterior by conduction and convection. On the whole, this constructed burner box was an insulated box assembly and thus not a duplicate of burner box construction in the stoves. The result of ibis type of construction would be higher efficiencies than would be found with the stove burner-box assemblies. This is shown by comparing the efficiencies of the Type E assembly with those of the Type J assembly in Table 12. Thus, the efficiencies found for Types fi, H, and J must be considered as being higher than they would have been had the tests been conducted with the burners built in the stoves. APPENDIX IV THE EFFECT OF TEMPERATURE ON GAS RATE FOR TYPE A. BURNER When it was decided that the time of heating would have to be corrected, so that heating periods could be compared on a common basis, an attempt was made to dis - cover what factors were affected by temperature in changing the gas rate. In Bureau of Standards Research Paper 49 (1929) the cftcct of temperature on the discharge coefficient of a square-edged orifice is discussed but no data are given which would help in locating the region of flow for the small orifices such as arc used on gas stoves. According to the work of Hodgson, one would expect that these gas stove orifices would be operating in a region of "clastic" flow where both density and viscosity have an effect. The particular factor of interest is the relation of the discharge coefficient to Reynold's number. Hodgson's "discharge coefficient-Reynolds number" curves arc given </seg>
         <seg id="p071">;.'¦. Selected Types of Gas Stoves Table 37.— Change in gas rate with temperature for Type A burner. .. .¦¦'.. ¦ Cas rate Discharge ¦ : : Gas cock temperature - | ¦ coefficient -¦ . _ . : ; . \ ' 1 *¦ DM, P. ¦¦""¦" ¦ Cti.tt./hr. Cu.11./hr. ¦ 77.7 9.05 ..... .0.8300 86J0....... ..: ....:.........:....., ... -¦¦'¦..MM 0.8105 92.3 ...........:.... 8.92 0.8060 103.5 ... 8.780 : 0.7850 105.9......; 8.80 .... 0.7840 119.8 ; 8.66 0.7630 121.5. .......................; ... 8.650 0.7600. 129.0 8.63 .... 0.7530 1345 ..„.......;...... ... ... 8.510 0.7380 134.8 .: I 857 .... 0.7430 137.8... 853 .... 0.7380 H0.6.::.. .;.... 5.16 .... 0.7310 142.8 ... 8.135 0.7250 H3.5 8.49 • .... j 0.7300 . 146.5.. 8.46 .... | 0.7260 ' ¦ 149.5... ... 8.355 i 0.7150 I 154.1....... ..:....... :;¦.¦ " 8.390 I . 0.7140 I 156.2 ... BJ6O ) 0.7110 : 111 — I I I—] r—i I—] 1 1 1 1 1 ri [— : ¦ H : ... % fc^^7~ — — . . —— — — — —— - —- — — ¦ ... .zh ¦—; — —- —i- —¦— ¦ j ¦"4 is 40 to co no iti tx&gt; ito tso too tv ito uo wxo mo ¦¦'.'¦'.¦¦ Fie. 31. —Relation of discharge coefficient to Reynolds number according to Hodgson. : ' 'f~C. in Figure 31. For Reynolds numbers from 0 to 5 the region of flow is considered as .. . • viscous and in this region change in the discharge coefficient is due only to viscosity. ;' For Reynolds numbers greater than about 150, the region of flow is considered as ',' v- turbulent and only density has an effect. Between Reynolds numbers 5 and 150, the i 1 region is a viscous-turbulent flow where both density and viscosity have an effect. The ! • question to be answered in the present work is as follows: If data obtained for the if ; correction factor curves can be used to determine the curve showing the relation be- I ¦ tween the discharge coefficient and Reynolds number, where would it fall on the curves ¦;' -': ' ¦ . in Figure 31? . ' ' i . ' ' ¦', ¦" " !¦!=¦ ¦'•¦¦¦; -',' ;"j-v--;;.:v ¦¦¦-?&gt;¦ ¦¦¦¦¦¦;.- i:: ¦.'•. -:. '¦: ¦'¦".. . . j '...¦¦¦ ....'. ¦• ' . '.¦'.;.¦.'•[ ¦ ¦- '• </seg>
         <seg id="p072">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 j The data (or the actual gas rate in cubic feet per hour as a function of temperature 1 for Type A burner set for a gas rale of &lt;J cubic feet per hour for a total pressure of { 30 inches of mercury. 60° F., gas cock temperature 75° F., and specific gravity 0.72 arc given in Table 37. In determining the Reynolds number for this orifice it must be ; remembered that the conditions arc not ideal, for the orifice; area could not be measured, because it was nf the adjustable type. However, by regarding the orifice as a fixed orifice, that would give a gas rate of 9 cubic feet per hour under the above conditions, comparable results may be obtained. From the data in Table 37 the discharge coefficient may be computed, for by definition the discharge coefficient X is equal to the ratio of the actual discharge to the theoretical discharge. The theoretical discharge in cubic feet per hour is given by j the equation , Q = 1f,58.5a N /h/d (7) white Q. a. h. anil d have the same units as in equation 1.- Since the value of A will be affected by temperature, the theoretical discharge will increase with temperature. This was taken into account in computing K. The value of "a" used in computing the theoretical discharge was 0.0027H square inch. This is the area' of a No. 53 drill. The change of discharge coefficient X with temperature is given in Figure 32. The change of both the actual gas rate and the theoretical gas fate with temperature a giwn in the same figure. "n —i —i —I —1 —1 —I —I —FT* .-V 1 H-7^ '— "\^ \7 "\ -¦Hn \y{/ —r"wt rr —^ —;^v * s.»vH ——P^ '"* / OiscMroe \ - ,i n -J- -coillicirttK =*&lt;— "« 70 «.. /- 68 Sa7l 0 90 o 0 UO 130 140 ISO 160 Go* Cock Temperature in Pefre*3 Fahrenheit Hii.. 32.—change iif &lt;lischargc cncflicicnt with temperature, showing j. also actual anil theoretical gas rates in cubic feet per hour. i Mhc juujl .luchjrtc ii Riven hi cqujlu.n 1 (sec p. HI. i </seg>
         <seg id="p073">Selected Types of Gas Stoves From Bureau of Standards Research Paper 49 it is pointed out that X = f(b,s,d,u) (8) where b = diameter o£ orifice ¦ . s = average speed of flow ;, ¦ • d = density ; v = viscosity , . ¦ ¦ ¦ . . ; . . Since X 'is by definition a dimcnsionlcss quantity of zero dimensions, all of the' terms in the brackets must be zero dimensions. The. quantities b, s, d t and v do not satisfy these conditions and they can not therefore appear separately. However, they can be taken in combinations, each of which when taken as a whole will be dimcn - sionlcss. The expression : .• ; ¦ . .... [ bsd/u = R ;,.-¦- . (9) will satisfy this requirement, as is evident upon substitution from the dimensional equations ' . i . '...¦ : ¦ [b] =L; [s] = LT-1; [d] = ML^; [uj = ML-IT-1 and further there is no other combination which will satisfy this requirement. Hence, X takes on the more specific form :'".:' X = F(bsd/u) "'= F(R) : (10) R is called the Reynolds number. Since s = q/a, R may be written in the form '"•'¦¦) R = 4qd/nbu (11) Of these quantities the effect of temperature on b is so small that b may be considered as constant, and the variation of q with temperature can be found from Figure 32. The change in density with temperature may be computed from the usual equation for the rclatiop of density to temperature. Finally, using the values of 0.000131, :JV3 JB" — t) «3- — la ib in ?. &gt; '"V . ,;;" ¦-': • ¦ V:^ ¦ .•¦ '¦;¦'¦'.-..: Fie. 33. —Discharge coefficient—• Reynolds number ¦curve for orifice of type A burner. </seg>
         <seg id="p074">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 86 0.000136, and 0.000160 poises as the viscosity of the gas at o°, 16°, and 100" C. respectively, intermediate points may be computed by Sutherland's formula u&gt; = u.(T. + C/T + C)(T/T.)Y» (_l2) By this procedure R was computed and values of X were plotted against ¦y/;i/4 so that the results would conform to the same scale as used by Hodgson. This curve is shown in Figure 33. If X had been plotted against R, the value of X as a function of R would have taken the form X = 0.391+0.0011R (13; It is evident from the curve in Figure 33 and the equation for X that the orifice was operating in a region of flow that began to be turbulent-viscous soon after it left the viscous region. This analysis can not be considered to be worth more than an attempt to determine approximately the region of flow, principally because the data obtained were not of the type to be sufficiently accurate to stand the test ot precision work. The analysis is worth something inasmuch as it shows the effect temperature has in making great change in gas rate when all other factors which might affect gas rate arc kept unchanged. [2M] </seg>
         <seg id="p075"/>
         <seg id="p076"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>