<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Annual Forage Crops</title>
               <date value="1925-04">1925-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 206 April, 1925 ANNUAL FORAGE CROPS T. A. KIESSELBACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Date of seeding tests with Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass... 19 Rate of seeding tests with Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass. ...21 Physical composition of the forage from various rates of seeding. 24 Chemical composition of the forage from various rates of seeding 26 Effect of the time of cutting upon the lorage yield of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass 28 Effect of the time of cutting upon the chemical composition Relative palatability of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay Comparative curing rates of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay Sorghum and Sudan grass as pasture crops Relation of planting rate to yield of corn silage Relation of variety type to yield of corn silage.. Relation of variety type to yield of sorghum silage 38 4(1 Comparative yields of corn and corn and soybeans mixtures for silage 41 Comparative yields of root crops 4^ Experimental technique of these investigations 13 Summary ... 3 Relative importance of forage and grain crops .... 7 Varieties ... i) Relative chemical composition of grasses and legumes 13 Comparison of crops in different parts of the state .14 Methods of seeding .17 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. The oarly and medium late varieties of sweet sorghum together with Sudan grass, and Common and German millet comprise the most important annual forage crops suitable for hay in this state. Sudan grass is the only one of these especially suitable as an annual pasture crop. 2. In a comparative 4-year test of 24 varieties of annual forage crops at the Nebraska Experiment Station, the sweet sorghums proved most productive of cured forage. Black Amber sorghum yielded 4.65 tons per acre. The yield of the other 23 crops varied from 26 to 116 per cent of this yield. Black Amber sorghum was surpassed in yield by 7 later maturing sweet sorghums and 1 grain sorghum which aver - aged 10 per cent more forage. The Sudan grass yield was 70 per cent of that from Black Amber sorghum whereas Common and German millet each yielded 75 per cent as much as the sorghum. Comparable alfalfa hay yields averaged 4.09 tons per acre. Black "Amber is the earliest maturing of tha commercial varieties of sweet sorghum. This quality in addition to its relatively fine growth, makes it a very satisfactory sort for the entire state. Red Amber, Early Sumac, and Western Orange are medium late varieties which yield sufficiently more to justify a more extended trial on farms in the southern part of the state. 3. Comparative values of leguminous and non-leguminous hay may be judged in part by their fodder analyses. As a 3-year average the protein content of sorghum, Sudan grass and alfalfa hay was found to be 5.7, 6.6, and 18.7 per cent, respectively. In nitrogen-free ex - tract these 3 crops analyzed 52.8, 46.7, and 40.7 par cent, and in crude fiber 30.7, 35.6, and 28.3 per cent, respectively. Feeds com - paratively high in protein are considered most valuable. 4. When grown as a grain crop corn yielded 60, 71, 55, and 61 per cent as much fodder as sorghum grown for forage at Lincoln, North Platte, Scottsbluff, and Valentine, Nebraska, respectively. At Lincoln, however, when both crops were seeded with a grain drill, the corn yield was 83 per cent of the sorghum. Yields of sheaf oats at Lincoln, North Platte, and Scottsbluff were 28, 39, and 33 per cent of the sorghum yield at these respective places. The relative superiority in total production of sorghum compared with corn in - creases as conditions for growth become more unfavorable. When seeded in comparable tests and according to the accepted cultural practices for the locality, Sudan grass yielded 69, 76, and 47 per cent as much as sorghum at Lincoln, North Platte, and Valentine, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">5. In a 7-year comparison of seeding methods at the Experiment Station, highest yields were obtained from seeding with a press drill. Sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn yielded 5.47, 3.76, 4.62, and 4.54 tons per acre, respectively, when seeded in this manner. In comparison with drilling, the yields of sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir, and field corn were reduced 14, 7, 10, and 20 per cent, respectively, when seeded broadcast. As compared with drilling, surface planting of sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn in cultivated rows de - creased the yields 35, 19, 35, and 32 per cent, respectively. In a 4-year test, these 4 crops yielded 20, 18, 27, and 12 per cent less respectively when listed than when surface planted in cultivated rows. 6. Black Amber sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn pro - duced average annual grain or seed yields of 1538, 564, 942, and 2332 pounds per acre, respectively, when grown during a 3-year period in cultivated rows. 7. The seeding of sorghum and Sudan grass should follow soon after corn planting. These crops were seeded during a 4-year period on May 15 and thereafter at 10-day intervals until July 5. Sorghum seeded May 15 yielded 4.87 tons per acre while the yields from the succeeding plantings were 95, 88, 86, 76, and 66 per cent as great. Sudan grass seeded May 15 yielded 3.85 tons per acre. The yields from the 5 successive later seedings were 101, 92, 89, 73, and 61 per cent as much. 8. There may be a rather wide range in seeding rates without very materially changing the yield. In a 7-year comparison, sorghum and Sudan grass were seeded at 5 rates varying from 25 to 150 pounds for the sorghum and from 20 to 80 pounds per acre for the Sudan grass. Relative average yields of sorghum seeded during 7 years at the rates of 25, 50, 75, 100, and 150 pounds per acre were 100, 110, 106, 113, and 114 per cent, respectively. Corresponding relative yields for Sudan grass seeded at 20, 30, 40, 60, and 80 pounds per acre were 100, 101, 105, 106, and 107 per cent. Sudan grass seeded during a shorter period at 10 pounds per acre yielded 5 per cent less than the 20-pound rate and when seeded at 120 pounds per acre yielded the same as the 80-pound rate. Coarseness of the forage as measured by stem diameters may be very materially changed by seeding rate. As a 3-year average, sorghum seeded 150 pounds per acre was but 52 per cent as coarse as sorghum seeded 25 pounds per acre. Sudan grass seeded 80 pounds per acre was but 65 per cent as coarse as that seeded 10 pounds per acre. As an average for the seeding rates, the stems, leaves, and heads com - prised 47.5, 35.5, and 17.0 per cent, respectively, of sorghum and 49.7, 32.5, and 17.7 per cent of Sudan grass. Sorghum seeded at 125 pounds per acre had the same average coarseness as Sudan grass seeded at 30 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The chemical composition of sorghum and Sudan grass forage and the yield of nutrients per acre were not affected very decidedly by change in seeding rate. 9. Highest yields can be expected from sorghum and Sudan grass if harvesting is delayed until they are rather mature even tho 2 crops may be secured when harvested at more immature stages. Harvest - ing of Sudan grass should not be delayed until full maturity since the yields will be reduced by shattering of leaves and seed soon after the seed has reached the soft dough stage. When sorghum was harvested at the 4 respective stages of maturity (a) first heads appearing, (b) well-headed, (c) seed soft dough, and (d) seed ripe, the relative yields were 100, 117, 129, and 138 per cent. Corresponding Sudan grass yields were 100, 114, 128, and 109 per cent, respectively. The chemical composition of sorghum and Sudan grass hay depends to a considerable extent on the stage of maturity of the crop at time of harvest. The highest yield of nutrients per acre, however, corresponds in the main with the highest acre yield of hay. 10. When fed to a mixed lot of cattle in connection with a rather limited feed of corn silage, 71 and 62 per cent of the sorghum and Sudan grass hay, respectively, were consumed. The percentage of ref - use will depend largely on the amount and kind of feed available to the stock. 11. Being relatively coarse stemmed grasses, sorghum and Sudan grass cure very slowly when cut for hay. Sudan grass, however, will dry at a rate materially faster than that of sorghum and consequently can be stacked sooner. In a rate-of-curing test, Sudan grass had dried to 26 per cent moisture content when sorghum still contained 46 per cent. 12. Since there is far less danger from prussic acid poisoning in pasturing Sudan grass than in the case of sorghum it has a much wider use as a pasture crop. During the relatively hot, dry, summer months Sudan grass pasture doubtless has a higher carrying capacity than any other pasture crop. 13. Corn, planted at rates the equivalent of 1 to 6 plants per hill, was found to yield the most silage at 4 plants per hill. Relative yields on a 15 per cent moisture basis for the 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 rates were 100, 153, 173, 187, 183, and 179 percent, respectively. The highest grain yield was obtained at 3 plants per hill or relative yields of 100, 155, 170, 167, 166, and 144 per cent, respectively, for the 6 successive increased rates of planting. 14. In a silage test with 5 types of corn varying as to length of growing season, it was found advantageous to grow the local full - season types. 15. In a sorghum variety silage test, relative yields of 100, 107, 110, 106, and 95 per cent, respectively, were obtained for Black Amber, Red Amber, Early Sumac, Kansas Orange, and Blackhull kafir. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Corresponding relative grain yields were 100, 89, 69, 29, and 64 per cent. Black Amber sorghum yielded 3.27 tons of silage with 29.9 bushels of grain per acre in contrast with 3.44 tons of corn silage (15 per cent moisture basis) containing 43.6 bushels of grain per acre, when planted at the optimum rate. 16. Corn and soybeans planted in combination for silage yielded 3.95 tons of field cured fodder per acre in contrast to 3.91 tons per acre of fodder from corn planted alone. The corn planted alone yielded at the rate of 45.6 bushels of grain per acre, whereas corn and soybeans planted together gave a corn yield of 42.2 bushels per acre. This combination is not recommended as a silage crop in this state. 17. During one year, sugar beets, half sugar beets, mangels and rutabagas yielded 2.10, 1.89, 1.86, and 1.23 tons per acre, respectively, of roots reduced to a 15 per cent moisture basis. Comparable yield? of Black Amber sorghum planted for hay and silage respectively, were, 4.19 and 3.72 tons per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ANNUAL FORAGE CROPS T. A. KIESSEI.BACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON The investigations reported in this bulletin deal primarily with variety tests of annual forage crops and with cultural practices employed in their production. These crops com - prise approximately 8 per cent of the hay acreage in Ne - braska and less than 1 per cent of the total area in grain and forage crops. All of the important annual forage crops suitable for this state are non-leguminous and cannot com - pare in feed and soil-building value with alfalfa and clover in those regions where these crops thrive. They occupy an important place thruout the state, however, as emergency forage crops and are regularly grown in regions of relatively low annual rainfall. The annual forage crops of sufficient importance to have their acreage listed in the published statistics of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture are the sorghums or cane, millets, and Sudan grass. In addition to these, several cereal crops including oats, rye, and corn, and a number of minor crops such as rape and the root crops are used to some extent for forage. Soy beans and Hubam sweet clover are being tried experimentally, but offer little promise of coming into ex - tensive use. RELATIVE IMPORTANCE OF FORAGE AND GRAIN CROPS It is of some interest to compare the acreage of the prin - cipal annual forage plants with that of the more important biennial and perennial forage crops, and with the acreage of the chief cereals grown in this state. Such data have been compiled in Table 1 for the 5-year period, 1920 to 1924. The 24,444,000 acres in pasture, 4,064,000 acres in hay crops, and 14,220,000 acres in grain crops comprise 57, 10, and 33 per cent, respectively, of their combined acreage. A very large proportion of the land in pasture and 55 per cent of the hay land consists of native grass. Forage crops, including range, tame and native pastures, and meadows, and the more im - portant cultivated crops grown primarily for forage or hay, occupy approximately 58 per cent of the total land acreage or 60 per cent of the rural land area. The total forage acre- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 Table 1. — Showing acreage of principal Nebraska forage and grain crops. 5-year average, 1920-192^ These data and those in Table 2 have been compiled from the annual reports of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and from the Nebraska Crop Reporter issued by the Federal and State Departments of Agriculture, co-operating. age is double that of the principal grain crops, and more than 95 per cent greater than all other cultivated land with - in the state. Comparative acreages of the sorghums, Sudan grass, and the millets for the 5-year period, 1920 to 1924, are given in Table 2. As compared with the sorghums and millets, Sudan grass is relatively a new crop within the state, the first seed being introduced into this country from Africa in 1909 by the United States Department of Agriculture. The first acreage reported by the State Department of Agriculture is for 1920. During the next 2 years its acreage trebled, largely Crop Crop Total area PASTURE CROPS Tame and native HAY CROPS Acres 24,444,000 Biennial and perennial Native hay Alfalfa : Timothy and red clover Red cover Timothy Other tame hay Sweet clover 2,250,000 . 1,193,000 85,000 66,000 28,000 35,000 79,000 Total 3,736,000 Annual Sorghums (hay) Sorghums (grain) Millets Sudan grass 171,000 20,000 76,000 61,000 Total 328,000 I Total of all forage crops I 28,508,000 ! GRAIN CROPS Corn Wheat Oats Barley Rye 7,784,000 3,580,000 2,453,000 257,000 146,000 Total i j 14,220,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Annual Forage Crops 9 at the expense of sorghum and millet. Since 1922 the relative acreages of the 3 crops have been rather constant, with the sorghums comprising about 51 per cent, Sudan grass 26 per cent, and the millets 23 per cent of the total land in these 3 crops. These annual forage plants are grown most exten - sively in the western, southern, and southwestern parts of the state where alfalfa and other legumes and perennial grasses are not so well adapted. Table 2. — Showing acreage of tlie •principal annual Xebraska forage crops, 1920-1924 Twenty-four varieties of annual forage crops were com - pared for yield ' at the Nebraska Experiment Station thruout the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, (Table 3). These included 9 sorts of sweet sorghum, 2 grain sorghums, Sudan grass, 7 varieties of millet, oats, field peas, oats and field peas mixed, Hubam clover, and field corn. All were seeded with an or - dinary press drill and at rates and dates considered normal for the various crops. In the case of varieties requiring a relatively long growing season rather immature harvesting was necessary. 1 Yields of forage are on the basis of 15 per cent moisture content except those in Tables 5, 6, and 21 which are in the main on a field cured basis. Methods of making these determinations are discussed at the end of this bulletin. All re - sults reported in this bulletin are for crops grown at the Experiment Station, at Lincoln except where otherwise indicated. Total area 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 Average Sorghum Sudan grass . Millet Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres 214,000 157,000 155,000 186,000 145,000 171,000 . 28,000 34,000 82,000 91,000 72,000 61,000 97,000 70,000 66,000 87,000 60,000 76,000 Total 339,000 261,000 I 303,000 | 364,000 I 277,000 | 308,000 Per cent of combined area Per cent ■ Per cent Per cent j Per cent Per cent \ Per cent _ Sorghum . Sudan grass Millet 63 60 51 51 52 55 8 13 27 25 26 20 29 27 22 24 22 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 Table 3. — Com /&gt;« rat ire i/ichlx of mutual forage crops, 1U~1-1'-&gt;1 Average| Maturity Yield of hay per acra with 15 p3r r?n Crop harven when Average imistlre cilfnt date harvested height 1921 1922 1921 1921 Av Inchr* Tnni ' Tons I Tons 1 Tun - !'■■■■ U, SORGHUMS Sweet varieties Black Amber' Sept. 21 Seed hard 62 4.05 4.67 : 5.69 4.19 4.65 Black Amber. Sept. 26 Seed hard 54 5.59 4.34 4.68 3.44 4.51 Red Amber Sept. 26 Seed ', hard 58 5.63 5.06 5.10 4.22 5.00 HIM Western Orange Sept. 26 Seed '. hard 57 5.00 6.08 6.10 4.40 5.39 116 Early Sumac Sept. 27 Stiff dough 57 5.94 4.05 6.30 4.31 5.1 Kansas Orange Sept. 27 Well headed 59 5.26 4.51 5.28 4.25 4.81 10 Sumac Sept. 27 Will headed 5) 5.61 4.44 5;74 3.84 4.91 106 Honey Sept. 27 Few heads 61 5.65 5.19 5.69 4.24 5.19 112 in. White African Sept! 27 Few heads 61 5^6 5!37 6A5 3^92 Average 5.37 4.86 5.69 4.0! Grain varieties Pink kaflr Sept. 27jWell headed 41 5.62 4.31 5.02 .1.04 4 Blackhull kafir Sept. 27 Well headed 44 5.32 5.29 4.89 4.02 4.8 Average ' 5.47 4.80 4.95 3.52 4.6 Sudan grass Sept. 21 Seed hard 76 3.29 2.77 4 MILLET. Foxtail varieties i Common Aug. 21 Still dough 39 4.31 4.26 2.45 3.0(1 3.5( J.:il 4 German Aug. 29 Stiff dough 42 I.I'! 4.25 2.23 2.97 3.4 Hungarian Aug. 14 Stiff dough 35 3.11 3.21 2.16 2.36 2.7 Siberian Aug. 12 Stiff dough 30 3.04 3.19 1.88 2.43 2 ti I Averafe | 3.7: 18 Hog Aug. 21 Stiff dough 31 1.81 1.69 0.7H 1.16 1.36 29 Japanese Barnyard Aug. 18: Stiff dough 41 Pearl iSept. 19; Soft dough 52 5.80 3.43 4.60 1.96 3.9S ft MISCELLANEOUS CROF Oats and Field Peas July 1 Soft dough 25 1.58 1.09 1.81 1.02 l.T, Oats July 1 Soft dough 27 1.99 1.14 2.2i 1.46 1.71 1.58 1.09 Field peas. , July 1 Soft dough 25 1.17 0.75 1.54 1.11 1.19 26 Field corn Sept. 16i Tasseling 56 5.65 5.04 3.84 3.09 4.40 95 [Sept. 16; Tasseling 56 5.65 5.04 Hubam' I July 14 Early blossom 18 0 3.43 1 'This Black Amber and th? Sudan gras3 seed consisted of ordinary commercial s?ed ■1 each year. The seed of the other s irghums was s^cired annually thru the Office of Forage (* Investigations, United States Department of Agriculture. 'Entire failure of Hlbim la 1921 and 1924 i-vn tho a good stand was secured. In 1922 and 1923 the crops produced consisted of a considerabl? p;rcentage of annual grasses and other w The average yield reported is for the 4-year period. Sweet Sorghums. — Since Black Amber sorghum or cane is by far the most extensively grown variety of the annual forage crops in this state, it may well be used as a basis for yield comparison. Commercial seed of this variety averaged 4.65 tons per acre during the 4-year period. Compared with this the relative yields of other sorghum varieties and other crops have been as follows: Improved Black Amber sor- ghum F. C. I. No. 7038, 97 per cent ; Red Amber sorghum 108 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Annual Forage Crops 11 per cent; Western Orange sorghum 116 per cent; Early Sumac sorghum 111 per cent; Kansas Orange sorghum 101 per cent; Sumac sorghum 106 per cent; Honey sorghum 112 per cent; White African sorghum 115 per cent. These varieties vary widely as to the time of maturity, ranging from mere heading to full maturity by the end of September. Since the first killing frost falls in this region on October 10, it has been necessary to cut the later varieties before they reached the most productive stage of maturity. It is considered that the finer quality of forage and the con - sistently earlier maturity of Black Amber sorghum will to some extent offset the higher yields from the larger and later maturing types. Late sorghums must frequently be harvested before reaching the most desirable stage of matur - ity in order to avoid frost. In view of their greater yield the medium late varieties such as Red Amber, Western Orange, and Early Sumac would seem to merit more exten - sive trial under the farm conditions of southern Nebraska. Grain Sorghums. — The 2 grain varieties, Pink kafir and Blackhull kafir, yielded 97 and 105 per cent as much, respec - tively, as Black Amber sorghum. Their forage is considered less palatable. This, together with much later maturity, causes them to be less desirable for forage. Sudan Grass. — During this 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, Sudan grass yielded 3.25 tons per acre or 70 per cent as much as Black Amber sorghum. During a previous 3-year period, 1915 to 1917, its yield of cured forage was 68 per cent of the sorghum. Thus in comparable tests covering 7 years, the Sudan grass has averaged 69 per cent as high yield as sor - ghum. Millets. — Common and German millet yielded 3.50 and 3.47 tons per acre or 75 per cent of the sorghum yield dur - ing the 4-year period. These 2 millets yielded 7 per cent more than Sudan grass, whereas the foxtail millets as a group including the 2 additional varieties, Hungarian and Siberian, yielded 5 per cent less. Japanese Barnyard millet or Billion Dollar grass and Pearl millet or Pencillaria yielded 61 and 85 per cent as much, respectively, as Black Amber sorghum. The forage of these 2 varieties is coarse and relatively un - palatable. The Pearl millet requires a much longer growing season than the other sorts. In comparison, data compiled from results assembled by Vinall and Getty in Bulletin 981, United States Department of Agriculture, for 20 experiment </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 Fig. 1. — Comparative test of millets. Common and German varieties have yielded 3.5 tons cured forage per acre during the' 4 years, 1921-1924. This is 25 per cent less than the yield of Black Amber sorghum and 5 per cent more than that of Sudan grass. stations at which the 3 crops were compared, give the aver - age relative yields of 100, 64, and 59 per cent for sorghum, Sudan grass, and millet, respectively. Corn, Oats, Field Peas, and Hubam Clover. — Field corn seeded for hay with a grain drill yielded 4.40 tons per acre or 95 per cent of the Black Amber sorghum yield. The for - age produced was of fair quality. Tho this is not recom - mended as a general practice, the data indicate that corn can be grown satisfactorily in this manner as an emergency for - age crop. Oats alone, oats and field peas in combination, and field peas alone yielded 1.70, 1.37, and 1.19 tons per acre, respec - tively, or 37, 29, and 26 per cent as much as the sorghum. Hubam, an annual sweet clover, was a failure 2 years out of 4, but during the other 2 years averaged 2.56 tons of hay per acre. As a 4-year average its yield was 28 per cent of the sorghum, whereas during the 2 years that it produced a crop its yield was 49 per cent of the sorghum yield. There is no annual legume known that is able to compete with the sor - ghums, Sudan grass, and millets in total forage production. Comparable alfalfa hay yields during the 4-year period, 1921 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Annual Forage Crops 13 Fig. 2. — Field corn seeded broadcast for forage. As a 4-year average, 1921 to 1924, the yield has been 3.55 tons per acre, which is 5 per cent less than that of Black Amber sorghum. Photographed August 15, 1922. to 1924, were 4.09 tons per acre or 12 per cent less than the yield of Black Amber sorghum and 26 per cent more than the yield of Sudan grass. RELATIVE CHEMICAL COMPOSITION OF GRASSES AND LEGUMES Forage crops may be grouped into 2 general classes, nitro - genous and carbohydrate. The distinguishing quality is the difference in nitrogen content, which is the basic element of protein. Sorghum, Sudan grass, and all the other forage plants belonging to the grass family are relatively high in carbohydrates, whereas all legumes such as alfalfa and the clovers are comparatively high in protein. The relative food values of these 2 classes of forage are quite generally known. It is well recognized that chemical fodder analyses which indicate the percentage of ash, protein, fiber, fat, and nitro - gen-free extract, which is largely starch and sugar, are not absolute indexes of the nutritive value of a feed. Such an - alyses do, however, permit closer comparative evaluations </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 of different feeds. The difference between these 2 groups of plants may be readily seen by a comparison of sorghum and Sudan grass with alfalfa hay grown under comparable con - ditions, the analyses of which are reported in Table 4 as a 3-year average, 1921 to 1923. Table 4. — Relatire ehemicml composition of typical leguminous and non-leg uminous forage plants, 3-year average, ]!Ul-l!)J.l Yield of hay Fodder analyses on a moisture-free basis per acre with — ; — : — harvested annually at 4 stages of maturity. Those of a all cuttings made at a normal stage of maturity during the All analyses reported in this bulletin were made for the Agronomy I under the direction of Dr. M. J. Bliss, Station Chemist. The protein content of these crops was 5.67, 6.56, and 18.75 per cent respectively for sorghum, Sudan grass, and alfalfa. The corresponding percentages of nitrogen-free ex - tract (largely starch and sugar) were 52.82, 46.75, and 40.71, while the percentages of crude fiber were 30.68, 35.63, and 28.28. The ash and fat content remained more constant for the 3 crops, being 8.35, 9.26, and 9.47 per cent for the former and 2.48, 1.80, and 2.79 per cent for the latter. COMPARISON OF CROPS IN DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE STATE The comparative production of sorghum, corn, and oats grown on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln, and at the North Platte, Scottsbluff, and Valentine Substations dur - ing periods of various lengths is shown in Table 5. 1 Ad - ditional data comparing sorghum and Sudan grass at Lin - coln and at the North Platte and Valentine Substations are reported in Table 6. These 4 stations represent a wide range 1 Acknowledgment is made to L. L. Zook, Agronomist, North Platte Substatio for aupplyine the North Platte and Scottsbluff data and to E. M. Rrouse, Supei intendent Valentine Substation, for the Valentine results. Crops 15 per cent n _ % j_ i n , Nitrogen- ™*£ content Ash f™* Crude Jf Fat Tons Per &lt;*»tf ; Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cen I Sorghum.. 4.62 8.35 5.67 30.68 52.82 2.48 Sudan grass 3.51 9.26 6.56 35.63 46.75 1.80 Alfalfa 3.81 9.47 18.75 28.28 40.71 ! 2.79 I ! I ! [ l___ Analyst's reported fur soruhum and Sudan urass are averages fur foray tat </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Annual Forage Crops 15 Table •"&gt;. — Com/Miratirc /nudmtion of sorghum, corn, and oats at Lincoln, North Platte, Scottsbhtf, and Valentine, Nebraska The yields at Uncoil were secured in 1915 to 1917 and 1921 tn 1924; at North Platte in . 19J8, and 191 1 t!&gt; 1921; at Seattsbl-iff 1912 tj 1921 ; and at Valsntine in 1920 to 1924. of climatic conditions within the state. The crops were grown without irrigation on normal soil and by prevailing farming practices in each locality. Sorghum and Sudan grass were seeded with a press drill at Lincoln and North Platte. and in cultivated rows at Scottsbluff and Valentine. The corn and oats were grown as grain crops in all cases but are here compared as forage crops. All yields are on a field-cured basis except those at Lincoln for sorghum and Sudan grass, which are on a 15 per cent moisture basis. Since the data for the various localities were not obtained during identical periods, the crop yields are strictly com- Iabi.k &lt;i. — Comparative yields of surf/hum and Sudan ynixs at Lincoln, North 1'hith mid Valentine, Nebraxka Annual rainfall Yield of forage Ratio of per acre* Sudan Location Duration of test of test 1 Average 8™^ to Normal during o nra u, lm ' Sudan sorghum | test s onJ hum grass yield Years Inc es Inches I Tons Tons Percent Lincoln 27.55 25.93 5.29 3.64 69 North Platte 4 18.86 20.97 3.30 2.50 7fl Valentine 5 22.46 19.83 \ 1.61 0.75 47 'The yields at Lincoln were secured in 1915 to 1917 and 1921 to 1924; at North Platte in 1914, 1915, 1917 and 1922; and at Valentine in 1920 to 1924. -'During the 4-year period 1921 to 1924 at Lincoln, millet yielded 75 per cant of the sorghum and at Valentine during the 5-year period 1920 to 1924 it yielded 44 per cent of the sorghum yield Duration Location tif t t si of test Annual rainfall Yield per acre Average Sorghum Corn Oats Normal during ■ , test i Total Fodder Stover Sheaf Straw ■I — { = = — =\ — = = Inrhrx Inchtf Tom Ton* Torn Tom Tom Linpul i 7 27.55 25.93 ' 529 I 3.17 I 1.79 1.50 I 0.75 North Plane 16 18.86 18.59 , 3.02 2.14 1.38 1.17 0.72 Seottsbljft 1U 15.84 17.19 2.73 1.51 ; 0.93 0.91 0.58 Valentine 5 22.46 19.8) 1.61 i 0.99 I 0.62 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ebra: Ixp: iriment Station, Bulletin 2s a* 1 Is g i s ! I i ! &lt; i I I I ii IS COt-Ot- IOOT31 O?J — t- OC3OM = ai -t „ -f *rf m -r es f^-ft-; ■* »o — t^ En -* -^ « n eo so oi -^ -v oj « «co«m : : : : E-, id-* CO i 030960 i #-#ii I VoOCQ. ~ M N M -1* i.*N-T W f — 30 3&gt; — 33» g -1-^T(OiO t^WQOCO -— iS — O CiflSO • EX w « — -^ mmcici m w — e* 3 £ t-a»»aao t-ouaeo sskis -r — si t- O- 5 «•«" O««5» ««-f^ -o &gt;. — r: :i;i nmNOJ — — — — --i-rr: — S U300CDO Ot-M(D CCCMX^l -TXXO -£ _x — t- -— t-X« N -r — r^ ;c r: » t- td^-Woi r-ciwoi usidnoi kd^reooi "= s E-i OiO-* - 9393E0- -r-PK -* r? -1 IS - 1 1 - s-. &gt;o»r- x-Ji- «o&gt;a- 3 q -*r ; nuia ntco ; o ® » ft* tO'-rc* . -fdn ■ -voocm ■ --------- , s -? tOMXO) «f*-50aC -CXJl 3Qt-O = »r-aao r-t-o5t- &gt;o&gt;aett 3 x x x ! •3 I — o &lt; 9 ii s| 1 iS 1050 ««""* gg 010 SS22 3 «— r NW 5 .it; S5 4 : ; ; 22§ : : I i I - — c — c 5* ■ "S I ■ ill! Nil Ml: Hi; \ m !ii Hi: nil ! E : :Sf : :«i : : •? : : Sf I a . .-cS ■ tS • -xB ■ xB m • : ile : :M : ill : ill J! eaSCQ'.r-v^— ■CD-t — — X^"&lt;? — — — — 5 n K E \ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Annual Forage Crops 17 parable at any one station only and not between stations. The data are of interest primarily in showing the relative performance of these crops under a wide range of con - ditions. The total production of corn and oats compared in this manner was 60 and 28 per cent as much as for sorghum at Lincoln, during a 7-year period. Corn, however, when seed - ed comparably (Table 7) during this same period yielded 83 per cent as much as the sorghum. At North Platte during a 16-year period the sorghum yield was 3.02 tons per acre while the corn and oats yielded 71 and 39 per cent as much, respectively. The Scottsbluff sorghum yield was 2.73 tons per acre during a 10-year period while the corn and oats yielded 55 and 33 per cent as much. Sorghum yielded 1.61 tons per acre during a 5-year period at Valentine and the corn yielded 61 per cent of this. Sorghum yields at Lincoln, North Platte, and Valentine during periods of 7, 4, and 5 years each were 5.29, 3.30, and 1.61 tons per acre, respectively. Corresponding Sudan grass yields were 3.64, 2.50, and 0.75 tons per acre. Sudan grass yielded 69, 76, and 47 per cent as much as sorghum at Lin - coln, North Platte, and Valentine, respectively. METHODS OF SEEDING Four methods of seeding annual forage crops including drilling, broadcasting, and surface planting and listing in cultivated rows were compared during a 7-year period 1915 to 1917 and 1921 to 1924 (Table 7). The 4 crops, sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn were planted by the first 3 methods thruout this period whereas listing was included during the last 4 years only. As an average for the 7 years, drilling, broadcasting, and surface planting in 42-inch rows gave the respective yields of 5.47, 4.70, and 3.57 tons per acre for the sorghum; 3.76, 3.48, and 3.05 tons for the Sudan grass ; 4.62, 4.16, and 2.99 tons for the kafir; and 4.54, 3.61, and 3.07 tons per acre for the field corn. During the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, surface planting and listing gave the respective average yields of 3.10 and 2.47 tons per acre for the sorghum ; 2.44 and 1.99 tons for the Sudan grass; 2.41 and 1.77 tons for the kafir; and 3.10 and 2.72 tons per acre for the field corn. Broadcasting compared with drilling decreased the aver - age forage yield 13 per cent or 14, 7, 10, and 20 per cent, respectively, for the sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 Fig. 3. — Black Amber sorghum (left) and Sudan grass (right) sur - face planted in 42-inch rows for forage. The yields during the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, have been 3.10 and 2.44 tons per acre or 62 and 71 per cent, respectively, of the yields when seeded in close drills. Photographed August 15, 1922. corn. Surface planting in cultivated rows compared with drilling decreased the average forage yield 30 per cent or 35, 19, 35, and 32 per cent, respectively, for the sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn. As an average for the 4-year test, 1921 to 1924, these 4 crops yielded respectively 20, 18, 27, and 12 per cent less when listed than when sur - face planted in cultivated rows. These lower yields may be explained by reduced vegetative development and more un - even stands which accompany listing. The decrease in yield from broadcasting as compared with drilling was doubtless due to a more imperfect covering of the seed resulting in ununiform germination and stand. SEED PRODUCTION Seed or grain yields were obtained from the Black Amber sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn when grown in 42-inch cultivated rows for forage during the 3-year period 1922 to 1924. These data together with the total acre pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Annual Forage Crops 19 duction are shown in Table 8. With each of the 4 crops list - ing has resulted in a reduction in both forage and seed yields as compared with surface planting. This decrease in yield was most marked with the seed production of kafir due to its slower development and immaturity as a result of list - ing. As an average for both methods of planting, seed pro - duction in pounds per acre was 1538, 564, 942, and 2332 pounds respectively for sorghum, Sudan grass, kafir and field corn. Fable n. — / inn jKirntire seed production of Black Amber gory h inn, Sudan grow, Rlarklntll kafir and field corn needed in 42-inch i ■idtir.iitcd roirx, o-ijcar arerage. 1922-1924 Yield of forage 1 Crop and method of seeding per acre with Yield of seed per 15 per cent acre on air-dry basis Total crop yield including seed. DATE OF SEEDING TESTS WITH BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass were seeded at 6 different dates in May, June, and July during the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, (Table 9). The first seeding was made May 15 and other seedings followed at 10-day intervals, the last being made July 5. One hundred pounds of sorghum seed and 25 pounds of Sudan grass seed were sown per acre with a press drill. The ground was prepared uniformly be - fore the first seeding and kept free from weeds thereafter by disking until seeded. Harvests were made at compar - able stages of maturity as far as possible. The yield of a second crop when secured from the earlier seedings has been included. moisture cont tent Tons Pounds Bushels Black Amber sorghum Surface planted Listed ■ludan grass Surface planted . . Listed Kafir corn Surface planted Listed Field corn Surface planted Listed 2.76 2.37 2.39 1.91 2.07 1.58 2.86 2.72 1,566 1,511 600 529 1,204 680 2,425 2,240 31.3 30.2 15.0 13.2 24.1 13.6 43.3 40.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 Table 9. — Date of seeding test with Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass for forage, 1921-1924 Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent moisture content Crop, date, and rate of seeding per acre 1921 1922 1923 1924 ! Average ■The May 15 yield for 1921 has been calculated from the May 25 yield on the bast average relative performance for these seeding dates during the other 3 years. The average yield of sorghum from the earliest seed - ing date, May 15, was 4.87 tons per acre and the yields from the 5 succeeding dates were 95, 88, 86, 76, and 66 per cent, respectively, of the yield from the earliest date. The yield from the May 15 seeding of Sudan grass was 3.85 tons per acre and the corresponding yields from the later dates were 101, 92, 89, 73, and 61 per cent, respectively, of this yield. These data suggest that the best results will be obtained from seeding rather early. In a cool and wet spring poor stands may result from very early seeding. In general it may be stated that seeding of the sorghums should follow shortly after corn planting. In occasional years late seeding may prove advantageous due to more favorable conditions at seeding time or during the time the major plant growth is made. Fair yields were secured from the July 5 seeding and these data suggest that these crops may be seeded even later than this in favorable years as catch crops. | Tons Tons Tons Tons Tons I Relative Black Amber sorghum, 100 lbs May 15' May 25 June 5 June 15 June IS July 5 5.93 4.96 3.73 5.63 5.12 3.56 4.62 5.30 2.72 4.97 5.16 2.80 3.90 3.67 3.51 3.32 2.62 i 3.81 4.88 4.87 100 4.20 I 4.63 ; 95 4.54 4.29 88 3.82 4.19 86 3.81 3.72 76 3.09 3.21 66 Average 4.73 I ! 4.47 3.35 4.06 4.15 ! ludan grass, 25 lbs. . . . May 15' May 25 June 5 June 15 June 25 July 5 3.90 3.95 3.66 3.54 3.31 i 2.18 i 5.11 5.06 4.45 4.57 3.02 I 2.3 3.19 3.72 2.83 2.72 2.79 2.89 3.19 i 3.85 100 2.86 | 3.90 101 3.22 ! 3.54 92 2.92 3.44 89 2.11 2.81 73 2.00 2.36 61 3.42 4.10 ■ 1 3.02 2.72 3.32 Average . </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Annual Forage Crops 21 Fig. 4. — Date of seeding Black Amber sorghum. From extreme left to right: Seeded May 15, May 25, June 5, June 15, June 25, and July 5. Photographed Aug. 10, 1922. As a 4-year average, 1921 to 1924, the yields were 4.87, 4.63, 4.29, 4.19, 3.72, and 3.21 tons per acre, respectively. RATE OF SEEDING TESTS WITH BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS Due to its greater stooling capacity, its smaller seed, and finer stemmed character of forage, Sudan grass is commonly seeded at a thinner rate in farm practice than sorghum. In these tests, both crops were seeded at 6 different rates annually during 7 years, 1915-1917 and 1921-1924 (Table 10). The rates differed somewhat during the 2 periods, but 5 of them were continuous thruout the 7 years. All seeding was done with a press drill under comparable conditions in the normal planting season. During the 7-year period, sorghum seeded at the rates of 25, 50, 75, 100, and 150 pounds per acre, gave the re - spective yields of 4.65, 5.10, 4.95, 5.27, and 5.28 tons of cured forage per acre. Corresponding relative yields in per cent were 100, 110, 106, 113, and 114 for the respective rates. Sudan grass seeded at 20, 30, 40, 60, and 80 pounds per acre yielded respectively 3.42, 3.46, 3.58, 3.63, and 3.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Annual Forage Crops 23 tons per acre. These are respective relative yields of 100, 101, 105, 106. and 107 per cent. When Sudan grass was drilled at the additional rate of 10 pounds per acre during 4 years, its yield was 5 per cent less than that for the 20 - pound rate and when drilled at 120 pounds per acre during 3 years the yield was the same as for the 80-pound rate. It appears that there may be a rather wide range of planting rate for sorghum and Sudan grass without very materially affecting the forage yields. The greater cost of seed for the thicker rates of seeding will be partly offset by the finer quality of hay produced, and partly by increased yield. This is especially true of the sorghum. Thin seeding results in taller, coarser forage which is more difficult to cure and handle and also results in greater waste in feeding. While he planting rate should vary with the region of the state nd the growing conditions it appears that for this locality aking both yield and quality into consideration, 20 to 30 Fig. 5. — Rate of seeding Black Amber sorghum. From left to right: Seeded 25, 50, 75, 100, 125, and 150 pounds per acre. The re - spective yields during the 4-vear period, 1921 to 1924, have been 4.53, 4.87, 4.52, 4.87, 4 82, and 4.73 tons per ocre. Photographed August 10, 1922. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 pounds of Sudan grass and 100 to 125 pounds of sorghum should be sown per acre. Thinner rates than any of those discussed usually occur in connection with seeding in cultivated rows. In these experiments (Table 7) sorghum and Sudan grass have been surface planted during 7 years in rows spaced 42 inches apart and at the respective rates of approximately 6 and 4 pounds per acre. Planted in this manner, the sorghum and Sudan grass have yielded 3.58 and 3.05 tons per acre, respectively, or 77 and 89 per cent as much as when drilled at the rates of 25 and 20 pounds per acre. The row method of planting is relatively more suitable in the western part of the state where growing conditions are less favorable. Fig. 6. — Rate of seeding Sudan grass. From left to right: Seeded 10, 20, 30, 40, 60, and 80 pounds per acre. The respective yields during the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, have been 3.14, 3.31, 3.46, 3.44, 3.48, and 3.48 tons per acre. Photographed August 10, 1922. PHYSICAL COMPOSITION OF THE FORAGE FROM VARIOUS RATES OF SEEDING BLACK AMBER SORGHUM, AND SUDAN GRASS In order to measure the relative coarseness of the sorghum and Sudan grass forage produced from different rates of seeding, measurements and moisture-free weights were taken for 200 systematically distributed stalks from each rate of </seg>
            <seg id="p025">100 sorghum stalks. The stem diameter of sorghum grown in the different rates of planting decreased from 0.25 inch for the lightest rate to 0.13 inch for the thickest rate. The relative stem diameters of the 25, 50, 75, 100, 125, and 150-pound rates of seeding were 100, 80, 76, 64, 60, and 52 per cent, respec - tively. Similar measurements for Sudan grass gave stem diameters of 0.17 and 0.11 inches for the extreme rates of planting. The relative stem diameters were 100, 94, 88, 82, 71, and 65 per cent, respectively, for the 10, 20, 30, 40, 60, Annual ] Forage Crops ,5 Pable 11.— Effect of the seed', and Sudan grass upon the produced 1 . Average for i Ing rate of Black A physical compositiai i years, 1922-1921^ iber sorghum of the forage Stalks Weight Crop and rate of per 10- i of 100 seeding per acre ft. drill stalks row' Propi irtion of parts Stem i at liameter base Stems Leaves Heads Hack Amber sorghum 25 pounds. 50 pounds . . 75 pounds 100 pounds. . 125 pounds . . . 150 pounds. . •I 69 97 111 136 153 182 Pounds 3.11 2.05 , 1.85 1.52 1.21 1.03 IPer cent 47.1 47.4 48.6 47.2 48.2 46.5 \Per cent 32.1 34.7 34.1 35.6 38.4 38.2 Per cent 20.8 17.9 17.3 17.2 13.4 15.3 Inches 0.25 0.20 0.19 0.16 0.15 0.13 Relative 100 80 76 64 60 52 Average. . . . 125 1.79 47.5 35.5 17.0 0.18 Sudan grass 10 pounds 20 pounds 30 pounds 40 pounds 60 pounds 80 pounds 116 157 186 211 261 312 1.46 1.14 1.19 0.94 0.70 0.72 50.2 49.3 51.4 50.0 48.1 49.5 29.8 32.1 30.3 33.6 34.9 34.5 20.0 18.6 18.3 16.4 17.0 16.0 0.17 0.16 0.15 0.14 0.12 0.11 100 94 88 82 71 65 Average. . . . 207 j 1.02 32.5 17.7 0.14 207 1.02 49.7 'These data were determined annually from 200 9 ystematically distributed stalks from each rate. -The data in this column are for 1924 only and are I ically located. in avenge of 10 3-foot drill rows systemat- planting for the 3-year period, ] The weight per 100 stalks decreai 3.11 pounds for the lightest rate tc iest rate of seeding in the sorghu 0.72 pounds in the case of Sudan g rates, 100 Sudan grass stalks weigl L922 to 1924 (Table 11). sed rather gradually from i 1.03 pounds for the heav- im tests and from 1.46 to rass. As an average of all led 57 per cent as heavy as </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 and 80-pound rates of seeding. The sorghum stalk diameters have decreased more rapidly in size with increased rates of planting than have those of Sudan grass. These data show that coarseness of stem in either crop can be materially reduced by increased rates, and that both crops are of ap - proximately equal coarseness when the sorghum is seeded at the rate of 100 to 125 pounds and Sudan grass at 20 to 30 pounds per acre. Using these same forage samples the proportion of stems, leaves, and heads of sorghum and Sudan grass were deter - mined for each rate of planting. In this ssparation the leaf sheath was included with the leaves, and the heads were re - moved at their lowest branch. As an average for all seeding rates, the sorghum forage consisted of 47.5 per cent stems, 35.5 per cent leaves, and 17.0 per cent heads, while the Sudan grass forage was com - posed of 49.7 per cent stems, 32.5 per cent leaves, and 17.7 per cent heads. The proportion of the various parts was found to vary somewhat with a change in planting rate. The percentage of stem remained fairly constant, fluctuating only 2 per cent for the sorghum and 3 per cent for the Sudan grass. A rather gradual increase in proportion of leaves was noted as the seeding rate increased, being 6.1 and 4.7 per cent higher for the sorghum and Sudan grass, respectively, at the heaviest than at the lightest rate. The proportion of heads was reduced from 20.8 to 15.3 per cent for the sor - ghum and from 20.0 to 16.0 per cent for the Sudan grass bv change in seeding from the thinnest to thickest rates. CHEMICAL COMPOSITION OF THE FORAGE FROM VARIOUS RATES OF SEEDING BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS Chemical analyses were made from the sorghum ami Sudan grass forage grown at these 6 rates of planting in 1924. The results are given in Table 12. The forage pro - duced at rates ranging from 25 to 150 pounds per acre for sorghum and 10 to 80 pounds for Sudan grass did not differ materially in composition even tho the coarseness of the for - age was decidedly reduced. Since the proportion of the stems, leaves, and heads of sorghum and Sudan grass may vary with seeding rates and other conditions, it was thought of interest to determine the relative chemical composition of these various parts. Such analyses are given in Table 13 for forage grown in 1924 at </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Annual Forage Crops 27 Tabu: 12. — Effect of the seeding rate of Black Amber sorghum mid Sudan frtttt upon the chemical composition of the hay produced, l.'/Ji Table 13. — Chemical composition of the stems, leaves, and grain i if Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay, 1924 Pro. Fodder analyses on a moisture-free basis Calculated from the composition of the st -ma, leaves, aad grain on a percentage basis. Fodder analyses on a moisture-free basis Crop and rate of seeding Stem j per acre diameter rv.,j«» n~»A Nitrogen- «- - £S C «E? J£ rt « Inches Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Black Amber sorghum 25 pounds 0.24 5.62 3.42 25.10 63.92 1.94 50 pounds 0.19 ! 6.15 3.52 27.00 61.18 2.15 75 pounds 0.18 5.72 2.97 26.80 62.52 1.99 100 pounds 0.17 5.56 : 2.58 j 27.20 62.38 2.28 125 pounds 0.14 6.04 2.89 j 28.90 60.04 2.13 150 pounds 0.13 5.82 I 2.79 j 28.20 61.09 2.10 Average 0.17 5.82 3.03 27.20 61.85 2.10 Sudan grass 10 pounds 0.15 7.46 2.48 36.20 52.02 1.84 20 pounds 0.13 6.84 2.78 32.60 55.95 1.83 30 pounds 0.11 6.96 j 2.58 34.80 53.94 1.72 40 pounds 0.10 7.04 ' 2.98 32.70 55.79 1.49 60 pounds 0.09 6.68 i 2.28 37.40 52.26 1.38 80 pounds 0.08 6.82 2.74 33.90 54.74 1.80 Average 0.11 I 6.97 j 2.64 34.60 54.12 1.68 Crop and rate of seeding portion j : : per acre of ,-._ |A , ,-._, j_ Nitrogen- ;-* J^J » [S? A. F " ■Per cen/ Per cenf Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cem Sorghum, 100 pounds Hay 1 100 6.13 3.16 28.77 59.81 2.12 Stems 46.5 4.80 1.12 29.90 62.58 1.60 Leaves 36.6 8.79 ; 3.44 35.40 49.96 2.41 Grain 16.9 4.06 j 8.19 i 11.30 73.52 2.93 Sudan 30 pounds Hay' 100 7.85 : 3.39 \ 32.99 53.85 1.93 Stems 50.7 6.98 j 1.85 ! 38.70 51.02 1.45 Leaves 30.3 9.80 3.54 ' 36.90 47.81 1.95 Grain 19.0 7.06 I 7.21 j 11.50 71.05 3.18 I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p028">the standard planting rates of 100 pounds and 30 pounds per acre, respectively, for sorghum and Sudan grass. These data show that the stems of sorghum contained much less crude fiber and more nitrogen-free extract than those of Sudan grass. In other regards the analyses of these crops are rather similar. The leaves in both crops were somewhat higher in ash, protein, and fat and lower in ni - trogen-free extract than were the stems. The grain was lower in crude fiber and higher in protein, nitrogen-free ex - tract, and fat than were the other parts. These data suggest that the composition of sorghum and Sudan grass forage and the acre yield of nutrients will be but little affected by any change in planting rate within prac - tical limits. EFFECT OF THE TIME OF CUTTING UPON THE FORAGE YIELD OF BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS The harvesting of sorghum and Sudan grass at 4 stages of maturity, namely, (1) first heads appearing, (2) well headed, (3) seed in soft dough stage, and (4) seed ripe has 'The 1921 and 1922 yiUds of the earliest harvest are calculated on the basis of relative yields during the 2 succeeding years. : Hay yields of a second crop are included. been practiced a\ vesting at arbitr ative study was at stated interval with their resuli uring the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924. Har- rary stages of development in this compar- considered more desirable than harvesting ,1s of time due to varying weather conditions tant effect on rate of growth. Comparable Table U.— Effect Black Ami t of the time of cutting upon the forage yield of her sorghum and Sudan grans, 1921-]f)2l Crop and stage of maturity Average date of cutting Moisture content when cut Average height " Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent moisture content 1921 1922 1923 I 1924 Average Per cent Inches Tom Tom Torn Tons '■ Tom Rtlati, Black Amber sorghum First heads appearing' Well headed Seed «oft dough Seed ripe Aug. 11 Aug. 20 Sept. 2 Sept. 27 87 77 73 67 53 4.02 4.37 j 2.97= ! 3.25 3.65 ! 100 56 4.71' 5.12 ! 3.53= I 3.76 4.28 117 63 5.69 4.92 4.42 3.84 i 4.72 129 67 5.99 | 5.07 4.68 4.43 5.04 138 Average 76 60 5.10 4.87 | 3.90 3.82 4.42 idan grata First Beads appearing' Well headed Seed soft dough Seed ripe Aug. 11 Aug. 20 Sept. 2 Sept. 27 83 74 70 65 58 62 67 76 I 3.55 j 2.81 ! 2.84= 2.26 j 2.86 100 4.(14-' j 3.20- ; 3.40&gt; 2.41 326 114 I 3.62 I 4.48 ! 3.94 I 2.60 3.66 128 3.11 I 3.34 j 3.79 2.27 3.13 109 Average n 66 3.58 3.46 I 3.49 2.38 3.2:! III!! </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Annual Forage Crops 29 harvests of both crops were usually made on the same day tho the Sudan grass ordinarily showed a little more maturity than the sorghum. The light second crops which were occa - sionally had following the early cuttings have been included in the yields. The data are recorded in Table 14. As a 4-year average the yield of sorghum increased from 3.65 tons per acre when cut at the early heading stage to 5.04 tons when mature. The relative yields were 100, 117, 129, and 138 per cent when ranked from the least mature to the most mature stages, respectively. Of the 16 yields secured during the test only one is slightly inconsistent. The mois - ture content at harvest time ranged from 87 per cent for the least mature to 67 per cent for the most mature forage. The average plant height ranged from 53 inches to 67 inches according to maturity. As a 4-year average the yields of Sudan grass ranging from the least mature to the most mature stages were 2.86, 3.26, 3.66, and 3.13 tons per acre, respectively, with cor - responding relative yields of 100, 114, 128, and 109. As full maturity is approached there is a measurable amount of shattering of both leaves and seed in the case of Sudan grass. This will explain in part at least the consistent decrease in yield that appears in the most mature stage of harvest. The moisture content of Sudan grass at time of harvest decreased from 83 per cent to 65 per cent as maturity was reached whereas the average plant height increased from 58 inches to 76 inches with maturity. EFFECT OF THE TIME OF CUTTING UPON THE CHEMICAL COMPOSITION OF BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS FORAGE The average fodder analyses for the 4-year period, 1921 - 1924, for Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass forage harvested at the 4 different stages of maturity are reported in Table 15. A consistent decrease in per cent ash and pro - tein is shown with increased maturity of both crops. The ash content decreased from 9.59 per cent to 6.85 per cent in the case of sorghum and from 9.99 per cent to 8.27 per cent with Sudan grass as harvesting was delayed to the most mature stage. Similar decreases in the protein content were from 6.48 per cent to 3.99 for the sorghum and from 6.82 to 3.87 per cent for the Sudan grass. With the sorghum the fiber content decreased from 33.36 per cent to 27.61 while the nitrogen-free extract increased from 48.48 per cent to 59.17 per cent as maturity increased. In the case of Sudan grass there was no material change in the fiber content and </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 30 Table 15. — Effect of the time of tmttimf upon the chemical com - position of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay, 4 - year average} 1921-1924 Fodder analyses on a moisture-free basis Crop and stage of Yield "" Xah Crude ! Crude i Nit "*? n - Fat acre Ash * • c , free maturity *_ruae i , ~ protein fiber I Tons \Per cent Per cent'Per centl Per cent Per cent Black Amber sorghum First heads appearing- 3.65 '■, 9.59 ; 6.48 ! 33.36 I 48.48 2.34 Sudan grass First heads appearing 2 2.86 ; 9.99 6.82 35.78 46.03 1.50 'Analyses for the first crop only. '-Results for the earliest stage are calculated for 1921 and 1922 on a basis of its average performance compared with the other 3 stages during 1923 and 1924. only 3 per cent increase in the nitrogen-free extract with maturity. There was no consistent change in the per cent fat content with either crop as maturity was approached. A distinguishing feature of these 2 crops is the difference in their proportion of crude fiber to nitrogen-free extract. As an average for the 4 stages of maturity the sorghum con - tained 30.98 per cent crude fiber and 53.78 per cent nitrogen - free extract whereas the Sudan grass contained 35.61 and 48.04 per cent, respectively, of these 2 constituents. The analyses which have varied from year to year suggest that the composition of the forage is influenced materially by weather conditions, soil fertility, and the total yield of hay per acre. The highest yield of nutrients per acre corresponded in the main with the highest acre yield of hay (Fig. 7). The sorghum hay yield increased consistently from 3.65 tons per acre for the least mature stage to 5.04 tons for the most mature stage. The relative proportions of ash and protein in the sorghum forage decreased with maturity but the acre Well headed Seed soft dough Seed ripe 4.28 4.72 5.04 7.74 5.22 S 33.39 i 7.16 4.88 ! 29.58 ! 6.85 3.99 27.61 | 51.36 56.12 , 59.17 2.30 ! 2.26 2.34 4.42 i ! 7.83 5.14 I 30.98 53.78 2.31 Averai Well headed Seed soft dough Seed ripe ell headed «d soft dough «d ripe ! 3.26 3.66 3.13 ! 8.77 8.38 8.27 6.48 5.85 3.87 35.00 34.83 36.83 47.85 48.92 49.33 1.88 2.01 1.69 1 1 ' . Average I 3.23 8.85 5.75 35.61 48.03 1.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Annual Forage Crops 31 STAGES OF MATURITY STA6E5 ofMaTUI?ITY 5O1?GHUM SUDAN GI?A55 FIG. 7. — Acre yield of moisture-free hay, nitrogen-free extract, fiber, ash, protein, and fat of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass when harvested at the 4 stages of maturity indicated by number at base of graph, i.e., (1) first heads appearing; (2) well headed, (3) seed soft dough stage, and (4) seed ripe. A 4-year average, 1921 to 1924, calculated from Table 15. yield of these nutrients remained rather constant due to the increased acre yield of hay. The yield of fiber increased from the first to the second stage and then decreased slightly with maturity. The increase in yield of nitrogen-free ex - tract and fat per acre has increased consistently with ma - turity. In the case of nitrogen-free extract this was due to percentage increase as well as to increased yield of hay. The </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 hay yields of Sudan grass were 2.86, 3.26, 3.66, and 3.13 tons per acre, respectively, for the successive harvests. The acre yield of all substances likewise increased up to the third harvest and then decreased with the yield of hay. Table 16. — Relative consumption of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay when fed with corn silage 1 to cattle Hay fed daily j Total moisture-free hay fed to 21 per animal cattle per 5-day period Crop Feeding : ; period r»_, Amount Refuse Amount consumed Actual J*2 weighed weighed I -n — _.,.„ weighed weighed ' — i — matter in back Actual jP'rc'tage 'Thirty-eight pounds of good corn silage containing 13.5 pounds dry matter was fed daily per animal. In the test were 21 head of cows and younger stock, averaging about 900 pounds in weight. RELATIVE PALATABILITY OF BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS HAY In order to measure the relative palatability or per cent consumption of sorghum and Sudan grass hay, these for - ages were fed in 1924 under comparable conditions to de - termine what per cent would be consumed (Table 16). These 2 crops had been seeded at the respective average rates of 80 and 30 pounds per acre, and were harvested when the seed had reached the soft dough stage. The hay was fed in a rack in an open lot to 21 head of cattle. These cattle, consisting of cows and younger stock, averaged about 900 pounds in weight. In addition to the average daily allow - ance of 6.5 pounds (dry matter) of sorghum or Sudan grass hay to which they had access in alternating periods at all times, the cattle were fed 38 pounds of corn silage consist - ing of 13.5 pounds dry matter per head daily. It was con- Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Per cent iorghum . . . iudan grass 1 2 8.1 6.5 806 225 581 72 7.5 6.5 806 335 471 58 Iorghum . . . iudan grass 3 4 8.8 6.5 806 193 613 76 7.7 6.5 806 260 546 68 iorghum iudan grass 5 6 10.6 6.5 806 277 529 66 10.2 6.5 806 322 484 60 Averagt Sorgl Suda 1 lum .... i grass.. 9.2 8.5 6.5 6.5 806 806 232 306 574 500 71 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Annual Forage Crops 33 sidered that 20 pounds of dry matter would keep animals of this size in good condition. Since the silage was always entirely consumed it was felt that the per cent consumption of the hay would be a measure of its palatability. Preced - ing the test the silage was reduced from about 50 pounds per day per head to 38 pounds and the cattle given access to a mixture of sorghum and Sudan grass hay. Sorghum and Sudan grass hay were fed during alternating periods averaging 5 days each. All results have been calculated to a 5-day basis. For the 3 feeding periods with sorghum it was found that 72, 76, and 66 per cent of the hay was con - sumed, or an average of 71 per cent. The tests with Sudan grass gave 58, 68, and 60 per cent consumption, or an aver - age of 62 per cent. These results were substantiated by 2 other experiments similarly conducted. While these data cannot be considered conclusive it is indicated that neither crop is outstanding with reference to its palatability. Fur - thermore, the amount of hay consumed in these tests de - pended largely on the amount of silage fed since increasing or decreasing the silage ration would decrease or increase the hay consumption in somewhat the same ratio. Table 17. — Comparative rate of curing of Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass hay, during 8 successive days, September 3 to 10, 1924. Crop ! Sept. 3 Sept. 4 Sept. 5 I Sept. 6 j Sept. 7 | Sept. 8 | Sept. 9 j Sept. 10 Per cent Per cent] Per cent j Per cent \ Per cent | Per cent I Per cent I Per cent MOISTURE CONTENT OF HAY' 73 64 I 61 58 I 55 I 58 I 50 I 46 69 47 42 41 35 31 30 26 Sorghum Sudan grass ACCUMULATIVE MOISTURE LOSS BASED ON INITIAL MOISTURE CONTENT Sorghum 0 I 12 16 21 25 29 32 37 Sudan grass 0 32 39 40 49 55 57 62 'Hay harvested at 11 A. M., September 3 and moisture content determined from composite samples. The other moisture data as recorded are from an average of 3 samples taken at 10 A. M. and 3 samples taken at 4 P. M. each day. COMPARATIVE CURING RATES OF BLACK AMBER SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS HAY Crops that are ordinarily harvested for cured forage contain a high per cent of moisture at the time they are cut. Before such forage can be safely hauled in or stacked, its moisture content must be reduced until it approaches an air dry condition. Coarse stemmed grasses such as sorghum and Sudan grass are especially slow in curing or drying </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 even during- most favorable weather conditions. A test was made during the 8-day period, September 3 to 10, 1924 (Table 17), to determine the relative rates of curing of these 2 crops under field conditions when harvested for hay. Al - tho the completion of the test was interrupted at the end of 8 days by unfavorable weather conditions, very suggestive data were obtained. The sorghum and Sudan grass were seeded May 29 at the respective rates of 100 and 25 pounds per acre and were harvested when the Sudan grass reached the stiff dough stage. The initial moisture content of the forage as determined from composite samples taken at the time of harvest was found to be 73 per cent for the sorghum and 69 per cent for the Sudan grass. The moisture contents were deter - mined during 7 succeeding days from averages of 6 com - posite samples taken at 10 A. M. and 4 P. M. from each crop curing under comparable conditions in the swath, wind - row, and cock. The loss in moisture from both crops was most rapid during the first 24 hours and thereafter the rate of loss fluctuated from day to day depending primarily on the drying conditions of the weather. At the end of the 8-day period the sorghum hay contained 46 per cent moisture and the Sudan grass 26 per cent. Hay free from external mois - ture may be safely stacked when its internal moisture con - tent has been reduced to 25 per cent. At the rate at which the sorghum hay had been curing, an additional week of favorable drying weather would have been required to re - duce it to a moisture content equal to that of the Sudan grass which was now in condition for stacking. The ac - cumulative daily moisture loss of the sorghum hay was 12, 16, 21, 25, 29, 32, and 37 per cent respectively of its initial moisture content at time of harvest. Corresponding accumu - lative losses from the Sudan grass hay were 32, 39, 40, 49, 55, 57, and 62 per cent respectively of its initial moisture content. These data indicate that both sorghum and Sudan grass hay cure very slowly but that Sudan cures materially faster than sorghum. This slower rate may be due in part to the somewhat coarser stems of the sorghum and in part to the greater density of its internal sap which contains a higher per cent of sugar in solution. These general in - dications of the more rapid curing of Sudan grass were sub - stantiated by other similar tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Annual Forage Crops 35 SORGHUM AND SUDAN GRASS AS PASTURE CROPS Due to hot, dry weather native and tame grass pastures very often fail to furnish sufficient pasture during the sum - mer months. Of the annual crops adapted to furnish emergency pasture under such adverse conditions Sudan grass is outstanding. The danger of stock being poisoned from pasturing on sorghum is well known and will prevent its extensive use for this purpose. This poisoning, as first established by S. Avery in 1903 in Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin No. 77, is due to prussic acid formation within the plant. It is recognized to be most serious in sec - ond growth and in the case of stunting by dry weather or injury by a frost. When the crop is harvested and the hay well cured most or all of the prussic acid is lost and there is little or no danger in feeding the dry forage. C. T. Doweli in Bulletin 122 of the Oklahoma Experiment Station, how - ever, has shown that under rare and abnormal conditions sufficient prussic acid may be retained in the cured hay to prove fatal. Formation of prussic acid in dangerous quan - tities is much less common in Sudan grass. This is borne out by actual pasturing experience and by chemical analysis. Very few cases of poisoning cattle on Sudan grass pasture have been reported. Menaul and Doweli, in Journal of Agri - cultural Research, V. 18, No. 8, report finding one-third as much prussic acid in Sudan grass as in the grain sorghums. Altho danger from pasturing Sudan grass appears to be small, caution and good judgment should be practiced at all times in pasturing it. Data that show the actual carrying capacity of Sudan grass pasture are very meagre. The Department of Animal Husbandry of the University of Nebraska reports that Sudan grass makes a very desirable summer pasture crop, especially during July, August, and early September. It has been used successfully for several years as a general pasture and in summer feeding tests with steers, sheep, and hogs without loss from prussic acid poisoning. During the hot summer months it undoubtedly has a higher carrying capacity than any other common pasture crop. Vinall and Getty in Bulletin No. 981 of the United States Department of Agriculture show in a review of Sudan grass as a pasture crop that it is becoming of increasing import - ance as summer pasture and that it ranks high under many conditions in comparative value with other pasture plants. When intended for pasture Sudan grass should be sown as early in the spring as conditions will permit. This is or- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 dinarily at the usual time for planting corn or soon there - after. Twenty to thirty pounds of good seed should be sown per acre on a well-prepared seedbed either by broadcasting or drilling. Pasturing should be delayed until the plants are well established or until the growth is from 8 to 10 inches high. Under favorable conditions this crop may be ready to pasture by the latter part of June or early in July. It should not be pastured so close that the plants will be destroyed or that new growth will be checked. In case there is not enough stock to keep the growth under control, a partial crop of hay may be secured. In the event of harvesting a hay crop it would be well to harvest only a part of the field at a time, leaving the other part standing until the new growth starts in that part first harvested. RELATION OF PLANTING RATE TO YIELD OF CORN SILAGE During the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, corn was drilled at 6 different rates varying from 7 to 42 inches apart with - in 42-inch rows. These spacings corresponded with the rates of 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 plants in hills 42 inches apart. Hogue Yellow Dent was used during the first year of the test and Nebraska White Prize thereafter. Nebraska White Prize is a few days later maturing than Hogue but both are standard full-season varieties for southeast Nebraska. These data in - cluding plant measurements and grain and silage yields are recorded in Table 18. The yield of silage increased consistently up to 4 plants per hill and then reduced slightly. As a 4-year average the thinnest rate of 1 plant per hill yielded 5.36 tons of silage per acre, and the 5 successive increased rates yielded 144, 157, 170, 166, and 164 per cent of this, respectively. Correspond - ing yields calculated on a uniform moisture content basis of 15 per cent were 1.84 tons per acre for the rate of 1 plant per hill and relative yields of 153, 173, 187, 183, and 179 per cent, respectively, for the 5 successive higher rates of planting. In both comparisons there was a consistent in - crease in yield of silage up to 4 plants per hill followed by a slight decline. When compared on a uniform moisture basis, however, the thicker rates have a somewhat higher relative yield as compared with the 1-plant rate. The thicker rates of planting contain a higher per cent of dry matter than the thin rates due to earlier ripening or drying, and are at a dis - advantage when yields are compared on a green field basis. The yields of grain increased up to 3 plants per hill and then declined with increased planting rate. The thinnest </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Annual Forage Crops 37 Table 18. — Comparative yields of corn planted at varying rates for silage, 1921-19%b ■An average of 20 plants per rate for the 3 years, 1921 — I 1923 rate averaged 26.1 bushels of corn per acre, while the relative yields of the 5 successive higher rates were 155, 170, 167, and 166, and 144 per cent of this, respectively. As the rate of planting increased, the ears increased in number, but de - creased in size. With an increase in planting rate the individual stalks became smaller as measured by their leaf area and stalk diameter. Leaf area decreased from 1385 square inches per plant in the thinnest rate to 1167 square inches per plant for the thickest rate. The stalk diameter decreased correspond - ingly from 1.28 to 0.94 inches. These decreases amounted to 16 and 27 per cent for the leaf area and stalk diameter, respectively. The relative proportion of leaf weight as com - pared with the total plant weight increased from 12.7 per cent to 16.3 per cent from the thinnest to the thickest rate. These data indicate that where a full season corn is grown, maximum silage yields can be expected under farm - ing conditions in southeastern Nebraska when planted at Leaf Stalk Propotnon Rate area dia- °fj«af of planting' per meter ""f* s== *■*■!■*&gt;■" I t^y mi Yield of ah [e per acre 1922 1923 1924 Average ; Hq. In. ! JncAfa fVr cm/ j 7"on« Tom Tom Tom Tom Relative late 1 1 1,385 158 12.7 7.37 Late 2 1,353 1.19 13.7 10.84 late 3 1346 1.08 14.6 11.82 Late 4 1,241 1.02 14.8 11.95 late 5 1,203 0.95 : 16.4 11.54 late 6 1,167 0.94 i 16.3 11.75 4.38 5.12 5.70 6.07 5.92 5.85 5.43 8.17 851 8.82 951 9.60 456 6.70 7.97 9.68 8.89 7.94 5.36 7.71 8.42 9.13 8.89 8.78 100 144 157 170 166 164 Average. 1582 ! 1.08 14.7 ! 10.88 5.51 854 7.57 8.05 Rate of planting Yield of grain | Yield per acre, air-dry ' basis IMI &gt;f silage er acre reduced to 15 pel loisture content \ 1921 1922 1923 1924 HuiheU | Relative Torn Tom Tom Tom Tom Rtlatii Rate 1 Rate 2 Rate 3 Rate 4 Rate 5 Rate 6 26.1 100 2.56 40.5 155 4X16 44.6 170 4.51 48.6 167 4.62 43.2 166 4.16 37.7 j 144 4.33 1.59 2.00 2.43 2.44 2.36 251 1.78 1.44 2.89 2.30 2.89 2.90 354 3.48 3.49 3.43 3.62 3.01 1.84 2.81 3.18 3.44 3.36 3.29 j 39.3 i 4.04 2.17 2.98 2.76 2.99 I ! Planted at rates corresponding to 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 plants per hill 42 inches apart. tAn ommMk n f 9ft nlanta iuf nfn fn. »ha 1 MMn&gt; 1Q91 1 QQV </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 38 rates equivalent to 4 or 5 plants per 42-inch hill, and maxi - mum grain yields when planted 3 or 4 plants per hill. Tak - ing everything into consideration, 4 plants per 42-inch hill or its equivalent may be considered most productive of sil - age value. The increase is only slight, however, over the yield from corn planted for a grain crop at the most common rate of 3 plants per hill. The same principle will apply thru - out the state recognizing the fact that the planting rate must be reduced westward to meet the less favorable moisture conditions. RELATION OF VARIETY TYPE TO YIELD OF CORN SILAGE Five varieties of dent corn namely: University No. 3, Hogue Yellow Dent, Reid Yellow Dent, Nebraska White Prize, and St. Charles White were grown in comparative silage tests during the 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, at a rate equiv- Tabij: 19.— Com pa rat ire yield of corn varieties i&gt;hmt&lt;&lt;J for gUage, UKil-l'J.l't Nebraska White Prize 1,312 102 ] 10.70 I 5.86 9.33 9.35 St. Charhs White 1,873 106 | 8.82 j 7.22 : 9.76 9.55 Average I 1,263 98 8.99 I 5.77 8.42 8.21 7.85 8.99 8.42 8.21 'This measurement is an average of 20 stalks far each variety in 1923. Variety Leaf Stalk area per , height stalk&gt; 1921 I Yiel I 1922 I Id of Ml 192J lige per acn 1924 re A Sq. In. j Inchr* rom Ton* Tort* Tuns Turn Jniveraity No. 3 1,106 91 8.36 j ] 5.30 6.84 6.06 &gt;■.."; i iogue Yelbw Dent 1,224 M 8.08 5.06 7.84 8.04 :■_':. teid Yellow Dent 1,300 j 100 I 9.01 i P.40 8.33 8.06 T.Tf Yield of grain Yield c Variety per acre, air-dry basis of silage per acre reduced ti moisture content i ' ■ ol to &gt; 15 per cent i 1921 1922 I 1923 1924 Average Bushels Relative Tons Tom Tom Ton* ' Tuns Bated University No. 3 47.8 100 3.32 2.07 2.69 2.41 2.62 100 Hogue Yfllrw Dent 54.0 113 3.35 1.90 3.01 3.40 2.91 111 Reid Yelbw Dent 50.8 106 3.24 j 2.00 3.17 3.12 2.88 110 Nebraska White Prize. ...', 45.8 j 96 3.50 1.94 3.43 3.56 3.11 119 St. Charles White j 28.9 60 3.28 \ Average | 45.4 j 3.34 2.04 3.13 | 2.81 1.99 j 3.09 3.06 i 2.81 1(17 2.87 ', Average I | i [ J I I l_ </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Annual Forage Crops 39 Fig. 8. — Field corn planted for silage. As a 4-year average corn planted at the optimum rate for silage has yielded 3.44 tons per acre (15 per cent moisture basis) as compared with 3.27 for Black Amber sorghum. alent to 3 plants per 42-inch hill. University No. 3 was se - cured each year from Washington County, Nebraska, and is slightly smaller and earlier maturing than the standard grain varieties grown in this part of the state. The Hogue Yellow Dent and Nebraska White Prize seed has been grown at the Experiment Station for many years. Both varieties are con - sidered full season corns for this locality. Nebraska White Prize, however, grows larger and is approximately 5 days later maturing than Hogue and is more subject to immaturity in the fall. The Reid Yellow Dent seed was secured each year from a farmer near the Station and was of somewhat larger type and later maturing than Hogue Yellow Dent. The seed of St. Charles White was secured annually from southern Missouri and was of a large late-maturing silage type. The data from these tests are recorded in Table 19. Compared on a green field basis, University No. 3 yielded 6.64 tons silage per acre as a 4-year average with relative yields of 109, 116, 133, and 133 per cent for Hogue, Reid, Nebraska White Prize, and St. Charles White, respectively. In this comparison the 2 latest corns yielded one-third more pounds green silage than the earliest maturing one. When compared on a comparable basis of 15 per cent moisture con- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 40 tent, however, University No. 3 yielded 2.62 tons per acre while the Hogue, Reid, Nebraska White Prize, and St. Charles White, yielded 111, 110, 119, and 107 per cent of this. The later corns contain a higher moisture content at the time ordinarily harvested for silage, and thus comparative yields on a green basis are unreliable. Grain yields were 47.8, 54.0, 50.3, 45.8, and 28.9 bushels per acre, respectively, for the University No. 3, Hogue, Reid, Nebraska White Prize, and St. Charles White. Cor - responding relative grain yields were 100, 113, 105, 96, and 60 per cent. University No. 3, being a little earlier ma - turing than necessary, is at a disadvantage both in grain and silage yields. The St. Charles White being too late ma - turing is low in grain yield and has no advantage in yield of silage. These data indicate that those variety types which are locally well adapted and most productive of grain are also likely to be best suited for silage. There would seem to be no advantage in growing special silage varieties. Rel - ative size and maturity of the 5 varieties used in these tests can be further contrasted by their respective heights of 91, 93, 100, 102, and 106 inches and leaf areas per plant of 1106, 1224, 1300, 1312, and 1373 square inches each for University No. 3, Hogue, Reid, Nebraska White Prize, and St. Charles White. The greater height and leaf areas are usually evi - dence of later maturity. RELATION OF VARIETY TYPE TO YIELD OF SORGHUM SILAGE Five sorghums, namely, Black Amber, Red Amber, Early Sumac, Kansas Orange, and Blackhull kafir were compared in cultivated rows during a 4-year period, 1921 to 1924, as to silage and grain production. The data are recorded in Table 20. Average silage yields reduced to a 15 per cent moisture basis were 3.27, 3.51, 3.61, 3.47, and 3.10 tons per acre, respectively, for Black Amber, Red Amber, Early Sumac, Kansas Orange, and Blackhull kafir. Correspond - ing relative yields were 100, 107, 110, 106, and 95 per cent. The 4 sweet sorghums averaged 11 per cent more silage per acre than the kafir. The 3 later maturing sweet sorghums, Red Amber, Early Sumac, and Kansas Orange, yielded 7, 10, and 6 per cent more silage than the Black Amber. Grain yields were 29.9, 26.7, 20.7, 8.8, and 19.2 bushels per acre, respectively, for Black Amber, Red Amber, Early Sumac, Kansas Orange, and Blackhull kafir. Correspond - ing relative yields were 100, 89, 69, 29, and 64 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 Table 20. — Comparative yield of sorghum varieties planted for silage, 1921-1924 Yield of silage per acre reduced to 15 per cent moisture content Variety Yield of grain per acre. air-dry basis 1921 I 1922 1923 I 1924 Average Pounds Bushtls Rtlatitt i Tons Tans Tons I Tons Tons Rdatitt Black Amber was the only sorghum to reach full maturity during each year of the test. The lower grain yields of the other sorghums reflect their relative immaturity during the 4-year period. While Black Amber sorghum is most depend - able in maturing seed, somewhat higher yields of silage are produced in this region by the later maturing sorts. Black Amber sorghum yielded 3.27 tons ( 15 per cent mois - ture basis) in comparison with 3.44 tons of corn secured from the optimum rate of planting. Corresponding grain yields were 29.9 and 43.6 bushels per acre. In connection with the recognized superiority of corn silage compared with that of sweet sorghums, these data indicate that corn is the most desirable silage crop under these conditions. COMPARATIVE YIELDS OF CORN AND CORN AND SOYBEAN MIXTURES FOR SILAGE Corn grown alone was compared for yield of silage with a combination of corn and soybeans during the 4 years, 1921 to 1924. The corn was grown at an average spacing of 14 inches between plants in 42-inch rows. In the case of combinations, the beans were grown in addition to the corn, spaced approximately 6 inches apart. The data are shown in Table 21. Average total production of corn alone on a field cured basis was 3.91 tons per acre as compared with 3.95 tons for the mixture. Average grain production was 45.6 bushels per acre for the corn alone and 42.2 bushels of corn for corn and soybeans grown in combination. These data indicate almost identical yields from corn alone and from corn and soybeans grown in combination. In com- Slack Amber j 1,494 29.9 100 | 3.91 3.00 | 2.44 3.72 3.27 100 Red Amber 1,385 26.7 89 3.47 2.77 3.25 4.57 3.51 107 Early Sumac 1,037 20.7 69 4.65 2.57 3.10 4.1S 3.61 110 Kansas Orange .. 441 8.8 29 3.68 2.56 2.78 4.88 8.47 106 Slackhull kafir . . . ■ 962 19.2 64 3.27 2.28 | 2.66 ! 4.20 j 3.10 95 Average j 1,054 j 21.1 3.80 2.64 2.85 4.30 | 3.39 2, 4.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 206 42 bination with soybeans the grain yield of corn is lower than when it is grown alone. In these tests the soybean yield has formed but a small part of the mixed crop. The growing of soybeans in combination with corn for silage is not recom - mended as a general practice for Nebraska conditions. Tablk 21. — Coin /xiriit ire yields of corn, nn&lt;I corn anil soybeans COMPARATIVE YIELDS OF ROOT CROPS Root crops were included with the annual forage crop variety tests in 1924. Four root crops commonly grown for stock feed, namely: sugar beets, half -sugar beets, mangels and rutabagas were grown in comparative yield tests, (Table 22). These data cannot be considered conclusive, but will permit of a comparison of these root crops with each other and with other annual forage crops grown in 1924. When compared on a green field basis at time of harvest the yields were 11.90, 15.19, 15.55, and 10.51 tons per acre, respectively, for the sugar beets, half-sugar beets, mangels and rutabagas, with corresponding relative yields of 100, 128, 131, and 88. When reduced to a uniform moisture content of 15 per cent in order to be comparable with the results from cured forage, the yields were 2.10, 1.89, 1.86, and 1.23 tons per acre, respectively, with corresponding relative yields of 100, 90, 89, and 59 per cent. Comparable yields (15 per &lt;/rotr,, for xilayr. l!&gt;Jl-l!tJJf I Yield of silage per acre on a field-cured basis Cr °P .... i .„. i .„■ i .„. , . 1921 1922 1923 1924 Average Tons Tons Tons Tons Ton* lorn (alone) 6.02 2.48 3.90 3.24 3.91 lorn and soybeans 5.87 2.58 3.90 3.44 3.95 I : ! ' I Grain yield of corn per acre on an air-dry basis Cro P .... i .„_ ■ .... i .... ■ 1921 1922 1923 1924 Average Bushels Bushel* Bushels Bushels Bushels lorn (alone) I 82.1 15.0 58.7 26.7 45.6 lorn and soybeans 68.4 13.1 58.7 28.8 42.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Annual Forage Crops 43 cent moisture basis) of Black Amber sorghum planted for forage and for silage were 4.19 and 3.72 tons per acre and of corn planted for silage 3.48 tons per acre. On the basis of one year's data it would appear that the acreage that can be profitably devoted to root crops will be very limited. For use as special purpose feeds where root crops are considered superior to other forage, they may often be grown advan - tageously even tho the yield is somewhat lower. EXPERIMENTAL TECHNIQUE OF THESE INVESTIGATIONS Duplication and Size of Plats. — All plats were in duplicate and the data as reported are an average of the two. Plats seeded to hay crops were one-thirtieth or one thirty-fifth of an acre in size, being 14 feet or 2 drills in width with a fallow strip 1 foot wide between plats. Silage and root crops were seeded in rows 42 inches apart with 3 to 5 rows per plat and usually 175 feet in length. Plat Competition. — To reduce border effect and competi - tion rather similar varieties and cultural practices were grouped in so far as possible in adjacent plats. When widely different varieties or treatments occurred in adjacent plats, bordering discard strips of each crop were included. Road - ways between fields or at the ends of plats were seeded down and not harvested until a short time before harvesting of the plats. Where border effects or competition were noticeable and discard strips had not been provided the plats were re - duced in size and the affected part discarded. Tabi.k ~2'2. — Comparative yield of root cropx ffwm for forn&lt;/&lt;', '.. ., I ■v:«i,i I Yield Yield per acre I per r acre Variety When harvested With 15 per cent moisture content : i i Tons Relative Tons Relative Sugar beets 11.90 100 2.10 100 Half-sugar beets 15.19 128 1.89 90 Mangels 15.55 131 1.86 89 Rutabaga 10.51 88 1.23 59 Average 13.29 L i 1.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Methods of Seeding. — All hay crops, except where the ex - periment required otherwise, were seeded with an ordinary press drill having 7-inch disks. Special care was taken in calibrating the drill so as to seed the specified amount of seed per acre. The silage corn was commonly planted by hand at double rate and thinned to the desired stand. The silage sorghums and the row crops grown in the method-of - seeding tests were seeded with a corn planter. Root crops were planted with a garden drill and thinned to the desired stand. Seedings were always made on a well prepared seed - bed. The silage crops were surface planted in rows during one year and the other years planted in listed furrows, but were drilled in thruout the test. Root crops were surface planted in rows. Date and Rates of Seeding. — Except in the special studies pertaining to dates and rates of seeding, all crops were seeded as nearly as possible at the time and rate considered optimum for each crop. Sorghum varieties and the Black Amber sor - ghum grown in such cultural studies as the date-of-seeding tests and stages of maturity were seeded 100 pounds to the acre while Sudan grass was seeded 25 pounds to the acre in corresponding tests. The millets were seeded 25 to 30 pounds per acre, oats 12 pecks, field peas 8 pecks, and the two in combination 8 and 4 pecks, respectively. In a corn and soy bean combination the corn was planted 14 inches apart in the row and the soybeans 6 inches. Silage corn was planted 14 inches apart in the row or the equivalent of 3 plants per hill, and the silage sorghums 2 to 3 inches apart. Root crops were thinned to 6 or 8 inches apart in the row. Harvesting. — Effort was made within any one compari - son, excepting in the stage-of-maturity tests and in cases where the crop failed to mature, to harvest the crops at com - parable stages of maturity. Hay crops were largely harvested when the seed was in the soft dough stage and silage crops when the grain began to dent or harden. All crops that re - mained standing late in the season when growth had ap - parently ceased or when there was danger of frost were har - vested regardless of maturity. Comparison on Equal Moisture Content Basis. — Compar - ative yields of crops based on weights of the green or field cured forage may lead to very erroneous conclusions. It is unlikely that the forage from any 2 crops, or from any 2 distinct cultural treatments will contain the same amount of moisture unless they are in a thoroly air-dry condition. The moisture content of air-dry hay will change from time to </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Annual Forage Crops 45 time with atmospheric conditions. A significant comparison of widely different types of crops, as hay, silage, and roots is impossible except on a uniform moisture basis. With but few exceptions (Tables 5, 6, and 21) all forage yields re - ported in this bulletin are based on a 15 per cent moisture content. Yields were first reduced to a moisture-free basis and then recalculated to forage containing 15 per cent mois - ture which is more comparable to well cured forage. Plat weights were taken in the field with a spring dial scale. As soon after weighing as possible a carefully selected composite sample (a 2-bushel bag was usually filled in the case of hay) was taken from each plat and its duplicate. These samples were run thru a small hand feed cutter, well mixed, and reduced in quantity to 500 or 1000 grams, de - pending on the crop and its moisture content. These re - duced samples were placed in small cotton bags and dried in an electric oven. The plat weights were converted to a 15 per cent moisture content on the basis of these samples. [6M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>