<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Systems of Farming and Possible Alternatives in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Bulletin 309 June, 1937 Systems of Farming and Possible Alternatives in Nebraska .: L. RGarey ' ¦'.; Department of Rural Economics : Type-of-Farming Areas in Nebraska Key— • Key— 143 Range livestock, some cash grain, potatoes. 188-B Cash grain, some livestock. 145 Same becu, some livestock, potatoes. 189 Cash (rain, livestock, potatoes. 18Z-A livestock, cash grain. 193 Livestock, general farming, tome cash gnln. 183-A Intensive livestock production. 194 General {arming. 184 Cash grain, livestock, potatoes. 195 Cash; grain, livestock. 186 Ranee livestock. : .196 Livestock, cash grain, general fuming. 187 Livestock, wild hav, cash grain. ' | . . . The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction . . i Area I'Ji 23 Area 182-A 46 Area 183-A 5 Area 187 28 Area 189 47 Area 194 10 Area 188-B 32 Area 143 .48 Area 195 14 Area IS4 . ... 37 Area 186 49 Area 196 19 Area 145 41 SUMMARY Alternatives open to farmers in the western half of Nebraska are more limited than in the eastern half. This is due to climatic conditions which limit the choice of crops lh.it can be grown successfully. Livestock enterprises arc adiustcd to crop production and where there arc limits in the choice of crops there arc necessarily limits in the choice and expansion of live- Mock enterprises. In the eastern part of the state where there is a greater range in the choice of crops than in the western part, some adjustment of crops lo livestock enter - prises may he made. There .ire undoubtedly certain alternatives o:x-n to some farmers in most localities in the Mate. 11 certain cropping alternatives were followed, without any change in the livestock inurnrwv then- would In- : greater conservation of soil resources with no appreciable ruluction m income. Fcnl units produced indicate the clTectivcncss of thg changes in farm organizations indicated. With mi appreciable reduction in the number and quality of feed units that would be pri'i\\ia-i\ b\ ilk- alternative cropping system, it 'is assumed thai the livestock organization would not lie disturbed. However, some changes in livestock could be nude on the lusis "I the Iced units produced il desired. It should be recognized that the feed unus in cither plan may not be of such character that balanced rations can Ik: obtained, but the\ would likely he more nearly balanced in the alternative plan be - cause (it more protein feeds raised. The net change in keel units from the ol&lt;: to the new plan docs not take into account any influence that the suggested cropping system may have on yields. If the system \s follnwcil anv length nf time, there should be an increase in the feed units pro - duced. espcjialK in the areas where tame pasture does well. As indicated, the livestock enterprises will tend to adjust themselves to the crop enterprises. If any appreciable change occurs, it would likely be toward more beef and dairy cattle because of an increased amount of roughage in the alternative system ?n some localities the change should lie toward diiry cattle and in others toward beef. However, in some instances there would be insufficient pasture and roughage to provide adequately for the existing livestock organization: thus no change in livestock would be Ukelv to «kcut. It is not intended th.it the alternatives mentioned are open to all farmers. Physical limitations on some farms would prevent their adoption even though they seemed advisable. Many farmers have already perfected their cropping systems to the point where no change would Ik- wise. For those who have not. it would appear that certain changes could he in.nU- without impairing their income, particularly if some parts of their farm now utilized for grajin production were,devoted to hay and pasture crops. The small percentage of crop land in grain crops in Area 145 is due to a relatively larger acreage of land in sugar beet* and potatoes than is true in the other areas. Be - cause of the adaptation of these crops in this area, the percentage of cultivated land for grain crops is small. The alternatives open to farmers in the way of crop adjustment arc more limited in Areas 14 i. 1 Rfi. and IS') than in the other areas. The alternatives in Area 182-A arc somewhat similar to those in 183-A. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Systems of Farming and Possible Alternatives in Nebraska ¦'¦ • . L. F. GAREYI .. . The results of, a study o£ the fundamental factors which determine the distribution o£ agricultural production in Nebraska appear in Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 299. Only the general conditions affecting agricultural production'were presented in that bulletin. The pur - pose ofthis study is to analyze the type-of-farming areas in greater detail than is done in Bulletin 299 and to present methods useful to farmers in ad - justing their production to changes in economic conditions. It is generally understood that there is considerable variation in the type of agricultural production in a comparatively small area. Although the cli - matic conditions may be uniform throughout, there may be differences in soils, even on the same farm.. Not all farmers have recognized these soil differences, but many have done so, and this fact alone is sufficient to cause some variation in the type of production within small areas. Another reas - on for variation is that farmers do not all respond to the same forces at the same time, nor to the same degree. Not all are willing to assume the risk involved in "taking a chance" by changing their systems of production, even though suggestions for changes may indicate a 'greater return. .-.) It should be tecognized that these typical farm organizations were taken from a small area covering in most cases two to four adjacent townships and are not necessarily'representative of type-of-farming areas as shown on the cover. It should also be recognized that there are many typical farm organi - zations in a township. As many as four typical farm organizations may be L found on 160-acre farms in a single township, and as many as a dozen typical organizations may be represented by the farms in a township. Organ - izations which were commonly found on different-sized farms in the sub - area were used to, represent a typical organization for a particular-sized fsrm. They are indicative of common farm practices found in the subarea. The crop production was determined from the acreage in a typical organ - ization and the yields in the county for the ten-year period 1920 to 1929. The livestock production was determined from t.he number of livestock and what are believed to be reasonable standards of production attained by suc - cessful farmers. The same rate of production has been used for the typical organization as for the alternative open to this organization. In order that all crop production could be measured by a common unit, "feed units" have been used instead of the common unit of measure for each crop. 2 Feed units in potatoes were not determined except in the areas 1 State and Federal Census reports for 1929 were used as a basis for determining the typical organ - izations on farms of different sizes in the" areas studied; Farm reports far small subareas were used'in setting up the typical organizations illustrated. From 200.t0 300 farms were involved in each subarea. The. typc-pf-farming map was the result of a cooperative effort on the part of the Departments of Rural Economics, Agronomy, and Animal. Husbandry of the College of Agriculture; the Nebraska Re - settlement* Administration; and the Bureau of. Agricultural Economics of. the U. S. Department of Agriculture. - ¦¦-.'. - - ¦ "¦: 1 "¦ '¦ • ¦ ¦ ¦¦ .¦ 3 Feed unit! have been determined on the basis of total digestible nutrients. One bushel of com was considered one feed unit and other feeds adjusted accordingly. Feed units per bushel are: corn 1.00, oats 0.47, barley 0.79, wheat 1.00, rye 0.95, and potatoes 0.21. Feed unit! per ton are: alfalfa 20.63, red clover 21.21, sweet clover 15.00, wild hay 15.00, sugar beet pulp 3.08, tugar beet tops 352, corn silage 6.88, sorghum silage 5.54,.and other tame hay 18.00. The figures for each unit of feed are the tout .digestible nutrients compared to those in corn as 1.00 and consequently are relative figures instead of the actual amount of digestible nutrients in any particular feed. - </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 where the crop is important. In such cases the feed units fot potatoes ap - pear in feed units for sale and seed instead of those set aside for livestock, ft is impossible to use a term which expresses accurately the feeding value of all feeds to all kinds of livestock. The digestive-nutrient basis is used for determining the feed units, which are convenient for comparison of feeds, rather than as a true measure of their feeding value. In this connection it should be pointed out that much of the feed grown in Nebraska does not constitute a well-balanced ration, because some of it lacks protein and some of it lacks calcium and phosphorus. While the feed units'as indicated are determined on the basis of total digestible nutrients, they may not be, and frequently are not used, in balanced form with respect to these element;. Only one alternative cropping system for the typical farm organizations used h:is been illustrated. The changes are .such as wouldj aid in the con - servation of agricultural resources and entail a minimum of expenditures. These alternatives are not to be interpreted as general recommendations but rather to be used as guides for farmers so situated that they may apply them tc their particular business in the light of the information available and the existing conditions. Neither are they to be interpreted as recommendations in agricultural planning, although they may be of some use in that con - nection. The alternative used in nearly all cases calls for an increase in the acreage of legumes and pasture, with decreases in that o£ soil-depleting crops. The problem of obtaining a stand of legumes or pasture crops should be considered in adopting an alternative which calls for an increased acre - age in these crops. The choice of legumes in a cropping system should be Umited to those adapted to the locality and farm concerned. No changes in the livestock enterprises have been made in comparing the original and alternative cropping systems illustrated. Certain changes in the livestock in these organizations could and undoubtedly would be made, the changes made depending largely on the changes in crops. An important objective of this study in this connection is to show that certain changes in the cropping system can be made without changing significantly the number of feed units produced. In other words, it would be possible with the indicated change to maintain the stated livestock organization and in many cases sell as many feed units of crops as in the original organiza - tion. If the alternatives illustrated were followed there would be an increase in the amount of feed provided by hay and pasture crops, which would like - ly mean an increase in the number of forage-eating livestock in some sec - tions. The increase in the number of cattle could be either beef or dairy cattle. Conditions other than the feed supply would be involved in deter - mining the nature and extent of the change. In many cases an increase in the number of cattle could be made without any change in the other live - stock enterprises. Such increases would reduce the amount of crops for sale and seed. On the other hand, there might be an. increase in the production of livestock products without any increase in numbers because of an in - creased quantity of more suitable feeds. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">;. Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska The areas will be treated from the standpoint of their agricultural pro - duction and geographic position rather than in numerical order. The map on the cover may be used to locate the different areas. AREA 183-A, INTENSIVE LIVESTOCK PRODUCTION The soils in this area are of loess formation and are very productive. Along the Platte and Elkhorn rivers there are strips of land classed as bot - tom lands and benches, and in the western section is an area known as the outwash plains. Because of the ample.rainfall and general productivity of these soils a rather wide range in the choice of agricultural production is possible. Hogs and beef cattle together account for over half of the total income. The sale of teed, grain, and miscellaneous livestock and livestock products accounts for the remainder. Wheat contributes very little to the income. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 1 shows thejproportion of crop land oc - cupied by indicated crops from 1910 to 1934. JThere was a noticeable de - cline in the relative importance of wheat and a less marked decline in oats. These decreases were absorbed by increases in barley and alfalfa. There was no significant change in the acreage of corn, rye, or wild hay. The acres in cultivated crops increased 31 per cent from 1910 to 1929 and decreased 11 per cent from 1929 to 1934. ' « i—r- : ; —- - : - i .!¦ - . ¦ ¦ ¦ •» • ' ' CORN I ¦ . ZO 1 —— —: - ' ; ID ¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ . - ¦ .: . I ¦ 01 " ¦ ' ' ' ' ' ¦ ¦ ' ' ' I¦¦ I I I ' I I I I r• I I | "«7^ 'tis /no /»«. /»jo —^»m Fie. I.—Percentage of crop land occupied by crops desjgnated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 183-A. Note the proportionately large amount of crop land occupied by corn and oats. ' . .• ¦•:¦ Crop yields.— The average crop yields arid variation for the 24-year per - iod 1910 to 1933, are given in Table 1. The yields of corn and rye were more dependable than those of any of the other major crops grown in Area 183-A. The yield of barley was more dependable jthan that of oats, although </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table I.— Average crop yields and their variation for the period 1910 to to 1933—Area 183-A Yield per zcre in bus. or tons Coefficient of variation 1 rop Average Range between Average Range between for area counties for area counties . P.ct. P.cl. Co™ 31.J6 25.41—37.62 18.46 16.63—30.63 O"" 2')M 26.18—U.12 24.95 22.45—35.67 Barlc V 27.22 2J.H-30.61 19.65 16.66—33.72 whral '7.10 13.72—19.11 22.96 19.65—26.12 R &gt;c 15.Sf&gt; 13.56—21.10 H.12 15.36—31.92 Albl!* 2.X5 2.28- 3.28 21.37 13.72—34.19 1 rooffic.cn. of variation = SUM X 1(10. The coefficient of lariation is a means of measuring the variability Irom ihe average in pcKrntagr. wlicn applied to crop yields it is an indication of the &lt;ie. pendability of (he yield at a particular crop. Small coefficients indicate more dependable yields than large coefficients, SD =: siandard dcsialion; M = mean or average. the acreage of barley was much less. Rye, with a low coefficient of varia - tion, occupied a small acreage, while that of alfalfa has been increasing in acreage for several years even though it has a high coefficient of variation in yield. Shifts in number of livestock units/ I —Figure 2 shows changes in num - ber of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. There was a general increase in the number of cattle other than milk cows up to 1924. From 1924 to 1929 there was a decline, after which there was a general increase. The number of milk cows did not vary much throughout the period. In general the num - -000 WITI no , " ~ — .— *°F- : I nanarM sHiiiiiiiiillii Fig. 2—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 &lt;o 19J-), Area 183-A. chicked. Uni' °f 'iV"IOCk " """""* '° bc equiva 'Cllt l0 onc ho"£. &lt;"" °&gt;w. ' &gt;heep, 5 hogs, or 100 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska ber of hogs increased, although there were some small decreases in some years. The number of horses increased from 1910 to 1920, after which there was a continuous decrease to 1934. The number of sheep varied from year to year. It was high in 1918 and again in 1930. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes are listed in Table 2, The most common size of farm repre - sented in the subarea where the sample was taken was 160 acres, 35 per cent of all farms being approximately 160 acres in size (Table 2). Only 71 Table 2.— Organizations of most typical farms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 183-A j I Acres per farm I 80 | 120 ) ) 160 | 240 | ~320" , P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent ot all farms represented i 10 10 35 8 8 Percent of specified size represented 65 60 45 55 55 C ™PS,' . ;¦•;¦.¦ Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres reed crops , •¦' ¦¦-.... Corn ¦ | 40 55 60 110 140 Oats. ...,,.:.,..;.:........ 115 25 . 35 50 80 Tame hay 1 5 10 15 25- 25 Wild hay 0 4 1 5 15 20 Pasture ...,;..................- 12 .18 35 30 45 Other land. .:......... 8 8 10 10 10 Livestock No. No. No. No. No. Horses .......;....;..;.. -4 5 6 9 10' Cows ....;. ;,,.¦¦ 3 7 82 82 142 Cows mi1ked....,,.......;,. (3) (4) (6) (5) (5) Other catt1e.......: 36 9 9 20 Sows .....,.:.....;....;...:. 5 : 8 ¦¦": 10 15 20 Poultry .............;:.,..... 125 120 125 125 110 'Mostly alfalfa. : ' . | ' !Mosily bed breeding. .' . ¦:. ' I ' per cent of all the farms were represented by the sizes listed in the table, the remainder being below 80 acres, above 320, orjof other uncommon sizes. The farm organization statements in Table 2 represent the most com - mon organizations found on the sizes indicated. |For example, 65 per cent of all the 80-acre farms had the organization indicated and likewise 60 per cent of the 120-acre farms, 45 per cent of the 160-acre farms, and so on. As the size of farms increased, there was an increase in the acreage of feed crops, most of which was corn. The acreage of tame hay increased at a more rapid rate than that of corn.up to the 240-acre farms, which indicat - ed that as farms increased in size there was a tendency for farmers to in - crease the number of their cattle at a more rapid rate than their other live - stock. . :¦. :_ '•": ..' ' '; ¦ ¦¦, .'{ \ : . ¦ ¦'¦ ¦ . :'. The livestock organization in this area has been built around the cattle and hog enterprises. Some of the cows milkqd were of beef breeding. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Fewer cows were milked on the 320-acre farms than on the 240 or 160, but there were more other cattle and hogs. Table 3 gives the cropping system for the typical 160-acre farm in a selected subarea and an alternative system which it is believed will aid in the conservation of the agricultural resources of the farm. The changes in the alternative system involve a reduction in the acreage of corn and oats and an increase in that of legume hay and pasture. In addition to these Table 3.—Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre jarm in a selected subarea in Area 18i-A Original cropping system Alternative cropping system Crops j j 1 1 Acres | Yield | Production Acres [Yield j Production flu. or Feed Bu.or feed Soil-Depleting T. tmittl T unit* 1 C°"&gt; 60 39 2,340 2,340 56 39 2,184 2,184 Oats 35 33 1.155 543 15 33 495 233 Barley 13 35 455 359 Sorghum 2 8 16 89 Soil-Conserving Legume hay2 15 3 45 92S 15 3 45 928 Sivccr clover *'' 2 60 r &gt;c3 2 .' ;; 6o Total for culti - vated crops 110 3,811 105 .. 3 913 Neutral Wild hay 5 l.s 'i 1?5 5 i.j 9 135 Total for all crops* ... 115 3,946 110 .. .. .f^g Permanent pasture 35 618 40 706 Other land 10 10 Total for h»m lf.U 4.564 160 .. 4,754 1 For explanation of iced unit see footnote, pace 3 'Mojily alfalfa. 1 Pastured. 1 Duel not include irraiv nor com stalks. changes barley, rye, sweet clover, and sorghum for silage and hay, which are not in the original organization, have been added. Rye and sweet clover have been added for pasture. These changes in acreage would result in some change in the feed units produced. There would be a reduction of 18 feed units produced from harvested crop land, but an increase in the feed units from pasture of 208, or a net increase for the farm of 190. The same yie d of crops per acre has been used in the two cropping systems. The yields in the alternative system would undoubtedly be higher in time and would aflect the production to that extent. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 4. In both the ongina and alternative systems this is in accord with the general practice in the locality. The quantity of each grain sold may not be exactly as in - dicated, for farmers may prefer to sell more corn and less oats, but the total amount in feed units will be about as indicated with the particular live- </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska -.-¦.¦ I . ¦ - .- . Table 4.— Disposal of feed to livestock^ in the original cropping system .¦•-.. shown in Table 3 \ _. , Feed units Livestock Number 1 Farm grown | Purchased I Total Hotsa 6 493 -.. 493 P°"? ••••• '¦'¦ '•¦.. 8 534 .. 534 Other cauls—-.. : 9 . 375 375 Sows .............. jo 250 47 297 Other h0g5..:..,...,... 15,0001b5. 1,050 60 1,110 % ulay ¦¦¦¦¦¦ ••• 125 126 22 146 Total, hot including • : . | ":..¦ '¦.'¦' pasture;.. .. 2,828 129 2,957 stock organization. The livestock would consume 2,828 farm-grown feed units, not induding pasture. No feed units from pasture have been in - cluded in those listed for sale and seed. There would be 1,118 feed units for sale and seed in the original cropping plan, consisting of corn, oats, and hay. . i The alternative cropping system would provide for the same livestock organization/There would be left 1,100 feed units for sale, consisting of corn, oats, and hay. The change in the number and nature of the feed units in the alternative plan would provide for an increase in the number of either beef or dairy cattle, the kind depending on the conditions on the farm and the desires of the operator. : ' Table s.—Cash returns above variable expenses for the original system on the 160-acre farm in Table 3, Area 183-A &#132;,_, ¦¦• ¦-¦:' Total Variable !"«&gt;«« *we . lICm income expense vanable ¦'--•• ¦ ¦ \ expense Corn ..................,........'.... $376 JB6 $290 p"5 ••¦:¦• .:............;:..:..;. 221 :7r w Legume hay 6, 45 -39 Total for crops.;.. §603 . $205 $398 Butterfat ... i ...;..; 1 .,".:...'...;.¦..;,:.;'.¦ $451 .. $451 Cattle., 232 .. 232 H °ss v..,.,.;.....:..;........, 1,050 $1H 936 Poultry .;.. , 143. 22 121 Total por LrvESTocK $1,876 ?136 $1,710 Total for crops and livestock... .... 52,479 5341 $2,138 Alternatives ' ¦ '.: \. : -y\ ... . ::. 1. Same as original cropping system except that corn and oats sold in original system are fed to hogs. . .$2,361 '. 2. Alternative cropping system given in Table 3 and same livestock as ' in original system... .... . .; $2,090 3. Same as Alternative 2 except that all of corn, barley, and part of legume hay sold in Alternative 2 are fed to beef cattle .......... .$2,282 ¦ : ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ .-¦¦..( . '¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Retums.-Table 5 gives the returns above variable expenses for the ori - ginal system and the alternative. The returns to the original organization above vanabe expenses amount to $2,138, of which $398 ate from crops and $1,740 from livestock Three alternatives with the returns for each are also listed as possAilmes for this particular size and type of farm organization. Alternative 1 md.cates the greatest return of any, but it includes no in - crease ,n conservation practices. Alternative 2 gives approximately the same returns as the original system. Alternative 3 gives more than the original or Alternative 2, but not as much as Alternative 1. In Alternative 3 no manure credit is allowed for the additional cattle feeding done under that system. It does include sound agricultural conservation practices and on the average would pay better when increased yields in this system and fertilizer credit are taken into account. AREA 194, GENERAL FARMING A large part of the soils in this area are of glacial origin. Along the eastern and northern edges of the area loess soils are prominent. These soils are productive and with a normal amount of rainfall a wide choice of crops is possible. r Hogs and cash grain account for about two-thirds of the total income Dairy and other cattle provide about equal amounts and together account for about one-fifth of the total. Winter wheat is the chief cash grain crop in the area although a considerable amount of corn is sold 30 - ¦ . . . 20 ¦ ' ~ ¦ CORH jo - — __ '*" '»*• idzs ' /tio ' ' n * 1934, Area 19-f Note the proporaonately large amount of crop land occupied by kXng W6 I"'' 5' tlOn °f WhClt aCreaBe " m7v"&gt; due to wint"- </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska dine in the relative acreage of wheat and an increase in that o£ corn. The decrease in the wheat acreage In 1917 was due to an unusual amount ot . winterkilling during the winter of 1916-17. The decrease in wheat land in 1917 was absorbed by increased acreages in corn and oats. Very little rye or barley was grown in the area and the relative importance of oats did not change much. The relative importance of alfalfa increased slowly until about 1920, after which there was not much change. Crop yields.—The average crop yields and for the 24-yeat per - iod from 1910 to 1933 are given in Table 6. The yields of alfalfa and wheat are more dependable than those of the other major crops grown in the area as indicated by their coefficients of variation. The decline in wheat acreage has doubtless been due to greater remuneration from corn in spite of a more dependable wheat yield. Table 6.—Average crop yields and their variation jar crops indicated jor the period 1910 to 1933—krea 194 Yield per acre in bus. or tons Coefficient of variation 1 ro '&gt; Average Range between i Average Range between • ¦ for area counties ) for area counties "¦¦:. . . ' : . . p.ct. , t.a. Corn... 28.05 23.88—32.43 26.18 23.77—37.44 Oats 29.30 27.14—31.20 23.53 24.36-32.93 Barley; 25.55 23.60—29.11 21.09 18.99—27.50 Wheat. .;.. 17.05 15.50—18.82 17.60 15.80—23.93 Rye 17.92 16.12—19.12 20.23 13.57—23.06 Alfalfa . ; , 2.76 2.42—3.05 16.74 18.86—25.29 : JSce note, Table 1. . ~ -'- /':._¦ ... ' Shifts in the number o£ livestock units.—Figure 4 shows the change in the number of livestock units. There was no definite trend in total num - ber from 1910 to 1934, although the number in 1934 was greater than that of any other year except 1917 and 1918. There was a tendency toward a de - crease from 1918 to 1931, with a rather rapicl increase afterward. After 1914 there was a tendency for the number of horses to decrease and dairy and beef cattle to increase. The number of hog units varied throughout the period, but in 1934 the number was higher tl an that for any other year except 1923. ' ¦tM . .i ' " ' ¦ ' ¦ •¦"-¦' ' ' ran ' \ wo - ¦ • —.-».. I ' ¦ •&lt;¦ call ' •*- O 1 r t I 1 I I I I ( I I I . t I 1 I t I I I I I Uio ISIS I*o 1» 'WS HJ» Flo. 4.—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 194. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of the most typical farms of different sizes are listed in Table 7. The 160-acre farms in the sub - area where trie sample was taken constituted 35 per cent oi all the farms. The 120-acre, 200-acre and 240-acre farms constitued 10 per cent for each group, the 80-acre 7 per cent, and the 1320-acre 6 per cent. Twenty-two per cent of the farms were below 80 acres, above 320 acres, or of other sizes which did not fall in the size classification used. The farm organizations listed in Table 7 represent the most common organizations found on the size of farms indicated. Table 7.— Organizations of most typical farms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 194 . Acres per farm Item _ mi | 120 ' 160 1 200 | 2-10 | 320 P. d. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent of .rl farms represented 7 10 35 10 10 6 Per cent of specified size represented nO 55 -10 50 50 50 Crops Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Feed crops Corn -M -10 50 80 75 100 Oats in 12 15 25 20 40 Tame h.iy 5' 8' 71 20 15 30 Wild h.n 5 5 3 10 5 10 Wheat II 25 -10 30 60 60 Pasture IS 25 40 25 55 60 Other land 5 i 5 10 10 20 Livestock Xn. Xo. \'o. No. No. No. Horses 5 5 (, 7 8 10 Cows 4 4 5 82 6= 10= Cows milked (5) (4) (4) (6) (4) (6) Other cattle 4 n d 6 10 28 Sows 3 .i 4 9 7 15 Poultry inn 1211 HO 120 HO 175 ' Mostly .illalfj. 1 Mostly ol beef tirccil.nc As ihe farms increased in size the acreage of feed crops increased ex - cept on the 240-acre farms. The reduction in feed crops on this size of farm was offset by an increase in the acreage of wheat. Farms of 160 to 240 acres devoted a larger acreage to the production of wheat than the smaller or larger farms did. The livestock organizations are built around the hog and cattle enter - prises. Some cows are milked, but many of them are of the beef breeds. Dairying is relatively more important in relation to other livestock in this area than in Area 183-A. Table 8 gives the cropping system for the typical 160-acre farm in the' subarea and an alternative system which should aid in the conservation of the agricultural resources in the area. The alternative system calls for a re- </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska Table 8. — Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre farm in a selected subarea in Area 194 Original cropping system Alternative cropping system Crops j r- ; —: —j 1 ; Acres | Yield | Production Acres | Yield Production ' Bu.or Fecdl Ba.or Feed Soil Depleting T. unitsl T. unitsl Cora ....... 50 .34.2 1,710 1,710 48 34.2 1,642 1,642 Oats ...... 15 33.0 495 233 9 33.0 297 140 Barley ...... .. ... .. .. 8 23.7 190 150 Sorghum .... .. ... . ..2 3.3 6.6 36 Wheat ..... 40 195 796 796 22 19.9 438 438 Soil Conserving ' ¦ }. " . '¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ .¦¦ Legume hay 2 7 2.8 19.6 405 13 2.8 36.4 761 Sweet clover3 .. .. .. .. 3 .. ..90 Rye3 ......:. .. :. '.. .. 1 .. .. 30 'Other hay.,.. .. ... 1: ... 2 1.0 2.0 30 Total for culti- ' -''-. . ¦ . ¦ ' ' . vatedcrop*.. 112 &#132; ..' 3,144 108 '&#132;:¦ .. 3,317 Neutral ! ¦¦ ¦ . .' ¦-. Wild hay:... 3 1.1 3.3 50 3 1.1 3.3 50 Total for all .. : crops*.....: U5 .. ..3,194 111 .. .. 3,367 Permanent . ¦¦ .... ¦ : pasture ... 40 .. ; ¦ ..: 480 44 .. .. 576 Odicr land,.. 5 ... .. ...', 5 .. .. .. Total for farm 160 &#132; • .. 3,674 160 .. .-. 3,943 1 For explanation of feed unii ice footnote, page 3. ' . ¦ 1 Monly alfalfa. ¦ ,; •.Uied tor pasture. . ,j ,' . :. ' ¦ . * Does not include straw nor coin stalks. .. duction.in the acreages of corn, oats, and wheat and an increase in that of tame hay and tame pasture. Barley, sorghum, and rotation pasture have been added in the alternative plan. Four acres have been removed from cultivation and added to permanent pasture. The changes would result in an increase of 269 feed units for the farm. Although there would be a re - duction in the acreage of cultivated land, the total feed units would be in - creased because of changing from low to high producing crops. The same yields for the two plans have been used in setting up the table, but one could expect a little .higher yield in the alternative plan in time, because of a larger legume acreage and the elimination of a few acres of the poorest land. ; ¦ . ; . !- . The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 9. It is assumed that the same feeding practices are followed in 1 both the original and the al - ternative system. The livestock would consume 1,796 farm-grown feed units, not including pasture, according to feeding methods used in the area. There would be 1,398 feed units for sale in the original plan, consisting of corn, oats, and wheat. In the alternative cropping system there would be 1,451 feed units for sale, consisting of corn, wheat, barley, and hay. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 9.— The disposal of feed to livestock in the original cropping system shown in Table 8 Feed lints Livestock Number j j Farm grown | Purchased | Total Horses 6 -197 .. 497 Cow&gt; 5 322 .. 322 Other cattle fi 261 261 Sows -\ 119 6 125 Other hogs fi.ooolbs. -I'll 24 -l-H Poultry HO 177 29 206 Total, not including pasture 1.796 59 1,855 There is an increase in the feed units in pasture in the alternative system of 216, which can probably best be utilized by dairy cows, but the expan - sion in the number of cows would depend on the conditions on the farm and the desires of the operator. Returns.—The method followed in figuring returns is the same as that illustrated in Table 5. The returns above variable expenses for the original plan and three alternatives are given below. Original cropping system §1,750 Alternatives: 1. Same as original except all corn sold in original system is fed to hogs $2,041 2. Alternative cropping system given in Table 8 and same livestock as in original system §1,756 3. Same as Alternative 2 except feed grain and hay sold in Alternative 2 are fed to dairy cows $2,21 1 The returns to the original organization above variable expenses amount to $1,750, of which 8907 are from crops and $843 from livestock. Alter - native 1 indicates a greater return than the original plan or Alternative 2. Alternative 3 has the greatest return, amounting to 52.2J 1 above variable expenses. This does not include the additional manure credit which would result from more cows nor any increase in crop yields which in time would likely result from this system. One should recognize that if milk cows are added to a farm organization, additional labor is required, and in some cases additional capital outlay may be necessary. AREA 195, CASH GRAIN AND LIVESTOCK The soils in this area are nearly a]) loess. The topography of the land is level or gently rolling, thus making the area as a whole well suited to cultivation. Because of undependable rainfall during the growing season, there is not as wide a range in the choice of crops as in areas east and north. The income from the sale of hogs and wheat is about equal and ac - counts for approximately two-thirds of the total. Dairy and other cattle </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska ¦-¦¦¦' ¦ ¦ • ''' I ' ' ¦ " ' contribute about as much as hogs. Miscellaneous sources account for the remainder. . , . . Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 5 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied-by different crops from 1910 to 1934. During the period there was a decline in the acreage of wheat and an increase in that of corn, with WHEAT so - A-l 1111 : IJ4\|[ilLl LlL^^ui-J-U^—a X - ... &gt;- CORN Ii ¦ . o| i ii ti i i i t it i i i i i ii i ii i ' i If'O :-,¦¦¦ ISIS I9ZO I9ZS 1930 l&gt;3* FlO. s.—Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 195. Note the proportionately large amount of crop land occupied by - corn.and wheat. The reduction of wheat acreage in 1917 was due to winterkilling .in 1916-17. ¦;, •¦; ; ¦ ..-. ¦.¦'. ' &#132; • . ;,j.'.-¦ ..-,-. : . ¦ . : not much change in that of other crops. The big decrease in the acreage of wheat in 1917 was the result of a large amount of winterkilling during the winter of 1916 and 1917. Most of the abandoned wheat land was planted to corn in 1917 and the remainder to oats, as indicated in Figure 5. . Crop yields.—The average crop yields and their variation for the 24 - -year period 1910 to 1933, are given in Table 10. The yield of alfalfa was the Table 10.— Average crop yields and their variation for crops indicated for . the period 1910 to 1933—krea 195 '¦"..' Yield per acre in bus. or tons Coefficient of variation l P Average Rangebetwecn Average Range between ¦ forarea. counties for area counties . ¦¦¦"¦'"['¦' P-ct. Pet. Corn ........... 24.77 19.17—30.20 3134 24.98--45.22 Oats 29.60 23.28—32.36 30.92 28.04—39.29 Barley .......:.. 25.12 ' 21.63—28.49 35.37 22.75—40.51 Wheat 15.19 12.23—17.21 26.68 25.56—37.77 Rye ........... 15.52 12.84—18.26 21,58 14.87—35^6 Alfalfa .;....... 2.55 1.99—3.01 ; 18.32 15.83—33.24 'Sec note, Table 1. .-.'¦¦¦¦. ..'..'. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 most dependable of all of the crops listed. Rye, with the next lowest coef - ficient of variation, was not grown as extensively as wheat, which had a higher coefficient. Shifts in number of livestock units. —Figure 6 shows the changes in the number of units of the different kinds of livestock from 1910 to 1934. The number of cattle in the area reached the peak in 1918 when there were a few over 290,000 head. Most of the increase up to 1918 was in cattle other than milk cows. After 1925 the number of milk cows increased and after ons| ~^~ I ill M||j). '' '" ' '' I — ornot "Tnr afc"~-^.,i, ¦ ¦ ¦ ' ito ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ 1^ ¦ ' ' ' &#132;i, ' ¦=^ Fig. r.—Slumber ..I tivmmck units f..r the period 1910 to 1934, Area 195. 1928 the number of cattle other than milk cows increased. The number of hogs on farms changed but little from 1910 to 1920 but increased slowly after 1920. There was a tendency for the number of horses to decrease throughout the period. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes arc listed in Table 11. The most common size of farm in the subarea where the sample was taken was 160 acres, 30 per cent of all the farms being approximately 160 acres in size. As only 80 per cent of the farms are of the sizes indicated, the remainder are belotv 80 acres, over 320 acres, or of other sizes. The organization statements listed under the specified size in Table 11 represent the most common organization tor a particular size. Sixty per cent of the 80-acre farms, 50 per cent of the 120-acre farms, 40 per cent of the 160-acre farms, 60 per cent of the 200-acre farms, 50 per cent of the 240 - -acre farms, and 60 per cent of the 320-acre [arms have the type of organiza - tion indicated. About 50 per cent of the crop land was devoted to the production of feed crops on all sizes of farms except the 80-acre ones, which had about 60 per cent in feed crops. Wheat was the principal cash grain crop grown. The livestock organization was built around the hog and cattle enterprises. The expansion in the number of livestock was not in proportion to the ex - pansion in crops as the size of the farm increased, indicating that a larger proportion of feed crops was sold on the large than on the small farms. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska ¦ ': ¦ ' ¦ . ¦- I . ' ' ; ¦¦ ¦ :¦'-.' ¦ ! . ¦ Table 11.— Organizations of most typical {arms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 195 : ' ' Acres per farm Item ¦ ~ 80 | 120 | 160 | 200 | 240 | 320 P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent o£ all farms .-.•-¦ i represented .......... .9 9 30 9 15 8 Per cent of specified i size represented....... '60 50 .40 60 50 60 Crops Acres {Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres F'tZ°" s ..:....,.¦ 25 ':¦'¦&gt; 40 si) : 55 70.-105 Oats 5 15 15 20 10 35 ,; Barley .....:. r :.. ,¦:¦;..- 3 ; 5 5 8 Tame Hay1.:....,. 5 5 5 .7 .8 15 Wild hay...... ;'¦ .. &#132; 2 6 ' 8 12 Wheat 25 . 35 50 60 100 90 Other cr0p52.......... .- , 3 .3 2 4 5 Pasture .. .....; 15 15- 25 30 25 40 Other land.. 5 7 . 7 15 10 10 Livestock No. No. No. No. No. No. Horses ..;,.......;. 4 ' :.5 . 6 . ' » \ Cows 4 3 5 5 6 8 ¦¦ Coi« milked.... .:. (3) (2) (4) (4) (5) (5) Other catt1e.......... 4 2 :5 5 6 8 Sows 3 2 4 4 5 10 Poultry ..........;.. 100 HO 125 125 125 125 'Mostly alfalfa. . ¦ . 2 Mostly grain sorghum, c . ' : Table 12 gives the cropping system for the typical 160-acre farm in the subarea and an alternative system which includes more conservation prac - tices than the original system. The changes in the alternative cropping sys - tem in Table 12 involves a reduction in the acreage o£ corn, oats, and wheat and an increase in that of barley, legume hay,| and both tame and perman - ent pasture. It is suggested that four acres of jthe poorest crop land be put in permanent pasture. The tame pasture would consist of rye and sweet clover and would have a greater carrying capacity than permanent pasture. There.would be an increase in feed units from crop land in the alternative system of 231. The increase is the result of shifting some of the grain acreage to legume crops. . I y The disposal of feed to livestock for the original system is indicated in Table 13. The total feed units of farm-grown crops required for the live - stock was 1,715, making 987 units available for sale and seed in the original system, not including pasture, and some hay consumed by livestock had to be purchased because of insufficient production on the farm. The crops for sale were practically all wheat and corn. In the alternative system there would be 1,078 feed units for sale and seed which would consist of wheat, corn, and a small quantity of barley and ••¦¦:. ¦ ; .... '... ; ¦ ¦.¦•.; '¦¦ ; . ''. ;. .' ¦'¦';¦ i:-.' ': v ..¦;--.'-.' ¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 12.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre farm in a selected subarea in Area 195 Original cropping system Alternative cropping system Crops j j ¦ ¦ Acres [ Yield [ Production Acres | Yield | Production -&#132; _ , Bu-or F«&lt;l Bti. or Feed Soil-Depleting T. units* 7 ttn j u l °"n 50 25.4 1,270 1,270 44 25.4 1,118 1,118 Oats 15 30.6 459 216 6 30.6 186 87 Barley i 26.9 81 64 8 26.9 215 170 Sorghum 3 2.2 6.6 37 2 2 2 4 4 24 Whrat 50 16.6 Bio 830 42 16.6 697 697 Soil-Conserving Legume hay2 5 2.5 12.5 258 13 2.5 32 5 670 Sweet clover 3 5 " ]00 Ryc 2 .. .. 40 Tm.M. 1 or ci I.TI - -vATiDriioi-s i:i. 2.675 122 .. .. 2,906 Neutral Wild hay 2 o.') 1.8 27 2 0.9 1.8 27 Total [OR all (Rnps4 !-'' 2.702 12-1 . 2,933 Permanent pasture 25 258 29 . 300 Other land " 7 Totm. ton farm lii» 2.''W) 160 3 233 !Ljrec part alfaKa. 1 Paj[urc. 4 Docl not include tlraw nor corn it.ilks. hay. The change in the feed units in the alternative system would provide for an expansion in cattle. Because of the increased carrying capacity of the pasture this could be dairy cows and has been so considered in determining the returns. Table 13.— Disposal of feed to livestock^ in the original cropping system shown in Table 12 t.i i F"d units Uvcsiock Number Farm grown | Purchased [ Total Horses 6 ~^ ~^j~ Cows 5 330 330 Other cattle 5 -&gt;23 223 Sows 4 U9 6 125 Other hogs 6,000 lbs. 420 24 444 Poultry 125 126 26 152 Total, not including "*"** 1,715 56 1,771 Returns.—The method of figuring the returns is the same as that used in Tab e 5. The returns above variable expenses for the original plan and three alternatives are given below. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska Original cropping system ......:.......;....... $1,439 Alternatives: 1. Same as original cropping system except all feed grain sold in original system is fed to h0g5..;........... $1,581 2. Alternative cropping system given in!Table 12 and ' same livestock as in the original 5y5tem.............. $1,454 /:' 3. Same as Alternative 2 except feed grain and hay sold in Alternative 2 are fed to milk c0w5.!............:.. .$1,646 There is practically no difference in the returns from the original plan and the alternative cropping system with the same livestock. The returns are greater when the feed grain sold is fed to, hogs. They are greatest in the alternative cropping system when more milk cows are included in the livestock set-up. The alternative cropping system should eventually result in greater returns for the Alternatives 2 and 3, fjecause of higher yields that would undoubtedly come from that system, i AREA 196, LIVESTOCK, CASH GRAIN, ANDGENERAL FARMING The soils of this area are loess. Most of the upland soil is fertile and suitable for cultivation. Because of the quality, of the soil and nearness to water the bottom-land soils are very productive'. Hogs constitute the largest source of income, about two-fifths of the total coming from that source. The income from the sale of hogs is nearly equal to that from the sale of all other livestock. The income from the sale of grain, of which wheat is the most important, accounts for about one - third of the total income. ' j 30=¦•-:: — _ • ' : : ' " -—corn ; ¦jo z - '- •" -'¦¦-¦ - ¦ - - o\ i i it ii I i i i ' i i r r ll r I it t it} /SIO 1915 '»iO /»« /»1O /»J» Flo. 7. —Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 196. Note the proportionately large amount of crop land occupied by corn and wheat. The decrease in wheat acreage in 1917 was due to winterkilling in 1916-17. Note a general increase in corn acreage and a decrease in wheat. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 7 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied by different crops from 1910 to 1934. There was a noticeable increase in the relative acreage of corn and a decrease in wheat. Following the decrease in wheat acreage in 1917, due to winterkilling during the winter of 1916-17, the abandoned wheat land was planted to corn and other ciops which, for the most part, were grown for forage. The acres in culti - vated crops increased 24 per cent from 1910 to 1930 and decreased 10 per cent from 1930 to 1934. Crop yields.—The average crop yields and their variation for the 24 - -year period 1910 to 1933, are given in Table 14. While there was not a wide variation in crop yields among counties in this area, there was wide variation from year to year. The yield of alfalfa is more dependable from year to year than that of grains, because the alfalfa in this area is nearly all grown on bottom land close to water tables, while the grain crops are grown on both the bottom and upland soils. Table 14.— Average crop yields and their variation for the period 1910 to mi—Area 196 Yield per acre, bus. or ions Coefficient of variationl Average Range between Average Range between for area counties for area counties Corn 19.33 17.30—21.03 36^6 34.86—53.41 Oats 26.U 22.60—28.91 33.19 32.14—38.62 Barley 2vl.S's 19.70—23.54 35.70 29.20—43 61 Wheat 12.56 10.92—15.46 28.06 25.34—41.57 Rye 12.M 11.36—15.18 27.24 25.80—34.28 Alfalfa 2.36 2.13— 2.92 17.26 14.13—27.86 1 Sec footnote. Table 1. Shifts in number of livestock units.—Figure 8 shows the change in the number of different kinds of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. There was sn increase in the number of cattle other than milk cows from 1912 to 1920, and not much change from 1920 to 1925. There was a decrease from 1925 Him *** " M unu «l ¦ i i i i i i i i i i i i i i i i i i ¦ i I i ¦ ""&gt; »'S MM 1)8 l))0 1W Fig. B.—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 196. to 1927, after which the number increased to the end of the period. The number of milk cows was lowest when the number of other cattle was high - est, except for the period 1932 to 1934. The number of hogs increased </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska generally throughout the period and the number of horses decreased. Sheep have been relatively unimportant in this area as compared to other live - stock. . .. ¦'.-;-'..¦ ..¦..';. ¦•; •-."'¦ Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes are listed in Table 15. The most common size of farm in the subarea where the sample was taken was 160 acres, 25 per cent of all the farms being approximately 160 acres in size, j Seventy-five per cent of all the farms were represented by the sizes, indicated in Table 15, the remainder being below 120 acres, above 640 acres, or of other sizes. Table 15.— Organizations, of most typical\jarms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 196 ¦ Acres per farm • Ilcm - 120 1 160 | 200 | 240 | 320 | 480 | 640 ':¦¦¦' P.ct. P.ct. ¦ P.ct.) P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent of all farms ! represented ........ 5 25 7 13 15 6 4 Per cent of.'specified size represented.... 50..'-.. 45 50 50 40 40 50 Crops Acres Acres Acres'. Acres Acres Acres Acne Feed crops ¦¦•'..' : Corn 50 50 80 80 85 120 140 Oau .......... 10 20 20 10 20 20 20 8ar1ey.......... .. .... .. .. ."...- 5 Tame hay1...... 5 5 5 20. 10 20 35 Wild hay........ .. .. .: :. 15 10 40 Wheat ............ 20 . 50 40 40 80 80 100 Other crops. ........ 5 .. 5 5 5 Pasture ............ 30 30 40 75 80 200 240 Other land.. ...... 5 5 10 15 25 .25 55 Livestock No.. No. No. No. No. No. No. Horses ........:.. 5 6 7 7.8 10 11 Cows ............ 3 5 42 72 9 2 10 2 252 Cows milked...... (3) (4) (3) I (4) (5) (6) (9) - Other catt1e........ 3 4 4 j 10, 7 18 36 50w5.;.........:. 2 4.5 54 9 25 Poultry ........... 75 90 75 125 120 120 150 1 Alfalfa, sweet clover. ; ¦ ".. ' . . ; 3Mo«Iy beef breeding. . - . .: .; "¦ . ¦ . ... The farm organization statements listed in Table 15 represent the most common ones found on.the sizes indicated. For example, 50 per cent of the 120 acre farms had organizations as indicated in the table, 45 per cent of the 160, 50 per cent of the 200, and so on. The proportion of crop land oc - cupied by wheat showed very little, tendency to increase as farms increased in size. This suggests that the larger farms either had relatively more live - stock than the smaller ones or that a larger proportion of their income was from the sale of feed grains. The livestock organization on the small farms was built around the cattle enterprises although there were some hogs. On the large farms hogs were relatively more important than on the small farms. -.-. . ;. ':•','-, : ¦ ¦ ¦..'" •'¦¦.'-¦: ¦-. - </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 16 gives the cropping system for the typical 160-acre farm in the subarea and an alternative system which has more conservation practices in it. In the original system 2,030 feed units would be, or were produced from crops, not including pasture. The permanent pasture would provide 153. In the alternative system there would be a reduction in the acreages of corn and wheat. Barley, grain sorghum, other tame hay, and sweet clover and Table 16. — Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre farm in a selected subarea in Area 196 Original cropping system Alternative cropping system '°P Acres | Yield | Production Acres Yield | Production Bu.or Feed Bu.or Feed T. units 1 T. unitsl Soil-Depleting Corn ill IH.'&gt; &lt;H5 945 47 18.9 888 888 Oats 20 2S.fi =512 241 Wheat =50 12.1 Wii fi&lt;)s J5 12.1 42-i H2-f Barley 15 22.fi 339 268 Grain sorghum 5 9.9 50 -)6 Soil -Conserving I.c K umc hay 2 5 2.1 1(1.5 217 5 2.1 10.5 217 Other umc ha) . 3 4 1.1 4.4 66 Sweet clover * ¦' 39 Rye * 2 26 Total for CULTI- „, VATF.D crops I-'S 2.008 Ilfi .. 1,974 NW hay 4 ".4 l-« V- 4 °--* 16 22 Total for am. , „_, crops I- 1" 2.1) 51) 120 . . 1,996 Permanent „„„ pasture 2h 15 i 55 206 Other lami 5 To, mum l'"&gt; m 2--202 1 For rxptjfUMilll »t tccit umi v« li..,uiiiic. l'.»Kt * : Moitly slfalla. ' Swrct clover ami inull jirjin * Pjtmrc. rye pasture have been added. Nine acres of the poorest crop land have been removed from cultivation and put into permanent pasture. These changes would result in a production of 2,202 feed units, an increase of 119 over the original system. The increase in the number of feed units from new crops and additional pasture more than offset the reduction in grain crops. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 17. The disposal cf farm-grown feed to livestock in the original cropping system amounted to 1,616 feed units from crops, not including pasture. There would be 414 Eeed units for sale and seed, nearly all of which would be wheat and corn. It would be necessary to buy additional roughage for the existing livestock in the original system. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska Table 17.—The disposal of feed to livestock inthe original cropping system shown in Table 16 I | F"d ""to Uvatock N"mW JFarmgrown | Purchased | To^T Horses .......:; 6 497 ' .. «7 Cows &#132;;...,.....:... 5 322 ;,... 322 Other cattle...... 4 : 167 .. J67 Sows ....,.;.... ¦) j H9 6 125 Other hogs. 6,0001b5. 420 24 444 Poultry 90 . 91 19 110 Total, not including ¦¦¦ pastuke. ¦,¦....¦......: .. 1.616 ¦ ® L665 The utilization of the crop land as indicated in the alternative cropping system would provide lor 315 feed units for sale and seed, but it would not be necessary to buy asmuch roughage as in the original system. The addi - tional feed units produced in the alternative cropping system would pro - vide for some additional livestock, which would be hogs. The returns are figured with this in mind. i Returns.— The method of figuring the returns above variable expense is the same as that used in Table 5. The returns for the original system and three alternatives are given below. ,' Original cropping system .........-.. .j. : $ 975 Alternatives: &#132; 1. Same as original cropping system except that feed grain sold in original system is fed to h0g5.......... $1,102 2. Alternative cropping system given in Table 16 and same livestock as in original system. $ 965 3. Same as Alternative 2 except that corn and barley sold '¦• ¦. in Alternative 2 are fed to h0g5......;...:....... $1,033 The returns above the variable expense jto the original organization and Alternative 2, which is the alternative cropping system, are practically the same. However, less land in the alternative system is cultivated and there would probably be some increase in crop ; yields in time because of more legumes used in the system. Alternative 1, where all feed grain is fed to hogs, returns the most above variable expenses, although there are no more conserving practices used in that alternative than in the original plan. Alter - native 3 would return $1,033 without any consideration to the conservation practices that would be adopted in this system. In the long run Alternative 3 would probably pay best. . AREA 193, LIVESTOCK, GENERAL FARMING, AND CASH GRAIN The soils in this area are for the most part loess. The western and northern boundaries are adjacent to.the sand hills and in these sections the soils are not as well suited to crop production as in the eastern and southern: parts of the area. Along the PJatte river the bottom lands and benches are very productive. • ¦'.''..' </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Hogs contribute about one-half of the income from livestock and nearly one-third of the total. Cash grain, of which corn and wheat are the most important, contribute about the same amount as hogs, and dairy and poul - try account for practically all of the remainder. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 9 shows the amounts of land occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. The most noticeable change was the decline in wheat land. There was very little change from 1910 to 1920, but after that the decline was almost continuous. The decrease in the wheat acreage was absorbed by an expansion in that of corn up to 1930, after which the expansion in barley absorbed most of the decrease in wheat. The im - portance of the other crops remained fairly constant during the period. 30 - ' _ "J^ _ «¦ ~ CORN /o ~ " ' ¦ . J»» ' ' ' &#132;'„ ' ' ' ~i ~l I I . I I I , ~ "" "ls '»*' /?Ts /jjo it ? Fio 9— Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to IVI-t, Area 193. Note the proportionately larpe amount of crop land occupied bv corn. Crop yields.—The average crop yields and variation for the period 1910 to 1933 are given in Table 18. The yield of alfalfa is more dependable in Table 18.— Average crop yields and their variation for crops indicated for the period 1910 to I9li—Area 193 Yield per acre, bus. or tons Coefficient of variation 1 Average Range between Average Range between . . (or area counties for area counties Corn 22.40 20.88-25.02 itVli 24.13—35.96 Oats 27.32 26.05-29.93 28.39 25.93-32 05 Barlc" 23.02 22.01-25.77 29.73 28.74—3794 n whcu H-22 13.25-15.-19 26.02 24.09—33 42 *&gt;l 15.25 12.91-16.68 24.11 2J.88-30.64 M(*lia 2^5 2.19— VO4 UAf, 12.93—25.49 1 See footnote. Table 1. ~* </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Farminc Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska this area than any of the other crops listed in Table 18, because most of it is grown on bottom land near the water table. The yield of rye is slightly more dependable than that of other grains and that of barley is less reliable than for other crops,' although the variation among the grain crops is not large. j L Shifts in livestock units.— Figure 10 shows the changes in the number of different kinds-of livestock units from,l9lo to 1934. There was an in - ¦ • :. ¦¦/ • • I .¦•¦•.-¦ ' «»F ' ~' ' : " &#132; -I ""• ¦¦-¦¦.¦ * g .' ' ' ul» ' ..' ' '¦.«*¦.-'-' .' 'iwa' '¦&lt;' '&gt;'*¦ ' ' '»» Fio. 10.—Number o£ livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 193. crease in the number of cattle other than those kept for milk from 1912 to 1917, after which the number remained fairly constant until 1925. From 1925 to 1927 the number decreased, but after that increased up to the end of the period. The number of milk cows fluctuated in about the same man - ner as did the other cattle. The number of hogs was greatest during the period 1922 to 1925. After that high points in die numbers were reached about every three years. The number of horses increased from 1910 to 1918, after which there was a continuous decrease. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes are listed in Table 19. The most common size of farm rep - resented in the subarea where-the sample was taken was 160 acres, 30 per cent of all farms being approximately 160 acres in size. Only 75 per cent of the farms were of the sizes indicated in Table 18, the remainder being be-, low 160 acres, above 480 acres, or of other uncommon sizes. The farm organizations in Table 16 represent the most common organi - zations on the farms of different sizes; for example, 35 per cent of the 160, the 240, the 320, and the 400-acre farms, and'so per cent of the 480 had the organizations indicated. . ; The acreage of corn increased with the size of the farm but the acreage of other crops did not change much after the farms reached 320 acres in size. There was no definite relationship between the number of cattle or hogs per farm and the size of the farms. j -. : </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 19.— Organizations of most typical farms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 193 * Acres per farm 160 1 2-10 1 320 ) 400 ,' 480 P.ct. P.ct. P. ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cem of all larms represented 30 12 18 8 7 Per cent of specified size represented 35 35 35 35 50 Crops Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Feed crops Co™ 60 70 100 100 NO °a" 20 15 25 15 20 Barl T 2 2 Tame hay ]0 12 20 15 15 Wild hay 8 10 15 20 15 Wheat 15 20 25 15 20 R &gt;c ... 10 Other crop« 1 5 3 5 10 10 Pa«urc .55 100 110 200 230 Other land S 8 20 25 20 Livestock \ n . No. No. No. No. Horses ft 8 8 10 11 Cows 4 7 9 6 8 Cows milked (•)) (5) (6) (6) (6) Other cattle 4 7 10 JO 9 Sows 4 7 5 4 6 Poultry 101) 100 120 100 125 1 .Mostly lorghumt. Table 20 gives the cropping system for the typical 160-acre farm in the subarea selected and an alternative system which has more conservation practices than are in the original system. In the original system, 2,641 feed units were produced from crops, not including pasture, and of this amount 2,081 were trom grain crops and 560 from roughage. The pasture produced 162, making a total of 2.803 for the farm. In the alternative system there would be 2,697 produced from crops not including pasture. Of this amount 1,843 would be from grain and 802 from roughage. The pasture, including the sweet clover, would produce 237, making a total for the farm of 2,882, an increase of 79 over the original system. The change in the kind of feed units would permit some change in the livestock set-up. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 21. The disposal of farm grown feed in the original cropping system to livestock amounted to 1,580 feed units not including pasture. There would be 1,061 feed units fot sale and seed, nearly all of which would be corn and wheat. Some rough - age would have to be purchased to meet the livestock production standard used in figuring the income. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska ' Table 20.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre farm . in a selected subarea in Area 193 ' . . Original cropping system ' Alternative cropping system Crop * : : ; . .-'. Acres I Yield I Production ' Acres I Yield I Production ¦¦'¦,:. .Bw.br Feed ; Bu.or feed T. units 1 ! T. units 1 Soil-Depleting . I ¦ Com ....... 60 25.6 1,536 1.536 !52 25.6 1,331 1,331 Oats ....... 20 27.9 588 276 i 9 27.9 251 118 Barley; 2 24.7 49 39 &gt;10 24.7 247 195 Sorghum ... 5 2 10 55 1 4 2.2 8.8 49 Wheat 15 15.3 230 230 jl3 153 199 199 Soil-Conserving ¦ '¦ . Alfalfa ..... 10 2.4 24 ; 495 f; 15 2.4 36 743 Sweet clover 2. .. .. .. ..4 .. ..; 52 Total for culttc- I . vated crops... 112 ... .. ; 2,631 (107 .. .. 2,687 Neutral - : .-. ¦ ; . Wild hay.... i 8 0.8 6.4 10 I 8 0.8 6.4 10 Total for all . . .. '¦!¦•• crops3 ....... 120 .. ... 2,641 ]115. .. .. 2,697 Permanent '¦'.'¦¦¦ ; ; ;•¦ : .. pasture 1.. 35 , ¦'.': :. 162 r4O .. .. 185 Other land... 5 .. ¦.¦.-..'. ¦"':.' . ! 5 .. Total for farm ... 160 .. .. 2,803 ' ... .. 2,882 I For explanation of feed unit sec footnote, page 3. . ; '.-¦ 3 Pasture. . , . '¦ 9 Docs not include pasture nor straw. In the alternative cropping. system there would be 1,065 feed units for sale and seed, consisting of corn, wheat, and alfalfa, and there would be more roughage than was needed to meet livestock requirements. This with the excess grain would provide for an expansion in livestock. Beef cattle would provide the best outlet for this feed surplus, because of insufficient pasture to carry livestock during the summer. . \ Table 21.— The disposal of jeed to livestock in the original cropping ¦ system shown in Table 20 • Feed units Livestock . Number —— j ; ¦. Farm grown | Purchased | Total Horses .............:.. 6 497 497 Cows 4 264 .¦ ...¦ 264 Other catlle. 4 179 .. 179 Sows :.:........ 4 119 6 125 Other h0g5..... 6,0001b5. 420 24 444 Poultry &#132; :...,.. ' 100, ¦ : 101 20 121 Total, not including ¦¦ pa5tdre............... ... 1,580 50 1,630 Returns.— The method of figuring the returns above the variable ex - penses is the same as that used in Table 5. The returns for the original system and three alternatives are given below, j </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Original cropping system $1,310 Alternatives: 1. Same as original cropping system except all feed grain sold in original system is fed to hogs Sl&gt;4BB 2. Alternative cropping system given in Table 20 and same livestock as in original system $1,263 3. Same as Alternative 2 except that feed grain and part of hay sold in Alternative 2 are fed to beef cattle §1.398 The returns above the variable expenses in the original system are a little greater than in Alternative 2, in which the livestock is the same as in the original. When the surplus feed grain is fed to hogs in the original system the returns are greatest, although no more conservation practices are in - volved. While the returns in Alternative 3 do not quite equal those in Al - ternative 1, it has some desirable features. Some poor crop land has been put into permanent pasture and more legume crops are grown, which should result in increased yields for the land devoted to crops. No credit has been allowed for the manure from the additional cattle fed. If allowed .'t the rate of one dollar per ton the returns would exceed those of Alter - native 1. AREA 187, LIVESTOCK, WILD HAY, AND CASH GRAIN The soil in this area varies from dune sand in the western part to high - producing but not extensive loess soils in the eastern. Only a small percent - age of the soil could be classed as high-grade land. Wild hay constitutes the principal source of income in the western part of the area, while the im - portance of cattle and hogs is more pronounced in the eastern and southern parts. Some income is obtained from the sale of grains, chiefly oats and barley. Shifts in crop acreages. —Figure 11 shows the change from 1910 to 1934 in the proportion of crop land occupied by crops indicated. Approximately one-half the crop land is devoted to the production of wild hay. After 1920, wheat had very little place in the cropping system. On the whole, the acre - age devoted to corn has decreased during the period, most of the decrease hiving been absorbed by an expansion of rye and barley. The importance of oats remained fairly uniform throughout the period. Crop yields.—The average crop yields and their variation for the 24 - -year period 1910 to 1933, are given in Table 22. The yield of alfalfa and rye in this area is more dependable than that of the other crops, although in at least one county the yield of wheat is nearly as dependable. In general the dependability of yields in this area is a little greater than in the south, al - though the yields may not be as high. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska « ¦—- : — —r— — :— •. —- :— /0 . CPRM • — 0 I t II I II I II II I I I I I I II I -1 I 13/0 ' /US ' litO &lt;US \ /MO /f3* Fig. 11. —Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 187. Note the proportionately large amount of crop land occupied by wild hay. Table 22.—Average crop yields and their variation for crops indicated for the period 1910 to 1933—Area 187 ~. Yield per acre, bus. or tons : Coefficient of variation 1 "P Average Range between Average Range between ¦ ¦• for area counties ',' for area counties Corn ........... 23.11 . 18.22—26.14 23.72 19.19—40.61 Oats .......... ; 23.08 22.29—23.73 T 28.29 25.10—37.90 Barley 21.34 20.95—21.51 f 23.38 22.33—32.48 Wheat ......... 12.25 11.28—13.15 | 21.60 - 20.58—34.14 Rye 11.58. .10.99—11.92 ¦" 1 20.75 19.24—30.91 Alfalfa ......... 2.14 : 1.99—2.29 ! 20.00 17.86—30.19 Wild hay........ 0.83 0.78—0.90 j 23.99 23.84—32.37 . 'See footnote* Table 1. •¦' j .: Shifts in the number of livestock units.—Figure 12 shows changes in the number of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. The most numerous livestock was cattle, mostly cattle other than milk cows. The number of cattle in - creased from 1910 to 1918, after which time there was a general decrease until 1927. From 1927 to 1934 the number again increased. The number of 000 i : ~* : ; '¦ ! " ' a&gt; ' ; _ ¦.•¦¦¦ ¦ . mB - . ¦ «l —~ i .' . i i t ¦ ¦ i i i i i i -i i i i i i i i 110 »15 XW&gt; • W» j • ¦¦ ¦ 1J» »» Fig. 12.—Number of livestock units for the. period (1910 to 1934, Area 187. ; </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 milk cows was greatest when the number of all cattle was greatest. While the number of hogs varied from time to time they are of minor importance in this area. The number of horses increased from 1910 to 1920 and declin - ed slowly thereafter. Sheep numbers in the area were small. Organization of typical farms.— The organizations of typical farms of different sizes are listed in Table 23. The most common sizes of farms were those of 160 and 320 acres, each representing 20 per cent of all farms. Eighty per cent of all farms were represented by the sizes indicated in Table 23, twenty per cent being under 160 acres, over 800, or of other uncommon sizes. The organizations in Table 23 indicate the most common organiza - tions found. For example, 25 per cent of the 160-acre farms, 40 per cent of the 240, and 30 per cent of the 320 had the organization as given. Table 23. — Organizations of most typical farms of different size in a selected subarea in Area 187 Acres per farm *"" 160 ' 240 ! 320 | 480 | 6W | 800~ P.ct. P.ci. P.d. P.ct. P.ct. P.d. Per cent of all farms represented 21) II) 20 10 10 10 Per cent ot specified size represented 25 10 30 -)0 50 35 Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Feed crops Corn ''II 'ill 30 (50 20 60 Oats ID |S 15 20 10 20 T.imc ha\ ¦ 10 SO Wild hay 10 &gt;&gt;il ]&gt;m 300 W0 ISO Wheat Rj-c 5 Idle or failure 5 5 5 5 5 Pasture mi &lt;S M 80 185 215 Other laml 5 10 15 15 20 20 Livestock .Vo. Xo. Xo. No. No. No. Horses f, 7 X &lt;&gt; 10 H Cou-s v 15 X H 12 25 Cows milked- (f.) i.H) (7) (6) (8) (7) Other cattle 7 2u d 8 12 20 Sows i 5 2 -t 3 Poultry 50 75 CO SO 110 100 1 l..irgc part was alfalfa. ¦ Mostly o( bctf brccdins There was no definite relationship between the size of the farm and the acreage devoted to any crop except wild hay. As the farm increased in size the acreage of wild hay increased. There was no consistent relationship between the number of livestock and the size of the farm except for work horses, which increased in number as the size of the farms increased. The livestock organization for income purposes was built around the cattle enter - prise. The cows that were milked were mainly of beef breeding. There was no relationship between the number of sows and the acreage of corn. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska Table 24 gives the cropping system for the, typical 320-acre farm in the area and an alternative which it is believed will aid in the conservation of agricultural resources in the area. There were 2,816 feed units produced from the original cropping system. Of this amount 829 were from grain, 1,710 from forage, and 277 from pasture. j., ' Table 24.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 320-acre jarm ; in a selected subarea in ArealB7 ' Original cropping system " ; Alternative cropping system tops Acres | Yield | Production Acres | Yield ) Production ,;¦¦¦ Bu.or Fcedl . Bu.or Feed Soil-Derjletinc T. units 1 . . .T. units 1 Corn .. 30 22.1 633 663 25 . 22.1 553 553 Oats , 15 23.6 354 166; 17 23.6 16 78 8ar1ey:......: .. ...... '¦•.. •.-¦-• i 6 u-1 M5 115 Crop failure.. 5 .: '..•¦¦ '¦'•] ;' ¦••• .'''¦.¦' " Soil-Conserving ¦ , ' , -&gt; a 174 Sweet clover 2 .. ¦'¦¦ : :. ¦ t •• i \ •-.' •• li Rjt.2 .:.... 5 ¦..;.; . ¦.;.-.. 65 ; 6 .. .. 78 Total for cultit ) o«i vWEDCRors.:. 55 ¦...,-.. .. ¦ 8911 53 .... 961 ¦NWu'hay."--- m : °-6 'H 1,710 j 190 0.6 114' 1,710 TOTALFORALL ! &gt;' . , cr0p53...;... 2-J5 .. &#132; 2,604 j 243.: .. .. 2,671 ¦ PC^r:./ 60 :: ¦..". -.. " 212J. 62 .. ... 218 t^o^;; 310 :: :: w.£ :: :: . &gt; For cxpUlution of feed unit sec footnote, page 3. . , ¦ 3 Pajturc. . .•¦:¦).¦.¦ 3Docs not include straw nor corn stalks. ... I -. The alternative cropping system, which involves a reduction in the acre - age of corn and oats, the addition of barley and alfalfa to the cropping sys - tem, and increase in the acreage of tame pasture, would produce 2,889 feed units. Of this amount 746 would be from grain, 1,834 from roughage, and 309 from pasture. The increase of 73 feed units would result from the intro - duction of barley and alfalfa and an increase in the acreage of tame pasture. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 25. The livestock in the original cropping system provides for consumption of 1,665-farm - arown feed units, not including the pasture, with 874 feed units for sale, all wild hay. Wild hay is substituted for the shortage of pasture to provide for the livestock. ...„«. i j • c i The alternative cropping system would provide 915 teed units tor sale, all of which would be wild hay. There would not be quite enough pasture in this system to provide adequately for the livestock and wild hay has been used for the pasture shortage. </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 25.—The disposal of feed to livestock^ in the original cropping system shown in Table 24 . . , Feed units Livestock Number : , Farm grown | Purchased Total "orscs 8 660~ ~ 660~ Cows 7 «I .: 421 Other cattle 7 255 255 Sow, 2 59 3 62 Other hogs 3.000 lbs. 210 12 222 Poultry f,O 60 12 72 Total, not including MST™E 1,665 27 1,692 Returns.—The method of figuring the returns above variable expenses is the same as that used in Table 5. The returns above variable expenses for the original and alternative systems are given below. Original system 5952 ' Alternative cropping system with same livestock as in original plan 5951 The returns above variable expenses in the original and alternative crop - ping systems, with no change in livestock, are practically the same. If the alternative system, with a larger acreage of legumes, would result in higher yields, as it probably would, the returns in the course of time would be larger in this system. There appears to be no livestock adjustment which can be made in either of these systems to increase the returns. No grain is sold in either system I he only way to increase the hog production would be to reduce the num - ber of cattle and feed the grain thus released to hogs. If the number of cat - tie in the original system were reduced to the carrying capacity of the pas - ture and the gram thus released fed to hogs, the returns above variable ex - penses would be about $100 less. If rhe same were done in the alternative system the returns would be about §90 less. AREA 188-B, CASH GRAIN AND LIVESTOCK This area is a part of the high-plains area. In some parts the soil is of a sandy character and not well suited to cultivation. In other parts it is a medium-tortured clay loam or silt, which is well adapted to the production of wheat. Most of the income in this area is from the sale of grain, about 60 per cent commg from this source. Hogs contribute more than any other kind of livestock and account for about 20 per cent of the total fJJSo l c?™T ses-~F,T re " shows the relatlve acrea s«in cr°F trom 1910 to 1934. In general the importance of wheat increased, and there were decreases in 1917, 1923, 1932, and 1933. The decrease in 1917 was absorbed by an increase in the acreage in "other crops", while in 1923, </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska 1932, and 1933 it was absorbed by an increase in corn. Oats decreased in importance during the period and barley, increased except for 1934. Wild hay decreased in importance because of the large amount of prairie land broken for crops. ." ' . ,gl ' ' ' '/&gt;)/' ¦ ' '/.V ',' '»V' ' .' '/»U' ' '/»'? Fie. ]3.—Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 188-B. Wheat occupied a large proportion o£ the crop land, which in general increased during the period. Crop yields.—The most dependable crop from the standpoint of yields in Area 188-B was alfalfa. Only a small acreage of alfalfa was planted, for the most part on the bottom lands. There was very little difference in the dependability of the yield of the grain crops. The increase in the proportion ot crop land occupied by wheat was due more to breaking up of new land than to shifting to wheat from other crops. Table 26.—Average yield and variation for crops indicated for the period - 1910 tol933—Area 188-B Yield per. acre, bus. or tons Coefficient of variation 1 Cro P '.'.¦: Average Rangebetween Average Range between . for area counties . for area counties CoTn ~~ 20.28 18.06—21.38 28.13 26.97—37.90 Oats "... .. 26.85 22.-J3—29.33 29.78 28.76—37.81 Barley" .. 23.84 21.15—26.25 30.75 27.52—41.86 Wheat ......... H.BO 12.77—16.93 31.81 2932—3656 R ye 15.10 12.52—15.70 29.43 25.16—35.38 Alfalfa "¦'¦'¦"¦"¦¦'¦'¦¦ 2.35 1.82-2.69 19.11 13.09-35.91 'Sec footnote, Table 1. : , | </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Shifts in the number of livestock units.— Figure 14 shows the changes in the number of livestock units. Cattle other than those kept for milk in - creased in number from 1912 to 1917. The number declined from 1917 to 1921, and since then there has been little change. The number of milk cows changed in much the same manner as did the number of other cattle, while hogs increased during the period and the number of horses decreased after 1917. Sheep were not important as compared to other livestock. 000 "S?F — , — —nacimi— — "' : ; r l I ;— -—T—, ..11... W° HI) i«to —jrir —' ' ' ' 1 1 1 ' Fie;. M—Xumlwr &#132;t liu-siink unu s for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 188-B The scale ..t this hjiurc &gt;s rive times that of previous figures on livestock and consequently can - not be c&lt;unp.iral directly vvilh them. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes .ire given in Table 27. The most common size of farm in the subarca where the sample was taken was 320 acres, 20 per cent of all the Tabu 27.—Organizations of most typical jams o) different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 188-B l lcm I Acres per farm i K&gt;o ' i2O ) 480 ) 6-)0 ; 800 „ . p- ci. P. a. P. ct. p ct P ci Per cent &#132;f .ill (jrim r&lt;,.r. sou,-,l |' 7,) H [g %' Per cent of vpccihci] M/r rc|iriscntnl W J5 35 en Kc«l r&lt;n '"" ACT" Ams Acr" Aet" J; orn ¦"' f.H 11)1) 51) 2~&gt;o 0315 2(1 2H 25 I?." 1 "* . , I' U) 30 ,'r c h;i! &gt; i« 5 15 10 , "' . „ 5" l«0 160 320 390 Summer fjllovv 30 w 5() „ F-"'urc 10 20 20 35 oTJ\ nd \l it '» '* « . UP X's "*. - Cows 4 4 5 54 Cows milked- (2) / 4j (}) &#132;, &#132;, Other cattle j V 5 ] V Sows 2 5 5 3 8 Poultr V 60 100 [QQ 100 m ' Allalb. Sudan, and millet. ' Moldy b«f cmlc. </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska farms being of approximately 320 acres in size. Sixty-five per cent of all the farms were of the sizes indicated in Table 27. The remainder of the farms were smaller than 160 acres, larger than 800, or of uncommon size. Fifty per cent of all the 160-acre farms had the organization indicated. Likewise 35 per cent of the 320, 40 per cent of the 480, 35 per cent of the 640, and 50 per cent of the 800 had the organizations listed. In general, as farms increased in size there was an increase in the acreage of corn and wheat. On the farms under 320 acres there was very little land in summer fallow and crop failure, but on farms over 320 acres about 10 per cent of the farm was in fallow and failure. On all sizes listed in Table 27 the cows milked were mosdy of beef breeds. The change in the number of hogs was similar to the change in the acreage of corn.' The number of horses increased as the size of the farm increased. , . Table 28.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 320-acre \arm in a selected subarea in Area 188-B Original cropping system Alternative cropping system Acres j yield j Production Acres | Yield | Production Ba.ar Feed . Bii.or Feed Soil-Depleting • 7*. nnittl T. units 1 Corn ....... 60 19.9 1,194 1,194 50' 19.9 995 995 Oats ...1..' .. - ;. 10. 26.2 262 123 Barley- ...... .20 : 26.6 532 420 20 26.6 532 420 Sorghum ... .. :.. .. '¦¦-... 5 1.5 . 7.5 40 Whcaf Y... ¦ 160 ; 16 2,560 2,560 130 16.0 2,080 2,080 Soil-Conserving i "'¦.". Tame hay... '10 0.9 9 135 15 0.9 13.5 202 Rye2 .. .. .. v. 5 .. .. 38 Fallow ....: 10 ../;.,.. 10 ... Total for culti- . .. ... vatedcrops &#132; 260 .. .. .4,309 250 .. .. 3,898 Neutral ...... ! % Permanent '¦ ". ... pasture 50 ' . :. 150 65 .. .. 195 Other land.:. 10 .. .: '.; 10 .; Total for farm3. . 320 .. .. •),459 320 .. .. 4,093 1 For explanation of feed unit tee footnote,-pace 3. - . ¦¦ 'Paiturc. ¦¦¦'-']' "¦:¦.'¦'¦¦¦¦'¦:¦. * Do« not include straw nnr pasture. ' Table 28 gives the crop system for a typical 320-acre farm in the area and an alternative that has more conservation features in it than the original. The. total feed units produced in the original cropping system was 4,459, and of this amount 4,174 were from grain crops, 135 from roughage, and 150 from pasture. 'The alternative cropping system calls for a reduction in the acreage of corn and wheat, an increase in that of barley and tame hay, and the addition of oats, sorghum, and rye. The total production of feed units would be 4,093, of which 3,618 would be from grain crops, 242 from </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 forage, and 233 from pasture. The decrease in total feed units produced in the alternative system is the result of shifting from corn and wheat to oats and pasture, which are both less productive from the standpoint of feed units in this area. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 29. The livestock in the original cropping system would consume 1,664 farm-grown feed units, not including pasture. There would be 2,645 feed units for sale, most of which would be wheat. Some hay would have to be purchased to meet the needs of the livestock, according to the standards of production used. Table 29.— Disposal of feed to livestock in the original cropping system, shown in Table 27 Feed units Livestock Number : i Farm grown | Purchased ] Total Horses 7 -K5B Cows 4 282 .. 282 Other cattle 4 HO 140 S01" 5 H8 8 156 Other hogs 7,500 lbs. 525 30 555 Poultry 100 101 20 121 Totals, vot ivcudiv,. p.mti-«e \M^ 58 1,722- The alternative cropping system would provide 2,196 feed units for sale, ntarly all of which would be wheat. Because fewer feed units are produced, there is not the possibility of as great returns as in the original system. How - ever, the alternative system provides for greater conservation of the soil and because of this might prove just as economical in time. Returns.—The method of figuring returns above variable expense is the same as that used in Table 5. The returns for the original system and three alternatives are given below. Original system $2,440 Alternatives: 1. Same as original except all feed grain sold in original system is fed to hogs $7 57Q 2. Alternative cropping system as given in table with - same livestock as in original system 52,109 3. Same as Alternative 2 except feed grain sold in Alternative 2 is fed to hogs $2 362 The returns to the original organization above variable expense'amount to 52,440, of which 51,827 were from crops and $613 from livestock Alter - native 1 gives the greatest return, although it includes no more conserva - tion practices than are in the original system. Alternative 2 gives the least return. Alternative 3, which involves conservation practices and an expan - sion in livestock, returns about $200 less than the original, which has less conservation practice in it. There would be an increase in yield per acre in the alternative cropping system because of an increase in the acreage of </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska tame hay and because some of the poorest crop land would be retired from cultivation. ..;¦¦¦'., . AREA 184, CASH GRAIN, LIVESTOCK, POTATOES Certain parts of this area, particularly the table land in Box Butte and •Dawes counties, consist of comparatively deep, heavy soils suited to culti - vation, but there are some shallow, sandy soils which are not suited to cul - tivation. The rough Jand is best adapted to grazing. ¦'[."...,¦ The income is from the sale of wheat, potatoes, cattle, and hogs. That fiom livestock and livestock products accounts for about 33iper cent of the income, and grains, of which wheat is the most important, for nearly all of the remainder. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 15 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. In general there was an increase in the proportion of crop land devoted to corn and wheat, lan increase in barley from 1925 to 1930, and a decrease in barley from 1931 to 1934. There was a general decrease in oats, rye, alfalfa, and wild hay. In general, the shift in this area has been toward corn and wheat. ''• /\ y 111 &lt;o ==A\ .-yYv^ril ; ¦ 1 111 /»- ¦ CORN - ollllll||||||| | | j | || ! ! t t '»/O HIS /MO . /M5" _/930 . /93f Fig. 15.—Percentage of ciop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 184. Note the general increase in the importance o£ wheat. Crop yields.—The average crop yields, and variation for the 24-year period 1910 to 1933, are given in Table 30. The yield of alfalfa in this area is more reliable than that of any other crop. It should be pointed out, how - ever, that in this area alfalfa is grown in the localities best suited to its production, while the other crops ate grown under a wider range of con - ditions.. In spite of the low coefficient of variation in the yield of alfalfa, </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 30.— Average crop yields and their variation for crops indicated /or the period 1910 to 1933—Area 184 Yield per acre in bus. or tons Coefficient of variation 1 Crop Average Range between Average Range between for area counties for area counties Corn 20.04 19.34—22.46 23.62 21.69—27.61 Oats 27.25 24.70—33.50 31.42 20.93—38.60' Barley 22.52 21.63—29.07 36.21 31.03—38.50 Wheat 15.03 13.92—16.51 27.51 21.32—32.43 Rye 14.15 13.58—14.95 23.81 21.14—31.35 Alfalfa 2.06 1.92— 2.60 17.96 13.69—41.48 1 See foomolr. Table 1. the acreage decreased in importance during the period. On the other hand corn, with a higher coefficient, increased in relative acreage. Shifts in number of livestock units. —Figure 16 shows the shift in the: number of livestock units. The number of cattle other than those kept for milk increased rapidly from 1911 to 1918. It decreased from 1918 to 1923, after which the number did not vary greatly. The number of milk cows remained fairly constant throughout the period. There was an increase in the number of hogs and a decrease in the number of horses except for the first few years of the period. The number of sheep increased noticeably after 1927. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of typical farms of different sizes .ire listed in Table 31. The agriculture in this area is so variable that the organization statements in Table 31 are representative 000 wm iK| ¦ °i^—a? '¦ ' ' ' '-^-^r— „;. ' ¦ ;,» Fig. 16.—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 184. The num - ber of sheep increased during the latter part of the period. The scale for this figure - is the same as that of Figure 14. </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska Table 31.—Organizations of most typical farms of different sizes in a selected subarea— Area 184 j Item Acres per farm ! 160 | 320 | 480 | I 640 | 960 P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent of all farms represented... 10 14- 8 jlO 6 Per cent of specified size represented 55 20 40 .! 40 30 Crops ¦ Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Feed crops ¦ ¦¦¦;. ¦¦ . ¦ . ;.' . | Corn. 55 50 80 j 100 80 Oats 15 20 40 !30 30 Barley : 15 15 15 1 30 .40 Tame hay........... .'. 10 10 25. 1=25 30 Wild hay.....;......,:.,... 10 10 45 !20 55 Wheat ;.: &#132;...: 20 100 60 ! 50 40 Potatoes : ...;............ 2 3 5 ! 5 5 Pasture and other land.. 33 112 210 | 380 680 Livestock /'¦¦. : No. No. No. \ No. No. Horses ...:...... .5 6 8 j 10 11 Cows ................:. i 5 1 ' 9 15 Cows milked (3) (5) (6) j (6) (5) Other cattle... :...:..... 3 5 9 j 12 13 50w5,;..... ........... 5 ¦ 5; 20 1 25 9 Poultry ............;.. -."-.. 50 75 120 I 30 125 of only small subareas and should not be considered typical of the area. A large amount of land is devoted to'grazing and it is not represented in the organization statements. The most noticeable change in the farm state - ments in Table 31 is that the amount of land for grazing increased with the size of the farm, while there was not a marked change in the amount of land devoted to the various crops indicated. The most important changes in livestock as farms increased in size were in the number of cows and sows. Table 32 gives the cropping system for a typical 320-acre farm in the area and an alternative that has more conservation features than the original. The- total feed units produced in the original cropping system were 3,892. Of this amount 3,362 were from grain crops,; 53 from potatoes, 270 from forage, and 207 from pasture. The alternative cropping system calls for a reduction in the acreage of corn, oats, and wheat and increases in barley, potatoes, tame hay, and permanent pasture. The alternative cropping sys - tem, in which eight acres of the poorest land now in crops would be put into permanent pasture, would produce a total of 3,859 feed units. Of this amount 3,193 would be from grain crops, 89 from potatoes, 353 from forage crops, and 224 from pasture. There would be a reduction of 33 feed units from the original cropping system without any consideration of possible increases in yield of crops. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 33. The live - stock in the original system would consume 1,688 farm-grown feed units, not including pasture. The pasture and roughage are insufficient to meet the requirements for the production standards used so it is assumed that </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 Table 32.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 320-acre jarm in a selected subarea in Area 184 Original cropping system Alternative cropping system '"' Acres Yield | Production Acres | Yield | Production Bu. or Feed Bu.or Feed Soil-Depleting T. nails 1 T. units 1 Corn 50 20.1 1.005 1,005 45 20.1 904 904 Oats 20 30.1 602 2KJ 15 30.1 452 283 Barley 15 27 J 410 324 20 27.3 546 431 Wheat 100 17.5 1.750 1,750 90 17.5 1,575 1,575 Potatoes i 85.0 255 53 5 85.0 425 89 Soil-Conserving Tame hay 10 O.ft 8 165 15 0.8 12 248 Total for culti - wtidcrops I'JH 3,580 190 .. .. 3,530 Ncutr.il Wild hay 1(1 (1.7 7 105 10 0.7 7 105 Total for all crops 2(18 3,fiSs 200 . .. 3,635 Permanent pasture 100 207 108 .. .. 22-1 Other land 12 12 Total for farm 320 3.802 320 .. . . 3,859 1 For explanation of feed unit sec footnote, pj^c 3. seme hay is purchased. There would be 1,997 feed units for sale and seed, practically all for sale being wheat. Somewhat the same situation exists in the alternative system in regard to pasture and hay except to a lesser degree. If some of the land turned to permanent pasture were used for sweet-clover pasture, the pasture require - ments could be more nearly met. In this system there would be 1,947 feed units for sale and seed, nearly all for sale being wheat. Table 33.— Disposal of feed to livestock in the original cropping system shown in Table 32 Feed units Livestock Number —"" . Farm grown I Purchased Total Horses 6 407 &#132; 407 Cows 5 321 . . J2l Other cattle 5 186 .. 186 Sows 5 148 8 156 Other hogs 7,500 lbs. 525 30 555 Poultry 100 101 21 122 Total, not inxludinc pasture — 1,688 59 1,747 </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska • -r &lt;i*| lrnS"~T'le Same met^od °* figuring returns was used as illustrated in Table 5. The returns above variable expenses for the original system and three alternatives are given below. .Original system &#132;......:..... , $2,223 Alternatives: ¦ 1. Same as original system except all feed grain sold in original system is fed to h0g5....-. i :...........-.. $2,380 2. Alternative cropping system as given in Table 32, but with same livestock as in the original system $2,115 3. Same as Alternative 2 except all feed grain sold in Alternative 2 is fed to hogs .. ; $236 / The variation in the returns above variable expenses is not great among the different systems. The returns are greatest in Alternative 1, but no more conservation practices are included than are how being used. With such a small difference between the original and Alternative 2, it would seem that the greater conservation practices involved in the latter system would pay in higher yields in time. Approximately the same situation prevails between Alternatives 1 and 3. , . •:• ¦-.'¦ . AREA 145, SUGAR BEETS, POTATOES, AND LIVESTOCK A large part of this area consists of bottom lands and benches adjacent to the north branch.of the Platte river and its.tributaries. It is an irrigated area for the most part, and for this reason the yields of crops are high. The sale of sugar beets and potatoes accounts for most of the income in the irrigated sections. They, with other crops, provide about 90 per cent o£ the total income; The sale of cattle and sheep fattened in the area ac - counts for nearly all of the remainder. The by-products of the sugar-beet industry stimulate the fattening of cattle and sheep to the extent that some feed grain is shipped into the area. ; Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 17 shows the changes in the relative amounts of crop land occupied by crops for the period 1910 to 1934. There was an increase in the relative amount of land devoted to grain production, the increase being in the acreages of corn and barley. There was a decrease in that of wheat and oats. The relative acreage of alfalfa and wild hay de - creased during the latter part of the period. Other crops include both sugar beets and potatoes. The number of acres in sugar beets and potatoes is not available for the early part of the period. The proportion of crop land oc - cupied by these crops is small when compared to that occupied by other crops. The acreage designated as other crops increased up to 1928 and de - creased thereafter. • -. ; Crop yields.— Table 34 gives the average yields and variation for crops in Area 145 for the period 1910 to 1933. The yields of crops in this area are more dependable than in other parts of the state because of irrigation. The </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 ~ ' —L^/*- '^l_k^ . —LJ— — CORN ». —'—'—'—'— ~—: —: — "" »" «« /mo —/ ? F,c. 17.—Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area US. N,, lc the proportionately large amount of crop land occupied by oilier crops and alfalta. Other crops consisted mostly of sugar beets and potatoes. yield of oats, barley, and alfalfa are fairly high and reliable. The yield of corn is below that in the eastern part of the state because of the cooler weather and shorter growing season. Table 34.— Average crop yields and their variation jor crops indicated for the period 1910 to 1911—Area 145 CroP . 'Yield in bus. or tons | Coefficient of variation l 9° rn 273 nfo9 9"f 16.02 Barlcy H2.sr i? 3.1 Wheat 22.20 1937 sinf i:ai 20-H Alfal/a 3.01 H45 Sugar beets (1924-l'J3si 12.77 U 51 Poatoes (1910-1931) 15^62 23^89 1 See footnote, Table 1. ' —— Shifts in the number of livestock units—Figure 18 shows the changes in the number of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. The number of cattle 600 I " ~ ' ' ¦ , , _—^ „ ffflp~f &lt;TTlt ' ~~~ — ~—' TTT' 11 M 1111. "" J^~"» zr^s —-^—• &#132;j. ' ¦ ,„ Fie. 1R —Numbers of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Arcs 145. The sale of this figure is the same as that of Figures H and 16. </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska other than those kept for milk increased from 1912 to 1919. There was a decrease from 1919 to 1923, after.which there was riot much change until 1932 when the number again increased. The number of milk cows in - creased throughout the period and for the most part the increase was in the dairy breeds. Hogs are not important in the area. The number of horses remained fairly uniform. This is the only area in the state where sheep are particularly important. The number of sheep was less from 1920 to 1929 than before or after that time, except for the first two years of the period. Most of the sheep in this area are shipped in for feeding purposes and consequently appear on relatively few farms. This accounts for the absence ol them in the organization of typical farms. Organization of typical farms.—The organizations of the most typical farms-of different sizes are listed in Table 35. The cattle and sheep ship - ped in for fattening are not included in these organizations. Seventy per cent of the 80-acre farms were classed as sugar-beet farms and 15 per cent as potato farms. Fifty per cent of the 160-acre farms were classed as sugar - beet farms and 12 per cent as potato farms. Fifty-five per cent of the 240 - -acre farms were classed as sugar beet farms and 15 per cent as potato farms. Table 35. — Organizations of most typical farms of different sizes in a selected subarea in Area 145 Acres pa farm , . ~~ 801 16Q2 2408 Hem ¦' —¦¦ - .'.'¦¦:.¦ ' S»S». .Potatoes Sugar,. -p o|a , MS Sugar beets beets beets P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Per cent of specified size ¦...:'• • represented..:.:..... ... V5 15 30 12 30 15 Crops Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Acres Feed crops . : Corn 10 3 15 15 , 40 30 Ons ............. 8.: 2 ¦¦ (| '¦;• 5 ( 2 (20 (10 Barley .. 10 ( 20 ( 20 Tame hay:........ 15 25 40 .40 10 50 Wild hay .. .. .. -.'.".: •• 15 Wheat .:..:.;..... .. ... &#132; ¦¦ .40 Potatoes .......... 5 15 5 20 5 25 Sugar beets. ..20 15 45 15 50 20 Pasture &#132; 5 25 25 80 55 Other land .....:. 22 5 .10 20 5 23 Livestock No. No.' ..- No. No. No. No. Horses :.....:.;... : 4 5 8 7 8 8 Cows 4; 3 5 4 5 9 Cows milked..:.... (3) (3) .(4) (4) (3) (5) Other catt1e,......:.. 5 3 8 3 3 9 Sows 10, 13. 2 . 4 Poultry ........:.... 80 75 ' 100 75 150Y 100 1 Were 25 per cent of alt farms. '. ¦ ¦ '•.'-.'.'-., s Were 22 per cent of all farms. . - ! . 'Were 8 per cent of all farmi. ¦ = ¦-¦•¦.¦ ... </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 There were two typical farm organizations producing sugar beets as a major source of income on all sizes of farms listed—those with a medium acreage and those with a high acreage. Those with but a medium acreage cf beets were the most common organizations on all sizes of farms except the 80-acre ones where the farms with a high acreage of sugar beets were just as common. The farms which emphasized the production of potatoes were about one-fourth as common as those that emphasized the production t f beets. The farms with a high acreage of potatoes grew a smaller acreage of sugar beets than potatoes, but the farms with a high acreage of sugar beets seldom grew any potatoes. There was some tame hay on all farms. The farms with a high acreage of sugar beets had more livestock, except hogs, than the potato farms. Hogs were not especially important in either type. More horses were needed on the sugar-beet farms because a larger acreage of sugar beets than potatoes was grown. Only on the large farms were cattle particularly important, except where feeding was done. Table 36 gives the crop production and alternative on a typical 160-acre farm in the area. The original cropping system produces 3,626 feed units, of which 38 are from pasture, 2,311 from tame hay, 589 from grain crops, and 481 from sugar-beet tops and pulp and from potatoes. The alternative cropping system includes a reduction in the acreage of oats, sugar heels, and tame hay and an increase in corn, barley, and potatoes. There is a decrease in the acreage of soil-depleting crops and an increase in Table 36.— Cropping system and an alternative on a typical 160-acre jarm in a selected subarea in Area 145 Original cropping system | Alternative cropping system Crop : —" j j Acrn | Yiclil | Production Acres Yield | Production Bu. or Feed Bu. or Feed Soil-Depleting T. units ] T. unitsl Corn IS 26.5 5&gt;JB 398 16 26.5 424 424 Oats 20 U.S 8-16 .W8 6 42.3. 254 119 Barley H 44.7 626 495 Sugar beets 4; 12. f» iBO 3H- 26 12.9 335 181 Potatoes i 15').! 7% 167 15 159.3 2,390 501 Wheat 5 20.9 104 104 Soil-Conserving Tame hay -10 2.H 112 2.J11 U 2.8 92 1,840 Rye3 10 .. 50 Total for all crops .... 125 .5,588 125 .. .. 3,714 Neutral Permanent pasture 25 38 25 .38 Other land 10 10 .... Total for farm . 160 i.626 160 3,752 ' For explanation of feed unit see footnote, page 3. a Include] only sugar beet tops and pulp. 1 Pairure. </seg>
         <seg id="p045">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska soil-conserving crops. There would be 3,752 feed units produced in this system, of which 38 would be from pasture, 1,840 from tame hay, 1,038 from grain crops, and 605 from sugar beets and potatoes. There would be an increase of 126 feed units in this system over the original. The disposal of feed to livestock is indicated in Table 37. There would be 2,173 more feed units than that required for livestock in the original system if no consideration is given to pasture. There is insufficient pasture to provide for the livestock and it is assumed that sugar beet tops and pulp and tame hay would be used to meet this deficit. In the alternative system there would be 2,249 more feed units than those required by livestock, not including pasture. The same condition with respect to the shortage of pas - ture exists in the alternative system as in the original but to a lesser degree, and the same assumptions with respect to feed substituted were used. Both systems provide for fattening more cattle than are listed in the organiza - tions in Table 36. Alternatives 1 and 3 in the statement of returns take into account the possibility of fattening enough cattle to exhaust the feed supply. Table 37.— Thedisposal of. feed to Uvestoc\ in the original cropping sys - \ system shown in Table 36 " :.-. •¦.'•¦•¦¦ ; .-. Feed units Livestock Number : :—j —: . ¦ Farm grown ] Purchased | Total Horses .. 8 ~~ " 618 ~ 7~~~ 618 Cows 5 208 ' .. 208 Other cattle 8 336 .. 336 Sows j.; 1 47 2 49 Other hogs 1,500 lbs. 105 6 111 Poultry 100 jlOl 21 122 Total, not including ¦¦. ''. pastdre 1,415 29 1,444 Returns.—The method of figuring returns is the same as that used in Table 5. The returns above variable expense for the original system and three alternatives are given below. Original system ..... $3,593 Alternatives: . ¦ ¦;..-¦¦ 1. Same'as original except feed sold in original system is fed to beef catt1e......:.,...:. ........:......... $3,616 2. Alternative system as given in Table 36 with same livestock as in original system.....:. $3,4&lt;J6 3. Same as Alternative 2 except feed sold in Alternative 2 is fed to beef catt1e...........t $3,517 There is not much difference in the returns among the four illustrations .given above. The cropping system in Alternatives 2 and 3 is a little more soil-conserving in character than the original; system and'Alternative 2. If all the tame pasture were sweet clover there would be some increase in ¦yield in the course of time. The alternative cropping system would be less severe on-the soil. </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Smtion Bulletin 309 OTHER AREAS I There are four areas for which data are not aval able to permit the kind of a study made in the areas previously discussed. The conditions in one or two of these areas are so similar to adjacent ; reas that it is believed recommendations for them would be much the samd as in the adjacent area. Such recommendations will be pointed out as eaci area is discussed. In one or two areas there appears to be no serious pnblem, so far as adjust - ments of farm enterprises and utilization of land Are concerned, and con - sequently very little in the way of alternatives is opejito farmers. In view of these conditions only a brief description of these arois is given. AREA 182-A This area is limited almost exclusively to Boyd county. The agricultural production is somewhat similar to that of 183-A but on a Jess intensive scale. 40 —_Z\^J_ \s^ ' " _ ~ 30 ¦ " ~~ ~~~ " ~ — ' io - "_~_~ "~ f"— '—' —i . "~i i~ i I &#132;",,,. ''° "/S "*&gt; ~I9£S /Mo ' W3+ Fig. 19.— Percentage ol crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area I*2-A. Note the pr.,p&lt;,rtion.iuly large amount of crop land occupied by corn. r i Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 19 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. Although the corn acreage fluctuated from year to year, there was a definite trend during the period, ?m e-, cllnCj'n the Whea' after 1920 ' an increase in wheat- barley&gt; and fye after 1927, and a decline in rye the last two years of the period. There was an expansion in the acreage of alfalfa in the earlier part of the period, a decline in the later part, and a decline in wild hay after 1930. Shifts in number of livestock units.—Figure 20 shows the change in the number of livestock units in the area from 1910 to 1934. The number of cattle other than those kept for milk increased from 1910 to 19?5 and de - creased from 1925 to 1927, after which there was an increase to the end of </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska ¦ ¦ w • •' _^ ' ¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ oMtcimi — ¦ fl r . . i i i - i i i ' ' ¦ ¦ ' ' ' ' ' ' * ' ' ' Via. 20.—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 182-A. The scale of this figure is the same as that of Figures 14, 16, and 18. the period. The number of milk cows fluctuated about the same as that of other cattle, and hogs fluctuated somewhat. The importance of hogs in the farm business is greater than their number indicates. The number of horses declined. Sheep are relatively unimportant in the area. The alternatives as illustrated in Area 183-A would be applicable to some extent. Some reduction in the acreage devoted to grain crops and an increase in that of grasses would probably help to conserve the agricultural resources in the area. ¦ .; \ . . , AREA 18? This area lies betwen Areas 196, 188-B, and 186. The soils are some - what sandy and some of the land is better suited to grazing than to crop production. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 21 shows the relative amounts o£ crop land Occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. Wheat and corn occupy about 80 per cent of the crop land. The amount of land devoted to each of these crops has fluctuated from year to year with no definite trend for either. to-. -..;"-. V town 10 - ... " ... &#132;/&amp;•' ..'•;; u,-' ' ' %io' ' &lt; 'nW ¦&#132;' '&#132;u »^i Ftc. 21.—Percentage of crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 189. Corn and wheat occupied most of the crop land. The harvested acreage of both corn and wheat decreased in 1926. ; </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 The acreage of barley increased somewhat during the last ten years of the period, while that of crops other than wheat and corn decreased. Shifts in number of livestock units.—Figure 22 shows the change in the number of livestock units in the area from 1910 to 1934. The only notice - able changes in the numbers of livestock were an increase in that of cattle and a decrease in that of horses. ¦«m ~~! t 1910 ISIS IVO Wi ~* 13J0 193ST Fir,. 22.—Number nf livestock units for the period 1910 to 193-), Area 189. The scale is the same as that nt Figures 14. Id. IH, and 20. An increase in the acreage of grasses and legumes where they can be grown is desirable in this area. The alternatives illustrated for Area 196 are applicable to the pans of the area where wheat and corn are most import - ant. Where the soil is of a sandy character, the alternatives used for Area 186. which will be discussed later, should be applicable. AREA 143 1 Kis area is in the extreme northwestern part of the slate. About two - ifiircJs oi the soils are classed as low-producing, indicating that they should not be used for crop production. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 23 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. There was an increase in the """till"'!. '¦" i' I'l 111- \\\)&amp;\ i' r ~T~* ¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ II U-\ \\ K CWlo yf. y' " I)\ / 'V r^ \jJUCAT' Is" \1 I \K ¦ ,— j. lII' I I i , ms "« "tf /&gt;» &#132;t iO!j Pcrcc"t:lf c ot cr °P land o«upi«l by crops designated for the period 1910 to im Area Hi. There was some tendency to reduce the acreage of land devoted to the production of hay and increase thar of grain. </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Farming Systems and Alternatives in Nebraska relative importance of corn, wheat, and barley during the period and a de - crease in alfalfa and wild hay. The amount of cultivated crops increased during the period even though some of the land was not particularly well suited to their production. ; Shifts in number o£ livestock units.—Figure 24 shows the changes in the number of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. There was a rapid in - crease in the cattle other than those kept for milk from 1913 to 1919. From 1919 to 1927 there was a decrease. There was practically no change from 1927 to 1931 but an increase from 1931 to 1934. There was no definite trend in other livestock although sheep were more numerous in this area than in several of the other areas of the state. A reduction in grain crops, except rye and barley, and an increase in grasses and sorghums would be desirable. Such changes should maintain coo ( ~~t : : : ; : ; OHM ' - \ ! . ¦ '..'¦ ;¦ ft I .1 I I I I I I I I I i I 1 I 1 I 1 1910 JJU ~ ISTO I*s IJJ» »» Fig. 2-).—Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 143. Cattle are the principal kind of livestock in this area. The scale for this figure is the same as for Figure 22. . • . . the present livestock and help to conserve the agricultural resources of the area. : •"¦¦¦¦,:-..:. AREA 186 . This area includes approximately one-fourth of the state. The soils are sandy ;n character. Only about 8 per cent of the soil is suited to cultiva - tion and only about 4 per cent of the area could be classed as good soils, which are located mostly along streeams. Shifts in crop acreages.—Figure 25 shows the relative amounts of crop land occupied by crops from 1910 to 1934. Wild hay occupied over half of the crop land throughout the period. Corn is the only other crop of much importance from the standpoint of acreage. These two crops occupied over 80 ,per cent of the crop land during the period. There was very little change in the relative importance of the remainder of the crops. Shifts in the number of livestock units.—Figure 26 shows the changes in the number of livestock units from 1910 to 1934. The number of cattle other than those kept for milk increased from 1912 to 1920 at a rather rapid rate. The number decreased in 1921 and increased again in 1924. It decreased from 1924 to 1928, after which it increased at a rapid rate to </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 309 80 — — ¦ ' ~' 40 - '" ' =~" ¦ l- ~i- ..•¦ — ,o : -CORN °l—l—i—l—l i i 1., i i i i i i i i i i i i i i '"0 W* «I IKS 1930 /S3* Fig. 25.—Percentage &lt;it crop land occupied by crops designated for the period 19 LO to 1931, Area 186. Wild hay occupied over two-thirds of the crop land and corn over two-thirds of the cultivated crop land. This is a caltle grazing area. win o I i i~T i i i i i i i i i i i i i i t i i i i i "" »« »» vm vat uu Fie. 26. —Number of livestock units for the period 1910 to 1934, Area 186. Cattle ate the principal kind of livestock in this area. 1934. The number of milk cows and hogs remained fairly constant through - out the period, while that of horses decreased slowly after 1916. Sheep are not important in this area. Because of the sandy nature of the soil and its tendency to blow, it is probably best that only the soils well suited to cultivation be used for crop production. If any change is made, it should be toward a reduction in the acreage of grain crops and an increase in that of hay and pasture, although any change made would likely be small. </seg>
         <seg id="p051"/>
         <seg id="p052"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>