<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association HELD AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JANUARY 21 TO 24, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">OF THE EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING DF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association LU LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 2 i TO 24, i 902 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Office of Secretary Nebraska State Poultry Association, To his excellency, Esra P. Savage, Governor of Nebraska: K»EA* Sir: — In compliance with the law in this case made and proviri - herewith transmit the Annual Report of the Nebraska State Poultry iation. for the year closing January, 1902. Very respectfully Ln VV GAROITTE. Secretary Lincoln, Nkbraska, Dec. i, 1902 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1901-1902. George W. Osterhout T. L. Norval, President, David Citv Seward. Vice President, - Secretary, BLUDDKN Lyman, Lincoln. Lincoln. Treasurer, MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. Ed. H. Eggert, E. B. Day, North Bend Lincoln E. E. Smith, W. A. Irwin, Tecutnseh </seg>
            <seg id="p004">PROCEEDINGS of the EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION of the NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION held at LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 21 to 24, 1902. In pursuance of the requirements of law in this instance provided, the Nebraska State Poultry Associ ; at Lincoln, the Capital of the state, in the I'nion Comm&lt; on Wednesday, January 22. is in the chair. President Harris the Aamx I am glad to see so .imiliar faces here tonight, and also those of a great nian\ It has been a very busy time with me for the last month or so, and I am not capable of making a speech without first writing it, so I hope you will bear "Ladies and Gentlemen, Brother r Fanciers of the Nebraska vjciation: — It is with the greatest pleasure that I welcome you all to 1!. er Annual Poultry Convention of the Nebraska State It has been the custom of this body of poultry fan - ciers to meet in Convention each year, to talk over the things that would be of benefit to each anil every one; to help to further this great industry and to help each and all to better make poultry pay. It is with the greatest pleas - ure that I, at this time can announce to this gathering that the hand of the In - seen Ruler of all things has been very mindful of us as a body and has per - mitted us all to be able to answer to our roll call, although some are not per - mitted to pe here in person, owiug to a large amount of business detaining them at their homes. mr worthy President, a year ago, stood before this body and made the statement that the Poultry Industry was in its infancy and growing fast, and I will assure you to night that such is the fact, and I am able to say without hesitancy that the poultry industry has been pushing forward in the last year with increased ii ;&lt;le. Although it is apparent that there were not as man -*d thi» season as in other seasons be - fore, still the prices paid for poultry have been far greater and the fanciers and farmers have made as much money as ever, or more even, that in previous </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 E thoroughbred ttock arv r the same pri. inon eggs k but it is to my certain destined to never come. Forty j the Twenty yuart Cow was to be the product E; today she exerts no surpris. rumon in all well ' an animal as a pedigreed hog would have been exhibited as a ity. Today, it &gt; ry neighborhood in Nebraska and Kientific breeding can produce. In those da;. were of burden only. Today, they are an jn that one gives to the work of art K or hundreds of dollars. Today, they sell for as n .inds. To - ;ken fleece is a living tt ,it the r has given to thoroughbred breeding, which hns so materially in - ■d his profits as to enable him to erect homes, that for their apart - i are elegant enough for Kings. Why this change.' Why, I say, because he has found that it costs no more to feed, care and bouse a th in it does a mongrel, and then the profits are much more and the satisfaction is far greater. It is a matter of pleasure as well as a matter of dollars and cents, and that is what we are all after. Well, now, how is it about the hen? Very much has been done toward making her fit company for the aristrocracy of the thoroughbred, but not so much seemingly, as has been done for the horse, the cow, the hog, or the sheep, for if you will go with me into the country today, you will se« that nine tenths of all the fowls in the farm yard are of the same old class — "The Dunghill" that they bred in their yards forty years ago. Their owners do not know that they ever had a grandmother. Their p&lt; could not be traced back a year, or more than one season and then it be a question. They roost in the trees, they get their food it can be found and even go hungry and cold. The huckster gath ip and they finally end their days as an offering to the hunger of man. Even then, ■ e despised for their toughness yielding not, even though all the arts of the kitchen were brought to bear in a vain effort to make them toothsome. Such chickens are the i in disgust, Iltry does not pay:" "the poul'. ss is a failure." But poultry pay. Do you ki.ow that if all the eggs laid ■ S, were n a continuous chain that th le the earth more than twenty times? The value of the egg and poultry sold this year, will aggregate $3,000,001 im greater by nearly 0,000 than the value of all the mineral pr in the -timate includ id and si! The average cow weighs 150 times as much as the hen, vet the hen's year's earnings would buy all the cows in the country and the entire tobacco as well. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 pound of it, besides paying fo - the entire wheat crop or the entire she cry in. hi. woman and child in the V . S. J3 She can buy all the oat crop and havi all the n be aides. She can in one year buy, at their MKMcd valuation, New M 1, North Dak. Idaho anil Wyoming, and if givt a chance, can pay off every mortgage in this glorious country of ours. word of this is true. These facts comes from the Secretary of culture. If the farmer will now turn his attention to the improving of his , he will be able to buy more land, have a fat bank account and pro - his family with many luxuries that are now impossible. ilt has been prove ngfaili fowl average 91 eggs in a urn soil weigh an averagi ind a half pounds. It I een proven and time again at several experimental S. that the aughbred will produce from 160 to 200 eggs per year, and weigh from 4 i pounds each. They eat no more, take up ho more room and are just as y and are far more satisfac Go down to our si r the different birds that are represented there and see if you would exchange a flock, if you li ■ females 0: d represt mmon Dunghill hi pare the 1 your common fowl a; re the poultry account of the bre&lt;-' irhbreds to thai ind then decide in your mind, which is the more profitable, the Dunghill, the common liarn yard fowl or the th&lt; bred fowl tl. • in our show room. The pou when con show a fair profit and provide ready worl for the ■ .2nd there breeding of pure bred poultry than thi I. It is centrally located near two good mar'- it all times of the sea - can see the Poultry Palace Car on the railroad, being filled with poultry to ped in ai: .&lt; as the market wa- It is fii - York, Boston. New Orlea Black Hills and the .,■ Camps and there 1 more ct •: ■a ted than this state of ours for the marl poultry and eggs and there is no state in the I'rion better located home of the breeder of fancy poultry than this, as we are in the centf ■ states with grand facilities for shipping North, East, South and West and save express charges to our 1 time and mon&lt; But one says that the Poultr be overdone. My kind hearers, it never will. England is much older in industry than U. S. and today, she imports fowls and eggs from the !'. S. as well as from other countries. I noticed in a report in a late Canada paper, that the Department of Agriculture at Ottowa, Canda, had received returns from the first </seg>
            <seg id="p007">nil brought 14 cents per pound and tl (.65 — 2 each. Whit crni be done it can be done here, ar. keep the best, whether for market or for fancy lireed - 1 matters not just so it is uilt edged. ■et us all at the close A thi nd show return to oar homes determined to make this poultry business a success, and succe&gt;~ out effort - At the close be called upon Judge * President and Members of the Sute Poultry Association.' (few d ' '.reed- Nebraska, and read hing on poultry. T!. v to a Higher Plane. In that I ai ig some thoughts, perhaps, that may be entirely aev nproval." The manuscript was lost Judge Rhoade a lent H.irri We w the report :m\, L. \\ - Mr. President and .V By your permission, will have a full report ii] will not make 1 : lit bu now take the time Association from the iatei a of prominent speakers, we have of past &gt;[) of the Poultry and Stock Associations are a success. .ent H tn us tonight, of the N't Associ Brown ville, Nebraska. We should like to Mr. Lewellin ' Mr. President an '. imation that I have had that I was on the program tonight hut I am surely pleased to have the honor of speaking before you once mure. It has been a good many yean since this organiza - tion was started and it commenced a very small infant. It had been run - ning some years before I became a member of it and the first me - attended was in this city. I saw in the State Journal a little notice that the Nebraska State I waa goin&gt;. in exhibit at a certain ! throughout this nation, whi us all </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 reeding p ; "t&gt;' and being interest* as I 1 - known to all of you and who is an officer I.eming of this city with it ion, and he is still a ijt the exhii ■are with ■ uditorium. I think, it iudge Richards there scoring ihe birds, which was the first time I ever seen birds scored. But that little show being the first one I at, the next season I be^ n or eight In enough to make a start. There were more t each year, but the trouble was, money. We ren ., I joined the I came to attend the Association. We rented a store room each 1 years after that. We paid our fee which was about $25.00 per week for the store room to bold the show in. We offered premiums which were very small but they were paid. We paid our own bills and hotel rs and went home. We had held a poultry show. How different today. The state has recognized the poultry interests. It would not have been worth while t' ne before the Legislature at that time and - hing about poultry, but since that time, the state has recognized the poultry interest and each year, there is appropriated from the treasury &lt;&gt;. state, $1,000.00 to help on the poultry industry. A little money was \ was needed and we were very grateful for the money we received. I am glad to say today that there are over 200 bn -late to my personal knowledge, while at the first poultry show I attended, I believe there were about nine who exhibited. There may have been other breeders in the the state. We have made rapid in the poultry industry, as the President has told you in his address, but there is something in the future and I must say that the recommendation of the Brother from Kansas is surely good. It is an education of the people that we need. Our p&lt;&gt; fanciers are becoming more educated, but you will find many farms upon h there is very little improvement for poul: I am sure t: erestimaie it when I say that the past year was one of the hai Nebraska has ever experienced especially in the western part of the state where corn was a total failure. At one time it was 1 1 1 degrees in the shade and it was so hot. and the winds blew so that neither man nor beast ■ I face it; the corn crop was ruined and the wheat crop saved before was all the fanner had, and today, they are tiding over with great difl, and distress with the poultry. And to call the hen business a small business - it really is not; it is one of the greatest that we have in tli nd comes in a time of emergency and helps the people to remain where they are and go on and raise another crop 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 cnt Harris: K'e have with us the editor of the Poultry Gazette of Topeka, Kansas, uld like a few remarks from hi Mr. Gco. H. Gillis: "I wasn\intending to make a speech. In Topeka, we have the Insane Asylum, and they hold religious meetings evi v afternoon and import a new preacher every time in order to make it more inter' One day the fellow got up and said that he didn't believe he had an to say today at all. and one of the he had better sit down. When I get starte when to stop and I suppose I can fill up a little time. I appreciate being with you tonight. I think you will acknowledge that your show never was a better one and the quality of birds that is showing. I will frankly s;.y that after having some experience in getting up the Kansas show and finding how hard it w 'arge a is you have. I was surprised to find that you have more bir year than last. I think this is the first show in the west that has had more birds this year than last, unless it might be a new organization. I am also very much pleased to see the feeling of good fellowship, of interest among the breeders If there is anything that I dislike it is going -how when- there are fights and scraps and back talk and getting be - hind the judge and wondering if he is going to score the life out of the birds. I enjoy the way the breeders take their medicine this year at the la of the judges. It does credit to the intelligence of the Nebraska poultry breeders. I like to see the breeders come to the show with the to have the judges score the birds to the best of their ability and go home satisfied. I believe when hiring honest judges, we can look fear hon - est work and when we get their honest opinion, we ought to take it. I been much interested in hearing these remarks about the poultr ■ try. I was just thinking awhile ago. I was in the poultry plant of the Armour Packing House at Kansas City, and talked with the manager there about the poultry crop in the west. He said it made him smile and laugh ■ he heard about the poultry industry being overdone. He sai : I the average individual had no idea that they were trying to get more and better poultry every day. They send these Palace Poultr portion of the state to gather up the best poultry that can be even when dressed and put in the case they would make the poultr lush at the sight of it. They have to plump and fix them in order to make them presentable to go against the eastern fattened I ilioma poultry go to N. Y. City. When y and eat Pennsylvania broilers you are possibly eating the poultry that we raise here in the west. I learned then it when these poult - ■round the countr\ rade of M allow the farmers to have the rooster they have and trade it for tt • e in stock to crradp iid the noultrv in the conntrv Two weeks atro I talke 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 the poultry industry and they said that surely the poultry breeders have no greater amount of money at stake than they h»d. They could now compete with the eastern market on poultry. I like the remarks here to - night about educating the general public up to the point where they know what good poultry is. It amuses me to see the uninformed poultry breeder go into a show and tell us that be has better birds at home that that. A gentle - man laid to me at a show a week ago, that he had some Barred Rocks that beat any he could see in any of the shows. He paid a good price for them, about 50 cents apiece. He had no doubt they would scorp 95. I said "so." Those are the kind of people we want to educate and show how to make it pay. The question of educating the public is one that we should pay great m to. I want to again thank you for the privilege of taking up this little time." President Harris: "We have with us, Dr. J. W. Conway of the Experiment Station oi souri. who will address us on. the poultry diseases of the west." Dr. Conway: :it: I think that this must be a mistake as I had no inti - mation of the same. I am before you without any paper and with but little knowledge of poultry diseases. This west is a great big country an' kens but I hope it is not full of diseases. As far as I know, we have the chickens. I think we could count them on • hand or less than that if we had a few of the fingt off. I believe that chicken cholera and roup and the lice and coop worms pretty nearly covers tht iroutte - lice a disease? Dr. Conway: sume disease, we &lt;!■ &lt; I think the Hub from the irritation more than any real depletition of the system. So f the cause of t) med, cholera, etc., I don't think that it would be profitable to go inio a description of germs and all of that which lave read about. We could not roscopes. On some occasion I hope I)r .■ope and - I I known trap he was getting me into, I would have been fixed for him. I bel that so far as the disease of the poultry is concerned, so far as the treatment is concerned, we can sum it up into a very short sentence "keep your grounds clean, give pure air ere not liable to have cholera if you have clean grounds unless you introduce the disease from outside sources. It doe - generate of itself. We do not have smallpox in the human family wit: bring it in, same with chicken diseases. Some of these troubles, like roup, the cause of it may grow in the soil. It may be more wide spread than we think, of course, we cannot always tell; cannot always trace the source of thev !o come from. We find them in our flocks; we </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 find it amoi is worth more than a poui strict attention to sanitary tneasu: i, a plentiful use of antiseptics. I think there is harilly a man present who has beeu in the cIik ken business four or five years who does not know more about the treat - ment of these diseases than I do. I have had very little to do with the treat - ment of chicki-ii Mr. Ludden Bin your ezperini v treating the Dr. Conway Would if they called on us bat they don't call on us Mr. Ludden vou give them an opportunity until we took it up as an ass- ■ to call? Thev didn't in this state Dr. Conwav B' We are ready to do any thing that the people want us to do and we at - their associations and talk chickens with them — some of the - do — I have never been called on in our state. Is there any real need ition aloi ■-. of chicken diseas. i 'There is a little book published by I &gt;. B. Salmon on poultry diseases contains a great deal of valuable information. He is the chief of the au of Animal Industry. It is a bureau publication. I think it costs t 50 cents. George E. Howard is the publisher. With a half hour y of that you will get more out of it than with my two years experience. Gillis: "Don't you think the book from Dr. Salmon is too scientific?" Dr. Conway KNo, sir, I don't think so. It has been my experience that the intelli - of the chicken man is n«t to be sneezed at." Or A T. Peters, on the Discussion of Diseases. Mr. Ludden: "We find it m Dr. Con« i n r troubles: 1 I am here to learn." Mr Ludden: "The fir Dr. Conwi "How many rouM that in the m braska are not B lulden: "Oh, more than that die." </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 I . President, Ladies and Gentlemen : I am iy that Dr Conway was not really notified that he w on the diseases of chickens. I knew that he had some experience in that line am! jested his name to the Board of Managers. Dr. Stewart had a call to an - other part of the state so he wishes to be excused. I am sorry that we haven't him with us this evening. A great many in th« room are familiar with the work done at the I'niversity Experiment station. f poul - :ie last two years We received quite a numlier of birds for examination from all parts of the state. The majority of the birds that were sent in for examination were suffering from paralysis of the limbs. Quite a number were also examined for sore heails. A few examis were made for the disease known as "going light." As surprisii. may be, there was not a single bird of this number that was affeett roup, in fact, no inquiries were received concerning tin. ! contribute this largely to the fact that the breeders are beginning to believe that this disease is not du&lt; but that it is due to either poor vent: lack ot cleanliness, and possibly bad feed. In other words, to summarize it. bad management. tin the experiments that were conducted in treating birds effected with vhere the affection was in the joints, we used with apparel: Its the preparation known as piperazine. We made h i solution and : them a teaspoonful of this solution three times a day. Some - that showed marked paralysis and enlargement of the hock joints, e a complete recovery. It will be noticed in cases of this kind that the s are very sore. This medicine seems to reduce the pain. We are still ing experiments with this medicine ami we believe that it will prove valuable where a large number of birds are affected with this trouble. Speaking of chicken cholera would say that we have just kept up our cultures and laboratory experiments with the same, but have not used any of the vaccine in the state for no requests were made for the same. Quite a few have made inquiries regarding the disease known as big head, where the how an enlargement of the head. We have received very good results by annointing the parts with blue vitrol ointment that can be secured from any drug store. If the blue ointment is not at hand we have also reco - mended the use of grease, namely axle grease, which is found on nearly every farm. This contains curative properties and can be used with fairly good success. In conclusion, I wish to say a few words in regard to lice. I believe that lice cause considerable loss among the flocks and I think that th e kept under control by guarding their natural breeding places, and for that reason I would warn all lovers of poultry not to have many cracks or crevices in their hen-house I think that the time will come when vt will use stationary nests. For hen nests it is better to use an ordinary soap box which can be hung up on a nail against the wall. These boxes can be taken out and cleaned, either with disinfectants or by lighting a little straw and placing these boxes over the same to char them a little. If </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 hem become affected, I would advise dipping them into sume of the coal tar preparations making a two percent solution of Lee's dip, chloni-naj - leutn. Either of these dips can be highly recomend . e this solution in a boiler and dip the affected birds, and house with :ie solution. Lime is also a great benefactor in ridding the hen from this pest. Allow your hens to have a dust bath as often as they can. I also wish to warn against over feeding. If these rules are taken int sideration, I believe that you will have \ ■ le with diseases of poultry. I invite all the members t ed with the Experi - ment Station, whenever they are in need of a r, to write down to the station. We shall be glad I If you have troubles, a bird We will investigate and report to you our find; have any questions about any certain diseases. I will be glad to er them if I can." Q. In this application f n this remedy for paralysis, how do you apply the in Kith; a tablespxmful given t. How often? . Once a day. Mr. Ludden: ■What about the "go light" disease which struck us a few years ago?" We haven't had but one report in two years and that came from Benkleman. y. How long will one dipping keep the birds free from lice? Our experience has been this: In pens where we did not do any disaffecting at all, and just left the coop filled with the lice, it kept them off With three fowls that were dipped in the Lee dip, they were kept in the pen for 10 days, an ordinary two per cent dip was used so that it lot affect the eyes. For 10 days we didn't find any lice, on the 12th we did, so that about that time you will have to renew the dip. The evap - oration is not as strong on fowls as it is on some of the other animals, such as hogs and cattle — it stays on the feathers longer. Q. What is the remedy for a bad cold? A. I would suggest taking the birds into a warm room, say the kitchen keep it in a box or coop; at an even temperature. If the throat seems to be filled with phlegm it can be removed with a swab of cotton and the throat swabed out with a weak solution of carbolic acid 1 part to 100 par' water. It is not necessary to give them any medicine. The majority of - that I have had the privilege to investigate seemed to be contracts houses where the ventilation was imperfect or where they were subje^ draughts. We received a number of birds in 1898 that were affected with 1 or what is known as roop. We treated the animals by keeping their air passages clean and keeping them in a warm room, and the larger per cent of them recovered. I feel certain that if this method is practiced on I affected in this manner that ***^ majority can be saved. If many slv KT-ik- in;l just put it in mouth. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ck. you must investigate your ben house and see that the animals are not contracting colds from draughts or imperfect ventilatibn. If you will remove the cause yon will soon perfect a cure." President Harris: This concludes our regular program for this evening, the meeting is open for general remarks. Mr. Lewelling: "There is one thing I don't believe we can afford to let go without some - thing of an explanation and that is the three pound chickens that have gone to market from Nebraska. I am not questioning the fact that there has been some small poulty but the fact that we can account for that and ac - count for it readily. It is no fault of the poultry or people of Nebraska that such small poultry has been marketed. In the last two years, in the western part of the state of Nebraska, the corn crop has been ver\ The last year was almost an entire failure in parts of the state. When there comes a failure of that kind the farmers begin to sell everything that they can sell that eats corn, and the chickens go with the rest, all that can be spared. Now, the small poultry is the first that is marketed from the farm in the Pall and the fact that the corn crop has been so short, the small poultry has been put on the market instead of being developed, but when corn was 60 cents a bushel and poultry worth 6 cents a pound, there could not be any profit in feeding the poultry, and, therefore, it has gone to market." Mr. Garoutte: E: light weight poultry referred to, Mr. Lewelling, is not, I am glad confined to any portion of Nebraska, except the small strip of mentioned. The remedy, a discontinuance of the ruinous practice ding, is easily applied. The poultry gatherers books for Missouri River packers, show a decreas - ing weight average for the three years they have regularly bought poultry over the 100 miles of road named. In the parts of the state you mention, this condition does not exist. -In the southern and western part of our state especially, the weights of market poultry have almost don bled in the post few years to my knowledge through judicious breeding ' about largely, in my opinion, through the enlightening influence of State Association and its annual exhibit Mr. Lewelling. "My observation has extended not only from (over) the southeastern part but also the southwestern part of the state. On most of the farms there is not a Plymouth Rock chicken that weighs well. I will say, too, that I have just returned from a trip over N. Y. State, and while there, visited in the country almost all together, and, of course, being interested in poultry, I took notice as we traveled over the country, and I do know that the farm poultry in Nebraska is ahead of the same in New York State in size and ap - pearance, showing that we have been using a better grade of poultry breed - ers in this state, than in that state. This was noticeable to me and I make </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 mention of it here. Nebraska is not behind as a poultry breeding state." Mrs. E. J. Mellette: "I feel as if I should like to say a few words. It is with the most in - tense pleasure that I am with you tcnight, and to say, that never in my ex - perience, and I think I have been a poultry fancier for 20 years, have I had the pleasure of meeting 160 such enthusiastic poultry people as are here and I am sure that I enjoy it more than you can guess. In my state, Colorado of course, we don't do things like this. There is so much waste land - our mountains. We haven't so large a number of poultry people but still the Colorado poultry industry is coming to the front. We are finding that we can make a success of incubators which is vastly needed. But there is room for a great deal of improvement. If you Nebraska people want to do a good thing for yourselves financially, if you will just send the war into Africa and send some of your poultry to our shows, you are sure to make it a paying investment, because the poultry industry with us, although we might say that it is almost in its infancy, still it is forging ahead. Any litera - ture is up hill work because there are not enongh of us to spread it. The prospects are that the poultry literature will all be such, and if you people charter a car or two and send some poultry out to our shows, I am sure that it will give you some advertising that you can get in no other way; that field should belong to you. I have been in Nebraska long enough and at your shows long enough to know that it seems to me, at least that you must have as good poultry as they have in the far east. I have seen some fair birds that came from the east, and I am sure that I shall remember this meetiug always with pleasure and I sincerely hope that I may be with you President Harris 'Are there any others who would like to say a few words in regard to the poultry question? We should be glad to hear from them." Mr. L widen: "Some of the other poultry women that are here, I presume, are not without views on this question, This is the twelfth time that I have been privileged to be with the poultry men of the state. I think it is eleven years ago that they assigned me the topic, "The Commercial Value of the Hen." I have heard from it a good many times in the way of derision but I have lived to see Nebraska more than double the industry. Today, three times as many birds and eggs are shipped out of the our state than when we commenced this question of poultry agitation. When we commenced talking ab»ut the commercial value of the hen, we persuaded our Legislature to give us the appropriation that they gave. It may seem to you a large sum of money : that is the way it seemed to the Legislature, $1,000.00 and yet that appropriation started the increase in our yield of poultry. Even in connection with our exhibition, it is made obligatory to gather as we gather here tonight. In correspondence with the poultrymen in other states, who are striving to secure through their Legislatures the same line of appropriation, I find that they are opposed to the feature 0/ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 held a convention. We could nut get the first Legislature to make the appropriation without we consented to hold a convention. They 1 at it: called it "A Hen Convention;" made all sorts of sport of it. A» a result, Nebraska has forged out to the front in the poultry industry. It is one of the hardest states to gather t cs from be - cause of the varied market which pre- If to us. The north and have our products in their particular seasons of the year, then the surplus that we have may go east or west into Colorado by millions of dol - lars worth, which shows that it is hard work for Nebraska to gather her actual statistics. It is surprising since the concentration of the work in the &gt;rage of eggs to see the enormity of the eg;.' in this state of ours but I am glad to see the other states getting in line. It will make it easier for as who have to bear the brunt of the battle in the Legislature. I hope the other states will not cut out this feature of the convention, a better attendance every year. Some of you will remember the meeting at Kearney several years ago. A nx&gt;m half this size would hold all the breeders that came to attend the convention. I am glad to see that our first breeders are well represented. I think when you go back to the show room tomorrow ig and see the awards put upon the birds some of you are going to be surprised. I suppose I know as much about the first, second, third, fourth, and fifth prizes as any of you. I am about the only one who knows for the reason thac the books are in mv charge. When the cards come into my I know who 77 or 91 or any nunibei belong to. I think you will be surprised at the result of the change when you go back there tomorrow mor - 3ome of our amateurs or beginners are goin}; home with the blue rib - bon and I am glad to see so many new exhibitors. It was hard work to get the show together this year. It has taken a large amount of correspon - dence. It is like Gov. Furnas tells in regard to the state fair. He said that 'Id him that he conld not get up a fair like last year's so he went at it with all his force and at the end of the year had the largest gathering • er had. Knowing that the conditions this year were not favorable to the development of the bird as in years past, I am greatly pleased to see that so many first exhibitors are with us. I know it by the 200 blanks. If you had to check up the books by the Premium List before you could make an entry in that book, you would find out whether they were new or hibitors. I am glad also to see them here in our Association tonight. I hope because of the amateur, as they are sometimes called, and the high scoring given their birds this year, will only be an inspiration and give us a larger exhibition next year than we have this year." Mr. Garoutte: "Speaking about the increase in egg production, as you know, that we have this year, inaugurated an egg exhibit. We secure our judges from the Beatrice Creamery Co., the largest egg packing establishment in the world. An expert happened to be here fi ington, D. C. and assisted in judging our eggs. They selected three samples and after they had placed the awards, one of the judges, Mr. Friend, President of the Creamery Co., </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 they had examined. He said: "I stand reads v numberof cars like these three samples and I will give $250 more per ( -~e than the average eggs we are receiving to day." Th stated upon the witness stand, that then value upon eggs as well as upon the hen herself. The hens that were all Nebraska bred." Mr. Trester: lould like to tell a conversation which I was : I met a gentleman over in the Auditorium used to be in the steamboat business on the Missouri river. He drift the try business in Nebraska City and from that into the whi nto Lincoln and from that bn is in the wholesale drug busi - ness and is one of the most successful business men here today. He looked the poultry on exhibition there and viid he could not help but think of experience while in the grocery business in I'laltsmouth. On accouir my having been in the steamboat business I had the of butter, eggs and chickens over others, but many times have I seen a I ly come in front of my store, with a wagon -igo, when I whispered to the clerks and said "There is Smith with chickens. We have no use for them under the sun. Tell him that I went out of the store awhile ago and don't know how soon I'll be back. I don't want them at any price be - cause I don't know what todo with them. "I could not get the steamboat people to take all the chickens I could get. Many other times has the farmer come to my store at Plattsmouth, 30 years ago, with a basket of eggs, and caught me when I could not run. He said "We want some groct to day: we have some eggs." I said: "I don't know what to do with them if I receive them any more than I know how to fly across the Missouri was cornered I had groceries to sell and there was a man offering me eggs. I wanted to keep his friendship. I took the cg| him groceries for them, when I made an absolute donation of the groceries to him, be - cause before the sun rose the next morning, I carried these eggs out of back door and threw them into the river id, looking over poultry show to day, "makes me think of all of that experience." He snys: "It is not so now, for the farmer who has tli sell, the man who wants to get them, or the people who are dealing in them run to meet him. They are watching for him. They will send a car over the rail - road at stated periods and notify him that the nag and want eggs. The revolution that has taken place in the last 25 years is simply I All the packing houses in the land are putting in 1 ige plants and when the grocer gets his eggs he knows what to do with them. We are ready to give him 7 cents in cash. There was n no price on the groceries. Now be says, if a man comes in with eggs. We m that we can get 8 cents per pound for them. We are ready to . him 7 cents in cash. When he has got his cash from the agent in the road car, us middle men do not get any chance at it, it is direct from the packing house to the man who raises the poultry. He comes in and deals </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 with us in the grocery business on a cash basis. He then ran from him but now runs to meet him." "The prize afforded by the Farm Poultry is one of the leading poultry journals in the east. It was for the greatest number of eggs laid in nine months, commencing the ist of January. The number of hens in the pen, the breed, the age of the hens, the method of feeding was all to be given each day on sheets furnished by the paper publishers. The time of feeding, the temperature night and morning, everything so that they made a lot of red tape about it There was something over 10,000 pens competing for that prize in th» U. S. and Canada. I had 21 Plymouth Rocks. I entered for that prize. They were hatched in May and I won first prize in that contest with these 21 birds. In the month of March, they averaged over 26 eggs apiece for each pullet in the pen. At no time was I in danger of loosing that prize except there was one pen of Leghorns passed me for several months. I was living then on the seashore. I got plenty of fish from the fisherman there. I used to boil them and mix them with the mash. An - other thing they used to have was raw clams; they ate them very plentiful, flesh and shells, Of course, we cannot get that in Nebraska. I gave them everything the market afforded in the way of egg producing food and I felt well repaid for it. There is another thing I wish to say. I have got the best egg trade in the city of Lincoln I think. I furnish eggs to some of the best people in the city — not all of them — I furnish them strictly fresh eggs and have done so for three years. They have always had their eggs. I have no trouble in getting five cents a dozen above the market price for the eggs. There are people in this city who are perfectly willing to pay it. The trouble with the farmers is that they are not particular enough with their eggs. They go oat and find say, jo eggs and bring them to town and sell them for fresh ones. Mrs. Mel lett : B 'Speaking of fish, I always wondered in the east where they feed so fish — for instance, cod fish that are caught. It seems to me that it is naterial: how do you manage about the bones?" Mr. Koss: "We never had any trouble with bones: we boil them until the flesh OHMS 0*." President Harris: Khis will conclude our program this evening. Before you leave the ng I would like to state that our annual meeting will occur tomorrow ig in this room at 8 o'clook. KHon. N. F. Greeley of South Dakota was placed on the program be - the Dairymen's Assocation tonight. He had been extensively adver - so I have arranged so as to have him here tomorrow evening. I can t you that it will be quite a treat to hear him speak for a few minutes." </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 ent Harris: I We shall be glad to have Mr. Greeley entertain us tomorrow evening. ae invite you all, everyone of the members of the Association to be it and also other people who are interested in the poultry industry, to mual meeting." The Association then adjourned. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 The stenographic report of the annual meeting was lost before being transcribed and hence only the merest outline can be given here. January 23d, 1902 The annual meeting was held this evening in the Commercial Club parlors with President Harris in the chair. The roll called showed 1 10 present besides a goodly nnniber of visitors. Mr. Greely of Dakota made a most excellent address on the subj. the Poultry on the Farm how to (are for them. He was followed by Dr. A. A vote of thanks was tendered the speaker: Blw association then proceeded by ballot I - which res ows: OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1901-1902. V. OSTERHOIT. N'ORVAL, President I Citv Vice President Secretary, ■. Ll'DDEN. LVMAN. Treasurer, MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. BH. E' . Day, Minden North Bend § Smith, . Irvin, Bishop, Lincdn Teem: Ulywn The Association then adjourned. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>