<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Wheat for Fattening Hogs</title>
               <date value="1931-10">1931-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 261 October, 1931 Wheat for Fattening Hogs WM. J. LOEFFEL Department of Animal Husbandry § ' ~ Champion Hampshire barrow and Grand Champion over all breeds at the National Western Stock Show, Denver, 1931. Bred and ex - hibited by the University of Nebraska. Ground wheat and a protein feed comprised his ration after weaning. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN ■ W. W. •nURK. DrHECTOK ' </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Page Summary ....: 4 Introduction 5 Trial I 5 Corn vs. wheat 7 Is it necessary to grind wheat? '. , 8 Does soaking ground wheat pay? 8 Trial II :. 8 Trial 111 , ". ."..; 9 Trial IV :....: ; 10 Carcass Studies 11 Slaughter tests. 12 Firmness 13 Cooking and palatability studies 13 General Discussion _ 14 Grinding wheat ..; 16 Soaking whole wheat 17 Soaking ground wheat ; 17 Feeding tankage with wheat 17 Combinations of corn. and wheat '. 18 The quality of wheat-fed pork 18 Literature Cited .' 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY Wheat is more palatable than corn. Pigs fed wheat gain move rapidly than similar pigs fed corn. Wheat when coarsely ground is slightly more efficient than corn. A bushel of coarsely ground wheat properly supplemented will pro - duce 15 pounds of pork. Less protein supplement need be fed with wheat than with corn. Where wheat is to be hand-fed, it is very desirable to grind it coarsely. Where whole wheat is self-fed, pigs apparently masticate it thoroughly enough to prevent excessive waste.- Soaking either whole or ground wheat does not materially increase its feeding value. It is a good practice to feed tankage or some other good protein supplement with wheat. The pork from wheat-fed pigs is equal in quality and palatability to, and is firmer than, corn-fed pork. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Wheat for Fattening Hogs WM. J. LOEFFEL Corn is the principal grain used for hog feed in the corn belt. There have, however, been periods during which other grains have occupied positions of more or less prom - inence, either due to the high price of corn or the low price of some other feed. Wheat is used principally for human food. From time to time the price spread between wheat and corn becomes so narrow as to make the feeding of wheat economical or desirable. Figure 1 shows the Nebraska average farm price for both grains since the Civil War. The December 1 price is used in this illustration. For a long-time considera - tion, this price is probably adequate, although it does not show the detail which would be available from a study of average monthly prices. Since the Civil War" there have been several times when the price of corn has approached that of wheat. In a few cases the price of corn has actually exceeded that of wheat. Most of the experimental wheat feeding work has been published shortly after those periods when the spread be - tween corn and wheat prices was narrow. While considerable experimental work has been done with wheat feeding, there is a popular lack of appreciation of its value as a feed. This is probably due to the periodical nature of the problem. For example, a feeder barely learns the basic facts of wheat feeding when prices change to the point where wheat cannot be fed profitably for a period of years. By the time the spread between prices again narrows, he must learn anew the essential facts. The Nebraska Experiment Station has carried on four tests in which wheat was fed. These tests are not of such a nature that they can be averaged and, therefore, each test is discussed in detail. TRIAL I Trial I was carried on in dry lot. It continued for 80 days from August 7to October 26, 1923. Ten pigs aver - aging 92 pounds were fed in each lot. The rations fed the various lots were as follows: Lot I — Corn and tankage, self-fed, free choice, Lot 2 — Whole wheat and tankage, self-fed, free choice, Lot 3 — Coarsely ground wheat and tankage, self-fed, free choice, Lot 4 — Soaked coarsely ground wheat and tankage, hand-fed twice daily. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 2.2oi I I I I TTTTTI I I I I I I I I I I II I I I I I I I I I I I I I II I II I I II II I I I rTTT"l~| I I I I I I I I' -II 1 1 mi 1 i. \W[ \i\ in\nVru\ 1 1 Ivf I HUM 1 1 1 11 II 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Itl Fig. 1. — Wheat is an economical feed when the spread between the price of wheat and of corn is narrow. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Wheat for Fattening Hogs The wheat fed to Lot 4 was soaked from one feeding to the next. Just before feeding approximately the same amount of tankage was added as was consumed by Lots 2 and 3. Every effort was made to give the pigs in Lot 4 all the feed they would consume without waste. The details of the trial are presented in Table 1. Table 1. — 80-day dry lot trial, August 7, 1923, to October 26, 1923 — 10 pigs per lot Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Com and Whole Ground Soaked ground tankage, wheat and wheat and wheat and self-fed tankage, tankage, tankage,! self-fed .elf-fed hand-fed Average daily ration: Pounds ■ Pounds Pounds Pounds Shelled corn : 5.19 Wholewheat 6.38 Ground- wheat. ; 5.60 5.54 Tankage 0.52 0 31 0.37 058 Average initial weight '. 91.83 ' 91.77 92.33 92.57 Average final weight 194.93 201 .2:1 211.13 203.43 Average Rain 103.10 109.46 118.80 110.86 Average daily gain 1.29 1.37 1.49 1.39 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn . .... 403 Wholewheat 393 Ground wheat 377 400 Tankage. . 40 22 25 20 , ■ CORN VS. WHEAT Wheat appeared to be more palatable than corn, for the average daily feed consumption of all lots receiving wheat was higher than that of the check group, Lot 1. Less tank - age was consumed by the wheat-fed groups. Lots 2, 3, and 4, which had received wheat, all gained more rapidly than Lot 1, which had been fed corn. In Lot I, 403 pounds of corn, or 7.2 bushels, and 40 pounds of tankage were required to produce 100 pounds of gain, while in Lot 2, 393 pounds of whole wheeat, or 6.6 bushels, and 22 pounds of tankage produced an equal gain. It is interesting to note that only a little more than half as much tankage was necessary to produce 100 pounds of gain where wheat was fed as where corn made up the grain ration. Purely on the basis of the grain required to pro - duce 100 pounds of gain, the whole wheat proved 2V£ per cent more efficient than shelled corn. Coarsely ground wheat such as was fed in Lot 3 made an even better showing. The average daily gain increased from 1.29 pounds in Lot 1 to 1.49 pounds in Lot 3. Three hundred and seventy-3even pounds, or 6*4 bushels, of ground wheat and 25 pounds of tankage were needed to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 produce 100 pounds of pork. The ground wheat proved almost 7 per cent more efficient than corn, pound for pound. IS IT NECESSARY TO GRIND WHEAT? Because of the small size and hardness of the wheat berry, it is commonly considered necessary, or at least desirable, to grind or soak it before feeding to hogs. Lots and 3 offer an interesting comparison of the importance and value of grinding. It should be pointed out that the grinding here was very coarse, producing what some would classify as "cracked wheat." In Lot 3, where ground wheat was fed, 377 pounds of wheat were required to produce 100 pounds of gain as compared to 393 pounds of whole wheat in Lot 2 The saving in producing 100 pounds of gain by grinding was 16 pounds of wheat. Ground wheat proved 4 per cent more efficient that whole wheat. As a result of this single trial therefore, it appears that grinding must be done for less than 4 per cent of the cost of the grain in order to pay where the wheat is to be self-fed. When wheat is high in price, grinding will be more likely to prove profitable than when the price is low, since the cost of grinding is not sub - ject to as wide fluctuations as the price of wheat. DOES SOAKING GROUND WHEAT PAY? By comparing Lots 3 and 4 it will be noted that where the ground wheat was soaked from one feeding to the next less feed was consumed and smaller and less efficient gains were made. Without even considering the additional labor required, soaking proved unprofitable. In fact, where the wheat was ground and soaked, as in Lot 4, the gains were no larger and no more efficient than where the whole wheat was self-fed as in Lot 2. TRIAL II Trial II began June 28, 1929, and lasted until October 30, a total of 90 days. All lots were full-fed by hand on sudan grass pasture. The lots were fed as follows: Lot 1 — Shelled corn and tankage, Lot 2 — Whole wheat and tankage, Lot 3 — Ground wheat and tankage. The essential data are given in Table 2. This trial differs from the first in that all feeding was done by hand, and, secondly, that it was conducted on pasture. The wheat fed to Lot 3 was coarsely ground and fed dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Wheat for Fattening Hogs Table 2. — 90-day trial on sudan grass pasture, June 28, • _ ■ 1929, to October 30, 1929 — 10 pigs per lot ■■;.;■ Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 ■ '■■'.' Corn and Whole wheat Ground wheat tankage, and tankage, and tankage, hand-fed hand-fed hand-fed Average daily ration: " Pounds Pounds Pounds Shelled corn 3.79 Wholewheat..: ... , 4.76 Ground wheat 4.51 Tankage 0.26 0.32 0 31 Average initial weight 77.30 77.83 77.13 Average final weight - 174.37 167.13 187.37 Average gain 89.55 89.28 104.40 Average daily gain 0.995 0.992 1.16 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn 380 Whole wheat 479 Ground wheat -, . 389 Tankage .'. .1 26 32 27 Here again as in Trial I wheat proved more palatable than corn, judging from the amount consumed. Since the amount of tankage was regulated, no reduction was noted as in. the previous trial where free-choice self -feeding was followed.. Approximately the same daily gains were made by Lots 1 and 2. However, 100 pounds more grain were required to make 100 pounds of gain where wheat was fed than where corn made up the grain ration. Whole wheat, when hand-fed in this trial, proved to be only 79 per cent as efficient as shelled corn per unit of weight. Ground wheat, when fed in place of corn in Lot 3, in - creased the daily gain from one pound to 1.16 pounds. Only a trifle more feed was required to produce 100 pounds of gain. Ground wheat in this instance proved to be 98 per cent as efficient as corn per unit of weight. Lots 2 and 3 show that grinding wheat in this instance, where hand-feeding was followed, increased the feeding value of wheat 23 per cent. More will be said concerning this later. TRIAL III Trial III was carried on from June 28. 1930. to October 11, 1930, a total of 105 days. All lots were full-fed by hand on sudan grass pasture. The lots fed w.ere : Lot 1 — Shelled corn and tankage, Lot 2. — Coarsely ground wheat and tankage. For one month No. 2 mixed corn testing 55 pounds was fed. For the remainder of the trial No. 1 and No. 2 yellow com was fed, testing 54.5 to 55.1 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 During the first two weeks of the trial, old wheat was fed. After this, new wheat which graded No. 1 hard winter (smutty) and tested 60.3 to 62 pounds was used. The wheat was coarsely ground with a burr-type mill. The modulus of the ground wheat as determined by the Agri - cultural Engineering Department was 3.76. 1 The wheat was fed dry. The essential data of this trial are sub - mitted in Table 3. Table 3. — 105-day trial on sudan grass pasture, June 28 1930, to October 11, 1930 — 12 pigs per lot Lot 1 Lot 2 Corn and | Ground wheat tankage, ! and tankage, ' hand-fed hand-fed , , ., . . Pounds i. Pounds Average daily ration : Shelled corn "&gt;.._ 4.22 Ground wheat ■ 4 66 Tankage . 0.29 . (K29 . ___^ !_ * Average initial weight . . 75.94 76 90 Average final weight. ; 187.75 °02 14 Average gain 111.81 125.24 Average daily gain . 1 .06 1.19 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Shelled com 397 Ground wheat | . . 391 Tankage I -27 "|. 24 Once again pigs fed ground wheat consumed more feed and gained more rapidly than similar pigs fed corn. Less feed was required to produce 100 pounds of gain where ground wheat was fed than in the check lot, which received corn. Seven bushels of corn and 27 pounds of tankage were required to produce 100 pounds of gain in Lot 1, while in Lot 2 an equal gain was produced with 6 ] /&gt; bushels of wheat when ground and 24 pounds of tankage" Ground wheat in this trial proved to be 102 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. TRIAL IV This trial was begun July 24, 1930, and lasted until November 22, a total of 121 days. It was carried on in dry lot. Instead of tankage, a supplementary mixture com - posed of two parts tankage* one part cottonseed meal, and 1 The modulus, as used in this publication, expresses the decree of fineness of the ground grain. A modulus of 2 would be fine and a modulus of 4 would be coarse. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Wheat for Fattening Hogs one-part alfalfa meal, by weight, was fed. This supple - ment as well as the grain was self-fed. The grains used were similar to those used in Trial III, except that the wheat was ground with a roller-type mill. The modulus determined by the. Agricultural Engineering Department for this ground wheat was 3.12. The data for Trial IV are presented in Table 4. Table 4. — 121-day dry-lot feeding trial, July 2J+, 1930, to November 22, 1930 — 10 pigs per lot Lot 1 Lot 2 Corn and Ground wheat . ' supplement, and supplement, . , self-fed self-fed , ... . Pounds Pounds Average daily ration : Shelled corn 4.28 Ground wheat " 4.63 Supplement ; . . 1.04 0.91 Average initial weight 71.47 71.77 Average final weight 220.78 231.61 Average gain 149.31 159.84 Average daily gain . 1.24 1.32 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn 347 Ground wheat 351 Supplement 75 68 In this trial, the pigs fed ground wheat again consumed more feed and made larger gains than the corn-fed pigs. As in Trial I where free-choice self -feeding was followed, the consumption of protein supplement with wheat was markedly lower than with corn. Four pounds more grain were required to produce 100 pounds of gain where wheat was fed. However, seven pounds less supplement were required with wheat, making the total pounds of feed required in the two lots approximately the same. On the basis of the pounds of grain needed to produce 100 pounds of gain in this trial, ground wheat was 99 per cent as efficient as shelled corn per weight unit. CARCASS STUDIES Three pigs from each lot in Trial III were slaughtered at Omaha to provide exhibit material for the meat dis - play at the Ak-Sar-Ben Stock Show in November, 1930. All of the remaining pigs from Trial III and six from Lot 2 in Trial IV were shipped to Chicago November 22, 1930, for </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 slaughter test there and for the meat exhibit at the Inter - national Livestock Exposition. Two pigs from each lot in rrial IV were slaughtered in the station abattoir for de - tailed carcass and palatability studies. Feeders frequently claim that pigs which have been fattened on wheat shrink heavily when marketed. They attribute this to failure of the pigs to fill upon the corn which is fed at the markets. For this reason, some feeders suggest that wheat-fed pigs be made accustomed to corn before shipping. The shrinkage on the pigs from Trial III, which were marketed in Omaha, was 3.64 per cent on the corn-fed lot and 5.06 on the wheat-fed lot. Since these figures are based on only three pigs from each lot, too much signifi - cance should not be attached to them.. At Chicago, as a result of an unfortunate misunderstand - ing, marketing and slaughter data were obtained on only one pig for Lot 1, Trial III. Since this was the check lot it is impossible to make any definite comparisons of the pics marketed in. Chicago. SLAUGHTER TESTS Through the courtesy of the Cudahy Packing Company dressing yields were obtained on the pigs slaughtered at Omaha. The corn-fed pigs dressed 71.4 per cent and the wheat-fed pigs 72.1 per cent, hence there was a difference of less than 1 per cent between lots. These figures are based upon final experimental weights rather than market weights. The pigs shipped to Chicago were slaughtered bv Armour &amp; Company, who furnished the slaughter data The pigs from Lot 2, Trial III, dressed 74.3 as based or the home weight and 76 per cent of the Chicago sale weight Lot 2, Trial IV, dressed 72.8 as based on- the final experi - mental weight and 76.3. per cent of the sale weight Both of these lots had been fed wheat. Since slaughter data were obtained on only one corn-fed pig, comparative dress - ing yields are not available. The wheat-fed pigs were heavier, principally because they were fatter. Provision men who examined the car - casses at Omaha and at Chicago stated that they were all satisfactory for their purposes and recognized no difference in value between the lots. «. Tw ? £ igS f u om . ? ach lot in Trial IV were slaughtered at the station abattoir. These were all slaughtered at 250 pounds live weight to obviate any possibility that degree </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Wheat for Fattening Hogs of finish might influence the results. No differences were noted between lots under these conditions. FIRMNESS The committee on soft pork from {h\U. S. Department of Agriculture, consisting of E. Z. RusseH, O. G. Hankins, and J. H. Zeller, all of the Bureau of Animal Industry, graded the careasses of the pigs slaughtered at Chicago. The single carcass of a corn-fed pig from Lot 1, Trial III, graded medium soft. All of the carcasses of wheat-fed hogs graded hard. This should not be construed as indicat - ing that corn-and-tankage pigs kill soft, but rather that no objectionable softness was noted in the carcasses of pigs which had received wheat. The committee had no knowl - edge of the rations fed the various pigs. Samples of back fat were taken from each of the car - casses and sent to the government laboratory at Beltsville, Maryland, for refractive index determinations. The re - sults of these studes are shown in Table 5. 2 Table 5.— Firmness studies on pigs killed at Chicago Refractive index I Finish Lot No. Trial Grain ted Range Av. finished O.K. finished 1 3 Corn ■ 1.4599 . . . . 777! 2 .•! Wheat 1.4582—1.4588 1.4585 4 2 2 2 4 i Wheat 1.4579—1.4590 1.4584 15 0 All of the refractive indices from the wheat-fed pigs may be classified as "hard" while that of the single corn-fed pig may be interpreted as being medium soft (33) 3 . The refractive indices coincide in a striking way with the re - port of the grading committee on firmness. COOKING AND PALATABILJTY STUDIES The cooking and palatability studies carried on at Lin - coln showed no significant differences between wheat- and corn-fed pork. 4 'The refractive index is one of the simplest and most reliable means of determ - ining the firmness of pork fat. The relation of refractive index to firmness is as follows: 1.4597 and below, hard; 1.4598-1.4601, medium hard; 1.4602-1.4605 medium soft: 1.4606-1.4618, soft: and 1.4619 and above, oily. ' """&gt;""" "Numbers in parentheses are references to publications listed in the back of the bulletin. 'The cooking tests arc conducted by Miss Matilda Peters of the Home Economics Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 discussion In four tests carried on at the Nebraska station, pigs fed wheat consumed more feed daily than similar pigs fed corn. This same observation has been made by other work - ers (7, 12, 28). In every instance but one, Trial II, pigs which were fed wheat gained more rapidly than those fed corn. In the single exception the gains of the wheat-fed pigs were equal to those obtained with corn. Many workers (3, 7, 10, 12. 17, 26, 28, 31) have reported greater gains on wheat than on corn. Snyder (1) and Ferrin and co-workers (11) re - port one trial each in which the gains made with corn have exceeded those made with wheat. In Trial I where whole wheat was self-fed with tank - age in dry lot, wheat proved to be 2V-&gt; per cent more efficient than corn, pound for pound. In Trial II where whole wheat was hand-fed on pasture, it was only 79 per cent as efficient as corn. In Trial I, coarsely ground wheat was 7 per cent more efficient per unit of weight than. corn, while in Trial IV, also conducted in dry lot, ground wheat proved to be only 99 per cent as efficient as corn. Trials II and III were similar in that hand-feeding on sudan grass was practiced in both. In Trial II, ground wheat was 98 per cent as valuable as corn and in Trial III it was 102 per cent as efficient as corn per unit of weight. The feed requirements for 100 pounds of grain are sum - marized in Table 6. ; It is probably a questionable practice to average Trials I and IV, since tankage was used in I and the mixed supple - ment in IV. A straight average of these two trials, how - ever, shows that less grain and less supplement were re - quired to produce 100 pounds of gain where ground wheat was fed than where corn constituted the grain ration. Six and seven-tenths bushels of corn and 58 pounds of supple- TABLE 6. — Summary of feed required for 100 pounds of gain Ground Trial Corn ' Supplement Total wheat Supplement Total Drv lot Pounds Pountl* Pour.tl* i Pound* Pottiuls Pound* 1 403 40 (tankage) 443 377 25 (tankage! 102 . 2 347 75 (mixed) 422 • 351 68 (mixed) 419 Average 375 58 43;J 364 47 411 Sudan grass pasture 2 380 26 (tankage) 406 389 27 (tankage) 416 3 397 27 (tankage) 424 391 24 (tankage) 415 Average 1 389 27 I 415 390 26 I'B </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Wheat for Fattening Hogs ment produced 100 pounds of gain, whereas only six bushels of ground wheat and 47 pounds of supplement were required in the other lots. Trials II and III on sudan grass pasture show unusually uniform results. Approximately the same amounts of grain and supplement are required to produce 100 pounds of gam regardless of whether the grain ration is composed of ground wheat or corn. Ground wheat appears to excel corn more when fed in dry lot. Pasture in these trials tended to equalize the results from these two grains. From the results herein reported, it would seem that the conclusion that coarsely ground wheat and corn are equal, pound for pound, would be conservative enough. From the standpoint of the pounds of grain required to produce 100 pounds of gain, Weaver (28) found, when wheat alone was compared with corn alone, that the wheat proved 10 per cent more efficient. However, when the grains were combined with 10 per cent of tankage, the wheat proved only 6 per cent more efficient than corn. Snyder (26) states that one pound of ground wheat will produce the same gain as 1.11 pounds of corn. Georgeson (17) reported ground wheat to be 6 1 /' per cent more efficient than corn. Porter (21) state's that wheat is superior to corn, pound for pound. Henry (19) ascribed the superiority of wheat to its higher content of "muscle and bone-building components." Smith (25) stated that wheat may be substituted for corn in the ration as long as the price is not more than 9 per cent higher than corn. A number of Kansas farmers and feeders circularized by Coburn (5) estimated that wheat was 16 per cent more efficient than corn as a hog feed. Mills (20) stated that 100 pounds of wheat were equivalent in feeding value to 118 pounds of corn, wh'.le Ferrin and Winchester (9) in one trial found groum. wheat to be 20 per cent more efficient than corn. Not all the references are so favorable to wheat as a feed. Ferrin and co-workers (11) at Minnesota and some work at Purdue (31) showed ground wheat to be only 90 per cent as valuable as corn. Durum wheat was used by Ferrin, Peters, and Johnson, although they state (10) that "durum wheat is practically as good as bread wheat." Another trial (10) with durum wheat showed it to be 96 per cent as good as corn from the standpoint of grain re - quired per unit of gain. Snyder (1) found whole wheat to be 91 per cent as efficient as corn. From the standpoint </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 of economy of gain Eastwood (7) reports the feeding value of wheat to be 96 per cent that of corn. Why the feeding value of wheat should range from 1 0 per cent below that of corn to 20 per cent above is hard to say. Possibly the quality of the wheat, or the climatic or soil conditions under which the wheat was produced were responsible, yet Ferrin (9, 10) states that shriveled wheat is just as nutritious as sound grain. Shepperd and Richards (24), on the contrary, found low-grade wheat in - ferior to corn. In many of the early wheat-feeding trials, no protein sup - plements were used. The use of good supplements and the use of pasture no doubt have tended to obliterate differ - ences between wheat and corn. Many of the early workers in this field (5, 15, 26, 28, 29) estimated that a bushel of wheat would produce from 11 to 13.7 pounds, of pork. In Trials I, II, and III, reported in this bulletin, 13.9 to 14.7 pounds of pork were produced with a bushel of corn when it was supplemented with a small amount of tankage. In the same trials, a bushel of ground wheat, when properly supplemented, produced 15.3 pounds of pork. GRINDING WHEAT French and Thompson (13) in 1892 observed that where whole wheat was fed, much of it was undigested. Coburn (5) estimated, that 25 per cent of the whole wheat was unmasticated and unassimilated, which he considered "a shameful waste." Henry (19) suggested that wheat should be ground and moistened with either water or milk. In Trial I, where whole wheat and tankage were self - fed in comparison with coarsely ground wheat and tank - age, grinding increased the daily feed consumption and the rate of gain and increased the efficiency of the wheat approximately 4 per cent. . As shown in this trial,, grind - ing must be done for less than 4 per cent of the cost of the wheat to be profitable. In Trial II, where whole wheat and tankage were full - fed by hand on pasture and compared with ground wheat, grinding did not increase the daily feed consumption but did increase the daily gain. In this instance, grinding in - creased the efficiency of the wheat 23 per cent. One may well ask, why the difference? Much of the early work with wheat feeding (1, 18, 19, 22, 26, 27) was done before the self-feeder had come in - to extensive use. Where a grain is hand-fed the competi - tion between pigs becomes very keen. They eat. ravenously </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Wheat for Fattening Hogs and bolt the grain without proper mastication. Ferrin and Winchester (9) in one trial reported results more ex - treme than those obtained in Trial I from grinding. Where the wheat was ground and self-fed, it actually proved to be only 97 per cent as efficient as whole wheat. It seems possible that in these two instances self-feeding gave the pigs ample time to masticate their grain, and, therefore, grinding proved of little, if any, advantage. SOAKING WHOLE WHEAT Soaking is a popular method of preparing wheat for hog feed because it does not call for the outlay for grinding equipment. While this method of preparation was not under investigation in this series, the results of other in - vestigators may be of interest. Spillman (27) said that after soaking whole wheat 12 hours, one more pound of pork could be produced per bushel. Smith (25) considered soaking preferable to grinding unless grinding could be done for less than two cents per hundredweight. However, Henry (19) states that "wheat when soaked is rarely satis - factory." Soaked whole wheat proved to be the least efficient of the rations studied by Bliss and Lee (1). Snyder (1) found pigs would gain 1.02 pounds a day on whole dry wheat and required 519 pounds of feed to produce 100 pounds of gain. Where soaked whole wheat was fed, the gain increased to 1.05 pounds, and a total of 514 pounds of feed was needed to make 100 pounds of gain. In an - other trial, Snyder (26) found soaked wheat less efficient than ground wheat or corn. The saving due to soaking cer - tainly did not pay for additional labor. Good and Smith of Kentucky (18) found soaking distinctly less desirable than grinding. SOAKING GROUND WHEAT No advantage in rate or economy of gain was noted in Lot 4, Trial I, where the ground wheat was soaked. These results are similar to those- obtained by Good and Smith (18). Soaked ground wheat proved the most efficient ration used by Bliss and Lee (1) and Snyder (1, 26) although in these cases no comparison with dry ground wheat was included. FEEDING TANKAGE WITH WHEAT While wheat does contain more protein than corn, it is not a balanced ration. Some high protein feed should be com - bined with it for best results. Good and Smith, Ferrin (9), Weaver, and Bliss and Lee noted stronger appetites and </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 261 larger and more economical gains where tankage was fed with wheat. COMBINATIONS OF CORN AMD WHEAT Weaver found combinations of wheat and corn, equal parts, to be superior to corn although not as efficient as all wheat. Similar results were obtained where these com - binations were fed with tankage. In these experiments the rations were hand fed. At the Purdue Station (31) where corn, ground wheat, and tankage were self-fed free choice, the average daily gain was 1.88 pounds, and 410 pounds of feed were necessary to produce 100 pounds of gain. Where ground wheat and tankage were self-fed, the pigs gained 1.82 pounds a day and required 443 pounds of feed for every 100 pounds of gain. In other words, the combina - tion of wheat and corn self-fed resulted in larger and more efficient gains. It is interesting to note that the pigs ate Zy&gt; pounds of ground wheat to every pound of shelled corn where both were available. In view of the fact that 60 pigs were fed in each lot in this test, the results should be particularly valuable. THE QUALJTY OF WHEAT-FED PORK By all of the tests which were applied in these studies, the wheat-fed pork proved equal to that produced with corn. This is in accord with the observations of other workers in this field. French and Thompson (14) say "The l'esults are such as to dispel all doubts from the minds of those who have thought that wheat could not produce pork equal in quality to corn-fed pork. The lean meat was very juicy, and light in color, which characteristic has marked all of the results in feeding wheat to pigs thus far carried on at our station." Smith 025) found the carcasses of wheat - fed pigs to have a little more lean meat. Chilcott (3) found that pork produced with wheat was equal to that produced with corn, and Friis (16), the Danish worker, comments on the excellent quality of wheat-fed pork. In an extensive wheat-feeding trial carried on at Purdue (31) in which sixty pigs were fed in each lot, it was found that lots of corn-fed, wheat-fed, and wheat-and-corn-fed pigs dessed out within one per cent of each other. The wheat-fed pigs were found to be a little firmer than those which had received corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Wheat for Fattening Hogs 19 LITERATURE CITED (1) 1914. ltliss, R. K.. Lee. C. B. and Snyrfer. W. r. Ground Wheat vs. Whole Wheat for Fattening Pigs. Nebr. Exp. Sta. Rill. 14-1. 13 Daces. (2) 1002. Burnett, E. A., ami Smith, 11. H. Feedlnit Experiments with Cattle unil Pics. VIIT. Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 78. pp. 37 - -(3) 1 s t» -t . . Chilcott, E. C. Feeding Wheat to Hogs. S. Dak. Exp. Sta. Bui. 3X. lfi paces. (IJ 1912. Clark. R. W. Experiments with Pins. Mont. Exp. Sta. Bui. 80. 10 paces. f5) 1X94. Coburn. F. D. Feeding Wheat to Farm Animals. Kept. Kana. State Bd. Agr. pp. l r&gt;-iw.«. (6) 1883. Dean, H. H. Ontario Acr. Col. and Kxp. Farm .' Kept. p. 151. (7) 1914. Eastwood, Geo. R. Substitutes for Corn in Rations for Fattening Swine. Ohio Exp. Sta. Bui. 258. pp. 159 - -160. (■•J- 190S. Elliott. E. E. ■ Experiments in Feeding Swine. Wash. Kxp. Sta.. Bui. 68; 24 panes. (B) 1921. Ferrin, K. F.. and win - cheater, H. B. Swine Feeding Investigations. Kilns. Kxp. Sta. Cir. 89. lip. I-.1. Mil) 1980. Ferrin, E. F.. and John - son, Don. Substituting Wheat for Corn. Minn. Kxp. Sta. Mimeo. Cir. 15. ■ -\ PBKGO. Ill) 1931. Ferrin. E. .■ F.. Peters, W. H., ami Johnson! Don. A Comparison of Five Grains as Hok Feeds. : Minn. F.xp. Sin. Mimeo. Cir. H IX. :l pages. ■ (I'l &gt; 1930. Freeman. V. A. Corn vt\ Wheat for Pic-^. Mich. Kxp. Sin.- An. Hush. Leaf - let 42.. 2 page*. (IS) 1R92. French. H. T.., and Thomp - son, C. D. ■ Experiments in' Pig Feeding-. Oreg. Kxp. Sta. Bill. 20. 12 paces, ill) 1894. French. 11. T., and Thomp - son, C. D. Experiments in Pic Feeding. Ores. Exp. Sta. Bui. 28. pp. 35 - -4S. lift) 1896. French, H. T. Pig Feeding. Oreir. Kxp. Sta. Hul. 85. pp. 49 - -56. (18) 1 899. Friis. F. Danish . Feeding Experiments with ■12 Rept. Kkl. Vet. Landboh.ijsk. I.ab. LRnddkon Forsde. (Vipen - . ha^en. p. lf»2. (17) lS!). r &gt;. Geuriccson, C. C, Burtis F. C., and Otis, D. H. Pic Feedinc Experiments. Kans. Exp. Sta. Bui. 53. pp. 103 - -(1S) 1915. Good. Edwin S.. and Smith. Wallace V. The Value of Wheat as Feed for Swine. Ky. Exp. Sta. Bui. 190, Part 11. PP. 19-27. (Hi) IH9S. Henry, W. A. Wheat as Food for Swine. Wis. Exp. Sta. Rept. pp. 24-111. (20) 1X94. Mills. A. A. The Relative Value of Wheat. Peas. Corn and Barley. Utah Exp. Sta. Bui. 34. 10 paces. (21) 109.1. Porter. E. D.. Conner. C. M.. nnd Schweitzer, P. Feedini! Wheat to Pics. Mo. Exp. Sta. Bui. 29. 20 paces. (22) 1X97. Plumb, C. S., and Ander - son, W. B. Wheat and Corn as Food for Pics. Ind. Exp. Sta. Bui. 67. pp. fil-70. (23) 1891. Sanborn. J. W. Utah Exp. Sta. An. Rept. pp. 20 - -32. (2 1) 1909. Shcpperd. J. H.. and Rich - ards, W. B. Fniteninc Trials with Hoes. N. Dak. Exp. Sta. Bui. 84. pp. fi-24. &lt;2B)- 1002. Smith. H. R. Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pics. VII. Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 75. pp. 33 - 3-36. (20) I■&gt; 1 r&gt;. Snyder. W. V. Pork Production. Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 147 (Limited Edition), pp. :!9-44. (27) 1895. Spillman. W. J. Feedinc Wheat to Hoes, Wash. Exp. Sta. Bill. 16. 12 paces. &lt;2X) 1918. Weaver. L. A. Feeding Wheat to Fattening Swine. Mo. Exp. Sta. Bui. 13H. 35 paces. (29) 1904. Withycombe. J. Some Results in Swine Feeding. Oreg. Exp. Sta. Bui. SO. 19 pages. CUD 1894. Relative Value of Corn and Wheat for Hogs. Agricultural Student, Ohio State U. 1 : 8-9. (31) 1930. Wheat as a Substitute for Corn in Fattening Hogs. Purdue U. Exp. Sta. Mimeo. Cir. 3 paces. (■32) 1930. Feedinc Wheat to Live - stock. U. S. Hept. Agr. Misc. Pub. 96. 6 pages. (33) 192X. Some Results of SoCt-Pork Investigations. 11. U. S. Dept. Agr. Dept. Bui. 1492. pp.. 6-8. [10M| </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>