<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty Ninth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1926-02-01">1926-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-NINTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February I, 1926 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station fo His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved Sarch 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the ate of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and gulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Thirty-ninth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, February 1, 1926. Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Lincoln, February 1, 1926. rr. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station: tSlR: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirty-ninth nnual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of ebraska. Adam McMullen, Governor. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Hon. George N. Seymour, Elgin Term Expires January, 1927 Hon. Frank J. Taylor, President, St. PauL.Term Expires January, 1927 Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Term Expires January, 1929 Hon. Wm. P. Warner, V. P., Dakota City Term Expires January, 1929 Hon. Earl M. Cline, Lincoln Term Expires January, 1931 Hon. John. R. Webster, Omaha Term Expires January, 1931 Samuel Avery, Ph.D., LL.D., Chancellor *L. E. Gunderson, Finance Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Director W. W. Burr, B.Sc., Assistant Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service R. P. Crawford, B.A., Agricultural Editor W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. Ackerson, M.Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry Arthur Anderson, B.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry E. E. Brackett, B.Sc in E.E., Associate in Agricultural Engineering E. M. Brouse, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Valentine W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Agronomy (Chairman) F. M. Coe, M.Sc, Assistant in Horticulture H. P. Davis, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Associate in Dairy Husbandry H. C. Filley, A.M., Rural Economics (Chairman) H. D. Fox, M.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry R. W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate in Plant Pathology H. J. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) J. A. HOLDEN, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Mitchell T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy W. J. Loeffel, B.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, B.Sc. in Agr., Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V.M.D., A.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene R. F. Morgan, B.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry F. E. Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) G. L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) J. O. Rankin, A.M., Associate in Rural Economics J. C. RussEL, M.Sc, Associate in Agronomy Rudolph San.ostedt, B.Sc.,Analyst O. W. Sjogren, B.Sc. in A.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) W. P. Snyder, M.S., Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte M. H. Swenk, A.M., Entomology (Chairman) L. Van Es, M.D., V.S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene (Chairman) H. Lew Wallace, M.Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Engineering H. O. Werner, M.Sc, Associate in Horticulture Don B. Whelan, M.Sc, Assistant in Entomology C. C. Wiggans, Ph.D., Horticulture (Chairman) •*L. L. ZOOK, B.Sc, Agronomist, North Platte • By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. •• Detailed from the Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agriculture. Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal 2 Governor's Certificate 2 The Official Roster of the Station 3 2 Contents 4 Introduction 7 Investigational Work 8 Agricultural Engineering: Tractor Testing 9 Plow Draft Investigations 9 Poultry House Ventilation and Construction 9 Farm Machinery Survey 10 Animal Diseases: Fowl Cholera Investigation 10 An Inquiry into the Sources of Tuberculosis in Swine 10 An Inquiry into the Part Played by Avian Tuberculosis as a Source of Tuberculosis of Farm Animals 11 European Fowl Plague 11 Current Laboratory Examinations 11 Dairy Husbandry: A Study of Weight in Dairy Cattle 11 A Study of the Principles of Ice-Cream Making 11 A Study of Fat Soluble A as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds 12 Factors Affecting the Quality of Fluid Milk ..12 Field Crops and Soils: Corn Breeding .■ 13 Water Requirements of Crops 14 Small Grains 14 Forage Crops _. 14 Soil Fertility 14 Relation of Weather, Cultural Practice, and Soil Con- tiuii ui h caiuci , vuii-uidi rrauucc, aiiu ouil \_&gt;Uil - ditions to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils 15 Effect of Lime on the Physical Properties of the Soil 15 Soil Acidity 15 Fruit Production: Pruning Fruit Trees, Grapes, and Small Fruits 16 Fruit Breeding 16 .16 Orchard Culture 16 Fruit Stocks Investigations 16 Insect Control: Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds 17 Life History of Several Common Cutworms 17 Nursery, Orchard, and Greenhouse Inspection 18 Livestock Feeding: Cattle- Effect of Age and Sex upon Rate and Economy of Gain 18 Fattening Rations for Calves 18 Summer Feeding of Steers 19 Lambs — Fall Feeding of Lambs 19 Spring Feeding of Lambs 20 Hogs — Summer Pig Feeding 20 Soybean Meal vs. Tankage 20 g, *t A </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS — Continued Milling and Baking Quality of Wheats 21 Proteins of Other Grains 22 Nutrition : Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks 22 A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding P\ant Diseases: \ A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the 23 Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alter- nate Host '.. 24 The Influence of Environmental Conditions on the Trans - mission and Development of Seed Borne Diseases, In - cluding the Potato 24 The Determination of the Differential Reaction of Puccinia Graminis Tritici 25 Potatoes : Potato Selection for Seed Purposes 25 A Study of Degeneracy in Potatoes 26 Poultry Production: Inheritance of Egg Production 27 Protein Requirements for Growing Chicks '. 27 Turkey Production 27 Rural Economics: Farm Management Survey 27 Cost of Producing Beef Cattle 27 Farm Tenure 28 Cost of Producing Farm Crops 28 Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and Pur - chasing Power of Farm Products 28 The Farm Land Problem 28 Cooperative Agricultural Organizations 28 Cost of Producing Range Cattle .28 Serum Production 28 North Platte Substation: Agronomy — Cooperative Work 30 Moisture Studies 31 Crop Improvement 31 Irrigation SI Livestock — Beef Cattle 82 Dairy Cattle 32 Hogs 33 Cottonseed Meal as a Feed Supplement SS A Comparison of Sudan Grass and Alfalfa S3 Pasture for Hogs on Full Feed 83 Horticulture and Forestry 33 Scottsbluff Substation: Crop Rotation 34 Soil Fertility 34 Tillage : 85 Pastures 35 Dairying 35 Hosts . . 3S </seg>
            <seg id="p006">CONTENTS — Continued Page Lamb Feeding 35 Poultry , : 36 Valentine Substation: Small Grains 36 Corn , , 36 Miscellaneous Crops _ 37 Sorghum Varieties , 37 Meadow Investigations 37 Dairy Herd v 37 Additional Land, Buildings, and Equipment _ '. 37 Needs of the Experiment Station 37 New Legislation 38 Changes in Staff ., 38 Publications '. 38 Bulletins 39 Research Bulletins 39 Experiment Station Circulars .39 Technical Papers _ .40 Acknowledgments .40 rancial Statement of Money Received from the United States Government 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-NINTH ANNUAL REPORT This report covers the thirty-ninth year of service rendered by the Experiment Station to the people of Nebraska. Dur - ing that time it has sought out and developed information and scientific facts that have contributed in a large measure to the welfare of the state. Any new information that in - creases the efficiency or certainty of agricultural produc - tion is a contribution to all of society, fully as much as to those engaged in agricultural pursuits. An adequate supply of the products of agriculture is vital to every one. The farmer in his vocation in agriculture is most concerned with the profitableness of production. In this report is given a brief statement of the problems under investigation and some of the conclusions arrived at during the past year in the work of the Experiment Station. The report covers the work under way at the main Experi - ment Station at Lincoln and the three Substations, located at North Platte, Scottsbluff, and Valentine. The Substations are located to study the problems of agriculture peculiar to these different areas. During the past year satisfactory progress has been made by every department of the Experiment Station. A num - ber of investigations have been completed and the results assembled and published. New lines of work, particularly in Home Economics and Rural Economics, have been undertaken. The Experiment Station cannot undertake to investigate promptly all of the problems which come to it. It is necessary to limit the number of projects under investigation to the resources of the Station. As lines of investigation are com - pleted or the resources of the Station are increased, new problems are undertaken. It is good administrative policy not to undertake more work than can be well done by the personnel and funds available at any given time. Acknowledgment is due to Assistant Director W. W. Burr for the preparation of this Report. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">The demand for new information along many lines of agriculture is continually increasing. The cost of production has been relatively high for agricultural products during the past several years. This is due largely to increased lane values and higher costs of machinery and labor. The price of agricultural products has on the whole been relatively low This leaves the farmer a rather narrow margin on which to operate and makes him seek for any factor that will increase his possibility of profit. In this he is looking more and more to the Agricultural Experiment Station for information. In addition to the investigational work of the Experiment Station there is a large amount of routine work which comes to it, which does not contribute materially to the research program. The Experiment Station receives many plant and animal specimens for identification and for general infor - mation concerning them; seed for purity and germination tests, samples of soils, commercial feeds, and numerous other things for various analyses. The Experiment Station does not undertake to test seed for germination and purity; the State Agricultural Department maintains a seed laboratory for that purpose. Such other requests as properly fall with - in the field of the Experiment Station are taken care of. However, the Experiment Station can not do general analyt - ical work. Where samples have a general community interest, the Experiment Station undertakes to make the analysis. INVESTIGATIONAL WORK The work of the Experiment Station is grouped around subject matter departments; such as, Plant Pathology, Ani - mal Pathology, Dairying, Poultry, and so on. This grouping tends to greater efficiency in the solution of the many prob - lems undertaken. In the following report the various pro - jects are grouped in much the same manner, regardless of the particular class of investigation into which they might properly fall. The investigational work of the Experiment Station is supported by both Federal and State funds. In this report no attempt is made to classify the investigations according ;o different funds. The financial statement which follows he report shows the expenditure of the various f linds allotted » the Experiment Station. In the space allowed in a report of this kind, any con - siderable amount of detail is not possible. Only a brief sum - mary may be given. On the conclusion of the various projects </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 publications are generally made and these are available to anyone interested in them, upon application to the Director of the Experiment Station. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Tractor Testing. — Work was continued under this project in accordance with the Nebraska Tractor Testing Law. Dur - ing the past fiscal year 13 tractors were tested. The test shows that considerable attention is being given by manu - facturers to the improvement of — drawbar efficiency, weight distribution, grouser equipment for drive wheels, and engine governor performance. Experiment Station Bulletin No. 200 gives a summary of the later tests. In a 60-hour test, a product advertised for removing car - bon, reducing fuel consumption, and increasing the power of the engine was not found to substantiate the claims. Plow Draft Investigations. — Work was continued on this project in an attempt to isolate the various factors that affect the draft of implements and to devise methods for measuring each factor. Poultry House Ventilation and Construction. — The work under this project was expanded during the past year. Eight units of similar construction and arrangements were used. In each of these an equal number of hens of the same breed and strain were housed. In four of the houses equipment was installed to study the effect of minimum temperatures on egg production. In these units minimum temperatures of 70, 60, 50, and 40 degrees, respectively, were maintained. The best egg production for a representative period of two months was obtained from the house in which the minimum temperature was 60 degrees. Among the other four houses one was heated with a stove, one was equipped with electric lights which were auto - ratically switched on at 4 A. M., one was tightly closed from P. M. to 7 A. M. each day, and the other house was main - tained as a check for the entire series. Among the entire 8 houses, the one with the increased day, furnished by the electric lights, gave the highest production. Basing this as 100 per cent, the others ranged — the minimum temperature of 60 degrees 90 per cent, the check unit 85.9 per cent, and the other four ranging from 76 to 78 per cent of the highest production. Work on this project will be continued in an effort to find the various factors in poultry house construction that may </seg>
            <seg id="p010">have an influence on the egg production and general con - dition of the birds. With this information it will be possible to design poultry houses that will tend to increase the egg production during the time of high egg prices, — namely, dur - ing the winter. Farm Machinery Survey. — Work on this project was be - gun during the past year. The purpose of the project is to study the life of farm machinery as it is handled in actual farm practice and to establish rates of depreciation which will be in line with this practice. These studies are being carried on on the farms in several representative areas of the State. ANIMAL DISEASES Fowl Cholera Investigation. — Owing to the fact that very little fowl cholera has occurred in the immediate vicinity of the Experiment Station, it has not been possible to pursue, with any degree of vigor, the field experiments with serum treatment. The serum producing horses are kept in a high state of immunity in order to resume the studies when con - ditions again become favorable for the purpose. An Inquiry into the Sources of Tuberculosis in Swine. — The work under this project has been completed and the results published in Research Bulletin No. 30 of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Some of the conclusions reached are: 1. The type of swine tuberculosis which is responsible for the increased retentions of carcasses and the condemnation of parts is for the greater part due to infection of avian origin. 2. In the eradication and control of swine tuberculosis suc - cess can only then be obtained when the two chief fountain heads of infection, namely, the tuberculous cattle herd and the tuberculous poultry flock, are regarded as equally im - portant. 3. There are indications that the steady increase in the incidence of swine tuberculosis as shown by abattoir statis - tics reflects a similar increase in the spread of avian tubercu - losis in a large area of the United States. 4. In the intradermal tuberculin test of swine in which a mammalian tuberculin is used, a considerable number of cases of tuberculosis will escape detection. For dependable results, avian tuberculin must also be used. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 11 An Inquiry into the Part Played by Avian Tuberculosis as a Source of Tuberculosis of Farm Animals. — This is a new project of the past year. In the data thus far obtained, while not sufficient for final conclusions, two features are apparent, namely : 1. That the bovine visceral tuberculosis infection by an avian type of bacilli is not nearly as common an occurrence as in the case of the disease in swine. 2. That tuberculous lesions of the bovine cutis and sub - cutis have thus far proved to be sterile in spite of their typical character and the presence of acid fast bacilli in the material. Owing to the frequency of this form of bovine tuberculosis it may be advisable to subject this type of lesion to more detailed study. At the present time we have not yet developed an experimental technique in which we can confide for the solution of this problem. European Fowl Plague. — This project comprises a search for the European fowl plague in Nebraska poultry. It was undertaken as an outcome of the discovery of the disease in some of the eastern states. Careful examinations have been made of a number of outbreaks of poultry diseases in the state. In not a single case was it possible to demonstrate the existence of the European Fowl Plague in Nebraska poultry. Current Laboratory Examinations. — During the past year 1471 specimens came to the laboratory for examination and diagnosis. DAIRY HUSBANDRY A Study of Weight in Dairy Cattle. — The program of weighing all calves in the dairy herd at weekly intervals up to six months of age, and at monthly intervals thereafter, has been continued. Body measurements are taken to deter - mine when and where the growth takes place. The weights so far taken indicate a distinctly slower growth in Holstein females than in Holstein males up to six months. The rate growth for different breeds varies widely with animals kept under the same conditions. Gain in weight due to advancing pregnancy indicates a regular progressing increase month by month. A Study of the Principles of Ice-Cream Making. — The year's work has been confined to the study of ice-cream in - gredients. The following phases of the work were carried out : The effects of the mixture upon the freezing point, the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station hydrogen ion concentration, and viscosity of mixture. A study was also made of the effect of methods of cooling and homogenization upon the freezing point, hydrogen ion concen - tration, and viscosity of the various mixtures of the ingred - ients. In carrying out this work the principal ingredients of the ice-cream mix were studied, as follows : Water, gelatin, sugar, lactose, skim milk powder, and butterfat. These were studied singly and in combination. In all experiments the ingredients were figured on the basis of their concentration in water of a standard ice-cream mix containing 14 per cent butterfat, 14 per cent sugar, 10 per cent milk solids not fat (serum solids), and 5 per cent gelatin. Bacterial studies were also made of Nebraska ice cream. A Study of Fat Soluble A as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds. — During the year the following phases of this subject have been studied: (1) Working out a prac - tical method of calculating the average gain of milk fed rats as a criterion of the amount of vitamin A in milk of different breeds. (2) A comparative study of vitamin A in graded portions of Holstein, Jersey, Ayrshire, and Guernsey milks. (3) Comparison of milk produced under summer and winter conditions. (4) A comparative study of vitamin A in the butter as churned from milks of Holstein and Guernsey cows. In this study vitamin A designates the fat soluble growth promoting substance as determined in the feeding experi - ments reported by Osborne and Mendel. The gain is being computed by a definite formula. While definite conclusions cannot be drawn from the small number of animals studied, the data obtained seem to indi - cate that the Jersey milk in the quantities fed furnished greater amounts of vitamin A than did similar amounts of Holstein milk. The same, relation is indicated as between the Guernsey and Ayrshire. These results are probably due to the fact that the percentage of fat in the Jersey and Guernsey milk was considerably higher than that of the other two breeds. Milk produced under summer conditions is more effective in producing growth than that produced under winter con - ditions. Attempts to work out a system of feeding whereby the amount of fat would be under control have not been satis - factory. Further studies are necessary. Factors Affecting the Qv/dity of Fluid Milk. — Under this subject a study is made of the daily fat tests, weekly sediment </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 13 tests, and bacteria counts on milk delivered from various farms. Studies are also made of the sanitary methods obtain - ing on the various farms, in order to determine the various factors influencing the quality of milk and the possibilities for improvements. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Corn Breeding. — During the past year the major portion of the work on this project has been the development of pure line strains and their hybridization and recombination. Two hundred inbred strains are undergoing development. These represent 11 varieties secured from several sources. They have been selfed for periods of 3 to 14 years. The object is to have pure line strains representing various degrees of earliness and size, so that hybrids may be produced which are suitable for different parts of the State. Various combinations of some of the pure lines have been compared with each other and with the original commercial varieties. These hybrids have consisted of F x single crosses, Fi double crosses, F, double double crosses, and restored synthetic varieties. Many of these hybrids have been studied in the F 2 generation to observe segregation of characters, etc. Several of the better F, hybrids appear to yield 10 to 15 per cent more than the original corn. No F&gt; hybrids have been found to yield satisfactorily, and average about 60 per cent as high as the F, crop. This is practically the same yield as that secured from corn that has been selfed for the first time. The pure line strains and hybrids differ materially in disease resistance, suckering, yield, etc. Varieties have been obtained from many sources and grown in comparison for the purpose of observing in what char - acteristics corn differs in relation to the environmental fac - tors to which it has become acclimatized. These and other varieties have been hybridized for a study of the inheritance of plant characteristics exhibited by commercial varieties. All hybrids and parent varieties are compared for yield and agricultural value. The behavior of commercial varieties and pure lines under hybridization is compared in both the first and the second generation. A comparison of various lots of seed which had been selected according to various recommended practices for high germination, freedom from disease, and type, has been con - tinued. All indications are to the effect that any practice </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of seed selection which leads to a satisfactory germination and to high adaptedness and broad breeding may be followed in farm practice. Water Requirements of Crops. — The purpose of this pro - ject was to determine the relationship of water transpired to plant characters and to varying environmental factors. The work on this project during the past year consisted of a comparison of 16 pure line (inbred) strains of corn, 8 F t hybrids between pure lines, 8 F 2 hybrids, 4 double crosses, 1 double double cross, and the original commercial variety. From 8 to 16 pots were grown of each strain or hybrid. Very satisfactory growth was obtained, with yields corres - ponding closely with those obtained under field conditions. The inbred strains were found less efficient in their water economy than were the hybrids. This year's work completes 15 years' study of seasonal variations in transpiration in relation to climatic factors. The studies with this project will be discontinued as soon as the data are compiled. Small Grains.— This work has been carried along lines quite similar to those followed in the past, the hybridization phases of the work being somewhat enlarged. Important varieties, strains, and cultural treatment for comparative yields and quality were studied in triplicated field plats. Several improved strains were being extensively grown by farmers of the state. The investigations with winter wheat have been summar - ized and are being published in Research Bulletin No. 31 of the Nebraska Experiment Station. Forage Crops. — Work under this project has continued in a comparison of various kinds of forage crops, varieties, sources of seed, and cultural practices. In a comparison of native grown red clover seed with Italian grown seed, the latter was not found satisfactory. In three-year-old stands of alfalfa where no considerable winter - killing had taken place, alfalfa from several foreign sources winterkilled severely during the winter of 1924-1925. The work with annual forage crops has been assembled and published as Bulletin No. 206 of the Experiment Station. Soil Fertility. — This work has been continued according to the definite plan. Four years' work at the main Station farm and four at the Agronomy Farm did not show any profitable response from applications of commercial fertilizer. Material improvement in yields of small grain have been </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 15 found by applications of barnyard manure. Numerous tests have been carried on in cooperation with farmers of the State. On the whole, results are very similar to those obtained at* the Experiment Station. In Hall County, how - ever, one particular soil showed a response to applications of potash and two to applications of phosphoric acid. Relation of Weather, Cultural Practice, and Soil Conditions to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils. — This project was planned to determine the importance of moisture, temperature, aeration, organic matter, and other fundamental factors in nitrate accumulation in the soil. Satisfactory progress has been made in both the field and the laboratory studies and the following results have been obtained. Many eastern Nebraska soils are so depleted of organic matter and nitrifiable material, either by erosion or by long continued cropping, that nitrate production is slow and may become a limiting factor for small grain. Nitrate production is comparatively slow at 5 degrees of temperature. It increases with temperature, reaching its maximum at 35 degrees and ceasing altogether at 55 degrees. This indicates that the prevailing temperature between the time of late plowing for winter wheat seed bed preparation and May 15 in the spring may be too low to supply adequate nitrate for the crop. Nitrate production is insignificant at moisture contents as low as the hygroscopic coefficient of the soil, but increases with moisture content up to the highest degree of wetness studied, namely, one and one-fourth times the moisture equivalent. Effect of Lime on the Physical Properties of the Soil. — This work has been conducted in both the field and the laboratory. Considerable time has been expended in working out apparatus satisfactory for making physical determinations on soils. The following results have been obtained : Liming materials made no appreciable effect on either the reception or the retention of moisture. Physical studies on two soils in the laboratory do not reveal that any liming material modified the fundamental properties of cohesion, adhesion, or plasticity of the soil, — which are fundamental tilth properties. Soil Acidity. — More than 700 samples of soil for acidity tests have been collected from 200 areas of the State. The </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Drift Hill region of southeastern Nebraska is the most acid region of the State. The Shelby and Carrington loam types in Johnson, Pawnee, and Gage Counties are the most acid soils. The Loess Hill soils are very slightly to medium acid, depending upon the extent to which erosion has laid bare the underlying calcareous subsoil. The Loess Plains soils grow less acid and the calcareous horizon comes closer to the sur - face as rainfall decreases westward, across the state. The soil acidity in Nebraska is due to leaching. The factors determining it are rainfall, original supply of carbonates, age of soil formation, extent of percolation, and the extent of vegetable decay, both in the virgin state and under culti - vation. FRUIT PRODUCTION Pruning Fruit Trees, Grapes, and Small Fruits. — The work under this project has been carried on as previously out - lined. In the apple orchard at Union, trunk diameter measure - ments under various treatments have not shown very con - clusive evidence as yet. On account of some loss among the cherry trees which necessitated replanting in the spring of 1925, the pruning project with cherries has been delayed. In the pruning experiments with grapes, late frost, May 24, 1925, interfered with the crop for this year and some of the proposed phases had to be abandoned. Fruit Breeding. — Very little work was done on this pro - ject during the past season. Some apple and pear seed - lings nearing the fruiting stage were sent to several Experi - ment Stations for test. Plantings of hybrid strawberries at Lincoln in 1924 were seriously injured by dry weather. Frost destroyed practically all of the crop in 1925. Orchard Culture. — This work is being continued, both at the Union Fruit Farm and at the Central Station. At the Union Fruit Farm the work consists largely of terracing, tree growth determination by trunk diameter measurements, and intertillage and cropping of young orchards. At the Main Station the work consists of cultivation and fertilizer studies for fruit trees. During the past year serious blight damage occurred where sodium nitrate was applied and to a lesser extent where ammonium sulphate was applied. Fruit Stocks Investigations. — Under this project several thousand apple stock seedlings and a large number of vari - ties and hybrids are being grown in the nursery. These are being propagated by grafting, root cutting, and layering. A </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Thirty-Ninth Annual Report method of girdling with wire above the graft union is being used to secure scion-rooted trees. The planting of the scion-rooted orchard at Union has been completed. A stocks orchard has been planted at Lincoln to test the value of topworking commercial varieties on Virginia Crab and Hibernal, using both scion-rooted and seedling - rooted trees as stocks. Work is already under way with seedlings from native and commercial varieties of plums, and a greenhouse study of the propagation by cuttings of the sand cherry and its culti - vated hybrids. INSECT CONTROL Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. — The principal work done under this project during the past year has been with the Hessian fly, but minor observations and life history studies have been made on several other pests, particularly the chinch bug. During the past year two observation stations were main - tained for observing the rate of emergence of the main fall brood of the Hessian fly and to determine the date of safe seeding for winter wheat. A great deal of additional infor - mation on the behavior of the main fall brood of the Hessian fly was secured, especially in relation to the influence of mois - ture on emergence. The information was assembled and given wide publicity in order that the farmers might know the safe seeding date. Twenty-six counties cooperated thru their County Agents, and two counties not having agents cooperated thru commercial clubs. The announced dates of safe seeding for the preceding year were checked up in several counties and found to be accurate. A large number of the farmers followed quite closely the announced date for safe seeding, which undoubtedly saved a great deal of wheat from the ravages of this pest and resulted in a large saving to the wheat growers of the State. Cooperative work with County Agents on the construction of barriers to protect cornfields from invasion by chinch bugs was carried out. With the ripening of the small grains the chinch bug migrated to the cornfields. Testing experiments with cyanide dusts were also tried, all of which added materially to our knowledge of chinch bug control measures. Life History of Several Common Cutworms. — During the past year work was continued on this project. Some of the material previously obtained has been assembled for publi- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station cation. An outbreak of the army cutworm in western Nebraska during the past spring presented the opportunity for securing additional data on that pest. Nursery, Orchard, and Greenhouse Inspection. — Work under this project is routine inspection work, as provided in the Nebraska Horticultural Inspection Law. During the past season 50 greenhouses and nurseries within the State have been inspected and certificates granted. LIVESTOCK FEEDING CATTLE Effect of Age and Sex Upon Rate and Economy of Gain. — In previous years the effect of age upon the rate and economy of gain has been studied. Thruout these experiments the younger cattle have made the most efficient use of their feed. This year it was decided to study the factor of sex in addition to that of age. In these experiments eight lots of high grade Hereford cattle were purchased. These consisted of two - year-old steers, two-year-old spayed heifers, yearling steers, yearling spayed heifers, yearling open heifers, and three lots of calves divided into steers, spayed heifers, and open heifers. These cattle were put on feed October 23, and fed for 175 days. All lots received shelled corn and alfalfa hay. So far as the effect of age is concerned the results obtained in this trial checked with the results obtained in previous trials. The calves proved to be more efficient than either the year - lings or the two-year-olds. This applied to both classes, — the spayed and open heifers, as well as the steers. As in previous experiments, the two-year-olds made the most rapid gain. In this class the steers gained more rapidly than the spayed heifers. In the yearling class the open heifers gained more rapidly than either of the other classes, and among the calf classes the steers made the most rapid gain. Figuring corn at $1.12 per bushel and alfalfa hay at $15.00 per ton, the cost of 100 pounds of gain was slightly over $19.00 for the two-year-olds, $18.00 for the yearlings, and from $13.00 to $15.00 for the calves. Fattening Rations for Calves. — In this test four groups of steer calves were put on feed October 28 and fed for a period of 200 days. Lot 1 received shelled corn and alfalfa hay; lot 2 shelled corn, plus 10 per cent linseed meal and alfalfa hay; lot 3 shelled corn, alfalfa hay, with tankage avail - able at will; lot 4 received shelled corn, limited feed, silage </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 19 / full feed, and alfalfa at will. Satisfactory gains were made. The first three lots made better than 2 pounds gain per day, the 4th lot averaging 1.74 pounds per day. To produce 100 pounds of gain, lot 1 required 515 pounds of corn and 304 pounds of alfalfa. Lot 2 required 485 pounds of corn, 48 pounds of linseed meal, and 277 pounds of alfalfa. Lot 3 required 516 pounds of corn, 14 pounds tankage, and 283 pounds of alfalfa. Lot 4 required 345 pounds of corn, 863 pounds of silage, and 270 pounds of alfalfa. Figuring corn at $1.12 per bushel, and oil meal $50, alfalfa hay $15.00, tankage $65.00, and silage $7 per ton, the cost of gain was, — for Lot 1, $12.55 per 100 pounds; Lot 2, $12.97; Lot 3, $12.88; and Lot 4. $11.96 per 100 pounds of gain. Summer Feeding of Steers. — In a 140-day summer steer feeding experiment, three groups of 11 steers each were fed. Lot 1 was fed in a dry lot on shelled corn and alfalfa; Lot 2 received shelled corn and sudan grass pasture ; Lot 3, shelled corn and second-year sweet clover pasture. The gain was practically the same for all lots, being a little more than three pounds per head per day. Figuring corn at 98 cents per bushel, alfalfa hay at $15.00 a ton, and pasture at 3 cents per steer daily, the cost of 100 pounds gain for Lots 1, 2, and 3 was $13.13, $11.97, $12.30 respectively. The dry lot cattle were valued at 20 cents per hundred more than either of the other groups when they went to market. LAMBS Fall Feeding of Lambs. — Under this project two tests were run. In the first test 210 head of western lambs were divided into seven lots for the purpose of obtaining more informa - tion concerning the possibility of utilizing corn supplements and substitutes for fattening lambs. The basic ration was corn and alfalfa hay and the following results were obtained. The addition of .17 pound of linseed meal to the ration resulted in larger and more efficient gains, higher dressing percentage, and larger profits. The addition of corn silage to the basic ration gave sMghtly larger and cheaper gains and slightly more profit per head than the basic ration. Lambs which were fed tankage in addition to the basic ration ate a trifle more corn and made somewhat larger gains with a- little larger profit per head than those receiving corn and alfalfa. The lambs fed barley consumed more feed and made larger and cheaper gains than the corn fed lambs. Where barley was fed during the first half of the feeding period and corn the latter half, the lambs made somewhat </seg>
            <seg id="p020">larger and cheaper gains and more profit per head than where only barley or corn was fed. Spring Feeding of Lambs. — In the second test 126 head of western lambs were divided into six lots and fed for 60 days. The purpose of this experiment was to determine the advisa - bility of feeding alfalfa molasses meal, and in what form corn should be fed when molasses meal is used. Lambs that were fed alfalfa molasses meal were practically self -fed from the various feeds. The addition of the molasses meal was bene - ficial, since the lambs which received this feed made larger and cheaper gains and sold for a higher price than did those lambs which did not receive it. Cracked corn gave better results than either shelled or ground ear corn when fed with molasses meal. The results indicate that it is not necessary to feed fattening lambs alfalfa hay when alfalfa molasses meal is fed during a 60-day feeding period. HOGS t Summer Pig Feeding. — In a test to compare dry lot with sture feeding; to determine the value of tankage with pigs on pasture ; to compare alfalfa with sudan grass pasture ; and to compare full feeding with limited grain rations, — eight lots of pigs with an average initial weight of 61 pounds were fed for a period of 110 days. In this test it was found that corn and tankage self -fed to pigs on alfalfa pasture produced 1.35 pounds daily gain, as compared with 1.09 pounds daily gain for corn and tankage fed to pigs in dry lot. More corn was required, but considerably less tankage, to produce 100 pounds of gain on pasture, but the cost was slightly less than in the dry lot. this test the feeding of tankage increased the gain and iuced the cost of gain ; a pound of tankage saved or re - iced almost four pounds of corn, even on alfalfa pasture. In this test sudan grass compared very favorably with alfalfa for hog pasture. The principal objection to sudan grass is its short grazing season under Nebraska conditions. Pigs on full feed made rapid gains and were ready for market at the close of the summer. Pigs fed a limited amount of grain made more efficient use of their feed than those with more liberal grain allowance, but the increased forage re - quirements offset this saving. The pigs on limited ration during the summer made large and economic gains when placed on full feed. Soybean Meal vs. Tankage. — In a test to compare ground soybeans with tankage as a supplement for corn for fatten- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 21 ing hogs, two lots of pigs were fed for a period of 70 days. Lot 1 was self-fed corn and tankage. Lot 2, self-fed shelled corn, ground soybeans, and bone meal. The tankage fed pigs gained 1.43 pounds daily, as compared with 1.07 pounds for the soybean fed pigs. Figuring the soybean meal at the same price per ton as tankage, 100 pounds gain where tankage is fed costs $7.55, while it cost $8.01, in the case of soybean meal. Winter Feeding. — In a 100-day feeding test, pigs on self - feeders gained at the rate of IV2 pounds per day, while hand fed pigs gained at the rate of 1 1/3 pounds per day, on the same basic rations. The cost of 100 pounds gain was $8.23 for the self-fed pigs and $8.82 for the hand-fed pigs. For pigs on full feed, corn and tankage proved superior to corn and alfalfa. A combination of all the feeds produced slightly larger and more expensive gains than corn and tank - age. Pigs on full feed weighed from 180 to 230 pounds at the close of the 100-day feeding period, while pigs on a limited allowance grew rather than fattened, and weighed from 118 to 145 pounds at the close of the experiment. Pigs fed ground ear corn made the least gain and the most expensive gain of the entire lot. HOME ECONOMICS During the past year two projects have been undertaken in a study of rural home conditions. The first project is a study of the amount of water used per individual and the labor expended in carrying water into and out of the house under rural conditions, where modern water supply is not available. The second project is a study of the lighting systems of farm home where electric or gas lights are not used. The study contemplates the determination of the kind and num - ber of lamps used per household and per person and whether such lighting systems are adequate for the family needs. MILLING AND BAKING QUALITY OF WHEATS As in the two previous seasons, a survey of the past year's wheat crop was made. The samples of wheat obtained were milled and baked by an arbitrary method used in the laborat - ory. The general baking qualities expressed in a single figure were based on loaf volume, texture, and color. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station As is generally true there is considerable variation in bak - ing quality, the average quality being slightly higher than for either of the two previous years. The average protein content for the 151 samples tested was 11.2 per cent. This is about one per cent lower than the average for the two previous years, &lt;tho the baking quality of this year's crop is higher. Apparently the better quality of gluten or protein of the 1924 whe&amp;J; crop more than offset the decrease in quantity. v In this survey the definite ratio between the protein con - tent of the wheat and its baking quality was found. Some samples of decidedly low protein content showed excellent baking quality, while some wheats of high protein content showed relatively poor baking quality. In connection with the milling and baking work some funda - mental studies have been made on the wheat proteins. Some of these studies have been completed and published during the past year. The first, entitled, " Glutenin — A Simple Method for its Preparation and Direct Quantitative Deter - mination," appeared in Cereal Chemistry, Vol. II, pp. 57-67. More work is in progress. The second, " The Individuality of Glutenin," appeared in Cereal Chemistry, Vol. II, pp. 127-131. In this, evidence was presented which refutes a recently pro - posed idea that glutenin in wheat flours is not a chemical individual but a mixture of at least two distinct proteins. During the past year an extended study of the possible appli - cation of Viscosimetric procedure to determine baking strengths of Nebraska wheat flours has been completed. No useful correlation between baking strength and viscosity was found, and it was concluded that either this procedure fails to indicate gluten quality, or some factors other than gluten quality are responsible for the variations in baking strength encountered. These studies have been published in Cereal Chemistry, Vol. II, pp. 191-201. Proteins of Other Grains. — Under this project the pro - teins of grains other than wheats are being prepared and studied, with regard to their respective chemical composition and properties. The glutelins of rye and corn have already been prepared for study and the proteins of this class are being prepared from other cereals for similar study. NUTRITION Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. — The work of the previous year under this project has been assembled and </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 23 «ML9 published as a techincal paper entitled, " A Study of the Phosphorous, Calcium, and Alkaline Reserve of the Blood Sera of Normal and Rachitic Chicks." This paper appeared in the Journal of Biological Chemistry, Vol. LXIII, pp. 75-84. The average content of inorganic phosphorus of the blood serum of 68 normal growing chicks was found to be higher than the average for 66 chicks suffering from rickets. The same was found to be true for calcium in the blood serum of these same chicks. No difference could be detected between the plasma bicarbonate content of normal and rachitic chicks. Neither the water extract nor the expressed juice of fresh green alfalfa prevented the onset of rickets on a diet com - plete save for the antirachitic factor. This is in disagreement with the findings of McCollum with rats. During the past year studies have been made to determine the optimum amount of a standard animal protein concen - trate which should be added to a specific chick ration for most rapid growth during the first nine weeks of the growth period. Incidentally it was planned to compare the nutritive completeness of a simple ration advocated by the Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station with several combinations somewhat more complex. The report of this phase of the work has already been published as Paper No. 12, Journal Series, of this Station. The paper was entitled, " The Pro - tein Requirements of Growing Chicks," and was published in Poultry Science. The following conclusions were reached : Growing chicks can, during the first nine weeks of their growth period, tolerate and even make good use of animal protein concentrates to the extent of 19.5 per cent of the total ration, when added to a mixed ration of corn, wheat, and barley plus minerals. The growth rate was progressively improved as the amount of protein was increased to 10.4 per cent of the total ration. A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding. — The work during the past year has consisted largely of attempts to explain wide apparent vari - ations in nitrogen elimination by birds on a nitrogen-free diet, and to arrive at a satisfactory method for obtaining this figure accurately, since it must be used as a correction when birds are on a protein ration. It has been found that moulting causes great irregularities in the nitrogen meta - bolism of birds, and further study is necessary to explain these more clearly. The addition of cystine was found to increase markedly the utilization of casein ration fed to moult - ing birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station PLANT DISEASES A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. — For the fourth consecutive season experiments on the overwintering of the urediniospores of stem rust of wheat yielded negative results, so that it is safe to conclude that the urediniospores of stem rust of wheat do not overwinter in this section and perhaps not in the entire State. The viability studies of the urediniospores of stem rust of wheat have been closed with the preparation for publication of Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin No. 34. It was found that there is a direct relation between the viability of the urediniospores and temperature and relative humidity. Viable spores capable of producing infection on wheat plants have been held one year at a temperature of 5 degrees C, and at a relative humidity of 50 per cent. While these results have no direct application for field con - ditions, they are valuable in laboratory procedure. During the summer of 1924, stem rust was collected in every county of the state for wheat, barley, wild grasses (some under barberry), etc., in order to determine: what physiological forms are present in Nebraska; whether stem rust spreads from barberry bushes or comes in from the south; whether the same forms are present each year; what form or forms are connected with a rust epidemic; and the correlation between the date and location of the collections and the spread of a form over the State. Likewise the identi - fication of the physiologic forms of stem rust in Nebraska serves as a basis for the selection of rust resistant varieties of wheat adapted to this State. A total of 130 collections were made and the physiological forms of stem rust occurring in these samples were identified. In all, 13 out of 40 physiological forms of Puccinia graminis tritici found in the United States were identified from Ne - braska collections. The Influence of Environmental Conditions on the Trans - mission and Development of Seed Borne Diseases, Including the Potato. — The results of the previous year's work have been published as Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin No. 29. The practical phases of these results are being published as an Extension Circular. Some of the conclusions drawn are as follows: High soil temperature and high soil moisture are found to increase the severity of the tuber symptoms, as to color, </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 25 increased number and shallowness of the eyes, and spindle shape of tuber. At low soil temperatures the symptoms were hardly discernible. Air temperatures had no effect on the tuber symptoms. The symptoms on the top are most evi - dent at an optimum soil moisture for growth of the plants. With high soil moisture the symptoms are somewhat obscured by the luxuriant vine growth. With low soil moisture a small, weak, spindly plant is produced. In identifying the disease a knowledge of the growing conditions for the plant is im - perative. It was found that spindle-tuber transmitted more easily than mosaic and 100 per cent infection was obtained in many experiments. It has already been found that spindle-tuber can be trans - mitted by some means not capable of transmitting mosaic or leaf roll. A survey is being made and experiments conducted in an attempt to determine whether or not insects other than aphids are capable of transmitting spindle-tuber and whether or not the native solanaceous weeds are able to harbor the disease. Transmission experiments and other phases are being continued. The Determination of the Differential Reaction of Puccinia Graminis Tritici. — Work under this project was commenced during the year, the purpose of the project being to analyze commercial varieties of wheat to determine the differential reaction of the component strains to various physiological forms of stem rust which occur in Nebraska. Five hundred seventy-nine pure line selections of Crimean C. I. 1435 were inoculated in the greenhouse with 14 physi - ological forms of Puccinia graminis tritici (identified from 130 collections under Project No. 100). Approximately 100 of the pure line strains were found to be extremely suscep - tible to all 14 forms of the stem rust. Others were sus - ceptible to only 6 of the physiological forms, but no strain among the entire selection was completely resistant to all of the 14 forms. POTATOES Potato Selection for Seed Purposes. — Seed certification has been continued under this project, in cooperation with the Certified Potato Growers Association. Seed trial plats were continued in Louisiana and in western Nebraska. Where rigid inspection has been given, a smaller percentage of disease is showing up in the plantings from such seed. The disease factor seems to be the important one in seed </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station potato production. If disease-free stock is used, good seed potatoes can be produced in any section of Nebraska and under any environmental conditions so far "studied. In a study to determine the most practical date for harvest - ing early potatoes, various lots have beeivharvested at regular intervals from July to October. The results obtained indi - cate that tuber formation practically ceased about the middle of August, but that the tubers continued to increase in weight up to early September. Some of the results obtained under this project are included in Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin No. 207, entitled, " Spindle-Tuber Disease as a Factor in Seed Potato Selection." A Study of Degeneracy in Potatoes. — After definitely con - cluding that the running out of potatoes was due to spindle - tuber, a virulent disease, this phase of the work under this project has been discontinued and future work along this line will be conducted by the Department of Plant Pathology. The results obtained are included in Bulletin No. 207, above men - tioned. Some of the conclusions reached are: 1. That the type of degeneracy occurring in western Ne - braska, causing elongated, poor quality, poor yielding potatoes, is the result of the spindle-tuber disease. 2. That this disease is very prevalent in all potato produc - ing regions of this State and is quite generally distributed thruout the United States. 3. That spindle-tuber is by far the most prevalent and most serious of all potato diseases found in Nebraska at the present time. 4. That spindle-tuber is very readily transmitted, as shown by very conclusive transmission studies with tuber grafts, by infection of alternate plants, and by infection of healthy stock at various distances removed from spindle-tubers in the field. 5. Spindle-tuber may be transmitted very early in the sea - son, for plants exposed only 10 days in 1923 were very seriously infected, whereas plants in cages or in isolated fields remained healthy. 6. Spindle-tuber develops more seriously under some con - ditions than under others. It increased much more rapidly under irrigation than in dry fields, probably due to the more succulent vine growth and better conditions for insect life in the irrigated plats. , 0 7. In eastern Nebraska the disease increased much more rapidly in cultivated than in straw mulched plats. 8. Environmental conditions exert a very great effect upon spindle-tuber symptoms. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 27 POULTRY PRODUCTION Inheritance of Egg Production. — This work was started as a demonstration in breeding for greater egg production. In five years of breeding work with the poultry flock at the Experiment Station, 395 birds have been produced with records of 200 eggs or better. During the entire period one bird has produced 1171 eggs and is still in active production. The plan now is to make the project somewhat more funda - mental, narrowing it down to a definite study of the optimum size of bird for best egg production. The size and weight of the eggs from the birds of the present flock are now on record. Protein Requirements of Growing Chicks. — Under this project it was undertaken to answer the question how much of a packing house by-product should be added to a basal ration of corn, wheat, and oats for optimum growth. The results indicate that growing Single Comb White Leghorns can well utilize meat meal products when these are added up to about 10 per cent of the total ration. There was an im - proved growth rate as the percentage of meat meal was in - creased up to 10 per cent. All the vitamin, mineral, and radiant energy requirements were met in the basal ration which was used for this experiment. A project report on this project has been accepted by the Journal of Poultry Science, for publication. Turkey Production. — This project was undertaken to demonstrate the possibilities of artificial brooding of turkeys and raising them on limited range. The eggs were hatched in incubators and the poults raised in artificial brooders. Satisfactory progress has been made. The first year's work indicates that the young turkeys are even more sensitive to feed deficiencies than growing chicks. It demonstrates that artificial brooding of turkeys is possible and also the necessity for clean feeding and clean yarding. RURAL ECONOMICS Farm Management Survey. — During the year, 150 farm management survey records were obtained. Twenty-six com - plete business records were secured. These records are be - ing analyzed and prepared in such a manner as to show a complete financial statement of the farmers' operations. Cost of Producing Beef Cattle. — This work has been carried on in cooperation with the Federal Government. Five years' records are available and have been analyzed, and </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station mimeographed reports of each year's work have been fur - nished to the cooperators. Farm Tenure. — This work is based on a survey which was made in several rural communities in the state. The data obtained have been assembled and analyzed and different phases of it prepared for publication ; several bulletins have been issued. During the past year two bulletins were pub - lished, No. 202, " Landlords of Nebraska Farms," and No. 205, " Tenure and Farm Investment." Cost of Producing Farm Crops. — This work is carried on in cooperation with farmers. Record books are furnished by the College and the records kept by the farmers. During the year, 69 records were completed and 211 more started. From these records the various factors influencing cost of produc - tion can be obtained. Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and Pur - chasing Power of Farm Products. — During the past year one bulletin, Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin No. 208, entitled, " Hog Prices," was published. This bulletin dis - cussed the factors influencing the price of hogs and the relation of the price of hogs to the price of corn. An Exten - sion Bulletin, entitled, " The Poultry Industry of Nebraska," has also been published. The Farm Land Problem. — This project is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Additional data have been procured and a manuscript based mainly on the land price and mortgage is being prepared. Special tax and mortgage studies are being made. Cooperative Agricultural Organizations. — Under this pro - ject a study of cooperative organizations and cooperative marketing has been made. Part of the material is now in mimeographed form. Cost of Producing Range Cattle. — Work under this project is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. It is proposed to make a complete survey of a number of cattle ranches in the State, this Survey to cover the methods obtaining on the ranches and the cost of producing calves and rearing animals to various ages. A project involving the study of market costs has recently been approved. SERUM PRODUCTION Annual Report of the State Serum Plant for the Year 1925. — The practice of buying and retesting serum was con- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 29 tinued as in years past. Virus is produced at the State Serum Plant in order to insure that it is pure, fresh, and virulent. During the past year there was no serious outbreak of hog cholera in the State and the demand for serum and virus was low. The price during the year has been 70 cents per hun- dred c.c. for serum and $1.00 per hundred c.c. for virus. The following is a complete record of the activities of the plant for the year ending December 31, 1925: Cubic Centimeters Serum on hand January 1, 1925 5,217,675 Serum bought during 1925 3*981,500 Total serum for the year. 9,199,175 Serum and virus sold by months as follows: Virus Serum c.c. c.c. January 12,420 200,450 February 8,620 138,550 March 9,260 161,050 April 8,885 118,750 May 25,355 393,400 June 56,210 868,250 July 45,910 799,000 August 70,040 1,069,500 September 40,915 740.450 October 19,375 339,700 November 14,840 228,300 December 13,450 226,550 325,280 5,283,950 Used at plant 2,500 60,200 Total used and sold 327,780 5,344,150 5,344,150 Serum on hand January 1, 1926 3,855,025 Total gross sales from all sources $41,941.90 Money collected and receipted for 41,977.02 Free balance in fund January 1, 1926, according to report of Bursar $44,495.36 Stock invoice January 1, 1926 26,985.17 Outstanding accounts with County Farm Bureaus.... 1,553.15 Total assets : $73,033.68 Number of pigs used in retesting serum 155 Number of pigs used in making virus 341 Number of orders _ 1,631 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 30 NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION All lines of investigation at the North Platte Substation have made progress during the past year. Climatic conditions were not favorable to crop production and on the whole the season was below the average in production. The physical plant has been kept in a fair state of repair. No improvements of a permanent nature have been made. The gasoline engine used for pumping water for irrigation has been exchanged for an electric motor, which on the whole is proving much more satisfactory. AGRONOMY Cooperative Work. — A considerable portion of the re - search work in crop production is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. The cooperation with the United States Office of Dry Land Agriculture has now con - tinued for 20 years. This work involves various crop rota - tions and tillage practices and a study of their effect upon soil moisture, soil fertility, and crop yields. The crop im - provement work of the Station is in cooperation with the U. S. Office of Cereal Investigation and seeks the development of strains and varieties of better quality, higher yield, and greater resistance than those now obtaining. Crop yields were seriously affected by insufficient moisture and high temperature. These conditions were so extreme that they completely covered the effects of several tillage prac - tices, which frequently produce increased yield. Summer tillage alone showed marked effect. While the amount of moisture carried over by summer Ullage was small, it was enough to support the crops thru the dry period and enable them to make fair yield. The average yields obtained on continuously cropped land and summer tilled land, respec - tively, were: Winter wheat 11.9 and 28.1 bushels per acre Oats 17.7 and 39.4 bushels per acre Corn 14.5 and 35.1 bushels per acre These increased yields from summer tillage over continu - ous cropping were, in percentages, 136 for winter wheat, 122 for oats, and 121 for corn. The 14-year average increase for summer tillage over continuous cropping is, — for winter wheat, 25.7 per cent ; for oats, 23.0 per cent ; and the 19-year average increase of summer tillage for corn is 16.7 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 31 The lowest yields of the year were in those rotations where barnyard manure was applied, indicating an over-stimulation by increased available plant food or a poorer physical con - dition of the soil. The season was such as to show up the detrimental effects of these factors. Moisture Studies. — In the soil moisture studies it was found that in the last eleven seasons 25.4 per cent of rainfall has been stored by summer tillage; that the heaviest losses in moisture storage are by direct evaporation from the upper soil immediately following a rain, and before the water has penetrated the soil sufficiently to escape rapid evaporation at the surface. Crop Improvement. — Sixty-six varieties of small grain were included in these studies. The yields varied widely for all crops. The winter wheat yields were only 43.1 per cent of those obtained in 1924. The highest yields were obtained from Nebraska No. 60, Kharkof and Kanred, respectively; in hardiness the ranking was Nebraska No. 60, Minturki, and Beloglina. In the spring wheats the average yields for the Durum group were 15.3 and for the common wheats 13.6 bushels per acre. The varieties having highest yield were Nodak, Marquis, and Kubanka. The average yields for 15 varieties of barley were 20 bushels per acre, the highest yield. — from Sandrel variety — being 23.7 bushels per acre. Among the oats Markton, a new variety, gave the highest vield ; it is also smut immune. The varietal and varietal cross comparisons of corn were failures on account of the extreme drought. In a comparison of the sorghums and corn, feterita, hegaria, and milo gave the highest grain yields of the sorghums, yielding 44.5, 41.5, and 41.0 bushels per acre, respectively, in comparison with a vield of corn of 27 bushels. Irrigation. — For irrigation the water is pumped from wells with a maximum head of from 50 to 60 feet. In all, 75 acres of land were irrigated from one to five times. The water is raised thru a No. 6 centrifugal pump, with a 40 H.P. elec - tric motor. The electricity cost is on a sliding scale from 7 to 3V2 cents per K.W.H.,. and gave an .average hourly pump - ing cost of 86 cents. \ Basing the increase from supplemental water on the yields where water was not applied, the increased production from irrigation is, — for corn 36.2 bushels, potatoes 252.7 bushels, and alfalfa I 1 /* tons per acre. Maximum yields of 70 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 32 of corn and 500 bushels of potatoes per acre were obtained. The estimated crop produced by supplemental irrigation was 966 bushels of corn, 804 bushels of potatoes, and 22.5 tons of alfalfa, with an estimated value of $1888.00. fFor the irrigation the pump was operated a total of 469 ours, which at an average cost of 85 cents per hour gave a total pumping cost of $403.34. The cost of distributing the water approximates 54 cents per hour the pump was operated, or a total of $253.26. A fixed charge of 18 1/ 2 per cent on $2500.00, the total cost of the plant, is considered sufficient to cover interest on invest - ment, depreciation, and overhead. This gives a total pump - ing cost of $1119.10, leaving a net profit of $768.90. LIVESTOCK Beef Cattle. — The Shorthorn and Hereford purebred herds have been increased by the addition of the females born into the herds. The Shorthorn herd now consists of 22 cows, 11 heifers, and 3 young bulls. The Hereford herd consists of 19 cows, 8 yearling heifers, and 9 heifer calves, besides 10 bull calves and the herd bull. Ready sale at fair prices has been found for the Hereford bulls, but the sale of Shorthorn bulls is slow and at a low price. Dairy Cattle. — At the end of the past fiscal year the dairy herd consisted of 57 females. 2 herd bulls, and 6 male calves under three months old. The progress made over the pre - ceding production records is shown by the following com - parisons. The average production of 15 cows and heifers that completed 365-day periods during the fiscal year of 1924 fas 15,971 pounds of milk and 708 pounds of butter. Dur - g the fiscal year of 1925, 15 cows and heifers averaging in age 4 years and 21 days gave on an average 19,394.7 pounds of milk and 903.80 pounds of butter. The aver - age of the 10 highest producing cows in 1924 was 17,768 pounds of milk and 797 pounds of butter. Comparable figures for 1925 are 20,936.5 pounds of milk and 972.49 pounds of butter. The last year has an advantage over the former year in the age of the cows. There are now in the herd 4 cows that have produced above 1000 pounds of butter in a year with an average of 1099 pounds, 8 cows that have produced above 30 pounds of butter in 7 days with an average of 32.51 pounds, and 10 cows that have produced above 20,000 pounds of milk in a year with an average of 22,526.8 pounds. Many of these are heifers or cows less than 5 years old. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 33 Hogs. — The hog herd consists of about 40 purebred Duroc sows, purebred herd boars, and their offspring. Some of the offspring is sold for breeding purposes, but most of it is used for experimental work in pork production. Cottonseed Meal as a Feed Supplement. — In a single test with six lots of 90-pound shoats, cottonseed meal was found superior to oil meal and equal to tankage as a supplementary feed. When given access to corn and cottonseed meal in self - feeders, the pigs ate 11.3 per cent as much meal as corn. When given both tankage and cottonseed meal in different compartments of the feeder, they ate more of the meal than of the tankage. It is stressed that this is only a single test on this subject. A Comparison of Sudan Grass and Alfalfa. — Three lots of fifteen 75-pound shoats were grazed on sudan pasture and three similar lots on alfalfa. On each pasture one lot was self-fed corn and tankage, one lot self-fed corn alone, and a third lot hand fed a 2 per cent ration of corn. Where both corn and tankage were fed, the results were quite similar to sudan grass and alfalfa. The average daily gain was 1.68 pounds on sudan grass and 1.72 pounds on alfalfa. The corn and tankage requirements on sudan were 381.7 pounds for 100 pounds of gain and on alfalfa 361.6 pounds. Where the grain ration was corn alone, sudan grass proved quite inferior to alfalfa pasture, — the relative daily gains being 1.10 and 1.44 respectively. The amount of corn for 100 pounds gain was 410 pounds on sudan grass and 374.5 on alfalfa. Where the grain ration was reduced to about half of the full ration, the inferiority of sudan grass pasture in comparison with alfalfa was further emphasized, the relative daily gain being .55 and .72 pound respectively. Pasture for Hogs on Full Feed. — In this test thirty 72 - pound spring shoats were self-fed corn, shorts, and tankage in a dry lot for a period of 84 days and a similar lot fed a like ration on alfalfa pasture for a similar period. The aver - age daily gains were 1.52 in the dry lot and 1.53 on alfalfa pasture, which indicates that the kind and quality of forage may have little effect during the fattening period, where pigs are on a full ration. HORTICULTURE AND FORESTRY • Fair crops of cherries and plums were obtained during the year, but no apples. Tip moth has done such serious injury to western yellow pine that it is considered inadvisable to plant many of these </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station species. The injury is confined to trees less than 4 to 6 feet in height. Austrian pine appears to be the most satis - factory conifer for windbreaks and forest planting, with Scotch pine following second. Black Hills spruce continues in favor as an ornamental conifer, but when planted thickly did not withstand the severe drought of this section. Among deciduous trees the hackberry, elm, honey locust, and cotton wood held first place. Two new elms, the Chinese and Turkestan, give promise as ornamental or shade trees. Among the ornamental shrubs the spirea, honeysuckle, syringa, and lilac are hardy sorts. SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION The work of this Station is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. It is designed to study the pro - blems of irrigated farming. The principal lines under investi - gation in crop production are rotation, soil fertility, cultural practices, plant diseases, and pastures. The work in live - stock consists of pasture and feeding tests with steers, sheep, and hogs, together with dairy and poultry work. Crop Rotation. — The crop rotation work is laid out on a permanent basis and continues from year to year. The ro - tations include many combinations from continuous cropping to a seven-year rotation containing four crops. Some rotations contain alfalfa, a few sweet clover, and some receive barnyard manure at regular intervals. The outstanding feature of the work is the increased yield obtained either by the use of barnyard manure or by a crop sequence including a leguminous crop. During the past year, yields of potatoes, sugar beets, and oats were increased by about 80 per cent thru applications of barnyard manure. The yields of these same crops together with corn and wheat were fully doubled where they followed alfalfa in the rota - tion, as compared with unmanured plats, showing clearly that soil fertility is a very important factor in crop produc - tion on these soils. Soil Fertility. — The question of soil fertility appears to be largely one of organic and nitrogen content of the soil, rather than of a deficiency in mineral plant foods. In a comparison of applications of commercial fertilizers and barnyard manure the commercial plant food gave practically no in - crease in crop yields, while barnyard manure applied at various rates gave materially increased yields. In a study of the proper rate of application of manure, 12 tons was found more profitable for immediate yields than </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 35 larger amounts. The carry-over effect of the manure as shown in the increased yields of second, third, and fourth year cropping was in direct ratio with the amount of manure applied. It is recommended, however, that the manure be spread at 10 to 12 tons per acre, rather than heavier dressings. Tillage. — In a comparison of plowing and disking as a prep - aration for beets on potato land, the beets on plowed land gave about IV2 tons more per acre than those on disked land. The stand of beets was almost in direct ratio with the yield, the poorer stand being on the disked land, where weeds caused a great deal more trouble than on the plowed land. Pastures. — The work with the tame grass pastures has continued as in previous years. Additional work has been done in using sweet clover as a temporary pasture. For this purpose sweet clover has been found satisfactory for dairy cows, steers, or sheep. Being less subject to injury from grasshoppers than alfalfa, this crop is being more and more used. Its beneficial effect on the following crop is about the same as with alfalfa. Dairying. — The dairy herd at the Station consists of about 12 milking cows and a purebred sire. Approximately one - half of the cows are purebred. The herd has shown great improvement during the past year. The average yearly pro - duction is 335.5 pounds of butterfat. The cows are kept strictly under farm conditions, with no attempt to crowd them for higher records. The better bulls from the purebred cows are loaned to farmers in the Valley who have organized themselves into bull associations. At the present time some 45 farmers, with a total of 300 cows, are organized into 8 such associations, each having a purebred bull loaned to them from the Experi - ment Station. It is felt that these bulls will be an import - ant factor in improving the grade of dairy cattle and in the development of the dairy industry in this section. Hogs. — From 15 to 20 purebred brood sows are kept in the Station herd. These are used for both fall and spring farrowing. Some of the pigs produced are sold to farmers for breeding purposes, while others are used in pork produc - tion tests, including alfalfa pasturing, dry lot feeding, and heavy and light grain rations. Lamb Feeding. — Each winter for the past five years western lambs have been purchased on the market and fed various rations. The feeds used are mainly those produced locally and include corn, barley, beet pulp, beet tops, beet top </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 36 silage, and culled potatoes, with commercial concentrates of oil and cottonseed cake. During the past year 13 lots of 25 lambs each were fed. The lambs cost $12.70 per hundred in Denver and $13.33 per hundred in the feed lot, the initial weight being an average of 59 pounds per lamb for each lot. The lambs were fed 130 days and at the close of the experi - ment were appraised at from $16.15 to $16.85 per hundred. The lowest gain, an average of 23 pounds per lamb, was made with the lot receiving dry pulp, containing 15 per cent molasses, and hay. The greatest gain, an average of 39 pounds per lamb, was made by the lot receiving corn, cotton - seed cake, and beet tops. Figuring the various feeds at their average market value during the period, the greatest profit per lamb, $2.77, was made by the lot receiving dry pulp, Sttonseed cake, and hay, and the least profit, $1.42 per head, the lot receiving corn, cottonseed cake, and silage. Poultry. — In the poultry flock three breeds of chickens are kept, — Buff Orpingtons, Single Comb Rhode Island Reds, and Single Comb White Leghorns. About 200 laying hens of all breeds are kept. The object of the poultry work is to demonstrate what a farm flock will do under proper manage- Sent and also to furnish breeding stock for the farmers of e Valley. A project is also under way in turkey production. Ninety - three turkeys were produced from six hens. These made satisfactory growth and showed a nice profit when sold. There is a widespread interest in the poultry work thruout the Valley. VALENTINE SUBSTATION The work of this Station is continued along lines of pre - vious years. The cooperative work has been extended over iarger territory and by the addition of new phases of work. The past season was so dry that some of the crop production work at the Station was a failure. The average yields were the lowest of any during the past five years. Small Grains. — Winter and spring wheat gave about the same yields and were relatively low. Rye gave a lower yield than winter wheat. In pounds of grain per acre, wheat and oats ranked first, rye second, barley third, and emmer the lowest. Kubanka spring wheat, Kanred winter wheat, and Nebraska No. 21 oats were the leading varieties. Corn. — A very low yield of corn was obtained at the Station. In comparative tests on the type of corn, the smooth type produced 10 per cent more than the rough type, with seed </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirt*-p.inth Annual Report 37 selected from 12 different cribs. The indications are, how - ever, that few farmers are growing too rough a type for maximum yields. Miscellaneous Crops. — Soybeans as a forage crop were a failure and for grain production have not been sufficient to warrant advocating their production. This year artichokes were planted on the subirrigated land in the Valley and produced approximately 10 tons per acre. Further work is contemplated with them, possibly including a feeding test. Sorghum Varieties. — The saccharin sorghums produced 60 per cent more forage than the grain sorghums. A little grain was produced from kaoling, milo, and feterita. Ordinary cane produced 60 per cent more hay than was produced from sudan grass. Forage crops that were drilled in 7-inch rows pro - duced very low yields; amber cane made almost double as much hay when drilled in rows wide enough for cultivation. Meadow Investigations. — The introduction of red and alsike clover into the subirrigated meadows of this region increases the production of hay from 50 to 100 per cent. Where the clover is cut twice during the season the increase is even greater. The greatest increase was from mammoth red, next from alsike, and third from medium red clover. The season was very severe for seeding clover, especially where it was attempted to seed it into the native sod. Seed - ing with the drill was superior to broadcasting. Ten varieties of grasses and legumes seeded on hay land failed on account of drought. In the water table studies the water table was the lowest in October of any time during the past four years. Dairy Herd. — The dairy herd is showing steady improve - ment. This is being brought about largely thru the use of better sires. Seven grade Shorthorn cows and a purebred milking strain Shorthorn bull have been added to the herd. ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT During the past year approximately 176 acres of land were purchased near the Agronomy Farm. This land is some three mlies from the central station. Its purchase will enable the Station to transfer some of its livestock work from the Main Station and to carry some lines of investigation which have not been possible with the limited amount of land previously available. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 38 Contract has been let for the building of a small cottage at the Valentine Station. This will make possible the keep - ing of another permanent man on the Station. Plans have been adopted for a new dairy barn, shed, and yards at the Main Station. These are somewhat more re - moved from the College Campus than were the older build - ings. At the North Platte Station the roads around the main buildings have been graveled and partially curbed. NEEDS OF THE EXPERIMENT STATION Among the urgent needs of the Experiment Station in physical equipment are barns, sheds, and fences at the out - lying farm near Lincoln, and at the North Platte Station a beef cattle barn, new corral fences, and a small cottage and barn on the tableland. These improvements are necessary to the greatest efficiency of these plants. As above mentioned, the investigational work is limited by the personnel and resources of the Station. The present re - sources are used as efficiently as can be done. If it is desired to undertake new lines of investigation or to increase the work along any lines now under way, additional funds are necessary. NEW LEGISLATION No new legislation has been enacted affecting the work of the Experiment Station. CHANGES IN STAFF There were no changes in staff during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1925. PUBLICATIONS Three classes of publications are issued by the Agricul - tural Experiment Station giving the results of the various lines of investigation. These are — station bulletins, research bulletins, and circulars. A station bulletin contains a definite report of some particular investigations. The data obtained are presented in a manner readily understood by the average reader. Research bulletins give more detailed reports of in - vestigations, and the information is of more technical nature. Circulars are either popular reports of experimental work or summaries of the best information obtainable on particular lines of work. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 39 As the bulletins are published, announcement is made to the public, and they may be obtained free of cost by writing to the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station. In addition to the publications put out by the Experiment Station, numerous articles, generally of a technical nature, have been written by members of the Station Staff and pub - lished in technical journals. The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Thirty-eighth Annual Report, by the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station. 2,000 copies. BULLETINS No. 205, Tenur eand Farm Investment in Nebraska, J. O. Rankin, 5,000 copies. February, 1925. No. 206, Annual Forage Crops, T. A. Kiesselbach and Arthur Ander - son. 6,000 copies. April, 1925. No. 207, The Spindle-tuber Disease, H. O. Werner, 10,000 copies. April, 1925. No. 208, Hog Prices, H. C. Filley. 5,000 copies. May, 1925. No. 209, Co-operative Marketing of Livestock in Nebraska, Harold Hedges and H. C. Filley. 4,000 copies. December, 1925. RESEARCH BULLETINS No. 29, Further Studies on the Effect of Environment on Potato Degeneration Diseases. R. W. Goss and George L. Peltier. 4,000 copies. January, 1925. No. 30, An Inquiry into the Cause of the Increase of Tuberculosis in Swine, L. Van Es and H. M. Martin. 6,000 copies. February, 1925. No. 31, Winter Wheat Investigations, T. A. Kiesselbach. No. 32, Spindle-tuber as a Factor in Seed Potato Production, H. O. Werner. No. 33, The Immediate Effect of Gametic Relationship and of Par - ental Type upon the Kernel Weight of Corn, T. A. Kiesselbach. Accepted for publication. No. 34, A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. George L. Peltier. 4,000 copies. October, 1925. No. 35, A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. George L. Peltier. 4,000 copies. November, 1925. EXPERIMENT STATION CIRCULARS No. 25, Tuberculosis of Swine, L. Van Es. 10,000 copies. Febru- No. 26, These Fifty Years, Robert P. Crawford. 3,000 copies. June, 1925. No. 27, List of Available Publications. 5,000 copies. July, 1925. No. 28, The Chinch Bug and its Control, M. H. Sw«nk. 5,000 copies. June, 1925. 636522 A </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station No. 29, Feeding the Dairy Cow, H. P. Davis. 5,000 copies. July, No. 30, Dairy Calf Care and Management, H. P. Davis and R. F. Morgan. 5,000 copies. July, 1925. No. 31, Selection, Breeding, Methods, Means More Milk, H. P. Davis. 20,000 copies. August, 1925. No. 32, Hardy Alfalfa for Nebraska, T. A. Kiesselbach and Arthur Anderson. 5,000 copies. August, 1925. No. 33, Better Rations — More Eggs, F. E. Mussehl. 10,000 copies. October, 1925. TECHNICAL PAPERS The Chromosome Number of Maize, T. A. Kiesselbach and N. F. Peterson. Genetics. January, 1925. The Occurrence of Starch and Erythrodextrin in Maize and Their Segregation in the Pollen of Hybrids, T. A. Kiesselbach and N. F. Peterson. Genetics. January, 1925. Effect of Low Temperature on Hatching Power of Hens' Eggs, F. E. Mussehl and Paul Bancroft. Poultry Science. January, 1925. A Study of the Phosphorus, Calcium, and Alkaline Reserve of Blood Sera of Normal and Rachitie Chicks, C. W. Ackerson and M. J. Blish. Journal Biological Chemistry. February, 1925. Two New Soil Thermometers, J. C. Russell and E. G. Jones. Journal American Society of Agronomy. February, 1925. Glutenin — A Simple Method for its Preparation and Direct Quanti - tative Determination, M. J. Blish and R. M. Sandstedt. Cereal Chem - istry. March, 1925. The Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks, F. E. Mussehl. Poultry Science. March. 1925. Studies on the Moisture Equivalent of Soils, J. C. Russel and W. W. Burr. Soil Science. April, 1925. Report of Certain Investigations on the Central Nebraska Supple - mental Irrigation Project, W. W. Burr and J. C. Russel. Fifteenth Annual Report of the Department of Public Works. The Relation of Environment to Spindle-Tuber Symptoms, H. O. Werner. Proceedings of the Eleventh Annual Meeting of the Potato Association of America. April, 1925. The Temperature and Moisture Factors in Nitrate Production, J. C. Russel, E. G. Jones, and G. M. Bahrt. Soil Science. May, 1925. The Individuality of Glutenin, M. J. Blish. Cereal Chemistry. May, 1925. Viscosity Studies with Nebraska Wheat Flours. M. J. Blish. Cereal &lt; hemistry. July, 19ZB"? A Fumigation Room for Farm Crops Laboratory Supplies, F. D. Keim. Journal American Society of Agronomy. October, 1925. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly news papers, especially those papers located within the state, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by giving liberal space to the experimental work re - ported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-Ninth Annual Report 41 THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1925, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 Total $15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1925, under act of Congress, approved March 16, 1906. Total $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 Total $15,000.00 L. E. GUNDERSON, At Lincoln, Nebraska, Finance Secretary. January 22, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT— (Continued) Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1925 (exclusive of Federal funds). SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees $40,865.84 Temporary employees 3,252!95 Total. $ 44,118.79 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 759.79 Laboratory Supplies 7,700.63 Food stuff 1,855.38 Educational and recreational 269.16 269.16 Janitor and barn supplies 188.85 Agricultural supplies and feed ". 32,594.20 Total. $ 43,368.01 EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ 700.81 Freight expense and dray 944.77 Water, heat, light, power, and fuel ., 4,270.52 Public printing, adv. and photo 4,817.84 Traveling expense 3,019.79 Rentals 474.78 Special and temporary services 18,389.98 Miscellaneous 552.99 Total 171.48 REPAIRS Buildings $ 2,675.09 Lands 134.97 Equipment 3,326.80 Total $ 6,136.86 EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures $ 717.14 Apparatus (labor and equipment) 3,286.18 Livestock 14,228.99 Machinery 3,717.15 Books 374.97 Total $ 22,324.43 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land improvements : $ 767.61 Original construction 30.00 Addition and improvements 1,704.69 Total $ 2,502.30 FIXED CHARGES Refunds and redemptions $ 17.65 Total :. $ 17. 6 5 * Grand total $151,639.52 This includes expenditures for the central station at the Agricul- tural Campus and the substations at Scottsbluff, North Platte, and Valentine. L. E. GUNDERSON, ' At Lincoln, Nebraska, Finance Secretary. January 22, 1926. [2500] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>