<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00047.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00047.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Condensed Report of the Board of Control Capitol Building Lincoln</title>
               <date value="1921-07-01">1921-07-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Condensed Report OF THE Board of Control CAPITOL BUILDING LINCOLN L. C. OBERLIES, Chairman July 1, 1921 KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Member A. E. ALLYN, Member </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 INSTITUTIONS UNDER CONTROL OF THE BOARD Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Beatrice Dr. S. J. Stewart, Superintendent Girls' Industrial School Geneva (Miss) Lena E. Ward, Superintendent Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors' Home Burkett, (Grand Island) Addison Wait, Commandant Hastings State Hospital Ingleside Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent State Industrial School Kearney R. V. Clark, Superintendent Hospital for Tuberculous Kearney Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent (Miss) M. Evelyn Meyer, Superintendent Soldiers and Sailors' Home Milford illors' Home J. O. Moore, Commandant J. O. Moore, Commandant Nebraska School tor the Blind Nebraska City [ for the Blind N. C. Abbott, Superintendent N. C. Abbott, Superintendent Norfolk State Hospital Norfolk ospital Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superintendent Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superintendent Nebraska School for the Deaf Omaha 1 for the Deaf F. W. Booth, Superintendent F. W. Booth, Superintendent State Reformatory for Women York ry for Women Dr. Alma J. Chapman, Superintendent Dr. Alma J. Chapman, Superintendent Nebraska Home for Dependent Children Lincoln for Dependent Children (Miss) Amy V. Stevens, Superintendent State Reformatory for Men . .Lincoln A. W. Miller, Superintendent rln State Hospital Lincoli Dr. D. G. Griffiths, Superintendent Orthopedic Hospital Lincoli Dr. J. H. Matthai, Superintendent itate Penitentiary Lincoli W. T. Fenton, Warden IHandcraft Furniture Company (State Penitentiary) ...Lincoln L. M. Eastman, Manager lebraska Industrial Home Milton </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF CONTROL 3 THE BOARD OF CONTROL Lincoln, Nebraska The Board of Control was established by a constitutional amendment adopted by the people, and was organized for busi - ness on July 1, 1913. It consists of three members, appointed by the governor for six year terms, so arranged that the term of one member expires every two years. The member whose term is first to expire, automatically becomes chairman. The original amendment designated the organization as the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, but this long and cumbersome title was shortened in 1920. It is required that no two members of the Board come from the same congressional dis - trict and that not over two belong to the same political party. There are seventeen institutions under control of the Board, as shown in the list on the preceding page. This number includes the State Reformatory for Men established by the last legislature. This institution is intended for the reception of first offenders un - der 30 years of age and over 16 years at time of commitment. It is the intention to teach these young men various trades, while keeping them segregated from the older men of the penitentiary whose habits are more permanently fastened upon them. At this time (July 1, 1921) there are 5589 wards of the state in the various institutions. During the beinnium which ended Nov. 30, 1920, this inmate population averaged 4980, and there was ex - pended for the maintenance of these the sum of $3,675,460.55. Owing to the decrease in cost of living, it is earnestly hoped by the Board to make a very decided cut in maintenance cost during the present biennial period. In fact, it will be necessary to do so if the limits of the appropriations made by the last session of the legislature are to be observed. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 At its various institutions the state has a little over 4000 acres of land, of which over 3500 acres are in farm and garden. A more detailed report of the agricultural activities at the differ - ent institutions is given in the pages following. NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR THE FEEBLE MINDED Beatrice, Nebraska Dr. S. J. Stewart, Superintendent This institution was established in 1885. It is a home and school for feeble-minded, regardless of age. It was originally in - tended for feeble-minded children only. Admission is confined to residents of the state and is had through commitment by juvenile or county court. Complaint may be filed by any bona fide resident or superintendent of any public or charitable institution. This complaint must be accompanied by the certificate of a physician. The parent, husband or guardian of any person committed shall pay $40.00 per year for clothing for each inmate if financially able, otherwise the county shall pay. There are 303 acres of land owned by the institution and other land is rented. 260 acres are under cultivation. Farming and stock raising are the principal industries. The school is maintained for those capable of being improved by such instruction in the common branches. This also includes manual training, music, domestic science, and needle work. There are at this time 57 employees ; the inmate population has grown from 607, which was the average for the biennium end - ing November 30, 1920, to 663. In addition to this number, there are 140 applications awaiting admission. During the same biennium the yearly per capita expense was $273.09, a total for the biennium of $331,533.35. New buildings are being erected to accomodate the increasing population. . The institution is remarkably free from sickness or epidemic and affords both home and school for the inmates. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OP CONTROL 5 GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL Geneva, Nebraska (Miss) Lena E. Ward, Superintendent From the year 1879 to the year 1891, girls as well as boys were sent to the Kearney School, but in the latter year, by legislative provision, the Geneva institution was established. It is a school for delinquent girls and at present it has a population of 147, with employees numbering 14. The average inmate population for the last bienniuni was 10G. During the same period the yearly per capita cost was $505.81, a total maintenance cost of +107,232.03 for the two-year period. There are 70 acres of ground connected with the school, of which 8 are used as a campus about the buildings. Admission to the school is by commitment by court of com - petent jurisdiction and girls are required to remain until they are 21 years old, unless sooner released by parole or otherwise. While in the institution, the girls are required to attend classes, and are also instructed in sewing, laundering and house - keeping duties. They are, of course, likewise given instruction and friendly admonition along moral lines. The influence and tone of the school are wholesome. The land that is devoted to farm and garden is cultivated ex - clusively by the girls who evince great interest in this work. Just as an instance it may be stated that during the past season the girls put up canned fruits and vegetables to the extent of several thousand quarts, besides doing their regular work in kitchen and bakery. The products of the garden, farm and cannery win many prizes at fairs and similar exhibitions. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 CONDENSED REPORT OF NEBRASKA SOLDIERS AND SAILORS' HOME Burkett, Nebraska Addison Wait, Commandant SOLDIERS AND SAILORS' HOME Milford, Nebraska The soldiers' home at Burkett was established in 1887, on a section of land near the city of Grand Island. It now has 67 offi - cers and employees, with 364 members. The average membership during the last biennium was 409 ; the annual per capita cost was $390.77, making a total maintenance cost of $319,648.05 for the two years. I The home on the Blue river, near Milford, started with an eage of 38, to which has recently been added 3 acres. The sent population is 32 officers and employees and a membership 157. The latter averaged 148 during the biennium, in whicli :0,378.57 was expended, the yearly per capita cost being $474.25. Honorably discharged soldiers, sailors, marines, and hospital nurses, who have become disabled from age or otherwise, are eligible to membership in the homes. The latter are also open to wives and mothers of ex-soldiers as well as the widows and mothers of those who died in the service, who have reached 50 years of age and are unable to earn a livelihood. Applicants for admission must also be bona fide residents of Nebraska of at least two years' standing. Applications are made to the county board of the county of residence on blanks furnished by the county clerk. Applicants must be unable to earn a liveli - hood or be dependent upon public or private charity, although the amount of pension received has no bearing in determining this But little farming is attempted at the Milford home, owing to the limited ground, but at the Burkett institution farm opera - tions are conducted on a quite extensive plan. The veteran mem - kpi« ot t"Ti p "FTom p^ jit*p of i"* on t*^»p n ot pxm*f*f f*d to work J. 0. Moore, Commandant </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF CONTROL 7 LINCOLN STATE HOSPITAL Lincoln, Nebraska Dr. D. G. Griffiths, Superintendent HASTINGS STATE HOSPITAL Ingleside, Nebraska Dr. Wm. S. Fast, Superintendent NORFOLK STATE HOSPITAL Norfolk, Nebraska Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superintendent Of the three hospitals for the treatment of mental diseases, the one at Lincoln is by far the oldest, having been established in ]870. This institution has a section of land near the capital city, of which over 500 acres is in farm, and over 100 in garden and orchard. At present there are 129 officers and employees and 946 pat - ients at the Lincoln hospital. During the last biennium, the aver - age number of patients was 837, entailing an expense of $513, - 231.48, an annual per capita cost of $306.59. The Hastings State Hospital, founded in 1887, is the largest institution in Nebraska. At present there are 1179 patients, re - quiring the services of 158 officers and employees. During the last biennium this institution cost the state for maintenance $649, - 993.35, the yearly per capita cost being $282.12 for an average of 1152 patients. Almost a section of farm land (623 acres) is connected with this hospital, and quantities of grain and livestock are raised. The Norfolk State Hospital is located on 455 acres of land in Madison County, of which 400 are in farm and garden, giving em - ployment to many patients and raising large crops, both of grain and vegetables. This institution, which was established in 1885, now main - tains a staff of 91 officials and employees for the care of 696 patients. The number of the latter averaged 646 for the last biennium. The annual per capita cost was $315.91, entailing a total maintenance expense of $408,164,93. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">■ Admission to the hospitals for the treatment of mental dis - eases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL Kearney, Nebraska E. V. Clark, Superintendent tThis institution received attention from some of the early slative sessions of the state, and was finally established in ). For some yean girls as well as boys were admitted to the &gt;ol, but in 1891 a separate institution for girls was started at eva. tThe Kearney school has 602 acres of ground, all excepting it 60 being vised for farm and garden. In addition to agricul , the 241 boys now at the school receive manual training along most approved modern lines. There is a well-equipped print - plant, which is in need, however, of a linotype machine. The ting for all of the institutions is done at this institution and le school for the deaf. Ettendance at classes is required during nine months of the •, an efficient corps of teachers being in charge. A ooiiiiner - training course is also offered to those going into business life, al and spiritual training is offered through the medium of rch and Sunday school. Admission to the school is through commitment by court and is confined to sane boys under 18 found guilty of crime (except homicide), or boys under 16 who are beyond parental control. Boys are required to remain until 21 years of age, unless sooner released by court order or paroled by the Superintendent. During the last biennium the average number of boys was 217, and the total maintenance charge $203,84:6.71, being an an - nual per capita cost of $469.69. The number of employees and officials at present is 37. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF CONTROL. 9 HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS Kearney, Nebraska This is one of the newer institutions of the state, having been established in 1911. There are at present 33 offieers and employees caring for 100 patients at this hospital. During the last biennium, there was expended a per capita eost of $653.48 per year, making a total of $101,943.17, the average number of patients being 78 during the period named. Owing to the nature of the institution, no extensive efforts are directed to farming, and of the 34 acres, only about 10 are in garden, the balance being campus. Admission to the Hospital for Tuberculous is had on full and detailed report from a practising physician of the state, made to the superintendent of the institution. The expense of the patients' examination is borne by the county of residence when not other - wise paid for. "Pay patients" may be admitted provided there is room for them. "In recent months," says the Superintendent in a report to the Board, "the institution has been filled to capacity and most of the time we have had quite a large waiting list. At times we could have accomodated a few more patients if applicants had been of the incipient type. The trouble is that we have entirely too many requests for the admission of far advanced cases." At the last legislative session $100,000.00 was appropriated for a new fire-proof hospital building at this institution, and it is expected that the completion of this will see a marked enlarge - ment of the usefulness of this most valuable institution. During the biennium 66 soldiers and sailors were admitted, the government paying for their keep as well as maintaining a school for their benefit. ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL Lincoln, Nebraska (Succeeded by Dr. J. II. Matthai, Superintendent) As might quite naturally be expected, the per capita cost of maintaining the Orthopedic Hospital is greater than that of any Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 other of the state 's institutions. During the past bieimiuni, when the patients averaged 64 in number, the state expended for these wards, $156,955.97, an annual per capita cost of $1,226.22. At present there afe 49 officers and employees and 84 patients. This institution was established in 1905 and is located on nearly three acres of ground at 11th and South streets in Lincolu. Application for admission must be accompanied by statement from a physician describing the condition of the patient. As preference is given to indigent cases, a statement is also required as to the financial status of the patient or his relatives. The Board of Control may admit "pay patients" if there is plenty of room and if the Superintendent thinks the treatment will benefit such patients. » Examination expenses, as well as those of transportation to from home, and cost of clothing, must be paid by the patient, friends or relatives, or by the county. Children are given the benefit of continuing their school work and classes are conducted for all grades of the common school. This class work is supplemented by industrial work and all per - sons at the hospital have access to the adequate library which is maintained by the state library commission. I A training school for nurses, fully accredited, is operated at hospital, entrance requirements being the same as those of recognized hospital. A class has been graduated from this school every year since 1908. The last legislature made provision for a new x-ray machine to replace the one that has been in use since the establishment of the hospital. It is expected that this equipment will fill the pres - ent-day needs of diagnosis. STATE PENITENTIARY Lincoln, Nebraska W. T. Fenton, Warden This institution is located three miles south of Lincoln and is surrounded by 416 acres of land of which all but 18 acres are under cultivation. It was established in 1869, being next to the oldest institution owned by the state. .There are at present 618 inmates at the penitentiary, and 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF CONTROL, 11 officers and employees. The average number of inmates was 363 during the last biennial period, the total maintenance cost being $365,809.63, an annual per capita expense to the state of $503.87. Inmates are allowed good time for exemplary conduct as fol - lows : two mouths on the first year, two months on the second, three on the third, and four on each year thereafter. Additional good time is also allowed for attendance at school. The indeterminate sentence applies to nearly all felonies, and the parole law and its enforcement are therefore of prime import - ance. The constitutional convention created, and the voters sub - sequently ratified, the provision for a parole and pardon board, composed of the governor, secretary of state, and attorney gen - eral, thus relieving the governor of an individual burden. The legislature has given the Board of Control authority to work on the highways such men as are deemed safe and suit - able, and the Department of Public Works has established sev - eral camps at which the men are employed with marked success. Provision is made for the men to assist in the support of any de - pendents they may have. The Handcraft Furniture Company is an organization at the prison and the workmen are all inmates. The furniture market has been a little slow for some months, but during the bienniura ending November 30, 1920, the total sales of finished products v mounted to $295,057.68. Both Protestant and Catholic services are conducted at the prison, and Sunday school classes are also held. Christian Science services are likewise attended by quite a few of the men. An ex - cellent library furnishes a wide range of reading. NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME Milford, Nebraska This institution, established in 1887, has at present an inmate population of 86, with 11 officers and employees. During the last biennium the census showed an average of 73 inmates who were maintained at a total cost of $74,700.98, being a yearly per capita cost of $511.65. This is one of the state's institutions, the workings of which (Miss) M. Evelyn Meyer, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 are not shouted from the housetops but that prove indeed a great blessing in many cases. Besides "shelter and protection," the statutes describe the objects of the Home to be to "provide em - ployment and means of self support to penitent women and girls, with a view to aid in the suppression of prostitution." To provide suitable homes for the children born at the Home, the Superintendent and the Board of Control may consent to the adoption of any child relinquished by its mother. Applications for admission are made to the Superintendent, and no information is given out as to the name or identity of any applicant or inmate. Domestic Science is one of the chief studies at the home, and the institution's sewing room is a busy place. During the canning season there is also much extra work done in the kitchen. During last biennium there were over 3,000 quarts of various edibles put up by the girls. A great deal of attention is paid to the moral and religious in - struction of the women and girls, and they seem to evince a great interest in Sunday school work and other labors intended for their spiritual betterment. ■ There are 40 acres in connection Avitli the home, 25 of which in farm and garden. * s NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND Nebraska City, Nebraska N. C Abbott, Superintendent K Founded in 1875, this interesting institution maintained an rage of 47 pupils during the last biennium at a yearly per ita cost of $719.42 — a total expense for the period of $67, - 625.41. The employees at this time number 23. The institution is open during the school year to such bona fide residents of Nebraska as are of suitable age and capacity who by reason of their disability cannot attend the common schools. Clothing, transportation to and from school, and support during vacation periods must be paid for by parent or guardian. If the parent or guardian is unable to pay, or if the pupil is of age and indigent, the county shall pay such expenses. The object of the school, in the language of the statutes, is "physical, moral, and intellectual culture and training" so that </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF CONTROL. 13 the pupils "may be returned to society capable of becoming self - sustaining and useful citizens." The Board of Control is authorized by law to keep as far as practicable a complete register of blind persons in the state; to provide home teaching when necessary; to assist in finding em - ployment for blind workers; to make loans to worthy blind men to carry on business or take advanced studies, and to collect and disseminate information as to the cause, cure and prevention of blindness. The moral and religious welfare of the pupils is looked after to a great extent by the "Golden Rule Society," composed of members of the institution. The superintendent speaks most highly of the results of the work done quietly and unostentatiously by the membership of this organization. The school occupying a plot of but ten acres, but little effort is directed towards farming, although a few acres are put in gar - den, and there is an orchard of two acres. NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF Omaha, Nebraska P. W. Booth, Superintendent About half of the twenty-three acres upon which this school is located, is devoted to farm and garden, the balance being in campus. This is the oldest of the state's institutions, the first appropriation being made for it in 1867. At the close of the school year just ended there were present 16S pupils, and 50 officers, employees and teachers. During the biennium last past the pupils averaged 171 in number and were maintained at a yearly per capita cost of .f448.49, entailing a total expense of .+iri^,381.42. Pupils are confined pretty generally to residents of Nebraska, although non-resident pupils may be admitted upon terms fixed by the Board of Control, which at this time is $500.00 per year. The same laws apply to this school as to the School for the Blind, relative to expenses and the objects of the institution. The statutes require that speech and lip reading be taught to all pupils mentally and physically capacitated for such instruc - tion. Others are taught by the manual method. Pupils are received in the school at the age of six and the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 CONDENSED REPORT OF Irse runs for twelve years. "It is unfortunate," says the erintendent in his report, "when deaf children are not sent shool at the proper age (eight years old at the most,) for if be older their minds seem to have lost in some degree their tic nature, and it is harder to train them in the simple things lent to the beginning steps. It is very hard to get a pupil of 'teen, for example, interested in beginning work, and we are uently compelled with such a one to abandon attempts to h speech and lip-reading, contenting ourselves with teaching ;ten language and this within a narrow range." 1A manual training department, well eqnipped, and a print - department, to which a linotype machine is about to be added, maintained, as are also classes in domestic art and science, in gardening. ■ This pamphlet is produced by the department of printing of school. STATE REFORMATORY FOR WOMEN York, Nebraska Dr. Alma J. Chapman, Superintendent Formally opened for the reception of inmates in May, 1920, this institution had an average population for such portion of the biennial period as had elapsed December 1, 1920, of 9. At the present time there are 17 women and girls at the farm and a total of 4 officers and employees. This taxes the present capacity of the institution. Girls are instructed in cooking, plain and fancy needle work, gardening, poultry raising and dairy work. During the school year classes in spelling, mathematics, music and Bible study aro conducted. Those in need of medical treatment are cared for by a physician. A new building containing housing for twenty girls, matron's quarters, industrial room, and library, will be built during the coming biennium and the institution will be generally improved and modernized. The institution is located on 119 acres of fine land, nearly all of which is in farm and garden. Live stock, much of which is pure-bred, is raised on the place. It is expected that in the course of a few years this institu - tion will greatly enlarge its usefulness. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF CONTROL 15 Admission is had by commitment by either the district court or by police magistrates. With the installation of water and electric lights, and espec - ially with the completion of the new building, for which $40,000 was appropriated, the institution will greatly enlarge its usefulness. NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Lincoln, Nebraska Dependent or neglected children under sixteen years of age, and of sound mind, may be committed to this institution by the county, district or juvenile court. Temporary inmates, not regu - larly committed, may be admitted to the Home at the discretion of the Board of Control, but the care and maintenance of thesi? must be paid for by either the parent, guardian or county. During the last biennium $2,864.10 was received for the board and care of temporary wards. The Board is made the legal guardian of all the children of the Home, and they are placed in suitable homes until of age, be - ing either adopted or taken on written contract. Educational ad - vantages must be given the children both at the Home and by the persons to whom their care is entrusted. This institution, founded in 1909, now has an inmate popula - tion of 76 and a complement of 13 officers and employees. The population averaged 53 during the past biennium, when $68,488. - 97 was expended for their maintenance, a yearly per capita cost of $646.12. "Dependency implies many things besides lack of means of support," says Miss Stevens in her report to the Board. "Parents who are able to furnish their children with the necessities of life are often unfit to provide the elements essential to their physical, mental or moral growth. Therefore we receive many children whose parents or other relatives are able to provide for and sup - port them, but who in spirit or character, or morality, are unsuited to have them under their control." There is but a small tract in connection with the Home. Ample room is provided for recreation grounds, but not very much for gardening and none at all for farming. (Miss) Amy V. Stevens, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p016">"« issssssasislsise i I «» •I SS8 : : ;aSl5 : : : : : :g 9 »OMO ■ -^HC3»O !.!...!&gt;. oo • ■ 'Cfa po co •-« ■ ■ -i!) (D T •» ■ ' - :::::: m S :S : :8S :SKS |8 ;8S S S '32 ' '2*^ -cO"* 1^ Q -"^Q (fa ■9 : :22 :S I : ; 3 S | j» _^ • ' ■ ' • ■» ■ i _2 I I I S Nr*t^.oc3»ocico ■ i-i c c. n n r» ■ f ffn- n -v co x cj6 q 9 Siq K09 ■ oi i " i 1 I Q 5 a 1 ill Tel If il _p I B ■ C&gt;a&gt;Soo^ni-iASm9otw«5«l I « gco = HOi-Hh-c&lt;3-t'Q«x^Hc;c5cor* b- ro -r c-i » t* — -r '^ re — &lt;- ••: x — -t I "5 S £! 3 ? - * '" ~ ~ ~ * * * I co J» I m t &lt;• s tocQ»oio^t^co^fOQor&gt;.--«coMcor^ i S eooixcotoco-HtcciCQOtfs-^'^-ecco 2 re t ~ t *t r^ ■" i * c- ?i • iC p&lt; co t* X I I 1 5 131 CONCOWMiOOOftOQfnN-rt I &lt;-|coioo&lt;MOSi-'-rr*ccti l 5oqQoasoqw I 0 5 M 3 cs 3? M N *^ w O) co « « c; &lt;n I "OOr-ic^cocfCwCtccc — ff 1 I J» I t- g? a w tN. ao r^. -t&lt; »mmn«-ho:« &lt;-i Q — C •" ■— I* CC » — r* *r -f -TNt »C t* CD f « Ol CO CO SO « CS &lt;if I ■:::::::::::: il i liaiiiiiiiijiiJ : 111 ' !3 till 1 SJJiiiJ iisJIll 5 -ai e,o ;» S s~ b'E o- 2 B* &amp;£ illiiiiliiiJil § 9 1 s 1 I </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>