<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  THE EFFECT OF BLEACHING UPON THE QUALITY OF WHEAT FLOUR.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 HE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA. Hl'LLETIX AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NEBRASKA MK XX, ARTICLE III. EFFECT OF BLEACHING UPON THE QUALITY WHEAT FLOUR. By P. J. Ai.way OCTOBKR li'i. 190' I.INCOI.X. NEBRASKA V. S. a </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS I work of previous investigators Snyder . lirahni Balland . Fleurent A very Conclusions ■ method of procuring the bleaching agent 1. Nitrogen peroxide 2. Nitrous acid and the nitritt 3. Nitric oxide . . . The action of the bleaching - for bleached flours bleached flour ■ amount of nil rites in flours use of measured volumes &lt; The color of the flour The effect of bleaching upon the a&lt; iilii The absorption of bleacln d dim The gluten of bleached flours. Baking tests of mill -bleached flours.. Baking tests of a flour treated wit] peroxide t amount of nitrites in bread nimli t occurrence of nitrites in sali\ a... physiological a&lt; tion of nitrai action of chlorine nnd bromir mary and conclusion- The possibility of unl)leac-h </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE \ *l EFFECT OF BLEACHING UPON THE QUALITY OF WHEAT FLOUR. BY r. J. VI. WAV. IXTBODUCTIOX. high-grade wheat fioun have a yellow tint vhea nilled. This color slowly fades when the flour is 11 a well-lighted place, but even after several months Hi. ••In former limes ■ yellow tint was considered bui now the Hour merchant demands the whitest ►or." 1 To comply with this demand, the artificial Mom- has been extensively introduced into the Western Europe and of the United States dnr- ]&gt;ast three years. A large part of the Hoar produced mills of this State at the present time is artificially being placed upon the market. The millers bleachers are of the opinion that they would \ i serious disadvantage if the present method of yellow tint of their high-grade flours had to he Mosi of the large mills have installed bleachers, few, which had a well-established trade before the n of the process, still place their product upon in unbleached condition dinarv advantages have been claimed for the lours, including an increase in the nutritive prop- an improvement in the keeping qualities and in tin ikiii!.' properties; on the as containing sulistanct &gt;ther hand they have been injurious to health, and ing inferior bread-making properties. Some of tb&lt; i-rs of the electrical bleaching processes have simi Flour Mai Suppli </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Tin Effrvt &lt;&gt;f Blemching Upon Whtmt Flo* larly condemned Hours bleached l&gt;y the pr in which nitric acid is used. The investigation, the results of which arc given in this bulletin and which have already been briefly reported, 1 was undertaken in order to determine the effect of bleaching upon die wiiolesoiiieness and upon the bread-making qualities of different Hours. Professor S. A very, who preceded the writer as chemist &lt;&gt; this Experiment Station, had already demonstrated to wha extent the various bleaching agents thai had been propose) might be used in the whitening of tloiy. His work eonclu sively shows that the bleaching of flonm by the differen Ralland and Fleurent in 1'iance. and by Rrahm in (\ Snviiki:.- As a bleaching nirent Snv«ler used u\\ which was generated from potassium rhlorati was led without any preliminary washing "into a la WoultV hotlle containing Hie Hour. \\ The bleaching process did not materially affect fh&lt; age amounts of the various compounds present in the fl "From these experiments there appears to !»&lt;• no bleaching purified flours made from a good quality of wl as the glutens wore sli^htlv oxidized, had lessened pow expansion and absorption, and the loaves from the bleached flours, altlio whiter in color, were in size and 1' weiffht." ■F ,T. Alway illetin ?l -.Ticuitnrnl K\ Station I February forms of commercial hleachera is tine rutirclv to ih II of :i jjas, nitrogen peroxide, which is produced in soim its hv iin electric prows, ;in«l in otherw by the dwom of nitric iirid. THE work OV I'i:i:vkhs i\\ i.siic.x Tons. Studies mi tin- bleaching of Honrs have been |&gt;iiMi Snyder, I.;nld. Willard and .\\&lt;-iv in the United St </seg>
            <seg id="p005">/. 5 I It i 1!.\ 1 I I'ur and aching of the loon dealt with in these i i|M limcints mall amounts of chlorine or &lt;&gt;f oxides of chlorine li oxygen by the heating of the potassium private communication Bnyder lias informed the hat in the examination of Hours bleached by means *ogen peroxide he has found no difference resulting he bleaching proves* except a whitening of the color ui.m.' —From his studies on the Alsop process of bleach our Brahm eonelnded thai "the odor and haling anal- •f the Hour were unfavorably affected and its acid con mi-eased. Tlie color, in this authors opinion, was not d nor was the composition altered." The use of MOM ml to improve the color lmt to impart an odor to the which rendered it unfit for use. .i.a.mi.- — Balland analysed a Hour both before and after ling by the electrical process. The bleaching improved dor of the Hour, while its odor ami taste became less Die only appreciable change in the composition 1 iii«) was in the acidity, the bleached product bring The moist glutens from the two Hours did r in weight or elasticity, but that of the bleached had licate odor. The dry gluten of the latter was lighter Baking tests showed that the bread from the ■d floor was whiter lmt less savory i i:i:vr. -Only the bleaching proi lepending he use of nitrogen peroxide have any technical value. &gt;zonized oxveen does not affect the color of the Hour. when ozonized air bleaches Hour it contains oxidei Dputscher Miiller (1904) Acadei I'aris) 139. 81!- ,t»4 lanu Kxperinu-! Northwestern Mil uldition &lt;&gt;l small quantities of nitrites. Experiment Station Record 16, 7M. From Versuchs-Anstir </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 n I nitrogen as well as ozone. .Moreover, Hours treat ozone acquire a disagreeable odor. The volume peroxide required for the bleaching of looo pram pounds i of tiuur varies according to the nature of i from 15 lo 40 cubic centimeter* i 1 in bleacheil in this way Buffer no appreciable chant;' chemical composition or in their bread-making The uitrogen peroxide arts upon the yellow oil of i but this action consists, not in a destruction of th iodine absorption of the oil is lessened by bleaching inply the nitrogen peroxide is absorbed i&gt;\ the fat cm bleaching of tlotirs bv aging is to he attributed to th lion of solid, white, fattv acids bv oxidation. l&gt;\ ll /.one the iodine absorption of tl is mcreasi formation of volat ile fattv a&lt; rv&lt; total acidity remains constant. The purer a tl&lt; is the iodine absorption of the Hour lower) will; nitrogen peroxide, the more peroxide the greater is the extent of the bleach the fat of the Hour become acid. &lt;&gt;nl\ explained." 1 No change in the acidity of the Hoi ■gliadin was caused by the bleaching. Tlie oil extracted from unbleached Hour wa bleached flour orange red, and from black. "Patent Hours of highest grade are readily blenched; pa ents of second grade are only moderately improved. I rrad&lt; Hours derive no benefit at all from bleaching : Abstract it oxidation Inn in a rhanin* in th«- tmnxluceurv &lt;&gt;f tli&lt; amount of the peroxide absorlK*&lt;l by tin- t improvement in tin- keeping qual </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 / / N i i l.-h h v of 1 ra &gt;xide and nitrogen peroxide can not be detected in litrogenoua matter added by the bleaching I'll to 50 parts ]mt million of Dour, or from lilliou of bread." xpressed the opiaioa that the addition of such ties of nitrogenous substances to the Hour is As the result of his investigations Ladd concluded ing, while improving the color of the bread, injures and odor, lessen* the absorption of the flour, and the expansive power of the gluten, and that bleached ike smaller loaves than unbleached. "The presence s acid in the Hour not only gives the bread a decided aste. but it would seem that the amount present in d would be harmful physiologically. While the re - aiued indicate that there is a loss of nitrous acid in from that in the Hour, I do not believe such to be I do not think that there would Ik' any loss what- isa of baking, and the amount present in the equal to the original amount in the flour."- irent loss of nitrous acid in the process of baking was d to the difficulty of extracting it all from the bread aking the analysis. Nitrous acid was not found in led Bonn that had been tipowd to the air for five Samples of unbleached flour in our laboratory in hags) gave no reaction for nitrous acid or ni - when placed between two bags containing flour id been bleached soon absorbed a determinable nuan - the nitrous acid." 1 "Low grade flours from well - wheat can be successfully bleached to resemble high ir patents." 4 North Dakota Agricultural Experiment Station (Novem- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 I i 1 I ulphui n recent the effective bleaching substances in all the electrical era, iind that bleached flow* were more acid than mil flours. AVKKY.-— -For many years proposals have been m patents toned for bleaching ...real product* with dioxide. British patent to Beans, No. ;.'..-&gt;&lt;!:_• issued in is7«t agent Modern bleaching of flour may be regarded a disposes the Use of nascent OXJgen ill a -aseous coll. brought in contact with the flour in a finelv di\ id, ozone is the chemical substance especially meni recommended that ozone be prepared by elect r patent No. ].(!t;i to Andrews discloses also the us oxygen, and recommended tin rogen \&gt; bleaching agent r. s. pal in to Alsop, No. "59.6." introduction of bleaching nto Anieri about the time of the las named patent. A tricity, and mixed with a large ex lowing suhstances. which have been j.i agents. V current of very carefully purified oxygen wa through the low heated to a temperature of 98 . No in? effect could be observed in the course of an houi lonj: as treated. The bleaching effect ascribed to oxy« be attributed to traces of chlorine which are usually i if the gas is not most carefully purified Bulletin of Kansas Ptato Hoard of h Journal of Aim-. WlLLABD. 1 — WUlard considered the oxides of niti appean to be the first i,&gt; mention ehlorii fruiii 189a French patent No. L'77.7r&gt;l. issn. discloses the use of air treated b\ bleacher*, in so tax ;is | run ucerta oxide, produced either chemically .gent." "Samples of unbleached don were tret </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 i *1 l I &lt; 11 1. Itoth ehloi niuri i u 1 I'.i limit lias also pointed out — does not bleach »ared bj electricity from air, or oxygen cou - nitrogen, contains nitrogen peroxide. The ribed to ozone is to be attributed to the present. lioxide is without effect ou the color of arlies effectively." ported itself similarly in all respec: side bleaches very slowly and requires a large ■ient bleaching can be obtained, as this agent &gt;es not have a tendency to discolor the Hour. pronounced in Hour bleached by its use." m bleaching effect, without regard to the reagent, can 1» obtained by the use of bro- r reagents follow iu the order named : chlorine, •. nitrogen peroxide." ' the Hour under consideration was placed in ch thick, between plates of glass. The plates ;ether at the ends with adhesive tape. The teed to the action of sunlight by placing in nd reflecting also the rays against the n roxide mixed with an excess of ozone shows ins effect as when mixed with air. The hleach- in the peroxide preseni . The work of the seven chemists mentioned &gt;\ inn conclusions : rine and sul])hur dioxide, while whitening tht nislv affect its qualities thai their use for earn is excluded. iches satisfactorily, but its inHuence on th« »f Hour is unknown. It is to be expected mirror. The sample was bleached BJ an rx hours." </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Tin i:/f,ct of Bleaching I pon Wheoi Flot i 1( &gt;''(•! I 1 I however, that in this respect, a&gt; in most others, it \\ scmble chlorine. 3. Ozone not only fails to bleach but imparts an obj able odor to tlic Hour. 4. Nitrogen peroxide is the sole bleaching agent us commercial scale There was little agreement as to the effects of nit peroxide apon the (loan. All recognized that there w appreciable change in chemical composition, hut. as t effect of the bleaching upon the acidity, the color, the a tion, the taste, the odor, and the baking qualities tiler no agreement. Fleurent and Ladd expressed widely dif views as to the wholesomeiiess &lt;if the bleached flours. From private communications the writer has learne many chemists believe that unbleached tlours contain quantities of nitrites as indicated by the Griess-Ilosva Till: MKTHO1I OK ['WXTBING TltK SAM1 As the object &lt;&gt;f the investigation was the detei the effect &lt;&gt;f bleaching, as actually practiced in Nebraska, upon tin- various grades of Sour, it w cure samples of both unbleached and Me from a considerable number of mills. Twenty l&lt; uished samples. All the millers to whom reques with a single exception, readily consented to eo the Experiment Station in the investigation. Tin furnished the samples are the following 15. &amp; II. Hilling and Ele- vator &lt; "o Vdams McDowell Kros Alexandria Jas. Taylor Auburn Aurora Milling Co Aurora Black r.ros Beatrice E. C. Carter Rearer City Cambridge Milling Co Bertram! R. II. Duff Co Cambridge Elevator Roller Mills &lt;&lt;&gt;. ... Colnml </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 1 \ i 1 i u*cordin ileached placed shelve: osad Irete I &lt; ( 1 alls City airhury 'riend I &amp; Mendenhall k Johnson Soldrege Valley .Milling Co Holmesvilh icy Flour Mills Kearney I'aul Schminke Co Nebraska City son k Son Riverton Mill Co Wahoo &amp; Aksamit AVilbcr tins Wood River the mills had no bleachers, nine used chemical and the other ten employed various electrical ulleiin the different Bonn are referred to by mun - c different mills by letter. Each miller has been letter designating his mill, and of the mini- different samples sent by him. The mills are »y letter instead of by name in order to prevent i he experiment* being used as a basis of com quality of the Hours produced by the different ii December, paper-lined sacks were sent to the dif - lls with the request that, as far as convenient, both and unbleached samples of three grades, patent, . and bakers', be sent. The samples, all freshlv were forwarded by express to Lincoln. The paper of the sample sacks prevented sifting of the flours; lv the bleached flour did not enter the sacks of un while in transit. The five-pound samples were ide by side, in the order of their numbers, on the &gt;f the storeroom. Milling Co Friend tlilliu^ ( 'o Fremont * Milling Co Hastings </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 !. l \ 1 1 vel\ l ra i ii&gt;iiie of the mills l&gt;lcaHi the lower grades of flour, v •rs do not, considering that it injures the appearaiN flour. Some of the latter class, however, were so obli o bleach samples of their low grade flours for the pm he investigation. It is necessary to point out that there is no uniform i the application of the names of the grade* to the diff&lt; Iowa, What one miller would call a "patent," ain would consider a "straight," :l1 "' ■oaie sent comparai high grade Soon as samples &lt;&gt;, "bakers'." In the set of pies from any one mill, however, the patent was the hi le and the (takers' the lowest. I sides the Hours secured directly from the mills. ■obm bleached, others unbleached, thai ha&lt; tl in paper boxes, side by side, for from two to ths. were obtained from .Mr. II. B. Smith of 1. total camber of samples thus secured amounted bred and forty-four. A considerable number of ined on the market and elsewhere were examine ic qaaatity of nitrites in these did not differ Iron ie samples furnished by the millers, no further wo ■ with them. Two unbleached flours, one a patent straight grade, made by different mills, at quantities were available, were used in bleaching experi performed on a small scale in this laboratory. To e these two ■■bleached flours there was a correspondini pie that had been bleached at the mill. These four tbn referred to in the following pages as Nos. 14.~&gt;. 146, 1 I En some thrc&lt;&gt; hundred experiments, measured vol bleaching ageat were allowed to act upon weigh) bs of flour. [n Table I there are given 'he lisi of Hours, the reported by the millers, the date of arrival of th&lt; I at the Experiment Station, and the kind of Id </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 t 64, f,r,. 66, 67, 128, 129, 133, ami 134, which are otioned in the table were samples of shorts and bran. Table II gives similar data in regard to Hours that had been me before they were examined. ished by Nebraska mill. i in ... , , Date of arrival Kind of Bleached or Experimtnt t) l e acher Bleached or Experimtnt t) l e acher unbleached St £ i(w use( , Unl.leache.l .. Dec. IB, 1WM Klectrical Unbleached.. Dec. 15, 1900 Kk-ctrical Bleached . Patent Unbleached . Chemical Unbleached . Chemical Bleached Bleached int Unbleached.. " Electrical Unbleached . . " Electrica K'lit Bleached Straight Patent Unbleached. . . No bleacher I'nbleached. . . No bleac Unbleached . Dec. 18. 1906 Electric Unbleached.. Dec. 18. 1906 Electrical Bleached Patent Unbleached No bleacher Patent Unbleached... Chemical G Hal C. l'at Ble :hed U 1 H Patent Electrical H Straight </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Table l.—Smmfilet of Hour furnish, Series Grade of Bleaehec nnbleacl No. of Mill flour. flour h tion 38 II 39 H 40 H 41 H Bakers Patent Unbleached. . Dec. H, V.tur, i Straight Kakers' . rn 48 J 49 J 50 J 51 J I Patent Straigl Bakers Patei Straight lUkers 68 M 69 M Patent So 70 N Patent Unt 71 N Straight 72 X Haker,' Patent Bit Straight 75 N Bakers' 76 O I Patent t nbl 77 () Straight 78 () Bakers' Patent Bleacl 80 O Straight 81 P Patent 82 V Straight 83 P Bakers at K\i&gt;&lt; 42 I Patent 43 I 44 I 45 I Pat 46 I Straight 47 I Bakers'. a k r&gt;.i K 54 K 55 K 56 K 57 K 58 I. 59 L eo l 61 L 62 I. 63 L 73 N 74 N 79 O </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 / / -Continued Dec. -20, 1S!O6 Electrical Unbleached.. Dec. 31, 1808 No bleacher a the* Bleacheil Unbleached Str Bleached Bleached I'nbleached Patent Inbleached . Clu-i \V 1 \V X Patent Unbleached.. Jan. 30, 1907 EX Straigh X Bakers 142 X Patent Bleached , , Date &lt;&gt;f arrival Kitnl of Bleached Unbleached... Jan. 5, 1907 Chei Jan. 10, 1S07 Electrical Bleached I libleacheil No 1&gt;K Unbleached... Jan. 17, 1907 Chei Rleacheil .... Unbleached... Bleached hX r-traight X </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 tolor and a vcrv raffocating odor, ii is about three times as heavv as air at ordiiiarj tenperatares. Its density compare with that of air is nut a constant, falling as the teniperaturt rises, aad rising as the temperature falls. Nitrogen peroxide when inhaled in large amounts, is very poisonous. It cor rodea most metals ami many mbatances of vegetable or ol animal origil. Like concentrated nitric acid it colors tin skin vellow. Nitrogen peroxide dissolves in water, forming a mixture of nitric acid and nitrous acid. The relative proportion* of these two acids formed from a given amount of nitrogen per- 1. XiTKo&lt;;i:.\ Pesoxids. — Tliis compound is. i hits iil.ovc 72 P. (22 C i. a vapor wiili a 1 Table II.— Samp/cs offlomr that had been stored for tome time Serid Mill. Grade of flour Bleached or Date of arrival Kin.! &lt;&gt; flour, unbleaiheil. at Lincoln. t r 90 AA Ilaker;.' Bleached Nov. S3, 1906 Electr 91 HK Straight . . Unbleached.. Sept. :&gt;."&gt; 19o.-&gt; No bk !r - I!Ii Feb. 13, 1900 !( -&gt; G " Feb. S3, litOti »* CC .... ■ peb! K, 1900 "•' DD Bleached. N..v. I, mm Not re !H j EE ■• ... Hov. i. 19()6.. Chemi P p Not reported.. Nov. 1,1906.. T Dnbleached. Sept. 30, 1906 Nobk " (;&lt;; " Mar. 30, 1SX»; J U) J " ... " ... Sept 2-J. 1905 101 AA Baken ■■ („,. 30, 1906 KK.tr }°- *A Patent ... Bfcachetl ... Jan. 19, 1906 mi CC Straight... Unbleached Sept. 19, 1906 Noble 1(11 IIH ... Sept. 1, 1908 t 11 Aug. in. 190ti Skctr II " Bleached Aug 10, JJ t'atent Unbleached. . . Juh I JJ THE Itl.KAClllMi AGENT. h lias already been Mentioned ihiii nitrogeo peroi nuw recognised as the active agenf in ilic tommerolal I l ing procewea. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 / / ii the temperature and iijmhi the amount of ! I", uitrogen peroxide may !«• i nnrtrnwd tv a wii liquid which is lighter in color the lower tin o whidi it is cooled; at :&gt;:.' F. it is colorless quid is cooled to Hi F. it forms cotorfom \ A i ordinary teni[H-rat ures tlic li([iiid form of nitrogen per - side when in contact with tin- air jjraduallv evaporates as a n gas. The nitrogen peroxide as used for bleaching pur- I is always mixed with such a large proportion of ait there is no chance of its becoming liquefied. Usually uantity is so small, except in the generator of the cheat- I bleachers, that the color is not noticeable, the odor iielv to be detected and the risk of poisoning quite Nitrogen peroxide mav We prepared by a great another of 1&gt;rent methods, either directly or by first preparing nitric tie, which in contact with the air combine! with oxygen orm nitrogen peroxide. Nmtors Acin ami tiik Xitkitks.— Nitrous acid, which niiied together with nitric acid l&gt;y the action of niti •xide upon water, is known only in the form of a solution Id water. When the solution is gently warmed the ni - acid decomposes, giving off nitric oxide. Solutions of rus acid in water are blue when concentrated, and color - when dilute. They are characterized, even when very Ite. li\ an odor resembling that of acetic acid. When ni - s acid acts upon liases as well as apon various salts of metals, nitrites are formed, ("onverselv, when a solution nitrite in water is treated with mineral acids, or witli .his organic acids, a solution of nitrous acid is obtained. The nitrites, unlike nitrous acid, are comparativeh stable and ovcur in small quantities very widely distributed in na - ture. Ammonium nitrite OCCnn in small amounts in the air, in rain water, and in many springs. The amount in the :)t- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 in f \ i I i lieu I I \ rn liiusplit-ric precipitation is greatest in the winter and spr Tin- occurrence of nitrites or &lt;»f nitrons acid in the jnict plants' and in human saliva' lias long been known. Eiti'ous acid or nit rites are formed in small amount evaporation of water, 14 and also by the burning of ating iras."' and l&gt;v the action of electric spark* or &lt;&gt; it electric discharge upon the air. 3. Nitric OXIDE. — This compound is so closely relat nitrous acid and to nitrogen peroxide that it should be tinned here. It is at ordinary temperatures a rolorlea only slightly soluble in water. When allowed to eom&lt; contact with oxygen it at once forma nitrogen peroxide, rordingly it nay l«- used for the bleaching of Hour, at changed by the oxygen of the air into ih • peroxide I coming into contact with the Roar. THE ACTION UK Till: BLEACHING U.IAT I !'(i\ TIM When nitrogen peroxide ■nines into i ontai forms both nitric acid and nitrous acid. As all li« tain from !• per cent to 15 per cent of water, these i are formed whenever nitrogen peroxide is allowed to a&lt; Hour. Both acids, when formed in fen small amount ably combine with metallic salts contained in the flou injr salts of the two acids, viz.. nitrate*) from the niti and nitrites from the nitrous acid. As shown farthe this bulletin, neither nitrogen peroxide nor nitrous present in Boars that have been bleached by means o gen peroxide. It is the formation of nitrites in flour, iptes rendus l'Academte Pschrilt fur Chemie. 1 sen, |16 Chemla P. Genadius. Am Chemist S, 7 iisMi: Spiege ■P. Griess, Berlchte der deutschc O. Low, Zeitsclirift fiir Chpn.i. R. Warington. Journi'i of ihi 1 C (1881). A. V. l.osecke. Anl'iv der Pha t I s I,. T Wright. Journal of the ( 79). ,\. R. Lcsds, Journal of \ </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I i itt pot i follow \-sllll 1 f I i \ h inn n Accoi i pet hi hiug process, that permit* of the easy recognition Sours. Whether the actual bleaching is due to peroxide or to the resulting nitrous acid is not No mat icr how small a quantity of the peroxide is greater portion of it is changed into nitrites and only a very small part going to act upon the color- ■r of the floor. It is not known which nitrites, so- assimn. calcium, or magnesium, are present in the The relative proportion of these four metals, ex - as their oxides, occurring in wheat, is approximately Potassium (K,O) &lt;&gt;3.:&gt; Magnesium I MiiOi 27.8 ralcium (GaO) 7.3 Sodium iN"ii : &lt;&gt;, 1.4 ing that the nitrous acid acts upon tin- compounds or metals, the weight of the resulting mixture of s most nearly expressed as sodium nitrite: it would gh if represented as potassium nitrite and too low nted as magnesium nitrite. Moreover, the phvsio - -t ion of the nitrites of these metals when in very nitrous acid that has been changed into nitrites, the weight of the resulting nitrites; accordingly, the results of the analyses it makes no difference selected as the ltasis of comparison. For the o\e reasons the nitrite* in the tiour are expressed as so- rite in the following pages of this bulletin. ling to Flenrent, nitrogen peroxide or nitrous acid &gt;ed hv the fat of the flour (which amounts to about nt in the case of patent grades), causing a lower ■ inline absorption of the fat. He attributes th&lt; effect of the nitrogen peroxide to a change in th&lt; translin encv of the fat. and not to the removal of the color of Ph'.nt :inrt Animal Life. p. 173 it ion is to be considered as proportional to the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 yellow color IS 11 i I)V (lie bleach lii-cll ha t |tro| 1 perox \ti \ ml tiitrtt trites from th Kie fat. The writer, however, found thai the matter of the fat \v;is destroyed t or, ;is wa changed into ;i colorless compound. TESTS Hill l;l.i:.\( llKli l-l, ()1 K There are three changes produced in the Houi in;:, viz. 1. The addition of a small amount of nitrate f. The change of the coloring matter of t nge in the fat itself. The tests proposed for lileached tlotirs hav ■poa one or other of the above chanties. The by Fletirent is baaed upon the change in the f:i "A flour that has been treated with n I easily recognised ''\ the color of the soap fat of the Hour. Fifty grauiH of flour are rolenm ether, and the solvent evaporated ■atiire. Tlie fat thus obtained is dissolved i ohol and treated with 1 of alcoholic In- is unbleached no change in the color 11 is produced Iiy the addition of 1I1 ill-, with a bleached Hour, the color ch;i intensity of which is proportional t&lt; &lt;rcn peroxide thai has been absorhed lit ion of five per cent of bleached tlotll this way." 1 KThe writer was unable to confirm Fleun is test was tried with mill-bleached flour tShaw- has proposer] the use of diphenvla lidi fiives an indiiro blue color with nilrati ie method of se]iaratin'r the nitrates and ni ■Comptes rendus de I'Acadesnie rt&lt; isrhes Centralblatt, 190fi. I. til 2. - Journal of American Chemical B 2. The addition &lt;&gt;f a small amount of nitrites. :{. The cliaiiiic of tin- i-olorine matter &lt;&lt;( tli&lt;- fat ui </seg>
            <seg id="p021">/ 21 Utb Mi.- ( V ii i t Id \ \ i how in unlilea idled tl T. \V N V iiis, and in the hands of the writer this \c reliable. n used the well-known Uriess-llosvay test 1 for icus acid. The extreme delicacy of thi&gt; ut l.v \\ arington-' in is,sl. No other chemical \c the test and it is extremely sensitive, allow- a quantity as one part of nitrite in rive hundred s of water to he detected. It may also l»e em- he quantitative determination of t In* nitrites in ess-ll..svay test is given by Button 3 as follows: tion of &lt;•.."&gt; grains of suljihanilic acid in l."&gt;0 cc of tic acid and another of 0.1 gram of alpha-naphthyl - 150 cc. dilute acetic acid are prepared. These two lire kept separate, and when required for use eqaal ire mixed, thus gaining the advantage of having a cut instead of two. and one which indicates by its her it has become contaminated by nitrous acid mi the ait-. The mixture is not affected by lijjht. protected from the air. It is preferable to mix only in small quantities, and keep the remaining parate until wanted." icid and nitrites (the latter, in the presence &lt;&gt;f uid of the test solution, forming nitrons acid i re or less intense pink coloration according to resent. The pink color develops within rifteeii ordinary temperatures, and in less time, if the the (Jriess-Ilosvay reagent with the solution being wted. There has been much difference of opinion definitely this test distinguishes a bleached from lied flour, Ladd. for instance, statinur that un - •ins which have Keen stored beside bleached Hours Haul Bull. KaENU State Hoard of Health IV 1"8: E. F. \.atU} th Dakota Agricultural Experiment Station. of Chemical Society (London). 1881. 231. Analysis. Ninth Edition. 44!" </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 give the i-liurai teristic tesi for niirites. Up to the \n&lt; time, however, the writer hiu fouud un unbleached dour has j;ivfii even the fainteiri pink coloration when the teal coadncted with the nnoMiirj pro ant urns. The pivcaut necessary in the case of this lest are extraordinary. All made indoors ai tliis Laboratory have proven unrcliabl&lt; the flour or water absorbed duriug tin- operation snilit nitrite, nitrous acid, or nitrogen peroxide froin the atosphere to give a pink coloration with all unbleached ti« It lias ai ciii-ilin^lv lieen found necessary t(» make all h-&gt;i- ii of doors. .Most niter papers c&lt; trites. As pointed &lt;&gt;ui above, u nitrites, and distilled water I'rei| i|iiant ities. The nitrites found the tests of unbleached Hours probably are derived from the u: of nitrites found in a mixture unbleached flour after exposure' for .several hours is noteworthy oiitain small amount: manv natural waters 1 1 Ilt-Il 1 1 \ eolllailis eolisi in the ilist illeil water performed in the lab Mam nitrite- fn to the ait The following method was found reliable and s. both for the detection of uitriies in llour and I'm t titative determination. A Laboratory table i&gt; lilt of doors. The water to lie used iu I he experiment in order to insure the absence of nitrites. All ap l&gt;e used is well washed with this nitrite free water. papers placed in funnels are washed until the wa no test for nitrites. Twenty grams &lt; - •'! oancei i to 1m' tested and LMIO n\ I C, 1' ."t ok. I stoppered flask and shaken ai frequcul intervals hour. The mixture is allowed to stand until the rioui largely settled to the bottom of the flask. A portion of the liquid in the Hask is carefully poured upon a washed tiller. Ten &lt;-c. of the filtrate thus obtained is diluted to BO cc. with water, treated with "_' cc of the Qriess Ilosvay reagent, and heated in a water bath to SO &lt;". i17»i F.) for fifteen min ■tea. If no pink coloration develops, the absence of nitrites </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 \ • v i » Ill \&lt;rv Econ r flo; inii.l t In- mixture has a more or less piuk color it a Nesaler tube and compared with a stand - i prepared l&gt;y warming a known aniouut of with an excess of the (ii - icss-llos\a_\ reagent. Heat ion of the teal which will serve for most desired merely to decide whether a flour i bleached is the following: Test the water ,\iiij; a half tilled giftM goblei treated with of the &lt; iriesN-i losvstv reagent to stand out of n hour. If no pink color develops, stir a tea- flour into half a goblei of water, add fortj drop* nt and allow to stand half an hour. If no dia- iloration has appeared at the end of this time, conclude that the Hour has not Ween bleached. n the above manner, none of the -\ samples of flour • eleven mills having no hleachen gave a reaction for ; 1&lt;&gt; samples of unbleached Hour from 24 mills having •s gave none, while 12 samples sent from six of theae ; iinMeaclied Hour, gave a more or less pink color. lamplea sent as those of bleached Hours. M gave the on, while two gave none. The failure of Xos. 17 and he reaction was doubtless due to the miller having by mistake, their color giving no evidence of any The explanation of the coloration produced bj ample* (No*. 10, 12. IS, ."»:?. 7&lt;&gt;. 77. 78, HM. r_':_\ .■&gt;."&gt;i sent as nnbleached is likewise simple; two. md r_T&gt;. were bleached Hours as shown both by the d the amount of nitrites, while into the others small bleached Hour had been accidentally introduced. Hue of some mills the bleacher* are so located that it litliciilt to take a rampie of the flour before it conies tact with the bleaching jras. The particles of MeadM d latino in the air also add of nnbleached flour. Tn to the difficulty of getting a the ran of several hundred n. Volumetric Analysis, p. 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Tin Efevi of ttlcaching I {ton \\l&lt;-&lt;it I l&lt; f intents in iliis laboratory in which nitrite free flours treated with nitrogen peroxide every sample of treated gave the test for nitrites. the possibility ok i m!i.i:.uiii:i&gt; ii.orus acqi'ikim; thi PBOPKKTIKS or BLEACHED Kl.ol K Es already pointed oat, it baa been claimed thai "un ened loon lying alongside &lt;&gt;f bleached noun*, &lt;&gt;r an i lied tluius from a mill win-re bleaching is practiced wil me contaminated, aa it is a well-known fact that floun • the power of readily absorbing any gaa or foreign odoi hich they are placed." 1 If this statement were true i Kid not he (Mtssiltle In &lt;list illiiU isli. liv tile &lt;i Hess- 1 1 for nit riles, between unlileached and bleached tloi rase the former had been stored quotation it is assumed that ft remains as aoch or as nitrous That the coneliisioiis stated in tenalile is evident from the loll unlilearhed (lour from -I mill tear the latter. It m the altove ijllotat win" : of the ~i)S here lileaehinii only \- gave an\ reaction with the (li- the other -Ki lM'imr ;!&gt;* free of nitrites and nitr&lt; VII the samples of flour that had arrived at this Exp l» tested oil .March 1st to 5th. The results of of tests were the same as those of tin- firxt. During lerval of eighi weeks the samples had been utorcd in | lined sacks, side by side, in the order of their numliers. T&lt; acid was given off by a Btronply bleached flour the f three experiments were performed Experiment I. — Two beakers, the one nearly tilled \vi bleached flour i No. 14tii ami the other equally full of un Bulletin 72. North Dakota Agricultural Exi sample* &lt;&gt;f unbleached Horn- from mills havii Station previous tO December L'f». l'.MMi. wel rember 26th u&gt; DotimiiImt 31sl for nitrittt*. All were ami decide whether any trace of nitrogen |M»roside or of n it r&lt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">/ 25 ii- i No. 1 i, were placed mi a ground glass plate, ■11 jar and allowed to stand three days. At me the unbleached Hour gave no coloration i layer of bleached Hour i No. 14t»i in Bottle III. lensely packed absorbent cotton in Bottles IV and V and over a layer of unbleached Hour i No. 1 i in Bottle VI. The floor in Bottle VI was tested every twelve hours for ni \t the end of forty-eighi hours, no coloration being I with the (Jriess llosvav reagent, the experiment was tinned. The absorbent cotton in Bottles IV and V &gt;i sed to prevent particles of the bleached Hour lx-in^ car - rom Bottle III lo Bottle VI. When the experiment ■ated. omitting Bottles I and II from the series, the the last bottle Rave a distinct reaction at the end of This is to he attributed to the air of the labora- ther containing nitrites, nitrous acid or a gas which apon nitrates in the Hour to prodnce nitrites; when ■ air was washed with caustic potash them were removed. It must he concluded from the above that neither nitrous icid nor nitrogen peroxide is contained in the bleached flours, the coloration with the Griess-Ilo.svay test being due entirely o the nitrites present, and also tint an unbleached flour tored beside a bleached flour acquire* none of the properties of the latter unless particles of the bleached floor are actually introduced into the unbleached flnur. li the Griess-lliwvay test. 1 1 • Experiment II. — A layer of bleached Hour i No. 146), ■ uter of ;in inch in thickness, was placed oa the bottom of ttuikow pw wasli bottle and subjected to the action of a •id current of air for ten days. At the cud of this time imitative determinations of the nitrites in the untreated i' - . No. 14t&gt;, and in the treated Hour showed no difference tlie amount of nitrites. Experiment III.— A series of six gaa wash Itottles was ar- med s&lt;&gt; that a current of air supplied bj a water blast -sim I thru caustic potash solution in Hollies I and II. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 V MU.I nitrites, ex rts of Hour loo sin lied sain linl.- d the eh I'll the a moil n three in I ii \ FHE AMiil NT &lt;•!■' MTltlTKS IN Kl.ol Its - In Table ill there is j;iveii the amount of pressed as sodium nitrite, in each million pa "Traces" indicates that (lie quantity present w to be measured. The average amount of nitrite in all the bleat is »;.."{ parts per million parts of (lour. There is eiiee between the averages for the electrical and bleachers, thev being ti.l and (i.e. respectively, general relation between the grade of Hour and of nitrite present. The average amounts in the were: patent •"•&gt;. straight ."..1, and bakers" s.4. taut, in this connection, to note that most mills &lt; their lowest grade for the market. In all cases in which there was conclusive the flour had not been treated with iiitro&amp;ren nitrogen lowed to become mixed with bleached ti was found. Table ill. -Nilri fill. Kind of bleacher. Series flour. &gt;er Reinjrte 1 flour. A A A Electrical 1 i 1 aten Straight . . . Bakers' Patent Straight . Bakers' . . . 0.0 -I. «.) .i.4 1.1 I Chemical 10 . li Patent Straight . Bake: Patent Straight . . 0.0 0.0 0 . 3 :i.l Cnbleai BUacln 5 Electrical U 13 14 : £ Patent Sbaight . Bakei Patent Straight . . . Traces Traces 0.0 a Ub!«fkhl </seg>
            <seg id="p027">•/ I 27 in bleached and un • iska mills. Contintu Flour re - nitntes u .P" " ul bWhed« li..n parti uni.iead.e,! ol flour. Remarks. N tde of flour Flour h is yellow tint like 14. 0.0 Bleached (i (i Unbleached o.O Straight Bakers' 0.0 •Jl Patent (I I) 0.0 o.u 24 Patent 1 Bleached Straight 0.0 I'nbfaachcd n.U •_".• Bakers 0.0 (PI) 11.1.1 Flour vi 1 - low, nulls - tinguish II. t) Bleached 1 S able fron 30. 4 4 36 Patent (1.0 Unbleached (i n 0.0 t -1 Bleached 10.0 42 Patent . 4! Straight 44 Bakers' . 15 Patent . 4i_i Straight 47 Bakers' 0.0 Unbleached 0 0 Bleached IS. 5 0.0 Unbleached 0.0 3 4 Bleached S.I Color of flour gave no evidence of bleach - ing. 0.0 Unbleached Traces 0.0 Bleached 5.0 I 6.2 Rijx&gt;rte Patent Straight Bakers' . Bakers Patent . Straight 10 Patent . 11 Straight ikers' . B Patent . U Straight 5T. Haters' . »7 Straight S8 Bakers' . i'.i Patent . )n Straight 41 Bakers'. )S Patent . Straight 50 Patent . 51 Straight 52 Patent . 53 Straight ."&gt;4 Bakers' . 56 Patent . 56 Straight 57 Bakers' . </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Tablk III. Xilrili ■ Jium mil;, bleached flout \ra%ka mills, (out inn ■•ka mills. Weight of pi I Weight of i.i „_ . ■ Kin.l o! aborted nitrites ' "I", ls '■ i.i. ....i,... No. ol grade of ner mil- .',.', Ki Mill Kind of Reported nitrite* t , ;" - MllK bleacher. No-o' K™le of p, r ,„„. ,|~U flour. flour. lum p,rt&gt; unWeache bleacher. N "- " ! K™le of per mil- i,*!^ flour. flour. lj,,,, auU . \, u lion parts unl)U or flour Ho I. Electrical.. tent 0.0 Vn I. Electrical - Patent 0.0 CTnbleach I. " V.t Straight 0.0 I- r.'.i Straight 0 I 1. M Bakers'... . o.o I. Kaker» bU L tl ['aunt :i 7 Bleached I- lit Patent ... 3.7 Bit-act Hl, 1. 03 Straight • B I- tw Straight 8 '.» I. '• 83 ! 1 20 u I. IS SI No inform - ation .... 88 Patent Trace* No infon M No inform atioii - mi I ■ u '. • No inforn SI No inform- ation ation &lt;8 Patent Trace- No infon M No inform- ation . N Electrical... To Patent 0.0 Unbleacht Electrical •II I N " ... 71 Straight 0.0 71 H ■■ .. 7J Bakers 1 N " . 7:: Patent ... L2.5 Bleached M " ... 74 Straight.. 12.5 74 H " 7.") Bakers' .... 1 .'.' O Chemical ... 76 Patent I nkitxVd Chemical 7(i 11 i . Straight 78 Bakers Bakers Patent Straigh 7!&lt; ■■ at §0 Straight t;.-J P Electrical.. Patent .... U.o DnUeachi I' Electrical . . 81 Patent I' Straik'lU it . . ii. 0 0.0 V P teat 6.2 Bk ■*! P 85 Straight ... 6 'Z Stnii^'li P " ... - ben P Hakt-rs Q y No bleacher. 87 Taunt 0.0 Ii No bleacher. 87 Patent Q Straight .. 0.0 Straight y Q Kakers AA Electric !HI Straight 0.9 I AA Electric !HI Straight.. 0.9 HH No bleacher. ill oil r.; No bleaclit-r itl KB 92 1 " !).'! i 93 CC ' H4 CC- '.i I DD UD Not reporte.l 86 0.". Bleached Not reported '.»:, KB EE Chemical . . M 1.1 Chemical ;«; St f !*7 Tracea Not report* T 1 No bleacher its 0.0 Unbleacht FP !»7 r No bleacher II- GG HI I 0.0 1' 100 AA Klectrical.. 101 Bakers' o!o AA Electrical.. 101 Bakers' AA " .. io» Patent 0.5 Bleached AA 102 Patent cc No bleacher. 10.1 Straight 0.0 rnbleaclni HH 104 II 0 ■Mills G. J, and T Installed bleachers after flours Nos were manufactured </seg>
            <seg id="p029">X in bleached and un h tinned. 'if mm illtr in Xebrmska in ■d Weight of Flour re Remark* I'atent 0.0 I nbleachcd 106 Straight 0.(1 0.0 ' itent . -traight lln Bakers'. l.'.t Bleached 4 13.8 1 1 1 Patent . IVi Straight 13 Bakers' . 14 Patent . raight Bakers' . Unbleached 0.0 (1.0 0.0 10.0 S.I Bleached 5 o 117 Taunt -!raitfht Bakers'. 130 Patent . L21 Straight 12-J Bakers'. 12.5 l.VO 10.0 Unbleached 0.11 Much more Yellow than il8an.lll'.i 1 6 1.6 &lt; Patent . 1J1 Straight 125 Rakers' . 1 Jt; Patent . 1 J7 Straight (I II 1.6 A hkafhfd flour. :i.l :t.i bleache&lt;l . 4.0 130 I'atent . 131 Straight 1 S-J Bakers'. l'nl)leache&lt;l 0.0 II II 0.0 Much more Traces vellow l.Ui .!.! Bleached . than 136. Unbleached ••57 I'atent 0.0 138 Bleached i I'nb'eached Bleacheil 0.0 Unbleached Bleached . 12 o ii.ii Unbleached Bleached Reported nitrites * "",, "" grade of per mil- ,P" rt , cl1 .-'* *" fl per imi l)] e achtil &lt;ir flour. lu,n i»rt» un ,, leacht&lt;1 ot flour. 138 " .... oil Hit Straight...! 0.0 141 Bakers'.... 14-J Patent .... 4 4 14.1 Str;ii K lit.. 12.5 144 Baker- -JT..') Straight 141 ! IT 1 atent 148 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 i I II nun ill i m in i 11 Hoi i i TIIK ISK OK MEASURED VOLUMES OF NITROGEN 1'KKOXII Very little has hitherto been reported as to tin- effei varying aniounts of nitrogen peroxide upon a definite am of Hour. Fleiiient 1 states thai the amount of nitroge niattei- added in tlii- blenching process varies from I'd i parts per million of Hour or is in 38 parts per mil lie bread, ami that the volume of nitrogen peroxide requiri bleach one kilogram of Hoar varies from 15 to 14 cnbic &gt; meters.- Tin' Methods of analysis used in the detennini of nitrogen in Boars are not sufficiently delicate to det&lt; rhangr of 20 to 50 parts per million in the amount of ni enoiis matter. If the nitrogen peroxide added to a were wholly absorbed by the fat, the increase in weigl tin- latter would be less than could lie detected by an a hence, it is not to he wondered at that the analvs tihin. Balland, Fleureni and Avery railed age in composition due to bleaching. Nitrogen peroxide, itself in not iniivi'iiii Bred, on account of the readiness w hv water and oilier liquids, and also us shy changes with the temperature. Nitric oxid&lt; may easily be obtained pure, and may convenient! ■red over water; when it is brought into cont atmosphere it is entirely changed into nitrog provided that the volume of the air is not lens ih that of the nitri&lt;- oxide. As the volume of the trogea peroxide is proportional to Mho wtric always less at ordinary temperatures i thai of the the volumes of nitrogen peroxide mentioned in are really those of the nitric oxide from whi-h formed by admixture with the air. »'Comptes rendus de rAradomii . 1906) ; 1 kiloKram=li»m . </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 / / / / method of bleaching Hours practised 1»\ the writer is &gt;\\s: A weighed quantity «&gt;f Hour, from 206 to 10M is placed in a 3-liter ( approximate] y 3-qoart) By means of a jrlass tube, drawn to a li&gt;n^ tint' point aching to the middle of the flask, tin- desired volume ic oxide is delivered from a uas liurette. The glaM tis at once withdrawn, the tlask rtoppered and'vigor - y shaken. Before delivering the first measured portion Eis a large quantity of nitric oxide is passed thru the imv tube to expel all air. Where a considerable number tuples of floor are treated in rapid succession the capil- ii\ end of die delivery tube prevents any appreciable ditfu - ini of #is. When' the volume of nitrogen peroxide was ian 50 iv. per kilogram of Hour, the brown fumes diaap - eared quickly on shaking the flask. With burger propor 10.0 Colorless . Almost colorless Colorless 1 . . Almost colorless 0 Whit* While' :am&gt; •J4.0 15 JIM 1 u :**) 1IRI Light yellow.. Light vellow llrown yellow &lt; hansf in &lt; olor from number to number between 2 and 7 an -mall to be satisfactorily described mis of the sliiikinii had t«&gt; !'&lt;■ coatinned longer, with [Ml ir. from one to two minutes, and witli 1000 &lt;•&lt;•. more t It n i » vi- minutes. uu.K IV. -The e/tee' of different quantities of nitrvgem peroxide u/hih the .... t i same flour. t Volume of Weight erf nitric nitrites . , f f t '^" U - J&amp; Ll ' U&gt;rof solution in ShiSJ per million low. ether kiloeram jiiirts of flour. of flour. II n Vtllow Yellow Yellow 1 Litfht yellow' Ligbt yullow' I.i);ht yellow 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 1 Oa October 16, l'.HMl, fifteen portions of Soar N&lt;&gt;. 146 were treated with different amount* of nitrogen peroxide, varying from 5 cc to LOW cc. per kilogram. The colon of the fifteen bleached samples were compared by Pekar's niethoil. 1 There was a distinct difference between the unbleached Hour and that to which nitrogen peroxide had been applied at the rate of 5 cc. per kilogram. The difference between adjacent mem - ben &lt;&gt;f the series of bleached samples was very alight, Itut when samples separated by two duihImth, such as No. :t an&lt; No. &lt;i, were compared a difference was apparent. There wa* an increase in the whiteness from No. 0 to No. s i ISO cc. pet kilogram), and a decrease from No. s to No. La i 1 (MM) cc. pel kilogram). Twenty-five grama (5 &lt;» oat.) of each Hour was extracted with ether. The ethereal solutions of the fats thu&gt; obtained were diluted in each case to 50 cc., and their color- compared. No. o was bright yellow. No. s colorless, and N 15 very slightly yellow. The colors of the i'at solutions ho 1 1n ■ same relation to one another that tin- colors of the llou did. The solid fats were obtained l&gt;\ th ethereal solutions, and their color and o lor compared. &lt;Jual itative tests made soon after the bleaching in October showed very large amounts of nitrites in Nos. 7 to 15, lait the quan tities had become surprisingly small before the quantitativi determination was made at the end of December. Othei series of experiments gave results similar to the iii-si . th&lt; maximum bleaching effect being produced by from ion t&lt; 150 ec. of nitrogen peroxide per kilogram of Hour, largei amounts imparting a yellow color to the Hour. When Mi maximum bleaching effect was attained, the fat was prac - tically colorless and gave a colorless ethereal solution. Th&lt; odoi of the Hour remained agreeable when the amount of ni trogea peroxide did not exceed this amount. The greater th amount of nitrogen peroxide that was used in excess of tin quantity required for this maximum effect, the darker wa» </seg>
            <seg id="p033">i i i !&lt;■ Hour and also uf its extracted tai, the mort lie ethereal solution of the Latter, the more dis v able was its odor, and the more objectionable its use for ikiny purposes. It is highly probable that many of rsc opinions on bleached Hour are due to the invest i- I samples to which execsshe quantities of nitrogen ide had been added. 1 lie difficulty of applying sutti - y small volumes of the gag wlieu bleaching on a small nriiiiiis apparent when it is considered that, iu order late actual commercial operations, it is necessary to to two pounds of Hour a volume of the bleaching gaa reater than one cubic inch. trder to decide whether it u possible from the amounts rites in bleached dour to estimate the amount of the binji agent that has been used, a large number of Hours bleached and allowed to stand three or four weeks be - the final determination of nitrites was made. The re- indicate that it is possible to make au approximate ite of the amount of nitrogen peroxide that is used in Nebraska mills. The amount of nitrite found in a IumI Hour is approximately proportional to the amount s used up to ."&gt;(( cc. per kilogram; the more gaa that is the smaller is the proportion of nitrite left in the Hour. per kilogram jjivini: from .'? to 4 parts per million of ind 50 cc. per kilogram jjivinj; only 90 parts pa ion. When not more than all cc. per kilogram of Hour been used, the proportion of nitrites was not found to me less on allowing the Hour to stand, while with larger mes of j:as the amount of nitrites fell rapidly; the mote nitrogen peroxide that was used up to 1000 cc. per kilogram mailer was the quantity of nitrites eventually found in tli- Hour. This is well shown hv Table Y </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 As is evident from ihis table, the mere determination tlic Miiuiiui of nitiilcs (Ittcs not servo to disl in^uisli a flour whirli an objectionably large quantity of bleaching ;l been applied inn overtreated Hour] from oik- i&lt;&gt; which &lt;&gt;n a ivasonalilc amount lias been applied. This is not a writ) matter, however, because a miller is not apt to overtreal flour when 1&gt;,\ so doing he not only injures the quality of i flour but also lowers its market value by spoiling its col and odor. All overtreated Hours (produced in this laboi torvi that the writer has examined bave given a bluish rol« at ion when added to diphenylamine in sulphuric acid sol tion. A small quantity of the overbleached Hour was t k 1 moistened with water, and then stirred into this lest solutic It is evident from Table VI that the amount of nitrogen peroxide used in Nebraska mills usually does not exceed 20 CC. iH'f kilogram of low. The volume occupied by a definite amount of gas depends upon the temperature ami preamre. As the difference* in the weight of a given volume of the peroxide due to the vary - ing pressure of the atmosphere and the slight fluctuations in the temperature of the laboratory (fg to 72 P.) are much Table 7 Ac ihain;t in the amount ol i win! ! /ion Kxperi- Si nient No- &lt;&gt;f No. flour. \ uluiiu of nitric oxiflt- Date oi bleaching Nitrite* ]kt million of March 1. March 1 a as U7 J4 h ; 1J7 •-"•• 147 as n; :t&gt; H7 •VJ 147 "k! 147 147 W 147 •''7 147 147 M 147 ■S, Mar 1 StS 1-\1. 28 :*i Feb. tt BO Feb « 50 Feb. 28 .VI 150 Feb. *»... ■Jin i Feb. 28... •2.-&gt;o l , j- ■ I Feb. •&gt; . 41W 1 Feb. 28 K»j.i I •J.\ . ;» i 17n irj iso n 115 H»i IV. 11 -J 245 lid 334 31 1" </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 nailer than l'del ime Hour fed oil ejlc sons. The million p 1 ;) ■* i Eel- til d VI those (hit- to the method of determination, mpentiue nor tin- pressure is ghrea in Tallies determine how concordant the results were for •, the quantity of nitrites in No. 145 was deter - h of several different days bj three different results rasped from 11 to IS parts of nitrites arts of flour. J bv the at /ion of difffirnt sa»it x weight of Jiour. of ni/nlts proa u n peroxide upon In nif itric Weight of ,xide nitrites per Series No Reported grade for each millkn of flour. of flour, ■gram of of flout. &gt;} A •&gt; • &gt; • » 2 •j g B .") .") .") .") ."i ."&gt; 5 B ."&gt; ."&gt; .") &gt;:&gt; ::&gt; 25 ■i:, i'&gt; ■_r&gt; 2") BO :*) 50 BO oO :i.7 3.:i 3.1 :*.o 3.0 4.2 4.3 7.8 8.8 6.0 .-).(•, 5.6 6.4 ti.4 ti 4 5.6 6.5 5.1 ».3 ao.o 18.1 M.O 21.."&gt; 19.0 21.0 :w.o 31.1 27.0 33.0 112 113 113 131 131 131 IS 132 120 120 Z\ 23 130 130 132 132 140 140 141 141 20 89 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 Straight Bakers' Straight Patent Bakers' Patent Bakers' Patent Bakers' Straight Bakers' Patent </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 rl VI. The quantity of nitrites produced unfs &lt;_■/" nitrogen peroxide upon the same me The liijili grade flours contain very fe» part iiinl arc therefore of a white rotor \\iili a tinge of yellow. The Intensity of the yellow tint varies greatly. The lower grades of low contain nioiv particles of bran ami have a darker color with a grajiah tinge. The amount* of yellow coloring matter in the different gradea of Hour obtained from the same wheat appear to be about the same. Eonnerly a yellowish tint was considered desirable in tin lest grade &lt;&gt;f tionr us mentioned by Kick in his "Ploni t Volume &lt;&gt;f nitric Weight of t oxiilv nitrites ]&gt;er oied for each million kilogram of of flour. Hour. No. Reported gr of flour. of flour Si :*) 30.0 :t4 31.0 B ."ill 32.0 :v\ so 3i.o li'.i :&gt;i ii 40 HI 4.i 0 41 '.«) .(8.11 4-J IUU 4:t 100 50.0 44 lui 4-J ii 4:&gt; LOU in ii M 1UI B0 II 47 l()0 58.0 100 51.0 4it 1011 W.O ."Ml 10(1 H Km 4o ii Ul 30 55 o 200 aoo ao.o 200 M 0 :joo 4im 31.0 500 1000 ion 147 Patent 147 147 147 Baki A mixture of 14 i with '3 A mixture of 147 with 5 A mixture &lt;&gt;l 147 with I 1 Short-, 145 Hal, •J I Patent 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 147 Till: COLOR (IK ■' THE I'M H I {V </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Manufacture" 1 published iu 1871. Coincident with the in trodnction of the roller process, public taste seeaaed rapidly bange, as indicated ia the "Supplement" 1 of the same k published in 18 Now the floor merchant ilemands the whitest possible r and ( ■onsequeutly the miller has to make it; and the ••.riant question for him is. How can I West make the pat- nt Hour of the desired color? Whether the demand is ia ional. however, is of no consequence to him. .Many kinds of heat produce Hour with a yellow tin^e. others flow with a v tinge, but it can uot be said that these appearance* in - ite either richness in gluten with hard wheat or poorness ii gluten with soft wheat. These appearances have as - larentlv no connection with the richness in gluten." Nebraska wheats are among those that produce Hours with Fellow tinge. The two causes of a departure from white in ise of Xehraska flours are these: The presence of particles of bran. This does not affect i' f hest mules of Hour. l*. The yellow coloring matter in the flour. Pile latter is not to lie overcome by any skill in the pr manufacture. The introduction of the bleaching pumas, wever. has enabled the miller* to remove this yellow tint d furnish Hour of the color that the market demands. Die yellow rolor slowly fades when the unbleached Hour red in a well-lighted place, but even after many months 11 distinct. The yellow coloring matter, which resein - i coal-tar dye in many respects, is exceedingly minute in quantity ami is contained in the fat or oil of the Hour. bearing the same relation to this that butter color d&lt;x&gt;s to the | lire fat of butter. The coloring matter is not an i - tial constituent of the fat. the latter bein^, when pure, color like lard and forming only about one per cent of the weight of the jiatent flours. Yellow Hour when treated with </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ll of th nn I,.,! i liquids tliat are able to dissolve the fat, such as ether, . form, lien/.eiie autl petroleum ether (bensine), become The yellow solutions thus obtained lose their color wh posed to the sunshine. The more yellow ;i floor is the yellow is the solution obtained by treating it with one i above liquids. Bleached Hours when treated with the solvents give a more faintly yellow colored solution or &lt; colorless solution if the bleaching has been carrie&gt; enough. If the amount of nitrogen peroxide used has excessive the solution will be yellow. The fat from ■ n Hour, obtained by evaporating the solution, is yellow from a thoroly bleached Hour white, and that from an treated tlonr vellow or vellowish brown. Tahi.k VII.— 7t U JV, No of if* flour I'.itml (,; : 7(i •21 IN 1 MB «3 fifl ill 190 i:«t Clear white with \ faint yt\\am tint Clear tight yellowish white yellowish white lijjht yellow ' ■ yellow " butter yellow Butler vellow with tract - •21 1 in 108 61 in 117 Clu Clu Ele Ch&lt; «"&gt;• -i Straight Grade. 1 ■&gt; I .ir white with faint yel- low tint and no trace of ■ 1 Rray Yellowish white with tt of Rray Yellowish white with no trace of k'ray Yellowish white with faint trace of Bray 71 11 M Clu </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 / hed and bleached flours.— CohIihiuJ Weight No. of li R aD fc of kind of trites bleached tileachcr. per gour million of flour Table VII gives the color of a considerable muiiiImt of un- iched Soon and of the corresponding bleached samples. liiiiiu indicates the rank of the unbleached flours. K&lt; the last column ghrea the rank of the corresponding ehed Hours. The onbleached Hours of each of the three rades arc compared with each other; the coinparison of the leached Hours is on the same basia. The samples were ar- ranged according to their degree r&gt;f whiteness, which was determined by a modification of Pekar's method. Wedge - shaped masses of Hour were prepared on small rectangular plates of window glaas, using a nickel Hour slick. After all the samples that were to he compared with each other had been thus prepared, using a separate piece of glass for each, the.v were dipped below the surface of water, allowed to re - main one minute, withdrawn, well drained, placed in an OVCB at 203 P. and heated half an hour. The differences in color Yillowi-h white with trace \ 11.-) Chemical. . 3.1 II Yellowish white with tract 7 i &gt; I I &gt; i &gt;f gray Yellow with gray tint | liutter yellow Light yellow with gtmy . . . " Butter yellow aa 143 1.5 Electrical.. ■■ B.I •• Chemical. . 12.5 Electrical. ■! 4 Makers' (hade. t I 1 i i I i &gt; ! Yellowish gnjr i'&gt; 7.-. 47 41 116 SI 14J 11(1 4 4 lit Chemical l_ Electrical.. 10. u Chemical.. 5.0 Electrical.. 6.2 Chemical. '11 5 18.7 4 4 Electrical. 5 n 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Iv nnicli more marked after the drying in the oven than ore. The ranking of the straight and especially of the ;ers' grades uf the unbleached is very unsatisfactory as two tints, gray and yellow, both come into play. The ;t to the last column gives the quantities of nitrites in Un - ions bleached Hours. In general the whitest unbleached irs gave the whitest bleached Hours altho containing tiler amounts of nitrites. As shown above, both the iteming of the Hour ami the amount of nitrites formed ies as the amount of nitrogen peroxide used, provided : the latter is no! excessive and the manner of application lie same. The great difference in the effectiveness of it En amount of the peroxide is well illustrated by So*. :U :57. The two ubteached Hours had the same color, but latter gave a much whiter floor on I, leaching altho tin unt of nitrite formed was only half as great. The lower grades of Hour did not have their gray weakened and many of the bakers' grade appeared moi desirable in the bleached than in the unbleached cond the yellow tint of the latter partly obscuring the erav THK EFFECT (if BLEACHING 1'PON Till: ACIUIT1 Of the 4!) pairs of Hours tested (Table VIII i :!s show, difference in acidity between bleached and unbleaehe three pain the bleached Hour was slightlv less acid. Tl difference in the case of all but two of the eleven pairs wa very small. Evidently the differences in acidity of the pain are due to some other cause than bleaching, as thev ai not associated with large amounts of nitrites in the of the bleached Hours. It is fair to con, hide from the aliov, that bleaching as practised by the mills of this state does not increase the acidity of the Hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">/ 41 nbleathtd and bleached flour Acidity ™P Nitrites per Excess of bleache.1 '"i'li, 0 " f 1 ,- , f ''','", Mill grade of „„„,. of bleached bleachefl graue oi N rt ,1,.- OI n 'eacne&lt;i meactie l nour, n (lour. flour. flour. percent I 4.9 o.OO A Patent 06 .1.4 a Straight "7 4 4 0.00 A Bakers' OB :i i o.oo b i ii lit; o.oi B '»; X.B 0.00 C Patent If, 07 -J..") 0.00 C Straight !• Patent I&gt; Bakers' •J4 O."&gt; S.I 0.00 E i »; •s, 06 2.8 0.00 E Straight 11 07 8.8 —0.01 K Bakers- it; H Patent P Straight 1- Bakers' k; 0t» 0.0 0.00 G Patent • il (| 7 l.B Him Q Straight 11 4.4 O.U'l O Rakers (4 :«t •H t!.-2 0.«) ! H I'atent 14 4(1 l)T&gt; 8.3 0.01 M 'I II 07 10.0 o.itt h r. 4.". .05 S.I 0.00 I l it; l&gt;4 •'5.7 I —0.02 I Straight 47 M 12. '. 0.00 ; I Bakers' H 1 &gt;" -04 3.4 0.00 J Patent 4 •}1 04 S.I 0.U0 J I Straight M ti.-J 0.01 K Patent 56 117 5.0 0 0) K Straight 11 8.1 0.00 K Bakers' til .'$.s n.oi i, i 08 H AW t.t il 00 I S- Oti 74 .00 U.8 U.00 N 74 11 ' ~~&gt; .08 1.9 0.00 N Bakers' 08 1.9 0.00 N Bakers- IH .'.' .04 IS. 5 ill)) o I'atent 79 ill &lt;H 18.5 O.OU o Patent 01 BO .0.; 6-J 0.00 &lt;) Straight SO OH 6 11.00 i) Straight ""•• s l &lt;»8 t.| —0.(11 r I'atent ■M &lt;« 8.1 -0.01 P Patent '«' .M B.S 0.00 P Stn-Kht 10 8.1 0.00 P Straight (^ 86 B.O 0.00 P Bakers' 86 08 B.O 0.00 P Bakers' Q Patent n Straight i Q Straight iiT '.a l.S 6.(X)" R Patent •••■ i Q Bakers' Ion .07 1.9 0.00 R I ]■ I 09 &gt;M -0» 3.4 R Straight 00 3 4 o. id R ll&gt; 11(1 .10 i:t.7 0.00 R Bakers' 1U ld.o 0.00 S Patent U8 .08 3.1 O.IK) S Straight 10 110 10 i:t.7 0.00 R R 114 08 ltl.O 0.00 S Patent 08 3.1 0.00 S Straight 10 111". 10 5.0 0 00 S Bakers' 11" iw n'm t '~ Ktr 10 .'. O 0.00 S Bakers' </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 t k k 1 Table VIII — The aciditx of unbleached and bleached flout Ees Aciditv q. Acidity v ... .. _ ofun-' Senes of Nitrites per Ex., n- bleached .. No . . bleached n " U ' on Pf rt , s ,f " 1 " 1 1 'M he&lt;l flour, t)1^ he ' 1 flour of bleached bleached M r. per cent. *—• percent. flollr - flolIr ' Flour No. 117 wiis Itlcaclicil on February 18th, usin fiTi'iit aiiiounts of nitrogen peroxide. Ob the follow-in: the aridity was determined, with the following results Experiment No 1 Volume of nitrogen peroxide used t each 100) grains of flour Acidity, per cent Portions of Hour No. 14."&gt; treated with different an of Bitiofu peroxide oa October 16, 10(Mi. were teste a&lt;i&lt;litv on February 18, L907. The results are given in •22 zS ■&gt;i :*) M as .57 a .04 OH .08 .06 !oa .or, .04 .06 .07 .01 118 11!» 136 127 "ia»"' 14-J 143 06 .M 1 6 U7 .07 it; 1 .6 3.1 4.0 " 3.i' 3.7 H 12 5 0.00 0.00 0.00 0.00 0.01 0.00 o mi 0.00 o.oo T T V V V V V w \\" X X X Sti Ba l'a Sti l'a Sti Ka I 'a Sti Ha </seg>
            <seg id="p043">7 / 43 i i Acidity &gt;er cenl 07 10 mill ■ No US w hen the amount of nitrogen peroxide used did not exceed &lt; &lt; . per kilogram of dour, there was no appreciable ekaage acidity. Larger amounts of the peroxide caused an in asc in il 1( . acidity. reported an inn-ease in acid - probably experiatented with due to the bleaching hare rtreated Hours. THE ABSORPTION OF U. KACUKl) Fl.OIKS. determining the absorption of water, the different Hours not compared with a standard; in the case of each pair, leached Hour was compared with the corresponding an- bed sample. A dougn was made from ."&gt;(» grama i I of anbleacbed Hour and thirty grams of water. Then toga water was added to EM grama of the bleached Hour to ike a donga of the same stiffness as the first. There was ictically no difference in absorption between the bleached il the unbleached Hours. 1 11 .{&gt; 13 :m : 1 Those investigatora who Iwm vounts of nitrogen peroxide upon th, m ii r. ■ r \ ! ! ! : I v . , Volume of nitric ox No of ex uv . d to each kilogram Aciditv percent. ISO .10 IT.") M» iu aw . 10 11 :mj .ii M 4W .11 13 500 .11 U 1000 U Tahi. irptkm cf bUmcked and unbleaihcd flou leriment Series No of Absorption of Series No. of Absorption of unbleached unbleached bleached bleached fl " r - fi&lt;&gt;ur. flour. flour </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 . -la he rod oveni 1. wai mi unt i n ih i .ehed I" ten hed kin The strength of the giaten wtm determined by the m Porter's giaten tester, tin- method being aa follows: •'"nee (3i grams) of iinl»lcarli,.,l §onr and 280 grain* c of water were placed iii a cap a n&lt;l mixed thoioly with i rod until all the particle* adhering to the eop and to I kad collected into the ball of dough. The cap was ,■« and allowed to stand hair an boar before the stare] washed out in a stream of lukewarm water. After all i had been removed the giaten was covered with water the jilnteii from the corresponding bleached Boar had similarly obtained. The two gluten* were then placed two cylinders of the teater and baked twenty-five ininu »■&gt;" I\ il'.Ii' C.) in a -as oven. The weight* on the p of the tester Were removed at the end of |. MI minutes. B (teaching evidently had i tlV.t on the utren; tens. 1 H - {l I '3 16 in. 4ii 1 13 16 a 1/8 it, -' ■ 2 1 s Loarea of bread were made from i':: samples of nnble Hours, as w&lt;-ll as from the corresponding L':! 1. leached Horn The sani].les came from twelve different mills and i ■ented three grades, seven pain belonging to the patent to the straight, and six to the bakers'. The writer wei ind measured the ingredient*, while the mixing an I I,.- THK GUTTEN OT BIJ5ACHKD KI.OIU Tabi.k XI rj No. of No. of Bxpaaa No u " sts " f ""■ unblea glutens, bleached fl.m flour. J S 13 2 3/S ■ * « 2 5/33 in i * 'tT 1 13 It; i,, ■' * 13 2 9 Hi in BAKING TlOSTS OF Mil. I. r.l.i: aciikii 1-l.iM us </seg>
            <seg id="p045">/ 45 / i i ijrai i u i i in- l&gt;\ one of i lie best commercial bakers in Lincoln. re baked on four different days, along with the i\ mniercial product, in an oven heated bj wood, For Kio minus of dour, 5 grama of salt, ."&gt; gram of ngar, ompressed yeast wen- used. The loaves after aked were allowed to stand twenty hours, then brought iis Experiment Station, where they were accurately led and measured. The color, texture, odor, and ta-te wo members of each of the i'.&gt; pairs were compared volume of the loaf was ascertained by first tillini: a box was a little larger than the loaves, with granulated irring this down, striking oil' the top and neasuring ugar contained in the box. This quantity of sugar was 1 for the determinations. The bottom of the box was covered with a layer of the Mgar, a loaf placed on it m downwards and the sugar poured in, with constant nir of the box, until the latter was full. The surface was ■d off and all the su&lt;;nr remaining was measured. The ne of the sugar remaining was eqaal to tin- volume of the Two or more determination* of the volume of each loaf made, this being necessary to make sure that all the rrer- n the loaf had been tilled with sugar. The results are in Table XII. &lt;/' unbleached and bleached flours Wl of Volume Uported Bleached No. ,„;, of loaf U't ,,f &gt;&gt;■■"■■■&lt; - ■ported Bleached No. , "' of loaf r , , "le of or of 'f f in cubic C °I°' , ot lour. unbleached loaf. ctntime- erunin. M or \ Patent Unbleached 1 556 : 2146 Yellowish white Bleached M White A 3 MO ■-'&lt;«n Yellowish eht liibkached white A Bleached I :*\\s VM\ White .") 553 1908 Y'ellowish A Bakers' t'nl)kaclieil \ Bleached !'. Patent . . I'nbleached P» m * tcim. white I .V.4 l'.tt) White 7 :*4 . 1944 Yellowi&gt;h white </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 « » r 1 m ■d flour flour. —bleached, loaf. L. ceiitinu IU I'. I'atent -'.raight - Vil 3 H C 1S47 \Y MG6 ".til (nbleacheil 11 IH-.1 . . 1-J ifiM SI I E Patent K Straight B *n E Bakers ■*;i G 1* 1 Blea L'nl) II H Bak. tl II HI. Unl 41 I Bakers I'nbK I Bleach* J I'atent Unbleachc Bleached -irai^ht \ K Patent K Unbleached '.4.'» K Bakers K iraight p I R I'atent R Cublearhed .'!*.• Bleached . 40 Cnbleached 41 Bleached . 4J Unbleached 4:S Bleached 14 Unbleached )5 536 .V«u ")44 1833 W 1H17 Li R Straight k USB w l'.M4 I.i 18M U is-_".i Gi S Patent S :&gt;41 538 -iraight 115 S Bleached 4H 177:, \V vvt ,.t Volnmt Reported Bleached No. I . '. of loaf No. of Mill grade of or "' i '" '" cuhii *j a t.i i i i f Bleached t nbleachei 18-N) U is&lt;;t v, I'nbleached 13 bed 1 1 Unbleached 15 iu-&lt;l . It! 1708 Vi 17.-)4 \V Yt 17'.*) Yi E G M raisin ■&gt;-ji i u «U V Straight Iiibleacluil 31 Bleached 32 Bleached I nbleached 35 Bleached . 36 Unbleached 3"! Bleached 1872 Yi 1946 \V 1827 Yi </seg>
            <seg id="p047">/ / 47 I I i Vl&lt; Idea bullet "ached llour gave tin- whiter loaf. No ,vas detected ill tile texture, odor, Of taste of auy from unbleached Hours weighed 12,851 z. i. while the -'.I loaves from tin* bleached M»4 (28 lbs., 6 oz. i. The volume of the 1'3 rota unbleached Hours was 12,851 «■•■. c!,»&gt;l4 cubic and from the other 23 loaves. Il'.7."&gt;."&gt; cc. t L'.HOT cubic In eight pain the unbleached loaf was the heavier. the lighter, and in one. of the same weight as the In li' pain the unbleached loaf was the larger, in I lie smaller, and iu one pair of the same size. The ir in weight and volume ltetween tin- two members were small and only sueh as might occur in the wo loaves made from the same llour. In all rases the vs were of practically the same size and weight. I ata given in Table XII should not In- used as a liasis larison of the bread-making qualities of the flours i-tured li,\ the different mills. The methods of treat - needing, time of fermentation, ete., necessary to ob- best bread may differ much for two different Hours. i these experiments all the Hours received the atmeiit. Further, the loaves were baked on four dif- ti OD one of which all the bread was decidedly l&gt;e - rage. It is a matter of common knowledge that isideralile variation in the product of a baker's fi lay to day. However, the above data arc ap- a comparison of tin baking qualities of the urs with those of the unbleached. Tn the cat pair the two loaves were kept side by side from the time being until they were measured. The conditions, favor - in- unfavorable, were the same for both. K OF A KI.OI I! TREATED WJTII IUKKKUKNT AMOUNTS OF NITROGEN PEROXIDE •ur Xo. 147 was used in this series of experiments, the hing being conducted as described on page 31 of this tin. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 la teXtlll i i utaiu All live- loaves were baked at the same time as iln of those given in Table XI. All were of linr. even and with the exception of the last were of agreeable &lt; flavor. No. ."&gt; had a must y odor ami taste, hut was This liakinji test confirm* the conclusion already dn th&lt;- use of move than L56 ee. of nitrogen peroxide gram of Sour is objectionable. Till: AMIUM nl MTUITES IN UICKAH MAI FLOIKS The method of determining tli was the same as that used in tin II) ( then ground to a powder. The mini from Hours Nos. 81, G2, 1 1, and loaves could be easily distinguished Ii was not possible to tell to which ii the four loaves belonged. According they are i tioned in Table XII. hut as none of lhe four bleached loaves contained nitrites they are mentioned in Tdble XIII. 1 evident that the bread made from bleached llo contains nitrites and at other times does not, dependi the treatment that the bread has received. In the ease of tw baking* all the loaves made from bleached Bonn c* nitrites, while in the ease of two oilier bakincH none of th loaves contained nitrites In the ease of the tirst t portion &lt;&gt;f each loaf was tirsi dri&lt; in?: unbleached flours, were lost E\]&gt;eriiiient ■r of loaf e of nitric oxi&lt;le, in used ]k.t kilogram of t of l&lt;iaf i in .ran e of loaf (in cc. i )f crumb 1 47 ii :»4."i 191H Almost white •&gt; N 041 IW7 Pure white too 1U8] Pure white I M I ".41 •J 1 1 1"» Pure whit </seg>
            <seg id="p049">/ 49 i i nn lea f in i nut of nitrites was o.s, while the aver- tea in the Boar from which the loaves u-ts per million. There was no relation of nitrite in the Hour and that in the ed (lie writer, in a private eoininnniea - il made from unbleached Hour is baked mid to contain nil riles. Inn when wood heat nitrites are absent. from bit ached //ours n Said number I'.irts ]h.t million of nitrite In Hour. In bread. 1 li s 111 12 11 16 3.4 4.4 S.I j :&gt; :t.l 0.6 1.6 o.a 1.6 0.3 90 30 i i 6 -J loo 3.7 12.5 .'..4 3.1 e.i I.I 0-2 o.-j II 4 8.3 0.0 1 •-&gt;.-&gt; 1 .it S.I no 0.0 o.o to 4-J 41 16 M 1 '.&lt; 3.4 10.U :s.l ii o o o II. II 0.0 0.0 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 THE OCCURRENCE OF NITRITES IX SALIVA It has long been recognised that nitrite* an- usuallv pi that the amount of nitrites, calculated as nitrous acid, vai Cram 0.4 to l'.o part« per million, in the same individual In mi- to hour Specimens of saliva from all the member* sixty-five students were tested for nitrites by the &lt;ii ray reagent. In each case from r&gt; to in cc. oi treated with l' cc of the reageni and warmed to 17t trites. In the case of six persons working it laboratory the quantities of nitrites were determini of V (Table XIV) th hours of tlie da\ "The quantity of saliva secreted during ~ lie exactly determined, Inn has been ca Schmidt to be 14(M» to 1500 gran the saliva is as low as 0.6 parts per million, tin- to produced in the saliva in tin nine ten-thousandths of a -ram i or on In the case of S the dailv ret n (UMi7r&gt; -rams i one-ninth of a main Table XIV.— Am Hoi Dec. 28 R 3 P. M B c I - 1 1 - 1- I V !• A.M 111 ■• •1 V. M J:TO ■ :5KO : Hammerstein, Physiological Chemistry, p. : Berichte der deu'sohen chemischen G 'Hammerstein, Physiological Ch. ■: eiit in human saliva. 1 (Jrii-ss- as Jon- ago as !&gt;;- iS(| C). Every specimen gave a distinct reacti Assuming that the averag ta E* ■&gt;•'&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 1 I U. ACTION OF NITRATES AND NITRITES. of salts arc the only chemical compounds r been proven to be added to Hour in the proc- ronsider their physiological action, is used in doses of from ."&gt; to grata s a diuretk and diaphoretic. In Iti irgation and cardiac sedation and, when I Hiaiiiities of y 2 ounce i l»i (HUM) or more in concen - lution, it may produce death. 1 ithstanding the poisonous properties of potassium hen taken in largely concentrated solution, it may in divided doses, to the extent of one to two ooncea 60.0 grams i in twenty-four hours, if copiously di - h water. Administered in this way the salt ac v n the circulation. &gt; n nitrate is rarely used in medicine. It has hem as a remedy in diarrhoea and dysentery in daily from 1 to 2 ounces (30 to &lt;&gt;&lt;&gt; grams). N i t ra occur in large amounts in many vegetable prod U foods. Nitrates have also beta used for redden - meats for so long a time that Bideal was unable to &gt;rigin of the practice. 4 mi nitrate is sometimes used by packers to pre- rhe nitrites, in comparison with the nitrates, are very pmv - ul drugs, and because of their presence in bleached Hours 11 latter have been severely condemned in one publication.* Amyl nitrite is a pow-erful cardiac stimulant and anti- ismodic. and is very valuable bv inhalation or by the mouth N Standard Dispensatory, p. 1248 I'nited States Dispensatory, Seventeenth Edition, p. 1108. National Standard Dispensatory, n 1412. ♦Rideal. Disinfection and Preservation of Foods, p. 409 'National Standard Dispensatory, p. 1249. Bulletin 72. North Dakota Agricultural Experiment Station v means ol nitrogen peroxide. Heine ii be- </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 i \ in whooping cough, anyina peetoris and certain fw asthma. The dose is from '2 to Hi drop* i o. l u&gt; y\.7&gt; gn "It produces cyanosis, throbbing in the head, vert ciiiiu. roaring in the cars, etc., and linalh relaxation. ••Sodium nitrite, like potassium nitrite, exerts tli&lt; influence upon ilic human organism as docs amyl nitrit account of the slowness of its absorption and eliminat effect is more prolonged. It is given in doses ol from grains i o.o&lt;&gt; to o.i'O gran). In doses of - to ;» grains ii relieves pain witln symptoms attending the use of larger do« Jt lias been shown above that ide used for each kilogram of Hour in the Nebn amounts in general to less than that correspond iu« of nitric oxide, while there is no |u cc. being used in auv rase. The ma thai can be produced from the gas arc 0.08 and 0.60 gram res] i rites produced by these quani 0.015 and 0.050 gram respective ahlc that the accompanying we proximately 0.0H5 and o.."&gt;it gram. &lt;&gt; produces three one-pound loaves of brea&lt; eat a pound loaf daily he would lake the dicinal dose of nitrate in from every ten and a medicinal dose of nitrites in tl Whether there will be any nitrites at all as has been pointed out above, upon the The amount of nitrites secreted daily amount to as much as ten times the nua in tlie loaf richest in nitrites. The amount of niti mally present in human foods and drinks probably 'Parke Davis &amp; Co.. Manual of T • National Standard Dispensatory. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 / It is e\ rgelv \ of 1,1 o,4O sra I 1 1 1 1 : 1 1 of th 111 be tiiki-n in the form of bread mad* bread made from bleached loon lias the characteristic symptoms of either HIM! AM) BKOMINE L'PON FLOU1 14."&gt; w;ts treated with different amounts ol tromine. The maximum effect was produced ■ bleaching agents for each kilogram of Bow. lamity of the bleaching agent exceeded o.s gram bromine or &lt;&gt;.:;."» gram iu that of cMorin &gt;f ttour there was an increase in the acidity of reater the excess of the bleaching agent tin • Hour. he following lest ii is possible to detect a •en bleached by chlorine or bromine e?en antity of bleaching agent used does not .■&gt; f chlorin • 0.08 gram of bromine per kilogram »&gt;ne ounce (30 grams) of the Hoar is extracted ■ne. and tlu- latter evaporated. A small amount is. A piece of copper wire is heated in a color e until it is black and no longer colors the tlaim t end of the wire is dipped into the oil and nto the flame. If chlorine or bromine has been teaching agent, a green or blue coloration is lent from the above test that chlorine and bromine absorbed by tin- oil of the flour. When the quan - tching agent used exceeded o.l7."&gt; gram of chlorine in of bromine per kilogram of Hour it was possible e the amount that had been used. A waterv ex - e floor was prepared ami titrated with decinormal hitioii. It was found that in each case j»rac- pproxiwatety 0.7 grui and L6 gram, re« </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 tically half of tin- chlorine or bromine added to the il bees, left ;is chlorides or bromides. SUMMARY AM) CONCLUSIONS. The work of previous investigators had already establishes that the bleaching of Hour, as commercially practi to the action of nitrogen peroxide. Then- was n gen lement, however, as to the effect of the bleaching in»on t! qualities of tin* Hour. A review of the above tables and detailed results bri with it the following conclusion V bleached Hour nia.v with certainty lie distinguished in unbleached Hour, and the kind of bleaching a nt ployed may be identified as nitrogen peroxide or hal (chlorine or bromine). The amount of bleaching agen trogen peroxide, chlorine or bromine) that lias been io ;i flour may be estimated from the amount of cert lion products remaining in the flour. With the Griess-Ilosvav reageni all ti means of nitrogen peroxide gave a pink colorai bleached Hours gave no coloration. Only wh Ktions are observed is the test reliable. (leached Hours lying alongside of unbleach L r ive oil' any substance which will so affect the lattei will pive the test for bleached Hours. Neither nit i ide nor nitrous acid is present in bleached flours, tin teristie reaction being produced by the nitrit The amount of nitrites in bleached Hours is verv small, tin BVCTftge beiBg &amp;3 parts per million for all the samp]' amined. There is little difference in the amount of nitrit* produced by the two kinds of bleacher The amount of nitrite in a bleached flour is approximately proportional to the amount of nitrogen peroxide that ha been used. The average amount of the bleaching agent used by twenty-five Nebraska mills would accordingly lie approxi- </seg>
            <seg id="p055">i i th Ml II I &lt; «ii i-;i 1 1 1 of Hum-. The use of more than L50 xitlc per kilogram injure* ilic cola* and _• qualities of a Hour. Low grade Mum arc is in resemble a patent Hour. or of Hours m due to a very minute quantity iv&lt;i siiltstiiiicc which is contained in the oil or fat of . When the oil is removed high grade Hours become Exposure to the sunlight or i real incut with nitrogen ■ changes the colored compound into one or more i compounds. I tot li the oil and solutions of the oil liorolv bleached Soar are practically colorless. Over - (so-called "overbleaehed" ) Hours hare a yellow to isli yellow color; the fat. as well as solutions of the fat. •viTtreatetl Hours are colored. general relation exists between the colors of mill •ached Hours and the quantities of nitrites present. hing docs not increase the acidity of Hours, while it ing them with nitrogen peroxide docs. N he absorption of a Hour nor the expansion of its r bv bleaching. ide from bleached Hours docs not differ in weight, exturc. odor, or taste from thai made from lin- ed Sours; ii is. however, in all cases whiter, where high flours are used. Low grade flours when bleached pro - read with an uninviting color. re is no difference in the effect u|M&gt;n the bread-making ies whether a chemical or an electrical bleacher is n- [{leached Hours sometimes yield bread containing nitrites &lt;l at other times bread free of nitrites. In all cases the unt of nitrite in the bread is much smaller than that in Hour. Nitrites, while harmful when taken in large doses, occur &gt;!&lt; I \ distributed in nature. The amount of nitrites nor - illy occurring in human saliva is large compared with that the bread eaten. Likewise the quantity of nitrat </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 The Efcci of Bleaching Upon Wheat I nil \ lot', til Ii sufti i I" * ilan ■&lt;1 liv ai bleached Sou is m small that ii is of n&lt;&gt; phj importance. {lie use of aitrogea peroxide in the quantities &lt;-ni| mills of Nebraska whitens the high grade floors lting bread without affecting the composition, &lt;&gt;&lt;) hit. or weight, and without addiug any sulistain-i t quantities to !«' injtiriims. the qnantitj &lt;&gt;i' peroxide may l»&lt;- so isereaaed slv injure the quality of the Soar, ba&lt; ;is mk-1i a ivoraldy affects the color of the Hour there is b iieh overtreated flour being intentionally produc&lt; er. \i KNOWI.KIH! Mi:\l An expression of thanks is extended to the mi lu-aska. whose hearty cooperation has made |&gt;o»* vest igat ion of the effects of bleaching Eoiuinercial scale. Thanks are also due Mr. K xl Mr. B. .M. Pinckney, assistants in the Depa ultural ( 'heniistrx . who have made the gi analyses reported in the preceding pagi </seg>
            
            <seg id="p057">NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD .ES KIRNS!. /', . \LLKN. I. \\ M. G. \\ H1TMOK1 Y REDERICK II. ABBO1 I \ U T&lt; »R G. LYFORD, lal CHAS. B. AM THE STATION OFFICERS E. A HI k N I I I \\M. W. MAKS1 THE WORKING STAFF II. R. Smith, B \. T. Pe i i k-. I KKK K I). I I \\.\\ . I'M \. I.. II \K&lt; KER, Lawrence Hki see. B.S .. I MO.N l(,u\IKK\ . I'.. Si ., I I k vnk I Phillips, Ml Kku in li. Bakmm k. 1'fi. I)., i ( i. R. I MATBIKN, A.M., 1 1 EmEKSON, It.Si .. II, till, idtltli \\ . P. Snvdcr, MS, Superintendent Experin I. H. Gain, M.D.C., Assodmte in Amimai Pat \. F. Magdakz, |k., A.I&gt;.. Assistant in Anin ■■tan/ in . Inninil \ A. Habtzell, MA.. Assistant in Che* E. M. Little, IS.Sc.A.. Assistant in Dairy Hu Maktin Nelson, M S \nt in Field &lt; n / I I Dcxi in //nr/ 1, i: P Irrigation oVK.l.AM). B.Sl ., fit R, A.M., 5 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>