<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00034">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0034</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Proposed Method for Classifying and Evaluating Soils on the Basis of Productivity and Use Suitabilities</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001"/>
         <seg id="p002">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 98 ; A Proposed Method for Classifying and Evaluating Soils on the Basis of Pro - ductivity and Use Suitabilities Arthur Anderson, A. P. Nelson, F. A. Hayes, and I. D. Wood IJNCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY, 1938 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Introduction . ' . 3 Procedure 4 Type area 4 I Jctermination of slope and erosion conditions on soil types 6 Determination of present land use according to soil types 9 Determination nl base acreages 9 Productivity ratings 12 Application .33 </seg>
         <seg id="p004">A Proposed Method for Classifying and Evaluating Soils on the Basis of Productivity and Use Suitabilities ARTHUR ANDERSON, A. P. NELSON, . F. A. HAVES, AND I. D. WOOD 1 During recent years increasing attention has been directed toward land-use planning and conservation, and the need for developing more effective systems of land classification and evaluation is thus becoming more urgent. Correct land use and conservation, equitable assessments and appraisals, and economic and social stability are dependent basically on sound land evaluation. Various systems of classification. have been used or proposed. Many of-them, designed to meet specific objectives, have been restricted in their application because of insufficient basic. information. They range from generalized surveys, physical, economic, or a combination of these, to relatively detailed surveys in which a variety of land types are mapped in accordance with differences in soils, relief, drainage, and cultural features, and are evaluated in terms of their agricultural possibilities. Obviously, the fundamental part of any land classification system must be based on the physical factors which are relatively stable. Economic and other more transitory factors then may be introduced to serve specific purposes. It is the object of this paper to present a method for classifying and evaluating the soils as mapped in regular soil surveys on the basis of land types, which are here defined as areas having reasonably similar pro - ductivity and use suitabilities. 2 The standards used to differentiate land types will vary according to the desired objectives, but any material differ - ence in yield, or in practices necessary to maintain a desirable level of productivity will justify recognition of land types. The materials necessary for the procedure in this study are (1) county soil survey maps and reports, (2) detailed land-use, slope, and erosion maps for selected farms or areas, (3) crop acreage estimates by soil types, and (4) average county production estimates. The total acres in each land type to be evaluated and the acreages of the various crops grown thereon are estimated on the basis of this information. Relative pro - ductivity ratings are then assigned and yields calculated on the basis of these ratings, the allotted acreages, and county production. : Soil survey maps and reports have been published or the field work 1 Official positions of the authors arc as follows: State Specialist Land Use Planning, Farm Security Administration (formerly Land Use Planning Section, Resettlement Administration); Regional Land Claijificaiion Specialist, Farm Security Administration (also, formerly Resettlement); Senior Soil Scientist, Bureau of Chemistry and Soils, U. S. Department of Agriculture, and Conservation and Survey Division, University of Nebraska; and Extension Agricultural Engineer, University of Ne - braska College of Agriculture. '.:-,¦ Suggestions and criticisms from staff members of the University of Nebraska and the Soil Con - servation Service are gratefully acknowledged. Special acknowledgment is due the Soil Conservation Service for supplying the 43 Johnson county farm maps, and to the Johnson County Agricultural Conservation Association tor supplying the 12S /arm records. aThc Bureau of Chemistry and Soils, United States Department of Agriculture, is credited with pioneer. work in rating numerically the soils e-f the United States, on the basis of productivity. Such ratings, are now a part of the; Federal Soil Survey Reports. Several states havt also developed similar ratings for land classification purposes. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 completed for all counties in Nebraska excepting eight in the sandhill region by the Bureau of Chemistry and Soils, United States Department of Agriculture, in cooperation with the Conservation and Survey Division, University of Nebraska. More than 400 soil types (including phases) have been described and mapped in Nebraska. The proposed procedure involves a move detailed study of the influence which soils, slope, erosion, and drainage have on specific crops and practices than is contained in the county soil survey reports. It would appear logical to develop it on an area basis, first by selecting counties in which the soils, their environment, and the agricultural practices are fairly typical of the area as a whole, and then enlarging to include all the state. Johnson county, located in the center of the drift-hill area ot southeastern Nebraska, was selected to illustrate the procedure, PROCEDURE TYPE AREA [ohnson county is in the prairie-grass region of the United States. The soils have developed on loess and glacial drift formations, either in situ or on alluvium washed from these formations. The greater part of the parent material was formerly calcareous. A rather high precipita - tion, about 31 inches per annum, has removed nearly all of the lime to depths beyond the reach of most crops except in some of the situations where the soils are relatively impervious or are developing on limy material that has been recently deposited or exposed. Most of the soils are slightly to medium acid in reaction, especially in the upper part of the profile. Except where they are severely eroded or are on recent alluvium, their topsoils are dark—in places almost black. The intensity of the dark color and the depth to which the color extends vary widely with differences in gradient and direction of slope and in the length of time that the soils have lain undisturbed by abnormal erosion. On many of the steeper slopes the dark topsoil has heen removed or failed to develop, and the slightly modified loess or drift is exposed. It should be recognized that topsoil does not develop to a uniform thickness even under what appear to be identical conditions. Furthermore, it generally merges with the underlying subsoil through such a thick transition zone that its lower limit cannot be determined exactly. Transition zones also occur between the subsoil and parent material. For these reasons any thickness ascribed to a soil horizon should vary within a suitable range and should be based on existing rather than on assumed former profiles. The various soils in Johnson county :| are delimited on the soil map and are described in the report of that area. The two soils mapped on the bottom lands, namely, Wabash silt loam and Wabash very fine sandy loam, which collectively comprise 14.1 per cent of the county, are essentially equal in productivity and use suitabilities and are regarded as a single land type. For a similar reason, the two soils on the terraces, 'Soil Survey ol lohnson coiinly. ScWailu. Field opcrationi. Unreal, of Chcminry and Soil!, 1920. ".hllihcil 1924. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils Waukesha silt loam and Waukesha very fine sandy loam, comprising 3.4 per cent of the county, are regarded as a land type. Two conditions are recognized, however, in the soils on the bottom lands and terraces, i.e., moderately to well drained crop land, and other land which may be poorly drained. The six soils of the uplands occupy the remainder of the county. Only one of these, Grundy silt loam, has developed on loess. The rest are on glacial drift. They are silt loam and loam types of the Carrington and Pawnee soils, and a loam type of Shelby soil. The acreages of the different soils and the percentages of the county occupied by each are shown in Table 1. • Table I.— Total acres in Johnson county, Nebraska, by soil types and in 43 jarms mapped by the Soil Conservation Service. ¦¦ ¦¦ ~~~ - ' ¦¦. ¦¦¦¦¦ county 1 Soil Conservation Service . ¦ - - ¦ farms ¦ Soil Type Number 2 Percent Acres Per cent of farms Acres (of type ' . ¦' ' involved total) Soils of the bottom lands Wabash silt and very fine sandy loams 33856 14.1 11 303.1 0.9 Soils of the terraces Waukesha silt and very fine ¦ : sandy loams. 8128 3.4 4 43.6 0.5 Soils of the uplands Grundy silt 10am............ 15616 6.5. 8 996.5 6.4 Carrington silt loam 71168 29.7 25 2826.3 4.0 Carrington 10am..... 46400 19.4 ." 17 1081.2 2.3 Pawnee- silt 1c0n'............ 39872 16.7 13 1234.9 3.1 Pawnee 10am.:........ 10880 4.6 7 514.3 4.7 Shelby 10am................ 13440 5.6 [ 9 418.9 3.1 Ail 1and..................... 239360 ldO.o 43 7418.8 3.1 1 From Soil Survey of Johnson county, Nebraska.- - . ;' ¦ .' . a In certain instances, two or more soil types as mapped in the regular toil survey occur on ihc umc farm. The arcal distribution of these soils was superimposed upon the Soil Conservation Ser - vice farm map in order to determine the land.types involved (sceiFig. 2). ; . . ¦ The factors which affect the productivity and use suitabilities through - out the uplands are so variable,. even within areas mapped as a single soil type, that each of the soil types has been separated into land types on the basis of differences in the slope gradient and severity of erosion. 4 The .land types are evaluated separately and the evaluations are later combined Jin order to determine the productivity of the different soils delimited on the soil map. Similar slope and erosion conditions on the two Car - rington soils are given the same rating. When weighted, however, accord - ing to the acreages in the respective conditions, the composite ratings for the silt loam and loam soils differ materially. The same situation'obtains with respect to the Pawnee silt loam and Pawnee loam. :. 4 Current soil surveys are recognizing slope and erosion conditions, but extensive publications of maps on a scale to show such detail is generally prohibitive. . </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 DETERMINATION OF SLOPE AND EROSION CONDITIONS ON SOIL TYPES The slope and erosion conditions on the different soils in Johnson county were estimated from data obtained on forty-three farms which were mapped (eight inches to the mile) by the Soil Conservation Service. The total acreage of each soil type mapped on these farms (based on the Johnson county soil survey) is shown in Table 1. The location of the forty - three farms is shown by soil areas in Figure 1, and one farm map is shown in detail in Figure 2. Three and six-tenths per cent of the area occupied by the soils of the uplands is included in the forty-three farms or from two and three-tenths to six and four-tenths per cent of each of the soil types delimited on the regular soil map. Since the farms are rather evenly distributed, they furnish an adequate sample upon which to base determinations regarding the influence of slope and erosion on the pro - ductivity and use suitabilities of all soils on the uplands. The slope and erosion classifications and interpretations of the Soil Conservation Service are used. The slope ranges in this county are as follows: A 0-3 per cent B 3-7 per cent BB 7-10 per cent C 10-15 per cent D . over 15 per cent Slope Groups B and BB are here combined, however, since the sub - group was not recognized in all instances. The interpretations of the influence which various slope gradients have on cultural practices are: A Slope, no restrictions; B Slope, certain cultural but no crop restrictions; C Slope, certain cultural restrictions and crops limited to those which are close drilled; and D Slope, permanent removal from cultivation with additional conservation practices. Although smoothness, exposure, and length of slope may affect crop growth, they are not recognized in this procedure because of the limited information. The erosion classification is as follows: 1 No surface soil lost 2 . oto 25 per cent of surface soil lost 3 25 to 50 per cent of surface soil tost ii 50 to 75 per cent of surface soil lost 4 75 to 100 per cent of surface soil lost 5 Topsoil entirely removed by erosion It is recognized that this erosion classification is subject to limitations in that these estimates are applied to the soils mapped in the regular soil survey when they were based on profiles of the soils as mapped by the Soil Conservation Service. Furthermore, no attempt was made by the authors to interpret the effect which gullies may have on productivity or use suitabilities. Gullies in themselves, if recognized as separate land types, would not materially affect the yields of the intervening land. They may, however, because of their position and extent, become important </seg>
         <seg id="p008">L itfitND ¦.:,¦: -,"¦' SCXLS Of THE fIOfTOM LANDS AMD TERRACES SOILS OF The UPLANDS CONTto. ' l~~= j PAWNte LOAM SOILS Of- TM&amp; UPLANDS I I - |¦;' . | CHUMOY *.LT UJAM |!}C| P*WNte A«IT UMM ¦ " [^ I CA«I»INCTON SIUT UDAM |. ¦»J SHELBY U)AM " ¦ .. )•"»;. |.—Lncation of the farms used to determine en on the ilittcrcnt soil types in Johnsur </seg>
         <seg id="p009">SOILS OF THE UPLANDS CONTID. " ;. . : . ' " . ;•' ;¦ : ¦ X^yi CARRtHCTON LtMM LOCATION OP FAAMS USED TO WTEAMINE , ; ' .'[ '¦. ¦¦ _^_^ - r~| CMPP^IC SYSTEMS HO1»! \-Z^t&gt;l\ ¦ ¦ ' i=! ¦ ';¦¦ -¦¦ . . ¦ " 10' L AHtA) ftUCtO - [^ MWNW. LOAM .. Q CROW.MG SYSTEM*. «U3«S AND EWtION "' .. [^j^MK.S.ULWM .[J SLOPK ANS tROS»M ; :". ; : ¦•¦ .^ " . V;' ;- " ' [&#132;» J SHELBY LOAM " ..... the farms used to determine cropping systems, slopes, and erosion ie tlilTercrnt soil types in Johnson county. Nebraska. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 9 Table 2.— The acres in crop land and other land by soil types and their distribution into slope groups and erosion classes for 41 farms in Johnson county, Nebraska, mapped by the Soil Conservation Service. ... p Percentage distribution into slo]&gt;c groups and erosion classes "f Acres A B I C D use | 21 2JJJ-&gt;s|l 2 3 334 234 drundy silt loam Cropland 750.9 7.08 6.53 U.-4H 10.59 72.83 2.26 012 0.11 Other land 245.6 18.52 16.49 SO.SK 14.41 . Total 996.5 9.90 4.92 4.43 2U.44 58.43 1.71 0.09 0.08 Carrin^'lon silt hum Crop land 2131.4 2.37 7.42 0.90 7.26 76.05 5.30 o.4** . 0.21 Othcrland 694.9 7.66 I.UB 24.98 31.58 30.11 2.25 U.I 2 0.86 1.08 0-2-4 0.04 Total 2826.3 3.67 5.86 6.82 13.24 64.76 4.55 0.37 0.03 0.21 0.42 0.06 0.01 I'arrinKtun loam Cropland 670.2 15.59 0.25 0.93 6.60 47.59 22.86 4.74 1.19 0.10 0.15 Othcrland 411.0 15.18 3.87 26.04 20.31) 11.31 11.44 1.14 1).46 1.58 17. 49 1.68 0.24 0.27 Total 1081.2 15.44 1.63 10.46 11.80 33.80 14.34 3.38 0.18 0.60 fi.65 0.74 0.06 0.73 0.09 0.10 Pawnee silt loam Cropland 1048.7 5.23 4.55 0.4 X 2.06 79.08 7.32 0.73 0.24 0.19 0.08 0.04 Othcrland 186.2 16.43 30.67 27.39 14.18 5.53 2.90 2.90 Total 1234.9 6.92 3.86 5.03 5.88 69.30 7.05 0.62 0.44 0.20 0.60 0.07 0.03 Pawnee loam Cropland 322.3 3.54 2.89 48.40 41.82 2.36 0.99 Other land 192.0 9.48 2.29 2.81 45.84 15.83 2.08 .1.82 18.44 1.41 Total 514.3 5.76 0.86 1.05 18.92 36.23 26.99 1.48 0.68 6.88 1.15 Shelby loam Cropland 260.7 3.49 . .. 2.03 7.33 60.07 24.59 1.53 0.96 ... ... Othcrland 158.2 19.41 . . 11.69 19.66 26.98 2.47 4.24 14.03 0.32 0.38 0.82 ... Total 418.9 9.50 ... 5.68 11.98 47.59 16.23 2.55 5.30 0.12 ... 0.60 0.14 0.31 All soils Cropland 5184.2 5.47 4.94 0.76 6.34 69.99 10.78 1.19 0.04 0.19 0.17 0.06 0.03 0.02 0.02 -land 1887.9 12.74 1.47 21.30 31.64 20.69 1.89 0.60 0.10 0.85 7.18 0.85 0.49 0.14 0.06 Total 7072.1 7.41 4.02 6.24 13.09 56.82 8.41 1.03 0.03 0.23 1.95 0.36 0.13 0.05 0.15 0.05 0.03 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Proposed Method-of Classifying and Evaluating Soils and slopes and under the various erosion conditions. There is less crop land than other land on the steeper slopes, but within a slope group the crop land is the more subject to erosion. Based on the 43 farms, 11.43, 85.62, 2.72, and 0.23-vper cent, respectively, of all upland is in Slope : Groups A, B, C, and D. In comparison, 13.88,19.21, 57.23, 8.54,1.11, and 0.03 per cent of all upland is in.Erosion Classes 1, 2, 3, 33, 4, and 5. Estimates pertaining to the total acres in crop and other land by slope groups and erosion classes are shown in Table 3 for the six soils of the uplands. These data were obtained by applying the percentages reported in Table 2 to the estimates for crop and other land shown by soil types j in Table 4. ' \ :¦¦'.'¦¦¦'.'¦ ¦'. ¦"• DETERMINATION OF PRESENT LAND USE ACCORDING TO SOIL TYPES The use made of different soils during 1935 and 1936 was determined I for 128 tracts of land from records of the Johnson County Agricultural j Conservation Association and is shown in Table 4. The tracts are occupied !. largely or entirely by one kind of soil, and most of them comprise entire ! farms. Their combined area is about ten per cent of the county, and since i they are so distributed that five or more of them occur on each of the I different kinds of soil (Figure 1), the cropping practices followed on these tracts in 1935 and 1936 are applied to the total acreages of corresponding soils within the county. When this is done, the total acreages for the county | agree rather closely with those obtained by the U. S. Census, Bureau of ! Agricultural Economics, and Nebraska Department of Agriculture; and the Johnson County Agricultural Conservation Association (Table 5). It may be concluded that differences in the acreages of specific crops as reported in this table occur without respect to soiljtype. Variations in cropping practices on different soils are no more marked than within areas of the same soil. In a few instances it appears that the cropping system has been adjusted to certain soil characteristics, but in general, differences in soils, unless especially pronounced, are not recognized. ." i „. DETERMINATION OF BASE ACREAGES .; Although there is some variation in the proportion of crop land to other land under the various conditions, cropped fields are not generally laid out on the basis of soil, slope, and erosion lines; The data in Tables 2 and 4 may be used, therefore, to estimate not only the acreages of specific crops on each of the different soils, but also on areas differing in slope and erosion. It is thus possible to break down the total or base acreages assigned to the different crops in table 4 (last line) into crop acreage estimates for the various land types. Such estimates are shown in Tables 6 to 11 for corn, wheat, oats, alfalfa, other crops, and other land (permanent pasture). </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 11 Table 3.— The acres in crop land and other land by slope groups and erosion classes for the six soils of the uplands in Johnson county, Nebraska, as based on 43 farms mapped by the Soil Conservation Service. Type Acres by slope groups ami erosion classes ° f A B C 5 ™ use 1 2 I 2 3 il 4 5 1 2 i ii 4 2 3 4 (irundy silt loam Cropland 851 785 5H 127-4 8757 272 . H 13 12024 Other land 665 592 1817 518 3592 Total 1516 785 650 30') 1 &lt;&gt;275 272 H 13 15616 Carrmjilnn silt loam Cropland 1231 3855 -168 3772 30510 2753 255 109 51953 Other land H72 208 4800 6068 5786 432 23 Ifis 207 46 8 19215 Total 2703 4063 5268 9840 45296 3185 255 [ 23 165 M 6 . 46 8 '. 71168 Carrinyton loam Cropland 4846 78 289 2052 14794 7107 1474 370 31 47 31088 Other land 2324 593 3988 3108 1732 67 175 70 2-12 2678 257 37 41 15312 Total 7170 671 4277 5160 16526 7174 1649 70 242 2678 370 31 304 37 41 46400 Pawnee silt loam Cropland 1606 1397 147 632 24279 22H7 224 . . 74 58 25 12 30701 Other land 1507 2813 2512 1300 507 266 266 9171 Total 3113 U97 2960 3144 25579 2754 224 ~~ 266 7l 32l 2l ~~ 12 ~ 39872 Pawnee loam Cropland 281 230 3844 3321 187 ... 79 7942 Other land 279 67 83 1347 465 61 53 542 41 2938 Total 56() 67 83 1577 43b1&gt; 3382" 187 ~. 53 542 !20 ~~. ~~. ~~ ~ 10880 Shelby loam Cropland 300 .. 175 631 5167 2115 131 ........ 83 8602 Other land 939 . 566 951 1305 120 205 679 15 18 40 ... 4838 Total 1239 T~ 74l 1582 6471 2235 JiG ~. ~ 679 15^ ~7. 83 18 40 .. . 13440 All soils : Cropland 9115 6115 1137 8591 96351 17815 2271 74 246 395 114 59 14 13 H2310 Othcrland 7186 868 12842 15803 11106 1187 380 70 584 4064 529 321 85 41 55066 Total 16301 6983 13979 24394 107457 19002 2651 70 584 4138 775 395 114 380 99 54 197376 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 12 Table 4.— Average of 1935 and 1936 crop acreages by soil types as de - termined from 128 records of the Johnson, county, Nebraska, Agricut - . ; turd Conservation Association. Number Acres and per cent 1 records Farmland |. Cropland ;,-. Total Crop Other Corn Wheat Oats Alfalja Other : SOILS OFTHE BOTTOM LANDS | . Wabash silt and very fine sandy loams ; 14 2356 1681 675 768 588 166 76 83 : 100 71 29 46 35 . 10 4 5 33856 24038 9818 11057 8413 2404 962 1202 SOILS OF THE TERRACES Waukesha silt and very fine sandy loams 5 952 790 162 292 ' 251 ' 64 40 143 • 100 83 17 37 32 .8 5 18 8128 6746 1382 2496 2159 540 337 1214 ¦. &#132; SOILS OF THE UPLANDS . .'.-¦¦ -. Grundy silt loam • 21 3750 2891 859 1169 854 340 196 . 332 100 77 23 40 30 12 7 11 15616 12024 3592 , 4809 3607 . 1443 842 1323 Carrington silt loam 24 4641 3372 1269 1250 960 417 238 507 - -100 73 27 37 29 | ,12 . 7 15 - 71168 51953 19215 19223 15066 : 6234 3637 7793 Carrington loam 21 3174 2140 1034 813 492 341 67 427 100 67 33 38 ' 23 16 3 20 46400: 31088 15312 11814 7150 4974 933 6217 . . Pawnee silt loam 21 .3666 2825 841 1229 688 493 129 286 ? 100 77 23 . 44 24 . 17 5 10 '39872 30701 9171 13509 7368 5219 1535 3070 ¦ . Pawnee loam 12 '¦ 2233 1620 613 747 286 241 52 294 100 73 27 46 18 15 3 18 10880 7942 2938 3653 1430 1191 238 1430 Shelby loam 10 1291 -827 .464 330 178 120 76 123 100 64 36 40 22 14 9 15 13440 8602 4838 3441 1893 1204 774 1290 ; ALL LAND . "100 72 28 41 27 13 5 14 I 239360 173094 66266 70002 47086 23209 9258 23539 1 The acres and percentages shown in the. first and second lines in each instance arc based on data from the respective records. The percentages for lout crop /and and other /arm /and are expressed in terms of the total farm land, and those for specific crops in terms of total crop land. The iota! acres in the third line are from the Johnson County Soil Survey, and the order acres are derived therefrom by applying the proper percentage in the preceding line. The acres in all land are obtained by summation and the respective ' percentages derived therefrom. . These estimates are based on all land in the county and would be slightly lower if adjusted to farm land. : </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 Table s.— Estimated acreages of the principal crops in Johnson county, Nebraska. Agricultural 1929 Averaßc 1 Conservation Association Crop or use U. S. 192?- records Census 1932 1935 I From . totals ) Table 4 Crop land Corn 72593 75148 61728 70002 Wheat 32835 30067 38737 -17086 ' Oats 19215 2257-1 21452 23209 Alfalfa 6408 76-15 9866 9258 Other 15915 20802 23539 All crop land 146966 . 155585 173094 Other land Wild hay 6246 . . 5766 • 5327 Pasture 70120 65243 42658 Other 11353 ... .... 18281 All other land 8*719 71009 66266 Total land 2346K5 226594 239360 'Esnmate* tupplicd by ihc Bureau of Agricultural Economic*. U. S. D. A., and the Nebraska Stale Department ot Agriculture, cooperating. PRODUCTIVITY RATINGS The county yield estimates supplied by the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, United States Department of Agriculture, the most significant estimates available, are used as a basis in calculating yields by land types. Such county yields for the period 1923-1932 are 28.3, 16.9, and 25.8 bushels an acre, respectively, for corn, wheat, and oats, and 1.75 tons an acre for alfalfa hay. Comparable data are not available for the carrying capacity of the pastures, but (based on a 1.5-acre requirement for the most pro - ductive land) it is estimated that 2.24 acres are required on the average to supply six months' pasture for one animal unit. The relative acre yield estimates (Tables 6 to 11) for the various crops and land types are based on a standard of 100, which applies to the land type or condition considered the most productive. The actual acre yield estimates are so derived that when weighted according to the acreage allotted they equal the estimate for gross county production (total acres times average county yield). Various crops, particularly corn, wheat, and oats, doubtless respond differently to soil conditions. There are no data, however, on which such yield responses may be based. Theoretical curves have been established in certain instances to aid and guide in interpreting crop response. Curves established for the various slope and erosion conditions on the loessial uplands of eastern Nebraska are shown for corn, wheat, and oats in Figure 3. As may be observed, these curves show: 1. Four slope and six erosion conditions, together with an estimated thickness of the topsoil for each condition. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 2. Yields for the most productive conditions ate estimated at 45.0, 25.0, and 42.0 bushels an acre for corn, wheat, and oats, respectively. 5. These conditions are on the more productive soils of the bottom lands and terraces. The most' productive upland conditions are arbitrarily estimated at 85 per cent o£ the best land. 3. The estimated relative response of corn, wheat, and oats to each condition. The curves are intended to represent present productivity, but their extension back from the Class 1 erosion condition provides an estimate of inherent productivity, which may be defined as the natural ability of the soil to maintain production at or near the level existing when it has become adjusted to tillage. It is recognized that cropping and cultural practices'may affect productivity. It is not likely, however, that productivity under most Nebraska condi- j tions would be materially and permanently lowered without physical j soil loss. , '.. ¦'•"¦" "¦"...¦ The curves are entirely theoretical and not all the conditions indicated thereon are found in the field. The fundamental factors affecting yields are largely moisture and nitrogen, but very little is known concerning the various physical and biological interactions. The following assumptions, however, were made in developing the curves: i 1. The range in inherent productivity from Slope A to Slope D is less than the range under Class 5 erosion. The difference in pro - ductivity becomes increasingly greater from Slope A, through Slopes B and Cto Slope D. ... 2. The most rapid decline in productivity occurs in.the range of 8 to 3 inches of surface soil. , : . 3. As growing conditions become less favorable owing to increasing slope and loss of topsoil, yields of wheat (a winter grain) are de - pressed relatively more than those of corn, and those of oats (a spring grain) more than wheat. The curves are based on loessial upland conditions of eastern Nebraska such as occur in the Marshall and Knox silt loams.. For any given slope or erosion condition on the uplands, it is commonly recognized that these soils have the highest productivity. Soils having less desirable character - istics are depreciated accordingly. In the accompanying tables the relative ratings for Grundy silt loam were taken directly from the curves in Figure 3, whereas the ratings for other soils of the upland were lowered from 1 to 13 points depending on soil type, slope, and use, as. shown in Column 1 of Tables 6to 9 and Table \\. All yields, however, are based on county averages and not on the yields shown in Figure 3. .¦: Perennial legumes and grasses are probably affected relatively more by unfavorable moisture conditions and less by reduced organic matter content than are annual crops. If this is true, their yields would decline 8 Tentative U. S. Standards for the most productive, corn, wheat, and oat land have been let at 50 25, and 50 bushels per acre. These represent yields which may be maintained on a soil or land type of significant acreage under practices which hold it at or near its inherent level of productivity. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 15 C-CORN - W- WHEAT O-OATS EST. YIELD IN SLOPE DEPTH OF TOPSOIL IN INCHES BU. PER A. C - 8 7.0 6.0 SO 4.0 3X&gt; 2O 1.0 O 4bO 25.0 420 | O o &gt;100 0 - 6 525 4.S 3.75 30 2.25 1.5 0.75 O O I I [ I I I 40.5 22.5 37.8 eQ £ b PRODUCTIVITY CURVES El9_ 15,0. 25,2 60 560 £ r^S&gt;P^VvT^§^ V FOR SLOPES 2 ° EROSION CLASS II 2 I «L 33 L ~ ioo PERCENT TOPSOIL LOSS O ?5 50 /S low Fie 3.—Estimated present productivity of soils on the loessul uplands ot eastern Nebraska according to slope and erosion conditions. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 16 relatively mote from lowland to upland conditions than would the yields of annual crops. Likewise, their yields would be affected less by the loss of topsoil. Further complications arise with respect to the deep - rooted crops such as alfalfa due to their ability to utilize the deep-seated inherent subsoil moisture. An attempt is made to recognize these factors in rating alfalfa and the pasture grasses. Such ratings are based on well established stands after the yields have reached a relatively constant level. It is desirable to convert the actual yield estimates for the different crops to a common denominator in order to measure production under a given.use pattern. This is done on the basis of commonly used replace - ment feeding factors. The equivalents used, based on one bushel of corn as one feed unit, are as follows: wheat, 0.93 bushel; oats, 2.22 bushels; alfalfa hay, 0.053 ton, and six days of pasture lor one animal unit. It is recognized that conversion factors have limited use, since feeds have widely varying values when fed to different types of livestock and under different conditions. The use of-such factors is essential, however, in deriving a composite productivity rating. The corn, wheat, oat, alfalfa, other crops, and pasture yield estimates for the various land types are reported in Tables 6to 11." In order to simplify procedure and obtain a composite rating for all land uses, other cultivated crops are combined and given a weighted rating on the basis of the four major crops, corn, wheat, bats, and alfalfa. Likewise, all other farm land is combined and given a pasture rating. With respect to the cultivated crops, ratings are established for 52" conditions. Seven slope and erosion conditions in the two Carrington soils and six in the two Pawnee soils are given the same ratings. There are, therefore, 39 conditions which may be considered sufficiently different because of yield or use suitabilities to be recognized as land types. In comparison, 56 conditions are given a pasture rating. Eighteen of these do not occur on the cropped land, but because of duplicate ratings in the Carrington and Pawnee soils only 10 may be considered land types. Although ratings are thus established for 70 conditions, only 49 land types are recognized. * The procedure may be specifically luted and illustrated as follows: \ . a. Average county production of the various crops is estimated on the basil of the acreages assigned in Table 5 and the average county yields. Example: The 70,002 acres of corn with an aver - age yield of 28.3 bushels will produce 1,981,057 bushels. . / . b. The county acreages are assigned to the various soil and land types on the basis of the data in Tables 3 and 4. Eiamplc: The 70,002 acres of corn arc assigned to the 52 conditions shown in Table 6. !• c The relative productivity of each soil or land type under the various uses is estimated in ternu of the one considered most productive. Example: The Wabash lilt and very Sue sandy looms on the bottom lands were considered the most productive corn land and therefore rated 100 for this crop. In contrast. Grundy silt loam. Slope A, Erosion. Class 1, is considered the most productive land type on the uplands with a rating of 85 (Table.6). d. The acreages assigned to the various conditions are. converted to their acreage equivalents in 10Q per cent land on the basis of the relative ratings and summated. . Example: &gt; The 340 acre* assigned to corn on Grundy silt loam, Slope A, Erosion Class 1 (Table 6) arc equivalent in production to 289 acres of the most productive land. Combined acreage equivalent for the 52 conditions equal 47,337 acres. . . . ¦ -' c. The estimated gross production divided by the acreage equivalent in 100 percent land will give the estimated acre yield ol the most productive land. This in turn multiplied by the respective relative ratings will give the estimated yields for each condition. Example: The estimated county production in corn, 1,981,057 bushels, divided by 47,337 acres of 100 per cent land gives 41.9 bushels, the estimated yield of the most productive land. The yield on Grundy silt loam, Slope A, Erosion Class I, is estimated at 85 per cent of this or 35.6 bushels per acre. ¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ . . - I . ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 17 Table 6.—Estimated corn acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. Erosion classes __ Slope j ¦ -j Jl * gr°" PS | Yield |^n T^T^Z^Kl^^-IZJ^^^U ™L_ 1^ 7^ ~b7. Pa. 8... Pxt. Bu. Pxt. Bu. P.ct. soils of the iiorroM lands Wabash nil ami very fine sandy loams A 11057 41.9 100 SOILS OF THE TERRACES Waukesha silt and very fine sandy loams A 2496 37.7 90 SOILS OF THE UPLANDS Grundy silt loam A 340 35.6 85 314 34.4 82 B 23 33.1 79 509 31.4 75 3503 26.4 63 109 18.9 45 d :. ::: :: ::: ..: 6 v.i 17 :::: ::: :; 5 5.6 12 Carrinutnn silt l«am B^ 173 nl 77 \m 10.6 73 14619 25.6 6. .019 18.0 43 94 I6J 39 c (3) . . 40 18.0 43 D (4) Carrington loam B(l) '"no I" 77 780 las 73 562. 25.6 6. 2700 18.0 43 560 16.3 39 D(4) '.'.'. '.'.'. '¦'. 18 15.5 37 '.'.'. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 18 Table 6.— Estimated corn acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. — (Continued) Erosion classes S'"!*, —— j" — 2 ~~" : J~~~ ~~ 33 ~~ 4 . Kroups 1 ¦' ' ' l i— - — Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Bit. P.cl. ttti. P.ct. Bit. P.cl. Bit. P.cl. Bit. Pxt. ".'...'¦:¦ .¦ ;¦ ¦'¦•¦' Pawnee silt loam •,.,¦'.."¦ .. ".'¦ A (3) 707 ' 34.4 82 615 33.1 79 .-...,....• ..:..„.,.. ... B (4) 65 31.4 75 278 29.7 71 10682 24.7 59. 988 17.2 41 . 99 15.5 37 C (5) .. ... .. 32 24.3 58 .27 172. . 41 11 10.5 25 ... :-. D(6) .. .:.:..¦ 5. 14.7 35 ..... ......;.. •• ••• '¦¦¦:,¦¦¦¦ :•'. ¦¦'¦. .'¦ ¦ ¦ .¦ '¦ ¦. ••¦¦¦¦ . '-Pawnee loam ¦\ * ' ¦.".-*; ¦' : ' .;' ¦¦ ¦ .'. A (3) 129 34.4 82 \.. ... -.'.'¦-'.:.'.'.¦' ... ¦¦':. ..v. ... .. ... ... B (4) ... ... .: 106 29.7 71 1768 24.7 59 1528 17.2 41 86 15.5 37 ¦ C (5) ... ... .. ... •• 36 17.2 41 ... .. '¦'.¦:'.'.' . Shelby loam ; A (10) 120 31.4 75 ... . ¦¦".: ... : ... .. .... ;..¦ &#132; ;..¦.' ... . . B (11) 70 '28.5 68 252 26.8 64 2067 21.8 52 846 14.2 34 53 12.6 30 c (12) .. ... .;¦.- ... ,:;.'-. ¦¦¦ •••¦ •¦¦ ..;... ..: :. 33 6.7 16 . ¦¦¦¦ ¦¦¦'¦-.¦- ¦¦:': ¦ ¦-' ¦-¦ : " ¦ ALLSOILS '¦..::. ;: ;.'-:- -¦ /. ¦"'.' '¦ ¦'.¦.".¦".¦ -A 17147 39.8 95 2385 33.9 81 .... ... .. .... ..: B 441 31.4 75 3321 30.2 72 38260 25.1 60 7190 17.2 41 892 15.9 38 C '¦'¦. .. '¦:.. 32 24.3 58 103 17.6 42 152 113- 27 45 7.5 18 D ... ... -:.¦ 23 15.5 37 6 7.1 17 .... ..... 5 5.0 12 slopes 17588 39.8 95 5761 31.8 76 38369 25.1 60 7312 17.2 41 942 15.5 37 1 The numbers in paremheses indicate the extent to which the relative ratines for soils developed on glacial drift were depreciated from the corresponding points (Pig. 3) for. soils developed on loess, became of less desirable inherent soil characteristics. ,- '. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 19 Table 7.— Estimated wheat acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. Slope - - . F.roM.m classes Acres [ Yield Acres I Yield Acres i Yield ~ Acres ~~i Yield ' Acres I Yield ""¦ p" B«- I'd- B,i. I.ci. Bu. P.ct. Bu. P.cl. SOII-S OF THE BOTTOM LANDS Wabash silt and very fine sandy loams A 8413 22.8 90 SOILS OF THE TERRACES Waukesha silt and very fine sandy loams A 2159 25.3 100 SOILS OK THE UPLANDS Cirundy silt loam A 255 21.5 85 236 20.7 82 B 17 19.7 78 382 18.7 7-) 2627 15.4 61 "82 10.9 43 C . . ... D '.'. 4 3.3 13 "..'. ;;; :; 4 vi 6 CarrinKtnn silt loam A (1) 357 21.3 84 1118 20.5 81 B &lt;2) 136 19-2 76 1094 18.2 72 11457 14.9 59 798 104 41 7-i 9 4 37 Carrington loam A (1) 1115 21.3 84 18 20.5 81 B (2) 66 19.2 76 472 18.2 72 3403 1V.9 59 1634 10.4 41 339 94 37 g% :: ::: :: ii 7 ; 8 ii :::: :;; ;: ,. 85 6-\ v ,. 7 »21 </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 20 Table 7.—Estimated wheat acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and. erosion classes for Johnson county, •..'.¦¦' ¦• • Nebraska. — -(Continued) . ' ¦'" ' .' ¦ . . ' . Erosion classes ¦¦¦'¦. '•:• . ¦¦:.•¦ ' Slope' '¦ : ; ' : . groupsi 1.. ' ¦2 3 _33 4 Acres ] Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Bit. P.ct. Bit. P.cl. Bu. P.ct. ' Bu.' P.ct. Bu. P.ct. ••;¦'¦ ¦"¦"¦¦'¦' ¦ " ¦ ' •'"'¦¦¦ """.'•"¦¦ '¦'¦"¦ " ""—-Pawnee silt loam ¦- .''¦' •- ¦ ¦- •.' ¦•¦_' '¦¦;'¦¦ " :. A (2) ' 385 21.0 83 335 20.2 80 .... .. ; •.'. . .... ... .. ..'. ¦ B (3) 35 19.0 ¦ 75 152 18.0 71 5826 14.7 58 539 10.1 40 54 .9.1 36 &#132; C (4) ' ..-.:. •¦¦¦¦-.: •18 14.2 56 .14 9.9. 39 6 5.8 23 ... ... .. ¦ ¦.' : D (5) :.. .... .. 4 7.6 30 .. ... ,';.. .... ... : -.¦ ¦. .¦. '-'¦¦.¦ . .-.'¦. ¦'¦'.¦' ... . ¦ . .'.' Pawnee loam :- A (2) 51. 21.0 83 .. .....:...¦ ..... ... .. . . ..; B (3) .. .:. ..41 18.0 71 692 H. 7 58 598 10.1 40 34 9.1 36 C(4). ..... .. .. ... .. 14 9.9 39 .... ... .. ... ..... ....;.. ._." .' ' ¦'¦''¦¦'•'.': .'¦¦;'¦' ¦¦'-. . Shelby loam ¦:¦¦¦¦ ..; ~ A~(io&gt; •" 66 - 19.0 75 ..;;.. ...... ... .... ... ... .. B (11) 38 17.0 67 139 15.9 63 1138 12.7 50 465 8.1 32 29 7.1 28 c (12) .. .. ... ..... .... ... ¦-! ••¦ :'... 18 3.0 12 - ¦¦¦' ,¦: ¦¦.¦¦:¦¦¦ :¦'¦¦; ¦¦¦;. ¦¦' ' : ¦¦¦...-. ¦¦¦¦ . ¦-.-. all soils ¦ :,,¦¦.-,¦¦. ¦-.. ,¦ .¦;. ¦.;.¦¦.;.. ¦-. . : A: 12801 23.0- 91 1707 20.5 81 .... ... ... -;. ...... ... .. B 292 19.0 75 2280 18.2 72 25143 14.9 59 4116 10.1 40 530- 9.1 36 C ... ... .. 18 14^ 56 60 10.1 40 91 6.1 24 25 3.8 15 D ... ;. .. 15 7.8 31 4 3.3 13 .... ... .. 4 1.5 6 slopes 13093 22.8 90 4020 19.0 75 25207 14.7 58 4207 9.9 39 559 8.9 35. 1 The numben in parentheses indicate the extent to which the relative rating! for soils developed oa glacial drift were depreciated from the corresponding points (Fig. 3) for soils developed on loess, because of less desirable inherent soil characteristics. .-' ' . ' ... ; </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 21 Table B.— Estimated oats acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. Krosuin (-'lasses Acres I ' Yield Acres ~ Yield Acres ' Yield Acres \ Yield Acres I Yield Bu. P.cl. fill. P.cl. Bit. P.cl. Hn. P.cl. Bit. P.CI. SOILS OK THK HOTTOM LANDS Wabash sill and very Tine sandy loams A 24(H 38.3 ''() SOILS OF THE TERRACES Waukeslia silt and very fine sandy loams A 5-10 -12.5 100 ..... SOILS OP THE UPLANDS Grundy silt loam A 102 36.1 85 SH 34.4 hi B 7 32.7 77 153 30.6 72 1050 24.7 58 33 17.0 40 D '.'.'. '.'. '.'.'¦ .. " 2 4.3 10 ..'..' ... .'. 2 1.7 4 CarrinKton silt loam A (1) 148 35.7 84 463 34.0 80 ... B (2) 56 31.9 75 453 2'J.B 70 4740 23.8 56 330 16.2 38 31 14.0 33 C (3) .. . B 14.9 35 D (4) Carringttin loam A (1) 775 35.7 84 12 34.0 80 B (2) 46 31.9 75 328 29.8 70 2368 23.8 56 1138 16.2- 38 236 14.0 33 C (3) 59 8.5 20 5 7.7 18 D (4) 7 11.1 26 </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 22 Table B.— Estimated oats acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes jor Johnson county, : Nebras\a.^— (Continued) . ¦'¦''&#132; . ¦'. ' .; ¦ . Erosion classes . ¦ rou Psl ~ ]~" 'I"2 I' .-'. 3331 4 T ~ KrO" PS Acres | Yield I Acres I Yield I Acres I Yield Acres I Yield I Acres I . Yield Bu. P.ct. Bu. P.cl. Bu. P.ct. Bu. P.ct. Bu. P.ct. -.. ¦... .•- . . ..'¦'" '¦'..'. ¦ . . Pawnee silt loam .., .¦'.'.¦ ...... . . A (2) • 273 .35.3 83 ; 237 33.6 79 ............ ...; ... .- ... ... •• B (3) 25 31.5 74 108 29.3 69 4127 23.4 55 382 15.7 37 38 13.6 32 C (4) ¦ .. .... .:¦•¦¦ 13 22.5 53 10 14.5 34 4 8.1 19 .... ... .. D(5) ....-..¦ .. /¦::¦¦ 2 10.6 25 .. ... .. .... i. ¦..'¦¦ .. ... ••• ; ¦¦.'¦¦ ¦ ' :i Pawnco loam , . A (2) 42 35.3 83 .. '..V ; .. ... ... .. ' ... .. ... ..... B (3) .'¦; ...• -.., 34 29.3 69 576 23.4 55 499 15.7 37 28 13.6 32 C (4) &#132; ... .. .. ..... 12 14.5 34 ....&gt;.. ........ .. : .. ¦ ¦¦''.¦¦¦¦. . ! r. Shelby loam ¦' ¦ A (10) 42 31.9 75 .. ... .. ........ ....... :. ...... .. B (11) 24 28.1 66 88 25.9 61 724 20.0 47 . 296 12.3 29 18 10.2 24 C (12) .; / ¦ .. ...:'.. ...... ..... 1..:" 1.'..- « 3.8 9 A 4326 37.8 89 806 .34.0 80 .... ... .. .... ... .. .... ... .- B 158 "31.5 74 1164 29.3 69 13585 23.4 55 2678 15.7 37 351 13.6 32 C .. ... .. 13 22.5 53 35 14.5 34 63 8.5 20 17 5.1 12 D ... ... .. 9 11.1 26 2 4.3 10 .... ... .. 2 1.7 4 slopes 4484 37.8 89 1992 31.0 73 13622 23.4 55 2741 15.3 36 370 13J 31 1 The numben in paicmhdcs indicate the extern to which the relative rating! for toils developed on glacial drift were depreciated from the corretpotidins poimi (Fig. 3) for soils developed on loess, because of lest desirable inherent soil characteristics. . ; . ............. </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 23 Table 9.— Estimated alfalfa acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. Erosion classes " Acres I Yield ~ Acre. I ' Yield Acres I Yield Acres ' Yield Acres I Yield Tons Pet. Tons P~7l. Tons P.cl. Tuns Pel. Tans F.cl. SOII.S OF TIIK BOTTOM LANDS Wabash silt an*! very fine sandy loams A 962 2J5 100 . . SOILS OK II IK TERRACES Waukesha sill anil very fine sandy loams A 337 2.23 95 SOILS OH THE UPLANDS Glumly silt loam A 60 1.88 80 55 1.88 80 _ 4 |.7fi 75 89 1.76 75 613 1.72 73 19 1.62 69 Carrinyton silt loam $$ &#132; \f 2 71l 264 L 72 73 2765 &#132;67 7. 'i« ..57 67 .8 M 3 61 C (3) . ... 8 1.34 57 D (4) Carrirtgton loam B(2) '4 9 \fz 11 62 1.72 73 445 1.67 71 213 1.57 67 '44 M 3 61 c \i) 11 1.18 50 1 1.06 45 D(4) :! '.'.'. ¦¦ J 1-03 44 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 24 Table 9.— Estimated alfalfa acres and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, . Nebraska.—(Continued) ¦''¦¦',} ¦' " . ' '¦':¦.:' . ''..'•¦ ; Erosion classes .'. . ' Slope .-- l - ,2 ••..... 31. 33 4 groups Acres | yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield I Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Tons P.ct. Tons P.ct. Tons Pm. Tons P.ct. Tons P.ct. '. ¦:•'.. ' ' ;. .; , ; .'¦¦¦.- •¦ ¦"-.- '.-,; Pawnee silt loam -.'¦.. _'.L"..."¦......'..'. .. "_ A (3) .'¦'•¦ 80 1.81 77¦'.¦¦" 70 1.81 - 77 ..... .. .:.. ... .. :&gt;. B (4) 7 1.67 71 32 1.67 71 1214 1.62 69 112 1.53 65 11 1.39 59 C (5) . 4 1.39 59 3 I^9 55 1 1.13 48 ... _.. D(6) &#132;. ¦¦;¦...'¦. ;.:•. -. I 0.99 42 " .. .... ...... .-• ¦¦ ••• ¦ .'•• ¦• :...-' . . ¦'. ¦'¦•'.¦'¦'"' Pawnee loam -,'...¦ B(4 3 } 8. !'Bl. 7? 7 1.67 71 Hi 1*62: 69 i 66 1.53 65 ' 6 1.39 59 C(5) '. ..... ... •• ¦•• -. 2 1.29 55 .... ... ......:. .. ¦ ¦¦,-¦¦¦ ;. ' - . ¦'¦ • Shelby-loam ¦¦ ¦ ' . _^. B (6) * 16 162 69 57 1.62 69 465 1.57 67 'J9O 1.48 63 "\2 1.34 57 C (7) ..... .. .. ... ..... ..... ....... .. 7 0.96 41 ¦: ¦¦¦; ¦':' ;.- ¦¦..:;;.¦¦¦ :•.¦¦• ¦¦¦.¦¦' ALL soils ;' ;¦;¦¦.. ¦. ; , .;¦.¦,' A 1705 221 94 397 1.86 79 ...; ... .. .:.'.:¦¦ ... '¦..¦ ... •• B 69 1.69 72 511 1.72 73 5617 1.65 70 827 1.55 66 91 1.41 60 C . 4 1.39 59 13 1.32 56- 12 1.18 50 8 0.99 42 D ..'¦¦'! 1. ••• ¦• 2 1.01 43 1 1.03 44 ..;. ... -.-. 1 0.66 28 'dopes 1774 2.19 93 914 1.76 75 5631 1.65 70 839 1.53 65 100 1.36 58 1 The numbcrt In parcnlhciel indicate the eitcnt to which the relative rating! for toils developed on glacial drift were depreciated from the corresponding pointi tor toils developed on loets, became of lets desirable inherent loil characteristics. </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 25 Table 10. — Estimated acres of other crop land and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. 1 Kr'iMon classes *X ir2 — — r »— —i Acres i Yield | Acres ! Yield Acres Yield Acres I Yield Acres- I -Yield F. U. Pel. /•. U. P.cl. F. V. I'd. /¦¦. V. l.cl. F. V. P.ct. SOILS OI" THK BOTTOM LANDS \V.ih;i.sh silt and very tine sandy loams A 1202 i.i.d Kill SOILS Ol' Tl IK TKRRACKK Wjukesh.i silt antl ver\ fine sandy loams A I2H 32.0 97 SOILS OF II IK UPLANDS Cirunily silt loam A 9-1 28.7 87 Sf&gt; 27. H M ... B 6 26.6 81 HI) 2'U 77 W 21.5 65 JO 15.9 -18 C .. . . ... D 2 6.2 19 1 3.8 12 Carrinjiton silt loam A 185 28.3 86 57S 27..! 83 ... . .... B 70 25.8 78 566 2-1.6 75 5927 20.7 63 ![} 15.1 46 38 13.7 42 C ... . . 16 H. 6 "H D ... .. ... \. Carrington loam A 969 27.8 84 16 26.9 82 B 58 25.4 77 410 24.1 73 2959 20.1 61 1421 U. 3 43 295 12.9 39 C 7^ 8.8 27 6 7.9 24 D 9 11.5 35 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Proposed Method op Classifying and Evaluating Soils 26 Table 10. — Estimated acres of other crop land and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska 1. — (Continued) . : , ¦ Erosion classes ; : Slope ——-——y— ; —— — — 33 ; ; —4— — groups ' : _ _ .. - i _ — : ; — —— Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres I Yield Acres 1 Yield " .'¦.;.' F.U. P.ct. F.U. P.ct. F.U.- P.ct. F.U. P.ct. F.U. P.ct. ¦ .. : . Pawnee silt loam '', : A ,161 .27.7 84 140 26.7 81 .... ... ./.... ... .':' i ... ..... B 15 25.2 76 63 23.9 72 2428 20.0 61 225 .142 43 22 12.8 39 C ¦¦¦..;¦ ... .. 7 19.2 58 6 13.9 42 2 8.6 26. ... ... ¦;. '. D.. ... .. : 1 11.2 34 ... ... ';. ¦ .... ... ...,;¦¦' ...... '...¦¦ ¦¦ ¦. ..'. ¦ ¦..'.¦. ¦'¦ . ._¦ . ..Pawnee loam '.'¦.' .. .¦ ¦ ' - ¦ :'. -.-. ¦ ¦ A : 51 28.4 86 .. : ... .. ... ... .. ....... .. ... B .. ..... 41 24.5 74 692 20.4 62 598 14.4 44 34 12.9 39 C .. ... .. .. ... •¦ H 14.0 42 ....¦: .... .. .:' . Shelby loam '. ¦¦ ¦ ¦ •¦" A 45 25.9 78 .. ... .. ...... ...... ... .. ..: '...- .. B :¦¦ 26 23.5 71 95 22.2 67 775 18.4 56 317 12.8 39 20 11.4 35 . C :."... .. ¦'..;• ... ..;-.... ..:.. •¦ .... ... .. 12 6.1-18 &#132;';.. ..¦..;••...; ...; •, ' .; ."...¦'.. . ..... . ...all soils -"¦¦.:. ' ._, ¦.¦- ;' ;¦•".',¦ ' . A 3921 30.7 93 820 27.2 82 &#132;.. ..... ..:. ........ ..... B 175 25.3 77 1315 24.3 74 13745 20.4 62 3004 14.3 43- 409 12.9 39 C . .. 7 19.2 58 36 14J . 43 76 8.8 27 18 6.7 20 0. . ... .. 10 11.5 35 2 6.2 19 ....... ..1 3.8 12 ¦¦, All ' .¦¦¦ ¦ ¦ -¦.:¦¦. ¦¦¦'"¦¦ ¦-': ¦":¦¦¦'¦¦¦¦¦:' . ...¦¦.¦,..¦¦.•,¦¦.. slopes 4096 30.5. . 92 2152 25.4 77 13783 20.3 62 3080 14.1 43 428 12.6 38 1 Other crop land includes all cultivated land not in corn, wheat, oats, or alfalfa. The productivity estimates in feed units (P. U.) are weighted according to the acreage and yield estimates for corn, wheat, oats, and alfalfa. The conversion factors used are shown on pace 15. The relative ratines are based on the land type having the hishuc estimated feed unit production per acre. .. " ¦ .¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 27 Table 11. — Estimated pasture acres (all non-crop land) and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes for Johnson county, Nebraska. ' Erosion classes Btl&gt;UpS Acres I ~ Yield Acres 1 Yield " Acres I Yield Acres 1 Yield Acres 1 Yield P.n. C. C. P.cl. C. C P.cl. C. C. P.cl. C. C. P.ct. SOILS OF THE BOTTOM LANDS Wabash silt and very line sandy loams A 9818 1.50 100 SOILS OF THE TERRACES Waukesha silt ami very fine sandy loams A 1382 1.76 85 SOILS OF THE UPLANDS Grimily silt loam A 665 2.H 70 B 592 2.31 65 1817 2.31 65 518 2.38 63 C D Carrington silt loam A (1) 1-172 2.17 (W 208 2.17 69 .- ¦¦ B (2) 4800 2 38 63 6067 2.38 63 5786 2J6 61 -132 2.63 57 C (3) 23 2.88 52 165 2.9-1 51 208 3.19 47 D (4) -16 4.41 U 8 5.00 30 Carrinyton loam B$ 3988 218 63 3^oB 238 63 .732 2.46 61 _ * -173 2M » C (3) 242 2.88 52 2678 2.94 51 ¦• ¦¦¦ ¦¦ D(4) 257 4.41 34 37 5.00 30 41 6.00 2^ </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 28 Table 11.— —Estimated pasture acres (all non-crop land) and productivity by soil types, slope groups, and erosion classes ¦ for Johnson county, Nebraska. I—(Continued) . ¦ ' Erosion classes ¦ '¦¦.-, groups 2 I : ¦¦¦¦ 2- ¦ - ¦3:33 I 4 . Acres I : Yield Acres | ; Yield Acres I Yield Acres | Yield Ucrcs I Yield C.C. P.ct. C.C. Pxt. C.C P.ct. C.C. P.ct. C.C. P.ct. : ¦. ¦ ' Pawnee silt loam ¦ A (3) 1507 2.24 67 .... ... .'-.. ....... .~. ....... .-.¦ ... : ... B (4) 2813 2.46 (SI 2512 2.46 61 1300 2.54 59 507 2.73 55 ... C (5) 266 3.00 50 .... ... .. 266 3.33 45 D (6) :... ...; ... ........ .... &#132;. : ..:v .. -: ..... :.-: ¦¦...¦¦ .... ... ... . ¦¦¦¦-.;¦ '¦¦'-. . ¦ Pawnee loam .'¦..¦¦ A (3)' 279 2.24 67 67 2.24 67 ...... ...... ... '... . ... ... .. B (4) 83 2.46 61 1347 2.46 61 465 2.54 59 61 2.73 55 ... ..... C (5) 53 3.00 50 542 3.06 49 41 3.33 45 .... ... .. ...... .. d (6) ¦¦-.. .¦.¦.¦•¦¦ .. •¦:..¦.' ¦...¦-;¦ .. ......... ;¦:.. .... ;;.. ...... .... .. ; '•'¦¦'¦¦'":'.¦' ..¦¦''¦ &#132;'.'•' ' ¦-'•;" . ¦ Shelby loam :..:¦ ¦'¦¦'¦: .¦'¦¦ "¦' . A (5) 939 2.31 65 ...... .. .... ..... ;........... ... .. B (6) 566 2.54 59 951 2.54 59 1306 2.63 57 119 2.83 53 205 3.19 47 C (7) ... ..... 679 3.19 47 15 3.49 43 .... ... .. ... ... .. D (8) ... ... .. 18 5.00 30 40 5.77 26 .... ... .. &#132;. ..... :.-.•:'..'¦. &#132;. :J.': '.'}'.:.'.'... ¦ ' ¦¦ ' all soils ;., ¦'".•;•,.¦' '.;• .'¦-..':'':¦.:¦ " .;¦¦'¦ A 18386 1.74 86 868 2.17 69 .:. ... .... ..... ... ... .. B 12842 2.42 62 15802 2.38 63 11107 2.50 60 1186 2.68 56 380 3.06 49 C 584 2.94 51 4064 3.00 50 530 3^6 46 .... ... ,:.¦" ... ... .. D ...... 0... 321 4.41 34 85 5.36 28 ... .. 41 6.00 25 slopes 31812 1.97 76 21055 2.50 60 11722 2.54 59 1186 2.68 56 421 3.19 47 1 Carrying capacity (C. C.) ii expressed In number of acres required to supply six months of pasture for one animal unit. . ¦ . '¦¦ - . - 'The numbers In parentheses indicate the extent toivhich the relative ratings for soils developed on gbcial drift were depreciated from the correspondinE points for soils developed on loess, because of less desirable inherent soil characteristics. 'This is B slope and Class S erosion and is not included in the Class 4 summary. . ¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 29 Table M.—Summary of estimated acreages and productivity for all uses by slope groups and erosion classes for John - son county, Nebraska 1 (based on Tables 6 to 11). hn»M&lt;in classes ""'"'' Acres !V.&gt;' VV ' Acr" ; '"'•"• ACr" ' *""• A"" ' VAJ A 17H7 S'-.K 23*5 ii.l "'"[ '9532 39.1 H 441 314 U2I 30.2 5X261) 25.1 71 ill 17.2 K'&lt;2 1 "&gt;-'&gt; 50HH 2^.2 C 32 2-4 -1 111.5 17.6 152 11.3 -ts 7.S 332 14.0 I) 2 3 ISS I, 7.1 S ¦&gt;.» 3-1 '2.3 All 175H8 3V.K 5761 31. h 3h{(,'» 2=&gt;.l 73-12 17.2 W2 15.S 70002 28.3 Wlirat A 12H01 2-l.f, 1707 21.1 ¦ •• ¦¦ I^soB 24.3 1) 2»2 20 5 "SO I'M 2S|H( IS. 1) 41l(i ID.S 530 ''.7 . . 32361 15.4 C " "lX 15.2 60 IO.H 'M 6.5 25 4.1 194 8.3 15 15 H. 3 4 3.5 4 1.6 23 6.3 All 13093 24.4 4020 20.3 25207 15.7 4207 111.6 559 9.5 470K6 18.1 Oats A 4326 17.0 8()(&gt; 15.3 ... 5132 16.7 B 158 142 1164 13.2 135K5 10.5 267K 7.1 351 6.1 17936 10.1 C 13 10.1 !5 6.5 63 3.X 17 2.3 128 5.0 D y 5.0 2 1.0 2 .8 13 3.9 All 44tM 17.0 l'»') 2 H.II 13622 10.5 2741 6.9 370 5.9 23209 11.5 Alfalfa A 1705 42.(1 397 35.3 2J02 40.7 B 69 32.1 511 32.7 5617 31.4 H27 29.4 91 26.8 . . .. 7115 31.2 c 4 26.4 13 25.1 12 22.-1 8 18.8 .. .. 37 23.0 D. . 2 ]g2 j |gfi j 125 4 , 76 All 177-i -ll.fi 914 33.4 5631 31.4 839 29.1 100 25.8 9258 33.3 </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 30 Table 12.— Summary of estimated acreages and productivity for all uses by slope groups and erosion classes for John - son county, Nebraska 1 (based on Tables 6to 11).—(Continued) , '¦¦'-. ; ¦ . ' ¦'' ¦' Erosion classes . ¦ .¦ .'.. ¦ ¦¦.. .¦¦'. ¦ ' ' " ¦1 I ¦'¦'•¦ 2 " ¦3-: " ¦¦ 33 4 5 All I Acres I F.U.| Acres I F. U. Acres I F.U. Acres I F. V. Acres I F.U. Acres I F.U. Acres I F.U. ¦ : "... . Other crop land ¦.-¦.'¦•.'¦"'.¦' A 392 i; 30.7 820 27.2 ... ... .... ... ... ... .. .i . 4741. 30.1 B ' 175 25.3 1315 24.3 13745 20.4 3004 14.3 409 12.9 .. .. 18648 19.6 . C .. ... 7 19.2 36 14.2 76 8.8 18 6.7 .. .. 137 10.5 D 1.. 10 11.5 2 6.2 .. ...;...;¦ 1 3.8 .. .. 13 10.1 All : 4096 30.5 2152 25.4 13783 20.3 3080 H.I 428 12.6 .. ¦ .: 23539 21.6 .. ..... &#132; Other land (pasture) : . .. ; ¦ ,: . A 18386 17.2 868 13.8 ¦ ..1. ... .... .:. ... .... &#132; 19254 17.0 B 12842 12.4 15802 12.6 11107 12.0 1186 11.2 380 9.8 70 4.0 41387 12.3 C 584 10.2 4064 10.0 530 9.2 .... ... • ... ....... 5178 9.9 D .. 321 6.8 85 5.6 .....,: 41 5.0 .. .. 447 7.4 All 31812 15.2 21055 12.0 H722 11.8 1186 11.2 421 9.4 70 4.0 66266 13.5 ¦ ..¦.¦:-.. ¦ •¦¦¦¦¦.¦"¦;¦,¦.¦.¦•¦..¦.'¦ Ail land ¦ i-.; ¦-.::, ¦'' : "''.:'¦:'¦¦ ¦'¦¦•¦" : A 58286 : 27.1 6983 25.6 .;i. : .v.. ... .... .i.'••'." ,'v.'.-. &#132; 65269 26.9 B 13977 13:4 24393 16.7 107457 19.5 19001 14.1 2653 12.4 70 4.0 . 167551 17.8 C 584 10.2 4138 10.2 777 10.8 394. 8.8 113 6.6 .. .. 6006 10.1 D.. ... 380 7.5 100 5.7 ... .¦ ... 54 4.7 .. .. 534 6.9 All 72847 24.3 35894 17.6 108334 19.4 ¦ 19395 14.0 2820 12.0 70 4.0 239360 20.1 ¦Sec page 15 for the conversion factors which arc used in converting bushels, tons, and carrying capacity to feed units (F. U.). </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 31 Table 13.- — Summary of estimated crop acres and productivity by soil types, Johnson county, Nebraska (based on Tables 6 to 11). ' Crop or use Corn | Wheat | Oals | Alfalfa j Other crops | Pasture | All land Acres Bit. P.cl. Acres Bti. I.cl. Acres Bti. I.cl. Acres Tons I'.ct. Acres V. U. P.cl. Acres C. C. I.cl. Acres F. U. P.ct. SOILS OF THE BOTTOM LANDS Wahash silt anil very fine sandy loams 11057 41.9 100 H413 22. X 9(1 2404 38.3 90 962 2.35 101) 121)2 33.0 100 'JXIB 1.50 100 33856 29.2 99 soils of nil-: tkrraces Waukesha sill and very fine sandy loams 2496 37.7 90 2159 25.3 1(10 12.5 100 337 2.23 &gt;&gt;5 12H 32.0 "7 1382 1.76 K5 8128 29.5 100 SOILS OF Till-: UPLANDS (iruruly silt Inam 4809 27.'J 67 3607 16.4 65 \-\-\i 26.6 (.3 B^2 1.74 71 1321 22.7 (&lt;'¦&gt; 35&lt;f2 2.29 66 15616 20.5 69 Carrinjjton silt loam 19223 26.4 63 15066 15.5 61 623-1 24.') 59 3637 1.69 72 77'»3 21.3 65 19215 2.41 62 71168 18.9 64 Carrintjton loam 11814 25.1 60 7150 14.7 58 4974 23.7 56 933 l.f.fi 71 6217 19.8 60 15312 2.46 61 46400 17.2 58 Pawnee silt loam 13509 25.1 60 7368 15.0 59 521') 24.0 56 1535 1.63 69 3070 20.3 62 9171 2.46 61 39872 18.4 62 Pawnee loam 3653 21.7 52 1430 12.9 51 1191 20.4 48 238 1.58 67 1430 18.0 55 2938 2.54 59 10880 16.3 55 Shelby loam 3441 20.5 49 1893 11.9 47 1204 18.8 44 774 1.55 66 1290 17.5 53 4838 2.63 57 13440 15.2 52 ALL LAND 70002 28.3 68 47086 16.9 67 23209 25.8 61 9258 1.75 74 23539 21.6 65 66266 2.24 67 239360 20.1 68 'Sec page 15 for (he conversion factors which were used in converting bushels, win, and carrying opacity (C.C.) to feed unid (I-. U.). </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 32 Table 14. — Acres and appraised corn yields by soil types from 123 records of the Johnson County Agricultural Conservation Association. 1 Number Total Appraised Percent (of ; - of appraised acre yields .. most productive records acres ¦ (bushels) soil) SOILS OF THE BOTTOM LANDS i Wabash silt and very fine sandy loams V H !¦ 1546 33.0 ¦ ,„/;,. 100 / : SOILS OF THE TERRACES '\ ,-' - Waukcsha silt and very fine sandy loams . ¦¦.-'¦- i 5 . 686 :'•'.¦.¦': ':¦-. 28.1 - .¦:.;' 85 .;¦¦', SOILS OF THE UPLANDS : ; Gnindy silt loam :|. 21 ¦ . 2«6 29.-1. 89 Carrington si\t \oam 24 '¦ :.-/. 2768 26.2 . 79 Carrington loam . ¦ 20 1709 . 21.5 .;. ; 65 Pawnee silt loam 19 ,' ¦ 2252 23.9 72 ' .. . ' . . . Pawnee loam ' . . : •12; ; -1315 ¦¦:.21.7 ¦ .66 . •¦¦":•.'¦ Shelby loam . , 8 \ 635 19.6 59 ALL SOILS J23 13337 ¦¦¦¦' 26.1 79 ciccpiion of five records which hid no appraisals, that are the records uicd in For the different land types or conditions, the range in acre yield estimates are as follows: corn (Table 6) 5.0 to 41.9 bushels; wheat (Table 7) 1.5 to 25.3 bushels; oats (Table 8) 1.7 to 42.5 bushels; alfalfa (Table 9) 0.66 to 2.35 tons; and pasture (Table 11) 7.50 to 1.5 acres. The pasture estimates represent the acres required to supply six months' pasture for one : animal unit. Composite ratings for the four major cultivated crops, corn, wheat, oats, and alfalfa, range from 3.8 to 33.0 feed units an acre (Table 10). ; :\:-, ¦¦ v. :&gt;¦ :; r ¦ ¦ : -; V , ' Depending on the slope and erosion conditions, estimated feed unit production ranges from 4.0 to 27.1 units an acre for all crops and soils ¦ (Table 12). It is further shown that yields for Slope Groups A, B; C, and D are 26.9, 17.8, 10.1, and 6.9 feed units an acre, respectively. Based on the respective acreages, 27.27, 70.00, 2.51, and 0.22 per cent of all land falls in these slope groups. In comparison, composite yield estimates for Erosion Classes 1, 2, 3, 33, 4, and 5 are 243,17.6,19.4, 14.0,12.0, and 4.0 feed units, respectively. • The percentages of all land in these classes are 30.43, 15.00, 45.26, 8.10, 1.18, and 0.03, respectively. The yield for Erosion Class 2 is relatively low because it has a high percentage of land in grass. :: : . </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 _ _ . 60- " 50 DC o X W o. 30 — m I?4=— fl a &lt; 20- - vi r w *k n r v. o _ _ tij I n _ _._¦ _Ln_ nintilirHiLTi lUri-rir I 2 3 33 4 S ABCO EROSION CLASS SLOPE GROUP Fig. 4.—Estimated \it-lds and ixmrt-nta^f of all land by erosion clasps and slope jiroups. lohnMm county. Nebraska. The estimates lor various crops are summarized by soil types in Table 13. Production in feed units ranges from 15.2 for Shelby loam to 29.5 for Waukesha silt loam and very fine sandy loam. The average for all land in the county is 20.1 feed units, which is 68 per cent of that for the most productive land. It is to be observed that the acre yields obtained for corn, wheat, oats, and alfalfa (Table 13—last line) are the same as the basic county yields. Corn yield estimates by soils range from 20.5 to 41.9 bushels an acre (Table 13). In comparison, the appraisals from the records of the John - son County Agricultural Conservation Association (Table 14) range from 19.6 to 33.0 bushels an acre. These appraisals, which averaged 79 per cent of their highest, are materially lower for the soils of the bottom lands and terraces, but approximately the same for the soils ol the uplands. </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Proposed Method of Classifying and Evaluating Soils 34 APPLICATION Productivity and use estimates are fundamental to effective systems of land classification and evaluation. Such estimates involve not only a detailed study and interpretation of the soil factors, but all other environ - mental conditions affecting crop production. It is recognized that theoretical productivity ratings are subject to error and at best are only relatively exact. It is also recognized that it would be impractical to test experimentally trie response of different crops on tht many land types and under various practices. It would be highly desirable, however, to measure experimentally the response of three or four important crops on a few major land types under widely varying climatic and cul - tural conditions., Even though this limited testing would require a number of years to obtain significant results, the dependability.and usefulness of theoretical estimates would be greatly increased by the preliminary data. If ratings for soil types as commonly mapped or for broader areas are to have significance, they must be properly weighted for all land types which may be involved. Relatively detailed mapping would appear essential, therefore, except in areas where there is a high degree of uni - formity in the physical factors and the rather limited uses are definitely recognized. Such detailed mapping, though highly desirable, will of necessity proceed slowly. ; • • It would appear desirable to supplement the information available in the regular soil surveys with that which may be obtained by mapping selected, but restricted, sample areas in greater detail, in order that the application and usefulness of the soil surveys may be extended to include not only the soil, but all factors influencing crop yields. Because of changes in mapping technique and soil interpretations, it will be difficult to correlate the soils mapped ¦in the detailed sample surveys with ths more, general soil surveys, particularly the earlier ones. This is not necessary, however, when ratings and interpretations are based on-the original soil survey. • &gt;¦¦ .-:.-.' -"-.¦¦¦-' Inconsistencies in yields across county lines and between physiographic and climatic areas will appear due to the limitations arid incompleteness of (1) the county yield estimates and (2) acreage and use determinations and relative productivity ratings by land types. It will be necessary, therefore, to make adjustments between counties and to base area yields on a composite of county yields; and, in turn, state yields on a composite of area yields where a soil or land type extends into two or more areas. The proposed method for'classifying and evaluating soils on the basis of productivity and use suitabilities will provide qualitative arid quantita - tive estimates for land types or those conditions assumed to have reasonably similar productivity and use suitabilities. Such estimates may be used in place in the sample areas, or ; when built up into estimates by soil types, they may be applied more generally to larger areas. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 98 Such analyses and estimates would be particularly valuable: 1. In the development of use suitability classifications (or such purposes as taxation assessment, conservation practices and programs, and individual farm analyses and planning. 2. To public and private agencies and individuals for land purchase and loan purposes. i. In general and specific programs of research, education, extension, and action designed to bring about more effective land-use practices. [2KMI 35 </seg>
         <seg id="p037"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>