<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Every Cow On Her Own Merit</title>
               <date value="1917-05-05">1917-05-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 44 BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE EVERY COW ON HER OWN MERIT I. Individual Records II. Co-operative Cow-Testing Associations III. Junior Cow-Testing Clubs D. H. Propps, Assistant Professor of Dairy Extension Distributed May 5, 1917 IT IS EASY TO WEIGH THE MILK LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purposes of the Cooperative Agricul - tural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture Cooperating. C. W. Pugsley, Director of Extension Service </seg>
            <seg id="p002">University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD (The Regents of the University Hon. Frank L. Haller, President, Hon. John E. Miller, Lincoln Omaha Hon. Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Hon. Victor G. Lyford, Falls City Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Hon. Edward P. Brown, Davey THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor E. A. Burnett, B. Sc, Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, Experiment Station J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF THE EXTENSION COUNCIL (Heads of Departments. E. A. Burnett, B. Sc, Dean J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A. Animal Husbandry Dairy Husbandry C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Director Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D. Agricultural Botany Entomology H. C. FlLLEY, A. M. Farm Managemen F. W. Upson, Ph. D. Agricultural Chemistry Alice M. Loom is, A M. Home Economics L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E. Agricultural Engineering R. F. Howard, A. M Horticulture W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy J. H. Gain, M.»D. C. G. A. Loveland, A. M. Meteorology Animal Pathology H. E. Bradford, A. B., Principal, School of Agriculture C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc., Director Floyd Wambeam, B. Sc, Agricultural A. E^Anderson, A. B., County Agent L .^ KINNEK&gt; B . Sc., Junior Ex- worlc tension Work Maud Mathes Wilson, B. St., Home P. L. Gaddis, B. Sc., Farmers In- Economics stitutes, Short Courses, and Exhibit* EXTENSION SPECIALISTS I. D. Wood, A. M., Agricultural En- Mary A. Rokahr, A. B., Home Eco- gineering nomics K. F. Warner, M. S., Animal Hits- Emma Ort, B. Sc., Home Economics bandry {Junior Work J. G. McMillan, B. Sc., Pig Clubs E. H. Hoppert, B. Sc, Horticultun- D. H. Propps, B. Sc., Dairy Hus- LOUISE MEREDITH, B. Sc.,- Home bandry Economics H. F. Williams, B. Sc., Farm Man- C. W. Watson, B. Sc, AmMm*, agement Demonstrations Junior Extension Work R. R. Spafford, B. Sc, Assistant, V. D. Keim, B. Sc, Agronomy Farm Management Fred L. Taylor, B. Sc, Amittm* Emma Reed DaVISSON, Women's County Agent Work Clubs COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENTS F. M. Seidell, Boxbutte County A. C. North, B.Sc, Sheridan County R. E. Holland, B. Sc, Kimball r. h. Camp, B. Sc, Thurston County A. B.Sc, Madison L- Boyd Rist, B. Sc, Gage County County C. R. Young, Dakota County C. E. Gunnels, B. Sc, Seward H. N. Thomas, Dawes County County </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i 1 1 1 EVERY COW ON HER OWN MERIT I. INDIVIDUAL RECORDS How much milk did Rose give today, and Bess, and Daisy, tc. ? How much profit did your best cow make last month ? Your &gt;oorest cow? Which of your cows are high testers? How much loes it cost you to feed each cow a year? To get definite answers to such questions takes the drudgery &gt;ut of dairying and makes milking interesting and profitable. The nore a man learns about any business the more successful he lecomes in it Dairying is an industry which yields profits ac - ording to the amount of study and effort put into it. Milking cows day after day and month after month without ■ceeping records is undoubtedly responsible for our shamefully low iverage yield and for the large percentage of low profits in the iairy business. Certainly no man wishes to retain cows that are "eturning only a small margin of profit or are kept at a loss, A-hile others in his herd are returning annually a good profit above :ost of feed. Weeding out the poor producers and milking only profitable ones is a business proposition that the owner can afford to neglect. In every herd there is a poorest cow. It s this poorest cow and the rest of the comparatively poor ones hat cut down the profits made by the good cows in the herd. The following report of a Nebraska herd for last year fur - lishes a good illustration of the difference in cows : Loss No. of cow Profit over cost of feed $3.19 $11.71 4.28 8.38 35.64 7.26 1.57 ,15 ■2.U2 Totals $67.48 $7.62 Net profit of herd ($67.48— $7.62) $59.86 Profit from four best cows 62.99 Profit from best cow 35.64 Net profit from remaining eight cows of the herd ... 24 9.9. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin No. -44, College of Agriculture These figures show that if the owner of the herd had milked only his best 4 cows he would have received from them $3.13 more net profit than he received from the whole herd of 9 cows, besides saving the expense of taking care of the extra five. PROFIT OVER COST OF HID rMM MIT 4 COW! 1 HMD 62.99 HIT PROFIT OVIR COST OF FIED FROM HCRD OF 9 COWS 59. M The figures also show that cow No. 5 returned $11.42 more net profit than the remaining 8 cows of the herd. cows of the herd. COW NO.5 PROFIT OVER COST OF FEED If the owner had milked only two cows like No. 5, they would have returned him a profit of $71.28 over cost of feed in - stead of the $59.86 which he received from the whole herd of 9 cows. Such facts as these certainly show clearly the necessity of keeping records of each cow. There is so much difference in cows, and profits depend so much on the kind of cows kept, that the man who milks can not afford to neglect the important part of his work — the business part. Some form of record keeping is absolutely essential in order to determine the relative merits of the different cows in the herd. THE CHIEF ADVANTAGES OF KEEPING INDIVIDUAL RECORDS 1. Individual records form a correct basis for the elimina - tion of unprofitable cotes. It is common to find men who believe that they can tell, without weighing the milk, what their cows are producing. This is mere guesswork and can not form a reliable basis for selection. The cow which produces exceptionally well when fresh is usually remembered as the best cow in the herd, even though she may continue in milk only a few months, whereas the ordinary but more persistent milker often gives the largest annual yield and in the end is the most profitable. Again, the income </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Every Cow on Her Own Merit 5 from the herd as a whole — the size of the cream or milk check — usually attracts the attention of the owner rather than what each cow is doing. Individual records place each cow on her own merit and bring to light the unprofitable producers. 2. Production records increase the value of the good cows in the herd. A cow that has shown by actual figures that she is a profitable producer has added to her value according to the an - nual profit she has returned. Such a cow is a safe investment, for under similar conditions she is capable of continuing year after year at approximately the same rate of production. A Nebraska dairyman had offered a grade Jersey cow for sale a number of times at $50.00 because he thought she was unprofita - ble. One year of keeping records showed that she had produced 8,391 pounds of milk and 454 pounds of fat, which was 85 pounds more than any other cow in the herd of 11 cows. The owner says of her now, "She is not for sale, but she is worth $125.00 to me." Individual records, then, not only assist in weeding out un - profitable cows but also increase the value of good cows, since they indicate what each cow is capable of doing. 3. The record of the dam is an important factor in selecting calves to retain in the herd. It is usually safer, cheaper, and more satisfactory to build up a herd by breeding good cattle than to depend upon buying them. Many calves of excellent merit have been disposed of because no records were kept of the dams and, therefore, the value of the former was unknown. 4. Upon the daily milk production is based the quantity of food required daily by each cow. It is too often the case that each cow in the herd receives the same quantity of grain instead of each one being fed in proportion to the milk she is producing. 5. Keeping daily records is an excellent means of stimulat - ing interest. What the different cows are doing forms a popular topic for conversation about the barn, in the field, at school, at the table, and around the fireside. Each milker strives to maintain or increase the production of his cows from day to day. As a consequence the cows are more carefully fed and handled, the problems of dairying are studied and everything tends toward improvement and efficiency. This advantage alone is well worth the time and effort necessary to keep records. 6. Daily records enable one to detect at once any sickness in the herd. One of the first symptoms of illness is a decrease in milk flow. Therefore, When the milk is weighed at each milking, any sickness in the herd can readily be detected and early treat - ment given. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin No. -U, College of Agriculture EQUIPMENT NECESSARY FOR KEEPING RECORDS A milk scale, a daily milk sheet conveniently placed, and a pencil tied to a string near the sheet, make up the equipment nec - essary for weighing the milk at each milking. Feed records and an occasional test tor butter fat complete the essentials for record keeping. The milk scale is the important thing in record keeping. The milk from each cow should be weighed separately at each milking. This requires but very little time and, once the milker is accustomed to it, he becomes so interested that he pre - fers to continue the practice. The milk sheet should be consulted frequently and from it the quantity of grain that the cows should receive daily can readily be determined. A Babcock tester for determining butter fat is inexpensive and should be in every well-equipped dairy. A test of the milk from each cow one day each month is as often as is necessary. Even three or four tests during a lactation period will give a rea - sonably reliable estimate of the average per cent of fat for the year. When properly arranged for, such records take very little time and add both pleasure and profit to what otherwise would be an unpleasant and unprofitable task. Further information in regard to equipment and plans for keeping records may be obtained by addressing College of Agri - culture, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. II. CO-OPERATIVE COW-TESTING ASSOCIATIONS In communities where a sufficient number of cows are milked a number of farmers may unite to form a cooperative cow-testing association. They employ, cooperatively, a competent tester whose duty it is to visit each member's herd one day each month, to keep an individual record of each cow in the herd, and to pro - mote in every possible way the interest of the members. Such an organization, besides providing a practical and eco - nomical means of obtaining individual records with the benefits already discussed, furnishes additional advantages such as: 1. Cooperation in buying feed and supplies, purchase and sale of live stock, etc. 2. It may serve as a center of social activity and community interests. In many sections the lack of some form of organization is a handicap to reaching the people in the most effective manner. It is possible for the cooperative cow-testing association to supply such a need. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Every Cow on Her Own Merit 7 i c 3. The tester, besides keeping records, is able to furnish nformation in regard to rations, equipment, herd improvements, ;tc. Such information as the tester is able to give often proves .ery valuable to members. As many of them often express it, 'just to have the tester come and spend a day on the farm each nonth is worth all that the association costs me." WHAT THE TESTER DOES He spends one day every month on each member's farm. He weighs and takes a sample of milk from each cow, both morning ind evening. The milk is then tested for butter fat and each cow LUvI t\ tlllllg. Jilt I I 11 I r\ 13 I I IV 11 lv.Ji.vu »V» lsmvi«.i a.u.1 uiim x.u.t_aa x»w M s credited with the total amount of fat contained in the milk for hat day. The feed for each cow is eifher weighed or estimated ind she is charged with the total quantity consumed in one day. Fhese figures are then multiplied by the number of days in the nonth. thus giving the amount of fat produced and the quantity &gt;f feed consumed in that month. The value of both the product the feed is estimated at market prices. Other calculations also made for each cow. such as profit over cost of feed, return for each dollar invested in feed, cost of producing jxnind of butter fat, cost of producing a hundred pounds of milk, i\ When the tester has finished his work at each visit he leaves th the owner the book which shows what each cow in his herd s done that month. The book is the property of the owner d remains on the farm. The tester repeats his visit about the same time each month for a year, at the end of which time he totals the records of ach cow for the twelve months and furnishes he owner a complete summary of his herd. The cow tester works under the direction of the college of agriculture and must be especially trained for the work before he permitted to take charge of an association. The following records of two cows owned in the same herd in the Central Nebraska Cow-Testing Association last year illustrates the difference in economy of production: M Pounds Pounds Value r t Returns Feed cost of cow milk fat of of feed for $1 P** P ound ol cow produced produced product ol teea invested of fat Feed cost per 100 pounds in fee,! of milk Note the difference in the quantity of milk and butter fat pro - duced, returns for $1.00 invested in feed, feed cost of one pound of butter fat and 100 pounds of milk. Such a record is kept of each cow in the association. 8,813 4,545 321.8 163.3 ! $126.17 59.80 $47.47 44.97 12.65 1.33 14c 27c 53c 98c </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Extension Bulletin No. kU, College of Agriculture HOW MANY MEN DOES IT TAKE TO FORM AN ASSOCIATION? About 26, one member for each working day in the month. In some cases two small herds, when close together, can be tested the same day. HOW MANY COWS MUST BE OWNED IN AN ASSOCIATION? At least 400 and they must be owned in herds of ten or more, unless two small herds are close together so that they can be tested the same day. HOW MUCH DOES IT COST? The Dairy Division, United States Department of Agriculture, the extension and the dairy departments of the University of Nebraska furnish assistance in organizing and also furnish cer - tain material and apparatus necessary for carrying on the work. The salary of the tester must be provided for by the association. The cost should not exceed $1.50 per cow per year. In an association of 400 cows this would make a total of $600.00, which is the minimum salary for a tester. He also receives board and lodging while on the farm, as well as transportation to the next place. In sections where there are not yet cows enough to form an association of 26 men owning a total of 400 cows, it is sometimes practicable to organize smaller associations in communities that are not too far apart, for instance, associations of from 12 to 14 men owning a total of 200 cows. Two of these small associations jointly employ a tester for full time, allowing him to spend part of his time with one association and the remainder with the other. The number of members will gradually increase until finally each association will have cows enough to employ a tester all the time. III. JUNIOR COW-TESTING CLUBS In communities where there are not cows enough to justify the organization of a cow-testing association, junior cow-testing clubs are sometimes practicable. Under the supervision of the public school teacher or some such competent person such clubs are proving successful in Nebraska. The records kept are exactly the same as cow-testing-association records. Besides the practical value of the records, the young people get a great deal of valuable training and experience. The clubs should finally develop into cow-testing associations as soon as the number of cows in the community increases sufficiently to justify such an organization. If there is a possibility of organizing a cooperative cow - testing association, or a junior cow-testing club in your community, address College of Agriculture, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>