<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Sixth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1912 1912 Tn WooMuvr Bank Nots Co. Lncow, NnwiA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">F. L. HALLER, President Omaha, Nebraska S. AVERY Chancellor of the University of Nebraska J. E. DELZELL State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY State Librarian DR. W. K. JEWETT Librarian of the University of Nebraska CHARLOTTE TEMPLETON, Secretary GUESS HUMPHREY, Librarian FLORENCE E. WAUGH, Librarian for State Institution! </seg>
            <seg id="p003">To Hit Excellency, Cluater H. Aldrick, Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sib: Complying with the requirement of the law, I herewith Ethe report of the Public Library Commission for the biennhim November 30, 1912. I commend to your attention this report of retary. Very respectfully yours, F. L. Haller. President </seg>
            <seg id="p004">X F • » i 4 • u 1 ■ R i' » • V' •i I 1 N - r z f i i—i 6 £il 1 * 1*. - • ¥ ■r •■ J • s ■ • | • ■» 1 i ~i ' !• • -- • I K it: • . * s "i • r .5 # » •■I % | • &lt; • • X 1 I ■ u • .• i • i • a • M o c 8 I 4. J :\ • • ■ g - s ■ I ■ ■ • • — • ■ 1 ■ J ■ ■ * •5 •\ • z ■ • m m ■ s • ■ 5 X X g I • ■ ■ • • s I I X »| ! F«, • ■ a o 9 m • r | I ■ t j ! </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 I The aim and purpose of the Public Library Commission is to foster library interests of the state. To encourage the formation of libraries re none exist, to advise as to the best methods of establishing, organiz - and administering such libraries, to furnish, through traveling libraries, 1 reading to those communities which have no library facilities, to ;est legislation favorable to the best development of public libraries, to rm communities of the possibilities of library service, to inspire li - ians and trustees with a desire to make the library a vital force for 1, these are the duties of the Library Commisssion. That it is accorn - ling its task in some measure is seen by comparing the library con - &gt;ns of the state today with those of eleven years ago. There were then thirty-four public libraries, about four librarians with special training, seven public library buildings, and the State Library Association consisted of a mere handful of people. We can now report ninety-one libraries, twenty librarians who are graduates of library schools and as many more who have had summer school courses, thirty-nine library buildings, and a Library Association which recently met in Lincoln with an attendance of over 100. We have a satisfactory library law which permits the establishment of city, county and township libraries, we have 10,000 volumes in a state circulating library, and we have made an excellent beginning in establishing libraries in our state institutions. That part of this work which has been accomplished during the past two yean is set forth in the following report. K During the past biennium there has been but one change in the per - el of the Public Library Commission. In October, 1911, J. E. Delzell the place of E. C. Bishop on the Commission. F. L. Haller, on the ation of his term of office in May, 1911, was re-appointed by the imor. Ehe regular semi-annual meetings have been held each year, and the business transacted. At the annual meeting in 1911 and again in F. L. Haller was re-elected president and Charlotte Templeton, n. The Commission was represented at the meeting of the American Library Association at Pasadena in 1911, by the Librarian; at the meeting at Ottawa in 1912, by Dr. Jewett and the Secretary; at the mid-winter meetings of the League of Library Commissions in Chicago in 1910 and 1911, by the Secretary. The Secretary and the Institution Librarian attended the meeting of the National Prison Congress in Omaha in 1911, and the meeting of the Nebraska Conference of Charities and Corrections in Omaha in 1912. All of the staff attended the meetings of the Nebraska Library Association in Omaha in 1911 and in Lincoln in 1912. The Secretary has given eighteen public talks at clubs, schools, and library dedications; the Institution Librarian has made talks at the State- Federation of Woman's Clubs and at the State Library Association. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Public Libr.rie. state by correspondence and by personal visits varying in length from a few hours to two weeks. Lists and samples of needed supplies, suggestive lists of books for first purchase and by-laws and regulations for the govern - ment of the library have been prepared for new libraries; building plans have been passed upon; and help in cataloguing and organizing has been given to eighteen libraries. The Commission has sent to all libraries the monthly Booklist, published by the American Library Association, and for the past year has sent also the Wisconsin Library Bulletin. Other book lists and printed helps on library administration have been sent wherever they were needed. The secretary has spent about six months out in the state and has travelled almost 10,000 miles in the interests of the public libraries. Since our report of two years ago we have added to the list of Nebraska libraries the following: Ainsworth, Auburn, Burwell, Exeter, Fullerton, Lexington, Murray, North Platte, Ogallala, O'Neill, Orleans, Palmyra, Sidney, Spalding and Winside, fifteen in ail, the largest number of new libraries ever reported in one biennium. Seven association libraries have lufonw tax-supported libraries. The towns of Bloomfield, Broken Bow, Fairfield, Genoa, Laurel and Pierce, all having made levies for the support of libraries already established. Library buildings have been completed in Ainsworth, Alliance, Alma, Ashland, Aurora, Chadron, North Platte, ' - j Pierce, Schuyler and Sutton, and buildings are under construction in Geneva, Gibbon, Madison, Ponca, Seward, and North Bend. The library at Ainsworth was erected at a cost of $4,000 by a citizen, L K. Alder, and presented to the town. The others were the gift of Andrew Carnegie in the following amounts: Alliance, $10,000; Alma, $10,000; Ashland, $5,500 from Carnegie, $1,450 from citizens; Aurora, $10,000; Chadron, $5,500; Geneva, $8,000; Gibbon, $6,000; Madison, $6,000; North Bend, $7,500; North Platte, $12,000; Pierce, $4,000 from Carnegie, $1,200 from citizens; Ponca, $4,500; Schuyler, $9,000; Seward, $8,000; Sutton, $5,700; Wayne, $9,000. I We have a total of ninety-one libraries in the state; sixty-eight sup - fd by taxation, and twenty-three association and subscription libraries, ■e are now only three towns of over 2,000 population which have not n steps to provide themselves with libraries. These are Benson, oo and Wymore. There is evidence of a growing appreciation of the public library in the increased appropriations made by city councils for library purposes. Almost as soon as the library law was amended by the last legislature, raising the limit of library taxation, several town councils made the full three mill levy. K&amp;t the last session of the legislature the library law was amended to ' possible the establishment of township and county libraries. Already townships have organised libraries. In Gibbon township a two mill was made, a library established by the Gibbon Library Association akra over by the township, the village of Gibbon donated a site and </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 and the town have turned over to the townships their public libraries. O'Neill had no library of any sort and having voted a two mill township levy will start from the beginning as a township library. KThe advantages of the township over the village and town library &gt;bvious. All of our libraries serve or should serve the country people g around the town and making it their business and social center. •iving these library privileges they should pay for them at the same that the townspeople pay. Then when all are paying their share, ncome of the library will be adequate to provide really efficient service for all. I Take for instance the case of Gibbon, a village of 700 people, where a mill village levy would bring MOO to the library treasury. Now the try people use and enjoy the Gibbon library as much as do the towns - le and are quite willing and able to pay their share toward its support. 10 mill levy on the township, including the town, amounts to over 0, on which a very good little library can be maintained. The library rving just the same territory that it served before, the only difference ; that all are helping to support it on the same basis and that in return are getting something really worth while. Certainly township ort seems to be the solution of the problem of the small library, strug - with inadequate means and striving to serve a large country con- stituency. Unfortunately township libraries are possible in only about one-third of the state, since two-thirds of our counties do not have township organiza - tion. However, another form of rural extension was made possible by amending the library law to provide for the establishment of county libraries. Taking advantage of this new provision of the law, Lancaster County voted at the general election this year to make a library levy on the county, outside Lincoln, Havelock and College View, which already maintain libraries. It remains for the county commissioners to fix the rate of levy and to determine the mode of operating the county library. Doubtless a contract will be made with the Lincoln City Library for the extension of its privileges to the county. I The establishment of these township and county libraries, the ex - on of the use of the library beyond town and city limits on terms of ort adequate to secure efficient service, is perhaps the most notable in library progress which has been made in the state in the past decade. Traveling Libraries The use of the traveling library department during the biennium has continued to increase. We sent out 30,225 volumes in response to 1,306 requests. This is an increase of over 32% over the number of volumes sent out in the last biennium. The increase might have been much larger however, had we had more books to send out. From November to May of last year there was seldom a time when the number of requests on file did not exceed the number of libraries in. The map facing the first page </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 of this report shows how widely distributed the use of the traveling library ha&gt; been. There are only seven counties to which we have not sent books during the biennium. We find our practice of combining the fixed group and open shelf system successful. We have a unit of fifteen adult fiction and twenty children's books to which we add books to suit the special community. Our patrons express far more satisfaction in the books and we find that we are holding our old stations better than formerly. Moreover the actual use of our non-fiction has increased. KiVhile we are doing our utmost to supply books to the people of the who have no other library facilities, we are so limited in resources we barely approach the task. If we are to meet the demands made us we must have more books, and we trust that the legislature will . us an additional $2,000 for the purchase of books. Libraries in the State Institution* In my report of two years ago I set forth the need of well-chosen and properly supervised libraries in our state institutions. The matter was presented to the Legislature, and the Legislature, recognizing the need, set aside $5,000 to be used by the Public Library Commission for the purpose of beginning this work. Miss Florence Waugh was engaged by the Com - mission as institution librarian and began work on May 15, 1911. Pre - liminary to forming any definite plans. Miss Waugh visited all of the state institutions, studying their various needs. After her return we made an apportionment of the funds and planned in detail the method of con - ducting the work. It was decided to follow the plan of a city branch system; ordering, accessioning, cataloguing and preparing the books for circulation to be done, for the most part, at the central office; the order cards with the addition of some items of information to be filed as a dup - licate author list in the office; all supplies to be ordered in quantity and distributed to the libraries as needed. Under this plan the librarian would do the most of her work in the Commission office with a great economy of time, and at the same time keep more closely in touch with all of the I The plan of procedure being determined upon and the funds appor - rd, work began in earnest. What we have accomplished in the different tutions is reported here in brief. I At the Orthopedic Hospital Dr. Orr became interested at once and fitted up a library room with cork carpet, low tables and chairs and book cases. We subscribed for a number of magazines for the use of patients and staff and bought over 200 volumes. These are the choicest children's books in the best editions. We bought no books he staff but Miss Waugh has kept a collection of books from the oln City Library on deposit for their reading, changing them once a th. The circulation here is good and the teacher reports that she es a great deal of use of the books in her school work. A story hour •Id in the library once a week and a boys' debating club for the older has been organized. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 In the Boys' Industrial School we found several hundred standard classics, and the tattered remains of a collection of boys' books which had literally been read to pieces. We bought about 250 volumes, all in Chivers bindings, anticipating hard wear. A central reading room being deemed impracticable, and our funds being insufficient to duplicate magazines for the different cottages, no magazines were subscribed for. The books are kept in a room in the central building and are exchanged on Sunday mornings. Ethe Girls' Industrial School a pleasant reading room was fitted up school; we subscribed for magazines and bought about 200 volumes I, readable girls' books. ■The Industrial Home for Women at Milford also fitted up a library 1. We bought for them about 100 books and subscribed for several azines. I The School for the Deaf already had a considerable library but it was ganized. We classified and catalogued the books, introduced a new ging system and added about 125 volumes. I The Tuberculosis Hospital was established after our appropriation made but we felt that we must do something for the patients there bought 125 volumes of popular fiction and subscribed for a few maga- For the Insane Hospital at Lincoln we bought 340 books and sub - scribed for magazines. The books are kept in the reception room and the stenographer acts as librarian. For the Insane Hospital at Norfolk we bought 300 volumes and also subscribed for magazines. The books are kept in the office of the Head Nurse who acts as librarian. For the Hospital at Ingleside we bought 444 volumes but subscribed for no magazines since they already took a good many papers. They have fitted up a small library room at Ingleside and the telephone operator is librarian. For the insane we selected wholesome, cheerful, and interesting fiction and a few - books of non-fiction, but we find very little non-fiction read. The prime requisite in a book for the insane is its power to hold the attention and since fiction does this to a much greater extent than non-fiction, fiction must form the bulk of the library. The function of a library in a hospital for the insane is obviously entirely different from its function in other institutions. tAt the Soldiers' Home in Grand Island we found an excellent library dy in the institution, but they welcomed the new fiction which we d. The magazines and newspapers are also very popular. They had ooks at the Soldiers' Home at Milford and we purchased for them volumes and subscribed for a number of magazines. For both the ers' homes we bought the Brady's Photographic History of the Civil which has proved a source of much pleasure. I We have to report one failure. Owing to a lack of interest on the of the superintendent at the Feeble Minded Institute, we have been to do nothing there. Books have been purchased for the institution are being held until conditions for work are more favorable. The largest piece of work which we have done has been the reorganizing of the Penitentiary library. It was, what I fear is the typical prison library, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 in very bad condition. The shelves were crowded, there waa no adequate lystem of records and the men had no way of knowing what there was in the library, since the supply of an old printed catalog was exhausted. However, we found there as our chief asset an intelligent and interested librarian, who soon became a veritable exemplification of the "library spirit." Our first task was to discard unsuitable and worn out books. Then the librarian made a card list of all the books left. About 340 new books were purchased and the whole library was classified and catalogued and a printed list prepared. The printing of this list took $100 from our book fund but we felt that it was essential. Many of the books were past rebinding, all were dirty and ragged, and successive librarians had devised new systems of shelving and had each added a label to the back of the book. The librarian soaked off all the old labels, washed and shellacked the covers, and put books back into loose covers with flexible glue. New shelving was provided and now the whole collection is in excellent order. The printed list and a number of short suggestive lists and the personal suggestions of the librarian have greatly stimulated an interest in the better sort of books and some of the non-fiction is having a remarkable circulation. The extent to which the men use the library is shown in the report for last month. The average population for the month was 380: 1,077 books were circulated and M% of the circulation was non-fiction. I We look back on the first year and a half's work in our institution ries with considerable satisfaction. By no means do we take all of ■redit for its success upon ourselves. Nothing could have been accom - ed without the cooperation of the heads of the institutions and they been most cordial and interested. Nor could we have made any ble success of our undertaking without the efforts of the local librarians have been generous of their time and services. Doubtless the statements of those most interested in the welfare of the wards of the state as to the value of our work will have more weight than anything I could say and I quote from the letters of several of the superintendents. I Dr. Orr of the Orthopedic Hospital says: "As you know I have been much interested in the educational side of the care of crippled children I can say that the library in which you have taken so much interest &gt;ntributed very largely to the development as well as the pleasure of atients in the Orthopedic Hospital. The library service not only con - tes books necessary for their immediate use but serves the larger we of teaching our children how to use a public library. This cannot » be of the greatest good to them in after life. All the officers of the ution, especially the members of the teaching staff, earnestly hope an appropriation may be made for the continuation of this very 1 work." I Mr. C. B. Manuel of the Boys' Industrial School: "I wish to add hearty approval and commendation for the splendid work of the ary Commission in connection with our state institutions. The library ■ which we received from the Library Commission have been a source </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 books have been wisely selected to meet the various requirements of the boys. I am in hopes that the Legislature will make a liberal appropriation that this work so splendidly begun can be continued and enlarged, as I believe no money can be expended in a better cause than that of placing before the inmates of the state institutions good books." Miss Lyda McMahon, Girls' Industrial School: "I most sincerely hope that the coming Legislature will appropriate sufficient funds for the promotion of the work in your department which has been of so much pleasure and of such benefit to the unfortunate people of our state. We certainly have appreciated what has been done for us by the Public Library Commission and I want to say a word of thanks for Miss Waugh for the deep interest she took in selecting wholesome reading for our girls. Every book has been useful and I do not know of any money that has been more judiciously expended to bring about a combined recreation and helpful improvement than our Library of which we are so proud." It. W. Booth, Superintendent of the School for the Deaf: "Speaking ir own school and the benefits coming to it from the labors of yourself -our associates, I feel that I cannot say too much in commendation » work of the Public Library Commission. The new books presented by the Commission were carefully selected with reference to subject ?r and to attractiveness of illustration and print, and they have been !y read and greatly enjoyed by the pupils. As reading must for the largely take the place of hearing, as a source of information and en - ent, you will readily appreciate that your work is most helpful to our 1 in providing its library with well selected, up-to-date books." Miss Lena Ward, Industrial Home for Women: "Your letter in regard to the library received, but I scarcely know how to reply to it as it would be impossible for me to tell you how much the girls have enjoyed the books and I am sure that they have greatly benefited by reading them. I have been really surprised at the number who never fail to get their books each week. Girls who had never seemed to care a thing about reading always come now for their books every time we give them out. They often speak of this themselves and say they never before seemed to care to read but they do now. I think that it is because the books have been so carefully selected and are so well suited to them. There is no question but what they have been of great benefit to the girls aside from the pleasure they have gotten from reading them." I Dr. B. F. Williams, Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln: "I want to say rd to you with reference to the value of the library in connection the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. At the time of the installation e library we were not fully decided as to its value. As the months passed the patients have become more and more interested in general ng. The periodicals and magazines are sought after diligently, and ooks of fiction are in constant service." Dr. A. Johnson, Norfolk State Hospital: "Many of our patients are reading the books out of our new library with a great deal of interest. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 like them." The G. A. R., Department of Nebraska, wished to express its ap - preciation of the libraries in the two soldiers' homes and at its annual en - campment held in Beatrice in May, 1912, passed the following resolution: "Resolved: That we most heartily endorse the appropriation made by the last legislature for the establishment of libraries in state institutions, placing the same under the supervision and control of the Public Library Commission, and recommend that in future such libraries be accorded liberal support by the state." But the last word must be said by the readers themselves. Some of the men at the Penitentiary have written us letters, striving to express what the library means to them. I quote from them in part: t' I believe books play a very important part to the shut-in, for with - hem a man has nothing to keep his mind off his troubles. And if one nothing but sit his idle hours away, rapt up in thoughts of his troubles ill soon become a proper subject for a mad-house. I am almost sure my mind would have gave away had I been deprived of reading it, as I am a man that talks but a little." K Another says: "The library books borrowed by me have been the us of obtaining a fair knowledge of the history of several of the fore - : countries. They have also given me a broader view of life and a er standard of morals. . . Having stopped school when very young, ve the library to praise for what education I have." I From another: "I am doing time in Lancaster and after my day's [ is done then the hardest part of my confinement commences . . . t had no books the time would be almost unbearable ... I think ing good clean books is one of the best ways of getting to the best of man. Get him to thinking good, clean thoughts and you have him be way to reform for 'as a man thinketh so is he.' " That the men themselves see in the book a moral agent is shown in the last letter. That idea is also expressed in this: "Sometime ago our librarian asked me to read a book on right living. I took the book and read it. It found it to be just what I needed and I have been reading books along that line ever since and have got a lot of good out of them." I will close with this tribute, indirectly to the library, but directly to the prison librarian for the splendid service he is rendering. It is a letter written to him by one of the men. "Allow me to commend your efficient service as librarian of this in - stitution. I deeply appreciate the delicacy of your position and slightly understand what it is to please all of us. Doubtless you are unique in selecting appropriate books for people with such various temperaments . . . I heartily thank you for the books furnished me which have been inspiring and helpful in elevating my thoughts and better fitting me for my return toaoeiety." </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 SUMMARY OF STATISTICS, NOVEMBER 30, 1912 Volumes in library, November 30, 1910 8,811 Added, November 30, 1910-November 30, 1912 1,490 Total 10,301 Withdrawn, November 30, 1910-November 30, 1912 237 Volumes in library, November 30, 1912 10,064 Volumes sent out, November 30, 1910-November 30, 1912 30,225 Number of requests 1.306 EXPENDITURES, NOVEMBER 30, 1910-NOVEMBER 30, 1912 S. 2Z Printing 140.00 Supplies, equipment, office expenses 1,409.46 Secretary 2,900.00 Librarian 1,780.00 Extra assistance 518.90 Total $9,670.28 EXPENDITURES FOR STATE INSTITUTIONS, MAY 15, 1911- NOVEMBER 30, 1912 Books and magazines $2,682.98 Printing and binding 114.08 Equipment 114.30 Travel '. 101.66 Salary 1,012.50 Total M.176.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">1 9 teii ijf linn, yiiffliiia IS aooeo^as-* ot-ci»oo« coo^o^Oito abt-^-^t-NO^tcsi n 0* CO . W MC4 W « «^ CS .53 2 ojoo&gt;oct-t-»o«woNr-o xoacoooMooecoot^^cooaooo oo ** f-T wf w* cScvw* w^eo *-T ' eo* i— • , •OO ON r:Je«t£0!CU!t-0"!ON*Ou:t-»aCl-MOCO«)'»aC t*o - C4 ao nnidnoQO)nacQteOAHiet-e4tec}(ioooototfi^t&lt; ac ■ cr^*A * fc *tw n i^o t-^^i5 oc^oi (C o ai t^ oc « « oi ft* t- f t6M5 * — p II P5 IO OC CD OOt-CXC-'Ct'iOXH^ CO 00 TO M O ■ XOC ac^NXc ccric^cwquj'fNOtD oc^t^-*o t^ cdoo ci »-« c r! i" c «c &gt;fl &lt;-&lt; 6 o; d wi 3; n cc &gt;o totdccc^io !*- o o o 3 nnntcach- Tfcicsci as ■» cz &lt;c t~ *~ &lt;r. ■&gt;» oc &gt;o — t- 1-« co&gt;o&gt;oco ! ooaooouico m •» ao t- © © «o © &lt;c t~ © ej-«t-teot£&gt;a&gt;©'V©r- cc w ci ui c-j oo^no oioeobtoaod lO^tcaicoccwxiono Haot^ioM ocooxo ooKHnva NOonvst-nanN •-" •&gt;» •©■♦ . "-"M N .CON'* "»«H iQie-«CM«5C O&gt; *- .«» . . . M " :gg§ggg : g^gS Sgg 52S :SSSS8838SSS 6 W »b «c c «o CNuid ;&lt;coo&gt; &gt;* t^ o O — X S 1 . •■£ -^ 00t~^*~4 ACOO t-t-CD WiONXI-^ONXUSOi ecco TOC i. .^^^&lt; t&gt; . oo .osoco R.^.^ m o&gt; h 10 HNNMMM _^ei5i-i— rtNNWi-l^CO CJ i-lNNi-lN £§ .*. H .°. B .*. M . N . W ■^. co . l °- 0 .'*-t ;0 c i^ c l t^. t l c^. e * 10 6 " *t oaci^iooioi' *o**coaoi-*w+ ooscfeo*^?© n" oo" liliiiiiiiliiiiilil </seg>
            <seg id="p015">i iScEt-r3E=«&gt;,cc.i-ai-=aEEEMgcciCEcEa -5 04W^V^O ■ ** -CO OOiOt-O-^^X-^MtOtO -COCO -00 - iO CM HsenNO o -us eiHNNnt-'H^aonna -o&gt;© i-h -t-«o N CM -*_tM ■* P) ■ ■» © ■ ©_&gt;O -i© ■* °. l °. °. 00 . * L'". O&gt; . 'i 0 ?. ' •?. ' *^*l «3 © x"t-"«-Tco" »" © o&gt; w"a» «s « t- eo" »J tdoDOii-! ' t-^co" ! eo 1 ! us «e IN I nowoocotcwoooto^ftffJHmt-oiaottnxoootto NOHOOOJIB)HOOOC)»01i»«N(-Ht-S»^X«NX»0 ooa&gt;c~ooa:'««oioMooMco —_«&gt; Nart»»«Nie»N&lt;e^HMH«i US e| •■• ~*" C4 -• P* | ato^nnoo^o^oioniOH^cQeQQOooiomoo^taAQXiot- t-ooat-OHOxOnoo«c&lt;«NC&gt;xi&lt;t-t-ion2«»ie3eiaH TO M 00_O_N 0000 r-_00 Ot-_M»1-OH10» 00 . t ".'°. 0 .''. N . 0 .* "°. tt l &gt;O . IS t-OSOOOn OOIO OAH0)t&gt;HOU34OOHOt«03Ot-QXa0 eeaoofl c~o&lt;-« oo^«eoquici&gt;ooooeriaH«e«ci odoot-oood ; ci ai ci *ujk0oiinkr&gt;tooieood^k6^cd&gt;-4cocdo30ci&lt;£ ■»«&gt;-«00»'&gt;1' .CJU3K1 NNHn«H0J»OB»««»»n«O«J- t- (O W£ O X . O_W 00 ON t~t^^^^HCOf-tO)C4C0O4e«l tJ 1 t-» -i-H t-7 us eJi eo | E I O ! eouooo KOKoeoai«MO&gt;ot-«ioaNo«c&gt;i tddaiidiOH I t&gt; © o'cio^doi- 'noujtbodwooTrt^orjio t-t 1O CO tC 00 N rt rt N Cl CQ04~* CC °°" E «»&lt;009&gt;N USplM ON«» CM rt CO CO « © C- CC t- 00 00 ■«» © CO « hSoo © ce © ooo&gt;nt^ooisnn»«!nooqao 06 cc t~ &gt;r&gt; &gt;b cd sdo uj t^ to «i t~ &lt;6 ■+ a6 &lt;6 &gt;6 ui oi t~ ei ■+ *-i si t~ t~ Nd^^CJH . 00 ~H . i-Hi-tCO . OJ »-H © N i-t HiHi-tH^H »S ■ V • - g§§gg§ S§§ §gg8§S§S§§§S§g§g§SSS H is o C4C4 NONHHrtN RMNHMNM Mi-NtHfHNNrtrtN if »aa»ioion«ioo&lt;diHt-SNH(Diooi««NNHoO'4ooHie« ou&gt;aaNOo&gt;2o«04as&gt;o«oouisoo«»4tt«&lt;aao&gt;o9 t^ ia •** *ti ■— t- Oh tOOOOiOJO-^00^^ O t- -^ fr^OO •~i^ 1 C^f- C^ ■ : :^ :::.::.::::::: : j :::::::::::: : :3 i :-g| : :.? : :| : : : : :| : : : : : -^ : : :% : §«-| ij6^do»s ■iali^^a ! </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 LIBRARIES NOT SUPPORTED BY TAXATION •Fee charged for the use of the books. Having been unable to get reports from the following libraries, they are not included in the tables above: Blair, Bloomfield, Edgar, Gering, Keystone, Ogallala, Pierce, Stanton, Valley, Waterloo. The following libraries have been established for such a short time that they were unable to make a report: Burwell, Exeter, Murray, O'Neill, Spalding POPULAT'N VOLUMES PATRONS LIBRARIAN ;uburn Srj5&amp;.:: seti "ullerton «xin«tonV 2,729 541 1,065 1,261 1,638 2,059 978 237 942 343 1,137 1,185 742 489 339 546 314 1,000 1,000 450 700 271 955 840 701 161 425 76 399 1,120 200 Mrs. Addie I. Johnson Mrs. H. N. McGriff Mildred Epperson Carrie Roehl Mrs. Irving Fuller Mrs. H. Grace Thomas Mrs. George Follmer Mrs. Lamson E-i h * 200 104 114 Mrs. Bertha Willey Mrs. Constance Corbett </seg>
            <seg id="p017">H 3 2f ot 111 SN « eo i- ■ • • i ifi iooo U3U3 laou: ana " l . m . tB . U3 CC « »O « ll 00^00-*NTftO«(DU5-&gt;*i-H eo h n m ■* N »h m »h »h hm ejoo oobh .« oootaoooooooaoo 5io-&lt;nooi»ooh!oh« p4 iiilii ; I !d :oaSJfc2 • ; s . filliiltlliil </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>