<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00032.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00032.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION NOVEMBER 30, 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS m m m Governor JOHN H. MOREHEAD Superintendent JAMES E. DELZELL Land Commissioner FRED BECKMANN m m m Chief Clerk J. \V. SHAMAN- ED 01 02 cW% 3W*? After January 7, 1915, the State Board will consist of JOHN H. MOREHEAD .Governor A. O. THOMAS Superintendent of Public Instruction KRED BECKMANN Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildinss CD ED CD aWe SWB SW6 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Institutions m m m NAME OF SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE 1. State Penitentiary Lane W. T. FENTON, Warden 1 State Industrial School Kearney R. V. CLARK, Supt. 3. Girls' Industrial School Geneva MISS LYDA J. McMAHON, Supt. 4. Nebraska Industrial Home Milford MISS LENA E. WARD, Supt. 5. Nebraska Hospital for the Insane Lincoln Dr. B. F. WILLIAMS, Supt. 6. Hospital for the Insane Norfolk Dr. W. D. GUTTERY, Supt. Nebraska State Hospital Inglesids Dr. M. W. BAXTER, Supt. 8. Board of Control for Dependent Children Lincoln MISS ETTA CATON, Agent 9. Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Dr. H. WINNETT ORR, Supt I" Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' IIoiiic Burke tl Commandant FERDINAND Z1MMERER 11. Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford Commandant. D. C. ROW DEN ■ebraska State Institution for Feeble Minded Youth ....Beatrice Dr. W. D. FAST, Supt. 13. Institution for the Deaf and Dumb Omaha FRANK W. BOOTH, Supt. 14. Institute for the Blind . .Nebraska Citv N. C. ABBOTT. Supt. 15. Tuberculosis Hospital Kearney Dr. E. R. VAN DER SLICE. Supt. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">OF THE State Board of Charities and Correction To His Excellency, John H. Morehead, Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir: I have the honor to present herewith the report of this Department for the Biennial period ending November 30, 1914. Mr. J. A. Piper had been Chief Clerk of this De - partment for a number of years, but on September 1, 1913, he resigned, and I was appointed to take his place. This being the case, I am unable to make a report that is as satisfactory to myself, at least, as though I had done all of the work myself. tnder the law as it now exists, the Chief Clerk of this rtment is also Secretary of the Advisory Board of &gt;ns, and of the State Prison Board, thus giving us an •tunity of doing a vast amount of work and good, for pbuilding of unfortunate and downfallen humanity. Chapter 63, Section 2, of the Revised Statutes of the State of Nebraska, provides that the Board "Shall inquire into the whole system of public charities and methods of and practices in the correctional institutions of the state and counties, and to ascertain the condition thereof from time to time by inspection or otherwise, especially of prisons, jails, infirmaries, public hospitals, asylums, re - formatories and industrial schools", and in accordance with that law and the instructions of your excellency, I have </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 6 visited and inspected the State Institutions and the Jails and Poor Farms in forty-two of the counties in the state. I would have been pleased to inspect the Jails and Poor Farms in the other counties had I the means to do so, but unfortunately the appropriation of the last session of the Legislature would not permit. I have now applications from the County Officials of two counties to inspect their Jail and Poor Farm, with the view of bettering the condition, but cannot do so on account of lack of funds. In my estimate of office and traveling expenses for the coming Biennium I have asked for an additional appropriation of four hundred dollars so that I may be able to perform all the duties imposed by law upon this Department, and I hope it may be granted. EPhe Jails of this state, as a rule, are not models of con - ence, many being located in dark, low basements, with - city water, toilet accomodations or ventilation, and are lecessity very unsanitary and unhealthy. Others are poor building, where prisoners have to be kept locked n iron cage, inside the building, deprived of exercise of kind, in order to keep them at all. I visited one Jail in a prominent city of the state where a prisoner had dug through the wall with an ordinary table knife and escaped, but was re-captured, and I asked him how long it took him to dig through the wall and he told me it took him about thirty minutes. In another the Jail was so poor, that although locked inside the cage, it was necessary to guard the prisoners day and night, at a cost of four dollars per day. This class of Jails deserves con - demnation, and new, up-to-date, ones should be built. On the other hand, some are good Jails, being located on the third, fourth or fifth floor of a good fire-proof Court House. At least three of such have been constructed during the last year, and arrangements have been made to build at </seg>
            <seg id="p007">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 7 POOR FARM BUILDINGS. (le law of our state providing for County Poor Farms tie distinction of being one of its most ancient, having enacted in its present form, except for one or two dments, in territorial days, by the Legislature of At our Poor Farms we find two general classes, the defective, and the dependent. In the defective class there are the feeble minded, blind, deaf and epileptic. In the dependent group there are those on account of poverty, old age, and deformity. The make up of these groups without means of classification makes it necessary for the almost constant association of the idle and industrious, the weak minded and intelligent, the vulgar and the decent. Our Poor Farms are also required to receive many who are sorely in need of special attention and nursing, and as a rule they have no equipment to render this service, and some thought should be given to this as well as to classi - fication. Some of the Poor Farms are conducted on sane and business principles, are clean and in good condition, while others, I am sorry to say, are poorly kept, are almost filthy, and it is a shame, in this great state of ours, that such conditions exist; and it is not altogether the fault of the Superintendent. I complained to one Superintendent about the condition of the building, the floors were worn out, the roof leaked, the plastering was falling off. no bathing: facilities, etc., and he told me that at least one of the County Commissioners, who had held the office for three years, had never visited the Poor Farm. I called upon the Com - missioners that day, they being in session, and recommended such changes as I thought ought to be made and they promised me that they would go out to the farm, and see that they were made at once. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD At some of the Poor Farms where they have from 160 to 320 acres of land, worth more than one hundred dollars per acre, we find fine large horse and cow barns, hog and chicken houses, granaries, etc., with an abundance of fine high bred horses, cows and hogs, and an old tumble down house for the inmates to occupy. The Commissioners seem to think it is their only duty to see how much the farm will produce, and how many blue ribbons they can bring home from the county fair. This is all right of itself but it should not be tolerated when it is done at the sacrifice of the poor unfortunate inmates. The most sacred place to any one, whether rich or poor, is home; so we should give to these unfortunate people, not only food and clothing, but with such comforts as will make them feel that they have indeed a home, and not a charitable institution. INDETERMINATE SENTENCE AND PAROLE. We have now been operating under the Indeterminate Sentence and Parole law for nearly three and one-half years, and during that time have granted paroles to 449 prisoners, mostly to those known as first termers. Of this number 80% have made good. Of the twenty per cent who failed to make good, nineteen have been returned to the Peniten - tiary by the Board for violating their paroles. While these 449 men were out on parole, serving time under restrictions, instead of being an expense and burden to the state, they have earned for themselves and those dependent upon them the sum of $65,595.00, and by them being out on parole have saved to the state the sum of $50,992.80, which amount the state would have had to pay for their keep, if they should have remained in the penitentiary. STATE INSTITUTIONS. Ehe State Institutions are all in excellent shape, clean, sanitary, and the different Superintendents are doing l their power to make their wards comfortable and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 9 tUp to July 1, 1913, these Institutions were under the trol of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. This ird consisted of the Governor, Secretary of State, At - torney General, State Treasurer, and Land Commissioner. While no doubt these gentlemen rendered the best service they could, under the circumstances, yet taking into con - sideration the numerous demands upon their time as state officers, it was almost a physical impossibility to do justice to the State Institutions. Evidently the people recognized the disadvantage under which these institutions were man - aged, for at the election of 1912 an Amendment to the Constitution was voted upon, and adopted by a substantial majority, creating a "Board of Commissioners for State This Board consists of three members, appointed by the Governor, and approved by the Senate. The following named gentlemen compose the present Board: Silas A. Holcomb, Chairman, Henry Gerdes and Howard Kennedy. These are wide awake business men, who are looking aftei the interests of the Institutions in a commendable manner. I herewith append a short biography of each institution together with the movement of the population of each, which will give a good idea of them, and the work ac - complished : PENITENTIARY, LANCASTER, NEBRASKA. W. T. Fenton, Warden. This Institution was provided for by an act of the Legis - lature in 1867. Here the state owns 296 acres of land; seven of which are within the prison walls. At the be - ginning of the biennium there were 381 prisoners and at its close 365. The number of prisoners on hand would have been nearly twice what it is at the close of the biennium but for the Indeterminate Sentence Law, and the Action of the State Prison Board, who have granted paroles and </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD placed out a large number of young men and first termers, some of them mere boys of 18, 19 or 20 years. Two boys of the age of 17, who should never have been sent to the Penitentiary have been transferred to the Industrial School A vast number of improvements have been made at the Penitentiary such as new roofr repairing roof, painting cells and woodwork of the buildings inside and outside, repairing sewer, replacing about 1000 broken window lights, grading grounds outside of the building, putting in cement walks, placing lights in front of the building, making new well, erecting large silo, and various other things — but the greatest improvement from a sanitary standpoint, was the tearing out of the twenty or more old rusty bath tubs, where disease could be transmitted from one inmate to another, and the installing of a number of shower baths to take their place, thus making a good, clean, convenient, and sanitary bath house out of a miserably poor one. I new dining room, kitchen, bakery, and hospital have erected, and they were very much needed. A new i was purchased for the kitchen, the first one that was owned at this institution. Arthur W. Richardson of Lancaster County introduced in the Legislature of 1913, House Roll No. 51, and the same was passed by both the House and Senate and was approved by the Governor on April 1, 1913, with the emergency This Bill makes it a Felony to give cocaine, morphine, opium, or intoxicating liquor, or any firearms, explosives or weapons of any kind or assist in procuring the same to be done, to any convict, prisoner, or inmate of any peniten - tiary, reformatory, jail or asylum, and provides a penalty for its violation of one to five years in the Penitentiary. Karden W. T. Fenton and his Deputy, N. T. Harmon, ce decided that that law should be enforced, and </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 11 through their diligence and watchfulness, have effectually eradicated the Dope habit among the prisoners. My pre - decessor said in his report two years ago: "A discharged prisoner said to me": "When you seal up your prisons so tight that neither light or air can enter you will keep out dope." This is not true. From my own observations, and from conversation with prisoners who were addicted to the habit, and with others who never have used dope, I am satisfied that there is not now one bit of dope used in the Institution, and even the looks of the men will verify that statement. Eie old dining room has been remodelled, cleaned and sd, and is to be provided with seats, the same to be as a school room for Night School. The attendance s School is not compulsory, but last winter there were risoners (pupils) enrolled and the work was very satis - fy. Many reforms have been adopted by the present Warden, among them are: yard privileges for two hours Sunday mornings, when the men are allowed to associate and con - verse with each other. Base ball is played every evening during the summer, commencing at six o'clock, after the men have performed their tasks and have had supper. Ninety games were played during the last summer, outside the walls, at which groups of seventy five to one hundred twenty five of the inmates were permitted to attend. A good Band and Orchestra are maintained, the Orchestra furnishing music in the new dining hall during the meal hour, and the prisoners are now allowed to converse while eating. Those privileges are thoroughly enjoyed by the inmates. Eie Contract Labor System having been abolished, it question what to do with the men. Idleness is not icive to reform. A goodly number could be employed id making if the Legislature would make suitable laws eby it could be done. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD The Warden worked from twenty-five to forty men on the land the state now owns at this institution during the last year. If another half section of land were added to this, many more could be employed and thus help to support the Institution, besides educating the young men in one of the best vocations in life, that of farming and stock raising. BOYS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA. In 1879 the Nebraska State Legislature established this school under the name of State Reform School, admitting both boys and girls. The name was later changed to State Industrial School for Boys. In 1891 the Girls' Industrial School was established in Geneva, since that year boys only have been received in the Kearney State Industrial School. Erhe first building was completed in 1881 and the first ite was received on July 15th of the same year. Now Institution is composed of seven large buildings besides is, sheds, etc., with a total enrollment of 203 boys. At the commencement of the present biennium, De - cember 1, 1912, there was 173 boys enrolled — 183 boys have been committed to the institution, while 65 boys, for - merly inmates, have been returned. During the biennium seven have been discharged and 211 paroled. The enroll - ment of 203 at this time is an increase of 30 over the enrollment two years previous. This increase is accounted for not by the fact that the boys of our state have become more incorrigible or delinquent, but because of the strict care the present management has taken to prevent escapes, and in refusing to parole boys until they have thoroughly earned their liberty by strict conformity to the rules of During the biennium the schools have become more efficient because of a more careful grading of the system. R. V. Clark, Sup't. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 13 B:rease in the number of teachers, also because higher hes have been taught, permitting the boys to enjoy ucation up to and including, in part, the tenth grade. Etfany repairs and improvements have been made, such earranging and refurnishing the offices, the removing Id wainscoating and old plastering, and replastering i hard finish, and painting the interior of the shop ling throughout, besides various improvements in the irent Company buildings. The exterior of all the build - has been painted white, giving the institution a clean, orm appearance. tne boys are trained not only in school work but in us trades, such as laundering, carpentering, tailoring, ing, and farming. The discipline of the school has strengthened and the possibility of escape has been led by the introduction into each and every dormitory night watch who insists upon order and prevents es - during the night. Other than the school and the trades, 44 of the boys enjoy first class musical privileges in the large band of 44 pieces, orchestra of 20 pieces, and the boys' choir. The Superintendent has been pleased to arrange for the boys a gymnasium equipped with trapeze, rings and basket ball goals. The boys have been immensely pleased by the in - troduction, by Superintendent Clark, of a modern and up - to-date moving picture machine, which has, with the aid of films procured once a week from Omaha, furnished much enjoyment throughout the two years. Eie needs of the institution may be summed up as rs : A Hospital, where boys with contagious diseases be cared for without jeopardizing the lives of other ution boys ; a large and better equipped gymnasium ; r and modern chapel ; also a modern ice house. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA, NEBR. Miss Lyda J. McMahon, Sup't. Until 1891 the deliquent and dependent boys and girls of Nebraska were cared for in one Institution at Kearney, but by a wise act of the Legislature this School was established and the small population of girls transferred from Kearney to Geneva. Two divisions comprised the classification, until 1912; now there is a better denned clueifica- E.nd segregation according to character has been secur - the addition of another class, or "Family" as they ait 1. In this division are placed the girls of excellent re - who are free from infection and are perfectly normal in every respect. The work is now handled to much better advantage ; all r girls in the Institution are afforded every opportunity education, domestic training, music and general up - building of character. The new building will soon be ready for occupancy and this will relieve the much congested condition. At the beginning of the biennium there were: INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA. Miss Lena E. Ward, Sup't. This Home was opened by the state to unfortunate girls in May 1889. Since that time nine hundred seventy-seven girls have been cared for. There are no charges made for the care of the girls, but each girl must help with the work of the Home to pay for her care. The object of the State in supporting the Home is two- fo. inmates present 86 Ibj received since 60 \o. returned from parole 21 \o. paroled — discharged 68 'otal present to date 99 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 15 this care, and to train her so that she may be able to again take her place in the world and lead a good, clean life. It also offers a home to the girl who has never gone wrong, but who, for lack of proper training is in danger. At the beginning of this biennium there were seventy - ix in the Home. One hundred eighty have been received ince; one hundred fifty-three have been discharged; nine - een paroled; nineteen died.. Number in the Home at the lose of the biennium sixty-five. ySome improvements and repairs should be made — A y barn and an outside cellar and root house should be rided. The buildings need painting inside and outside, /ell as a number of other repairs. HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN. Miss Etta Caton, Agent. This is really the successor to the Home for the Friend - less and the State Public School for Dependent Children. The Home for the Friendless was incorporated in 1876 but the first assistance given it by the Legislature was in 1881. In 1909 the name was changed to the State Public School for Dependent Children. In 1911 the name was again changed by the Legislature to the for Dependent Children". In April 1911 this institution was moved from the old "Home for the Friendles: " at 10th and South Streets, to the private residence property at 944 H Street. !rhis was an old house, entirely unfitted for the needs tie Home, in poor repair, and was hard to heat. It was ed for two years at a rental of $50 per month, the e to make necessary repairs. The house was wired at e expense, several of the room were papered, and a it deal of other repairing done. In January, 1914, the tion was again changed to 1425 F Street, the present ress. This is also a residence property, and although ood condition, is just as unsuited for the needs of the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Home as the other house. It was leased for two years at a rental of $65 per month. The plan of boarding the children in family homes and Eng for their board and care until permanent free homes secured, is still carried on, but after a trial of this tod for a period of five years it has not proven satis- As ninety per cent of the children received by the Home are defective at the time received, either physically or moral - ly they could receive much better care and treatment for their afflictions in an institution than they can in the aver - age family home. As soon as a child is in a normal condition, it is not difficult to place it in a free home, therefore I think it would be a wise move if this work be again placed in an institution, built and equipped for the purpose of caring for the dependent children who are in need of in - stitutional care. This method of caring for the children would not cost the state any more than under the present plan, and would be much better for the children. On Nov. 30, 1912, the number of children being cared for No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 222 ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL. Dr. H. Winnett Orr, Sup't. Ehe Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital was established by al enactment of the Legislature of 1905. Oct. 1, 1905, irst patients were received, after extensive alterations been made in a portion of one of the buildings at the e for the Friendless. Officers were selected and rules ibb No. since received 200 LNo. placed out under adoption 56 No. discharged on account of maturity or otherwise 80 No. who have died 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 17 made for the conduct of the institution by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. This Board, with Hon. H. M. Eaton as Chairman, had entire charge of all the affairs of the institution by special provision of the law creating it. Er. John P. Lord of Omaha was made Superintendent ]hief Surgeon — and continued in this office until 1911, which time he has been Chief Surgeon only. Dr. H. ett Orr of Lincoln was made Assistant Surgeon, but 11 he was made Superintendent. Ei 1911 the entire plant formerly occupied by the Home 'riendless was turned over to the Orthopedic Hospital the number of patients rose rapidly to 100. Since time the number of patients has averaged over 100 for ntire three years. EMI of the buildings have been partly or wholly re - elled to adapt them for Hospital purposes. While there still changes and improvements necessary, the plant i better condition than ever before. S)uring the past few years, the following important im - ements have been made. A modern automatic elevator been put in the Hospital building. A circular fire escape been built and other equipment installed for fire pro - on. A reinforced concrete underground passageway been built connecting the Hospital and Main buildings, enables patients and employees to go from one build - to another fully protected in all kinds of weather. In tuch as they are obliged to serve meals and have school cises in both buildings this is of very great service. Knew laundry building has been built and additional ment purchased so that they now have an efficient and jly satisfactory plant. Above the laundry an assembly room was provided which communicates by a passageway with the hospital building. This had long been needed and now gives an </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 assembly room accessible to all patients for school and re - creation purposes. Sleeping porches have been built to the south of the Main building for the use of nurses and em- Dloyees. These are entirely modern and very useful. July 1, 1913, the institution came under the administra - tion of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. In June 1914, this Board let the contract for a fine new modern Hospital building. This building is now nearing completion and when finished will add about fifty beds, increasing our capacity to 150 patients. The new building will give us not only one of the finest hospital buildings in the State but one of the largest strictly Orthopedic Hospitals in the United States. The great interest in this work manifested by the State Officers, members of the Legislature, members of the medical profession and even by the people at large, has been in large measure responsible for the rapid development and progress of the institution. In return, the Hospital can point to a record of nearly 1,000 patients treated ; from 60 to 80 per cent of whom have been either entirely cured or materially improved by the care afforded. Elt is hoped that the generous support both moral and ancial already accorded the Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital 11 be continued to assist in its further usefulness. there were 100 persons ;it this institution Nov. 30, 1912, dnce that time 590 were received. 279 were discharged ared; 258 discharged as benefited; 30 discharged as mproved and 16 have died, leaving 107 at the institu - on Nov. 30, 1914. HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN. Dr. B. F. Williams, Sup't. Kie first building at the Nebraska Hospital for the e was erected in 1870, and on the 26th day of November it year the first patient was received. An act of the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Legislature of 1905 established the narcotic ward for the treatment of inebriety and persons addicted to narcotic drugs. The commitment for same was provided in much the same manner as the insane, a maximum time limit of three years placed upon commitment. The legislature of 1910 appropriated means to construct two new buildings. The buildings were completed, but no appropriation was made for furnishing same. The result was that the institution became badly crowded before the Legislature of 1912 appropriated money to furnish these buildings. The buildings were furnished in May. 1913. The institution was so crowded at that time, and so many patients were held in custody, in local hospitals and county jails that the buildings filled up almost immediately. At the close of the biennal period ending Nov. 30, 1914, the in - stitution is said to be even more crowded than at the time the appropriation was made in 1 910. I 'here were 610 patients at the Hospital Nov. 30, 1912. ng the biennium there have been received 741 patients; of whom were insane and 327 dipsomaniacs. 508 snts were discharged; 179 of whom were insane and were dipsomaniacs. There were 119 deaths during the &gt;d. 115 were insane and 4 dipsomaniacs. Of those re - &gt;d there were 50 drug habitues, some of whom used )hine and some used cocaine and morphine. There was tal under treatment for the biennial period of 1351 mts. Number of patients enrolled Nov. 30, 1914 — 724. The Legislature of 1912 voted $75,000 for the con - struction of a new building for Industrial pursuits and re - modeling of outside departments. Of this appropriation a contract was let for constructing a new industrial building and amusement hall. This contract was let at the figure of $32,500. This building is devoted to sewing room, where articles of clothing are manufactured for the institution, an art room where patients are thaught industrial pursuits, a </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 storage room for the preservation of supplies, a drug room and laboratory. In the sub-basement are located nine em - ployees' rooms, and the wood work and carpenter shop where furniture is repaired, shoes repaired and some sup - plies for the institution are manufactured. The top floor is used for an amusement hall ; moving pictures are ex - hibited, weekly dances are held for the patients with an occasional lecture together with chapel services each Sun- The laundry of the institution was completely remodeled and new machinery installed. The engine room was en - larged, new boiler installed, a new dynamo and a new roof on the building. A new bake shop was built and completely equipped. Cement side walks were installed and new cattle shed built at the west farm. A new slaughter house con - structed and a large vegetable cave with drying room and incubator house combined. The improvements in out departments have been of per - manent nature and will serve the institution for many years HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK, NEBR. Dr. W. D. Guttery, Superintendent. Eis institution was provided for by the Legislature of The State owns at this place 320 acres of land, but small portion of it is good agricultural land. At least res of GOOD farm land should be added to this. The new building which was provided for by the Legis - lature, at its last session is now being erected, and will when completed provide for at least seventy five additional patients. A large amount of permanent improvements and repairs has been done during the biennium such as cleaning up and grading the grounds in the rear of the buildings, repairing roofs, painting wood work, repairing plastering, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The disused ice house has been raised and a new foun - dation placed under it, a cement floor and ceiling put in, divided into two stories and otherwise repaired so as to convert it into an excellent carpenter and paint shop and cold storage. An addition of 62 feet has been added to the cow barn and the old barn completely overhauled and converted into a modern barn with cement floor, steel stanchions, steel pens for calves and in every way fitted up as a modern The hog yards have been moved further away so that the odor from them would not reach the sick ward. The grounds back of the ladies Hospital building which were allowed to grow up to weeds and were strewn with dis - carded boilers, cinders, and other refuse have all been cleaned away, the ground graded up and parked and a small orchard planted. This has greatly improved the view from this building. There has also been constructed about 16,500 feet of cement walk, and floors, in various parts of the grounds, and many minor repairs and improvements too n umerous to mention, all of which adds to the appearance as well as increasing the value of the premises. There were at this institution Nov. 30, 1912, 408 patients, since received 225. Returned from parole 5. Now out on parole 23 -Total 661. Number discharged 109. Transferred to other institutions 2. Died 66. Committed suicide on parole 4 — Now out on parole 23. Number now at Hos - pital 457. NEBRASKA STATE HOSPITAL, INGLESIDE. Dr. M. W. Baxter, Superintendent. During the Legislature of 1887 an appropriation was made for the purpose of building a hospital to take care of the insane. The location selected was two and one-half mi Ips wpst o"f H^ fist in its This fouildincr w&amp;s com Dieted Jinci </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD ready for occupancy in 1889, and was known as the Asylum for chronic Insane. This name being somewhat misleading, in addition to being obnoxious generally, was changed by an act during a session of the Legislature of 1906, and it was re-christened so that at the present time it is known as the Nebraska State Hospital, Ingleside, Nebr., this being its post office address, and not Hastings, as many still persist in directing their mail, thus causing unnecessary delay in all correspondence. An enormous amount of general repair work has been undertaken and completed, consisting of plastering, repaint - ing and decorating, the plumbing and heating system has been overhauled and also the power plant has received at - tention. For the benefit of the patients who care to take advantage of it, a lounging room has been provided where they are permitted to smoke, read the newspapers, play cards, checkers, etc. Special attention has been given to improve sanitary conditions. Unfortunately a part of the herd of dairy cows, after examination and testing on two separate occasions by State Veterinarian, Dr. Kigin, were found to be affected with tuberculosis. The number so found amounting in all to eighty animals. These were shipped to Omaha and killed under the inspection and supervision of the Board, the Steward, Mr. O'Meara, and State Veterinarian, Dr. Kigin. To protect the remaining healthy cows, and feeling reasonably sure that the old barn was the cause of infec - tion, it was decided to build a new, modern dairy barn. The dimensions of the barn are as follows: 34x136, having a capacity of seventy cows with hay loft above for 250 tons of hay. The W. D. James steel stanchions were selected and installed. The King system of ventilation was adopted thus all foul air is carried off through properly constructed ventilating flues. The floors are of concrete excepting that part upon which the cows stand, this being of pressed cork brick, as concrete is considered too hard and cold for the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 23 cows to either stand or lie upon. • The walls are steel lathed and plastered. It is also equipped with hot and cold water and electric lights through - out the entire building. A detached sterilizing room has also been provided for the purpose of properly sterilizing all untensils used in the handling of milk. With but little exception, the entire work has been accomplished by the ♦ regular force of workmen under the inspection of the Steward, M. O'Meara, and the Board, to whom great credit is due for providing a barn which has been pronounced, by competent judges, as one of the most modem and sanitary dairy barns in the state. The cost was a little less than $6,000, a very moderate amount taking into consideration the splendid addition to tl&gt;e institution and the state. Ehere has been an abundance of all kinds of vegetables d on the farm during the year. This has enabled the rintendent to change the diet from day to day which been greatly appreciated, and is also beneficial to the Numerous and varied amusements have been provided for, consisting of music, dancing, moving pictures, base ball, etc. These amusements are undoubtedly a welcome re - creation, and assist to relieve the monotony of hospital life, in addition to being considered by all authorities as a great factor in the treatment of nervous and mental diseases. In addition to these amusements there is always provided some special entertainment and amusement on all our na - tional holidays. Religious services are conducted every Sunday after - noon, presided over by one of the ministers of the respective denominations of Hastings, in turn. The music is provided by the orchestra of the institution, and singing conducted by the officers and attendants, assisted by all those patients who care to do so. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 MOVEMENT OF POPULATION: Nov. 30, 1912, there were 1071 patients in the institu - tion. Received during the biennial period 399 — Returned from parole 299 — making a total number of patients cared for during the biennium of 1769. There were paroled 287 — Discharged 183 — Deaths 172 — leaving at the institution Nov. 30, 1914, 1127 patients. The general health of the patients may be considered very satisfactory. Fortunately, the institution has escaped any serious epidemic. The death rate, 6 1-3 per cent, is low when we consider that many people are taking ad - vantage of the improved conditions of state institutions, looking upon them as a haven of rest rather than as an asylum, and are sending many senile and infirm cases which in former days would have been kept at home. This con - dition must necessarily decrease the number of cures, and increase the number of deaths. KBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent. Following an act passed by the Legislature in the session of 1885, the first building of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth was soon there-after commenced, and on May 27, 1887, the first children were received into the institution. During the first year after the opening of the Institution about 60 children were received. Within a short time more room was needed to shelter and care for the mentally defective children of the State, and from time to time more land and buildings have been added until at the present time the farm comprises 220 acres, and there are eight large brick and stone buildings used for the purpose of caring for the children. These buildings are exclusive of the store-rooms, laundry, boiler house, barns, etc. The Superintendent is able, with his corps of teachers to do much in the way of mental training for the class of </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 25 children sent to him. About half of the children are able to learn to read and write. The teachers also instruct in the various industrial avocations ; for the boys, bra?h mak ing, painting, carpenter work, plumbing, etc. ; for the girlr needle work, crocheting, basketry, weaving, house wo-k, etc With adequate facilities in way of room much more could be accomplished in an educational way. The assembly meetings, religious services and amusements are held in the day room of one of the cottages. The school rooms were originally built for dormitories. With the present arrange - ments in these rooms only half of the children who are able and who should attend school, church services and general assembly meetings, can be accommodated. The health of the colony during the past biennium has been uniformly good. Early in the period there was a threatened typhoid outbreak, several cases occurring among inmates and employees. This was an aftermath of an epidemic during the former biennium, and was soon gotten under control. During the past year no true cases of typhoid have appeared. This is considered to be due to the fact that the Superintendent has guarded carefully the pos - sibility of any of the food stuffs becoming contaminated with" the ice supply. The management has also improved the plumbing where defective and has also vaccinated against typhoid, every inmate and every employee at the Institu - tion, and with new inmates and new employees this plan is followed. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION No. of inmates enrolled, Nov. 30, 1914 495 No. of inmates present, Nov. 30, 1914 470 o. of inmates, Nov. 30, 1912 42$ o. received during biennium 161 o. discharged during the biennium . . 5i o. died 4? io. on vacation 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, OMAHA. Prof. Frank W. Booth, Sup't. Eis institute was provided by the Legislature of 1869. ? the first school year 12 pupils were enrolled; the sr of all those who have attended this school is at date 906. At the beginning of this biennium there were 168 pupils in attendance, of whom 87 are being taught orally and 81 by means of silent methods. The school is now in process of change whereby more of the children are taught to speak and lip-read as from year to year the older manually taught pupils are graduated to be replaced by younger orally taught children. A new primary building was provided for by the last legislature, and this when completed will be used for housing the new incoming children, thus effectually segregating Bfrom the older pupils and making possible the giving em of a speaking and lip-reading environment out of il in place of an environment now almost wholly of The school has an industrial department in which cabinet making, wood-carving, clay-modeling, printing, and gardening are taught to the boys, and sewing, dressmaking, embroidery, domestic science, basketry, wood-carving, clay - modeling, and laundrying are taught to the girls. Trained and skilled instructors are employed in all departments of the school, it being recognized that the school can be ex - cellent only to the degree that its teachers are thus thoroughly trained and skilled in the difficult work they are called upon to accomplish. The school term extends from September to June, and the course of study requires twelve years for its comple - tion, the pupils taking up in the final years American and English History, Physiology, Physics, Civil Government, Arithmetic, Algebra, Grammar, and English Literature. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 27 The school is free to all children residents of Nebraska too deaf to attend the public schools, no charge being made for board or tuition. rSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY. Prof. N. C. Abbott, Superintendent. I his school was provided for in 1875 and was first ed in a rented room on March 10th of that year, with ; pupils, but now is equipped with large modern build - and has an enrollment of 51 pupils. The official name is "Institute for the Blind" and this name I am sure stands in the way oi securing many boys and girls that ought to be enrolled. The Superintendent thinks the name should be "School for Blind and Defective - sighted". As the name now stands, people get the im - pression that only those totally blind will be admitted, but this is far from the truth. Those whose sight is so de - fective that they cannot secure an education in the common schools are gladly received. About two-thirds of the pupils at this school have partial use of their eyes. Out of the total number of new pupils admitted during this biennium only four were totally blind. I here is little red tape to be unwound before a boy or s admitted. Teachers, Ministers, and others in public :ities who learn of children with eyesight so defective they cannot successfully prosecute the studies of the ion schools would confer a benefit if they would send lames of such children directly to the Superintendent, will return a blank form and as soon as this form has o. of students at the school Nov. 30, 1912 162 b. since received 61 b. graduated 16 b. left for various reasons 37 b. died 2 b. at School Nov. 30, 1914 168 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD been filled out and passed upon by the management of the institution the pupil will be admitted. At least eighty to one hundred pupils can be easily taken care of. Some children who are not attending this school, though they should be, are kept at home by the natural fear of their parents lest some harm befall their offspring. This is natural, but unreasonable when all of the conditions and surroundings of the school are taken into account. Prac - tically all of the time of the children is spent under one roof. Trained teachers and employees are ever on their guard — a night watch makes hourly inspection of. the build - ing, looking into each room where the little children sleep. There is also a trained Supervisor on the boys' side and another on the girls' side to watch for any indisposition ; so parents may have no fear that their children are ne - glected or that any harm may come to them. rThe School has a course of study that embraces as nearly the peculiar conditions will admit, the same subjects as are taught in the Common Schools. For the elementary grades the same course of study is followed as that pre - scribed by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction, with such adaptations as are necessary — Arithmetic, Lan - guage, Grammar, Physiology and Hygiene, Reading, Spel - ling, U. S. History, Writing and Nature Study. In addition to this, the girls are. taught needlework, the making of bead articles, knitting, crocheting, and cooking. As special work for the boys fitting them to make a living in the world after they leave school, they are taught chair - caning, the making of hammocks, flynets, brooms, carpet weaving and piano tuning. Khere were 52 pupils at this institution Nov. 30, 1912, \0 received during the biennium. Five graduated, one discharged and twenty five discontinued, leaving 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 29 tDIERS AND SAILORS HOME, GRAND ISLAND. Ferdinand Zim merer. Commandant. The Home was established in 1887. The state owns at this place 640 acres of land. The sanitary conditions are very much improved, the painting of the West Hospital Building has greatly added to the appearance as well as the healthfulness of the surroundings. The people at the Soldiers' Homes are mostly Soldiers of the Civil War (1861—1865) together with the wives and widows of such Soldiers, and are now on the shady side of life, and as a consequence the death rate is large— 97 having died during the last two years. It is gratifying to know that our State has provided such good homes for our dis - abled Soldiers as are now found at Grand Island and Milford. E; this home there were 535 enrolled on December 1, -Number since received 235. Of this number 109 have discharged, 97 have died, and 74 are now out on igh, leaving at the home on November 30, 1914 — 490. SOLDIERS AND SAILORS HOME, MILFORD. D. C. Rowden. Commandant. I 'his Institution was established in 1895 as a branch of lome at Grand Island. Here at Milford the state owns cres of land, with the Blue River running through it, its banks are well skirted with timber. I am pleased ly that at the present time harmony seems to prevail le Home, which is important for the welfare of the tution. §new Hospital Building is now being erected at a cost 1,000.00, which is a fireproof building and will provide for about 60 patients. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Male Female Total No. of members Dec. 1, 1912 135 11 14G No. since received 73 8 81 No. discharged or died 82 2 84 No. at the Home Nov. 30, 1914 126 17 143 TUBERCULOSIS HOSPITAL, KEARNEY NEBR. Dr. E. R. Van der Slice, Sup't. This Hospital was provided for by an act of the Legis - lature in 1911, and the present site was selected by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. It is situated a short distance west of the city of Kearney. The site contains about fifteen acres of land, upon which there is a large sandstone building, which was originally built for a residence, but which was afterwards used as a private hospital. Since purchasing it there has been erected a modern hospital building, with large sleeping porches. The patients sleep out on these porches the year around, canvas curtains having been put up for use in stormy On Dec. 1, 1912, there was thirteen patients at this Hospital, 159 have since been received, 118 have been dis - charged and 29 have died, leaving the number now enrolled </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Cvement of the Population of the various State Institutions INSTITUTIONS l.8 |s 1M1 li 1 d a I! 5 J S S ~ be »; &gt; 5S -2^ I" "^ 1 JH _5 _z 864 499 365 K Penitentiary I 381 48J Industrial School, Kearney . . 173 24f Industrial School, Geneva ... 86 8] )tal for Industrial Schools ... 259 32! 483 248 81 329 421 218 203 167 68 99 588 286 302 — Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 76 18( 180 256 191 65 B Hospital for Insane, Lincoln . 610 743 al for Insane, Norfolk 408 251 ska State Hospital, Ingleside 1071 69! jtal in Hospitals for Insane 2089 169! -4— 741 253 698 1692 nmz: 1351 627 724 661 204 457 1769 642 1127 3781 1473 2308 ~~i 1 Home for Dependent Children ... 166 I 20( 200 366 144 222 _1_ | Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 100 59&lt; 590 690 583 I 107 . Bs' and Sailors' Home, MiHord 146 8: rs &amp; Sailors' Home, Grand Isl 535 231 otal in Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home 681 311 81 235 227 84 143 770 280 490 316 997 364 633 "I i Pute for Feeble Minded outh, Beatrice 429 16: 161 590 120 470 Nebraska School for Deaf, Omaha 162 6: 61 223 I 55 168 Nebr. School for Blind, Nebr. City . 52 3&lt; 30 82 31 51 "I ™^^~^^~ 159 Tuberculosis Hospital, Kearney, . 13 172 147 25 l I Total for all Institutions . . . . ■I 4»ns 4201 I 8609 389P. 4716 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 The following is compiled from i the County Clerks relative to the care counties for one year: the &gt;of reports received from the poor in the various i- of "2 5 &amp;~ It County J3-= jj £ .§ e 3 V o* X Remarks fc * 3 £ l £ "•§ *» °&lt; 2-s;i5 •— ■c p5 o 000 ■ Adams I 9 6 $1,350 Farm self supporting Antelope .... N F |NR Arthur X F X R loo 100 Banner N F 1 23 25 Blaine |NP| X R Boone 0 0 15 I 1073 I 1073 Pay $3.75 per week for each inmate. Box Butte ... 1 1 I 50 I 1500 ' 1500 Boyd NF X R Brown N F X R Buffalo E 4 90 I 3200 1 4200 Burt IN R Butler 6 6 X R 495 1395 Cass 19 U X R 1500 2520 Cedar I 10 1 6 : 29 1155 1935 Chase N F 8 1 150 tM N F I N R ne .... X F 11 1198 1198 Clay 7 X R 10 1200 j 1200 Farm self supporting Colfax 6 6 3 ' X R TM Cumins 7 7 10 960 1960 Farm self support ins Pay $4 per week. Cusler 15 ! 15 0 540 Dakota ' 6 X R 1260 Dawes I 5 X R 7 j X R 960 Pays i'S per week each in Dawson 1 i 55 2000 2720 mate Deuel ' X F ' NR XR Dixon X R X R X R X R DodKe 12 12 X R 2500' 3400 Douglas 1386 ! 268 '51000 52,000 Dundy INF 4 100 ! 100 Fillmore 10 10 ' 720 100 i Fillmore 10 m Franklin 7 7 1 980 1780 Pays $3.50 per week Frontier ' N F '■ 4 | 400 400 Furnas 6 2 X R : 473 ! 1073 Ga*e ! 16 I 16 r 40 6556 7576 Garden N F ' X R Garfield ' X F X R Gosper I X F 12 [ 44 ' 144 Grant 'X F 1 1 120 I 120 Greeley ' 4 j 1040 | 1040 Farm not in operation Hall : . . . 6 6 X R 1000 1780 Hamilton .... 11 11 14 X R 1200 Harla-B fN F Cared for by townships IX F' Hayes 1 N P Hitchcock .... N F 8 | 240 X R 240 Cared for by townships Holt IN F Hooker | N F ' IT. 300 ' 300 Howard 1 ' X R 11 1400 ' 1948 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 tThe following is compiled from the reports received from e County Clerks relative to the rare of the poor in the various unties for one year. 9 _ T c Name of y 2 « ~ 1 1 § * T. c Name of y „ * C o ! o .£ o. bounty || *g |2 || g g ■ "S ■ &gt; ■ 2 ts S — \i y I y e? zl County 53 fc 2 .c - fe ? 5 - Remarks « o 6 o d £ Z2 'Z Johnson E 5 12 N K N I Johnson 15 5 11 \ R N R Pays $2 50 per week each Jefferson j 16 j 6 j 15 2140,286 Jefferson I 16 I 6 I 15 l'14U 2860 inmate Kearney M F j Kearney N F Cared for by townships Keith ; 1 j N R 50 j 5 Keith ; 1 i N R ; 50 50 Pays $10 per month each 200 inmate. Kimball , N F | N R j 200 \ 20 Kimball ■ N F N R i 200 Keya Faha . . . X F 2 12 21 Keya Paha . . . N F 2 \z •' 212 Pays |4 per week Knox N F; NR 2400 24n Knox N F i N R I 2400 24IW Lancaster ... 21 21 N R 1571 tti Lancaster ... 21 21 \ N R 1571 2351 Lincoln N F IN Lincoln N V N R 12H Losan | N F 1 1M U Logan | N K 1 120 Loup X F ! N ladison I INK MOO &lt;M IcPherson . . N F N Loup N F N R Madison 12 2 N R 4300 4900 McPherson . . N F N R Merrick I 3 6( Merrick 607 Pays $4 per week each in- Morrill N F N N R Morrill N F mate. Neniaha 12 9 X R (00 Nemaha 12 9 X R i 600 | 10' 1075 Supt. has use of farm Nuckolls :: 2 j X R MOO 10( Nuckolls :: 2 IN R lnno 1000 Pays $3 per week each in- Nance X F N N R Nance N F mate Otoe 18 | 18 j ,84 Otoe ! 18 I 18 840 Farm self supporting Pawnee N F ! N Pawnee N F X R 90 Perkins 1 j 90 | 'helps X F N Perkins I 1 90 Phelps H F N R Pierce I 2 ' N Pierce 9. I 2 N R Pays $3 per week each in- Platte I I j IS | 1000 1 171 Platte &lt; 8 I 8 I 12 ' 1000 1720 mate. Polk 4 X R J olk 4 X R N X R Pays $3.50 per week each Richardson . . M 10 10 ; 1000 22( Richardson . . 20 10 10 1000 2200 inmate. Red Willow . . X R 7! Red Willow . . N K 780 Just building house. Rods X F 2 360 : 3&lt; 360 Pays $3 per week Saline M it 5 540 l.V arpy I 2 20 3*13 Ml Saline 10 it 5 500 1500 Sarpy I 2 20 3*11 •&gt; 013 Pays $3 per week Saunders 18 IS 8 3000 Saunders 18 IS 8 MM "V. cons Bluff . . X F X eward 9 I 112 1500 Hi heridan .... X F 4 1000 10( herman X F ioux X F 2 130 U 3720 Scotts Bluff . . N F N R Seward 9 I 112 1500 2040 Sheridan .... X F 4 lOf.O 1( Pays $2.50 per week Cared for by townships Sherman N F 130 Stanton 6 fi X R 154 1W Pays $3.25 per week ea&lt; '■ 720 inmate. Thayer :'. 1 Thomas X F N R Thurston ] X F X R 1600 1600 Valley 'N F X R Washington . . 5 4 10 X R X R Pays 13.50 per week each Wavne 2 ! 1 21 11235 1235 inmate 600 Webster 2 X R Wheeler X F 1 4M 450 York • 6 6 1450 Total . . . 1730 540 599 108,130 N. F.— Xo Farm X R Xo Report 138.200 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD The following shows the report received from the various Ke.». relative to the • .Jsiils for one jrea number of prisoners in the various ;ir. ■J. •/. 3 31 b, '■ ■ m County • . County M 5 -Si * s = s - |Yes 51 2 1 2 Howard"! Yes 0 9 I Adams iYesI 51 •' Howard Yes Antelope jYesj 11' 0 Antelope Yes 12 U i 2 Jefferson Yes :\l I | Jefferson Yes ",4 4 :t Arthur No 0 0| 0 Johnson Yes 11 I :: Arthur No 0 1 0 0 IJohnson Yes 11 ii Banner |Yes 10 0 Kearney Yes 7 9 | Banner I Yes I II 0 0 Kearney Yes Blaine Yes 0 0 0 Keith Yes 5 | n niaine Yes! 0 0 0 Keith yea Boone Yes I 0| 0 Keya Paha .... Yes g 0 2 Boone Yes 6 0 0 Keya Paha Yes S 0 Box Butte Yes IS 0 L' Kinil.all Yes 2 a I Box Butte Yes IS ii Boyd :Yesj 6 0 0 Knox Y. s 6 Boyd :Yes 6 U Brown Yes; 9 10 Lancaster Yes ."ill 1 4s Is Brown Yes; I 1 0 Lancaster Yes; ."ill 1 4^ Is Buffalo Yes IS 0 8 Lincoln Y.-s 362 7 Buffalo Yes 15 0 •;-. 8 Lincoln Yes 362 7 •&gt; ;;., .- Burt |Yes M 1 0 Logan Yes 3 1 I Burt Yes U 1 it Lo^an Yes S 1 II Butler Yes: 2 0 0 Loun Yes 3 -' 0 Loup Yes 3 0 ! ' Cass Yes lnu •&gt; 10 jMadison Yes s 8 0 Cedar Yes I n ■&gt; 0 McPherson Yes 1 6 • Chase !Yes[ (I it « Merrick Yes 2« 1 Cherry Yes 1 0 Morrill Yes 13 1 Cheyenne Yd 10 Nance Yes 3 0 1 o a Clay Yes 4 1 0 0 Nemaha ...NKYes Colfax Yes! In n » Nuckolls Yes ti 0 0 Cumins Yes| 31 •' lOtoe Yes 73 2 I •&gt; ■ Outer No 1 i 0 0 Pawnee Yes 5 4 o &gt; Dakota NR Yes 'erkins Yes n u u Dawes Yes 16 6 ■'-, L'.. Phelps Yes | 1 0 Dawson Yesl l. r , 0 0 Pierce Yes In 8 1 0 l)euel Yes 1 0 0 Platte Yes 21 1 3 Dixon Yes 2 0 i o Polk Yet s ii it Ilodee Yes 8 j 0 0 Red Willo-.v Yes 20 0 I Douglas Yes 24 44 540 50 I Richardson ....Ye- 50 ' • •&gt; Dundy 'Yes 4 1 0 1 [Rock Yes (I n n Fillmore Yes In 1 11 ' Saline Yes 1H n n Franklin Yes! 4i 0 0 I Saundrrs Yes 20 1 1 Frontier No I 0 11 Scolts I5hifr. . . . Yes 9it 1 Furnas !Yes| I! n n Reward Yes! 18 | 2 I .; - (~,a-'.- NR Yes Sheridan Yes 26 I I Garden No I 0 i rman Yei I C.arfield No 0 1 0 0 Sioux Teal 2 ! o I Gosper ;Yes| 2 6 n Stanlon NR Yes Grant lYes! 4 1 0 1 Thayer Yea 1 16 I n Greeley lYesI 6 1 1 Thomas Yes 1 9 Thn^L.rnn N'I&gt; Hall IYes| 176 8 Thnrston . . .NR Hamilton . . .NRIYesI Valley Yesl 2 n •&gt; Harlan lYesI ?2 n 11 Washington . . . Yes 1 :!5 2 0 3 •-&gt; Hayps NR Yes 1 Wayne Yes ! 5 1 1 .) Hitchcock !Yesl 3 I 0 0 Webster Yes ?,1 h Holt Tes 1 11 n 0 |W'&lt;eeler Yes ii Hooker IYes| 12 1 [York Yes 10 1 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 35 EOF SOCIETIES, INSTITUTIONS, HOMES OR COR - ATIONS SUPPORTED WHOLLY OR IN PART BY EVOLENCE. Name and Location Supervised and maintained by Special class cared for OMAHA lies, of Omaha over 6~i Old Peoples' Home Womans' Christian Asso. years of age. Entrance 2214 Wirt St House of Hope fee $300.00. Peoples Institutional Home for aged Church Voluntary contributions Salvation Army Penitent fallen women 958 N 27th St. Salvation Army Rescue Home, 3824 N 24th St. Home of the Good Voluntary contributions Sisters of Good Shepherd Fallen and wayward Women and girls Shepherd Scandinavian Y. W. C. A. Kespectabl.' young Scandinavian Y. W. C. A Home. 26th and Co - pital Ave. women Private Corporation Care for children of The Creche working niolhers. K31 Park Wilde Ave. muel Deaconess In - te. 34th and Mere Immanuel Lutheran Care and "ducation of Deaconess Association friendless children. dith Ave Can of and finding Private Corporation holm , s for nonlt . Iess and Child Saving Institute 619 So. 42nd St. neglected children. Private Corporation Find homes for home- The Neb. Childrens' Home Society less and neglected Womans' Home Missionary &lt; hi 'dren. Society of Methodist Temporary care of and Episcopal Church finding homes for orphans. Grand Lodge of Nebr. Indigent Masons and 514 Brown Blk. Mother Jewels' Home York. Nebr. Nebr. Masonic Home ■ Plattsmouth. Nebr Fellows' Home their families. Grand Lodge of Nebr. Members of I. O. O. F. Rebekahs and widowsand children of Odd Fellows York. Nebr Cares for aged and in- Tabitha Home Lutheran Synod firm $300 entrance fee. Also finds homes for 45tb and Randolph. dep. children. Lincoln. Nebr Sisters of Mercy Care of orphans and de- St. Thomas Orphanage South 27th St., pendent children. Lincoln. Nebr. Christian Orphans' Private Corporation c&amp;rc of orphans and Home destitute children Holdrege. Nebr. Lutheran Orphans' Ger. Ev. Luthern Orphan Care or orphans Home Society Home Fremont, Nebr Sisters of Mercy Indigent deserving aged St. Joseph's Home for Aged, West Point, Nebr. Sisters of Mercy Care of orphans and de- St. James Orphanage Benson. Nebr. pendent children </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 I have made some inquiry into private charities, and have visited several of those finding homes lor children, and herewith give the movement of population of those from which reports have been received : CHILD SAVING INSTITUTE 42nd Ai Jackson Sis.. Omaha, Nebraska W.M A. 1»K I!OR1&gt;. President ALMA NOLI. MANN, Office Secretar&gt; No. of children at the Institute Nov. 30. 1912 5: Since received 413 Total number given care and protection during the biennium 466 No. placed in homes under adoption during biennium 113 No. of deaths during biennium 33 No. that otherwise passed from our care 276 No. being cared for Nov. 3d, 1914 44 They accept children who are legally relinquished or committed by order of the court and find for them permanent homes. They also give temporary shelter and care to dependent children, receiving such payment as those responsible for them are able to make. OLD PEOPLES' HOME 2214 Wirt Street. Omaha, Nebraska MRS. CLARA MERRIAM, Superintendent. No. at the Home Nov. 30. 1912 _' t No. since received No. died 2 No. at the Home Nov. 30, 1914 26 1'ersons 65 years old, or over, residents of Omaha, Nebraska, are admitted by paying an entrance fee of three hundred dollars. BETHLEHEM CHILDRENS" HOME 34th St. and Meredith Ave.. Omaha, Nebraska I". M LINDBERG. Superintendent No. of persons in the Home Nov. 30, 1912 19 No. since received 4 No. discharged i No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 It; This home is maintained by the Immanuel Deaconess Institute. Contributions and free will offerings are received from individuals and from the Sunday Schools of the Nebraska Conference of the Augustana Synod. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 HOME OF THE GOOD SHEPHERD Omaha, Nebraska. SISTER M. RAPHAEL, Superintendent No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1912 17f) Since received 16 Since discharged 161 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 182 Wayward girls and those in need of protection are admitted to this Institution SALVATION ARMY RESCUE HOME 3824 North 24th St., Omaha, Nebraska ELIZ. CALDWELL, Matron No. of persons being cared for Nov. 30, 1912 34 No. since received 237 No. passed from their care 2 J No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 31 Homeless and fallen women willing to reform are given carp Money secured by donation of friends and by small fees from those who are able to pay for their care. None are refused admission whose cases are deserving LUTHERAN ORPHANAGE Fremon*. Nebraska G. W. WOLTER, Superintendent. No. of persons in the institution Nov. 30, 1912 No. since received 71 Total number given care and protection during biennium 91 No. placed in homes for adoption 41 No. placed in homes under contract 31 No. of deaths No. that otherwise passed from their care 1( No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 Orphans or dependent children are received provided they art relinquished or legally committed and are subject to adoption or arf surrendered to the Homes' care until past school age, or until legal age. Money for maintenance is secured by charitable donations of Lutheran Church Members in Nebraska. ST. JAMES ORPHANAGE Benson, Nebraska JOHN ROCHE, Superintendent No. of persons in institution Nov. 30, 1912 11. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Total number Riven care and protection during biennium r placed in homes under adoption during biennium placed in homes under contiact during biennium No. that otherwise passed from care of the orphanage 192 No. being cared for at the present time, Nov. 30, 1914 13«t Those entitled to admission are orphans, half orphans, or any destitute children. This institution is not endowed: the money neces- sary for its maintenance is secured by voluntary contributions. TABITHA HOME 46th and Randolph Sis.. Lincoln, Nebraska REV. ERNEST WALTER. Superintendent. No. at the Home Nov. 30, 1912 32 No. since received 35 No. discharged 2 No. died 12 No. at the Home Nov. 30, 1914 53 Of those now at the Home 32 are old helpless people and .1 are children. ODD FELLOWS' HOME York, Nebraska. J. H. WILSON. Superintendent. No. at Home Nov. 30, 1912 24 No. since received No. who left for any cause 5 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 65 Members of the I. O. O. F., Rebekahs, or widows of Odd Fellows and their children, who are unable to earn a livelihood are entitled to admission. NEBRASKA MASONIC HOME Plattsmouth, Nebr. No. at the Home January 1. 1913 48 No. since received 20 No. died No. who left for any cause 11 No. being cared for Nov., 30, 1914 Superannuated members of thf Masonic Fraternity, their widows and children are admitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 39 HOUSE OF HOPE 958 North 27th Avenue, Omaha, Nebraska. CHAS. W. SAVIDGE, superintendent. No. of patients Nov. 30, 1912 No. since received 61 No since discharged 36 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 11)1! Admit all deserving unfor'unaic- persons. No entrance fee re- quired, but the patients or their friends are expected to pay whatever amount they can. Whatever balance is required is secured by cash ~uiis( riptions from outsiders MOTHER JEWELS' HOME York, Nebraska BI'RWELL SPrRLOCK, Superintendent. No of children in the Home Aug. 1, 1912 64 No. since received ..: No. gone from the Home 54 No. at the Home Aug 1,191' 6:"&gt; This Home receives and cares for de-pendent children and is under the auspices of the Women's Home Missionary Society of the M. E Church, and is supported by this society and by voluntary contrihu During the Biennium this department has expended the following amount : From an unexpended balance of appropriation of 1911 and 1912 of M7J.14 For salary of Chief Clerk APPROPRIATION OF 1913 AND 1914 For Salary of Chief Clerk $3,000.6 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1914 2,375.00 Balance unexpended S2S.0O For Salary of stenographer $1 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1914 1430.00 Balance unexpended 350.00 For Office and traveling expense. Postage, Reports, Stationary. Telephone, etc $1, 250.01 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1914 843.4!) Balance unexpended 4OC.51 Respectfully submitted, J. W SHAHAN </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>