<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Board of Health BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">Nebraska State Board o! Health BULLETIN Published quarterly at the office of the Secretary of the Board. Seward, Nebraska. Entered as second class matter, February 6th. 1914. at the Postoffice, Seward, Nebraska, under the act of July 16th, 1894. VOLUME 2 Jl'LY, 1915 NO. 3 This Bulletin will be sent free to any person within the State upon request. P. F. DODSON, M. D., President. Wilber E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Vice-President, Lincoln C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., Treasurer, Fails City H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Secretary, Seward BOARD OP HEALTH JOHN H. MOREHEAD, Governor WILLIS E. REED, Atty. General. A. O. THOMAS. Supt. Pub. Instr. J. D. CASE, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln WM. F. WILD, M. D., Director Bacteriological Laboratory, Lincoln Nebraska's State appropriation for purposes of a State Board of Health, a State Bacteriological and Pathological Laboratory and for the Vital Statistics Department combined is a little over seven and one-half mills per capita. SECRETARIES </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">THE OLD AND THE NEW. Dr. P. F. Dodson has retired from the Board of Secretaries of the State Board of Health, by expiration of his term of office, and his place has been filled by Got. Morehead by the appoint - ment of Dr. Lucien Stark of Hartington, Nebr. The work of Dr. Dodson on the Board has been well and favorably known all over the State. He has given freely of his time and energies to the work and has been a booster for every activity that the Board has undertaken. We feel that onr asso - ciation with Dr. Dodson has been of great benefit and that his genial and pleasing personality and untiring energy will con - tinue to inspire us. We also feel that we will continue to have him as a supporter and a booster for good health and sanitation in Nebraska. Our new member, Dr. Stark, is a son of ex-Congressman W. L. Stark of Aurora. He was graduated at the Greighton Medical College in 1003 and has practiced here ever since. He is a mem - ber of the State and County Medical Associations and had their endorsement for the position as well as that of all the physicians in his locality. We therefore are certain that he will creditably represent the medical profession on the Board. The Doctor is an enthusiast in public health matters, young and practical, and will, we feel, bring to the work many qualities of mind and disposi - tion which will be a material assistance to us. We are glad to welcome him to a place on the Board. We have also to chronicle the departure of our former Health Inspector, W. H. Wilson, M. D., whose place is taken by J. D. Case, M. D., of Dorchester. Dr. Wilson's unflagging devotion in the cause of good health is too well known for words. Dr. Wilson has held this office for the past eight years and has given the best of satisfaction to the Board and the public in general. He has handled the difficult problems as they have presented themselves in an able and fearless manner. His ad - vice and counsel have been of the best, and it is with much re - gret that the Board parts with his services. Dr. Wilson has not only acquired a state but a national repu - tation in health matters, and we know that in the future we can expect his hearty co-operation and assistance in furthering the causes of health and sanitation in this State. He stands high in the councils of the profession of the State and we predict success for him in whatever branch of medicine he shall take up. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska State Board of Health Dr. Wilson was a pHwral practitioner for a nmiilier of yean* licfcire assuming the office of Health Ins|iector, and his exjie - rierice in that office adds gymtly to his knowledge of diseases and their prevention. From our new inspector we have reason to exjtect an unusual grade of service. Flis recommendations speak of him very highly, and we are certain that he will give of his full measure of ability to this important and highly exacting position. By Willard 8. Small, Ph.. IX Prin. Eastern High School, Washington. I). C. : "Medical inspection lias pretty fully solved the prob - lems incident to the control of communicable diseases in the schools — both infectious and parasitic In either case competent and frequent inspection is of primary im - ,M&gt;rtance. The daily ins]&gt;eetioii. by doctor or nurse, of suspected cases, referred by the teacher, must be supple - mented by a careful weekly insjtection of all pupils. This insures immediate detection of all cases of disease in the schools. Prompt disinfection of classrooms, and a sane policy of exclusion and quarantine, almost always prevent epidemic of disease. In Orange, H. •!.. where there is weekly inspection of all pupils by the school nurse, no schools have been closed on account of an epi - demic of disease in the two years during which medical ins|&gt;ection has been in force. "The function of medical insjtection is to keep pupils in school, not to turn them out. but to keep them in school without injury to others or to themselves. In the early days of medical inspection wholesale exclusion of children with vermin and parasitic skin diseases was the rule. The common practice now is to reduce exclu - sions to the minimum." The total enrollment of pupils in the State of Nebraska is 288,269. Statistics show that more than 10 per cent of this number are retarded by means of physical defects that can be removed, such as defects of sight, hearing, etc., equal to one year in seven, which makes an annual increase of teaching 4.120 pupils. The cost of education per pupil "on enrollment" isf80.ll, which amounts in round numbers per annum to fl25,000. This does not take into consideration the loss of attendance on ac - count of contagious and infectious diseases, which will amount in </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Axicual Bulletin No. 5 all probability to at least one-half of the above, which would be 162,500, making in all $187,000. This estimate is based upon the savings that is reported by other states where school inspection is carried out. By Homer H Seerley, President Iowa State Teachers' College. Cedar Falls, Iowa: "It is well known that the educated and trained tepresentatives of the people do not yet acknowledge and believe that the principles of school hygiene are worth while. Even the scholar is not necessarily a hygienist !o any remarkable extent. Intelligence and cleanliness do not necessarily go together. Regard for knowledge and regard lor health are not associated t adore in civili - zation. Consequently churches, public buildings, private homes, hotels and restaurants are generally the most flagrant violators of the simplest laws of hygiene. It is therefore very difficult to get public attention to the ne - cessities of school hygiene. The janitor does not receive the impression that a hygienic schoolhouse is required, and an indifferent public encourages him to l&gt;e careless, indolent and even unfavorable. It is possible that laws requiring suitable standards will be some benefit ; it is possible that earnest and interested teachers can be of much influence; but, after all, a higher degree of intelli - gence and of appreciation for scientific results must be brought to the consciousness of the masses of the people. Today the states are sending out expert representatives to help the masses of the people to a better kind of agri - culture, to a better success in animal industry, to the making of more wealth and prosperity in business; but when it comes to human health, human happiness physi - cally, human progress in caring for human life, but few such experts are employed and but little instruction is given." Our last legislature appropriated to the State Board of Vet - erinarians for the prevention and cure of disease among live stock $28,700 per annum, aside from laboratory, while for the State Board of Health, whose duties are to protect the health of the j»eople, it appropriated $9,480, aside from laboratory, thus continuing the opinion set forth in the above article. — Ed. Following are the rules adopted by the Board of Secre - taries in July, 1913, pertaining to the common drinking cup, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska State Board of Health 6 which have now become a law by the adoption of same by the Staii' Board of Health, consisting of the Governor, Attorney General and Superintendent of Public Instruction : "Whereas, under the provision of chapter 82, Session Laws of 1913, the Slate Board of Health is authorized to prohibit in such public places, vehicles or buildings as it may designate, the providing and use of a common drinking cup and to establish such rules and regulations for this purpose as it may deem necessary, it is therefore the sense of this Board that the following rules and regulations should be promulgated in that behalf, that is to say: Rule 1. The use of public and common drinking cups, glasses or vessels of any kind to be used in common, for the pur - pose of drinking therefrom on railroad trains (within this State! or in stations, in public or private schools, public buildings, balls, churches, theaters, markets, playgrounds, parks, stores, hotels, offices and office buildings, factories or manufacturing estab - lishments, or in any other public place whatsoever within the State of Nebraska is hereby prohibited. "Rule 2. No person, partnership or corporation in charge or control of any railroad train or station, or public or private school, public building, hall, church or theater, market, play - ground, park, store, hotel, office or office building, factory or manufacturing establishment shall furnish, provide, place or ex - pose, or allow to be furnished, provided, placed or exposed, any cup. glass or other drinking vessel, at any place where the pub - lic or more than one particular individual may or can have access to, or the use of such vessel, or where such vessel can or may be used in common by the public or more than one particu - lar individual, on any railroad train (within this State) or in any station, or public or private school, public building, hall, church, theater, market, playground, park, store, hotel, office and office building, factory or manufacturing establishment, or at any other place whatsoever under his or its control in said state. "Rule 3. The owner, lessee or person in charge of any hotel, saloon, restaurant, drug store, soda fountain, or any place of public refreshment shall furnish glasses, cups or other drinking vessels used in said hotel, saloon, restaurant, drug-store, soda fountain, or other place of public refreshment, to be thoroughly cleaned after use bv each and every customer." </seg>
            <seg id="p007">knnvAi Billitin No. 3 7 i A WORKING PLAN FOR SECURING MKDh'AL IN SPECTION. By Alfred B. Morrill, Wallingford, Conn. The problem of securing adequate hygienic conditions in our schools is one of educating the public. This is particularly true of the financial aspect of the problem. In all communities where money must be voted, a campaign of education, not only upon the social and moral aspects of the subjects, but upon the financial side as well, must be inaugurated. It must be shown that physical ill health costs money that can be saved by ade - quate medical iiisjK'Ction. It must be shown by tables of promo - tion rates, such as Dr. Ayres has worked out, for example, that retarded children mean added exjtense to the school system; that medical ins]tection, by lessening the number of preventable retarded cases anil bettering the promotion rate, will produce an actual saving in terms of dollars, teachers, school plants, equip - nieiii, and children's time. Medical inspection, therefore, becomes a business proposition. In a typical community with 250 children, for instance, a saving in the promotion rate of 10 per cent, if the children complete the eight grades on time, will be 175 years of schooling, repre - senting an annual saving of $5,250 at the rate of $30 per child per year. The school plant needed for the accommodation of the children would be decreased $17,500. Here are some facts as to the needs of medical inspection and what has been accomplished when adequate medical inspection has been established : 1. In contagions diseases. It can be shown that in places where a thorough system of medical inspection has been estab - lished, the number of cases of diphtheria has fallen off two thirds, and scarlet fever five-sixths. 2. In non-contagious diseases. Medical ins|&gt;ection eliminates a large proportion of the physical defects that have been proved to retard advancement through the grades. The fact to be made clear is that failures of promotion are a large and |»ositive force in increasing the cost of our schools, and that medical inspection will reduce the number of these failures; in other words, medical insi&gt;ection has a direct bearing upon the reduction of school ex - ]&gt;ense. The initial cost is more than saved from the lowest stand|&gt;oint of dollars and cents. Too great emphasis cannot be given to the value of a public presentation of the needs and benefits of medical inspection, in written reports or otherwise, before asking money for adequately doing the work. A discussion of the financial aspect of the case ap]&gt;eals to the practical men usually composing the councils </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska State Board ok Health which fix the budgets or the conn mini tics which decide u]k&gt;ii items of expenditure. A plan should be presented giving an estimate of cost. Those striving for the introduction of medical inspection should always present a well-thought-out plan. The following is suggested: (a) A daily inspection for contagious diseases: il&gt;i an annual physical examination of each child; (c) a system of fol - lowing up the parents to we that the children have the proper treatment; (d) team work in co-operation of teachers, janitors, principal and superintendent, with the physical director, school nurse and medical inspector in the various phases of school hy - giene. This work should be done by (1) The room teachers, who m;il.*«* *h»« viwinn »?u1 hoaHncr tpQts rtiiI phti Iw* tsniirlifr to kmUh'I children to be referred to the inspector on his daily rounds. These include: Children suspected of illness, children returning after having been excluded. (2) Medical inspectors acting under the general direction of the superintendent of schools or of the director of school hygiene; (a) calling at each school as near the opening of the morning session as possible for the pur - pose of examining cases referred to them by teachers; (b) once a year examining each pupil and recording the facts on a card for future reference. This could be done at any time in the day. and would take 10 to 15 minutes for each pupil. Such examination is fruitless without a system of records and the machinery for following up the cases needing attention. The inspector should diagnose cases, not treat them. The parents must provide the treatment. Experience has shown that some parents will heed printed notices, but that main require a per - sona! explanation, and that some need to be shown how. This has led to the introduction of the most indispensable factor, namely, the school nurse. The doctor visits for a few minutes, whereas the nurse devotes her entire time to the work. She is the most important feature of the whole plan. Her duties are briefly these: To aid and advise the teacher in her work and to act in emergency cases until the doctor arrives; to follow up children excluded on account of minor contagious diseases, such as scabies, impetigo, pediculosis, and ringworm ; to visit the home and confer with the parent, either showing her how to treat the case or influencing her to put the child under the care of a physician. The nurse is the most efficient link between the home and the school. Her work is immensely important in its direct re - sults and very far-reaching in its indirect influences. The Hoard of Health is very much pleased with the interest that the women's clubs are taking in public health matters in </seg>
            <seg id="p009">A.N.MAI BlLI.ETIN No. 3 9 this State. We have had the honor of addressing three federa - tions by request and are sorry that in two or three instances we were unable to comply with their wishes. We realize the fact that the women's club is one of the most potent factors in the St.it*' for the advancement of sanitation and public health. For their information and guidance we publish the following: "How Women's Clubs Can Aid the Hj'giene Movement," by Elsa Deni - son, published by the United States Bureau of Education in Bul - letin No. 48, 1913, entitled "School Hygiene." Any member of the club can secure this bulletin by addressing the United Statet* Bureau of Publication. The greatest service of women's clubs during the next few years will be to apply everywhere what we already know; to use all the machinery already available in every city and every coun - try; and to carry out definite programs based on the proved experience of other communities. The cities and towns where there is not adequate medical in - spection, examination and treatment of physical defects, where all school buildings are not properly cleaned, ventilated, heated, lighted, outnumber 10 to 1 the cities and towns where even a beginning has been made. There is no need for more organizations of women. There is no need of wasting precious time while communities "grow up" to health facts. There is no need for added experimentation about the more important phases of school hygiene, i. e., the physical condition of the children themselves and the environment they go to school in. May I suggest, therefore, that our "prophecies and promises" for the next few years group themselves under the following four heads : 1. Use Fact-Giving Machinery. — Women's t-lubs will use the machinery already in full swing to avoid being handicapped by lack of facts. Reference agencies like this congress, the United States Bureau of Education, bureaus of municipal research, the Russell Sage Foundation, State and local boards of health, tu - berculosis associations, etc., are spending thousands of dollars every year getting facts, making them available, answering ques - tions. 2. Draw 100 Per Cent Picture*. — Women's clubs will use the machinery of all organized women, whether in their clubs or in other clubs, to give to their city a 100 per cent picture of school health needs in that city. If an inspecting committee finds one school with unwashed windows and dirty floors, the club machin - ery will ask. How many more? If 90 out of every 100 children in our schools were found with decaying teeth, club women will ask, How many more, and how can they all be fixed? If a </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska State Board ok Health building is found with one open-air room for 20 children and bad air for !&gt;80 children in all other rooms, club women will ask. What's the use? :?. Enlist Professional Co-operation. — Women's clubs will use the machinery of their local medical and dental associations and their local groups of business men to secure (a) publicity about health needs not met; {b) preliminary volunteer exam - inations; (c) financial support by the city. 4. Solve Other Health Problems. — Women's clubs will use the machinery of the whole city administration to correct condi - tions affecting the health of school children or school buildings. Constant watching, reporting to authorities specific bad condi - tions, following up promised improvements, will be given to the questions of clean streets around school and for play; prompt garbage removal; where drinking water comes from; how milk is analyzed ; what cake, candy, soda, and ice cream in shops near schools is made of, etc. MEDICAL LEGISLATION. To appreciate the importance and influence of pending med - ical legislation on the present medical laws, it is necessary that we review for a few minutes the reasons as to why medical laws were passed and of what they consist and something as to their provisions. Many years ago it was thought to be desirable that the records be kept of the educational requirements or standing of those who presumed to practice medicine, in order that the public and pro - fession itself might be apprised of the standing of its individual members. To accomplish this it was necessary that an officer should be empowered to perform this duty who was familiar with medical education and would be able to make intelligent rec - ords for his office. At that time and at this time, under the constitution of the State the legislature was not and is not em - powered to create a new office, and the subterfuge of imposing these duties on the State officers, consisting of Governor, Super - intendent of Public Instruction and Attorney General, was used, and four secretaries appointed to this so-called State Board of Health, who, while ostensibly secretaries to the so-called Board, were expected to be at that time, and all the time since, inde - pendent in their actions pertaining to technical matters, while referring those of a judicial character to the Board proper, which did not have then, and does not now, any technical knowledge of the matters which come before the Board of Secretaries. In the spirit of the law it was not intended that the Board of health proper should be the ruling power, but it was expected </seg>
            <seg id="p011">•Vx.m-ai. Bulletin No. 3 11 that they would comply with whatever the Board of Secretaries found to be proper and correct. The personnel of the Board was provided for by the same laws which regulate the practice of medicine and the activities of the secretaries and provided that two should be from the so-called regular school of medicine, one from the so-called eclectic aud one from the so-called homeopathic school. Later the duties and authorities of the Board of Secre - taries have been increased to include written and oral examina - tions to those applying for registration and desiring to enter the practice of medicine and surgery in this state, which was an excellent measure, the reason for which we all understand and do not need to enumerate, together with the supervision of such sanitary matters as immediately affect the people. These features of the duties of the Board of Secretaries orig - inated in the national medical associations of the various schools of medicine and had for its primary object, so expressed, a na - tional board of health, composed of doctors representing the Hi ree schools of medicine, who would be able to receive findings and grades from the various states, keep in touch with the exam - inations made, offering and receiving such suggestions as might be necessary to facilitate the universal recognition of diplomas in this country, which were recognized in any of the states, to gether with such other functions as would be helpful to the vari - ous states in enforcing such laws. The duties of these secretaries were again extended by sug - gestions to them through the profession of the importance of carefully kept vital statistics and, desiring to institute such fur - ther regulations as would safeguard the lives and health of the people of the state and that investigations might be carried on and conclusions arrived at scientifically, they were given the privi - lege of establishing a laboratory to be a public and private bene - fit to the people and profession throughout the State. The greatest embarrassment to the carrying out of these plans at the present time is that apparently the spirit of the es - tablishment of these laws has been changed, and while the sec - retaries were exepected to be the authority on matters coming be - fore them of a technical character, there is a disposition to cause judgment arrived at scientifically to be subject to the approval of the lay committee. Another serious handicap under which any health commis - sion will necessarily find itself is that it is not a source of income to the state, making no demand for remuneration for its services, requiring no fee for laboratory examinations, and, unfortunately, does not receive the consideration it should. There is no difference of opinion as to what might be accom - plished in the State with a properly equipped health department. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nkhkask v State Board or Hf.altii 12 with the assistance which it might give from the laboratories in mat tern pertaining to pathology as well as sanitation, were the doctors in charge not handicapped by being required to get the approval of lay committeemen who are not educated to appre - ciate the necessity of the work thev have so well carried out thus far. In talking over these measures with a large number of physi - cians over the State we find there is some difference of opinion as to whom or how these measures should be carried out. Almost unanimously we have found it to be their desire that such addi - tional powers and duties be conferred upon the present secre - taries as would make it unnecessary for them to submit their finding* of technical character to any committee before they might lie enforced, except those of a judicial character which might come to their office. House Roll 722. which is Senate File 2!(5, provides for this ad - ditional authority, while House ltoll 384 would change the en - tire character and management of these departments, and would so complicate the carrying oui oi me provisions of the medical laws that it is not probable we would receive the benefit of en - forceiuent of the laws as with its present management with added authority. In Senate File 108 we find provisions for the punishment of itinerant doctors, together with privileges of registration without education and examination or responsibility of any character, and restrictions of those who are attempting to comply with the requirements in every particular, governing the practice and sani - tary laws at this time, which makes this bill not only peculiarly aggravating but insulting. It would seem to me that any man who employs a family physician must have more respect for him than to give this bill serious consideration. However, it would be well for this body to acquaint themselves with the provisions of various medical bills, as mentioned before, and register their approval or disapproval with their representatives and such in - fluential people as will be of assistance in properly advising the legislature in its decision on these matters. A bulletin recently issued by the State Department of Public Instruction sets forth the standards for schools, giving special emphasis to school buildings relative to light, heat, ventilation and sanitation. It seems strange that particular emphasis was not laid on these features many years ago. Throughout the State wherever you may go you will find school buildings, of the rural type especially, constructed without regard to the features above named. Cross-lights and shadows play about in the ma- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">AXNIAI. Ill I.I Kl I N NO. 3 13 jnriiv of schoolrooms. com{M-Uing the child to sit in his own shadow with cross-lights and shadows in front of him, with glar - ing blackboards, straining the eye and causing its readjustment under painful conditions. Impaired vision is on the increase, and from this condition arises a complexity of disorders, the cause &lt;&gt;f which has seemed to baffle hoth child and parent. In a large number of the schools of the State the buildings are healed by stoves which overheat certain portions of the room, while other portions are subjected to frigid temperatures. There is also no system of ventilation aside from the window, which in many of the buildings is kept closed in the severe weather, com - pelling the children to breathe and rehreathe the foul, dead atmos - phere, producing sluggishness of both mind ami body and pre - venting the keen, active development of the child. The standardization of school buildings insists that the light be admitted largely from one side — the left of the child, and that the light area be one-fifth of the floor area. This will give suffi - cient light in all parts of the room. There may be small windows for the purpose of admitting sunlight as a disinfectant. The Door area should contain 15 feet of floor space for each child accommo - dated, while there should be ar least 200 cubic feet of air space for each child. Some approved type of heating, with the pure air brought in from the outside, heated and properly distributed throughout the room, with foul air ducts, should be installed. Buildings conforming to these standards cost no more than the old iv pe, while the beating and ventilating apparatus are so inex - pensive that they are within the reach of all. Another feature to which I wish to call attention is the water supply. Wherever possible districts should supply wells. In many places windmills could be installed with little expense; pressure tanks ami drinking fountains or individual drinking cups are accessible to all with very light expense. School build - ing should be kept clean, well swept, dusted and scrubbed. Some suitable form of disinfectant should be used, chalk trays kept clean and the walls tiuted occasionally with water colors. This is a valuable prevention and need cost but a few dollars. School buildings should be thoroughly renovated and put in proper con - dition before the opening in the fall. The schoolrooms should lie made inviting and sanitary. Very sincerely, A. O. THOMAS. HEALTH INSPECTION OF SCHOOLS. If, as has been said, the highest function of philanthropy be to render itself unnecessary, then truly it may be said (in connec - tion with health inspection I that the work of the most eminent </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nerkaska State Board ok Health and thoughtful physicians* tends to gradually eliminate the physi - cian himself, at least in the capacity and position he holds today; fur the medical man of the future will not be the self-sacrineing, all-night-working man of today by the bedside, but rather the teacher who shall instruct humanity how to prevent illness, how to breed good health. Medical men and women, therefore, or at least that portion of them who feel the dignity and high mission of their calling, occupy the unique jn&gt;sition of plotting and plan - ning to take the very bread and butter out of their .own mouths. 80 health inspection, once established, will lead progressively to that condition of affairs which will in the end make health in - spection unnecessary — except in the instance of epidemics — and 1 lie severity and frequency of these will be greatly lessened. Health inspection, wisely administered, will demand school nurs - ing with its most valuable follow-up work in the homes where such aid would otherwise be unobtainable. It will establish open - air classrooms; an inquiry into the well-being, physically and mentally, of school children; why is eye strain and spinal curva - ture; why is inattention and chronic mischief -making ; a pro - cedure which will some day make for a race with a big lung and a clear head, for whom health inspection will have no meaning whatsoever. Seeing far into the future, you think not so far. One generation of health inspection which really inspects, unhanijtered by politics, ignorance, prudery, superstition, religious fanati - cism, but accompanied by a course in practical physiology com - mencing in the kindergarten, would go a long way toward making school children immune to a large percentage of children's phys - ical ills. Our grandchildren could measure up to this standard if we, here, today, were to feel the burden of childhood's handi - caps strongly enough to make you and me do the necessary thinking to bring about this reform. Some one has said that being a reformer is the quickest way to become despised; but the eminent English professor, Sir Kay Lankester, calculates that by research, prevention and cure every epidemic disease could be abolished within the next fifty years ; and considering the centuries of mismanagement in this respect, the centuries of unnecessary suffering from unnecessary sick - nesses, fifty years is not such a very great while to be despised ltecause one is a reformer. But we have no uniform health inspection today, and it may be that only our great-grandchildren will be the beneficiaries, ex - cept we are up and doing soon. Do not forget this, however, when you listen to criticisms of more or less feeble attempts to install such inspection : that those who believe in its virtues have fully as much, if not more, right (as citizens and taxpayers) to its benefits, as those who oppose it for any one or more of the rea- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">A.vnl'al Bulletin No. 3 15 sons before cited; they have a right to very definite protection against those who, opposing it, may spread unsuspected contami - nation broadcast. Tliis brings to mind a rather coarse but effective story of a (ill happening in a Philadelphia school where health inspection is conducted along scientific lines: A teacher, unable to endure any longer the odor of au unwashed boy, sent a polite note to the ■other asking her to give Johnny a bath. Instead of the bath the mother gave Johnny an answer to carry back to his teacher which read like this: "Johnnie ain't no rose; learn him; don't smell him." I leave it to you whether you think you have the right to protection against that. Another mother, learning that her boy suffered from defective vision called astigmatism, wrote that she had whipped him soundly and hoped he would not do it again. I leave it to you whether this boy had a right to protection against his misguided and strenuous parent. In a large town in Nebraska a member of the school board told me this story: A boy of good parentage, clean habits and gentlemanly demeanor developed a curious practice of taking his B classes with flying colors, but fell down miserably in the A classes. In the latter he was indolent, inattentive and impudent, and for over two years had Ix-en a sort of problem in the school. Then health inspection was installed and the lad's case became clear to everyone with common sense. lie was proved to be stone deaf in one ear and that ear, on account of the seating of the class, was turned to - ward the teacher's desk in the A classes, while the normal ear was on duty in the B classes. Thus, through a physical defect of which he was unconscious, his parents and teachers, likewise this otherwise splendid specimen of young manhood, took two semesters to pass every A class and made much commotion in so doing. It is estimated that it costs $35 per annum to teach each child in public school ; this boy, therefore, caused a waste of the taxpayers" money amounting to f70 — two years of his own life and a not to be estimated amount of nerve and energy wasted by his teachers. 1 leave it to you whether the parents, the teachers and (he boy had not the right to be protected from this most de - plorable waste of good material all around. The time limitations of this paper forbid any effort to lay l»efore you a plan for health inspection, for the subject is too large and too important to be treated lightly; it deserves as much time for consideration of its every phase as has been allotted to me foi - the entire subject. The writer, therefore, will mention here for tU - benefit of those interested the latest authority on the subject, a 600 - page volume by Dr. Walter S. Cornell of Philadelphia, entitled "Health and Medical Inspection of School Children." This very splendid treatise goes to the heart of the matter exhaustively and </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 N'kbraska Statk Board of Health is most fair in its treatment. A lu&gt;ok by Gulick &amp; Ayres, of play - ground fame, called "Medical Inspection of School Children." is a standby and not to be discounted by the Ixtok just cited. Kings - ley's "Open Air Crusaders" is a story of the scientific reclamation of sick school children which would appeal to anyone not made of flint and steel. These three books should be in every public library for general circulation, and not confined to the few who read because they have to write a paper and who have uo personal con - victions in the matter, for the truths contained in these volumes should become common property if we intend to graduate from the present system of political interference with our school gov - ernment, from the thralldom of ignorance and its twin sister, superstition, and from the blight of religious fanaticism. Neither is there time at present to note the points in Nebraska where health and dental inspection is now in force to a greater or less degree of success, nor the places where it is being held in abey - ance by interested individuals. The writer is in possession of data, however, where in one town two rival physicians deep in polities are holding off health inspection because neither wants the other to Itecome insjiector. It is superfluous to observe that this atti - tude would disqualify them both. Of another instance where a healer of a faith cult is pulling against popular demand for inspec - tion, while the healer's own child is a nervous wreck and a daily menace to the other children. Of a third instance where a man of education and member of a school board held out against inspec - tion because he thought it would "coddle the children and make them imagine they had spinal curvature, and so forth." Curious to get at the man's real reason, the writer investigated and proved beyond a doubt that he had good reasons of a strictly personal nature connected with his own children whom health inspection would show up as mentally deficient. So it goes, and an intermin - able array of facts might be listed to prove that too many people think not of the common welfare first. If health inspection did nothing other than watch the child safely through its little understood and trying j&gt;eriod of adoles - cence, guarding against emotional disturbances which might be costly in after life, then health insj)ection would justify its right to exist. If it performed only the homely service of checking ped - iculosis, for instance, there is ample excuse for it. We are all of us clamoring for civic righteousness, and if such a thing can ever exist, it cannot exist, I submit, without civic health as a base; and civic health is never to Ite attained until individuals are brought under control and taught at public expense how not to become disqualified in the race of life, through mere preventable and avoidable illness. Dr. Cornell lists "the principal defects most frequently met </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Annual Bulletin No. 3 17 with in school children as eleven in number: Eye-strain, ealarged tonsils, nasal obstruction, defective hearing, discharging ears, poor nutrition, decayed teeth, stoop shoulders (including Hat chest), lateral curvature, nervous exhaustion and mental defi - ciency." He also says that "records of heart and lung disease can - not lie made as routine work, because our laws prohibit the un - dressing of school children." And he recommends that "if our teachers live health as well as teach it, the children will sit straight from habit, keep their teeth clean, breathe through their noses and enjoy fresh air. If a systematic attempt were made to teach ventilation and practice it, what a revolution would be wrought in the homes of the children full of mission and enthu - siasm," he says. "In addition, a few simple facts about the eye, iliwmt fhost nutrition ami iliwt would »iiv» thp lifp of 1 1* many a baby brother at home." lit- also mentions casually, but apparently with unconscious humor, that it is not necessary for children to grow up as ugly in appearance as a large percentage do in the great eastern cities because their parents are too stupid to apply the remedial meas - ures offered free. Such defects as squint of the eyes, skin diseases, adenoids, etc., do not tend to produce a handsome race, supposing beauty were to rank ahead of utility. I think I cannot close better than with a parody on Hiawatha, used for a song in a tooth-brush drill in an eastern school : "Will you promise, ob my darling! To brush your teeth a little? It's all I ask * •• a little. I do not want to scold; You will not want them funny, hollow, empty, When you're old. You'll be glad I made you brush them; You'll be glad I seemed to scold; Asked you morning, noon and night time, If you brushed them • * • When you're old." MRS. K. It. .1. EDHOLM, Omaha. Executive Sec'y Nebraska Association for Study and Prevention of Tuber - losis; Chairman Health Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs; Gov - ernment Special Agent Children's Bureau. KKI'ORT OF THE STATE HEALTH INSPECTOR. For the First Half of the Year 1915. To the Honorable Slate Board of Health: (Jentlemen: — 1 beg leave to submit to you the following report and i ecommendations : I Miring the first half of the present year the following places </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nkrkaska State Board or Health were visited by the inspector once, and some of them two or three times, to settle disputes in the matter of diagnosis, quarantine ami sanitation : Dorchester, Bloomfield, Stella, Glenville, Rose - niont. Wood River, Talmage, Waverly, Unadilla, West Point, Clay Center, Coaad, Davey, Havelock, Elmwood, Pickrell, Uni - versity Place, Benkelman, Central City, Beatrice and Weeping Water. During this ]ieriod there has been much less smallpox than for the corresponding j»eriod of 1!&gt;14. Other contagious diseases have averaged about the same. In all places visited the local authori - ties were in complete harmony with the department, with the result that epidemics were checked and serious results prevented. In view of the fact that the quarantine pamphlet supply is running low and has not been revised for several years, I would recommend that the same be gone over and at least the following changes made: Tn the matter of epidemic cerebro-spinal menin - gitis and poliomyelitis, the same quarantine has been required for several years as upon smallpox, diphtheria and scarlet fever, but in view of the fact that those ailments are not so virulently con - tagious as the latter, the quarantine for the former might well be modified to admit adult male members in such families to go and come from their homes to their usual avocations, under the fol - lowing restrictions: To be required to change the clothing and use disinfectant washes, and especially the spraying of the interior &lt;&gt;f the nose and throat with disinfectant washes. In the diseases of measles and whooping-cough the role should specifically prohibit the person having such disease from leaving the premises until permitted to do sit by the local Board of Health, and the rule should also specifically forbid the attendance at school or public gatherings of persons in the family where such disease exists and where such persons have not themselves had the disease. The I'M:! session of the legislature amended the law pertaining to the powers and duties of the State Board of Health relative to quarantine and sanitation, giving the board broad and sweeping powers in regard to sanitation throughout the State, and the formulating of rules governing the same. Inasmuch as such rules have never been promulgated in the matter of sanitation as the law contemplates, I would recommend that practical and compre - hensive rules and regulations applying to sanitation throughout the State be promulgated and the same included in the make-up of the quarantine regulations, and an abstract of the law as enacted by the 1913 legislative session be published in the front part of the pamphlet. All of which is respectfully submitted. W. H. WILSON. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Akkual Bulletin No. 3 19 CAUSES OF DEATH PROM DECEMBER, 1914, TO JUNE, 1916. Typhoid fever 39 Measles 32 Scarlet fever 16 Whooping-cough 22 Diphtheria 36 Influenza ' 61 Dysentery 7 Erysipelas 18 Purulent infection and septicemia 59 Tetanus 4 Tul&gt;erculosis of the lungs 205 TtilieiTular meningitis 9 Pott's disease 4 Tuberculosis of other organs 3i Syphilis 5 Cancer of liver, stomach Ill Cancer of peritoneum, intestines, rectum 20 Cancer of female genital organs 30 Cancer of the breast 21 Cancer of other parts 102 Other tumors 7 Acute rheumatism 7 ( 'lironic rheumatism 7 Diabetes 105 Exophthalmic goi t re 8 Leucemiii 10 Anemia, chlorosis 40 Alcoholism 10 Meningitis 71 Locomotor ataxia 8 Other diseases of the spinal chord 12 Cerebral hemorrhage, apoplexy 304 Softening of the brain 11 Paralysis without specified cause 116 General paralysis of the insane 28 Other forms of mental alienation 9 Convulsions 42 Epilepsy 18 Pericaditis 12 Acute endocarditis 29 Organic diseases of the heart -. 591 Angina pectoris 30 Diseases of the arteries 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska State Board ok Health Embolism and thrombosis 41 Diseases of the veins (varices, hemorrhoids, etc.) 1 Hemorrhage; other diseases of the circulatory system 18 Diseases of the pharynx 3 Diseases of the larynx 4 Bronchitis, acute 41 Bronchitis, chronic 31 Broncho-pneumonia 163 Pneumonia 597 Pleurisy 9 Pulmonary congestion 43 Asihma 17 Pulmonary emphysema 17 I'lcer of the stomach 22 Disease of the esophagus ■ 1 Other diseases of the stomach, cancer excepted 44 Diarrhea and enteritis | under two years) 40 Diarrhea and enteritis (two years and over) 18 Appendicitis and typhilitis 39 Hernia, intestinal obstruction 55 Other diseases of the intestines 35 Cirrhosis of the liver 43 Biliary calculi 16 Other diseases of the liver 29 Simple peritonitis ■ 76 Other diseases of the digestive system 4 Acute nephritis 1W7 Bright's disease 137 &lt; 'hyluria 1 ( &gt;ther diseases of the kidneys and annexa 6 I tiseases of the bladder 20 Diseases of the prostate 27 Cysts and other tumors of the ovary 1 Accidents of pregnancy 9 Puerperal hemorrhage 5 ( Mher accidents of labor 6 Puerperal septicemia , 17 Puerperal albuminuria and convulsions 24 Gangrene 22 Diseases of the bones (tuberculosis excepted) 1 General debility, icterus, sclerema, etc 493 Acute abscess 1 Senilitv 293 Suicide by poison 30 Suicide by hanging 16 Suicide by firearms 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">AS 5 UAL BULLKTIN No. 3 21 Suicide by other means 29 Accidental poisoning; 10 Accidental drowning 9 Hums 37 Tra i ■ in :i i ism bv firearms 22 Trauinatism by machines 6 Traumatism by railways, vehicles, etc 28 Injuries by animals •&gt; Starvation 1 Excessive cold 1 Excessive heat 1 Lightning 1 Homicides 4 &lt; &gt;ther external violence 60 X&lt;&gt; cause 52 Cause of death not sjtecitied or ill defined 30 III denned organic disease 31 Other diseases of the respiratory system 1 ( &gt;ther general diseases 6 Neuralgia and neuritis 4 Poisoning by food 3 Other diseases of the skin and annexa 1 Hodgkin's disease 3 Other diseases of the nervous system 1 Absorption of deleterious gases i conflagration excepted ) .... 7 Chorea 1 I Hseases of the thyroid body 3 •&gt; Encephalitis 8 Calculi of urinary passages 1 Anthrax 1 Diseases of the joints •&gt; Mastoiditis ■&gt; Rickets 1 Mycosis 1 Sudden death 1 Still births 232 Total 5750 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska State Board or Health la ted Report of Births py Co Jun )unties. Beginning December. 1914. ti ie. 1915. Adams Antelope. . . . Arthur . Banner Blaine Boone Box Butte.. Boyd Brown Buffalo . Burt Butler Caw Cedar Chase Cherry Cheyenne.. . Clay Coif ax ... Cuming. . . Cust«r Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel Dixon Dodge .... Douglas . . Dundy Fillmore Franklin Frontier .... Furnas Gage Garden . . . Garfield Gosper Grant Greeley Hall Hamilton . . Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Holt Hooker... Howard .... Jefferson .... Johnson ... Kearney . . . Keith Counties ■ 1 129 63 1 3 3 100 48 43 30 154 90 89 92 84 12 49 33 88 56 106 148 41 41 115 13 99 158 vyy 18 77 73 41 54 119 17 57 13 11 41 110 74 54 12 29 101 4 56 97 70 49 17 a I 116 58 1 1 I 92 34 50 37 110 68 72 83 95 28 40 13 77 64 85 158 29 44 84 11 101 155 925 12 59 63 31 57 124 19 45 22 10 33 121 73 42 12 23 82 7 57 108 57 S 245 121 2 4 5 192 82 67 264 158 161 174 179 40 S7 46 165 119 191 306 70 85 199 24 200 323 1,898 30 136 136 72 111 243 36 102 35 ao 74 231 147 96 L&gt;4 52 183 11 113 205 127 100 31 s 2 ] c O 1 ["2 » C "S &lt; 215 112 2 4 4 177 77 86 66 258 143 152 163 158 40 85 42 155 98 171 295 66 82 194 20 188 301 1,335 30 123 123 68 110 232 34 95 34 19 66 220 137 94 23 51 176 11 97 188 110 89 I 18 1 1 4 3 4 4 3 6 12 3 4 5 3 7 4 2 1 2 2 2 4 80 11 2 7 1 2 1 10 2' 4 1 4 1 3 3 1 1 7 8 130 C I.! .2 jfl a l 2 1 l ' 3 2 1 15 5 1 E * « 3 1 3 2 3 1 3 2 2 1 1 7T C - 26 38 93 2 3 248 1 6 4 1 8 5 3 ... 2 6 2 "i 1 1 1 "§■ 1 2 '"% .... I" "i 1 8 5 2 1 2 2 2 1 2 1 1 .... i "V i 2 .... .. 3 "2 3 14 12 2 10 1 1 1 i 1 2 1 9 i </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Aicxual Bulletin No. 3 23 American Foreign 220 American - - - 9 4N abu! lated Report of Births by Countiei to June. 1915 — Cor I. Begi icludec mini December. 1914. .. Counties 1 1 2 i 30 12 236 935 149 15 33 257 3 138 70 113 138 136 191 98 20 91 156 222 120 96 206 39 172 71 203 120 191 104 127 6 96 127 16 114 124 132 126 129 15 187 3 I s a &lt; s i a -t5 O M ■D a | T3 "5 p — Keya Paha . Kimball ... Knox Lancaster.. . Lincoln . . Logan Loup Madison . . . McPherson . Merrick. . . . Monill Nance Nemaha . . . Nuckolb.... Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte Polk Red Willow. Richardson . t&gt; i_ 14 5 129 471 77 8 17 112 3 67 40 62 72 78 96 54 17 44 97 119 61 46 101 17 99 35 105 63 103 53 63 5 53 3 10 62 72 74 61 60 6 104 16 7 108 466 72 7 16 145 71 31 51 66 58 95 44 3 47 59 103 59 50 105 22 73 36 98 60 88 52 64 1 43 64 6 77 52 58 65 63 9 83 » 1 30 11 222 782 145 14 32 232 3 128 (iS 102 136 120 181 '.Mi 19 88 144 200 115 87 201 37 tea M 182 100 180 105 IK) .") SI 123 16 121 104 125 98 128 14 175 8 92 1 10 5 1 5 1 1 9 1 1 13 6 1 1 2 2 3 16 5 i 4 39 2 1 1 7 3 1 1 11 ' 1 2 4 2 I 2 13 2 2 1 2 2 1 7 1 3 1 1 1 10 1 4 1 5 1 4 1 1 Rock Saline Sarpy Saundere Scotts Bluff. Seward Sheridan . . . Sherman . . . Sioux Stanton Thayer . . . Thomas. Thurston . . . Valley Washington . Wayne Webster Wheeler York 3 1 4 7 1 1 7 4 4 "»" L... 2 3 i 5 3 .... "*4 5 3 1 3 1 2 1 " 25 7 2 1 18 9 6 5 9 2- 4 1 1 8 1 .... "e 4 2 Total... 6,995 6,448 13,379 11,949 487 168 365 84 380 M Twins Males - Female* White - IM 12. r . m 388 Triple Males Fema ets s e - Three sets 3 - 6 9 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>