<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Cereal Variety Experiments at North Platte</title>
               <date value="1932-06">1932-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin June, 1932 Cereal Variety Experiments at North Platte N. E. JODON Bulletin 33 of the North Platte Experiment Substation W. P. Snyder, Superintendent Winter wheat variety plats and view of experimental fields, 1928 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pagc- Summary ; 3 Introduction •- Corn "~"^~I~^Z-Z''Z 6 Earlier tests : ■• ( . Adaptation and type 6 Hybrid c0rn.....' • Corn varieties and hybrids on dry land 8 Corn varieties and hybrids under irrigation 11 Grain Sorghum Varieties ; 1;{ Small grains .... K; Sources of new varieties ; ... 1,; Methods of testing varieties 1C Winter wheat varieties '. 17 Turkey varieties.. _ : ' -20 Vai-ieties derived from crosses 21 Disease resistance ..'......' 2° Adaptation o-i Spring wheat, varieties .... 23 Durum varieties ; ; ■• 93 ' Common spring wheat varieties &gt;?.-&gt; Barley varieties : og Rough-awned varieties 26- Smooth-awned varieties 28 Oat varieties' ; 9() • Kherson varieties 31 Red varieties ..., .jj Burt varieties ........' 3.7 Smut-resistant varieties ..... 32 Comparative Yields of Cereals and Their Leading Varieties . 33 Progress in Cereal Improvement 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY Varietal tests of cereal crops have been conducted at the North Platte Substation since 1904. The results given in this bulletin cover the period from 1924 to 1931 inclusive. Comparative results are given for corn, grain sorghums, winter wheat, spring wheat, barley and oats. Locally adapted and selected strains of corn are best suited to western Nebraska dry-land conditions. Increased yields have been obtained from corn hybrids produced at North Platte, | but as yet no suitable commercial hybrids are available. Under irrigation, local adaptation is hot so important as on dry land, since the limitation im - posed by lack of moisture is removed. Hybrids will probably come into extensive use where irrigation is practiced. Certain hybrids from east - ern sources may prove suitable for irrigation. With the development of better-adapted varieties, grain sorghums have become a potentially valuable crop for the south-central and southwestern part of Nebraska. Nebraska 60 and local Turkey varieties of winter wheat are most satisfactory for corn ground. Tenmarq is superior for! favorable con - ditions and where lodging may be expected but is less winterhardy than Nebraska 60. Oro is resistant to bunt (stinking smut) but is not as productive as Nebraska 60. Ceres spring wheat has yielded 13 per cent more than Marquis and is resistant to stem rust. This is the best variety available for western Nebraska. Trebi barley is the most productive of the varieties included in the eight years of tests. The principal advance in barley improvement in recent years has been the production of smooth-awned varieties. The average yield of short-type Comfort during a five-year period was 5 per cent above that of Trebi. It appears to be superior to all other smooth-awned varieties tested at this station. The awn tips of short - type Comfort are not entirely free of barbs. Burt and Nebraska 21 oats are probably as satisfactory as any now available for western Nebraska. Two new varieties, Brunker and Carleton, are to be distributed. It is recommended that barley be sub - stituted for oats in western Nebraska. Cereal crops rank in the following order in productiveness: corn, winter wheat, barley, sorghums, spring wheat, and oats. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Cereal Variety Experiments at North Platte N. E. JODON » The program of cereal variety testing and improvement at the North Platte Substation was enlarged and reorganized in 1924, when it became a co-operative project j between the United States Department of Agriculture and the Nebraska Experiment Station. Field tests conducted before 1924 are summarized in Nebraska Bulletin 193, "Sixteen jYears' Grain Production at the North Platte Substation." - | The present bulletin gives the more important practical results obtained during the eight yeai's this program has been in effect, 1924 to 1931 inclusive. Comparisons of varieties of corn, sorghum, winter wheat, spring wheat, oats, and barley are presented. The varietal experiments with small grains are conducted entirely under dry-land conditions, while corn varieties are tested both on dry land and under irrigation. Tillage for varietal tests is, as far as possible, in accordance with the methods . shown by cultural experiments to be jmost suitable under the prevailing conditions. Winter-wheat and spring - grain stubble ground is prepared for corn by disking or duck - foot cultivation in the summer and fall for the purpose of controlling weeds and volunteer grain. It is usually disked again in the spring before planting. Corn is planted in lister furrows in the dryland, tests. In the irrigated tests, corn follows potatoes. The land is usually plowed in the spring. Winter wheat varieties are grown both on disked corn land, from which the crop is removed before planting the wheat, and on summer-tilled land. Spring small grains are grown on disked corn land. Early planting of spring small grains is always preferred. In every case weeds are jkept down as much as possible, to conserve moisture. In western Nebraska shortage of moisture rather than lack of fertility limits the productivity of crops. While seasons vary greatly, there is seldom a year in which periods of un - favorable growth conditions, usually caused by insufficient moisture, are not encountered. Varieties differ in their response to these conditions. Those which \ are least in - fluenced by adverse conditions and which also respond to favorable conditions are the most desirable. (Their adapta - tion to western-Nebraska conditions can be determined only by tests over a period of years. * Junior agronomist, Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases. U. S. Department of Agriculture, co-operating in cereal improvement work at the North Flatte Experi - mental Substation. This project was conducted by G. P. Sprague from 1924 to 1929 inclusive. L. L. Zook originated the work and has had general supervision. 1 Other Nebraska Experiment Station publications giving results of variety tests at North Platte are Bulletin 109 (1009), Bulletin 118 (1911). Bulletin 135 (1013) Bulletin 179 (1922), and Bulletin 193 (1923). </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 CORN EARLIER TESTS Varietal tests of corn from local and other sources have been conducted under dry-land conditions at the North Platte Sub - station since 1905. Inferior varieties were usually discarded after a single year's test, while the better ones were continued for several years. Between 1905 and 1924, some 150 strains and varieties were tested, with as many as 35 and as few as 6 being tested in individual years. Of this number, none was consistently better than the Substation varieties which were grown each year for comparison. Substation White and Calico were among the better varieties in the earlier tests and were selected further for ear type and maturity. While these are very similar except for color, Substation White proved to be somewhat better in yield and was retained as the standard dry-land variety. . ADAPTATION AND TYPE - These earlier tests indicated the importance of local adapta - tion, aided by selection. Variety names in themselves mean very little. A variety grown and selected in western Nebras - ka is usually characterized by its small plant type and early maturity as compared with a strain of the same origin and name grown in eastern Nebraska. Both extremely early and extremely late maturity are undesirable in western Nebras - ka. 3 Late maturity results in a crop of poor quality in seas - ons of early frost. Extremely early varieties, although they occasionally yield well by maturing before being injured by a late summer drouth, do not ordinarily use the full growing season and for that reason produce low yields. Individual corn varieties contain a large number of con - trasting characters kept in constant flux by cross fertiliza - tion. By means of selection, some of the undesirable char - acters can be gradually eliminated. A variety of corn can be considerably modified by continuous selection for particular types of plants and ears. It is not advisable, however, to select with a single character in view. Close breeding is likely to result, followed by decreased productivity. Improve - ment is limited beyond a certain point because of the large number of contrasted characters maintained by uncontrolled wind pollination. This makes it impossible to eliminate all undesirable characters without also losing some desirable ones. Adaptation and yielding ability are indicated to some ex - tent by ear type. The recognition of this relationship is •T. A. Kieaselbach, Corn Investigations, Nefar. Aer. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 20, 1922. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cereal Variety Experiments 1 bringing about a considerable change throughout the corn - growing region in the standards used by growers in selecting seed ears. Rough ears with deep, narrow kernels and a high proportion of grain to cob are losing their former popular - ity. Ears of this type usually indicate late maturity, starchy texture, and susceptibility to ear-rot diseases. Smoother ears, with wide, shallow kernels containing more hard starch, appear to be associated with earlier maturity and higher yield. There is much evidence of the superior adaptation of this type of corn to western ' Nebraska. HYBRID CORN Corn improvement through hybridization has been devel - oped in recent years and promises greater improvement than can be obtained by selection in open-pollinated varieties. Briefly, the method consists of inbreeding corn by artificially controlled self-pollination, selection of the more vigorous lines, and crossing between selected inbred lines to secure "hybrid vigor" which, in certain combinations, results in yields considerably higher than those obtained from the best varieties. The increase obtained is thought to be due mainly to the elimination in the process of inbreeding of characters unfavorable to growth, and to the bringing together of a large number of favorable growth factors in hybrid plants. The inbred plants used as parents of hybrids are much in - ferior to those of an ordinary variety. Seed should not be saved from hybrids, since the next generation jtends to return to the type of the inbred parents because of the segregation (separating out) of the characters brought into the combina - tion from the parent lines. It is entirely possible to produce hybrids which are better adjusted to dry-land conditions than are the best varieties, but their economic value is still in question because of the extra labor involved in seed produc - tion and the small increases in yield in unfavorable seasons. Suitable hybrids will undoubtedly have a place under irriga - tion in western Nebraska. The better hybrids have characteristics which cannot be obtained in varieties. A field of hybrid corn jis very uniform because the inheritance of all plants is much the same. The uniform ear height and also the resistance to lodging found in good hybrids make them desirable for harvesting with mechanical pickers. A desirable hybrid should also have less smut infection than, a variety. It is thought that farmers who have irrigation water available would be justified in testing hybrids in comparison with their own corn. Enough seed to plant a round through the center of the field would </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272' give a good first-hand comparison. It is usually impossible to obtain exactly the same commercial hybrids year after year because the producers of hybrid seed do not always use the same parent inbreds. i The present program of corn improvement at the North Platte Substation continues to include a limited number of open-pollinated varieties in yield tests. The greater part of the program, however, now consists of the development of inbred lines and tests of hybrid combinations between them. Hybrids and inbred lines from other stations are tested in comparison with those developed at the Substation. The ex - periments are now conducted under irrigation as well as on dry land. . CORN VARIETIES AND HYBRIDS ON DRY LAND All varieties and hybrids tested on dry land are grown in comparison with Substation White as a check variety in every third plat. Stands are thinned to an average space of 2 feet between plants. Results of tests conducted on dry land dur - ing the eight-year period, 1924 to 1931 inclusive, are given in Table 1. A bushel is considered to be 56 pounds of shelled corn containing 12.5 per cent moisture. No yields are record - ed for 1925 and 1926 because of crop failures in those years. Yields of each variety are given for the years grown, together with the average yield and the average of Substation White for the same years. A generalized summary is also given of the desirability of each variety with respect to maturity, freedom from suckers, and resistance to lodging and to smut. Substation White was originally known as Silver Mine and has been in variety tests at the Substation for 27 years. It was selected by W. W. Burr, now Dean of the Agricultural College, who disregarded the show type popular at the time. Substation White has been superior to all varieties tested in comparison with it. Substation Yellow requires more favorable conditions than Substation White and is somewhat later. It is now used as the standard variety under irrigation. In two of the three years tested on dry land, it was distinctly lower in yield and was only slightly higher in the other. Dawson, a yellow variety from Dawson county, was below Substation White in each of the three years tested and aver - aged 2.3 bushels less. Cattle Corn has been grown two years and has yielded very much less than Substation White. It is entirely unadapted, being too late and making too much plant growth. It is a tall </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table 1. — Corn varieties and hybrids — comparative results under dry-land conditions — eight-year period, 1924-1931 . ■■;':■ Desirability with respect lo ! : B Yield (bushels per acre) • : ■ . ' ■ • H - . --. ' — . Free- . . M Variety Aver- Av. Substa- Adap-' Lodge dom Smut g' 1924 1027 1928 1929 1930 1931 asrc 1 tion White, tation resist- from resist- ~ . ■ same yrs. ance ■ suckers ance . Substation White 27.9 55.1 48.5 15.8 44.4 25.7 27.2 D . M M j M 3 White Flint 23.7 • 49.3 45.3 18.5 32.0 24.7 24.2 27.2 D U U U g Blue Flour 19.9 52.5 49.6 15.0 34.4 23.6 24.4 27.2 D U U U k! Calico . ~ 23.6 54.3 41.8 13.8 38.3 24.5 27.4 D M M M Substation Yellow 28.4 42.5 11.4 16.5 18.4 M M M M g 1 Dawson 21.2 53.3 46.9 12.2 22.3 24.6 U M M M Q Cattle Corn \ - 39.9 19.2 29.6. 35.1 U M M M g McCullock 27.3 27.3 25.7 D M M M 2 Mahogany ~ ~~ ■. r - - 22.6 22.6 2C.7 D U U U S Highest-yielding hybrid 57.8 65.9 22.1 47.5 42.7 47.2 37.9 - .. • - , -. § . — — — — — jj 'Includes failures liT1925"and 1926 for the first six varieties listed. : Oj_ &gt;Des!rab!e=D Undeslrable=U </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 variety characterized by its extremely long and smooth yellow ears, wide, shallow kernels, and few kernel rows. McCvIlock, a yellow variety from Chappell, Nebraska, was grown for the first time in 1931. It yielded 1.6 bushels more than Substation White. It resembles Substation White in growth characters and general type, although it is slightly earlier. A yellow variety equal to Substation White in other respects would be of great value for dry-land conditions. Calico Corn has been widely 'grown in western Nebraska and has generally been quite satisfactory. During the seven - year period from 1924 to 1930 it averaged 2.9 bushels less than the check, confirming the earlier tests. It grades as mixed corn according to the federal grain standards, which makes it less desirable as a market variety. Blue Flour and Australian White Flint are the only vari - eties other than Substation White which have been grown throughout the entire eight-year period. Their average yields are respectively 3.0 and 2.8 bushels less than that of the check. This difference could possibly be made up by thicker planting, as the plant type is small. It has been thought that flint and flour varieties possess special drouth-resistant qualities but probably their only advantage in this respect is their early maturity, which occasionally enables them to evade the effect of dry conditions late in the season. Flint and flour varieties are undesirable because of their profuse suckering and their small ears, which grow low on the stalk Their only practical value is for "hogging down." Mahogany Corn originated near Hastings, Nebraska It is a flour variety of a very dark red color. It is somewhat later and has a larger ear than Blue Flour. In other respects it is similar to Blue Flour, and, as indicated by the 1931 re - sults, probably has about the same yielding ability. Hybrids have been tested in large numbers but no par - ticular combination has been grown long enough to be re - ported separately. The highest-yielding individual hybrid m each of the 5 years, 1927 to 1931, has been included in Table 1 to show that it is possible to obtain higher yields from hybrids than from varieties even under dry-land con - ditions. There is at present no hybrid available which can be recommended for dry-land conditions. Hybrid combina - tions between inbred strains developed at North- Platte have indicated a superiority to hybrids from other localities, again emphasizing the necessity of adaptation. Crosses between inbred lines from dissimilar types of corn, as for example between flour and dent lines, are more productive than those between lines of similar origin. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Cereal Variety Experiments CORN VARIETIES AND HYBRIDS UNDER IRRIGATION Corn varieties having a somewhat later maturity may be used under irrigation because the period of growth is not as frequently shortened by lack of moisture. | Consequently, adapted dry-land varieties are not necessarily the best for irrigation. Table 2 summarizes the results of varietal tests under irrigation. Irrigated tests were begun in 1926. Sub - station Yellow is used as a check variety. Substation Yellow has been selected under irrigated con - ditions and x has compared very favorably with all varieties tested with it. It is much like the yellow dent varieties grown in eastern Nebraska. Substation White yielded fully as well as Substation Yellow during the four years tested. The plant type as grown under irrigation is slightly earlier and smaller than Substation Yellow, and the shank is somewhat tougher, making it harder to harvest. Hogue Yelloxv Dent averaged about a bushel better than Substation Yellow over a three-year period. It was discarded because of lateness and weak stalks. Cattle Corn is later than Substation Yellow. Its yield in the two years tested was considerably lower. It is evidently not desirable for irrigation in. this locality. Blair White, from Washington county, was distinctly lower in yield than the other varieties in the three years tested. Corn hybrids may be expected to give yields well above those of the best open-pollinated varieties. Over a period of three years a hybrid combination between inbred lines developed from Hogue averaged 15.9 bushels more than the check variety. This is an increase of 24 per cent. This particular hybrid had an extremely weak stalk and lodged severely. It was discarded for that reason, j. Newlin Hybrid, in a four-year period, averaged 6.7 bushels better than Substation Yellow, or nearly 10^ per cent more. This should more than pay for the increased cost of seed. This hybrid is less susceptible to smut than Substation Yellow and .has a strong stalk. It is a commercial hybrid produced in Iowa. Funk 365 from Illinois has been grown two years with a yield slightly below Substation Yellow. This is also a com - mercial hybrid. Single Cross 365 is an experimental hybrid from Illinois. It has averaged 5.0 bushels better than the check in a two - year period. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Table 2. — Corn varieties and hybrids — comparative results under irrigation — six-year j» period, 1926-1931 &gt; . Desirability with respect to 1 : H Yield (bushels per acre) pi ..' — , — Free- ►O Vnricty A v&gt; Substa- Adap- Lodui; dum Smut W 19^6 11127 I'JSS 19-D 19M 1931 Aver- tion Yellow, tation resist- from resist- SO iikc sumu yrs. ance suckers ancc S Substation Yellow '50.6 S4.5 ! 64.4 5G.G 103.0 49.G I G8.1 ! D M M M Substation White 53.1 7f».2 ! 77.4 l!i.l ....... I 64.8 64.0 D M M M HoKiie Yellow Dent ! 49.9 91.1 : CG.l \ f 69.0 66.5 M ; U. •' U M Blair White !..... ; 48.2 84.1 ! 55.7 ...... ■ •■- j G2.7 GG.5 M M U U. p C:ittlo Corn :...:....!. , ...... ' I HG.G 46.5' 71. C 7G.3 M M M M H Hofcue Slhg l le b Ci'oss._, I 7G.7 ! 96.4 74,0 : 82.1 j GG.5 U U M U Z Wallace-Newliii ; : ; VO.it .57.5 112.8 MM ' 75.1 G8.4 D . D D U Punk 365 .:.:.; I I 1Q8.3 42.2 7,5.3 .1 7G.3 M D D D W ShiKlo Cross 36H . ... -■•■ U3.0 49.6 j 81:3 | 76.3 D D ! D P p Unilosirable=U •'•... .. to </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cereal Variety Experiments The results given illustrate the possibilities in the utiliza - tion of corn hybrids for irrigated farms in western Nebraska, but do not definitely prove any particular hybrid yet developed to be fully suited to these conditions. Hybrids produced at North Platte from inbreds -developed from local varieties have been too early to take full advantage of irrigated con - ditions, since the parents were selected under dry-land con - ditions. Some hybrids from eastern Nebraska, Iowa, or even Illinois may prove suitable for irrigated conditions. In 1931 the highest yields were obtained from hybrids produced by crossing North Platte inbreds with lines developed under cen - tral corn-belt conditions. GRAIN SORGHUM VARIETIES Western Nebraska is north of the main grain-sorghum area. Nearly all the varieties commonly used for grain in the western parts of Oklahoma, Kansas, and Texas require too long a growing season for Nebraska conditions. If pro - ductive, early-maturing varieties become available, sorghum should become a valuable crop in Nebraska for late seeding and for replacing failed stands of small grains or corn. Dwarf types for; combining may come into use to some extent. At present a large proportion of the sorghums grown in Nebras - ka are used for forage. Grain sorghums yield nearly as much roughage as Black or Amber sorgo cane but the quality i.s much poorer. Sorghum varieties have been tested each year since 1924. A summary of the comparative results obtained on the more important varieties is given in Table 3. Yields for 1927 are omitted because they were not reliable. Yields are based on duplicate 6 100 acre plats. Grain yields, forage yields, height, and date of heading are shown. All grain sorghums are commonly grown as row crops. The experimental plats are planted with an ordinary grain drill with spouts stopped so as to seed in rows 40 inches apart. The stand is thinned by blocking out with a hoe. The seed is treated with copper carbonate or other dust seed treatment to prevent smut. • Planting is done about the first of June when the soil has become thoroughly warmed. Sorghums are hot-weather crops and germination is likely to be poor if plantings are made during cool weather. Grain sorghums are usually harvested with a corn binder. After the grain has cured in the shock, the heads are cut off by means of a header on the side of the rack and then threshed. Sorghum grain is difficult to cure. This makes com - bining hazardous, even with the small-type sorghums which </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Table S— Grain sorghum varieties— comparative results in field tests— seven-year period, p* 1924-1931 (1927 omitted) ■_ ■ M -■.'■■ ■: : '"■ ~ "yield (bushels per acre) 1 " _" ' Comparative gj — T * ■• . " Aver I FetcrlW. ■ Forntre Height Date 2 Varlt;ty l 9 o, 1025 1926 1928 1029 1930 INI W _i^! ! !^^i g - ' \ ' . _^ - _. ;-■-•—• ;-- -.--■■ Lbs. per . S ■ ylere Inches ~i X; n°r n " ■-■• ■■■" " 19 4 40.4 32.6 30.8! 24.5 5600 48 8/10 % Club Kalir ■ ;,•--■• lg ? 38 7 2fl ; 8 u 5 C200 B6 8/7 Modoc - ; -., •■-•• -g 0()9 32G 216 | 215 3100 54 7/3i x Yte1ds for 1927 omitted ns unreliable. ". W to .-.■■• - • .-■■ bo </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cereal' Variety Experiments are now being developed especially for combine harvest. Effort is being made to develop dwarf varieties that will stand in the field indefinitely without lodging so thai; they will not need to be harvested until thoroughly dry. 4 Another method of harvesting that has been suggested is cutting with a header. The heads would be spread out on the ground to dry before threshing. . • ' The varieties listed in Table 3 are not strictly combine types, being too tall for this purpose. Yellow Kafir could possibly be harvested satisfactorily in this way. A few dwarf types have been tried in one or two seasons. They are apparently early enough in maturity, but are much lower in yield than the larger sorts. It is thought that any combine type that may be recommended and distributed by the Hays, Kansas, station should be tried by farmers on southern, cen - tral, and southwestern Nebraska farms who are interested in sorghums as a combine crop. Dwarf Milo is very productive but is often; somewhat im - mature when harvested. The recurving, "gooseneck" heads necessitate hand heading of the standing grain. Milo is not satisfactory for combine harvesting. Feterita produces about the same yields as milo and usually matures before frost. This is probably the best variety for Nebraska conditions now commercially available. The grain is chalky white. The germination is especially poor in cool, wet weather. Daivn Kafir is too late for North Platte conditions. The yields are usually below those of Feterita. Pink Kafir has been dropped from the tests as entirely too late. Farmers in the vicinity of North Platte frequently attempt to grow Pink Kafir or equally late varieties with unsatisfactory results. Yellow Kafir and Club Kafir were developed at the Hays, Kansas, station from crosses. Club Kafir |has given the higher yield of the two but does not mature properly. Yellow Kafir differs from other varieties in that the heads all mature at the same time. It does not have the late suckers which produce immature grain in most varieties. The poor yield in 1931 is thought to be due to a rather heavy stand. In a com - bine experiment conducted at Hays, Kansas, there were heavy losses in Yellow Kafir from lodging when harvested in Decem - ber. 5 ♦ John H. Parker. Breeding Grain Sorghums for Combine Harvesting. 27th Biennial Report of the Kansas State Board of Agriculture, pp. 233-246. s See . previous footnote. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 Modoc has given a good average yield but is less desirable in type and maturity than Yellow Kafir. Dwarf Freed matures and could probably be combined but is low in yield. SMALL GRAINS SOURCES OF VARIETIES Varieties of small grains may be placed in one of three groups according to the manner of their origin. Many of the original varieties, like Turkey wheat, were grown under primitive conditions for centuries before being introduced to America. They consist of a mixture of strains which main - tain their identity through self-fertilization. Until recently, importation has been a very important source of varieties. The earliest method of improving small grains was by select - ing especially desirable strains from old varieties. Varieties originating from individual plant selections are known as pure-line varieties. This method is universally used in cereal improvement. Artificial crossing is the latest method of im - provement. A stabilized selection from a cross is also a pure - line variety. METHODS OF TESTING VARIETIES A varietal test, to be of value, should contain several vari - eties of the same crop. grown in father small plats so that they may be compared under similar conditions of soil and environment. The yield of one variety ..in a given year cannot be directly compared with that of another grown in a different place or year. Several years' results are necessary to evaluate a variety. The yields of small grains reported in this bulletin have been obtained from field plats 1/40 acre in size, and are the average of four plats distributed uniformly over the land on which the test was grown. These are planted with an ordinary 8-foot grain drill, one drill strip eight rods long making a plat. The seed used is treated for covered smut or bunt {Tilletia. levis) to eliminate any differences in yield from that cause. Preliminary tests of selections of the various crops are con - ducted in nurseries consisting of rod rows. Results of' these trials are not reported here. Selections reported by North Platte numbers, however, have been advanced to field tests because they were outstanding in the nursery among selec - tions from a particular source. Varieties which were dis - carded previous to the 1931 season or grown only in 1931 are not recorded in the tables. Since 1924 the variety experiments with small grains have been conducted on the table-land fields of the station. The soil conditions are similar to those found on other table-land </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Cereal Variety Experiments areas of "hard" soil in western Nebraska. Previously some of the varietal tests were grown on the bench land. For this reason and because of changes in methods of conducting tests, no yields are reported for individual years preceding 1924. There have been no varietal tests of small grains under irrigation. WINTER WHEAT VARIETIES Variety tests of winter wheat have been conducted at the North Platte Substation since 1906, a period of 26 years. Two varieties, Turkey Red. (called Local Turkey in this bul - letin) and Kharkof, have been grown on summer-tilled land each year with average yields of 32.2 and 32.0 bushels respec - tively. None of the other varieties, except Kanred, showed any superiority to these two. Most of the varieties in the early tests are no longer of interest. The present plan of test - ing varieties both on fallow and on corn stubble was adopted in 1918. Two plats are grown under each treatment. The corn fodder is removed before- wheat is planted. In the four - teen-year period all varieties of wheat on fallow have aver - aged 32.9 bushels, or 11.2 bushels more than wheat after corn. Wheat after corn yielded 66 per cent' of that after fallow. The average yield of corn for the same period was 26.0 bushels. Each bushel of wheat gained by summer tillage was made at the expense of 2.3 bushels of corn. ■ Very similar results have been obtained in rotation experiments conducted at this station. Results of comparative tests conducted from 1925 to 1931 inclusive and including 26 varieties are given in Table 4. Results of earlier tests are not presented here because they were conducted on bench instead of table land and on larger plots with fewer replications. Tests in 1924 were on fallow only, and are not included in the table. The relative suscep - tibility of the varieties to bunt has been obtained from a special nursery. The tests have included most of the well - known varieties grown in the hard red winter wheat area and also a number of experimental varieties which for various reasons have not been certified for distribution. Kanred is used for comparison because of its consistently high produc - tion. ... Winter wheat varieties of the Turkey type represented by Nebraska 60 are very well adapted to western Nebraska. While there is considerable variation between yields of differ - ent varieties in individual years, it will be seen from the table that over a period of years a number of varieties have very nearly the same average yields. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Table 4. — Winter wheat varieties — comparative results in field tests — following corn and summer tillage — seven-year period, 1925-1931 Yield (bushels per acre) Comparative Z Variety and C. I. number IYe- Both Date Bunt 03 piira- 1925 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 Aver- treat- first Height Infec- j# t ion 1 age 1 ments heading tion Seven-year period . Inches P.ot. jj« Tenmarq— G93G P 28.7 12.0 63.4 31.7 (13.7 50.0 39.9 31.2 G/l '34 Ti . &gt; S 12.7 25.3 23.0 21.3 47.9 2fi.3 22.4 .. Kanred— 5146 F 3O.li 38.3 60.7 31.3 45.3 49.3 3fi.5 29.7 6/2 33 17 H S 1C.7 19.« 211.7 23.7 46.3 24.3 22.9 ' X Marquis x Kanred 449 — 10.009.. F 2S.fi 39.7 CS.O I 32.6 47.fi I 45.3 37.0 29 5 fi/1 33 18 • ■*fl S 14. 3 | 25.(1 25.0 i 24.0 42.5 23.3 22.0 S Local Turkey : F 29.1! j :!7.0 R3.3- 29.3 I3.fi 51.9 3fi.4 20.1 ' C/3 34 4.1 . 2 S 11.0 23. « 2fi.fi i 22.7 44.2 2C.7 22.4 . g Montana 36—554!) F 31.3 41.0 fil.7 ] 27.3 43.fi 48.3 3G.2 29 2 6/3 34 24 S ■ -" S 13.3 23.7 21.7 22.(1 43.2 28.0 22.1 y Nebraska GO— 02r.lt F S3.fi- 33.7 5G.4 ' 23.11 45.3 53.0 35.1 29.1 . G/3 3T 25 3 S lfi.O 22.fi 29.2 ! 20.3 43.fi 30.0 23.1 • Kharkof — 14 12 : ' F 33.0 36.3 fiO.O : 27.0 42.3 48.6 35.3 29.0 C/3 .11 44 rn S 14.6 23.3 89.1 21.7 12.5 27.7 22.7 H Kanmarq— 6037 . F 30.0 12.0 5S.7 | 27.:? 51.9 50.3 37.2 2S.9 6/1 33 25 &gt; S 12.0 24.6 19.7 I 23.3 39.1 25.0 20.5 Hi Rlackhuli— 6251 F 32.0 44.0 57.4 27.7 4li.fi 4G.9 36.4 2S S 6/1 33 24 C , S 13.3 24.7 24.0 1 21.7 37.3 26.7 21.1 ►* Nebraska 6— G2I9 F 31.0 3!&gt;.3 5!l.3 25.fi 42.7 49.3 35.3 2K.:&gt; 6/3 31 33 ' f&gt; S 15.7 22.3 24.3 22.0 40.S 26.3 21.fi Nebraska 30— 735S ........: "P 32.6 ■ 36.3 B8.3 25.3 41.3 50.3 34.9 2S.5 6/3 35 211 W S 14.7 22.0 25.7 2O.'t 42.6 29.0 22.0 • G Newturk— 6935 F 32.3 1 31.7 58.3] 22.3 43.7 51.6 34.7 2S.5 6/2 33 33 f S 14.7 21.6 28.0 ! 20.0 43.0 2S.7 22.3 IT 1 Marquis x Kanrrd 111 — 10.00S.. F 29.6 36.7 57.4 I 30.0 51. ft 41.3 35.fi 2S.2 6/2 35 31 M S 14.3 23.fi 21.0 ! 25.7 '35.7 24.3 20.7 ■' 2 Karmont— G700 F 32.0 3ii.fi r.fi.O ; 25.7 35.3 I3.fi 32.7 27 3 fi/3 34 '52 5 S 15.0 23.0 25.1 20.fi 11.7 27.7 21.9 Sherman— 4430 ' V 26.7 33.7 5fi.fi 23.7 46.0 51.3 34.0 27.3 fi/4 34 0 to S 13.7 19.7 25.4 I 17.0 37.7 I 30.0 20.5 -q Minturki— 6 155 F 31.3 26.(1 55.2 I 25.0 T.O.fi 45.6 33.1 2li,9 6/5 3G 2 N&gt; S 16.0 19.7 21.9 I 21.3 ■['*.» 22.7 20.1 ncloffllna— 1543 : F 32.fi ' 35.0 57.4 ' 23.3 11.0 45.0 33.5 2fi.7 6/3 33 12 S 13.3 : 20.3 i 24.0 | 1S.0 39.7 j 21.0 19.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">, Table 4. — Continued. Yield (bushels per acre) Comparative ~"pr e . '■"' • Aver- Both Date Bunt Variety and C. I. number pnia- 1925 1927 192S 1929 1930 1931 hkc= treat- first Height Infcc - * jon 1 ments ncatimg lion Oro-822o'" mr : 1 ' CBr .. P !!'. i ! d F :... 66.3 28.3 41.1 48.6 46.1 37.4 6/2 '"I? _ S 24.7 21.0 40.7 28.0 28.6 I • . ' W Superhard-8054 F 54.4 27.3 50.3 47.0 44.8 35.7 6/1 34 18 « S I 19.7 22.7 40.8 23.0 26.6 j . g Fulhard— 8257 F 1 51.4 26.0 47.3! 47.6 43.1 34.4 5/31 35 36 £ S 22 6 22 3 34 9 22.7 25.6 Kanred-5146 (four-year av.)... F '.'.'...'. ...... 60.7 31.3 45^3 43.3 46^7 38.9 6/2 34 &lt; S 29.7 23.7 46.3 24.3 31.0 , » North PlaUe'll-S^ F 32.0 42.6 50.0 41.5 36.9 6/4 34 32 . « S . .: 24.0 44.3 i 28.7 32.3 «; Early Blackhull-8856 F 31.3 58.3 ! 37.7 42.4 34.5 5/24 32 42. S 22.0 35.5, 22.3 26.6 S North Plalte 14-10,012 F I 28.0 48.3 j 42.7 39.7 33.4 6/6 37 50 3 a 20 0 38 7 22 7 27 1 * " Hays No 2—6686 F ■ __- "I "'2 29.3 40&gt; j 4o!3 36.'g 32.1 6/5 37 41 S S 19.3 36.6 26.0 27.3 g Kanred— 5146 (three-year av.).. F 31.3 45.3 49.3 42.0 36.7 6/2 32 .... g .-j s — ;;;;:_ r 23.7 46.3 . 24.3 .3.1.4 _h Cheyenne^SsT..^.....- P -■• 45.3 56.6 51.0 43.8 5/30 31 27 S 46.6 26.3 36.5 North Platte 15—10.013 F 40.6 41.3 41.0 36.1 5/31 32 1 S 38.6 23.6 31.1 Kanred— 5146 (two-year av.)... F 45.3 49.3 47.3 41.3 5/29 31 S 46.3 24.3 35.3 1 F=Fallow. S=Corn stubble. 'Includes failure in 1926 for the varieties tested seven years. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 .';.' New varieties for western Nebraska will probably not have any greater ability to produce high yields . under favorable conditions than those now grown. They should, however, be superior under adverse conditions. Further advances in winter wheat improvement for this section of the state will probably come through the development of strains resistant to plant diseases, cold injury, and lodging; having superior milling and baking qualities; and with non-shattering and non-lodging qualities suitable for combine harvesting: Turkey varieties. — Turkey wheat is of Russian origin. The majority of the present well-known winter wheat vari - eties are pure-line selections from Turkey or very similar types introduced from various regions in Russia. Local Turkey represents the original unselected Turkey variety. Its excellent yield at North Platte indicates the adap - tation of this type of wheat to the region. Nebraska 60 was selected at the Nebraska Experiment Sta - tion at Lincoln and was distributed in 1918. It has proved very popular, and is no doubt equal in yield to any variety now being grown extensively in western Nebraska." It is of good quality, is resistant to cold injury, is possibly slightly less susceptible to bunt than ether common varieties, has a fairly stiff straw, and does not shatter appreciably. Nebraska 30 and Nebraska 6 were selected at the same time as Nebraska 60, and are very similar. . Kanred and Cheyenne are selections from Crimean. Cri - mean is very nearly the same as Turkey. Kanred was selected at the Kansas station and like Nebraska 60. is winterhardy. It tends to yield slightly better than Nebraska 60, especially under favorable conditions. Its principal fault is a rather weak straw. Cheyenne, which was selected at the Nebraska station, has been tested only two years. In 1930 it gave the same yield as Kanred on both corn ground and fallow, while in 1931 it was decidedly higher. It has a stiff er straw than most Turkey varieties. It will probably be distributed to farmery within a year or two. Kharkof was introduced from Russia about 1900 by the U. S. Department of Agriculture,, and cannot be distinguished from Turkey. It has produced a slightly lower yield after fallow than Kanred. Three selections from Kharkof have been tested. Montana 36 is practically identical with Nebras - ka 60 in yield and other qualities. Karmont, another Mon - tana Kharkof selection, is considerably lower in yield especially on fallow. Hays No. 2, a selection made at the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Cereal Variety Experiments ■ Hays, Kansas, experiment station, has a very poor yield in comparison with Kanred, averaging 4.1 bushels less in the years tested. , Oro is a Turkey selection from Oregon which is of interest because of its resistance to bunt. It has been grown for four years with an average of 2.4 bushels less than Kanred on corn ground. It has a stiffer straw than most Turkey selections, and has good milling and baking qualities. It has been grown by a few farmers in the vicinity of North Platte, but is not certified by the Nebraska Crop Growers' Associa - tion. North Platte 11 has been tested for three years. The aver - age yield has been very nearly the same as for Kanred, and it has a stiffer straw than that variety. It is slightly less winter - hardy than Nebraska 60. North Platte 11 was selected from another Turkey type variety imported from Beloglina, Russia. The original Beloglina looks very much like Turkey but is weak strawed and low in yield. A bunt-resistant Belog - lina selection, North Platte 15, is very low in yield. Blackhull was selected from Turkey by a j Kansas farmer. It differs from Turkey in that it develops a dark glume color in dry seasons and is less winterhardy. Since its milling and baking qualities are considered to be much inferior to those of Turkey, it is objected to on the market. On corn ground it was not as productive as Kanred, averaging' 1.8 bushels less in the seven-year period. Early Blackhull is a very early strain selected from ordin - ary Blackhull. It has been used where an early wheat is desired for combining. The yield was very low on corn ground. It is being discontinued from the tests. Superliard is another Turkey selection having dark-colored glumes. Its baking qualities are poor, although the grain appears to be of exceptionally fine quality. Varieties derived from crosses. — Tenmarq was derived from a cross between a selection very similar to Kanred, known as P1068, and Marquis spring wheat. In favorable seasons, Tenmarq was the most productive variety included in the North Platte tests. It is very resistant to lodging. This factor has given it a very high average after fallow. On corn ground it was equal to Kanred. The grain makes a satis - factory flour, but the variety is less winterhardy than the Turkey wheats. It is being distributed in Kansas where it is recommended for the southern part of the-state. Tenmarq is not certified in Nebraska. Kanmarq, Kansas Ul, and Kans - as U0 are of practically the same origin as Tenmarq, but are inferior to it and are being discontinued from the tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 Newturk is a beardless strain from a cross of Newton and Turkey. It has a good average yield on corn ground. It is sometimes stated that beardless sorts are more resistant to lodging than the bearded ones. This has not been true with varieties included in these tests. Minturki, a Minnesota selec - tion from a cross of Odessa with Turkey, is tall, stiff -stra wed, and resistant to bunt and rust. • It is unadapted to Nebraska conditions because of its lateness. North Platte 14 is from a cross of Minturki with Kanred. It is also too late. Disease resistance. — The loss incurred in wheat yields because of plant diseases focuses special interest on resistant varieties. Two rus$ diseases, black stem rust (Puccinia gram - inis tritici) and orange leaf rust (Puccinia triticina) , are often prevalent, especially in seasons when there is sufficient moisture at the proper time to permit their development. Leaf rust is coming to be recognized as causing more injury than was previously thought. It is usually more prevalent in western Nebraska than stem rust. Ftdhard, a Kansas selec - tion from Fulcaster, is slightly resistant to leaf rust. Its yield is very low. Superhard also appears to be slightly resistant to leaf rust. The cereal rusts are composed of races or varieties. Kan - red is resistant to many physiologic forms of stemj rust but is attacked by others. Minturki is somewhat resistant to stem rust. Among the buhtri-esistant varieties grown at North Platte, Oro is the only one of value for western Nebraska. It is moi-e susceptible to leaf rust than other Turkey selections. Sher - man wheat also originated on the west coast. It isj resistant to bunt but is poor in baking qualities and yield. North Platte 15 has been tested mainly and Minturki partly, because of resistance to bunt. Adaptation.— It is usually found that the best-adapted varieties are those which have been selected under the con - ditions prevailing in the region in which they are to be grown. Among the many factors involved in adaptation in winter wheat in western Nebraska are time of maturity and resist - ance to cold injury. Turkey varieties such as Kanred, Nebraska 60, and Cheyenne, which represent the more pro - ductive sorts in the tests, are also known to be among the most resistant to injury from freezing. The Turkey wheats were originally grown in parts of Russia having seasonal con - ditions very similar to those of the Great Plains. Turkey varieties seem to be adapted in respect to length of season. Kanred, Nebraska 60, Montana 36, Kharkof, and Local Turkey come into head at practically the same time. Earlier </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Cereal Variety Experiments and later varieties are in nearly all cases less productive. Winter wheat varieties also differ in their response to local environment, as indicated by a comparison of yields from fallow and stubble. Tenmarq made an exceptional yield on fallow, largely because of its resistance to lodging. During the period of the test it was equal to Kanred on corn stubble. Blackhull, with practically the same average yield as Kanred on fallow, produced 1.8 bushels less on corn ground. Oro was also better on fallow than after corn. Nebraska 60, as compared with Kanred, yielded better after corn than after fallow. The same is true of Nebraska 30, j Newturk, and Kharkof. There was no significant difference! in the respec - tive average fallow yields of Kanred, Local Turkey, and Mon - tana 36, and their yields on corn stubble were also much alike. SPRING WHEAT VARIETIES From the earlier varietal tests of spring wheat carried on at this station between 1906 and 1923 inclusive, it was con - cluded that the durum wheats were superior! in yield to the common varieties. This was due partly to the! rust resistance of the durums. . This relationship was changed with the in - troduction of earlier-maturing rust-resistant common vari - eties of greater yielding ability than those previously grown. Comparative results with 14 spring wheat varieties tested in four replications of field plats on disked corn ground are given in Table 5. The tests have covered from three to eight years. Early planting is necessary to obtain satisfactory yields. In a date-of-seeding experiment conducted during the five-year period ending in 1931, an average increase of three bushels from the first over the second seeding was obtained. The third seeding produced only slightly more than half as much as the first. The average yields in the order of planting were: 25.4, 22.4, and 13.8 bushels. 0 The first seeding is usually made about the middle of March, or as soon as possible after the danger of serious injury from low temperatures is over. The subsequent plantings are made at intervals of ten days or two weeks. Plantings made much later than the first week in April almost always give very poor results. Durum varieties. — Durum or "macaroni" spring wheats belong to a separate species of wheat. The market in Nebras - ka is very limited since most mills are not equipped to handle it. The durums were introduced to the Great Plains area • Previous results of dato-of-secdinc experiments at North Platte are civen in • Nehr. Ai.t. Exp. Sta. Bui. 213. Sprinc Grains. Time of Seeding and Comparative Yields, by L. L. Zook. 192G. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">r«* B ,.- Sprina fieU tests lollop *H*m. Yield (bushels pur aero) I ~ ~ Variety and C.i: number — J C^P^tive ; gj --_-_...: .' I9 "'. 1!l - : ' I!) -- .»»» 1020 I mo 1931 A a£5- fi«t Hei 8 ht .'5 1 'I heading . W tlight-jfcar period : ;—. ;- j? Progress-6902 ..... o 4 » 1qn 1C . /n " 1 " &gt; Nodak 1 -6519 , Tor ] 3 A ]*'. 272 14 -7 ! 21.5 23.2 17.6 G/1R 33 M Akronn^6881 1~;; ." ' I ' 2S.4 14.6 I 22.2 20.0 17.0 6/20 34 f ■ Kubanka«-1440 ... ' : "" : "" ' ' -'•;■; I 25.9 . 1.4.3 ]'. 20.8 21.8 16.5 6/17 33 3 Marquis-3641 'Z.Z ' &gt; ! r Hi 23 - 8 »•» i 20.8T 2O.n 16.3 6/'O 34 " HcvoHwr period -: 13.6 ' 15.8 21.8 27.3 15.6 15.6 2n.J 16 2 6/18 ll g Cores-6000 • . ..„■.,,; W Rellance-7370 ' ,' r ' .7! '! ' ' ! S 16.0; .23.3 22.2 18.8 6/18 ' 31 Manjuillo-6887 ' I }H %;* I **■* ■! "•' I 19.1 22.8 17.9 6/19 " H ' MarqulH— 3641 (soven-year aver aK o) l.'s 8 07, ,1'r ' ?H 1!) ' 5 171 l 6 / 14 30 W Hve-ucar period ■ ' \ -' s 27.3 . I5.fi 15.G 20.2 16.6 6/18 39 g Garnet— 8181 . i "" ' S ' Java— Kearney Count'}"'- I i/ll Yll R1 - 1S - ' - 0 - 8 2 °-6 6/14 34 S Marquls-3641 (flvo-yenr" a'™^: " J?"« «S -«1 ■ ' S" 6 ' 22 " 3 20 ' 2 6 / 15 35 §• Fourycar period ■ - IS - -'■' ! 1.5.6. . 15.6 20.2 20.1 6/°0 35 Reward— 8182 ! W Miniliim 1 — 52D6 . . ' " " 24 - 2 j 15 -' -i -'2.2 21.6 20.9 6/12 ! 34 C Marquis 3641 (fnur-ycar :n(»ra K ej •'■' 0-, 1H 20 - 6 18 ' 5 200 6/17 39 P ; Tli rrc-j/rar period '. .■ ;•-'-' I ]r '- 6 '■ ™.C, 20.2 19.7 ' 6/17 37 M Supreme — 8026 ■ ■ S Hope— 8178 "■'"" ■ I 14 -3 15.1 23.0 17.5 6/15 33 Z Marquis— 36.(1 (three-year avpraRO)': • ' I Jjj.O il6n ] 5J ».7 6/15 31 to - 1I)urum • ;; i 15.6 I 15.6 .20.2 17.1 6/15 | 34, g ;. Inclmio failure in 192fi r-&gt;, vnri.-ti™ listed „ v,.,, : ,,..l . -iuht v,,,r- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Cereal Variety Experiments from Russia about 1900 and proved much more productive than the rust-susceptible, late, unadapted, common varieties being grown at that time. Four durum varieties are reported in Table 5. The Kubanka variety was a direct importation ifrom Russia. Noduk was selected in North Dakota, Mindum in Minnesota, and Akrond at Akron, Colorado. The latter is the earliest, but the yields of all four are very nearly equal. They are all somewhat later and taller than the varieties of common spring wheat. Durum wheats are equalled or excelled in yield by the better varieties of common wheat now available. . Common spring wheat varieties. — Marquis is an awnless variety of common spring wheat developed in Canada from a cross between Hard Red Calcutta and Red Fife. It was in - troduced into the United States about 1912 and because of its high quality and good yield as compared to the other varieties in use at the time, it became widely distributed. Its average yield at North Platte during the eight-year period is equal to that of the durums. There were, however, no serious epidemics of rust in this period. Marquillo was derived from a cross between Marquis and Iumillo durum. It is a common wheat with some of the rust resistance of durum. The average yield for the eight-year period shows it to be equal to Marquis. Hope was selected from a cross between Marquis and Yaroslav emmer. It is the most rust-resistant common wheat known, but is very low in yield, Kearney County Java is a strain of an old variety of that name. It was originally obtained from Kearney county, Nebraska. Its average yield in five years is practically the same as that of Marquis, but the quality is poor. Progress was selected from Java at the Wisconsin Experiment Station and has averaged 1.4 bushels better than Marquis in eight years. Supreme is a selection from Red Bobs, another of the old varieties. In two of the three years tested, it was below Marquis in yield. Garnet and Reward are two Canadian varieties originat - ing from crosses. Garnet is beardless. Both are early, and Reward has good quality, and both are equal to or slightly better in yield than Marquis under North Platte conditions. Reliance was selected in North Dakota from a cross between Kanred and Marquis. In seven years it outyielded Marquis by ah average of 1.3 bushels. Ceres is the most productive spring wheatj now available. It was also developed in North Dakota, and is from a cross </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 of Kota and Marquis. It is somewhat resistant to rust. It has been included in the tests seven years and has averaged 2.2 bushels more than Marquis, representing an increase of 13 per cent. BARLEY VARIETIES Barley is increasing in popularity in Nebraska. The acre - age of barley grown in 1930 was six or seven times as great as that grown in 1914. 7 During the same period the acreage of corn increased about one-fourth, spring wheat declined nearly one-half, and oats and winter wheat remained nearly stationary. Barley is better adapted to western Nebraska conditions than oats and spring wheat. It would probably be grown even more extensively if it were not for the fact that it has a rather weak straw and, in the varieties com - monly grown, rough, barbed awns. Most of the newer vari - eties are smooth awned, which makes handling less disagree - able and increases the value of the straw. Varieties with stronger straw and more resistance to shattering are needed for western Nebraska. Barley variety tests have been conducted at North Platte each year since 1909. In the experiments preceding those re - corded in this bulletin, the leading varieties were Common Six-row, Coast, Trebi, and McClymont. These have main - tained their high place among the productive varieties. Varietal tests reported in Table 6 were conducted on corn ground on table-land fields. Trebi is used* in Table 6 as a standard of comparison since it is the best-known variety in western Nebraska at present and is well adapted. Early planting is essential with barley. Five-year average yields of 39.7, 36.6, and 19.7 bushels have been obtained from early. medium, and late seedings of barley. Ordinarily very low yields are obtained from barley when planted after the first week of April. Rough-awned varieties. — Four varieties of the Coast type (Coast, Trebi, Sandrel, and Common Six- row) have been grown throughout the eight-year period. Coast has long been popular in semi-arid regions in the western United States. A large percentage of the barley grown in Nebraska belongs to this group. ' Coast was prob - ably introduced from north Africa. It is characterized by heavy, rough awns which do not break off readily in thresh - ing. Coast is apparently fully as productive as Trebi, having an average of 0.8 bushel more. * ' Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1030. . ' , </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Table 6— -Barley varieties-comparative results of field tests following corn— eight-year ■ period, 1924-1931 __■ .. _ " r ~~ ~ '- — T - • Yield, (bushels per acre.) Comparative Variety and C. I. number . ■ Aver- f t Height 1921 1925 . 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 age' hcadin(S o Common Six-row-4640 :..-- -- 29.9 2-.7 37.3 .4-.1 -* 2g x 24 g *S2K5Sf: -±;s Hi lii Si S ii:i S « Trebi— 936 (Ave-year average) •— ■ 40 -° 4&lt;J -° s 'f **•* a -' &lt;"»•«&lt; &gt;g Fawwear period 33 7 40 8 17 3 34 . 2 6/n 2 9 g Arequipa— 1256 ™-" „* r ,, „ 19 2 35.7 6/11 25 S Trebi— 936 (four-year average) 43 -° 37 ° ilJ 19li ■' D/ g Three-year period , 7 7 ,, 8 , n 2 33 r 6/8 29 5 N.P. No. 1 (2126-89)-5266 ".7 4-.8 20.2 iSM b/8 g N.P. No. 5 (2126-30)-5510 38.1 39.1 19.8 «.i b/ g (690-223)^5488...........^ = _^1 _^ _^_ _ 3 3^ 7 _ _|g^ _|°;g jg 6/12 30 Glabron— 4577 v ■■ , 7 5 42 9 19 2 33-2 6 /n 25 Trebi— 936 (three-year average) - d ' !) * AS aai °°" ' Two-year period 39 6 14 4 27.0 6/2 21 Vaughn— 1367 ■- : 4 ," 9 19 2 31-1 6/9 25 Trebi— 936 (two-year average) __--• _ • •—; *** "' ' ilndudes failure in 1926 for the varieties tested eight years. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 ■ Common Six-roiv is very similar to Coast in height, matur-. ity, and yield. It has "been in varietal tests at the station since 1909 and has not been greatly excelled by any variety compared with it. It is probable that there is considerable difference among varieties known as Six-row. Trebi is very much like Coast, and is a productive, vig - orous-growing, variety. It is a pure-line selection made in Minnesota from an importation of barley from Turkey. The hull is white but the grain has a bluish color. Sandrel is a pure-line variety of the Coast type developed by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. The grain does not have the bluish color found under the hull in Trebi and certain other Coast varieties. It has averaged 1.9 bushels more than any other variety tested over the entire eight-year period. North Platte U, a selection from Coast, has been tested in the field plats three years. The average is only slightly better than that of Trebi. North Platte 1 is a Coast-type selection from McClymont. It has been outstanding in nursery tests and makes an even more vigorous growth than Trebi. The stiff, rough awns are objectionable. In field plats it has aver - aged practically the same as Trebi in the three years tested. Arequipa is a pure-line Coast-type variety selected from barleys imported from Peru. It has been tested four years and is somewhat inferior to Trebi in yield. McClymont was obtained from a farmer near North Platte. It differs from the Coast varieties described above in that the awns tend to break off as soon as the grain is fully ripe. .Vari - eties having this character are sometimes known as malting barleys. The eight-year average yield is exactly the same as that of Coast. The straw is rather weak. North Platte 5, a selection from McClymont and having the same tendency to shed the awns, has averaged 0.9 bushel less than Trebi in a three-year period. Club Mariout differs from the Coast type chiefly in having a much shorter and more compact head. This variety was in - troduced from Egypt where it has been grown since ancient times. It is slightly less productive than the Coast varieties. Smooth-awned varieties. — All smooth-awried strains have been developed from crosses involving a black, smooth - awned variety known as Lion as one parent. Comfort (short type) has been grown in varietal tests in five seasons and has averaged 1.7 bushels more than Trebi, an increase of 5 per cent. This was largely due to a high yield in 1928, a very favorable season. This is a Coast-type </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Cereal Variety Experiments variety, except for the difference in. roughness I of awn. The awns are much smoother than those of Coast but are barbed near the tip. The tall-type Comfort was grown only in 1931 when it yielded 18.8 bushels as compared to j 21.5 for the short type. Ill appearance it is much like Glabron and may prove to be unadapted. It has a much smoother awn than short Comfort. These two varieties are different selections from the same cross. Glabron, like the Comfort varieties, was developed in Min - nesota. It has a very smooth awn. It has a three-year aver - age of 5.7 bushels below that of Trebi and seems unadapted to western Nebraska. Vaughn is. a smooth selection from California.! It resembles Coast in plant type. The awns are not as smooth as would be desired and the plant is very short. Vaughn is entirely too early to be suitable' for North Platte conditions. •There is more diversity of types in barley than in any other cereal crop. Most of the productive- varieties tested at North Platte are of the rough-awneel sixfrowed Coast|type. A hull - free variety which threshes free of glumes like wheat gave an average yield of 21.0 as compared to 27.3- bushels for Trebi in a six-year period. Allowing 15 per cent for hulls, a yield of 21.0 bushels of hull-free grain would be equal to 24.7 bushels with hulls. Even on this basis, the yield is much lower than that of Trebi. Colaess, a stiff-strawed, hooded variety re - commended for irrigated conditions in Colorado averaged 34.8 bushels in three years, and the smooth-awned Velvet, 32.9." In the same years, Trebi averaged 40J2 bushels. A short two-rowed variety known as Smyrna gave a six-year average of 25.4 bushels, while Trebi averaged 27.3 bushels. The difference in this case was probably due in part to loss in harvesting the extremely short-strawed Smyrna. There are also black-glumed varieties, but their color makes them undesirable. OAT VARIETIES Western Nebraska farmers continue to grow oats because of their desirability for feed, although they are less productive than other cereal crops. Oats need no preparation for feed - ing, stand well in the field, and are agreeable to handle. They are, however, primarily a crop for regions haying cool sum - mers. Oat varieties have been tested at North Platte each year since 1904. In the experiments preceding those reported here, the leading varieties were all of the early type. Kherson, Sixty-day, Nebraska 21, and Burt gave practically the same yields. In a 16-year period Kherson averaged 32.4 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Table 1—Oat varieties— comparative results of field tests following cornr-eight-year g period, 1924-1931 _ _■ _^_ :=r===== g Yield (bushels per aero) Comparative w Variety and C. I. number Aver- fl a £ Heieht.. '** • ...... 1D2I 1925 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 age' headins hn _ ■— - . — : — ' Inches VXZtS* ■ 32 5 32.8 46.9 71.6 42.8 56.0 .['. 47.2 ■' 41.3 6/18 32 g Markton-2053 ...................... "° 43 7 54 4 3!) 0 40 3 6/9 28 S »"** r !™ 1 60.0 6S.3 13.7 41.9 .-.'«* 51.5 8/15 31 g. Iogold— 2329 ■— ; rfi _ pr o o R - j. 7 40 o . 40 2 6/16 36 5 . Iowar— 847 (five-year average) • •• G,&gt;.3 | u8.4 41.7 W.J *»■■* o/" 5? Pour-year period ■ I 60 7 1 48 4 4!&gt;.O 3!).l 51.6 6/17 30 W Gopher— 2027 ••• -■ • 44 7 40 9 47 3 6/]6 32 G Iowar— 847 (four-year average) - ; - -•- -- v™ • 5S '» •._«•• *" J f Three-year period 43 7 5 , g 43 j 465 6 /10 28 .g North Platte 7, -: ■•. ; -- 45 n 4 " 7 42 2 453 6/11 27 H North Hatte 10 ■ •- ; • ■ gf 44 , 8 6^ 9 27 § Burt— 2491 .: - : • :— ! „„ 4 447 409 41.3 6/15 30 Iowar— 847 (three-year average) | -v-- •■■ ■ .-■ — - ■■• ; I is - 4 **•;_ &gt; ■ ,.._. _*_ "IndudeB failure in 1926 for the varieties tcstx-d etght ' year... • ' . N&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Cereal Variety Experiments and Sixty-day 31.0, and in a 14-year period Burt averaged 29.5 as compared to 29.4 bushels for Kherson. These varieties are the ones now commonly grown in the state. Texas Red, a variety used as a winter oat in the south, yielded about the same as Kherson, 26.3 for the former and 26.8jbushels for the latter as a 10-year average. Late northern varieties yielded only about 60 per cent as much. Results obtained from oat varietal tests during the years 1924 to 1931 are given in Table 7. Earlier results -are not given because the tests were conducted under different con - ditions. Comparative data are given for 12 varieties. Seven have been grown throughout the eight-year] period. With the exception of Markton, which may be classed as midseason, all the varieties are early in maturity. Liberty Hull-less is probably the only discarded variety of interest. This variety was tested only in 1925. The yield was 15.6 bushels. Allow - ing 30 per cent for hull, this would be equivalent to 22.3 bushels. Iowar, which is used as a standard of comparison in Table 7, yielded 30.0 bushels in the same year. Kherson varieties. — Kherson was imported from Russia by the Nebraska Experiment Station. Sixty-day, imported by the U. S. Department of Agricul - ture, is practically identical with Kherson. The Kherson dis - trict in Russia has a climate very much like |;hat of western Nebraska. Kherson oats are much better adapted to this region than the late varieties previously grown. Kherson and Kherson-type selections form an important group of oat vari - eties in the corn belt. Nebraska 21, a Nebraska selection of Kherson, is probably the best known variety in the state. Its average yield in eight years at North Platte, however, is only 0.6 bushel more than that of the original variety. 1 Iowar is a Kherson selection from Iowa. It has averaged 1.1 bushels more than Kherson in the eight-year period. Since Iowar has been the leading Kherson variety, it is used as a standard of comparison in Table 7. Iogold, another Iowa Kherson-type selection, has averaged 2.3 bushels more than Iowar in a five-year period. Gopher, a Minnesota selection of the Kherson type, has outyielded Iowar in three of the four years tested, and aver - aged 4.3 bushels more. It is slightly later than Iowar. Red varieties. — Fulghum is said to have originated in Georgia as a winter oat. It is a red oat, with plump kernels. The variety comprises a number of types. It usually heads three or four days earlier than the Kherson varieties. The </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 272 original Fulghum variety averaged only 0.8 bushel less than Iowar in the eight years grown. Kanota has not been included in field trials at North Platte but nursery tests indicate that it is inferior to Fulghum. This: variety is grown to some extent along the southern border of Nebraska. Burt varieties. — The original Burt variety is said to have originated in Alabama by selection from Red Rustproof. It is not a pure-line selection, however, but a mixture of plant and kernel types. The kernels range in color from black and red to yellow and white. In the eight-year period it has given practically the same average yield as Iowar. Brunker was selected from Burt at Akron, Colorado. It is an early red variety with a kernel much like Fulghum. The eight-year average is 1.3 bushels above Iowar, and 1.7 above Burt. Brunker has a slender straw and is very uniform in appearance in the field. It stands up well under conditions at North Platte. It is being distributed in Colorado and will probably become quite popular in western Nebraska. Burt C. I. No. 2491, a white selection resembling Kherson, has been grown three years with an average yield of 3.5 bushels above that of Iowar but did not equal the- original Burt. North Platte 10, a light-colored selection/has averaged 45.3 bushels or 4.0 bushels more than Iowar. In a three year test in field plats Burt outyielded it each year. North Platte 7 is a Fulghum-type selection from Burt. It has been included in field tests three years and has average;! 46.5 bushels, as compared to 41.3 for Iowar and 16.2 for Burt in the same years. Smut-resistant varieties. — Markton is a yellpwish white. midseason variety with a distinct branching head-type. It has the highest average of any variety tested throughout the eight-year period, having averaged 2.3 bushels more than Iowar and 2.7 bushels more than Burt. It is very resistant to smut, but is susceptible to rust. The yield results obtained at North Platte are more favorable to Markton than those obtained at Lincoln. Markton is grown in the Pacific North - west and in Montana. Selections from crosses between Markton and Sixty-day received several years ago from the Sherman County Branch Station, Moro, Oregon, are being tested at North Platte and other stations, and it is probable that one of these, named Carleton, will be distributed. It is earlier than Mark - ton and is more like Kherson in growth habit. It is fully as </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Cereal Variety Experiments ■' '■' - ' ' ■ ' [. resistant to smut as Markton and the yielcl is apparently also as good. Until Carleton and Brunker become available, it will be advisable to use Nebraska 21 or other varieties which have given satisfaction in the past. COMPARATIVE YIELDS OF CEREALS AND THEIR LEADING VARIETIES The average yields of the various cereal crops and their leading varieties have been converted into pounds of hull - free grain for comparative purposes in Table 8. All yields except in the case of sorghums are seven-year averages. All varieties were grown on dry land. Comparisons between crops in terms of bushels per acre are misleading because of the differences in standard bushel weights and in percentage of hull. In computing the yields of barley and oats on a hull - free basis, barley hulls were taken as 15 per cent of the total weight and oat hulls as 30 per cent. The average yields of all varieties grown throughout the period are used to represent the yield of a crop, except in the case of corn where the average yield of Substation White is used.! The sorghum yields represent seven-year averages for the period from 1924 to 1931 with the year 1927 omitted. Corn is the most productive crop, with winter wheat sec - ond. The. average yield of winter wheat on corn land in pounds per acre is 86 per cent of that of corn. Barley yielded 77 per cent and grain sorghums 76 per cent as much as corn. Spring wheats yielded 68 per cent as much as corn, and oats only 59 per cent. The order of yield remains practically the same when the highest-yielding varieties of each crop are compared. The comparative yields of these crops from rota - tion experiments at this station which cover! a longer period of years give them the same ranking. Winter wheat, how - ever, is somewhat higher in yield in relation to corn. PROGRESS IN CEREAL IMPROVEMENT During the period covered by this bulletin, greater pro - gress has been made in the improvement of some crops than others, considering adaptation to western Nebraska dry-land conditions. Ceres spring wheat represents a; 13 per cent in - crease in yield over Marquis and is more rust resistant. It yielded very nearly as many pounds of grain per acre as Trebi barley on the hull-free basis. Sandrel has butyielded Trebi by about 5 per cent. Smooth-awned varieties represent the greatest improvement in barley breeding.) In comparing sorghum and barley, it will be seen that there are varieties of the former crop that are more productive than barley. The </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Table 8. Comparison of cereal crops and their leading varieties, 1925-1981 ' . — - - Comparative hull-free yields based on varieties Wt. Bushels Pounds per acre " indicated ZJ Crop and variety per per , M bushel acre Tota j Hull-free Kanred Marquis Trebi Iowar Corn w ~" ~P~Tt. P.et. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. g* Winter wheat— after corn: .60 W Av. 17 varieties grown entire period ■ 2.7 ........ 1302 $•}» g 147 86 &gt; K^ -•■•■ - - 23.! : 1386 ioi 139 118 157 91 gf Nebraska 60 • . 1344 gg 135 115 152 89 K STuri^zz::::::::;:ii::z: 22.4 1344 98 135 ub 152 . 89 g Spring wheat— after corn: 60 g Av. 8 varieties grown entire period.. . .17.3 1038 76 104 89. 118 bjj | J? 1 }; 11111 ,? - • ■ ■ 166 II 996 72 100 85 113 66 § J5 u r b o f ka - " . 18.8 1128 82 113 96 128 74 £ ceres ... — - : • _ ■ ■ . ■ . C/J Barley— after corn: ■ 4 » " „- 11? 100 132 . 77 g Av 6 varieties grown entire period.. 28.6 1373 1167 85 117 100 132 77 g J rebi : ■ ~ - 29.3 1406 1195 87 120 102 135 79 O S^^aS^rilZI^Z: 28.3 1»S - 1154 84 116 99 131 76 J8. Oats— after corn: , o 0 o io 7 i ono cr. on 76 101 59 W Av. 7 varieties grown enure period, 39.8 1.74 8 g 9- 6a 9 g 0 7 ? 6 101 gg S3Sf «wT"7i : 38^2 1222 855 62 86 73 97 56 r «™«Sr ■■■■"■ Z 41.6 1331 932 68 94 80 106 61 " JtoAton 42.6 1363 954 69 96 81 108 63 g Corn-after small grain: 50 m m Substation White r " (1 ~ -q Sorghum-after potatoes and corn: 06 g gg m 7( . W Average 3 varieties - i221 89 123 104 13g 80 Feterita ■— ■ _ . . .. _ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Cereal Variety Experiments sorghum crop is, however, much less certain than barley and is more expensive to handle. Better-adapted varieties of sorghum will probably bring it into greater prominence as a Nebraska crop. Sorghums and barley are jmore tolerant than other cereals to alkali in the soil. The smut-resistant Markton oats are eight per cent higher in yield than ■ Iowar, a leading Kherson variety] At the best, oats are the least productive of the important cereal crops in western Nebraska. With winter wheat as with barley, practically no gain has been made in yield. Bunt-resistant varieties are being de - veloped. It is probable that it will be possible to develop varieties resistant to both bunt and rusts. It has been demonstrated that increased yields can be secured from hybrid corn, but this work is still entirely ex - perimental so far as dry-land conditions are concerned. [4M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>