<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Soybeans in Nebaska</title>
               <date value="18??">1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Bulletin 322 OCTOBER 1939 SOYBEANS In Nebraska T.A.KIESSELBACH ' "vndL W.E. LYNESS :^ )epartment of Agronomy (^riKl Bl^fJK^fl INI B^M:i -jSil^9J*! THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA CaLEGE aACRiCULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. WW BURR, DIRECTOR </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Description a History and Economic Importance 4 Utilization c Adaptation in Nebraska 7 Yields in Other Corn Bell States JO Place in Rotation 22 Varieties j2 Seedbed Preparation ja Seed Inoculation j3 Manner of Planting j4 Time of Planting j4 Rate of Planting j5 Tillage jj Harvest jj Threshing and Storage jg Market Price Time Schedule of Field Operations _ (g </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Soybeans in Nebraska T. A. KIESSELBACH and W. E. LYNESS Department o£ Agronomy TIT IS THE PURPOSE of this bulletin to present information regarding -"- the characteristics, utilization, adaptation, and production of soybeans as applied to Nebraska conditions. The recent increases in acreage of soybeans grown in other Corn Belt states and the greater industrial utiliza - tion, of the threshed beans have stimulated considerable interest in their possibilities in this state. DESCRIPTION Plant characters.'—Since many Nebraska farmers have had no experi - ence with soybeans, a brief description may be of interest. •'¦¦¦ The soybean plant is ah annual, bushy; legume, varying in height under normal conditions from lA to 4 feet. The stem usually has five or six main branches, upon which are borne the leaves and clusters of seed pods. The pods are. small, resembling somewhat those of an ordinary garden pea. They contain from 2 to 4 seeds which differ greatly in color in different varieties. The yellow color is preferred for processing. All the seeds on a plant mature at practically the same time. : The soybean plant has a branching root system which, in common with the roots of other legumes, bears nodules when the proper symbiotic bacteria are present in the soil. It is commonly accepted that, under conditions of favorable inoculation, these bacteria are capable of extract - ing about two-thirds of the needed nitrogen directly from the air while one-third is taken from the soil reserve. 1 Since the roots have been found to comprise only one-tenth of the plant substance, removal of the entire crop from the land results in a diminution of total soil nitrogen. 2 Soy - beans harvested for grain therefore have come to be.regarded as soil - depleting by the U. S. Department of Agriculture in connection with soil conservation compliance payments to farmers. Composition.—Soybeans are prized for the high protein content of theiij forage and the high protein and oil content of the matured beans. Their composition, compared with other forage and grain crops, is shown in Table 1. The composition of the cured forage is very similar to that of alfalfa and red clover hay, all of which greatly surpass such carbohydrate forage as prairie hay and sorghum in their protein content. The grain of soybeans contains approximately three times as much protein and four times as much fat as oats. Since the meal remaining after oil extraction is a superior protein concentrate for livestock feeding, its composition compared with that of other protein concentrates is also given in Table 1. ; 1 P. E. Brown and J. H. Stalling*, Inoculated legumes at nitrogenous fertilizers, Soil Science 12:365 - -•M7, 1921. •Ohio Ajr. Eip. Stt. 44th Ann. Rpt., 19M-M. ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 Table I.— Composition of soybeans and other grains, forage, and certain by-products. P.ci. P.ct. P.cl. P.ci. Pjct. P.ct. CHAIN Soybeans . .. . 90.2 36.9 17.2 4.5 26.3 5.3 Corn 88.5 9.7 4.0 2.3 71.1 1.4 Wheat 89.6 13.5 2.1 2.4 69.8 1.8 Oats 91.1 12.0 4.7 10.6 60.2 3.6 Barley 90.4 11.8 2.0 5.7 68.0 2.9 Kafir . 88.6 11.2 3.0 2.3 70.3 1.7 FORAGE Soybean hay 90.8 14.8 3.3 28.4 37.0 7.3 Alfalfa hay . 90.4 14.7 2.0 29.0 36.4 8.3 Red clover hay 88.2 11.8 2.6 27.3 40.1 6.4 Prairie hay 90.4 5.7 2.4 30.3 44.4 7.6 Sorghum fodder 89.2 6.4 2.5 25.8 47.3 7.2 BY-PRODUCTS Soybean meal 91.7 44.3 5.7 5.6 30.3 5.7 Cottonseed meal 93.5 43.2 7.2 10.6 27.0 5.5 Linseed meal 91.3 35.2 6.3 8.0 36.3 5.5 Wheat shorts ...... 90.1 17.9 4.5 5.6 57.8 4.1 Wheat bran 90.6 15.8 5.0 9.5 54.3 6.0 Data compiled from F. B. Morrison, Fccdi and Feeding, The Morrison Publishing Company, Ithaca, N. V., 1936. HISTORY AND ECONOMIC IMPORTANCE Soybeans are used as human food, livestock feed, and in numerous industrial products. While they have been the most important legume in Asiatic countries for many centuries, their extensive production in the United States is of rather recent date. Their first mention in American literature was in 1804. Extensive introductions by the United States Department of Agriculture date back to 1898. The crop has been tested by the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station since 1902, and there is a continuous yield record beginning with 1909. Although seed of adapted varieties has been available, soybeans have never been of import - ance in this state, the maximum production in any year prior to 1939 being estimated at 7,000 acres grown chiefly for forage. The acreage in the United States grew rather gradually between 1900 and 1925 and was largely devoted to livestock feed in these earlier years. It has been estimated that previous to 1917 less than 500,000 acres were grown. By 1924 the acreage had expanded to 1,782,000 acres, while in 1937 the production reached 6,982,000 acres. The annual acreages and their utilization as hay, pasture, and grain together with the average yield of grain per acre are given in Table 2 as summarized by the United States Department of Agriculture. 3 IE. W. Grove. Soybeans in the United Stales; recent trends and prcscJU economic Status. U. 5J&gt;. A. Tcth. Bui. 619. 193*. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">'¦¦'.. Soybeans in Nebraska ¦ UTILIZATION In 1937, two-thirds of the soybean acreage grown in the United States was used as forage and one-third as grain. Data available for 1936 indicate that 68 per cent of the beans were crushed for oil extraction, the rest beingjused on the farm for feed or seed. Since 90 per cent of the meal is fed to livestock, it is readily seen that fully 90 per cent of the yield from all soybean acreage is consumed as feed oh farms. 8 The major uses made of the oil and meal as well as the forage and whole beans are indicated in the oi line 4 (page 6) prepared by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. If able 2.— Soybean production in the United States, 1924-1937, ,* Acreage- . '. : Yield o£ Year ; I Harvested Grazed or Harvested &gt;^ &amp;****» I I'otal I forhay hogged off forbcans I*racre Acres Acres Acres . Acres Bu. Bu. 1924...... 1,782,000 ' 1,147,000 187,000 448,000 U.O 4,947,000 1925...... 1,785,000 1.175,000 195,000 415,000 11.7 4,875,000 1926...... 2,127,000 1,431,000 230,000 . 466,000 11.2 5,239,000 1927...... 2,350,000 1,556,000 226,000 568,000 12.2 6,938,000 1928. 2,439,000 1,609,000 251,000 579,000 13.6 7,880,000 1929...... 2,736,000 1,742,000 286,000 708,000 13.3 9,398,000 1930 3,387,000 2,021,000 358,000 1,008,000 13.4 13,471,000 1931.: .... 4,194,000 2,700,000 390,000 1,104,000 15.2 . 16,733,000 1932...... 4,049,000 2,675,000 397,000 977,000 15.3 14,975,000 1933...... 3,777,000 2,443,000 337,000 997,000 13.2 13,147,000 1934 5,994,000 4,069,000 386,000 1,539,000 15.0 23,095,000 1935:..... 7,111,000 4,000,000 414,000 2,697,000 16.5 44,378,000 • 1936..... 6,646,000 3,251,000 1,263,000 2,132,000 14.1 29,983,000 1937.,..:. 6,982,000 3,659,000 986,000 2,337,000 17.5 40,997,000 1 From U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 619. ~~~ ~ Hay.—When properly harvested and cured, the hay compares favorably with that of alfalfa and red clover except that there may be some waste due to coarse stems. Several days' more time is required for curing the hay because of the-coarser stems. Where alfalfa and red clover thrive, these crops are decidedly preferable for forage. In case of a deficient acreage of th:se, however, soybeans may be grown as a substitute or emergency crop, | producing a fair yield the same year as planted. Grain.—A ton of mature; beans, or 33% bushels, containing 19 per cent oil, will yield approximately 250 pounds of oil and ,1600 pounds of mealfby the expression method. The remaining 150 pounds is lost as moisture and waste in milling. After the oil has been extracted for industrial use, the resultant meal is a very valuable high-protein feed concentrate, suitable as part of the rations for all kinds of livestock. It may jbe substituted for all or part of the cottonseed meal or linseed meal of these rations. : : Moderate quantities of ground beans with their entire oil content are suitable in cattle and poultry rations. Feeding such ground whole beans *WJ. I. Morse and J. L. Canter, Improvement in loybeani, U. S. D. A. Yearbook, 1937. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 SOYBEAN UTILIZATION PI11" f Fuel. fur- Forage i f ura |, hay. Green manure I s ,i a(!c , sm i age Pasture [Cattle Bean ('Celluloid substitutes Dnj;s Core binder Fish Feeds ¦ Hogs Fertilizer Poultry Mea l Glue Rabbits [.Sheep C Beer brewing Humanfood I Flour (See Dried bean) \ Seasoning powders Plastics Soy sauce I Water paints '-Vegetable milk i' Candles Celluloid (&gt;ire oil I hsinfcctant Klcctrical insulation r Butter substitutes F-namc!s Cooking oils Food products J t^rj su b st itutes .1 ¦ Salad oils rCandies 011 Cocoa , -"¦"mn jEmulsificr 1 Margarine ln""'u'n Medicines cSr [Textile dyein S Painis Pnntin); ink Rubber substitutes /"Hard !^ oapS, j Liquid / WatcrprtMf for cement Waterproof goods dreen bean. . | Canned or frosted [^Green vegetable and salad 'Baked ("Baked products Boiled Breakfast foods Breakfast foods r Cattle, Candies F«d.&lt; J hogs, poultry, Chocolate I sheep Diabetic foods Flour J Health drinks f Candied Ice-cream cones Roasted I Coffee Ice-cream powder Dried bean .J f TPainu | substitute Infant foods Soy sauce Ca e j n J Paper size Macaroni products Sprouts Condensed! Textile dressing LMeatproducts,filler Vegetable I Fw)di [ Waterproofing mllk j Powder f Canned Dried Curd J Fermented I Fresh L I Smoked </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Soybeans in Nebraska to hog, is very objectionable as it results in soft por\. It is especially stressed by the Animal Husbandry Department of the Nebraska College of Agriculture that this state now has an enviable reputation for its fine quality of hard hogs. Should increased production of soybeans in Nebraska result in the feeding of beans with their full oil content and in an appreci - able percentage of soft hogs going to market, all hogs in the state will be discounted, incurring serious financial losses. There is no way of dis - tinguishing a soft hog on foot. It is only after slaughtering that this be - comes apparent. ./':¦ ' ,j Certain varieties are desirable and palatable as a green vegetable for table use, much as are the green pea and lima bean. In this state they may be ready for such use early in September. For the human diet, the mature beans are largely used in this country in the form of oil and meal. These enter into many different manufactured food products as previo lsly indicated. : ;.'. ADAPTATION IN NEBRASKA . Soybeans have proved relatively well adapted to the soil and climatic conditions of eastern Nebraska or that region included rather arbitrarily east of Madison and York counties. Attractive yields have sometimes been obtained farther west, but experience with the crop has been too limited there to justify its recommendation. The Experiment Station has made occasional seed distributions for limited testing throughout eastern Nebr: ska during the past 35 years. Although these farm trials have failed to bri lg about a large acreage, this has not been due to inadaptation of the crop but rather to the fact that alfalfa and clover have proved superior for forage production and threshed-bean prices.have been inadequate to attract production. This situation is common to eastern Nebraska.and western lowai In eastern Towa and in other more eastern states where soybeans are extensively grown, lime applied to the soil is commonly required for the successful production of alfalfa and clover, whereas soybeans thrive relatively well without liming. ' ..•..-.¦ 7 .¦"..¦ ...Soybeans leave the surface soil in a rather loose condition, subject to excessive water erosion on rolling and hilly land. For this reason their production should be limited to fairly level land. . While soybeans are relatively free from- harmful diseases, they are highly subject to damage by grasshoppers and rabbits. During recent years they have been damaged fully as much by grasshoppers as has corn on the Experiment Station farm. Rabbits have frequently destroyed small, isolated acreages. Loss from this source should be comparatively small in large fields and in communities where the crop is extensively grown. Varietal test plots on farms should be planted as part ot a larger soybean fieldjin order to avoid serious damage from rabbits. Soybeans are highly resistant to chinch bugs. , '&#132; . ¦ Grain yields of soybeans and standard cereal crops.—The adaptation and (productivity can perhaps be judged best by comparing the grain yields of soybeans with those from standard cereal crops on the Experiment </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 Table 3.— Annual gram yields of soybeans and other crops, maximum and mean temperature during the four months, June to September, and annual precipitation October 1 to September 30, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, at Lincoln, SO years, 1909-1938. 1 Temperature, 4 months, Prccipi- Yields of grain per acre y ear June-Sept. ati°" ** I^P-io'Corn &amp; Q 3ts hHg Kafir °F °F In. Bit. Bit. Bit. Bit. Bit. Bit. Bit. 1909 &#132; 103 73 26.7 41 9 67 27 18 1910 106 73 -10.7 58 20 42 48 30 1911 110 76 22.6 43 15 38 51 16 1912 . . 104 71 23.2 48 13 37 9 14 1913 109 76 22.2 8 8 45 50 17 1914 103 75 43.5 53 17 68 34 17 1915 96 68 36.1 75 13 33 30 16 1916 101 73 25.5 62 21 85 38 22 1917 106 72 23.3 47 26 69 32 30 1918 ... 109 74 15.4 3 12 14 19 8 1919 103 75 34.5 21 33 44 26 4 1920 . 99 73 26.9 54 23 54 41 18 1921 103 76 27.5 65 17 66 37 20 1922 ... 106 75 21.7 47 11 31 31 11 1923 98 73 31.9 61 19 66 24 22 1924 101 71 18.7 39 12 43 34 12 20 43 1925 103 75 27.2 38 13 27 15 7 14 32 1926 105 73 22.9 3 U 12 14 2 4 2 1927 . 100 71 26.1 66 7 45 37 14 53 9 1928 101 71 21.6 38 12 44 24 14 56 41 1929 104 72 25.0 55 17 62 34 16 53 56 1930 108 75 22.3 9 24 71 43 22 48 49 1931 105 77 28.9 30 18 56 45 26 42 57 1932 101 74 33.2 47 30 61 29 22 41 63 1933 108 76 26.6 38 25 3 24 3 3 46 1934 112 77 15.0 0 8 0 22 0 0 0 1935 106 75 25.6 7 12 31 8 16 18 13 1936 115 80 17.4 0 1 18 31 8 5 0 1937 106 77 17.9 5 2 36 15 11 23 22 1938 105 76 28.3 4 6 55 17 14 42 29 Average 104.5 74.1 25.9 35.5 15.2 44.1 29.6 15.0 .. 1 The yields arc for standard, adapted varieties grown throughout the 30 yean at follows: Hogue Yellow Dem corn to 1933 and Krug thereafter, Habaro soybeans ro 1923 and Akjarbcn thereafter, Kherson oati. Turkey winter wheat. Early |ava spring wheat, Trebi barley, and Pink kalir to 1934 and Kato thereafter. The temperature and precipitation data are compiled from annual records of the Nebraska Section of the U. S. Weather Bureau. Station farm at Lincoln during the last 30 years. Such data together with the annual rainfall and mean and maximum temperature during the growing season of June, July, August, and September, are given in Table 3 and are summarized by five-year periods in Table 4. Combinations of excessively high temperature and low precipitation are seen to be especially unfavorable for soybeans and other crops. During this period of 30 years, </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Soybeans in Nebraska Table 4.— Summary by 5-year periods of annual yields of soybeans and other crops, maximum and mean temperatures during the four months, ]Une to September, and annual precipitation October 1 to September 30, .Nebraska Agricultural^ Experiment Station, 30 years, 1909-1938—com - piled from Table 3. Temperature, ... 4 months, Precipi- Yields o£ grain pet acre Ycf rs June-Sept. qrio" '- - averaged —; —: ~ Oct. 1 to —. —: —; : r~ ~~ ~ r Maxi- sept. 30 Soy- Winter Spring I mum Mean ¦ ¦¦.. Corn beam Oats | wheat I wheat Barley Kafir . ! 'F "F .In. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bit. Bu. Bu. j ¦;." FIVE-YEAR PERIODS 1909-13.... 106.4 73.8 27.1 39.6 13.0 45.8 37.0 19.0 ... ... 191448...: 103.0 72.4 28.8 48.0,17.8 53.8 30.6 18.6 ... ... 1919-23 101.8 74.4 28.5 49.6 20.6 52.2 31.8 15.0 ... ... 1924-28.... 102.0 72.2 23.3 36.8. 11.0 34.2 24.8 9.8 29.4 25.4 1929-33.... 105.2 '74.8 27.2 35.8 22.8 50.6 35.0 17.8 37.4 54.2 1934 38.... 108.8 77.0 20.8 3.2 5.8 28.0 18.6 9.8 17.6 12.8 ¦ ' . FIFTEEN- AND THIRTY-YEAR PERIODS . . . 1909 23..,. 103.7 73.5 28.1 45.7 17.1 50.6 33.1 17.5 ...... 1924138.... 1053 74.7 23.8 25.3 13.2 37.6 26.1 12.5 28.1 30.8 1909138.... 104.5 74.1 25.9 35.5 15.2 44.1 29.6 15.0 ... ... there have been complete or nearly complete failures of all grain crops in one or more years. Soybeans have ranged in annual yield from 1 to 33 bushels per acre, compared with 0 to 83 bushels tor oats, 0 to 75 bushels for corn, 8 to 51 bushels for winter wheat, and 0 to 30 bushels for spring wheat. The annual rainfall figured from October 1 of the previous year to September 30 of the current year has varied from 15 inches to 435 inches and the mean seasonal temperature during June 1 to September 30 from 68° F. to 80° F., while the maximum seasonal temperature varied from 96° F. to 115° F. ; f !a.s an average for 30 years, the yields of corn, soybeans, oats, and winter wheat were 35.5, 15.2, 44.1, and 29.6 bushels per acre, respectively. Spring wheat produced an average of 15.0 bushels. The comparative yields of barley and grain sorghum are also shown as averages for the last 15 years. The data in these crop comparisons are all taken from standard varieties as indicated in the footnote to Table 3. It is of interest to note that during the last 15 years in which there were 11 crop years of "sub - normal" rainfall, soybeans averaged only 2 bushels less yield per acre than the! 30-year average, while oats, corn, and winter wheat averaged 65, 102, and 35 bushels less, respectively. . ' From die standpoint of crop diversification there is an advantage in choice of crops which do not respond the same from year to year to seasonal variations. In general, yields of soybeans are not found to have fluctuated very closely with those of other standard crops during these </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 30 years. They yielded relatively high in some years when other crops were low." Forage yields oi soybeans, alfalfa, and sorghum.— The suitability of soybeans as a hay crop in eastern Nebraska may be judged by a comparison of their yield with that of alfalfa and sorgo (Table 5) on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln during 11 years. The soybean and sorgo yields are for standard varieties grown in cultivated rows in the varietal tests, while the alfalfa yields are for the Common variety grown in solid-drilled test plots. As an average for the 11 years, the cured forage yields cal - culated on a 15 per cent moisture content basis were: soybeans, 1.32 tons; alfalfa, 2.23 tons; and sorgo, 4.63 tons. Considering annual variations, the range in forage yields of soybeans was approximately % to 2% tons per acre; alfalfa, % to 3% tons; and sorghum, l'/i to 8 tons per acre. Table s.—Cured jorage yields (15% moisture) per acre from soybeans, alfalfa, and sorgo during 11 years on the Agricultural Experiment Station farm at Lincoln. Vl ., r i Soybeans 2 Alfalfa » ,*°? S°* - (Aksarhcn) (Common) tlas a, n&lt;J Orange) Tons Tons Tons '"; 2 1.63 2.59 -1.53 i l;.' 1-77 3.03 5.28 '" 1-U 2.23 4.50 1 '&lt;&lt;&gt; 0.88 0 79 3 15 mo 1.75 3.H9 6.95 )' J*&gt; 2.20 3.35 4.57 \°\l 2.66 3.13 8.13 I'll 0.97 1.70 4.86 ml 0.25 1.44 1.28 m' 0.37 1.34 3.17 IWN 0.87 1.00 4.55 ¦ t&gt;&lt;rjj;i- lot U y.ars 1.32 22i 4.6 i ' So so) bean hay yields were determined for llic yean omitted Sojbcan yields arc from cultivated rows spaced 35 inches. ( Alfalfa yields arc taken from meadows differing in a s e Ouncc'soVo't'ev.ou'.ly 0' ""S° gr°"" '" CUlliVattd rOWS ''"« I9M. &gt;"* '« lolid-drilled YIELDS IN OTHER CORN BELT STATES The yields of threshed beans per acre obtained by farmers in other Com Belt states are of interest to Nebraska farmers by way of suggesting possibilities with this crop. The data in Table 6, compiled from U. S. Department of Agriculture statistics, show the total bushels of beans pro - ducedjmd the acre yield in 1938 and the mean average yield per acre dur - eoefl.llent/'bleJw '"f^"' 1"" n&lt;"«»&lt;\°" i» V^ '• expressed statistically by the rather lour corrthlion coefficients between the annual yields of soybeans and the annual yields of oau corn and winter wheat as follow,: Soybean and corn yields 0.369 + .106, soybean ,l&lt; l oa. yields' OJ97+ 103T and soybean and winter wheat yields 0.259+.115. The correlation 3 o™B3 + ~OM b^Sri' nZnee 1":! yieW """"' """"""^ » ""*"«»* " '-dictt .ha.-rainfall 'has " rSS </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Soybeans in Nebraska ing thb 14-year period, 1924-1937, in the five leading Corn Belt states. The year 1J938 was unusually favorable for soybeans in all these states. As; an average for the 14 years, the yield in Illinois has been 16.2 bushels; Indiana, 14.4 bushels; lowa, 15.2 bushels; Ohio, 15.7 bushels; and Missouri, 7.9 bushels per acre. In the state of Kansas with only a small acreage, the reported farm yield has averaged 8.5 bushels. No corresponding yields are-available for Nebraska farms because practically no beans have been grown or harvested. The 30-year average record of 15.2 bushels per acre on the Agricultural Experiment Station farm at Lincoln, however, compares favorably with the above yields from other states. Since there has been a gradual improvement of varieties it seems probable that these yields would all; have been approximately 10 per cent higher had improved varieties been grown throughout. Table 6.— Soybean yields on farms in other Corn Belt states in 1938, and also the average yields, during 14 years, 1924-1937. [ ' &gt;8 producuonl- J^ C 2 f tate .T, . Harvested Beans Yield vJ-S' . ;.,. ¦ Total forbear.* threshed peracrc 19240937 Acres Acres .':' 811. ,Bu. Bu. Illinois 2,118,000 1,356,000 31,866,000 " 23.5 . 16.2 Indiana ....... 828,000 431,000 8,404,000 19.5 14.4 lowa ......... 950,000 294,000 5,733,000 19.5 15.2 Ohio ....:..., 445,000 253,000 5,313,000 21.0 15.7 Missouri ........ 320,000 :. 58,000 609,000 . 10.5 • 7.9 *U S. D. A. Crops and Markets Report, December, 1938. . '; ¦' U S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 619. ¦:*•». V PLACE IN THE ROTATION Crop sequence.—The growing period of standard.!full-season varieties of soybeans grown in east-central Nebraska is approximately May 25 to October 1. Thus it would be possible to grow them j following any crop of the previous year. Likewise, any spring-sown crop may follow the soy - beans. Unless an exceptionally early variety of soybeans is grown, they cannot be relied upon to ripen in time for the seeding of winter wheat. A very early variety such as the Ito San, also known as the Early Yellow, ripening at Lincoln about September 15, may be followed by winter wheat, which need not be planted till October 1 in this region. Since the bean plants have lost most of their leaves and require very little soil moist - ure the last two weeks, this, provides practically three weeks for the ac - cumulation of soil moisture and development of soil nitrates before the wheat need be planted. Unfortunately such early-ripening varieties arc so small and early that they lack the capacity to give a maximum yield per acre. For example, the Ito San yielded 6.7 bushels less per acre at the Experiment Station during a six-year period than did the Illini variety which ripens about 12 days later. Under these conditions the use of such an early variety seems impracticable. . . ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p012">AcRtCULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 322 Crop rotation value. —It has come to be generally recognized that soy - beans have materially less soil-improvement value than do alfalfa, sweet clover, and red clover when grown in the rotation. Alfalfa and the clovers leave the soil higher in available nitrogen supply. Accordingly they have a greater beneficial effect on succeeding crops in years of favorable rainfall and under irrigation. On the other hand, in years of severe moisture - deficiency, crops suffer less from overstimulation following soybeans. Soy - beans are rated as a soil-depleting crop by the U. S. D. A. Soil Conserva - tion Service. 0 VARIETIES It is just as important to select varieties of soybeans according to their characteristics as it is with corn. The varieties differ as to vegetative size and time of ripening, shatter resistance, yield of grain and forage per acre, color of grain, oil content, and lodge resistance. Varieties which require nearly the full growing season are likely to yield most, but care must be taken to avoid those which are apt to be injured by a killing frost before the beans are well matured and sufficiently dry. Beans which are frozen in a green, immature condition are inferior in market value. Well matured, yellow beans of high oil content are in greatest demand. Varietal tests have been made at the Agricultural Experiment Station for many years. The (J. S. Department of Agriculture has assisted with the tests by suggesting varieties and often supplying seed. Two of these tests summarized for 10 and 6 years, respectively, are reported in Tables 7 and 8. Miscellaneous varieties were tested during the period 1925 to 1929 and are not reported in the tables. Considering performance in these tests and in other Corn Belt states die commercial varieties recommended for east - central Nebraska, in the order of preference, are Illini, Dunfield, and Manchu. These are all medium-late, shatter-resistant, productive, yellow, high-oil beans, and are also suitable for forage production. There are two types of the Manchu, differing about two weeks in time of ripening. While die Illini variety has surpassed other varieties by two or more bushels per acre on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln during six years, its northern limit of adaptation has not been determined. The Dunfield variety ripens about five days earlier and may be more suit - able for grain in counties north of Burt. The Ito San (Early Yellow) variety is so much earlier that it may be grown with safety in central Nebraska. The yield of this variety, however, has been so low in Station tests at Lincoln that it is not recommended for eastern Nebraska. Uniform cooperative tests are being conducted on farms in eastern Nebras - ka for the purpose of determining varietal superiority and limit of adapta - tion. The varieties represent a wide range of type and the 1939 tests con - sist of the Manchu, Illini, Mingo, Dunfield, Richland, Habaro, and Minsoy, listed in order from the latest to the earliest ripening. 1938 A ' Pi"c"' Soil-deploing, loiUomcrving, and ioil-building cropi. U. S. D. A. Leaflet No. 165, </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Soybeans in Nebraska Table 7. — Variety test of soybeans, Lincoln, Nebraska — average for 10 I years, 1915-1924. ¦ _¦./ . S.P.I. Date Days to Seed Bushels Origin or variety No lipc mawtity color tiCK Harbili, Manchuria, 1914. ...... 28050 Sept.26 115 Yellow 18.9 Habaro ......Y ....'. Sept.23 115 Yellow 18.6 Aksarfcn ..................... .36576 Sepr.23 112 Yellow 18.4 Shanangchcngpu, Manchuria, 1911 30600 Sept.2s 114 Yellow 17.8 Harbin, Manchuria, 1910 28050 Sepr.23 112 Yellow 17.1 Tsitsitar, Manchuria, 1913..... 36914 Scpr.23 112 Yellow 16.8 . Ito San. Scpt.l6' 105 Yellow 15.8 Pchtaiinlintza,N.Manchuria, 1913 36653 Sept.23 112 Yellow 14.6 Average planting date, June 3. ';¦ ¦ ' . ' . .¦' - . .: . ¦'• |TableB.— Variety test of soybeans, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1930-1938. Yield ot beans per acre (bushels) . j^ V- Vati| ty 1930; | 1931 | 1932 I 1933 | 1934 | 1935 | 1938. |^^ rfpe' Ulinil.'- 29.6 22.3 34.7 25.8 8.1 12J 7.5 22.1 Oetl Manchu 31.2 18.9 29.2 24.9 7.2 9.9 ... 20.2 Oct. 1 Aksatben 23.6 17.6 30.4 25.3 7.7 11.8 6.2 19.4 Oct. 1 Virginia 24.3 12.3. 24.8 17.3 6.1 7.4 4.2 15.4 ; Oct 10 Midwest 26.9 10.5 22.r 14.6 5.1 : 4.2 ... 13.9 Oct. 14 ltoS[in 20.8 18.3 21.9 17.0 6.1 S3 ... 15.4 Sept. 18 Average planting date, June 2. : ¦ . . • ¦ The variety tens in 1936 and 1937 were complete failures because of drouth and grasshoppers. The Dunrlcld and Cayuga varieties, tested also in 1935 and 1935, yielded 2.7 and 6.1 bushels ieu per acre, respectively, than lllini as an average for the two years. The seed color.of the varieties in this test is yellow except Virginia (brawn) and Cayuga (black). SEEDBED PREPARATION ¦ ' iarly-spring seedbed preparation, designed to conserve moisture and to destroy several crops of weeds in the seedling stage before planting the beans, is highly important for successful soybean production. Since planting is seldom done before May 25, there is a period of four to six weeks for this seedbed preparation. A satisfactory procedure is to double-disk cornstalk land about April 10, followed by plowing and harrowing May 1, harrowing again May 15, and double-disking May 25 just before planting. ': ' . : SEED INOCULATION When soybeans are grown on land for the first time it is important to inoculate, the seed with the necessary bacteria before planting. This may be done through the use of pure commercial cultures of the bacteria orlby application of soil from an inoculated field where beans were successfully grown the previous year. The pure cultures are applied directly to the seed in accordance with accompanying directions. They may be purchased from seed companies. "...;¦ : </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 Soil taken from near the roots of well inoculated plants of the pre - ceding year may be applied to the seed as a mixture with water having the consistency of thick cream. About 3 pints of soil are required per bushel of beans. The beans are sprinkled with the mixture and stirred with a shovel until all of the seeds are thoroughly soiled. This is a satisfactory and economical method. Other practices for applying the inoculated soil may be used. On land that has recently grown a crop of well inoculated soybeans, artificial inoculation is not necessary. MANNER OF PLANTING c Drilling.—Soybeans may be grown either in cultivated rows or drilled like small grain. While solid drilling is a kss expensive procedure from the standpoint of tillage, it is also less successful under the conditions ot eastern Nebraska (Table 9). Weeds have almost invariably Table 9-—Comparative grain yields proved more bothersome and have fro ".' soyj&gt;e&lt;"is drilled with a curtailed both grain and forage s™'n dr'^ and planted in eul - yields. The saving in cost or cultiva- """ted rows spaced various dis - tion is practically offset by the tances apart- 1 greater cost of seed, as approxi- D|iilcll Cultivated rows mateh 1 one bushel more seed per .. 7 ; acre is required for the solid drill- C" inches . ¦*? .4? • T ' inches inches inches Cultivated rows.-Growing soy- mi B", f"' B"' B"' beans in cultivated rows has proved 1923 '^ liv) 216 178 172 most satisfactory at the Experiment 1024 3^4 6.6 7$ 5.7 Station. These rows may be spaced m 5 15-4 32.0 31.7 36^0 any distance suitable for inter-tillage \l\\ "¦* '"5 « 8.6 up to 42 inches without materially 1931^"' 33 8 7 affecting yields of grain. Thirty-five- 1932....'. 21.7 ... 29.2 inch spacing is regarded as very 1933 u-9 ¦¦¦ 24.9 '.'.'. practical. Such planting can be done J9JS 9 g -\ ¦ 72 •¦• with the ordinary corn planter 1938:.:: w.l 12.3 107 112 fitted with bean plates or with a — gram drill after proper adjustments £?/!£, g 155 |" &gt;« and calibration. If the grain drill is ' I6A •" used part of the feeds should be J.A^ n ™'f^ closed to give proper spacing of the drlllln B W3! =i ih= 'm of 95 pounds. Zmnf^^f °n beet and bean dril[s are also suitable- Listing is not Furrrinene °f " C°Vered in Cul'ivatJon - factory °" P Md alsO lu"OW drills hare P™"ed saris- TIME OF PLANTING </seg>
         <seg id="p015">, Soybeans in Nebraska . June 5 since this provides better opportunity for previous destruction of weeds with the harrow or disk. Late planting should be avoided if the crop is to be grown for grain, as the most desirable varieties require the entire season to mature. While early planting results in earlier ripening, the difference in time of maturity will not be so great as the difference in time of planting. Under no circumstances should planting be done later than June 15 for grain, and not much later for forage. . ; - RATE OF PLANTING When grown in cultivated rows, from 30 to 40 pounds of seed should be planted per acre, the amount varying with seed size of the different varieties. These fates space the seed about I'/z to 2 inches apart in rows spaced 36 inches. It is not important that the seed be dropped equidistant but jrather that the desired number of beans be dropped per foot of row. The amount of seed should be increased to approximately 90 pounds per acre when drilled solid with a grain drill. This increase in amount of seed provides better competition for control of weeds since cultivation cannot be continued until the plants bloom. ' .¦¦¦/'•. -';. -"'¦;: . --..';¦¦-¦¦¦' TILLAGE ' " '•',¦ ".:¦'. The need for thorough tillage to control weeds prior to planting has been stated. Even though planted on land that has just been cultivated it will often prove advisable to harrow again before the beans are up. Such tillage is especially important in case the surface soil has crusted. Further weed control may usually be accomplished effectively and at least expense with a rotary hoe, spike-tooth harrow, or spring-tooth weeder up to a 6-inch growth. If weed seedlings have become established, the spike-tooth har - row is most effective in this early weed destruction/The rotary hoe does the least injury to the soybean plants but should be tractor drawn at a fairly rapid speed to destroy weed seedlings successfully. Harrowing is preferably done diagonally to the rows. After growth is too large to per - mit harrowing, two or three cultivations with a shovel cultivator are needed. Cultivation should be discontinued before the plants start bloom - ing. Most ordinary corn cultivators can be adjusted to any row spacing between 35 and 42 inches. The sugar-beet cultivator gives good results when soybeans are planted in closely spaced rows/ Level cultivation .leaves the land in best condition for harvest; . . '. "¦ . HARVEST Hay. — Soybeans give the highest yield of good-quality hay if harvested when the seeds are about half developed and three to four weeks before fully ripe. This is.before the leaves begin to fall and before the stems have lost their palatability by becoming harsh and woody. More of the coarse parts of sterns are refused by stock as maturity is approached. The crop is commonly cut for hay with the ordinary mower. A combination of swath curing for a day or two until well wilted, and cur - ing in the windrow or small shock thereafter until sufficiently dry for </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 322 Seed ( J4 Natural Size) of Six Important Yellow Varieties. The approximate number of beans per pound is indicated for each variety: (1) Manchu, 2510; (2) Illini, 2870; (3) Mingo, 3040; (4) Dunfidd, 2970; (5) Richland, 2660; and (6) Habaro, 2970. stacking or placing in the barn is recommended. The entire process of curing requires about twice as long as for alfalfa or clover but similar methods should be used. Loss of leaves by shattering should be avoided as they comprise about 40 per cent of the dry weight of the entire crop in well made hay. Grain.—As the soybean crop matures, the leaves turn yellow and fall, leaving the stems bare with their clusters of seed pods. At this time the beans are in the hard dough stage and the crop is ready to harvest for grain with either a binder or a mower with side-delivery attachment. It is not practical to harvest earlier with the idea that the straw would be of better quality as feed. Soybeans are handled similarly to other grain when harvested with a binder. The bundles should be tied loosely and set up in small shocks for curing. Growing lodge-resistant varieties facilitates harvest. By permitting the crop to cure thoroughly in the field, the beans may be harvested with a combine. Excessive moisture, as with small grain, results in spoilage in the bin. THRESHING AND STORAGE Soybeans may be threshed with an ordinary threshing machine by reducing the speed of the cylinder and replacing all or part of the con- </seg>
         <seg id="p017">¦¦¦-. V. Soybeans in Nebraska Mature Soybeans Ready for Harvest. caves by blank concaves. The best adjustment of the thresher is by the use of special pulleys which reduce the speed of the cylinder without retard - ing [other motion of the machine. Broken seeds lower the market value of the crop but do not reduce their feed value. The beans should be watched carefully after threshing to detect heating and) molding during storage in the bin. In case of heating, they should be spread out thin to dry. L MARKET PRICE According to E. W. Grove 7 of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, prices are largely dependent upon three important factors—the price of soybean meal, the price of soybean oil, and the demand for soybeans as seed. In turn, the prices for the oil and meal depend primarily upon the supplies and prices of competing products, chief of which are cottonseed and linseed oil and meal. In the earlier years of rapid expansion of soybean acreage in the United States, a larger percentage of the threshed beans was sold as seed and this tended to create a farm price in excess of what it would be when dependent more largely on industrial demand. (Since heretofore there has been no soybean market in this state, the farm price of beans in the neighboring state of lowa 8 compared with that of [other crops, is of interest because of similarity of conditions and proximity. As an average for the five years (1933-1937) the lowa farm TE. W. Grove, V. S. D. A. T«h. Bui. 619. • Pricn arc lummwiud ftom Ihe U. S. Department o£ Agriculture Yearbockj for 1929 to 1935. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">ACRICL'LTL'RAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 322 Table 10.— Approximate time schedule of field operations involved in the growing of soybeans, oats, corn, and winter wheat. Operation | Date Operation | Date SOYBEANS CORN Double disk April 10 Double disk April 15 Plow May 1 List May 15 Harrow May 1 Cultivate May 30 Harrow May 15 Cultivate June 15 Double ilisk May 24 Cultivate July 5 Plant May 25 Husk Oct. 20 Harrow or rotary hoc June 5 Harrow or rotary hoc June 15 WINTER WHEAT Cultivate June 30 plow July 20 Cultivate July 20 Harrow July 20 Harvest Oct 5 Double disk Aug. 20 Double disk Sept. 25 OATS Drill Sept 27 Double disk March 25 Harvest July 5 Drill March 25 Harvest July 5 l-&gt;tr weed lomrol in tuyticani It may he advantageous in some seasons to harrow also before the bons come up, ami tv include an additional cultivation. On the contrary, in exceptionally dry seasons and in relatively weed-free fields, fewer tillage operations may suffice. prices have been: soybeans, $1.00; corn, $0.68; winter wheat, $0.92; and oats, $0.33. Corresponding average prices during the 10 years (1928-1937) were: soybeans, $1.09; CO rn, $0.60; winter wheat, $0.81; and oats, $030. Thus, the average farm price of soybeans has been 56 per cent higher than the average price of wheat, corn, and oats during the five years, and 91 per cent higher during the 10-year period. TIME SCHEDULE OF FIELD OPERATIONS When the growing of a new crop is considered, it is of interest to know how the time of performing the various operations of production fits in with that of other crops that may be grown. Such information is of help in planning the season's farm program. While the dates of certain field work will vary with the season and individual preference, a normal pro - cedure for soybeans, oats, corn, and winter wheat may be outlined as in Table 10. This will also be suggestive of the comparative labor costs which need be considered when evaluating the merits of the various crops. The details of the various operations have been discussed at greater length in other sections of this bulletin. </seg>
         <seg id="p019"/>
         <seg id="p020"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>