<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00077.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION LINCOLN BIENNIAL REPORT 1931-1932 and 1933-1934</title>
               <date value="1934-12-01">1934-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1933-1934 VOLUME 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 961056A ASTOK, IXNOI AND TODEN FOUNDATIONS &gt; 1938 L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS ■'.■■■■'-' i ■ ■ ■ ■ . VOLUME 4 1. Department of Agriculture and Inspection, Biennial Reports, 1931 - 1932, 1933-1934. 2. Board of Agriculture, Annual Reports, 1933, 1934. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION LINCOLN BIENNIAL REPORT 1931 - 1932 and 1933 - 1934 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION D. F. Felton, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p006">(Courtesy C. B. &amp; Q. Ry.) One of the many nice farm homes m Dawes County, near Marsland, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">GOVERNOR CHAS. W. BRYAN </seg>
            <seg id="p008">ii§^ ~ ■ ■ ■ — _ ■' ' ' Btfn i ■ BBtjKb 'I (Courtesy C. N. W. Ry. ) Nebraska State Capitol </seg>
            <seg id="p009">LETTER OP TRANSMITTAL Honorable Charles W. Bryan; Governor Sir : I herewith submit for your consideration and approval, the Biennial Report of the DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION for the period from December 1st, 1930, to December 1st. VXi'2. and from December 1st, 1932, to December 1st. 1934. DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION D. F. Felton, Director. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">TABLE OP CONTENTS FOR BIENNIAL REPORT 1931-1932 1933-1934 Page Letter of Transmittal 5 Table of Contents G General Powers 7 Progress of Nebraska Agriculture, 1931-1934 8-21 Bureau of Animal Industry 22-50 Division of Nursery and Bee Inspection 57-62 Division of Seeds 63-G5 Division of Dairies, Food, Drugs and Oil 6G-77 Division of Eggs and Poultry 78-79 Division of Bread 80 Division of Weights and Measures 81-83 Division of Potato Inspection 84 Division of Beer 85 Financial Statement 86-94 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION GENERAL POWERS Section 1. (7294) Power enumerated. — The Department of Agricul - ture and Inspection shall have power: 1. To encourage and promote, in every practicable manner, the interests of agriculture, including horticulture, the live stock industry, dairying, cheese making, poultry, bee keeping, forestry, fishing, the production of wool, and all other allied industries; 2. To promote methods of conducting these several industries with a view to increasing the production and facilitate the distribution thereof at the least cost; 3. To collect and publish statistics relating to crop production, marketing and farm economics, the production and marketing of beef, pork, poultry, fish, mutton, wool, butter, cheese and other agricultural products so far as such statistical information may be of value to the agricultural and allied interests of the State; to co-operate with the Federal Government in the matter of collecting such statistical informa - tion. Such department shall include in its publications the reports of agricultural, horticultural and like societies, and of live stock associa - tions. Such published statistics shall be the official agricultural statistics of the State; 4. To encourage the planting of trees and shrubs and the improve - ment of farm homes generally; 5. To produce and manufacture biological products to be distributed to live stock producers at the actual cost thereof: 6. To inquire into cause of contagious, infectious and communicable diseases among domestic animals, and the means for the prevention and cure of the same; 7. To take all measures necessary for the preservation, distribu - tion, introduction and restoration of fish, game birds and other wild birds; 8. To see that live stock and stock yards, and other like places where live stock is confined, housed or fed, are properly cared for; 9. To execute and enforce all laws relating to the inspection of foods, drugs, dairy products, oils, commission merchants, cider and vinegar, oleomargarine and butterine, sanitation of premises used for manufacturing and preparation of foods, cold storage ware-houses, paints, seeds, commercial feeding stuffs, live stock remedies, hotels and inns, weights and measures and commercial fertilizers, and from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations a"nd adopt such standards of food products as are necessary and proper to enforce the provisions of this title. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION Many of the duties enumerated above no longer come under this Department for enforcement. The interests of agriculture, including horticulture, cheese making, production of wool, etc., are now carried on by the State Agricultural College. The game and fish laws are en - forced by the Game, Forestation and Parks Commission. Ninety per cent of the work carried on by this Department con - sists of the collection of different fees and taxes and enforcement of laws which have been assigned to this Department for enforcement. Those laws relating to the inspection of foods, oil, drugs and dairy products are the most essential as they affect every individual in the State. New laws passed by the 1031-1033 Legislature and assigned to this Department for enforcement are as follows: Bread Law, Egg and Poul - try Law, Beer Law, Collection of Gas Tax, and House Roll No. 512 relating to special live stock sales which provides for the bonding and licensing of persons conducting the same. NEBRASKA AGRICULTURE. 1931-1934 The quadrennium, 1931-1934, was a period of extremes in weather, crop production, stocks of grain, number of livestock and prices. The depression which began belore the close of 11)29 had reached the low - point in farm commodity prices in the early part of 1933. Before the middle of 1933, farm commodity prices had increased and before the close of 1934, there was a very marked increase in farm commodity prices. Among the outstanding features of the period was the bumper corn crop in 1032; the almost complete failure of crops in 1934; extremely low prices and the marked advance soon aftej* the low point had been reached; the extreme weather characterized ■ by abnormally high tem - peratures, high and continued winds and dust storms; the seven- winter kill of wheat for three out of the four years; the accumulation of stocks of grain and live stock until a very high point was reached and also the reverse with the lowest stocks of grain, hay and numbers of livestock for decades and probably the lowest purchasing power of the farmer's dollar in the history of the state. Last but not least should be men-, tioned the unprecedented Governmental activities to help not only agri - culture, but also other industries, all of which were Hearing the point of collapse. Probably as marked as anything else which characterized this period of time was the rapidity of handling the varied and gigantic Governmental activities which was a great factor in the marked increase in prices of farm and other commodities. Had it not been for the ex - treme drouth covering the greater portion of the nation, the close of 1934 would undoubtedly have brought much better times and consid - erable prosperity throughout the country. Sections of the country that produced average crops or better ai*e now in the best condition they have been for years. Just prior to the near collapse in the economic structure which occurred during the latter months of 1929, prices had reached very high </seg>
            <seg id="p013">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 levels. The sudden and marked drop in prices of farmers' commodities during the latter part of 1929 and through 1930 to 1933 created a tend - ency to hold back not only grain, but also livestock which resulted in an accumulation of large surpluses of most of the farm commodities. As in the past, the farmer's response to low prices was met by an attempt to further increase production until the burdensome supplies had reached such large proportions that prices tumbled, reaching the lowest point for decades. This made it impossible for farmers to pay off indebtedness that had been contracted at a time when farm com - modity prices were several times as high. Taxes which had been in - creased by demands for greater public service when conditions were better, became very burdensome. The slowing down of other industry created a lot of unemployment, which resulted in withdrawing funds from the banks and from other places where the unemployed had reserves, as well as the demand for funds on the part of the farmers to pay interest and taxes, until the financial structure of the country was about to collapse. it was only by prompt and courageous Governmental action that a more or less complete National collapse was avoided. Such were the results of the depression which began in 1929. Among the several causes of the depression, one was the unbal - anced relationship of agriculture to other industries. Before the close of 1920. agriculture was deflated and suffered more severely than other industries. Never at any period of time between 1920 and the beginning of the depression had agriculture received its fair share of the National income. During this entire period there was much talk of farm relief, but very little was done that brought results. Finally, but too late, an attempt was made through the Federal Farm Board to help agricul - ture. Failure to provide lor the control of agricultural production resulted in a most complete failure of the plan and nothing further was done until it appeared that the entire country was facing a catastrophe unless agriculture, as well as other industries was assisted. Since most of the new physical wealth to be created must come from the land, either from the farm, the mine or the forest, it was very plain that about the time that the country's financial structure was about to tumble that it was very essential that agriculture, one of the country's leading basic industries, must again get its share of the National income if conditions were to improve. Agriculture had not only borne the brunt of the depression, but for nearly ten years prior to. the depression it had been at a great disadvantage in that its pur - chasing power had been greatly diminished. Under such a condition, it is really surprising that the depression did not come earlier. It is unfortunate that other industries did not fully appreciate the significance of agriculture in the financial and economic role of the country. Give agriculture a parity price for its commodities and there will be a great demand and potential buying power for the products of other industries. That this demand is essential for the country's economic prosperity has been amply demonstrated by what took place since the agricultural defla - tion in 1920. Had agriculture received a parity price instead of a fractional part since 1T20, it is reasonably safe to assume that the depression might have been partly if not entirely avoided. The lessons learned should be an excellent future guide for the Government in taking neces - sary action if there again occurs such an unbalanced condition between agriculture and other industries. Agriculture can well afford to learn a lesson from other industries in the matter of controlling its production. For decades manufacturing </seg>
            <seg id="p014">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION and other leading basic industries have exercised a certain amount of control over their production. Until recently the farmers have made no special effort to adjust their production. In fact, there has been the tendency to do the opposite thing. Instead of reducing production at a time when prices are low, the farmer made the usual or greater effort to increase his production which simply made a bad situation worse. Unless stgriculture cooperates and adjusts its production to the demand, it can never hope to get the so-called parity price with other industries. Until foreign markets for agricultural commodities are regained, it is absolutely imperative that agriculture adjust its produc - tion if it expects to prosper. While some may contend that prosperity cannot be regained by restricting production, past experience has dem - onstrated that production far in excess of demand can absolutely not bring prosperity. Increased production is desirable only as long as there is an outlet and demand for such increased production and until such outlet is. obtained, agriculture will fare better by adjusting its production to the prospective demand. Early in 1933, the Government began taking action to help agri - culture. The first was the wheat program, that provided a benefit payment, which, added to the market price, gave the farmer the so-called parity price. The parity price is a price that gives a bushel of wheat the same purchasing power of other commodities as it had during the five year pre-war average. The contract covered a three-year period and assured the farmer who signed it a parity price for his wheat. He was required to reduce his acreage 15 per cent below his past base acreage which was determined by the previous three-year average acreage. This program brought approximately §(&gt;.(:00.000 additional money for wheat contract signers in Nebraska for both ]i)33 and 1!).'S4. The next and largest program that followed was the corn-hog deal. This provided for a reduction of 25 per cent of the previous two-year average of all hogs raised and sold. The required reduction ranged from 20 to 30 per cent of the base acreage of corn. The farmer signing the contract was given a benefit payment amounting to $5.00 per head on 75 per cent of two-year average base production. He was allowed thirty cents per bushel on the average yield of corn on land taken out of production. Benefit payments for the year 1934 will exceed $30, - 000,000. This amounts to nearly $3G0 for the average farmer signing the contract, or, in other words, it amounts to $30 a month for a period of twelve months. Another popular and very outstanding action was the corn loan. When corn was^ selling around thirty to thirty-three cents per bushel during the last months of 1933 and early months of 1934, the Govern - ment made arrangements to lend the farmer forty-five cents per bushel on corn stored' in acceptable cribs on the farm. Approximately 41,000 farmers took out corn loans on nearly 53.000,000 bushels of corn. These loans totaled more than $23,000,000. It wasn't long until the market price of corn advanced to the loan price. Before the close of the year 1934 it was more than twice the forty-five cent loan value. This action not only enabled the farmer to take advantage of the marked advance in price, but it kept the corn back on the farm where it was badly needed due to the almost complete failure of corn and other feed grain crops in 1934. Had it not been for this timely action, much of this corn would have been sold at thirty to thirty-five cents per bushel and someone else would have had the benefit of the increased price. Keeping </seg>
            <seg id="p015">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 this corn on the farm has enabled many farmers to save a larger per cent of their cattle and other livestock, which otherwise would have been forced on the market due to the short crops of grain, hay, and forage. Another action which showed much foresight was the Government purchasing of pigs and piggy sows in the autumn of 1933. A total of 438,000 pigs were purchased and nearly 36,000 piggy sows. A total of $2,460,000 was paid for these pigs and sows. This took nearly 615,000 pigs out of production in Nebraska alone. For the country as a whole, it exceeded 6,000,000 head. Had these pigs been saved for market it would undoubtedly have reduced market prices even below the low figure paid. However, that is not all. In Nebraska, this purchase of pigs saved at least 12,000,000 bushels of corn that would have been fed to them for which the farmer would have received something like twenty to thirty cents per bushel when sold in the form of pork. As it was, farmers received from two to five times that amount for corn thus saved. Thousands of farm mortgages were renewed at a much lower rate of interest, thereby saving the farms for the owners. Furthermore, the iGovernment is making! crop production loans, feed loans, farm home and building loans, at a low rate of interest. In addition, the Govern - ment is furnishing relief to farmers on the ten unit livestock plan and in other ways. The PWA projects in Nebraska, by the close of 1934, have exceeded ?30,000,000, a large part of which will be spent in the interest of agriculture through irrigation and power projects. Plans are being made to increase the appropriation for the power and irrigation projects. These irrigation projects will not bring new land into culti - vation, but will simply enable the farmers now holding or operating such land to do so more profitably. Plans are to furnish power at a low rate of cost so that farmers can afford to purchase it. There is prpb - ably nothing else that adds more to the home comforts than electricity. Nebraska has no coal, oil or gas and therefore cheap power is her greatest need. Nebraska is one of the leading states in the production of staple crops, livestock and its products. . Therefore, if cheap power can be furnished, Nebraska can manufacture the surplus of farm products raised within the state into finished merchandise, thereby saving freight, increasing local employment and wealth. Much of the land which could be irrigated by the Tri-county project has lost its virgin fertility and will go backward unless water is supplied, because it is impossible to add manure and build up the soil under the present short supply of rainfall. Adding manure or other organic material to the soil causes the crops to bum up under the present inadequate supply of moisture. Another action taken to help agriculture is the tree shelter belt which will be planted in the western portion of the state. This should offer some employment to farmers. The construction of ponds and dams is also very beneficial in conserving the underground supply of water. Anything that conserves moisture or holds snow or breaks wind or storms is a very useful development. The value of windbreaks was demonstrated during the drouth of 1934 as well as the need for con - servation of the underground supply of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION The Government drouth cattle buying project also saved Nebraska farmers more than $6,000,000 which otherwise would have been a total loss. The Government purchased 470.C00 head and before the close of the year the total is expected to exceed 500,000 head, with the additional allotment for purchase made. Had it not been for the Government purchase of these cattle, the market would have been demoralized and these starved cattle would have been a complete loss to the farmers. Since drouth covered the greater part of the country, it appears that the cattle surplus has been reduced so that the country probably does not have more than enough breeding cattle to supply the demand. Nature has assisted the Government in the task of re - ducing the surplus cattle. Nature's method of reducing surplus has been more drastic to certain states and counties. Individual producers have been forced to reduce more than desirable under methods insti - tuted by the Government which provide for a certain reduction by each individual. With surplus of grain and livestock eliminated, a higher price level should follow in the coming year. The Government has modified its reduction program so as to provide for a reasonable surplus of grain. It is asking for a smaller reduction in corn acreage next year. It permits an unrestricted use of the : corn acreage taken out of produc - tion. Corn benefit payments have been increased to thirty-five cents per bushel. The benefit payments for hogs will amount to $15 per head on ten per cent of the base number. In fact, the conditions are so favorable that the farmer cannot afford to stay out of the program. In the case of the corn deal, he can almost "eat his pic and have it too." That is, he is to be paid thirty-five cents per bushel on the average corn yield for his farm on the acreage taken out of corn production, but at the same time, he can plant this corn land to other grain crops, such as oats or barley, hay or pasture crops. He can use this land in seeding pasture crops which will be a great help because much—of the pasture was killed by the severe drouth in 1X31. The farmer can get benefit payments for corn land taken out and put this into pasture for his livestock, thereby giving his usual pasture a chance to recover. He is allowed $15 per head on ten per cent of his base production of hogs. He can produce 90 per cent of his base num - ber of hogs. Such a fair and liberal program cannot help but solicit the cooperation of farmers. When such cooperation is obtained and production is reduced to meet the demand, the farmers should come more nearly getting parity price and the industry will certainly bring better returns than if it were allowed to drift as in the past. The law of supply and demand is still working as it has in the past. The present outstanding example is the price of corn, which is almost "sky high" because the demand is so heavy and the supply very short. It is reasonable to expect that a controlled production will bring a higher price level. While it is true there will not be as many units of farm commodities for sale, the higher price per unit should bring a larger gross return than a larger quantity would bring at such low prices as were received in the past when there were large surpluses. For example, a thousand bushels of corn sold for about $100 in 1932. If a farmer reduced his production 20 per cent and produced eight hundred bushels and received 25 cents a bushel as a result of the re - duced supply, he would not only get twice as much for his reduced supply, but also save the expense of producing the additional 20 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 When domestic demand increases and our foreign markets are re - gained, increased production will be permitted so that the farmer can again utilize all of his land, but until markets are regained, it is folly to argue against controlled production. During the period of 1931 and 1934, inclusive, there were marked changes of the crop production. Corn ranged from 269,293,000 bushels in 1932, the second or third highest on record, to 13,352,000 bushels in 1934, the lowest since 1875. Spring wheat varied from 830,000 bushels in 1934 to 3,312,000 bushels in 1933. There were two years of moder - ately high production. In the case of winter wheat, three out of four years, crops were less than half of an average crop and one year ap - proximated the average. Oats ranged from almost a failure in 1934 to considerably above the average in 1932. One of the crops was almost a failure, two were below average and one above average. Barley and rye show about the same variations. The potato crop was ex - tremely short in 1934 and the farm crop was also short in 1933. How - ever, the commercial acreage has been increased considerably so that three crops out of the four rate quite satisfactorily. The tame hay crops were extremely short in 1934. Wild hay was short three out of the four years. Total hay production was very short in two out of the four years. As in the case of crops, livestock has also shown a very marked change in numbers. There has been more or less steady increase in milk cows, especially since 1930, when the increase was marked. There has been an increase in other cattle, particularly during the past four years, due to holding cattle off low markets. Cattle numbers, however, were reduced very heavily in 1934 and the close of the year will find the lowest number on hand for years. There has been no heavy marked change in the number of hogs for several years until 1934, when numbers were reduced heavily by both drouth and Governmental action. Sheep have varied about the same as hogs. Numbers were reduced considerably this year since fewer sheep were shipped in for feeding. Horses and mules show a more or less gradual reduction throughout the entire period, but there are now evidences of increased production of colts during the last year or two of the period. Market receipts of cattle were more or less constant until 1934, which year will show an increase of something like 50 per cent, due largely to the forced marketing of cattle as a result of the drouth. Market receipts of hogs have been more or less constant throughout the period, but with heavy evidences of marked reduction in numbers at the close of 1934 and with prospective small pig crops in 1935. The market receipts of sheep have also held fairly constant until 1934, when numbers were reduced because of the lack of grain and hay to feed the usual large number that are shipped into the state for feeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION NEBRASKA CROPS, 1931-1934* .„„„„ Area | Yield per Total Price per Total CROPS Year Acres I Acre Production Unit Value Corn. , 1931 10.042 17.0 170,714 $0.38 $61 871 1932 10,644 25.3 269,293 .14 37 701 1933 10,4:ill 22.5 214,698 .30 70 409 1934 6,67^ 2.0 13,352 .89 11,88:1 Spring Wheat 1931 126 7.5 D45 41 387 1932 202 10.0 2.020 25 505 193a 414 8.0 3.312 .60 1.987 1934 166 5.0 830 .85 705 Winter Wheat 1931 3,294 17.0 S5 998 10 "&gt;■» '199 1932 2,075 12.5 25,938 .27 7"003 1933 2,023 12.8 25,894 .61 16.V2 1934 2,114 7.0 15,008 .89 13,357 All Wheat 1931 3,420 16.6 56 941 40 "&gt; 7«« 1932 2.277 12.3 27,958 .27 T.WX 1933 2,437 12.0 29,200 .61 ls's.V) 1934 2,310 6.8 15,838 .89 u|C62 OaU 1931 2,311 21.5 19,686 .21 li.925 1932 2,473 30.0 74,190 .11 8 161 1933 2,226 10.5 2i,37:l .25 5 813 1934 1,224 7.5 9,180 .5!&gt; 5,416 Barley 1931 820; 16.6 . 13,530 .28 S.788 1932 918 20.0 18,360 15 '"754 1933 799 10.5 8,390 27 2*265 1934 36!) 7.5 2,700 .71 1,911 Rye 1931 333 9.0 2,997 33 !i8!&gt; 1932 281 10.0 2,810 .1!) 518 1933 214 8.0 1,712 .43 7:S« " 1934 182 1.0 728 ,S!I 618 Spelt 1931 28 11.6 32". :!l 1U 1932 14 21.2 3U1 .19 . 58 1933 19 13.4 2.-&gt;! .27 68 1934 9 7.5 7.; .71 53 Buckwheat 1931 1 8.5 s (i"i r i 1932 1 .■ 8.5 .s '.Z1 1933 1 " 11.0 11 .55 ti " 1934 0 . .0 u 0 0 I FUuaecd 1931 U 3.5 21 95 20 1932 3 6.0 18 .70 13 1933 2 6.0 12 1.10 17 1934 0 1.6S 0 0 0 Grain Sorg 1931 15 14.5 218 65 142 1932 22 15.0 330 .30 99 1933 37 15.5 574 45 "58 " " 1934 74 2.0 148 8.70 1,287 Potato Irish 1931 131 55.0 7,205 0 50 3 60" 1932 135 65.0 8,775 .29 2*645 1933 115 75.0 8,625 .65 5,606 1934 115 30.0 3,450 .79 2,725 All Tame Hay 1931 1,661 1.26 2,093 7.20 15,070 1932 1,880 1.76 2.960 4.50 13 320 1933 1.871 1.53 2.858 4.80 13 718 I 1934 1,480 .94 1.386 17.30 23,978 Alfalfa 1931 1,194 1.40 1.672 12 038 1932 1,170 1.90 2.223 4.90 10,89:1 " 1933 1,205 1.80 2.169 6 00 1:1 014 " 1934 928 1^20 1,114 18.30 20.386 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 NEBRASKA CROPS, 1931-1934* Area Yield per Total Price per Total CROPS Year Acres Acre Production Unit Value Wild Hay 15):U 2,728 .55 1,500 $6.10 9150 19.J2 3,065 .75 2,291 3.75 8,591 " . 1933 2,!m .60 1,760 4.20 7,392 "... " 1934 2,258 .35 790 14.40 11,376 All Hay . ...... 1 !&gt;!? 1 4,389 .82 3,593 6.74 24,220 1932 -1,7:J5 1.11 5,251 4.17 21,911 " " 1933 4,804 .96 4,618 4.57 21,110 " " 1934 3,738 .58 2,176 16.24 35,354 Sucar Bi-ets ,; 1931 65 13.7 891 5.46 4,868 1932 66 13.3 877 4.58 4.021 1933 88 12.1 1,068 4.50t 4,816 1931 61 9.0 549 6.50f 3,574 Sweet Sorg. for 19:!1 125 1.60 200 4.60 920 Forage and Hay . . 1932 200 1.50 300 3.25 975 19.TI 274 1.90 521 3.50 1,824 1934 480 .80 384 9.70 3,728 Clover Seed, Sweet 1931 21 4.4 105.6 3 20 338 1932 19 3.0 57 1.45 81 1933 21 3.7 77.7 1.95 152 1»34 28 3.8 79.8 4.40 194 Clover Soed, Red .. 1931 . 12 1.6 19.2 8.00 154 1932 10 1.6 15. 4.60 74 193.1 12 1.8 21.6 5.60 121 1934 3 1.5 45.0 10.50 47 Alfalfa Seed. ..,. 1931 37 2.65 96 7.00 673 1932 20 1.6 42 4.60- 191 193.! 47 2.0 94 4.80 451 1931 42 2.5 105 9.50 998 Beans, Dry Edible . . 1931 14 4.50e 63 2.80 176 19:?2 14 7.20 101 1.60 162 193.1 16 7.20 115 2.80 322 1934 12 7.20 68 4.10 279 Top Corn ...... 1931 6 618 3,775 1.40 53 1932 5 456 2,390 .96 23 1933 3 553 1,659 .50 8 1931 ...:.. Apples '...,':■', 1931 ..... 500 90 450 1932 627 .80 602 1933 370 1.00 370 1934 .. 357 1.20 431 Peaches 1931 ...... ..... 50 105 52 19-'2 . 58 • .95 55 1933 ...... 4 1.70 7 1934 5 1.28c 7 Pears..; 19:&gt;1 ...... .... 35 1.00 35 1932 ....... ..... 38 .95 36 1933 17 1.40 24 1934 ...... ..... 20 1.15c 23 Oapes 1931 ...... 2.520d 50.00 126 .'. 1932 2.960 40.00 118 1933 1.824 60.00 109 1934 1.216 60.00c 73 *Acreaße. production and value given m thousands; that is, (0001 omitted: 1934 data is ten - tative. [Preliminary, a-Pounda, b-100 ll&gt;. bags, c-tentative, d-.\ctual tons, e-Units of yield Cwt. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION i * FIVE-YEAR CROP AVERAGES, 1930-1934 Yield Price Value CROP Acres per Production Unit* per per Total Acre/ Unit i Acre Corn . fVtOS.OOO 19.6 1 ) 18l."50,000 Ku. $0.33 $6.50 $61,474,000 Winter Wheat 2.6!2,000 11.67 38,622,000 Hu. .49 7.19 19.033.000 Spring Wheat .... 219,000 3.21 2,1,2:1,000 Bu. .81 4.71 1,024,000 All Wheat . 2.851,000 11.26 40,615,000 Bu. .49 6.99 20,057,000 OatB. ., 2,141,000 22.C6 47,289,000 Bu. .22 4.85 10.590,000 Barley..' .. 724,000 18.01 11,062,000 Bu. .28 5.05 3,619,000 Rye..., 269.000 9.86 2.652.C0O Bu. .35 3.45 922,000 Grain Sorghum ... 33,000 9.76 322,000 Bu. .71 6.93 229.000 Potatoes 118.000 6&lt;.)8 7,191,000 Bu. .60 38.09 1,494.000 Sugar Beets 72.000 12.51 903.000 Tons 5.58 69.97 5.036.000 Alfalfa 1,126.000 1.80 2.030,000 Tons 8.66 15.59 17,571,000 Tame Hay* 1,681,000 1.56 2.62-1,000 Tons 7.76 12.11 20,:l49,000 Wild Hay 2,810,000 .81 2,320,000 Tons 4.73 3.93 10,964,000 All Hay 4,491,000 1.01 4,943.000 Tons 6.33 6.39 31.313,000 Apples 461,000 Bu. 1.14 669,000 'Includes Alfalfa. LIVE STOCK, JANUARY 1, ESTIMATES, 1925-1934* MILK COWS OTHER CATTLE EAR Average Total ■ Average Total Number Value Value i Number Value Value 1925 625 $54.00 ! $33,750 2,689 $28.80 $77,478 1926 625 58.00 36,250 2.566 31.90 81.833 1927 613 . 55.00 33,715 2,206 32.04 70,673 1928 613 71.00 43,523 ' 2,153 43.21 93,026 1929 619 84.00 51,996 2,312 52.34 121,058 1930 625 79.00 | 49,375 2,336 47.90 112,095 1931 680 56.00 | 38,080 2,487 34.30 85,456 1932 700 36.00 ( 25,200 2,438 20.80 50,732 1933 735 27.00 19,845 2,591 16.50 42,648 1934 765 26.00 19,890 2,695 14.60 39,523 SHEEP SWINE vpiR i i 1 1Cian Average I Total I Average Total Number Value Value Number ' Value Value i i I 1925 ' 780 $10.50 ' $8,163 5,200 $14.50 $75,400 1926 810 10.30 8,353 4,405 17.60 77,528 1927 684 8.70 5,929 4,660 19.50 90,870 1928 905 9.10 8,212 5,340 15.50 82,770 1929 1,050 9.50 9,955 5,305 15.00 79,575 1930 1,208 8.20 9,860 5,010 15.60 78,156 1931 960 4.70 4,512 4,820 13.40 64,588 1932 1,036 3.00 3,124 5,334 6.00 32,130 1933 1,057 2.80 2,924 4,534 4.30 19,436 1934 997 4.20 ' 4,193 4,307 4.50 19,453 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">17 BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 HORSES MULES I . . 1 - . . , | Average Total Average Total Number Value Value Number Value Value 1925 8G2 $58.00 $49,775 120 $74.00 ' $8,932 1926 840 61.00 50,951 120 78.00 9,398 1927 815 56.00 45,458 118 69.00 8,135 1928 788 60.00 46,868 112 75.00 8,360 1929 772 61.00 46,778 106 76.00 8,056 1930 757 61.00 45,923 99 79.00 7,869 1931 719 52.00 37,376 95 62.00 5,923 1932 697 44.00 30,944 91 56.00 5,121 1933 676 46.00 31,242 88 56.00 4,932 1934 662 58.00 38,243 86 72.00 6,220 'Number and value given in thousands; that is, (000) omitted. GROSS INCOME AND CASH INCOME FROM FARM PRODUCTION* Farm Income, 1931 Farm Income, 1932 Farm Income, 1933 Commodity 1 1 1 Gross Cash Gross Cash Gross | Cash Corn $ 10,288 $ 10,261 $ 19,841 $ 19,820 $ 17,228 $ 17,204 Wheat 14,452 14,208 7,478 7,174 17,238 16,670 Oats 1,202 1,202 1,447 1,447 608 608 Barley 541 541 588 588 282 282 Rye 257 255 153 151 294 290 Buckwheat 3 3 2 2 4 4 Flaxseed 19 19 12 12 16 16 Popcorn 53 53 23 23 23 23 Hay 1,576 1,576 1,327 1,327 1,918 1,918 Sweet Sorghum Forage 92 92 98 98 182 182 Clover Seed 115 115 65 65 112 112 Swcot Clover Seed . 245 245 70 70 144 144 Alfalfa Seed . 673 673 192 192 481 481 Dry Edible Beans 159 158 199 197 289 287 Potatoes 3,719 2.961 2.110 1,055 6,171 4,701 Truck Crops . . 829 768 275 255 418 387 Apples.. 475 261 395 225 363 265 Peaches 52 4 55 11 7 Pears 35 7 36 10 24 5 Plums and Apricots 142 78 118 68 145 67 Grapes 126 56 118 68 109 44 Strawberries 100 86 107 94 69 69 Small Fruit 50 43 53 47 35 30 Sugar Beets 4,868 4,868 4,021 4,021 5,335 5,335 Forest Products. . 732 285 722 249 732 285 Farm Gardens 2,356 2,913 2,740 Nursery Products 308 308 295 295 198 198 Green House Products 530 530 176 176 267 267 TOTAL CROPS $ 43,997 $ 39,659 $ 42,889 $ 37,740 $ 55,432 $ 49,761 Livestock and Products — Cattle and Calves $ 6'J &gt; 622 $ 62,369 $ 37,163 $ 36.119 $ 37,604 $ 36,524 Hogs 82,007 77,789 45,943 43,408 47,565 44,822 Sheep and Lambs 4,521 4,601 2,407 2,382 1,963 1,937 Horses 3 Mules 374 374 345 345 440 440 Chickens 11,266 7,767 7,981 5,265 6,280 4,199 Eggs (Chicken) 12,144 9,084 8,428 5,848 8,325 6,800 Milk 29,810 23,501 21.465 16.340 23,426 18,047 Wool 306 306 130 130 492 492 Honey 129 81 .154 111 TOTAL LIVESTOCK $204,179 $185,322 $124,016 $109,948 $126,084 $112,261 GRAND TOTAL $248,176 $224.981 $166,905 $147,688 $181,616 $162.022 ('Farm income given in thousands of dollars; that is, (000) omitted.) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">18 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION GROSS CASH FARM INCOME* (Year Ending December 31) VALUE OF SALES j PER CENT OF TOTAL YEAR Crops and Crops Livestock Livestock Crops Livestock 1925 $105,939 $283,286 ' $389,225 27.2 72.8 1926 80,732 298,663 379,395 21.3 78.7 1927 174,285 242,403 416,688 41.8 58.2 1928 125,130 271,028 396,158 31.6 68.4 1929 127,097 292,006 419,103 30.3 69.7 1930 89,268 255,639 344,907 25.9 74.1 1931 39,659 185,322 224,981 17.6 82.4 1932 37,740 109,948 147,688 25.6 74.4 1933 49,761 112,261 162,022 _ 69.3 *This is a new scries of (arm income. The old serie3 with years ending June 30 has been abandoned. Values given in thnuian.I.*. I MARKET RECEIPTS^ OF LIVESTOCK FROM NEBRASKA . 2 . CATTLE ! HOGS SHEEP Year : . „ L Omaha Other I Omaha Other j Omaha Other Receipts Markets Total Receipls Markets | Total Receipts Markets Total 1925 1,100 523 1,623 2,636 3,116 5,652 ~:W ;!20 1,116 1926 1,232 612 1.861 1.U70 2,'.K&gt;1 1,871 U1S .!27 1,245 1927 909 445 1,365 1,866 2,578 I. Ill 917 28:1 1,200 1928 972 457 1,429 2,306 3,:!S2 5,689 1,038 324 1/IG2 1929 971 432 1,403 2,4!" 3,:!86 5,H2:i 1,129 :!7'&gt; 1,504 1930 986 444 1,430 2,nfi2 2,756 ",.:118 1,140 111 1,590 1931 1,079 503 1,582 2,f,:)I 3,049 5,840 1,262 37!l 1,611 1932 887 380 1,268 2,:127 3,421 5.751 1,019 :IS7 1,406 1933 976 442 1,418 i 2.1:12 3,421 5,563 1.002 513 1,515 1934* 1.552 720 2,272 1,920 3,743 3.663 975 400 1.375 'Estimated. t </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OF AGRICULTURAL STATISTICS A. E. Anderson, Agricultural Statistician The work of the Division of Agricultural Statistics through the quadrennium, 1931-1934, has been carried on in about the same manner as previously. State personnel and support has been reduced somewhat. No annual reports of agricultural statistics have been issued, but plans are now being made to issue a report covering the four years. The office moved into new and very adequate quarters in rooms 1103-1105 State House. The work of the office during most of the last half of the quadren - nium was greatly increased by the additional work placed upon it by the A. A. A. in administering the wheat program and the corn-hog pro - gram. Practically all of the statistical work in connection with thes,e programs was assigned to the Division. It involved a large increase in the personnel, not only in the office, but in the field, to handle this large task. The Statistician in charge was made Chairman of both the State Wheat Board of Review and the State Corn-Hog Board of Review. As in the past, there has been a heavy demand for information concerning the State on the part of schools. This is highly desirable as it is important that pupils should bo taught more about the State's resources and its liossibiliiies. Since Agriculture is the leading basic industry of the State and since nearly all other industries depend largely on Agriculture for their development, it is important that the State's agricultural resources be taught in the schools in connection with the subject of agriculture that is being taught. It. would seem highly desirable to appoint a publicity agent in the Division who would assemble not only the statistics on agriculture, but all of the other industries of the State and publish them in pamphlet form for supplying the schools and others who are interested in Ne - braska. Nebraska has not boen properly advertised. Since most of the information is available in this office, the work could be handled at a minimum expense. The drastic reduction in prices of farm products, due partly to overproduction, and the marked reduction in the world demand for farm products has necessitated Governmental action in controlling production. The administration of these control programs has shown a great need for better records of crop and livestock production. The lack of accurate records has made it more difficult to administer the control programs. It has shown the need for greater care on the part of the farmers in reporting their acreage and livestock records to the assessors. It is, therefore, more important than ever before that farmers keep recoi-ds of their crop and livestock production and that greater care should be used in giving accurate reports to the assessors upon the schedules which they are asked to fill out. The law for the collection of agricultural statistics should be revised somewhat. One part of the law was repealed through error at a time </seg>
            <seg id="p024">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION some change was made in another law, a portion of which included part of the law for gathering agricultural statistics. While the Division feels that as a rule it is better to use persuasion than force in gather - ing statistics, at the same time there should be a little more effective way to reach those who continue to refuse to give agricultural statistics. There are still, and perhaps always will be, certain individuals who misunderstand the work and feel that it is detrimental to the interests of farmers. The response of price to supply and demand during the past few years ought to convince the most skeptical that price does not respond to supply and demand. Probably one of the most striking examples is that of the corn price in the autumn of 1934. The 1934 crop is one of the smallest for years. Furthermore, the carry-over from previous years had been reduced. Also, other feed grain crops such as oats and barley were very short. Yet, despite the unfavorable ratio between livestock prices and grain prices and the unfavorable financial and economic conditions, the price of corn is far above that justified by the prices received for livestock and its products. It is apparent that the law of supply and demand still prevails and is one law that cannot be repealed. Since firms that purchase large quantities of farm products are keenly interested in supply and demand, and since many of them main - tain private crop reporting systems to get information, it is fully as important and essential that farmers cooperate through the State and Government to get dependable information on crop and livestock pro - duction. Not only does this give farmers a basis for selling their com - modities and adjusting their production, but it has the tendency to eliminate or off-set ill effects of misleading crop reports. The farmer should profit from the example of the manufacturer who adjusts his products more nearly in line with demand. Although the farmer cannot hope to balance his production with the demand to the same degree as the manufacturer, because of the laws of nature over which he has no control, he can accomplish considerable by cooperating with public agencies established to help him. At least, he can endeavor to be guided by what the information shows. In the past, many individuals who have made use of agricultural statistics have profited by the same. However, no systematic effort has been made to utilize information collected on crops and livestock until the coming of the A.A.A. programs. Here, the Federal Administration calculated the needed supplies, taking into account present stocks, present and future demand, both domestic and foreign, and arrived at a con - clusion as to what changes should be made. In order to bring about such changes, the Government agreed to make certain benefit payments. Some additional equipment, chiefly calculating machines, have been supplied. The Division is in need of more filing cases and particularly shelving to take care of the increasing supply of records that must be maintained. There has been a marked increase in demand for statistics since the depression and adequate space for systematic filing is essential. Not since the world war has there been a greater demand for statistics on the part of the Government. They are needed as a guide for actions taken to improve the economic situation. Statistics are necessary for every endeavor and prevent many missteps. Past records serve as a guide for future action. The Government procures statistics </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 on many of the leading industries and keeps a close observation of the trend of business, of semi-public and private concerns, as an indicator of changes in the economic situation. Many do not realize the great demand that exists for agricultural statistics. The Government could not have conducted its wheat, corn - hog, cotton, tobacco and other programs without agricultural statistics. One of the first actions taken by the Government tree and shelter belt division was to get statistics on acreage and production of crops by counties. Land utilization work requires a knowledge of statistics on crop and livestock production. A study of the statistics of acreage and yield was among the first actions taken by those interested in the development of irrigation projects. Terminal market dealers who load grain and livestock are continually seeking information on production :ind demand. Legislators almost invariably make a study of statistics before drawing up bills to become laws. Railroads are continually seeking information on prospective movement of commodities. Large industries are writing continually for information on statistics that indicate potential buying power so as to be in a better position to make a more economical distribution of their wares. Farm organizations, such as cattle producers, grain producers, cotton producers and fruit pro - ducers, are interested in the statistics of their respective lines in order to make recommendations and take action that will be to the best advantage of their organizations. Prospective settlers desire the sta - tistics of the counties in which they are interested. Requests from public schools come nearly every day for statistics on agriculture and other industries of the state. With such a great and varied demand for sta - tistics that are so important in the economic role of the country, more adequate support should be provided. Quite a few changes in personnel have been made. Miss Florence Schneider, state clerk, resigned and was replaced by Miss Florence Mulligan. Miss Mulligan, who later became Mrs. Florence Stevinson, resigned August 1, 1934, and was replaced by Miss Lucile Carroll. Hazel Pavey, state clerk, resigned and was replaced by Wynona Roe. Later, Miss Roe resigned and was not replaced, so that the office was left with only one state clerk. Hazel Pavey and Adra Brown were appointed as Federal part time clerks, but both of them resigned before the close of 1934 and Miss Ann Margaret Petersen was appointed as Federal part time clerk. Mrs. Laura Brewer, who has been serving as Head Statistical Clerk, is also Head Clerk of the office.. Miss Edith Heed resigned November 1, 1934, and will probably be replaced later. Mr. Evan V. Jones, Assistant Statistician, has been offered a promotion to the position of Secretary of the Crop Reporting Board at Washington, and will probably accept soon after the close of 1934. Mr. Arnold V. Nordquist, who has helped in the corn-hog work during most of the year 1934, will probably receive a permanent appointment to take the place of Mr. Evan V. Jones. Mr. Robert W. Parke, Statistician in the corn-hog work, has also helped in the regular and special work of the office. In addition, a number of temporary clerks were hired from time to time to handle a large amount of extra work. Mr. A. E. Anderson, who took charge of the agricultural statistical work for Nebraska for the Government, has been in charge of the office since August 4, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">BUREAU OP ANIMAL INDUSTRY H. L. Feistner, Chief Biennial Report — December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1932 The Bureau of Animal Industry of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and Inspection is charged with the protection of the health of livestock within the State from disease conditions, more particularly those of a communicable nature. Activities in this connection are varied in scope and during a two - year period involve investigations covering many different animal diseases. While such infections as Tuberculosis, Scabies and swine diseases (especially hog cholera), for which specific appropriations have been made, continue to receive major consideration, other conditions, the importance of which is more apparent than in the past, are receiving an ever increasing attention. In the latter classification. Abortion Disease, Anthrax and Swine Erysipelas are outstanding. Economic conditions, which have prevailed more especially during the past biennium, have had an influence to\ a marked degree in the control of communicable diseases of livestock. Low prices offered for products of the farm and lack of ready capital have resulted in an inability on the part of many owners to protect their livesto?k by established methods of treatment. In view of this fact, extensive losses have occurred from disease, more particularly among swine, and as a result, areas of infection have been extended. The control and eradication of communicable diseases of livestock, those especially for which specific appropriations are made, is carried on as a cooperative arrangement between the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and Inspection and the United States Bureau of Animal Industry, as provided for under memoranda of understanding covering each specific project. Assistance extended through the laboratory facil - ities of the Department of Animal Pathology of the University of Ne - braska has been of inestimable value in the furtherance : of livestock disease control work in the State. Activities of the Department of Agriculture and Inspection as re - gards the Bureau of Animal Industry have been carried on under the same laws and regulations which were in effect immediately prior to the period of this report. TUBERCULOSIS The testing of cattle for Tuberculosis has been carried on during the biennium under the same arrangement as that prevailing immediately prior to this period. The county area plan, individual accredited herds, compliance with the State dairy law and tests for interstate shipments of dairy and breeding cattle have constituted the chief plans requiring such tests to be applied. Eradication of the disease in cattle continues to receive major attention under this project, although some work has been done among swine and poultry. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 The Department concerns itself mainly with the County area and accredited herd work, other testing falling almost entirely to local practicing veterinarians. A summary of tuberculin tests applied under the different plans during the past two-year period is set forth in Table I. TABLE I— TUBERCULIN TESTS APPLIED TO CATTLE Part 1 — December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1931, Inclusive Tested Reactors Infected Plan of Testing — , Herds Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 19,034 287,277 2,347 1,221 Accredited Herd 83 5,508 34 6 Private Service 15,244 18,612 141 56 Total testing 34,141 311,397 2,522 1,283 Part 2 — December 1, 1931 to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Tested Reactors Infected Plan of Testing Herds Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 16,257 ' 232,395 846 458 Accredited Herd ...... 76 5,678 80 10 Private Service. ...... 2,748 13,885 80 30 Total Testing. 19,081 251,958 1,006 498 Part 3 — December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Tested Reactors Infected Plan of Testing 1 : Herds I Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 35,291 519,672 3,193 1,679 Accredited Herd 159 • 11,186 114 16 Private Service 17,992 32,497 221 86 Grand Total 53,222 563,355 3,528 1,781 COUNTY AREA Testing in the counties of Antelope, Nance and Webster, having been commenced previously, was completed and these counties accredited during this period. Furnas, a new area, was completely tested and accredited during the biennium. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION Activities have consisted for the most part in the retesting of herds in county areas whose three-year period of accreditation had elapsed and retests required to continue their status. In few instances was it necessary to retest all breeding herds in the various counties to reaccredit them, owing to the low percentage of diseased cattle found on last general test. In every instance, how - ever, at least twenty per cent of the breeding herds, including previously infected herds and dairy herds supplying milk to the towns of each county, were tested. In each instance where tuberculosis infection was found to exist in no greater degree than one-half of one percent, the county was reaccredited without further testing. To November 30, 1932, fifty-four counties in Nebraska have been established areas under provisions of the statutes, forty-nine of which have been fully tested one or more times and designated Modified Ac - credited Tuberculosis-Free Areas, as follows: (A) Adams, (A) Antelope, (A) Boone, (A) Butler, (A) Buffalo, (A) Burt, (A) Cass, Cedar, (A) Clay, (A) Colfax, (A) Cum - ing, (A) Dakota, (A) Dawson, (A) Dixon, (A) Dodge, (A) Douglas, (A) Fillmore, (A) Franklin, (A) Frontier, (A) Furnas, (A) Gage, (A) Gosper, (A) Hall, (A) Hamilton, (A) Hitchcock, Harlan, (A) Jefferson, (A) Johnson, (A) Kearney, (A) Knox, (A) Lancaster, (A) Madison, (A) Nance. (A) Nemaha, (A) Otoe, (A) Pawnee, (A) Perkins, (A) Phelps. Pierce, (A) Platte, (A) Polk, (A) Red Willow, (A) Richardson, (A) Saline, (A) Seward, (A) Sarpy. (A) Saunders, Stanton. (A) Thayer, (A) Thurston, (A) Washington, Wayne, (A) Webster, (A) York. The (A) preceding a county name indicates that such county has been certified to be a Modified Accredited Tubercu - losis-free Area. TABLE II— RESULTS OF INITIAL AND FIRST GENERAL TEST IN THOSE COUNTIES ACCREDITED DURING THIS BIENNIUM Count Tested | Reactor Cattle J Herds Infected Herds | Cattle I Number I Per cent ' Number t Per cent Antelope 2,1.17 37,120 614 1.65 298 13.94 Furnas 1,610 25,761 45 .17 34 2.11 Nance 1,158 20,699 285 1.37 155 13.38 Webster 1.469 22.780 IHl 1.51 168 11.44 Four Counties 6,374 106,360 1,288 1.17 655 10.21 As previously stated in this report, retests were required of the breeding herds in certain counties to preserve their status as modified accredited areas. In the following table is given a list of those county - areas retested during the biennium and results of these retests: </seg>
            <seg id="p029">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 TABLE III— RESULTS OF RETESTS IN COUNTY AREAS FOR REACCREDITATION December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Tested I Reactor Cattle I Herds Infected y I Herds I Cattle I Number | Per cent | Number 1 Per cent Bonne?. . '. 828 12,:t75 14 .11 10 1.20 Hurt . 733 8,120 22 .27 II 1.91 ButliT 356 3,459 17 .49 12 3.37 Cass : 1,168 12,510 62 .49 25 2.14 &lt;Tlay : »IO 8.136 3:t .40 21 2.86 Duwson .: 2,085 25,289 101 .40 62 2.97 Dixc.n -.':, ,.. -100 B,:i70 27 .42 14 3.50 Dodge ...., 180 1,916 4 .20 2 1.11 RUmore 808 8,9:15 11 .12 10 1.21 Franklin . 581 8,945 9 .10 9 1.55 Frontier 458 10,467 30 .28 12 2.62 Gage 218 3,001 15 .49 14 5.64 Hamilton 200 1,352 0 0 0 0 Hitchcock 120 2,111 5 .23 5 4.16 Johnson 142 903 0 0 0 0 Kearney. 1 361 4,856 ■ 17 .36 16 4.43 Nemaha . 977 10,188 33 .32 24 2.45 Otoe 287 3.519 13 .36 7 , 2.44 Polk 1,074 13,951 68 .48 43 4.00 Kichanlson : 901 10,513 27 .25 2:1 2.54 Saumk-rs 2,225 27,821 111 .40 87 3.91 Sarpy : 551 4,901 7 .14 5 .90 Thayer 410 3,917 19 .48 14 3.41 Washington 1,020 13,061 63 .48 26 2.54 draper 38 770 2 .26 1 2.63 Twenty-five Counties . 16.S95 207,442 710 .34 459 2.70 PERSONNEL ENGAGED IN AREA TESTING Besides repularly employed State and Federal veterinarians, local practicing veterinarians are employed in county areas on a per diem basis as an aid to completion of the work in the least possible time at a minimum of expense. Following are tables showing the different classes and number under each class employed each month during the two - year period: TABLE IV— NUMBER AND CLASSIFICATION OF VETERINARIANS ENGAGED IN COUNTY AREA TESTING Part I — December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1931, Inclusive 1930 ! 1931 Veterinarians — 1 — . 1 . 1 Dec. i Jan. | I-Vbr. , Mar. ! Apr. ' May I June ' July [ Aug. | Sept. | Oct. | Nov. Federal 9 9 8 8' 9 8' 7 o' 2 2 4' 4 State 17 17 15 15 11 14 15 1 1 2 6 6 Practicing 775 3 67 10 00068 Total 33 3t 28 26 21 21 32 1 3 4 16 18 Part 2 — December 1, 1931 to November 30, 1932, Inclusive 1931 1932 Veterinarians . 1 1 , Dec. Jan. , Fcbr. | Mar. | Apr. May | June July I Aug. I Sept. j Oct. : Nov. Federal ! 3' 5' 5' 5' 4' 4' 5 4 4' 3' 3' 4 Stale 6 7 77 7 9 9 9 7 5 5 7 Practicing 13 9 5 15 22 19 19 8 3 1 1 4 Total 22 18 17 27 33 32 33 21 14 9 9 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION FIELD OPERATING EXPENSE AREA TESTING A general summary of expense incident to area testing is outlined in the following tables. Under provisions of the Statutes a certain portion of the cost is to be returned to the State by the counties, but this does not include salaries or subsistence of those engaged in the work, nor in any instance shall the sum to be paid by the county exceed 15c per head for the cattle tested. Expense to the county includes automobile transportation of those engaged and miscellaneous items such as telephone, ear tags, etc. TABLE V— EXPENDITURES UNDER COUNTY AREA PLAN Part 1 — December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1931, Inclusive FROM STATE FUNDS FROM FEDERAL FUNDS Month 1 1 j Salaries j Subsistence Transportation Salaries | Subsistence December $ 3.717.87 ' $ 891.50 $ 1.7-18.90 $ 2.561.07 ' $ 353.38 January 3.380.00 812.18 1,721.6-1 2,624.56 614.41 February 3,168.32 872.05 1.902.60 2.727.18 683.08 March 3,411.37 902.02 1.790.82 2,727.19 795.51 April 3,303.00 924.09 1,792.92 2,513.30 781.47 May 3,206.00 911.94 1,811.06 2,021.64 568.78 June 2,867.00 861.55 1,737.06 1,821.64 497.48 July 3,007.35 781.75 1,219.80 941.44 251.34 August 3,413.00 871.80 1,761.78 069.14 252.25 September 3,649.65 1,004.00 1.791.96 986.10 159.02 October 3,758.81 1,137.99 1,866.54 1,211.65 412.95 November 4,085.00 961.75 1,864.70 1,287.19 352.10 $10,967-37 $10.951.52 $21.065.78 $22,425.10 $5.655.07 Part 2 — December 1, 1931 to November 30, 1932, Inclusive FROM STATE FUNDS FROM FEDERAL FUNDS Month . Salaries Subsistence i Transportation Salaries Expense December ' $2,101.50 ' $ 362.85 $ 682.95 ' $ 1.612.48 $ 458.66 January 1,511.72 458.75 482.05 1,562.48 434.71 February 1,821.00 494.50 665.25 1,693.72 504.00 March 2,692.50 552.50 889.95 1,563.87 6U4.:i6 April 3,139.50 465.75 1,021.10 1,486.08 468.35 May 3,613.50 573.41 1,158.85 1,515.25 525.75 June 3,424.50 569.20 1,187.95 1.515.25 433.21 July 2,196.00 540.75 861.90 1,515.25 344.48 August 1.218.67 352.19 561.85 1,534.69 312.22 September 751.00 277.25 404.55 1,515.25 496.67 October 870.00 321.75 1 12.50 1,515.25 505.08 November 1,494.00 402.75 721.70 1,515.25 482.90 $21,836.89 $5/m.65 $7.083.69 $18,514.82 $5.600.39 INDEMNITY AND SALVAGE Owners of cattle reacting to Tuberculin tests who are eligible under provisions of the Statutes governing the payment of indemnity are reimbursed from State or Federal funds or both (depending upon class of test), at a certain percentage based upon one-third of the difference between the appraised value and the value of the net salvage (amount brought on sale at slaughter after expenses of shipping have been de- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 ducted), not to exceed $25.00 for a grade animal or $50.00 for a pure - bred. The State and Federal Departments pay like amounts in the instance of purebred cattle, but the Federal regulations allow but $20.00 maximum for grade female cattle and no indemnity on grade bulls. No indemnity, either State or Federal, will be paid for cattle not sexually entire. Cattle classified as reactors to the Tuberculin test are required to be slaughtered under inspection of the United States Bureau of Animal Industry at the various market centers and carcasses disposed of in accordance with the extent of lesions found. Premises from which Tuberculous cattle are removed are required to be cleaned and disin - fected before indemnity can be paid to the owner. Reacting cattle are appraised at their actual worth, taking into consideration the class to which they belong as to whether purebred or grade, and their value as dairy or beef type cattle. The appraised valuation of diseased cattle has been materially lowered during the biennium, owing to marked decrease in prices offered on the open market for all classes of cattle. The following Table VI shows the amount of indemnity paid, both State and Federal, during the last two-year period. The State's share includes not only its portion of cooperative indemnity, but double in - demnity on reactors outside of areas and accredited herd work in which the Federal Department does not participate. -I TABLE VI— INDEMNITY REIMBURSEMENT TO OWNERS United Period Nebraska States Total Dec. 1, 19:50 to Nov. 30, 1931 $57,552.20 $51,079.27 $108,631.47 Dec. 1, 1931 to Nov. 30, 1932 16,281.79 14,118.92 30,400.71 Totals $73,833.99 $65,198.19 $139,032.18 PROGRESS IN BOVINE TUBERCULOSIS ERADICATION To give a comparative view of the progress of this work since the inauguration of cooperative organization in 1918, the following table VII is given. Attention is called particularly to reduction of the incidence of Tuberculosis infection among cattle tested as work has progressed. Activities during the past biennium have been almost wholly confined to retests for accrediting the county areas which will account for the low percentage of reacting cattle as would have prevailed otherwise had more new areas been entered. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Per cent DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE Vl}— SUMMARY OF CATTLE TESTED IN NEBRASKA Period — 1918 to November 1932, Inclusive Year No. Cattle Tested Reactors Per cent 1918 984 62 I G.3 1919 18,315 1,204 5.5 1920 49,792 2,002 4. 1921 124,292 3,067 2.5 1922 203,532 5,704 2.5 1923 50,507 854 1.6 1924 211,835 3,276 1.5 1925 361,706 4,470 1.2 1926 476,841 5,140 1.1 1927 413,721 3,876 .9 1928 368,445 3,601 1. 1929 461,855 2,832 .6 1930 447,232 2,483. .5 1931 267,371 2,037 .7 1932 (11 Months) 220,483 873 .3 3,676,»n__ 41.481 PARA-TUBERCULOSIS (JOHNE'S DISEASE) OF CATTLE This disease, a form of tuberculosis, while of considerable economic importance, is not increasing among breeding herds of cattle in Nebraska at compared to some of the other infections according to field observa - tion of the Department, although in a few herds it is a serious problem. The temperature test is the one employed in detecting diseased cattle and where found are slaughtered and the owners indemnified on the same basis as for reactors to the Tuberculin test. These tests have been applied by representatives of the Department in an endeavor to gain information relative to the nature and progress of the disease. The following tables show the extent of activities in this connection: TABLE VIII— TESTS OF CATTLE FOR PARA-TUBERCULOSIS Part 1 — December 1. 1930 to November 30, 1931 Tested Reactors Indemnity Paid Herds Cattle Cattle Suite Federal 4 234 22 $404.42 $404.42 Part 2 — December 1, 1931 to November 30, 1932 Tested Reactors Indemnity Paid Herds Cattle Cattle State Federal 6 272 22 ' $683.40 $683.40 Note — Increase in amount of indemnity paid in 1932 over 1931, due to the increased number of purebred cattle involved. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">BIENNIAL REPORTS — 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 SCABIES This disease continues to be of great economic importance and the successful handling of cattle in Nebraska under range condition depends much on its control and eradication. i Dipping the cattle at intervals in approved baths of nicotine or lime-sulphur solutions properly prepared and heated is the practice fol - lowed, together with certain sanitary measures. Official dipping and inspection are carried forward as a cooperative project under direction of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and the United States Bureau of Animal Industry. Greatest attention is given to the range area but breeding herds and feedlot cattle and sheep affected with Scabies are of great im - portance. The State is maintaining two and the federal Bureau three full - time veterinary inspectors, each with a district under his supervision. One inspector maintains headquarters at each of the following points: Alliance, Valentine, Mullen, Hyannis and Sutherland. The following tables covering sheep and cattle scabies cover infected herds only and do not include exposed herds. Number and Location of Herds of Cattle Affected with Scabies: Part 1 — From December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1931, inclusive: Arthur (1), Burt (1), Chase (1), Cherry (15), Cheyenne (1), Colfax (1), Custer (2), Dawson (1), Dodge (3), Deuel (1), Frontier (1), Gage (2), Garden (8), Grant (4), Hamilton (1), Keith (4), Lancaster (2), Lincoln (8), Logan (9), McPherson (3), Morrill (2), Nuckolls (2), Pierce (1), Richardson (1), Sarpy (1), Scotts Bluff (9), Seward (1), Sheridan (2), Sioux (1), Thomas (1), Thurston (1), Wayne (2)— Total 93. Thirty-two shipments of scabby cattle received at public markets from Nebraska points. SHEEP SCABIES Number and Location of Lots of Sheep Affected with Scabies: December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1931, inclusive: Burt (1), Cheyenne (1), Dakota (1), Gage (2), Nance (1), Nuckolls (4), and Scotts Bluff (4)— Total 14. Nine shipments of scabby sheep received at public markets from Nebraska points. CATTLE SCABIES Part 2 — December 1, 1931, to November 30, 1932, inclusive: Arthur (7), Box Butte (2), Burt (1), Cass (1), Cherry (14), Cuming (1), Dawes (2), Dawson (10), Furnas (1), Gage (1), Grant (11), Hamilton (1), Kearney (1), Keith (9), Lincoln (18), Logan (l), McPherson (3), Merrick (2), Morrill (2), Perkins (1), Phelps (1), Sarpy (2), Seward (1), Sheridan (7), Stanton (2), Thomas (2), York (1)— Total 105. Twenty-five shipments of scabby cattle received at public markets from Nebraska points. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Aiseene m the North Platte Valley where sheep m lar K e numbers are fed each year. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 SHEEP SCABIES Xumber anil Location of Lots of Sheep Affected with Scabies: Dixon (1), Dodge (1), Madison (1), Pierce (1), Scotts Bluff (1), Total 5. All of the above shipments received at public markets. TTABLE IX— INSPECTIONS AND DIPPINGS OF CATTLE ON ACCOUNT OF SCABIES Part 1 — From December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1931, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH f~ Cattle" Lots Involved l Lots Cattle December. 115 46,917 ' 57 25,068 January... 171 72,488 75 35,862 February 200 69,044 74 21,194 March ! 149 61,045 51 24,487 April 179 83,720 11 3,144 May. ......... .'. 198 79,018 25 13,038 June 160 58,827 10 4,723 July 75 20,437 5 1,236 August 119 35,042 ... September...... 137 50,061 29 12,671 October 114 45,874 26 13,389 November. 121 48,630 55 22,073 Total 1,738 671,103 418 176,885 Part 2 — From December 1, 1931, to November 30, 1932, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH Clrtui Lots Involved Lots Cattle December 139 62,754 ' 48 23,636 January 129 41,034 38 18,318 February 135 60,987 25 20,989 March 192 81,978 27 17,746 April 247 72,656 42 8,195 May 291 58,748 37 7,751 June 221 51,739 5 4,386 July 194 53,045 10 3,780 August 89 23,715 1 275 September '. 148 42,751 7 6,754 October 173 60,393 43 19,001 November 188 59,923 98 43,094 Total 2,146 669,723 381 173,925 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE X— INSPECTIONS AND DIPPINGS OF SHEEP ON ACCOUNT OF SCABIES Part 1— From December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1931, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH I"^ 1 ' Lots Involved Lots Sheep December 9 7,955 gk| ! f « ! 1 i| liiiii i I? i I J i ulv v 6 1,284 2 "90 August 16 5298 5 ■ ™ September 4 2,161 2 2 018 October. 2 583 j -' u Jg November 1 300 Total 75 48,793 ~23 9,156 Part 2— From December 1, 1931, to November 30, 1932, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPING^ MONTH j-~sl^p - . Lots Involved Lots Sheep BSS^-.;:.:-::::-::-:::::^: 4 7 fflB : . j g Ma^ h G 26,100 0 o A"" 1 7 10,600 0 0 ■• une 0 0 0 0 July i 19 o o August 0 0 0 o September 0 0 0 0 October. 0 0 0 0 November. jj 3,543 1 3,193 Total 40 83,537 1 3,193 GLANDERS fnr J he a dis {; ase gliders once the scourge of horse stock has been, as far as can be ascertained, eradicated from the State, no cases having appeared during the past biennium. „* u" 1^ a P plied , as have b een required for the interstate movement of horses and mules are shown in the following table: </seg>
            <seg id="p037">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 TABLE XI— SHOWING TESTS OF HORSE STOCK FOR GLANDERS TESTED INFECTED ,„._-, tw PFRIOD - Indemnity ToTTl Animals T^s] Animals Reimbursement December 1, 1930 to November 30, 19IS1 91 1,056 0 0 0 December 1, 1!&gt;:S1 to November 30, 1932 96 1,353 0 0 0 Total . 187 2,409 0 0 0 ANTHRAX During: the past biennium the Department has given a great deal of attention to the control of Anthrax infection among livestock, particularly in the northeast counties of the State. This Disease was found to be present in 1931 on 116 individual premises which was the greatest number reported as far as records of the Bureau show since the office has been established and with the close of the year 1932 a much greater number of farms were found to bo affected than during the year previous, a total of 240 premises. History discloses the fact that in years past Anthrax was quite widespread over the entire midwest territory and owing to the nature of the organism causing the disease, it is capable of remaining dormant in the soil over long periods of time awaiting favorable conditions to develop. Drouth conditions prevailing in the northeastern section of the State during 1931 caused livestock to come in close contact with the infected soil in grazing over areas where the vegetation was very scant or practically absent. As a result of the 1931 outbreak, the virulence of the disease was increased and a greater area infected so that the increase in number of outbreaks and territory involved in 1932 was not unexpected. Preventive measures by way of the administration of biological products and pasture rotation will control the disease, and, had not adverse economic conditions prevailed, livestock on farms infected in 1931 would have been protected more generally, thereby reducing the number of outbreaks. The Department maintained from one to as many as five veteri - narians in the territory affected throughout the season and the State force was augmented by the cooperation of two Federal veterinarians under the direction of the United States Bureau of Animal Industry. The duty of these veterinarians was to work in conjunction with local practicing veterinarians and other individuals in locating and quaran - tining diseased livestock, where positive Anthrax was diagnosed. Proper disposal of diseased carcasses promptly is one of the important features in the control of Anthrax and to this activity much attention was given. The following tables with accompanying statements give a complete picture of the extent and location of infected territory: </seg>
            <seg id="p038">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE XII— ANTHRAX QUARANTINES ISSUED BY COUNTIES AND NUMBER OF LIVESTOCK INVOLVED Part 1 — From December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1931, Inclusive No. Quarantines No. Head of County Issued Livestock Antelope 7 580 Boyd 30 1,046 Cedar 2 500 Cheyenne 4 357 Dawes 2 797 Garden 1 844 Holt 10 1,388 Knox 42 2,115 Platte 1 33 Sioux I 282 Sheridan 3 370 Thurston 1 10 Valley 5 180 Washington 7 1,355 Total .-. . . _1 16 9^857 First Anthrax quarantine was issued under date of March 31, 19!?!, and the last issued on November 3, 1931. Final release on last quaran - tine December 14, 1931. Part 2 — From December 1, 1931, to November 30, 1932. Inclusive No. Quarantines No. Head of County Issued Livestock Adams 1 120 Antelope 3 89 Boyd 58 1,746 Cedar 31 1,530 Cherry... 1 206 Dodge 1 26 Dixon 5 375 Douglas 1 67 Holt 15 677 Keya Paha 1 71 Knox 108 4,783 Lancaster 1 215 Madison 1 79 Pierce 2 283 Polk 1 39 Washington 4 240 Wayne 4 669 York 2 24 Total 240 11,239 . The first quarantine placed on livestock for Anthrax during 1932 was on March 8th on a farm near Fort Calhoun in Washington County, and the last quarantine to date was issued November 7th. At the time of filing this report nine quarantines remain in force. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">(Courtesy C. B. &amp; Q. Ry.) A herd of Jerseys seen on a farm m Northwestern Nebraska. Dairyine m this section of the state has grown rapidly. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION ABORTION DISEASE— CATTLE Abortion or Bang's disease occurring among cattle has been given more attention by the owners of cattle the past year than ever before. A great deal of this concern on the part of cattle owners has been brought about primarily because of the wide-spread amount of infection in cattle herds coupled with the economic situation at this time. Cattle prices have been low and low prices with poor breeding efficiency caused by Bang's disease (contagious abortion) has made it doubly difficult for the cattle owner. The losses from abortion disease in cattle are not confined entirely to the actual abortions. Abortion disease is also responsible for a good percentage of the breeding problems confronting the cattle owner, es - pecially sterility. To the dairyman abortion disease is the cause of considerable loss through decreased milk production. The information regarding abortion disease, its phenomena and the various ways in which it produces a financial loss other than from the mere abortion, has been disseminated to cattle owners through this Department, as well as the information given cattle owners by practicing Veterinarians in Ne - braska. At the request of several groups of farmers, meetings have been held in various sections of the State during the year, bringing to the attention of these cattle owners information regarding the disease with ways and means whereby they can clean up their herds. Withal, very Fatisfactory progress has been made, and more farmers are besoming interested. Abortion disease in cattle is an individual farm problem and must be handled according to the facilities as they present themselves on that farm and it requires close contact between the owner of the cattle and the Veterinarian to accomplish this purpose. With this in mind and due to the limited funds available for this work, this Department has acted in an advisory capacity, that is, helping the owner in getting his program started for establishing a clean herd, and it is then nec-essary for the balance of the work to be carried out by the farmer and his own local veterinarian. Where this procedure has been followed out, much success has been attained. At this time scattered in various sections of Nebraska the Depart - ment has cattle herds under observation, both dairy and beef herds, located on small farms and on large ranches for the purpose of making it possible for cattlemen in that vicinity to watch the progress in the herd and witness the methods used in establishing a Bang's disease (contagious abortion) free herd. Due to the fact that all of the work on abortion disease has been done incidental to other official duties from the State office, it has not been possible to devote as much time for this work as if there had been a special project for abortion disease. There have been a total of forty-eight private herds tested in 1932 and handled by the Department in the limited amount of work that the Department has been able to do. These forty-eight herds represent 3,951 cattle, and 565 or 14.03 per cent of these were infected. A good many of these herds where it was the owner's desire to clean up the herd, further tests were made and the amount of infection has been decreasing. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 It is difficult at this time to state accurately the extent ot tne infection throughout Nebraska, but from the contacts established and inquiries received along with information obtained from practicing veterinarians, there are about forty (40) per cent of the breeding herds in Nebraska affected with abortion disease. Along with the small amount of time that the Department has been :ible to devote to individual herd owners in Nebraska, work has also been done in the State-owned herds coming under the supervision of the Board of Control in the establishing of abortion-free herds at these Institutions. In 1930, when it was decided to establish abortion-free herds at these Institutions, it was becoming a necessity, for in several of the herds the disease had reached such proportions that the cattle would either have to be sold for economic reasons and milk purchased, or clean up the herd, the latter procedure was inaugurated. In 1930, taking all of the Institutions as a unit, there was 18.6 per cent infection and at the close of 1932 there was 2.7 per cent infection. Much progress has been made in these herds and they are now rapidly approaching a high degree- of breeding efficiency. It is possible through practical sanitation and hygienic measures when adopted to reduce the great economic losses caused by Bang's disease among cattle. Practical measures for control and prevention are within reach of every cattle owner but much educational and field demonstrational work will undoubtedly be required to bring this infor - mation to Nebraska cattle owners. Once this has been accomplished, the cattle owner must then realize that his problem is a local individual problem and that close cooperation between himself and his veterinarian is essential for the establishing of a Bang's disease-free herd. TABLE XIII— SUMMARY OF TESTS FOR BANG ABORTION DISEASE Part 1— From December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1931, Inclusive Herd Tests Reacting Cattle Non-Reacting Cattle I Total State State State Cattle Private owned Private owned Private owned 12 25 297 ' 35 742 771 1,845 Part 2 — From December 1, 1931, to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Herd Tests Reacting Cattle Non-reacting Cattle _ Total State- State- State- Cattle Private , owned Private owned Private owned 48 24 565 40 3,386 876 4,867 BANG ABORTION DISEASE— SWINE Beginning in the Spring of 1931 many inquiries came to the De - partment regarding abortions in swine. Previous to this time very few reports had been received, but in the Spring of 1931 and extending </seg>
            <seg id="p042">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION through 1932 there has been quite an enzootic of Bang's disease (con - tagious abortion) among swine, resulting in serious losses on the farms involved. It was necessary to make these investigations along with general investigational work by the Department, but considerable effort has been expended and information gathered regarding this serious problem presenting itself to swine owners. Practically all of the experimental work done on abortion disease universally has been confined almost exclusively to the abortion disease problem in "cattle. When this problem presented itself to Nebraska swine owners in 1931, the Department immediately set out with the meager amount of facilities at hand to gather as much information as possible for the purpose of aiding distressed swine owners. After starting the investigational and experimental work, it was found that abortion disease in swine was more common than first thought, but it was necessary to confine our efforts to a small group of owners, and fifteen herds having abortion disease were selected. These herds were located in various sections of Nebraska. There has not been enough time elapsed since this work was started to gather all the experimental data and to draw conclusions, but this will be done the coming year. In light of the experimental work done to date, one constant factor is evident and that it the danger in placing gilts on ground the next season after there have been abortions on this ground. Clean ground with negative sows and gilts seems to be neces - sary to forestall an abortion disease disaster. Abortion disease is a serious menace to swine herds at this time in Nebraska, and swine owners are advised that when they have clean herds, to use the utmost care in purchasing boars and gilts when making additions to their herds. This report is submitted before all of the conclusions for the management of herds so infected have been determined. The work will be continued^ as it is the Department's desire to furnish any infor - mation possible in the handling of abortion disease in swine. RENDERING ESTABLISHMENTS Nebraska laws provde for the licensing of plants engaged in the rendering of animal carcasses and for the inspection of same, which activity is delegated to representatives of the Bureau of Animal Industry. Periodical inspections of these plants are made to determine whether they are properly equipped and operations being carried on under sanitary methods. During the year 1931 eighty-two plant inspections were made by Department Veterinarians. Location and Number of Licensed Rendering Plants — 1931: Benson (2), Beemer (1), Beaver Crossing (1), Fremont (1), Grand Island (1), Humboldt (1), LaPlatte (1), Lincoln (2&gt;, Norfolk (1), Seward (1), Schuyler (1), Scottsbluff (1), South Omaha (1), Tecumseh (1), Tekamah (2), Wayne (1)— Total 19. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 During the year 1932 thirty plant inspections were made. De - crease in the number of inspections during 1932 from the year previous was due to the closing: of many plants for several months on account of economic conditions. Location and Number of Licensed Rendering Plants — 1932: Beaver Crossing (1), Beemer (1), Benson (1), Fremont (1), LaPlatte (1), Lincoln (2), Norfolk (1), Omaha (2), Schuyler (1), Scottsbluff (1), Tecumseh (1), Tekamah (1), Wayne (1) — Total 15. SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS Many individual outbreaks of livestock diseases are investigated by the Department during a two-year period involving a wide variety of conditions. Work in this connection is at the request of practicing Veterinarians and livestock owners and in numerous instances has resulted in checking the spread of dangerous communicable diseases. All species of livestock are involved in these investigations and all diseases common to this section are met with. SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS 1931 1932 In Cattle Ill 95 In Horses 6 28 In Swine 200 209 In Sheep 14 12 In Poultry 13 9 General 54 Totals 421 407 ■ ■.-■■.' . LIVESTOCK IMPORTS AND EXPORTS Each State has its own regulations governing the entry of livestock and in addition, the Federal Government has certain fixed regulations applying to the interstate movement of domestic animals as pertains to specific disease conditions. Authorized graduate licensed Veterinarians are empowered to make tests and inspections for interstate movement of livestock and uniform reports are required on forms furnished by the Department of Agri - culture. Before such certificates are acceptable to State livestock sani - tary officials in State of destination, they must be approved by live - stock officials in State from which shipment is made. All certificates, therefore, pass through the office of the Bureau of Animal Industry where record is kept of all shipments. The following tables show the species and class of livestock, all numbers of each, both for export and import: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE XIV— LIVESTOCK IMPORTS Part 1 — December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Class 1931 1932 Cattle for Feeding and Grazing (largely female cattle) A. From Omaha Stockyards 56,276 41,720 B. From Other Points 135,596 77,902 Cattle for Breeding and Dairy A. Beef Breeds 692 112 B. Dairy Breeds .... 4,367 2,995 Swine A. From Public Stockyards 13,771 4,154 B. From Other Points Interstate 114,845 30,587 Sheep for All Purposes A. From Public Stockyards 3,119 3,130 B. From Other Points Interstate 126,092 129,306 Horses — All Purposes , 5,774 4,761 LIVESTOCK EXPORTS Part 2 — December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932, Inclusive Class 1931 1932 Cattle A. Dairy 586 483 B. Beef (Breeding Stock; 5,588 304 Swine — Breeding 4,505 2,569 Sheep — All Purposes 466 15,566 Horses — All Purposes . 1,915 2,469 Biennial Report — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1934 Activities under direction of the Bureau of Animal Industry of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and Inspection have continued during the biennial period December 1, 1932, to November 30, 1934, on the same general plan as prevailed during the preceding two year period, December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932. Some minor changes of policy and additional activities have resulted from new laws enacted by the last legislative session, as hereinafter reported. Major disease control measures continue as, cooperative projects through assistance rendered by the U. S. Bureal' of Animal Industry to the Nebraska Department. Special Federal funds and trained Veteri - nary personnel augment those of the State in the carrying forward of these various measures. In any livestock disease control program, laboratory diagnostic work plays a very important part and in this the Department has been most fortunate in having the very efficient assistance of the Depart- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">BIENNIA1, REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 merit of Animal Pathology and Hygiene of the University College of Agriculture. Continued loyal support of all activities by Nebraska's Veterinary practitioners has made the entire program possible. Field activities of the Bureau of Animal Industry may be mentioned for a better understanding in order of their relative importance. Con - trol and eradication of Animal Tuberculosis, Scabies eradication, Swine diseases, Anthrax control, Abortion disease, General investigational work, inspection of licensed rendering plants and livestock sales pavil - ions. TUBERCULOSIS Tuberculosis eradication work in Nebraska continues under three classifications, namely, County area, Accredited herd plan and as a private service by local veterinary practitioners. The work of greater importance has been under the plan of main - taining counties, their status as Modified Accredited Tuberculosis-free Areas in view of funds expended and work entailed. TABLE 1— TUBERCULIN TESTS APPLIED TO CATTLE Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933. p. f T .. TESTED Reactor Infected Flan of lesting 1 c^n^i u _j Herds Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 10,289 142,361 372 235 Accredited Herd 64 6,625 195 13 Private Service 2,084 11,104 52 33 Total ,. . ... 12,437 160,090 ~619 281 Part 2 — December 1, 1933, to November 30, 1934 WaB f -, „«„„ TESTED Reactor Infected rlan of lesting 1 /-"«*n« xi_. j~ Herds Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 10,880 169,522 . 895 540 Accredited Herd 114 11,044 414 34 Private Service 2,237 12,967 58 40 Total 13,231 193,533 1,367 614 Part 3 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1934 Plan of T P stin«r TESTED Reactors Infected .rian oi lesting 1 r"atti&lt;» n nr ,i o Herds ] Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 21,169 ' 311,883 1,267 775 Accredited Herd 178 17,669 609 47 Private Service 4,321 24,071 110 73 Total 25,668 353,623 1,986 895 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION There were no initial or first general tests in counties December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1934, in conformity with the law providing for the establishment of Areas by petition. An emergency fund to augment Federal allotments provided by the congress has made possible the entering of certain counties for the testing of breeding herds on a voluntary basis without cost to the counties involved, and without these counties, having been established testing areas through petition. TABLE II— RESULTS OF RETESTS IN COUNTV AREAS FOR REACCREDITATION December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Tested Reactor Cattle Herds Infected County . • Herds Cattle Number Per cent Number Percent Adams 621 7,305 6 .08 6 .96 Buffalo 1,120 16,343 44 .27 31 2.76 Colfax 64 1,052 0 0 0 0 Cuming 690 13,436 32 .24 16 2.30 Dakota 49 350 0 0 0 0 Douglas 1,465 17,498 88 .50 43 2.93 Hall 549 6,563 30 .46 9 1.64 Jefferson 265 4,098 4 .09 4 1.51 Knox 982 20,601 77 .37 50 5.09 Lancaster 1,204 17,071 24 .14 17 1.41 Madison 677 12,447 44 .35 35 5.17 Nemaha 685 8,651 12 .14 8 1.17 Pawnee 161 1,246 1 .08 1 .62 Perkins 153 1,816 7 .38 5 3.27 Phelps 471 7,274 4 .05 4 .85 Platte 2,221 39,864 185 .47 123 5.53 Polk 1,124 12,592 53 .42 31 2.75 Red Willow.... 207 4,459 22 .49 17 8.21 Richardson 216 2,132 7 .33 5 2.31 Saline 1,025 12,442 14 .11 11 1.07 Saunders 1,493 18,202 76 .42 43 2.88 Seward 626 7,264 2 .03 2 .32 Thurston 123 790 0 0 0 0 York 883 8,815 . 35 .39 30 3.39 24 Counties 17,074 242,311 767 .24 491 2.33 PERSONNEL ENGAGED IN COUNTY AREA TESTING Three classes of Veterinarians are engaged in the Tuberculin testing of cattle under the Area plan, regularly employed State and Federal Veterinarians, and practicing Veterinarians. The latter are paid on a per diem basis as their services are required. The State Department has paid for the services of practicing Veterinarians engaged in this work prior to September 1, 1934, when this expense was assumed by the Federal Department through the allocation of emergency funds. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 TABLE III— NUMBER AND CLASSIFICATION OF VETERINARIANS IN COUNTY AREA TESTING Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive 1932 1933 Veterinarians Dec . — , 1 1 1 1 Jan. Febr. Mar. | Apr. May June | July | Aug. | Sept. | Oct. [ Nov. Federal 4 4 5 T" 1 5 4 4 3 3 2 2~~^ 2 State 7 7 7 7 7 4 4 3 3 3 3 3 Practicing 2 2 7 8 5 S 2 4 4 A 5 6 Part 2 — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive 1933 1934 Veterinarians Dec. 1 . ■ 1 1 1 1 1 1 Jan. I Febr. Mar. Apr. I May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Federal ' 44 4 4 4*4 4 4 4 13 11 8 State I 4 5 5 5 5 4 3 3 3 A 4 Practicing 9 5 4 14 1 6 9 11 5 0 1 6 The following table No. IV gives a summary of expenditures for the biennium covering salaries, subsistence, and transportation of both State and Federal Veterinarians engaged in testing of cattle for Tuberculosis. TABLE IV— EXPENDITURES UNDER COUNTY AREA PLAN Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive From State Funds From Federal Funds Month ~~ Transpor- Salaries Subsistence tation Salaries Subsistence December ' $1,191.00 377.75 459.40 $1,515.25 412.59 January 1,353.00 429.75 776.30 1,515.25 419.44 February 1,652.00 318.50 670.65 1,515.25 282.33 March 1,263.00 360.85 723.15 1,515.25 377.63 April 1,300.50 417.35 766.65 1,515.25 463.79 May 1,003.00 237.00 552.30 1,515.25 390.43 June 579.50 220.50 372.80 1,358.28 310.78 July 726.00 203.75 390.05 1,358.28 316.08 August 614.00 158.00 358.80 1,358.28 281.21 September.... 719.00 184.50 315.10 1,358.28 245.51 October 705.00 173.50 301.10 1,358.28 280.36 November 677.00 185.00 223.95 1,358.28 376.47 Totals... $11,783.00 3,266.45 5,910.25 $17,241.18 4,156.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION Part 2 — December 1. 1933 to November 30, 1934. Inclusive From State Funds From Federal Funds Month | Transpor . - Salaries Subsistence tation Salaries Subsistence December $ 92G.00 254.00 255.70 $ 1,358.28 199.87 January 870.00 294.00 296.10 1,358.28 153.08 February 951.00 318.00 292.65 1,358.28 184.81 March 1,917.00 358.50 399.60 1,358.28 247.10 April 972.00 352.75 290.30 1,358.28 293.10 May 1,091.00 363.50 375.60 1,358.28 182 29 June 1,129.00 254.50 333.20 1,358.28 207.28 July 1,013.00 207.50 307.40 591.65 15.10 August 971.00 157.50 244.85 0 0 September 445.50 180.00 204.30 2,196.23 365.03 October 667.00 268.10 309.65 2,721.59 886.51 November 660.00 236.50 310.45 2,903.66 1.012.53* Totals $11,612.50 3,284.85 3,619.80 $17,921.09 3.746.70 •Incomplete. INDEMNITY AND SALVAGE Net salvage and indemnity on cattle reacting to Tuberculin tests are paid under thejsame arrangement as prevailed during the previous two year period. The last session of the Legislature reduced the maxi - mum indemnity from $50.00 to $30.00 on purebred cattle and from $25.00 to $15.00 on grade cattle. On September 1, 1934, a new arrangement was perfected whereby the Federal Department through emergency funds began payment of indemnity on cattle reacting to cooperative tests with a view to relieving limited funds of the State for this purpose. The Federal Department pays up to their permitted maximum for indemnity on reacting cattle, the State making up the balance, which has greatly reduced the amount which the State is required to pay. Heretofore the two Departments have shared equally in these payments on all cattle with the exception of grade bulls on which the Federal Department pays no indemnity. TABLE V— INDEMNITY REIMBURSEMENTS TO OWNERS United Period Nebraska States Total Dec. 1, 1932 to Nov. 30, 1933, Incl.. $ 7,520.43 $ 5,852.47 $13,372.90 Dec. 1, 1933 to Nov. 30, 1934, Incl. . 11,476.91 12,354.48 23,831.39 Totals. . $18,997.34 $18,206.95 $37,204.29 State Indemnity includes indemnity for both private and cooperative tests. PROGRESS IN BOVINE TUBERCULOSIS ERADICATION The following table No. VI gives a comparative view of the number of cattle tested during the years 1918 to and including the eleven months of 1934. Number and percentage of reacting cattle during these years &gt;= also indicated. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">45 BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 TABLE VI— SUMMARY OF CATTLE TESTED IN NEBRASKA Period — 1918 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Number of Year Cattle Tested Reactors Per cent 1918 984 62 6.3 1919 ..: 18,315 1,204 5.5 1920 .;.,■ 49,792 2,002 4.0 1921...' 124,292 3,067 2.5 1922 203,532 5,704 2.5 1923.. 50,507 854 1.6 1924 211,835 3,276 1.5 1925 361,706 4,470 1.2 1926 476,841 5,140 1.1 1927.. 413,721 3,876 .9 1928... 368,445 3,601 1.0 1929 . ... 461,855 2,832 .6 19:50 447,232 2,483 .5 19151 267,371 2,037 .7 19:52 234,900 925 -3 19:53 148,307 588 .3 ' 19:54 (11 Months)..... 181,752 1,203 .6 Totals 4,021,387 43,324 1.8 Ave. PAR A -TUBERCULOSIS (JOHNE'S DISEASE) OF CATTLE This disease is characterized by a progressive emaciation and where it becomes established in a valuable herd of cattle, is of great economic importance. While this condition is not widespread in Nebraska, there are numerous herds so affected and when detected the owner should use every means at his command to eliminate it. Trained Veterinary assist - • ance is required to diagnose and recommend means for its eradication. TABLE VII— TESTS OF CATTLE FOR PARA-TUBERCULOSIS Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive TESTED Reactor INDEMNITY Herds | Cattle Cattle State Federal 5 1C5 6 $131.92 $131.92. Part 2 — December 1, 1933 to November 30,. 1934, Inclusive TESTED INDEMNITY , Cattle 1 Herds Cattle State Federal 4 180 5 $137.99 $137.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Bi^^^^^B Wm^^^W^BMlß WBP^^^^ (Courtesy C.B.&amp;Q.Ry.) Hog raising has proved a very profitable line of farming m the Republican Valley south of McCook. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 SCABIES Eradication of Scabies among cattle and sheep continues as a cooperative project between the Nebraska Department of Agriculture and Inspection and the United States Bureau of Animal Industry. States bordering Nebraska on the west have been particularly fortunate in being able to practically eliminate Scabies infection among cattle within their borders. In Nebraska there is apparently an increase in new centers of infection. As a result, it appears necessary that additional activities will have to be inaugurated through larger ap - propriations if Nebraska is to control and eventually eradicate this disease which is of great economic importance to the cattle herds in the range area. Nebraska, over a period of years, has been very fortunate in having excellent range conditions in the sandhill area with the exception of 1934. It has been the custom for herds of other states to be shipped in for grazing on account of drouth conditions existing in those states from which they are shipped. This, no doubt, has been one of the important causes of increased infection in our own state. Range inspection of herds is carried on by State and Federal field Veterinarians. Infected herds are quarantined for later dipping in approved dips under official supervision. NUMBER AND LOCATION OF HERDS OF CATTLE AFFECTED WITH SCABIES Period — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive Arthur 1, Boone 2, Cherry 13, Cuming 1, Douglas 1, Fillmore 1, Garden 15, Grant 6, Hooker 2, Jefferson 1, Keith 18, Lincoln 18, Mc- Pherson 1, Otoe 1. Perkins 1, Sarpy 3, Sheridan 7, Scotts Bluff 4, Sioux I, Webster 1. Total 98. NUMBER AND LOCATION OF BANDS OF SHEEP AFFECTED WITH SCABIES Period — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive Antelope 1, Cedar 1, Cuming 1, Dixon 1, Dodge 2, Madison 1, Sarpy 1. Total 8. NUMBER AND LOCATION OF HERDS OF CATTLE AFFECTED WITH SCABIES Period — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Antelope 1, Arthur 3, Box Butte 2, Cherry 22, Colfax 1, Cuming 3, Custer 1, Dawson 2, Gage 1. Garden 8, Grant 12, Hooker 3, Keith 12, Lincoln 18, Madison 1, Morrill 1, Sarpy 3, Saunders 3. Stanton 1, Sheri - dan 6, Thayer 1, Thomas 1, Webster 1, Wheeler 2. Total 109. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION NUMBER AND LOCATION OF BANDS OF SHEEP AFFECTED WITH SCABIES Period — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Cass 1, Dixon 2, Madison 2, Sarpy 1, Thurston 1, Wayne 1. Total &amp; TABLE VIII— INSPECTIONS AND DIPPINGS OF CATTLE ON AC - COUNT OF SCABIES Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH j (Sttli Lots | Involved Lots Cattle December 145 24,566 23 5,688 January 212 87,354 42 27,872 February 183 62,469 36 8,989 March 198 72,936 39 18,678 April 285 69,894 31 6,695 May 194 51,246 34 14,072 June 136 46,661 17 9,916 July 168 46,502 2 201 August 118 39,772 I 305 September 68 28,660 14 4,802 October 63 25,901 39 18,467 November.. 123 54,713 46 26,140 Total 1,893 610,674 324 141,925 Part 2 — December I, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive _ INSpECTI0N g DIPPINGS MONTH Cattle"" ~T~ Lots Involved Lptji Cattle December 129. 68,911 35 26,015 January 136 81,849 ' 23 24,684 February 118 53,633 60 31,867 March 143 52,976 48 13,941 April 169 71,710 50 7,712 May 110 48,855 26 9,330 June 69 23,950 0 0 July 58 18,793 2 600 August 68 28,261 1 1,861 September 53 21,373 14 8,868 October 50 29,728 42 18,088 November 84 63,565 57 48,686 Total 1,187 563,604 358 191,652 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 TABLE IX— INSPECTIONS AND DIPPINGS OF SHEEP ON ACCOUNT OF SCABIES Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH Sheep Lots Involved Lots Sheep December, 1932 ■ 9 3,653 4 124 January, 1933 9 7,414 3 135 February ... 3 139 2 89 March 3 G50 1 50 April 1 100 0 0 May 12 1,365 2 100 June : . . . 0 0 0 0 July 0 0 0 0 August .-. .0 0 0 0 September 0 0 0 0 October 0 0 0 0 November 1 107 0 0 Total . . . ~38 13,428 ~H 498 Part 2 — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive INSPECTIONS DIPPINGS MONTH Sheep ~~ Lots Involved Lots Sheep December, 1933 ' 2 214 2 214 January, 1934 9 14,736 2 68 February 4 2,725 1 25 March 0 0 0 0 April .....;.....: 6 ooo May _ 0 0 0 0 June. 0 0 0 0 July . .. .. 0 0 0 0 August 0 0 0 0 September 0 0 0 0 October 0 0 0 0 November 0 0 0 0 Total . . . ~I5 17,675 5 307 ANTHRAX Members of the forty-ninth session of the Legislature realizing the importance of providing for a more adequate arrangement for the con - trol of Anthrax in livestock passed House Roll No. 110, known as the Anthrax Law and appropriated $30,000.00 for enforcing the provisions thereof. The law provides for the quarantining and vaccination by the De - partment of infected herds and the enforcement of sanitary measures. Treatment of herds affected with Anthrax has been delegated tc local practicing Veterinarians on a per diem and mileage basis under State supervision. Regularly employed Veterinarians of the State have enforced quarantine and sanitation. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE X— ANTHRAX QUARANTINES ISSUED BY COUNTIES AND NUMBER OF LIVESTOCK INVOLVED Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive No. Quarantines No. Head of County Issued Livestock Antelope 1 47 Boyd 11 264 Cedar 7 478 Cuming 3 31 Dawes 3 234 Dixon 2 79 Douglas 1 70 Holt 2 163 Knox 38 1,824 Lancaster 1 97 Madison . 1 ' ' 48 Pierce 1 35 Thurston 1 455 13 Counties Total 72 3,825 During 1933, 41 cases have been treated at the State's expense. Death loss approximately 155 head of all classes of livestock. Treated at State's expense: 1233 cattle, 121 horses, 360 swine, 17 sheep. Part 2 — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive No. Quarantines No. Head of County Issued Livestock Antelope 1 14 Boone 4 791 Boyd 14 732 Cedar 3 70 Cuming 6 764 Holt 2 604 Knox 42 2,426 Madison 2 250 Merrick '. 1 55 Pierce.. 2 194 Stanton 3 448 Thurston 2 237 Washington 1 109 13 Counties Total 83 6,694 During 1934, 64 cases have been treated at the State's expense. Death loss approximately 231 head of all classes of livestock. Treated at State's expense: 2620 cattle, 295 horses, 735 swine, no sheep. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 BANG ABORTION DISEASE Increased attention has been given to the control and eradication of Bang's Disease especially during the last half of this biennium. This Department has had no special funds to carry this work forward so consequently efforts have been largely confined to State - owned herds. Congress, during the last session, made an emergency appropria - tion for livestock disease control work and of the amount appropriated an initial amount of $68,000.00 was allotted to Nebraska. Of this amount $56,000.00 is for indemnity payments on reacting cattle and 812,000.00 for operating expenses. Work under the new arrangement was commenced during the month of September, 1934. The State Department is cooperating through the furnishing of laboratory facilities and such other service and supplies as funds will permit. A special fund appropriated for State operating expenses for the furtherance of this important work in cooperation with the Federal Government would be highly commendable. TABLE XI— SUMMARY OF TESTS FOR BANG ABORTION DISEASE Part 1 — December 1, 1932 to November 30, 1933, Inclusive Herds Tested Reacting Cattle Non-Reacting Cattle Total State State State Cattle Private Owned Private Owned Private Owned 8 ' 29 ' 78 152 454 1,012 1,696 Part 2 — December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Herds Tested Reacting Cattle Non-reacting Cattle Total State State State Cattle Private Owned Private Owned Private Owned 23 23 335 61 1,994 663 3,053 SWINE DISEASES During the past biennium no serious outbreaks of swine diseases have occurred. It is remarkable in view of the low price prevailing for swine and the small amount of immunization against hog cholera practiced that a serious outbreak of this disease did not occur. There have been, as always, cases of hog Cholera reported at different points throughout the State, but the disease in no sense reached an epizootic form. Swine Erysipelas is a disease of swine which apparently is on the increase and although there has been some confusion in diagnosing </seg>
            <seg id="p056">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION this condition in the past, most graduate Veterinarians at the present time are equipped to fully identify this condition with available lab - oratory assistance. This condition yields quite readily to treatment where the cases are not too far advanced, and this, together with proper sanitary measures, familiar to the Veterinary profession and full co - operation of swine breeders, will prevent this condition from becoming wide-spread. In a general way, swine feeders and breeders have adopted a sani - tary, clean ground method of handling their hogs and where this pro - gram is followed carefully, practice has shown that the' common filth - borne diseases can be practically eliminated. While there are no serious outbreaks present in the State at the present time nor have been during the last biennium, swine raisers should not lessen their vigilance, as history reveals that serious out - breaks occur quickly and without warning and while hog prices as com - pared to feed prices are low at the present time, according to the best authorities, there is every reason to believe that the near future will command increased prices, which is additional reason for the proper care, particularly of choice breeding herds at this time. ENCEPHALOMYELITIS IN HORSES During the early fall of 1932 it appeared as if we were confronted with a serious situation, the result of Encephalomyelitis among horse - stock. The spread of the disease was of short duration, however. The period of the greater number of outbreaks reported was from September 15th to October 25th. The west central portion of the State and the southern half of the pan-handle section were probably the areas most involved although there were isolated outbreaks in practically every locality. Death loss was low and confined in the majority of eases to one animal of individual ownership. From the observations of our field Veterinarians and local practitioners we have formed no definite con - clusions as to mode of the dissemination of the disease or best method of treatment. The highest mortality rate was in the upper North Platte valley ex - tending from Torrington, Wyoming, to near Oshkosh, Nebraska, in the irrigated valley. Approximately one hundred and fifty horses died in this area. In York and Seward Counties the losses were on pastures and from hay receiving an exceedingly heavy rainfall during July. Losses started about August 10th. In Butler County losses occurred on creek bottom pastures with the first case reported August 13th. Lincoln County losses were along the Platte river near North Platte and started about September first. The irrigated valley near Imperial in Chase County was the location of a large number of cases. The condition developed here after Sep - tember 15. The Scottsbluff area was undoubtedly the most severely affected and in this district the disease was most virulent. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 Symptoms of the disease vary somewhat but in general from the onset there is a listless sleepy appearance, blindness, paresis of the throat muscles and incoordination of movement, with death occurring in from twenty-four to forty-eight hours. At no time does the animal become violent. In some cases death would occur after a duration of four or five days or longer. Practically all cases reported were either on pasture in the irrigated areas, along creek bottoms or those having an abnormally high rainfall. There "have been a few cases on higher pastures but it is thought that those isolated cases could be accounted for by having some access to areas such as previously described. Hay from such areas was also found to be a factor of almost equal importance when cut after August first. Death losses during the 1932 outbreaks were estimated at three hundred head. Few cases have been reported in 1933 and 1934. MALLEIN TESTS (GLANDERS) Some states still require Mullein tests for Glanders on all horse stock moved interstate, and the following table shows number of such tests applied. The one infected animal was suspected on clinical exami - nation by a Veterinary practitioner and on application of the Mallein test gave a very positive reaction. Glanders, several years ago, was considered the worst scourge of the horse raising industry, but a proper understanding of the disease lias made possible its almost complete eradication. The statutes provide for the payment of indemnity on horse-stock affected with Glanders, when such animals are at least one year old and have been owned and kept within the State for one year immediately preceding the date of the determination of the existence of such disease. The owner shall be entitled to reimbursement by the State in the sum of two-thirds of the appraised value thereof, but not to exceed $133.33 for any such animal so slaughtered. TABLE XII— SHOWING TESTS OF HORSE STOCK FOR GLANDERS TESTED INFECTED Indemnity PERIOD 1 1 Reimburse- Lots Animals Lots Animals ment December 1, 1932 November 30, 1933... 229 3,089 0 0 0 December 1, 1933 November 30, 1934... 344 4,052 1 1 $50.00 Totals 573 7,141 1 1 $50.00 PUBLIC LIVESTOCK SALES House Roll No. 642 known as The Public Livestock Sales Law was enacted by the Forty-ninth Session of the State Legislature. This law defines a public livestock sale under the meaning of the Act as applying to any person, firm or corporation engaged in the </seg>
            <seg id="p058">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION business of conducting a stockyards or sales pavilion where more than three hundred head of livestock is bought or sold monthly for purposes other than immediate slaughter through public auction or on a com - mission basis wholly or in part. Such livestock sales pavilions must furnish $1,000.00 bond and procure license for which a fee of $2.00 is collected by the Department. The law provides for health inspection of all livestock sold through these sales by licensed Veterinarians approved by the Department. The cost of inspection is paid by the person or persons conducting such sales. The law does not apply to stockyards under Federal supervision for health inspection by the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry, farm sales or sales conducted by livestock breed associations, 4-H Clubs or exposition societies where State or Federal inspection is maintained. Penalties are provided for violation of the law or regulations there - under. Since the enactment of this law 100 public livestock sales have been licensed. 87 are licensed at the time of filing this report. The $2.00 license fee from each sale pavilion is the only revenue received by the Department for regulatory supervision and is extremely inadequate. SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS Many requests for assistance are received during a two year period from livestock owners and Veterinarians in the diagnosis and treatment of animal diseases. The policy of the Department through its Bureau of Animal Industry is to render assistance supplementary to and in conjunction with that of the local Veterinary practitioner except in the event of infectious disease outbreaks of a nature requiring special direction of the Depart - ment in which event practicing Veterinarian's services are used as re - quired. Conditions met with are varied and each individual case requires special attention for the suppression or control of the disease present. The number of investigations and classes of animals involved for the two year period is shown below. TABLE XIII— SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS December 1, 1932 to December 1, 1933 to November 30, 1933 November 30, 1934 Incl. Incl. In Cattle 93 121 In Horses 84 9 In Swine 211 130 In Sheep 10 10 General 117 120 Totals. 515 390 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 RENDERING PLANTS The nature of work performed at these plants requires that strict sanitary measures be observed to protect the public health and to pre - vent the spread of livestock diseases. These plants are licensed under the provisions of the rendering plant law and Veterinarians of the Department make frequent inspec - tions to assure proper methods of operation. Number and location of licensed plants in the State are listed below. The following- Rendering plants were under license and inspection by the Department during the year: December 1, 1932, to November 30, 1933, Inclusive Beemer 1, Fremont 1, Grand Island 1, Lincoln, 2, LaPlatte 1, Nor - folk 1, South Omaha 3, Scottsbluff 1, Tecumseh 1, Wayne 1. Total 13. December 1, 1933, to November 30, 1934, Inclusive Beemer 1, Columbus 1, Fremont 1, Grand Island 1, LaPlatte 1, Lin - coln 2, Norfolk 1, Omaha 3, Scottsbluff 1, Tecumseh 1, Wayne 1. Total 14. LIVESTOCK IMPORTS AND EXPORTS Federal regulations govern the interstate movement of certain classes of livestock and each State has its own adopted regulations petting forth the conditions under which the various classes of animals will be eligible to enter. Graduate licensed Veterinarians approved by their State of resi - dence and the Federal Government are permitted to certify to the health of livestock destined for interstate movement and to make the necessary tests and inspections. All certificates are submitted to the Department for approval and statistics compiled of the number and various classes of livestock im - ported and exported. Drouth conditions prevailing particularly during the year 1934 have materially increased exports from Nebraska. TABLE XIV— LIVESTOCK IMPORTS Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 Class to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 Incl. Incl. Cattle for Feeding and Grazing (a) From Omaha Stockyards 75,410 40,869 (b) From Other Points 162,931 127,463 Cattle for Breeding and Dairy (a) Beef Breeds 100 436 (b) Dairy Breeds 2,922 3,938 Swine (a) From Public Stockyards 15,172 20,337 (b) From Other Points Interstate 127,053 33,427 Sheep for All Purposes (a) From Public Stockyards 27,153 32,703 (b) From Other Points Interstate 375,494 346,960 Horses— All Purposes 9,225 14,250 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION TABLE XV— LIVESTOCK EXPORTS Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 Class to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 Incl. Incl. Cattle (a) Dairy , 359 480 (b) Beef (Breeding Stock) 2,106 3,066 Swine — Breeding, All purposes 1,226 45,421 Sheep— All purposes 1,603 44,435 Horses — All purposes 10,441 22,106 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">DIVISION OP NURSERY AND BEE INSPECTION L. M. Gates, Entomologist REPORT OF ACTIVITIES DURING THE BIENNIUM FROM DECEMBER I, 1930 TO NOVEMBER 30, 1932 The Division of Nursery and Bee Inspection has the responsibility of carrying out the provisions of the Nursery Inspection Law, the Bee Inspection Law, the Insect Pest and Plant Disease Quarantine Law, the European Corn Borer Law, the Cedar Rust Law and the Pest Eradication Law. The purpose of these Laws is the control or eradication of plant pests and diseases now iound in the State and the exclusion of foreign pests and diseases. Service has been rendered to the citizens of Ne - braska under all of these measures during the past biennium with the single exception of the Pest Eradication Law. This Law provides for the eradication of such pests as prairie dogs, pocket gophers, and other destructive pests and although there have been requests for aid under this Law the lack of funds for the purpose have made it impossible to give much assistance. NURSERY INSPECTION The Nursery Inspection Law has operated very much as in previous years except that there have been fewer requests for inspection and the fees have been less. General business conditions will account for the reduction in number of inspections and the change in the Law made during the last session of the Legislature has been responsible for somej of the loss of fees. This change in the Law exempts many of the growers of nursery stock and cuts the fees in half for many others. However, the appropriation of $2500.00 granted by the Legislature in 1931 jfor this work has made it possible to continue the nursery inspec - tion service in spite of the smaller receipts in fees. In addition to the regular nursery inspections many inspections have been made of ship - ments of plants for individuals who wish to send nursery stock to friends by mail. BEE INSPECTION Under the Bee Inspection Law many more inspections were made during the past biennium for the beekeepers of the State than has been possible during any similar period in the past. Some counties were given service for the first time and other counties where the work has been carried on for two or three years have the amount of bee disease reduced to less than one per cent. A few counties have not been given inspection service because of their failure to remit the special tax of 10 cents per colony provided in the law. However, continued support of the law by the beekeepers should make it possible to inspect every colony of bees in the State every year and the great losses caused by American Foulbrood reduced to an insignificant amount. Should the inspection service be discontinued the benefits of the disease eradication accomplished would soon be lost. The amount of inspection work that can be done is directly depend - ent upon the amount of money available for the purpose. The 10-cent </seg>
            <seg id="p062">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION colony tax pays about one-half the cost of inspection and the balance has been paid from the appropriation, which was $3,000.00, for the present biennium. PLANT QUARANTINE Two quarantines are being maintained under the Insect Pest and Plant Disease Quarantine Law. The first to be promulgated was the Alfalfa Weevil Quarantine, which has been revised from time to time to prevent the introduction of the alfalfa weevil from western States where it has become established. If it should become established in Nebraska our alfalfa growers migj^t suffer serious losses both because of the destructiveness of the pest* and because of the quarantines that would prevent the movement of Nebraska hay to other States. The European Corn Borer Quarantine is. the second quarantine issued under the Insect Pest and Plant Disease Quarantine Law. This quarantine was necessary because of the revocation of the Federal quarantine on this subject and is the only quarantine protection Ne - braska now has against this serious insect pest. There are no funds available for the enforcement of either of the above quarantines. EUROPEAN CORN BORER LAW Grasshopper Control Under this law there was appropriated S2f&gt;, 000.00 for use in com - batting the European Corn Borer or other highly dangerous insects. It was from this fund that aid was given to a number of counties in their fight against grasshoppers during the past two years. As shown in the tabulated report of this division, $6,720.54 was given to 11 coun - ties in 1931 for the purchase of poison bait and $6,699.80 was given to 19 counties in 1932 for the same purpose. Some of the counties were able to match funds with the State in purchasing the bait and other.-. depended entirely upon State aid. Surveys made by representatives of the College of Agriculture ami the United States Department of Agriculture have shown that the poisoning program was effective in reducing the amount of grasshopper damage to crops and in reducing the number of eggs laid by the grass - hoppers. Very few eggs were found this fall in counties where an extensive poisoning program was carried out. The grasshopper outbreak has emphasized the need for an appro - priation that will be available in emergencies to combat insect pests such as European corn-borer, grasshoppers or other dangerous pests. Cedar Rust Control The Cedar Rust Law was made operative for the first time during the past year. At the request of a number of southeast Nebraska orchardists. investigations were made by this Department in four coun - ties. As shown in the appended tabulation, 2,437 cedar trees were re - moved by owners before the court enjoined the State from further action under the law. A hearing on the injunction was held at Omaha in October and the court has not yet handed down a decision. A summary of all the activities of this division is contained in the following tables: </seg>
            <seg id="p063">59 BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 I t REPORT OF NURSERY INSPECTION ACTIVITIES For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec 1, 1930 Dec 1, 1931 Total Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30. 1932 Bibnpium Nursery and Greenhouse Inspections . 178 143 t 321 Ccrtificati's ami Permits Issued: Nursery Inspection Certificates 140 122 262 Healers Certificates 76 S3 12* Agents Permits 131 69 200 Non-ilesirii-nt Permits 178 156 334 Duplicate Certificates 100 57 157 Total Certificates and Permits Issued 625 457 1,082 REPORT OF BEE INSPECTION ACTIVITIES For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec 1, 1930 Dec 1, 1931 Total to to for Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 Biennium County Inspectors Appointed 22 24 46 Counties AssiRned to Inspectors 51 59 65 Counties Remitting Bee Tax 3G 51 58 Counties KeceivinK Inspection Service 42 54 61 Apiaries Inspected 1,355 1,974 3,329 Apiaries Diseased (A. F. B.I 284 672 956 Per cent Apiaries Diseased (A. F. B.t 26.8% 34.0% 28.7% Colonii-9 Inspected 8,574 12,273 20,847 Colonies Diseased (A. F. B.I 1,481 1,390 2,871 Per cent Colonies Diseased (A. F. B. ) 21.8% 11.3%, 13.7% Diseased Colonies Burned 986 1,125 2,111 Diseased Colonies Treated " 412 437 849 Apiary Inspection Certificates Issued 7 9 16 REPORT OF CEDAR RUST CONTROL For the Bienninm December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 Total to to for Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 Biennium : Localities Requesting Investigation 8 8 Counties Involved '. 4 4 Apple Orchards Inspected 24 24 Acres of Apple Orchards Inspected 2,528 2,528 Cedar Tree Locations Inspected 307 307 Cedar Trees Condemned 4,139 4,139 Cedar Trees Removed by Owners 2,437 2,437 ■Cedar Trees Removed by State None None None REPORT OF GRASSHOPPER CONTROL For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec 1, 1930 Dec 1, 1931 Total to to for Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30. 1932 Biennium Investigations Made 31 23 54 Counties Given Investigational Assistance 11 17 28 Counties Given Financial Assistance 11 19 30 Cash Given Counties for Purchase of Poison Bait $6,720.54 $6,699.86 $13.420.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION REPORT OF CASH RECEIPTS For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 19:11 Total to to for Nov. :iO. 19:11 Nov. 30, 19.'I2 Biennium Nursery Inspection Certificates $1,597.20 $1,222.00 $2,819.20 Nursery Dealers Certificates 670.00 -190.00 1,160.00 Nursery Agents Permits 1:1:1.00 68.00 201.00 Duplicate Certificates 9.98 5.70 15.68 Apiary Inspection Certificates 7.00 9.00 16.00 Bee Tax from Counties t.I47.:)8 2,022.48 3,lli9.8G Cedar Rust Investigations 21.50 24.50 Total Cash Receipts for thp Division $:l.5SI.56 £1,841.68 $7.406.21 FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF NURSERY INSPECTION ACTIVITIES For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 COLLECTIONS Dec. 1, 19:10 Dec. I, 19:11 Total to to for Nov. 30. 1931 Nov. 30. 1932 ltionnium Certificates, Permits, Fef*. etr- . $2,272.98 " $1.984.20 $4.257.18 EXPENDITURES Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1. 1931 Total tn in for Nov.^lO,J9:U Nov. .-Ill, 1932 Biennium Salaries $1,210.00 $2,101.00 $5,31 1.00 Supplies ,......: .18.60 36.02 !&gt; I.G2 Expense ",-|7.49 514.99 1,072.18 Equipment 326.90 325.90 Repairs 91.91 77.45 169.36 Total $1.918.00 $1.058.36 $6,97r..3fi FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF BEE INSPECTION ACTIVITIES For the Biennium December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 COLLECTIONS Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1. 1931 Total to to - for Nov. 30. 1931 Nov. 30. 1932 Biennium Bee Tax from Counties $1.147.38 $2.022.48 $3.169.86 EXPENDITURES Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1. 1931 Total to to for Nov. 30. 1931 Nov. 30. 1932 Biennium Salaries. . $1,270.19 $4, 157.68 $5,427.87 Supplies 8.90 51.29 60.19 Expense 19.75 308.75 ! 328.50 Repairs 45.70 45.70 Total . . $1,298.8-1 $4.561.42 $5.862.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">BIENNIAL- REPORTS— -l'j:U-1932 AND 1933-1934 FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF GRASSHOPPER CONTROL ACTIVITIES For the Biennium December I, 1930, to November 30, 1932 EXPENDITURES From $25,000.00 Appropriation for Control of European Corn Borer and Other Dangerous Insect Pests Total for 1931 1932 Bii-nnium Aid lo Counties '. . . $6,720.51 $6,699.86 $13,420.40 Kxpcnw of Inspector 172.58 98.80 2/l.:l8 Mimeograph U&gt;tu&gt;r». . . . : 1: 11.20 11.20 Tolal KxpeiKlitun* .. ■ • . • ■ • • ...' ..--.; S6.89J.12 $6,809.86 $13,702.98 REPORT OF ACTIVITIES DURING THE BIENNIUM FROM DECEMBER 1, 1932, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1934 The work of this Division during the past two years has paralleled very closely that of the previous biennium. Approximately the same number of nursery and bee inspections have been made. During the first year of the biennium financial and advisory aid was given grass - hopper infested counties and during the second year cooperation was given the Federal program of grasshopper control, the State funds having been practically exhausted. Also, some time was given to the chinch bug control project in cooperation with Federal and other State agencies. The demands on this Division have increased steadily during the past four years because of the grasshopper and chinch bug outbreaks and it seems likely that in the future larger appropriations will be needed if the people of the State are to receive the services that should be given them in helping to solve their insect pest and plant disease problems. Nebraska still is comparatively free from the more dan - gerous pests, but each year there is greater possibility of infestation by some new insect or plant disease. For example, the Japanese beetle was found during the past year in Missouri, although it had previously been confined to the Eastern States. This insect caused serious injury to fruit and other horticultural crops and in ease it becomes established in Nebraska would cause immense losses. The fund of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000.00) originally appropriated for the control and eradication of the European Corn Borer or other dangerous pests and used in grasshopper control should be appropriated again for just such emergency. Also, the work of inspecting the bees of the State for bee diseases cannot be adequately carried on without the appropriation of at least $5,000.00 for the biennium. The same amount is needed to keep the nurseries of the State free from insect pests and plant diseases and to cooperate with the Federal authorities in any insect control campaigns that may be inaugurated in Nebraska during the next two years. It seems probable that this Division will be called upon to aid the Forest -Service in obtaining healthy trees for the shelter belt planting that is to </seg>
            <seg id="p066">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION' pe planted across the western part of the State and this will mean increased travel expenses and possibly some additional part time personnel. The enforcement of the alfalfa weevil quarantine has required more than the usual amount of attention because of drouth conditions. Numerous attempts have been made to bring into Nebraska alfalfa hay from Idaho and other western states that is infested with the alfalfa weevil. Several carloads of hay were turned back and the danger of the introduction of another serious pest into Nebraska apparently was avoided for the present. The responsibility of protecting Ne - braska from invasion by the alfalfa weevil and other dangerous insect pests and plant diseases rests upon this Division of the Department of Agriculture and Inspection and this responsibility cannot be properly met unless adequate support is given. L. M. GATES, Nov. 13, 1934. Entomologist. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">DIVISION OF SEEDS Sarah E. Cohen, Seed Analyst Nebraska is an agricultural State. The basic industry is the pro - duction of agricultural crops. Every successful farmer strives to produce the best possible crops, and today more than formerly he 'wants to know more about the seeds he plants so that his crops will bring him the most profits and the least losses. Enforcing the State Seed Law is a very essential part of Nebraska's government. It is primarily for the interest of the farmers of the State and secondarily for the protection of honest and careful seedsmen. It is the duty of the Seed Department to enforce the Seed Law, also to render service, give advice and information to farmers and those citizens who are engaged in the seed trade. In enforcing the law the true facts about the quality of seeds are revealed. When the true facts are revealed farmers and seedsmen have an opportunity to protect themselves by refusing to buy or plant seed which is of inferior quality. The State Seed Law requires that all agricultural seed offered for ,~ale must be properly labelled. Labelling requirements: (a) Commonly accepted name of such agricultural seed. (b) The purity of the seed, expressed as a percentage of the total weight. (c) The quantity of weed seeds, expressed as a percentage by weight. (d) The quantity of other crop seeds, expressed as a percentage by weight. (e) Noxious weeds in Nebraska are as follows: (1) Bindweed (Convolvulus arvensis). , (2) Wild Mustard (Brassica arvensis). (3) Quack Grass (Agropyron repens). (4) Wild Oats (Avena fatua). (5) All species of Dodder (Cuscuta spp.). (6) Canada Thistle (Cirsium arvense). If there is more than one seed of the noxious weeds in one-sixth {Ve) of an ounce of the agricultural seeds, its presence must be indi - cated on the label. If the seeds contain Canada Thistle, the presence of such seeds' must be indicated on the label. (f ) The germination or vitality of the seed. (g) The date on which germination test was made, (h) Full name and address of vendor. (i) Origin of seed or where grown. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION The regular inspectors of the Department of Agriculture and In - spection are instructed to visit all places of business where seeds are sold and collect samples of seed. Lots of seed are sampled which are not properly labelled. These samples are sent to the Seed Laboratory for an analysis. Sale is stopped on all seed not labelled in compliance with the law, until a report is sent back to the dealer as to the analysis on his seed and until he places the correct label on it. From 1926 to 1930 inspectors of the Department sampled 1,632 lots of seed which were improperly labelled. From 1930 until November 1, 1934, 884 lots of seed were found to be improperly labelled. This decrease may be due to the fact that seedsmen and farmers who sell seed are coming to realize more and more that compliance with the State Seed Law is the best policy. In the years 1926 to 1930, 13,133 samples of seed were sent to the Seed Laboratory for analysis. From 1930 until November 1st, 1934, 26,544 samples of seed were analyzed by the Seed Laboratory, which is over twice as many as were received the four previous years. This large increase in number proves that farmers and seedsmen are realizing that they are receiving valuable and indispensable service. From January 1st until November 1st of 1934, 9,570 samples of seed were tested. This is the largest number taken care of in the history of the Seed Laboratory in one year. More samples were received in the month of March, 1934, than in the entire year of 1926. Although the work of this Department has doubled in the last four years, the Seed Laboratory has used the same equipment that was in use the four previous years. New and more equipment is badly needed. WEED CONTROL In connection with the seed analysis this Department has much to do in helping control weeds. The control of weeds is one of the most difficult and expensive operations in agriculture. It is estimated that weeds cost Nebraska farmers $2.00 per tillable acre. Weeds in the United States as a tax on agriculture exact yearly a total in the aggre - gate estimated to be three billions of dollars. The weed problem is still of fundamental importance to the Ne - braska farmer and will be for years to come. However, in recent years the public has become more "weed minded," and more and more is being done' toward weed eradication. The Seed Laboratory in cooperation with the College of Agriculture and County Agents, has done much toward waging a war on weed pests. At the present time the worst weed pest in Nebraska is Bindweed (Convolvulus arvensis). It has become so bad that the last session of the Nebraska Legislature passed a law in regard to the eradication of it. In the last four years approximately 4,500 requests for copies of the Nebraska weed bulletin have been sent to the Seed Laboratory. Hundreds of circulars and letters giving information as to the eradica - tion of weeds have been sent out also. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 DIVISION OF SEEDS Identi- Identi- Year Inspec- Germina- Purity fication fication tions tion tests tests of plants of seeds 1926-1927:.... 405 2.840 1,994 212 154 1927-1928 415 3,377 2,973 112 76 1928-1929 359 2,112 1,588 137 66 1929-1930 453 4,804 3,329 218 15 1930-1931...,. 263 5,742 4,411 172 17 1931-1932.;.,. 296 5,802 4,906 217 10 19:52-1 933.:... 245 5,430 4,868 206 24 1933-1934 80 9,963 9,905 102 39 i This table shows a comparison of the work of the Seed Labora - tory from 1926 to December 1, -1934. Note the increase in number of tests made in 1934. DIVISION OF SEEDS Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 Total to to for Dec. 1, 1931 Dec. 1, 1932 Biennium Inspections 263 296 559 Germination tests 5,742 5,802 11,544 Purity Analysis 4,411 4,906 9,317 Identification of Plants. .... 172 217 389 Identification of Seeds 17 10 27 TOTAL 10,605 11,231 21,836 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 Total fl to to for Dec. 1, 1933 Dec. 1, 1934 Biennium Inspections \-\ . . 245 80 325 Germination tests ?. . . 5,430 10,345 15,775 Purity Analysis 4,868 10,301 15,169 Identification of Plants 206 102 308 Identification of Seeds 24 39 63 TOTAL... 10,773 20,867 31,640 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">DIVISION OF DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS AND OIL D. F. FELTON, Director ■'■■-'•'■■ \ ' • ' This Department is charged with the enforcement of approximately twenty-five laws and in presenting these Biennial Reports, it will be of some value to list the different laws that come under this. Department for enforcement. They are as follows: Gasoline and Kerosene Inspection Law Collection of the Gasoline Tax Law Pure Food Law Sanitary Food Law Cider and Vinegar Law Oleomargarine and Butterine Law Cold Storage Law Paint and Linseed Oil Law Livestock Remedy Law Commercial Fertilizer Law Commercial Feeding StulFs Law Dairy Law Hotel Law Potatoes — Grading of carlpt shipments Filled Evaporated and Condensed Milk Law Turpentine Law Serum and Virus Law Soft Drink Law Commission Merchants Law- Egg and Poultry Law- Collection of Beverage Tax Law- Imitation Butter and Dairy Products Law (H. R. 117) Weights and Measures Law Seed Inspection Law Apiary Law Nursery Inspection Law Pest Eradication Law Rendering Establishments Law Standard Loaf of Bread Law Tuberculin Law Cedar Rust Law BUREAU OF FOOD, DRUGS AND OIL The Division of Food, Drugs and Oil is composed of inspectors trained for inspection of food, drug and petroleum products. These inspectors are also employed in the regulation of sanitation on premises used for the manufacture or sale of food. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 The State is divided into thirteen (13) districts, each in charge ol an inspector responsible for the details of inspection work in that dis - trict. In addition, there are special inspectors whose duties are of a special nature, such as inspection of food factories, cream stations and for the investigation of complaints involving special qualifications. Each inspector is responsible directly to the Director or Chief of the Bureau and is required to submit regularly reports of all places visited and of all activities. LABORATORY The Laboratory Division comprises three chemists necessary in the analysis of samples submitted by inspectors to determine as to their freedom from adulteration or misbranding within the meaning of the law. Laboratory reports are made directly to the Chief of the Bureau and on the basis of such reports recommendations are made to the Director of the Department when it appears that the law has been vio - lated and legal proceedings are deemed advisable. Besides samples submitted by our inspectors, many samples are submitted by citizens of the State for analysis and inspection. A report is made on all work performed and if any irregularities are found, a warning notice is sent to the proper person. GAS TAX COLLECTION Tin' 1033 Session of the Legislature transferred the collection of the State gas tax to this Department. Bill for this transfer having been requested by the Governor, who, realizing that this Department maintained a force of twenty field inspectors who cover the entire State enforcing the Pure Food laws, knew that this Department was in a position to look after the collection of this tax with little or no addi - tional expense to the State. Further, that inasmuch as inspectors collected gas samples for our laboratory, they were in a position to look after collection of the tax where dealers were delinquent. The Legislature in Special Session, 1931, appropriated, out of the gas fund, $30,000.00 to the State Treasurer's office for use in covering the expense of collecting this tax. Collection of the tax was transferred to this Department April 25, 1933, and all except $3,764.07 had been spent. . The unexpended balance of this appropriation was spent by this Department in auditing the records of the Mona Motor Company, Council Bluffs, from which we collected $11,203.92, and in purchasing necessary equipment and records to carry on this work. Immediately upon assuming the responsibility of collecting this tax, the Governor having been informed by this Department and by gas dealers in all parts of the State, that thousands of gallons of gas were being imported each month by so-called gas bootleggers, who were evading the tax and not only defrauding the State of thousands of dollars, but hundreds of service stations were being driven out of busi - ness as they were unable to meet bootleg competition, a drive was </seg>
            <seg id="p072">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION immediately ordered by the Governor and nine extra men were employed for a period of approximately fifty days and numerous prosecutions against violators of this law were filed. A statement can be made now without fear of successful contradic - tion that there is no gas being illegally imported into this State; how - ever, sharp watch is being maintained at all times, which alone will protect the State from gas tax evasion. Under our present law a dealer can import 400,000 gallons of gas a year under a $1,000.00 bond, or an average of 33,334 gallons a month. Average tax on this amount per month is $1,333.36. He has until the fifteenth of each month to report and pay tax on the preceding month's importations which allows him to import for a period of forty-five days before making report and paying tax. The law should be amended and date of payment changed to the fifth of each month, or the amount of gallonage allowed to be imported under a $1,000.00 bond should be reduced. OIL AND MOTOR FUEL INSPECTION House Roll No. 388, passed by the 1933 Session of the Legislature and placed in the Department of Agriculture and Inspection for enforce - ment, was without question of more benefit to the public than any other law passed by this Legislature. Under the old method of inspecting fuels the importers left a quart sample of the fuels imported at their warehouses or service stations. Inspectors would inspect the sample and collect the inspection fee. In case the inspector was unable to locate the dealer he was forced to proceed on his trip and try it again probably two weeks later. Conse - quently, in all probability, one-half of all fuels imported into the State I were sold without being inspected and collection of all the inspection , fee due on fuels imported was an impossibility under the old law. Under the new law importers remit the inspection fee the same . time as the gas tax and on a separate report; hence, we are able to . check one report against the other and collect all of this fee. Inapec - . tors now collect samples of fuels from the service pumps and storage I tanks. I respectfully call attention to the fact that our laboratory has I analyzed approximately 11,428 samples of gas in the last ten months, and a total of 23,712 samples since April 25, 1933. A total of approxi - 'mately 40,000 samples of motor fuel have been analyzed during the four years of this administration. At least 30,000 of these samples have been taken direct from the service pumps at service stations. A total of 5,539 samples of fuel were analyzed by this laboratory during the prior four years. There are approximately thirty-five hundred gas service stations in the State from which we collect gas samples. At times we use as high as five stills in our laboratory to handle the volume of samples Collected. , Before this law was passed the State was flooded with bad gas and we were forced almost daily to stop the sale of gas in different stations throughout the State. Under the new. system we seldom secure a sample that does not meet State specifications, and we venture to say that in no other State do the users of gas receive a better quality. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 DAIRY The present Dairy law requires milk and cream, the source of all Other' dairy products, to be obtained under proper conditions as to the care and housing of cows. Also provides certain requirements for milk ami cream and all other dairy products from the time of their production or manufacture until they reach the hands of the ultimate consumer. One of the most important provisions of this law is the one requir - ing' all milk and cream used for consumption to be obtained from tested tows or to be pasteurized before being sold. Under this Act, all cows supplying milk and cream must be tested at least once each year and pronounced free from disease by a duly licensed veterinarian. This is designed to protect the health of our people of the State. In addition to dairy establishments and dairy products, this law also provides regulations as to the maintenance of cream receiving sta - tions and station operators. Each station must be in charge of an operator who is required to be licensed by the Department and before securing a license must pass a written examination and test demonstration before one of our Inspectors. The law provides a penalty for testing without a license or manipu - lating the Babcock Test in any way and requires that stations shall be maintained in a clean and sanitary manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION POOD AND SANITARY INSPECTIONS Perhaps no better service can be rendered the people of our State than an honest and faithful supervision of our food and sanitary laws. Food, as defined by the code, means any article used by man or domestic animals for food, drink, confectionery or condiment. A food establishment is any place used as a bakery, confectionery, cannery, dairy, creamery, cheese factory, packing house, slaughter house, restaurant, hotel kitchen, grocery, meat market or any other place in which food is kept, produced, prepared or distributed for com - mercial purposes. There are in round numbers, 8,938 of these places registered in Nebraska where food is prepared, stored or handled. The raw material must be free from all defects that tend to make it unfit for consump - tion. Its manufacture and distribution must comply with the various laws that have been found necessary to safeguard the million and a half people of the State, who are consuming each year more food pre - pared outside of the home. The putting of a law on our statute books, no matter how meri - torious it may be, is only half of what is necessary to obtain the results desired. The remaining half depends on enforcement. Of the thirty thousand inspections that were made during the year, fully half were devoted to the processing and selling of food. Two - thirds, if not more, of our food is sold in package form; that means wrapped or packed in a container, weighed or measured and labeled. Compliance with our labeling law is very essential, as it is the backbone of our food law; the main purpose of which is that the con - sumer must know what he is getting; how much he is getting, and who is responsible for it. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 LICENSES AND CERTIFICATES OF REGISTRATION DAIRY DIVISION Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 to to Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 TOTAL Commission Merchants 45 38 83 Cold Storage Warehouse 28 29 67 Cold Storage Inspection 25 25 50 Creamery 15G 149 305 Dairy ,- 124 157 281 Babcock Test 3,610 3,447 7,057 Temporary Permits 422 359 781 Retail Ice Cream 94 138 232 Wholesale Ice Cream 82 102 184 Cheese Factory 19 17 36 Retail Oleomargarine 2,059 1,516 3,575 Wholesale Oleomargarine 24 17 41 Oleomargarine Manufacture 1 1 2 Rendering Plants 13 12 25 Cream Station Permits 2,292 2,300 ' 4,592 Field Superintendents 51 42 . 93 Temporary Permits made regular 308 308 Live Stock Remedy 62 21 83 Commercial Fertilizer 11 13 24 Hog Cholera Serum 16 15 31 Soft Drinks 700 76 776 TOTAL LICENSES AND CER - TIFICATES 9,834 8,782 18,616 INSPECTIONS Dairy Establishments 62 52 114 Cream Receiving Stations 1,491 1,675 3,166 Re-inspections 78 1 79 Creameries 21 4 25 Ice Cream Manufacturers. 10 13 23 TOTAL DAIRY INSPECTIONS.. 1,662 1,745 3,407 MISCELLANEOUS Babcock Test Examinations 763 1,045 1,808 Dairy Notices 63 75 138 New Cream Receiving Stations 537 814 1,351 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION 1 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 TOTAL, Commission Merchants 36 32 68 Cold Storage Warehouse 28 32 60 Cold Storage Inspection 28 26 54 Creamery 149 153 302 Dairy 141 128 2G9 Babcock Test 4,076 4,051 8,127 Temporary Permits 500 641 1,141 Retail Ice Cream 190 183 373 Wholesale Ice Cream 97 84 181 Cheese Factory 16 15 31 Retail Oleomargarine 1,524 1,567 3,001 Wholesale Oleomargarine 15 16 31 Oleomargarine Manufacturing 1 1 Rendering Plants 13 16 29 Cream Station Permits 2,868 2,871 5,739 Field Superintendents 59 59 118 Temporary Permits made regular... 413 499 912 Live Stock Remedy 1.7 T.I !)0 Commercial Fertilizer 13 18 31 Hog Cholera Serum 18 24 J2 Soft Drinks 69 69 138 10,271 10.557 20,828 INSPECTIONS Dairy Establishments 88 30 118 Cream Receiving Stations 2,814 2.531 5,345 Re-inspections 33 25 58 Creameries 14 11 25 Ice Cream Manufacturers 11 8 19 TOTAL DAIRY INSPECTIONS... 2,900 . 2,005 . 5,565 MISCELLANEOUS Babcock Test Examinations 1,719 1,585 3,304 Dairy Notices 36 66 102 New Cream Receiving Stations 1,176 905 2,081 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 FOOD AND SANITARY INSPECTIONS Dec. 1,1930 Dec. 1,1931 Dec. 1, 1931 Dec. 1, 1932 TOTAL A. Groceries 3,986 3,809 7,795 B. Meat Markets 712 575 1,287 C. Bakeries and Confectioneries . . . 675 467 1,142 D. Drug Stores ..:.. 687 965 1,652 E. Soda Fountains 654 585 1,239 F. Miscellaneous and Food Factories 561 656 1,217 G. Bottling Works 9 22 31 H. Flour and Feed Mills 12 12 I. Sanitary Re-inspections 256 107 363 .1. Special Reports 903 1,006 1,909 K. Cold Storage 14 ..... 14 Total Drug and Food Inspections 8,469 8,192 16,661 MISCELLANEOUS A. Chemical Analyses Completed... 8,606 9,549 18,155 B. Sanitary Orders Issued 171 62 233 C. Prosecutions Filed .. 17 70 87 D. Prosecutions Terminated 16 69 85 E. Licenses Revoked 1 1 F. Tax on Commercial Feeding )• Stuffs 87360.9T 60208.4T 147569.3T — - -• . _i _ Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Dec. 1, 1933 Dec. 1, 1934 TOTAL A. Groceries.'..'..- 5,289 4,481 9,770 B. Meat Markets 1,000 736 1,736 C. Bakeries and Confectioneries . . . 582 468 1,050 P. Drug Stores 1,066 888 1,954 E. Soda Fountains 203 40 243 F. Miscellaneous and Food Factories 592 372 964 G. Bottling Works 4 1 5 H. Flour and Feed Mills I. Sanitary Re-inspections ........ 41 24 65 J. Special Reports 442 197 639 K. Cold Storage 12 12 Total Drug and Food Inspections 9,231 7,207 16,438 MISCELLANEOUS A. Chemical Analyses Completed. ..16,626 14,466 31,092 B. Sanitary Orders Issued 59 39 98 C. Prosecutions Filed 87 20 . 107 D. Prosecutions Terminated 87 20 107 E. Licenses Revoked F. Tax on Commercial Feeding Stuffs 48410.9T 76272.4T 124683.3T </seg>
            <seg id="p078">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION LICENSES AND CERTIFICATES OF REGISTRATION HOTEL DIVISION Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 to to Dec. 1, 1931 Dec. 1, 1932 TOTAL A. Hotels 687 693 1,380 B. Restaurants 3,780 3,513 7,293 C. Rooming Houses 720 556 1,276 D. Boarding Houses 128 102 230 E. Aplartment Houses 248 202 450 P. Concessions 448 ■ 336 784 .■■.-. ■ Total Certificates of Registration 6,011 5,402 11,413 , SANITARY INSPECTIONS A. Hdtels 329 360 689 Re-inspections 92 6 98 B. Restaurants and Hotel Kitchens. 2,504 2,565 5,069 Re-inspections 210 35 245 C. Rooming Houses 392 236 628 Re-inspections 8 2 .10 D. Boarding Houses 6 8 14 Re-inspections 2 2 E. Apartment Houses 80 54 134 Re-inspections ..... F. Concessions 91 22 113 Total Inspections 3,714 3,288 7,002 SANITARY ORDERS ISSUED A. Hotel Notices 87 13 100 B. Restaurant and Hotel Kitchens . . 226 54 280 C. Rooming Houses ?Tt 24 7 , 31 D. Boarding Houses 8 8 E. Apartment Houses 1 1 Total Notices Issued 346 74 420 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Dec. 1, 1933 Dec. 1, 1934 TOTAL A. Hotels 559 472 1,031 B. Restaurants 3,910 3,630 7,540 C. Rooming Houses 447 323 770 D. Boarding Houses 75 55 130 E. Apartment Houses 188 138 326 F. Concessions 308 198 506 Total Certificates of Registration 5,493 4,816 10,309 -■■-■■ ' ■ .;■,■■■..■;■■. • ■ ■ .... SANITARY INSPECTIONS A. Hotels 351 157 608 Re-inspections 2 1 3 B. Restaurants and Hotel Kitchens. 3,390 2,909 6,299 Re-inspections 32 10 42 C. Rooming Houses 254 69 323 Re-inspections ..... D. Boarding Houses 6 4 10 Re-inspections E. Apartment Houses 97 16 113 Re-inspections F. Concessions 36 168 204 Total Inspections 4,168 3,334 7,502 SANITARY ORDERS ISSUED A. Hotel Notices 4 3 7 B. Restaurant and Hotel Kitchens.. 60 14 . 74 C. Rooming Houses 3 3 D. Boarding Houses E. Apartment Houses Total Notices Issued 67 17 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION ANALYSIS COMFLETED IN LABORATORY Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 to to Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 TOTAL Alimentary Pastes ,'5 18 21 Beverages 74 85 159 Bread 71 5 76 Butter 495 385 880 Butter Substitutes 27 47 74 Candy 28 3 SI Canned Goods 43 4 47 Cereals 6 1 7 Cheese .26 2 28 Coffee and Tea 7 2 '.» Drugs (58 64 132 Eggs • 11 ..... 11 Extracts 32 16 48 Feeds— Commercial 91)8 647 1,645 Fish and Fish Products ..... Flour 4 4 8 Fruits 16 3. 19 Gasoline 4,891 6,406 11,297 Ice Cream 281 320 601 Jell and Jell Products 3 2 5 Kerosene and Tractor Fuel 97 513 C10 Liquor 553 477 1,030 Live Stock Remedies 22 1 23 Meat and Meat Products 26 5 31 Milk and Cream 626 430 1,056 Miscellaneous 77 .93 1 70 Nuts and Nut Products 7 ..... 7 Pastry 32 2 34 Oils— Edible 12 . 12 Saccharine 8 8 Spices and Condiments 37 9 46 Vegetables 9 9 Vinegar 16 5 21 Total 8,606 9,549 18,155 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to ' to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 3D, 1934 TOTAL Alimentary Pastes 20 20 Beverages 29 209 238 Bread 1 12 13 Butter 192 118 310 Butter Substitutes 3 16 19 Candy 1 2 3 Canned Goods 1 5 6 Cereals 2 2 Cheese 14 14 Coffee, Tea, Cocoa 1 2 3 Drugs 12 6 18 Eggs 1 1 Extracts 23 23 Feeds — Commercial 349 403 752 Fish and Fish Products ,..., ,.... Flour 2 2 Fruits 13 1 14 Gasoline 13,924 Ili748 25,672 Ice Cream 64 12 7G Jell and Jell Products Kerosene and Tractor Fuel 1,102 1,151 2,253 Linseed Oil '. 2 2 Liquor 281 237 518 Live Stock Remedies 3 3 Meat and Meat Products 33 15 48 Milk and Cream 534 391 925 Miscellaneous 18 22 40 Xuts and Nut Products 1 1 Pastry Poison Bran 55 55 Oils— Edible 3 17 20 Saccharine 2 2 Spices and Condiments 4 4 Vegetables 1 1 Vinegar 16 18 34 Total 16,626 14,466 31,092 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">m ■f&gt;,m iJHj , &gt; I ?"/."•' pLJ-'i^ 111 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1032 AND 1933-1934 EGGS AND POULTRY The 1929 Statutes provided that every person, firm or corporation buying eggs in this State for re-sale were required to candle all eggs except during the months of January, February, March and April. The Legislature of 1931 amended this law, making it compulsory to candle all eggs purchased for re-sale during every month of the year. Also required every person or corporation purchasing eggs or poultry for re-sale to first secure a permit from this Department authorizing the applicant to engage in such commerce and applicant was required to pay a fee of $1.00. This permit covered the buying or re-sale of eggs and poultry, or both. The law did not make clear whether the permit was to be renewed each year or not. The Attorney General's office gave an opinion that we could collect but once. Receipts received from the sale of these permits were expended on enforcing this law. A great many commer - cial truckers were stopped on the highways and the loads of eggs were inspected for candle slips required by the law. Several prosecutions were brought against dealers for violation. This law should be amended and dealers required to renew permits each year and the money collected should be spent entirely in behalf of this industry. ■ The amendment to this law was of vital importance to the public as it prohibited the sale of inedible or incubator rejects for human con - sumption, caused all eggs placed in incubator for hatching to be in - delibly marked, prohibited the sale of eggs, case count, and where an excessive number of inedible eggs were found in a case, although a candle certificate was contained therein, made prima facie evidence of violation of the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION: BREAD LAW The law known as the Standard Bread Law was passed by the 1931 Session of the Legislature, but did not become effective until February 19, 1934. Enforcement of this law was assigned to the Department of Agriculture and Inspection for enforcement and Department given authority to promulgate rules and regulations necessary to effectively enforce the Act. The law, however, sets up and prescribes the different weights at which bread may be sold as follows: "Every loaf of bread made for sale in this State shall be of the following weights: One-half pound, one pound, one and one - half pounds, and also in exact multiples of one pound and of no other weights. Whenever twin or multiple loaves are baked, the weights herein specified shall apply to each unit of the twin or multiple loaf, provided that a twin one and . one-half pound loaf may be made and sold, but units of said loaf must not be sold separately." This law did not apply to fancy breads. Under the rules and regu - lations prescribed and promulgated by this Department the following tolerance or excess variations in weight for bread baked for sale in this State: (a) One and one-half ounces for one-half pound loaves. (b) Three ounces for one pound loaves. (c) Four and one-half ounces for one and one-half pound loaves. (d) Six ounces for two pound loaves. (e) The same relative tolerance for loaves of larger size permitted to be sold under said Act. Without question this law has been of great benefit to the consum - ers of bread and has in no way worked a hardship on the baking in - dustries. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">BIENNIAL REPORTS — 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 I .:,■•"'.■ ■ ■■;■'■■ ■ DIVISION OF WEIGHTS AND MEASURES I- ' The law requires that this Department inspect every commercially used scale, pump, and measure in the State (except in the city of Omaha) each year. January 1, 1932, the Governor, realizing the impossibility of testing large heavy duty scales, such as are used in elevators, mills, and coal yards with five hundred pound test weights, which" were then carried by inspectors, ordered the purchase of two l'/fe-ton trucks which would carry up to three thousand pounds in test weights. Up until 1932 live stock companies were required to have Federal inspection of their scales. This Department interceded with the Federal Government in their behalf and were fortunate in having the Federal Department accept State tests after establishing the trucks, which proved the saving of hundreds of dollars to owners of this class of .scale. This Department employs a field force of seven men, including the Chief of the Scale Department. Before putting on these trucks in January, 1932, the State was divided into five districts with an inspector for each district who drove his own car and received eight cents per mile for its use. In addition a Chief Scale Inspector maintained an bffice in this Department and directed field operations. Under this administration and under the new system we employ seven men, two men to each truck, two men with cars to inspect light scales and who jreceive five cents per mile for the use of their car, and the Chief In - spector who, while having an office here, spends 90 per cent of his time in the field testing scales. In 1932 the inspection of all scales in Lincoln, formerly done by the city, was turned over to the State for State inspection. Use of these trucks has not only given owners of heavy duty scales more accurate tests, but has proven to be less expensive to the State which reports of former years will show. The Department should purchase another truck, discontinue the use of light cars entirely; also dispense with the services of an office inspector, employ six men, two to each truck, which will give the scale owners the service they are entitled to, and prove a saving of consider - able money to the State. Under the former administration this De - partment employed six inspectors. We have added but one additional inspector, which became necessary upon our taking over inspection work in the city of Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION INSPECTION OF WEIGHTS AND MEASURES LINCOLN AND STATE Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 to to Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 TOTAL Scales Sealed 13,940 13,373 27.313 Scales Condemned 37 169 206 Pumps Sealed 6,567 7,425 13,992 Pumps Condemned 5 22 27 Measures Sealed 19 19 Measures Condemned G 6 Weights Sealed Weights Condemned Total Inspections 20,574 20,989 41,563 Scales Released 7 70 77 Pumps Released 4 25 29 Slot Weighing Machines 680 838 1,518 OMAHA Dec. 1,1930 Dec. 1,1931 to to Nov.30,1931 Nov.30,1932 TOTAL Scales Sealed 1,704 1,446 3,150 Scales Condemned 93 76 169 Pumps Sealed 748 777 1,525 Pumps Condemned 20 14 34 Measures Sealed 244 266 510 Measures Condemned • Weights Sealed 1,234- 1,171 2,405 Weights Condemned 17* 204 221 Total Inspections 4,060 3,954 8,014 Scales Released Pumps Released 30 Bonded Scales 120 120 240 (City scales) checked every 90 days. TOTAL NUMBER OF INSPECTIONS Dec. 1,1930 Dec. 1,1931 to to Nov.30,1931 Nov.30,1932 TOTAL Lincoln and State 20,574 20,989 41,563 Omaha 4,060 3,954 8,014 TOTAL INSPECTIONS 24,634 24,943 49,577 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 LINCOLN AND STATE Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 TOTAL Scales Sealed 13,828 16,257 30,085 Scales Condemned 239 323 562 Pumps Sealed 7,975 9,276 17,251 Pumps Condemned 50 53 103 Measures Sealed 3 3 Measures Condemned 4 ■ 2 6 Weiphts Sealed Weights Condemned Total Inspections 22,099 25,911 48,010 Scales Released 77 155 232 Pumps Released 30 29 59 Slot WeitfhinK Machines 872 824 1,696 OMAHA Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 TOTAL Scales Sealed 1,154 1,795 2,949 Scales Condemned 56 12 68 Pumps Sealed 1,177 1,191 2,368 Pumps Condemned 89 36 125 Measures Sealed 508 257 765 Measures Condemned 71 44 115 Weights Sealed 1,241 416 1,657 Weights Condemned 91 14 105 Total Inspections 4,387 3,765 8,152 Scales Released 12 12 24 Pumps Released 39 34 73 30 Bonded Scales 120 120 240 (City scales) checked every 90 days. TOTAL NUMBER OF INSPECTIONS Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30, 1934 TOTAL Lincoln and State 22,099 25,911 48,010 Omaha 4,387 3,765 8,152 TOTAL INSPECTIONS 26,486 29,676 56,162 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION POTATO INSPECTION This inspection work is in cooperation with the Bureau of Agricul - tural Economics and is in force in the counties of Kimball, Dawes, Mor - rill and Sheridan. This inspection is not compulsory unless 51 per cent of the commercial potato growers in a county demand the work. State law setting up this inspection was passed by the 1929 Legisla - ture and inspection fee was set at four dollars ($4.00) per carload. Two dollars ($2.00) of this amount was allowed for the inspector for his work, one dollar ($1.00) was paid to the Federal Department and one dollar ($1.00) retained by this Department. Believing the four dollar (§4.00) per car charge to be prohibitive, the matter was taken up by this Department with the Federal Depart - ment at Washington and they agreed if the law was amended and fee cut to two dollars and fifty cents ($2.50) per car, as suggested by this Department, they would be willing to accept fifty cents (SOo) per car, pay the inspector one dollar and fifty cents ($1.150 ) per car, which would leave this Department fifty cents (50c) per car. A bill to amend the law was passed by the Legislature of 19153, re - ducing fee as requested. The following gives the total number of carloads of potatoes Fed - eral-State inspected from December 1, 1930, to November 1. 1934: Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 to to • Dec. 1, 1931 Dec. 1, 1932 _ _TOTAL__^ 7,694 4,422 12,116 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 to to Dec. 1,1933 Nov. 1, 1934 TOTAL 1,087 1,721 2,808 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 BEER The Legislature of 1933 passed House Roll No. 585, which legalized the manufacture and sale of beer, ale, porter, stout and other malt, brewed and fermented beverages containing not to exceed 3.2 per centum of alcohol by weight and imposed a State tax of 93£ for every barrel containing not more than thirty-one gallons. This law went into effect August 10, 1933, tax to be collected on all above beverages brewed, manufactured or imported for sale in this State, this tax to be paid to the Director of the Department of Agricul - ture and Inspection who shall deliver the net receipts from this tax to the State Treasurer. The cost of collecting this tax has been high in comparison with collection of other Bureaus on account of the fact that the law states every beer dealer in the State shall submit, on forms to be furnished by the Department, a monthly report of beverages handled by them. There are approximately thirty-two hundred beer dealers in the State, which means that number of reports received each month. These re - tailers' reports are checked and compared with reports submitted by brewers, importers and distributors who pay the tax. One can readily understand the work involved by the checking of thirty-two hundred reports each month and the heavy cost of postage and supplies. Up and until the last few months rtfne people were employed in this Department to carry on this work of collecting the tax, filing and checking all reports. Under our new bookkeeping and filing system we have been able to reduce the total number of employees to six. This Department has no authority other than to collect the tax and if any dealer neglects or refuses to pay, we are forced to bring civil action in the courts, so it is necessary that a strict check on accounts be kept at all times. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION EXPENDITURES OF DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE December 1, 1930, to November 30, 1932 Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 Total to to For Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 Biennium DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS, OIL, MARKETS AND MARKET - ING Salaries $ 74.1G7.70 $ 73,302.03 $147,469.73 Supplies 4 825.99 3,499.82 8,325.81 Expense 42,284.36 39,677.66 81,962.02 Repairs 510.11 855.63 1,365.74 Equipment 2,056.10 2,657,47 4,713.57 Fixed Charges 70.00 47.43 117.43 Total $123,914.26 $120,040.04 • $243,954.30 ANIMAL INDUSTRY - GENERAL ACTIVITIES Salaries '. $10,805.93 $11,019.96 $21,825.89 Supplies 1,618.27 409.17 2,027.44 Expense 1,564.95 1,450.47 3,015.42 Repairs 203.62 194.54 398.1G Equipment 1,338.22 50.80 1,389.02 Fixed Charges 35.00 35.00 70.00 Total $ 15,565.99 $ 13,159.94 $ 28,725.9:1 ERADICATION OF BOVINE TUBERCULOSIS Salaries $ 31.222.76 $ 30,439.91 $ 61,602.67 Supplies 382.22 945.66 1,327.88 Expense 24,468.62 ■ 16,758.57 41,227.19 Repairs 70.78 519.09 589.87 Equipment 465.45 23.00 488.45 Fixed Charges 58,355.01 17,082.47 75,437.48 Total $114,964.84 $ 65,768.70 $180,733.54 eradication! of scabies, swine and chicken diseases Salaries , $ 7,961.45 $ 5,641.74 $ 13,603.19 Supplies ! 81.38 132.70 214.08 Expense ' 2,728.91 2,167.03 4,895.94 Repairs L 489.55 624.55 1,114.10 Equipment [ 294.75 767.01 1,061.76 I Total $11,556.04 $ 9,333.03 $20,889.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">I; BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Salaries $ 3,210.00 $ 2,104.50 $ 5,314.50 Supplies 58.60 36.02 94.62 Expense 557.49 514.99 1,072.48 Repairs 91.91 77.45 169.36 Equipment 325.90 325.90 Total $ 3,918.00 $ 3,058.86 $ 6,976.86 POTATO INSPECTION I Salaries § 9,845.08 $ 7,295.67 $ 17,140.75 Supplies 83.73 28.80 112.53 Expense 536.18 593.62 1,129.80 Equipment 40.17 40.17 Total $ 10,505.16 $ 7,918.09 $ 18,423.25 BEE INSPECTION Salaries $ 1,270.19 $ 4,157.68 $ 5,427.87 Supplies 8.90 51.29 60.19 Expense 19.75 308.75 328.50 Repairs 45.70 45.70 Total : $ 1,298.84 $ 4,563.42 $ 5,862.26 '..■''-.' I ■ . ■■;...- ■'..... ERADICATION OF CORN BORER Supplies $ 6,680.65 $ 6,364.75 $ 13,045.40 Expense 125.43 101.93 227.36 Repairs 47.15 8.07 55.22 Total $ 6,853.23 $ 6,474.75 $ 13,327.98 GRAND TOTAL $518,893.19 GENERAL SUMMARY Salaries $272,444.60 Supplies 25,207.95 Expense 133,858.71 Repairs 3,738.15 Equipment 8,018.87 Fixed Charges 75,624.91 Total $518,893.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION EXPENDITURES OF DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION December 1, 1932, to November 30, 1934 Dec. 1, 1932 Dec. 1, 1933 Total to to For Nov. 30,1933 Nov. 30, 1934 Biennium DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS, OIL, MARKETS AND MARKET - ING Salaries ? 74,332.77 $ 74,280.24 $148,613.01 Supplies 4,031.92 4,317.86 8,349.78 Expense 40,131.66 39,472.01 79,603.67 Repairs 1,125.89 1,057.42 2,183.31 Equipment 2,803.69 1,411.02 4,214.71 Fixed Charges 25.53 21.74 47.27 Total ". $122,451.46 $120,560.29 $243,011.75 ANIMAL INDUSTRY - GENERAL ACTIVITIES Salaries $ 9,336.63 $ 8,454.96 $17,791.59 Supplies 716.40 337.05 1,053.45 Expense 2,222.53 1,470.05 3,692.58 Repairs 489.33 92.46 581.79 Equipment 637.97 32.25 670.22 Total $ 13,402.86 $ 10,386.77 $ 23,789.63 ERADICATION OF BOVINE TUBERCULOSIS Salaries $17,157.98 $15,310.93 $32,468.91 Supplies 317.53 494.27 811.80 Expense 10,882.70 7,326.38 18,209.08 Repairs 132.67 224.53 357.20 Equipment 265.00 265.00 Fixed Charges 7,883.59 11,429.18 19,312.77 Total $ 36,374.47 $ 35,050.29 $ 71,424.76 ERADICATION OF ANTHRAX Salaries $ 1,774.70 $ 3,510.00 $ 5,284.70 Supplies 939.20 3,060.68 3,999.88 Expense 1,295.05 2,346.36 3,641.41 Repairs 158.72 158.72 Equipment 328.50 328.50 Total $ 4,008.95 $ 9,404.26 $ 13,413.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 ERADICATION OF SCABIES, SWINE AND CHICKEN DISEASES Salaries ? 4,403.00 $ 4,320.00 $ 8,723.00 Supplies 351.69 64 . 94 * ' 416 63 Expense 1,522.69 1,281.04 2,803.73 Repairs 424.54 456.74 881.28 .Equipment 311.10 311.10 Total $ 6,701.92 $ 6,433.82 $ 13,135.74 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Salaries $ 1,290.00 $ 1,600.00 $ 2,890.00 Supplies 59.47 52 . 4 i 111.88 Expense 628.42 603.94 1,232.36 Repairs 247.61 189.47 437.08 Equipment 289.80 289.80 Fixed Charges 15.00 15.00 Total $ 2,240.50 $ 2,735.62 $ 4,976.12 POTATO INSPECTION Salaries $ 1,680.00 $ 2,247.83 $ 3,927.83 Supplies 24.63 24.63 Expense 464.46 394.90 859.36 Equipment 34. 18 34 18 Total $ 2,144.46 $ 2,701.54 $ 4,846.00 BEE INSPECTION Salaries $ 2,293.00 $ 2,212.96 $ 4,505.96 Supplies 11.15 20.35 31.50 Expense ; 127.73 66.00 193.73 5?P B . lr * 40.65 4.90 45.55 Fixed Charges 20.00 20.00 Total ..$ 2,472.53 $ 2,324.21 $ 4,796.74 ERADICATION OF CORN BORER Salaries $ 185.00 $ 185.00 Supplies 11,134.06 $ 1.50 11,135.66 Total $11,319.06 $ 1.50 % 11,320.56 PUBLIC LIVESTOCK SALES* Equipment $ 200.00 $ 200.00 Total $ 200.00 $ 200.00 961056A </seg>
            <seg id="p094">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION BEER TAX** Salaries $ 1,674.52 $ 11,554.77 $ 13,229.29 Supplies 413.95 594.28 1,008.23 Expense 870.98 3,692.94 4,563.92 Repairs 3.55 1.00 4.55 Equipment 130.80 412.85 543.65 Fixed Charges 26.58 113.63 140.21 Total $ 3,120.38 $ 16,369.47 $ 19,489.85 GASOLINE TAX COLLEC - TION*** Salaries $ 1,432.77 $ 112.50 $ 1,545.27 Supplies 1.45 1.45 Expense 1,675.39 5.95 1,681.34 Repairs 15.85 15.85 Equipment 284.40 284.40 Total $ 3,409.86 $ 118.45 $ 3,528.31 GRAND TOTAL $413,932.07 GENERAL SUMMARY Salaries $239,164.56 Supplies 26,944.79 Expense 116,481.18 Repairs 4,665.33 Equipment 7,141.56 Fixed Charges 19,535.25 Total $413,932.67 ♦Law effective August, 1933. ♦♦Law effective August 10, 1933. ♦♦♦Balance of 1929 appropriation, transferred from State Treasurer's office April 25, 1933. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 RECEIPTS OF DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION BUREAUS OF DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS, OIL, MARKETS AND MARKETING Dec. 1, 1930 Dec. 1, 1931 Total to to For Nov. 30, 1931 Nov. 30, 1932 Biennium Gasoline and Oil Inspection Fees.$ 83,608.60 $ 74,341.22 $157,949.82 Babcock Test Permits 8,064.00 7,612.00 15,676.00 Cream Station Permits 4,584.00 4,600.00 9,184.00 Field Superintendents Permits.. . 102.00 84.00 186.00 Dairy and Creamery Permits 3,369.00 3,325.00 6,694.00 Cheese Factories 222.00 194.00 416.00 Commission Merchants and Cold Storage Permits 590.00 525.00 1,115.00 Retail Ice Cream Permits 94.00 138.00 232.00 Wholesale Ice Cream Permits.. . 410.00 510.00 920.00 Retail Imitation Butter Permits. 2,059.05 1,516.00 3,575.05 Wholesale Imitation Butter Per - mits 600.00 425.00 1,025.00 Manufacturer Imitation Butter. . 100.00 100.00 200.00 Livestock Remedy Registration. . 310.00 105.00 415.00 Commercial Fertilizer 220.00 280.00 500.00 Bottlers License 700.00 740.00 1,440.00 Rendering Establishments 650.00 600.00 1,250.00 Cold Storage Inspection 735.00 695.00 1,430.00 Weights and Measures 28,162.50 26,797.75 54,960.25 Hotel, Restaurant, Rooming House, Apartment and Concession Permits 13,443.00 11,943.00 25,386.00 Commercial Feeding Stuff 8,736.09 6,020.84 14,756.93 Refund on Liquor Cases 271.75 318.05 589.80 Seed Inspection 132.00 134.00 266.00 Miscellaneous Reports, etc 35.65 16.58 52.23 Eggs and Poultry* 3,634.00 1,491.00 5,125.00 Total $160,832.64 $142,511.44 $303,344.08 POTATO INSPECTION Certificates of Inspection $15,498.00 $ 8,846.00 $24,344.00 DIVISION OF GRAIN WAREHOUSE AND FARM STORAGE** Permits Issued, etc 24.00 24.00 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Nursery Certificates, Permits, and Inspections 2,272.98 1,984.20 4,257.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION BUREAU OP ANIMAL INDUSTRY Refunds from Counties: Bovine Tuberculosis 21,338.23 6,062.64 27,400.87 DIVISION OF BEE INSPECTION Bee Tax Remitted by Counties. . . 1,147.38 2,022.48 3,169.86 GRAND TOTAL $201,113.23 $161,426.76 $362,539.99 ♦Law effective August, 1931. "Transferred to Railway Commission, July, 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">BIENNIAL REPORTS— 1931-1932 AND 1933-1934 RECEIPTS OF DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION BUREAUS OF DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS, OIL, MARKETS AND MARKETING Dec. 1, 1932 Dec 1, 1933 Total to to For Nov. 30, 1933 Nov. 30,1934 Biennium Gasoline and Oil Inspection Fees $ 79,099.71 $ 85,468.32 $ 164,568.03 Babcock Test Permits 9,152.00 9,384.00 18,536.00 Cream Station Permits 5,736.00 5,742.00 11,478.00 Field Superintendents Permits. 118.00 118.00 236.00 Dairy and Creamery Permits.. 3,276.00 3,492.00 6,768.00 Cheese Factories 184.00 . 192.00 376.00 Commission Merchants and Cold Storage Permits 500.00 480.00 980.00 Retail Ice Cream Permits 190.00 183.00 373.00 Wholesale Ice Cream Permits. . 485.00 420.00 905.00 Retail Imitation Butter Permits 1,524.00 1,567.00 3,091.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter Per - mits 375.00 400.00 775.00 Manufacturer Imitation Butter. 100.00 100.00 Livestock Remedy Registration 85.00 365.00 450.00 Commercial Fertilizer 260.00 360.00 620.00 Bottlers License 690.00 690.00 1,380.00 Rendering Establishments 650.00 800.00 1,450.00 Cold Storage Inspection 710.00 690.00 1,400.00 Weights and Measures 24,018.20 26,474.07 50,492.27 Hotel, Restaurant, Rooming House, Apartment and Con - cession Permits 12,188.00 10,597.00 22,785.00 Commercial Feeding Stuff 4,841.09 7,627.24 12,468.33 Refund on Liquor Cases 191.60 198.55 390.15. Seed Inspection 144.24 106.00 250.24 Miscellaneous Reports, etc 1.85 1.85 Eggs and Poultry 924.00 815.00 1,739.00 Total $ 145,443.69 $ 156,169.18 $ 301,612.87 POTATO INSPECTION Certificates of Inspection $ 1,819.00$ 1,744.00$ 3,563.00 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Nursery Certificates, Permits, and Inspections 1,770.50 1,788.90 3,559.40 BUREAU OF ANIMAL INDUSTRY Refunds from Counties: Bovine Tuberculosis ' 8,763.95 3,900.75 12,664.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE AND INSPECTION in VISION OF BEE INSPECTION Bee Tax Remitted by Counties. 1,194.06 1,905.79 3,099.85 DIVISION OF GASOLINE TAX* Tax Collected 4,945,178.22 8,512,041.18 13,457,219.40 BEER TAX** Tax Collected 50,741.62 266,384.20 317,125.82 Livestock Sales*** 144.00 184.00 328.00 GRAND TOTAL $5,155,055.04 $8,944,118.00 $14,099,173.04 ♦Transferred from Treasurer's office April 25, 1933. **Law effective August 10, 1933. ♦**Law effective August, 1933. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>