<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00064.00004">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00064.00004</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Report of the Department of Public Welfare NEBRASKA For the Biennium 
Closing June 30, 1928 </title>
               <date value="1929-01-01">1929-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>



		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06-26</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06-21</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-12-20-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF Department of Public Welfare NEBRASKA For the Biennium Closing June 30, 1928 LINCOLN FROST, Secretart </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska's new capitol is nearing completion and is already famous among the architects of the r»orld. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">State of Nebraska My Dear Governor: I hereby transmit for your consideration a report of the activities of the Department of Public Welfare for the recent biennium. In view of my four years' experience I have felt it proper to make some sugges - tions as to the future work of the Department and as to some needed changes in the law relating to the different Bureaus. tl want to take this occasion to express my appreciation for the y courtesies which you have shown me and for the privilege of ing with the several able Secretaries whom you have appointed to ide over the different civil administrative departments. Respectfully submitted. Lincoln Frost, Secretary). </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INDEX Activities Child Hygiene 42 Activities Child Welfare 53 Activities Laboratories 44 Annual Renewal Fee 22 Appropriations 12 Audit, Report of 25 Barber Act, The 17 Basic Science Law, The 18 Bedding Law, The 30 Bulletin, Nebraska Welfare 60 Bureau of Examining Boards 13 Child Health Conferences 41 Child Hygiene, Division of 40 Child Placing Agencies, Nebraska 52 Child Placing Agencies, Foreign 52 Child Welfare, Bureau of 46 Child Placing Agencies, Nebraska 62 Child Placing Agencies, Foreign 52 Defective Children 49, 50, 51 Juvenile Courts and Probation 59 Maternity Homes 60 Mothers' Pensions 64 Soliciting Agents 59 Survey of National Probation Association, General Summary. ... 60 Committee on Nursing Education 28 Conditional Restoration of Licenses 24 Defective Children 49 Department of Public Welfare 13 Director, Nursing Education 27, 28 Epidemology, Division of 45 Examining Boards, Bureau of 13 Annual Renewal Fee 22 Barber Act, The 17 Basic Science Law, The 18 Committee on Nursing Education 28 Conditional Restoration of Licenses 24 Director of Nursing Education 27, 28 Finances 24 General Rules Governing Licensure 24 Licenses Issued 22 Licenses Revoked 23 Nursing 27 Report of Audit 25 Uniform Licensure Law 14, 15, 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 INDEX — Continued Finances 24 Free Bulletins 42 General Rules Governing Licensure 24 Health, Bureau of 31 Activities of Division of Child Hygiene 42 Activities of Laboratories 44 Child Health Conferences 41 Child Hygiene 40 Division of Venereal Diseases 45 Epidemology 45 Free Bulletins 42 Laboratories 43 Public Health Association Organized 32 Scottsbluff Branch Laboratory 43 Vital Statistics 33 Juvenile Courts and Probation 59 Laboratories 43 Legislation, Needed 60 Survey, National Probation Association, General Summary 60 Letter of Transmittal 4 Licenses Issued 22 Licenses Revoked 23 Maternity Homes 60 Mothers' Pensions 54 Nursing 27 Public Health Association Organized 32 Roster 9, 10, 11 Scottsbluff Branch Laboratory 43 Soliciting Agents 59 Survey of National Probation Association, General Summary 60 Uniform Licensure Law 14, 15, 16 Venereal Diseases 45 Vital Statistics •... 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE INDEX OF TABLES Birth and Death Statistics, Negro. . . ." 35 Cause of Death 39, 40 Child Placing Agencies Licensed, Nebraska .■ 52 Child Placing Agencies Licensed, Foreign 52 Child Welfare, Bureau of — Afflicted Children Reported 49, 50, 51 Child Welfare Placing Agencies Licensed 52 Examining Boards Licenses Granted 22 Licenses Revoked 23 Report of Audit 26 Laboratory, Division of Examinations, 1925-1928 44 Marriages and Divorces, by Counties 36, 37, 38 Mothers' Pensions Questionaire, Summary of 55, 56, 57, 58 » Number of Children Placed 62 Nursing, Accredited Schools of 29, 30 Vital Statistics, Division of Activities 34 Births and Deaths, Negro 35 Causes of Death. , 39, 40 Marriages and Divorces 36, 37, 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">9 ROSTER DEPARTMENT SECRETARY Lincoln Frost BUREAU OF HEALTH: Chief W. H. "Wilson, M. D. Director Division Venereal Disease .... P. H. Bartholomew, M. D. Director Division Vital Statistics Miss Hattie M. Summers Director Division Child Hygiene Miss Louise M. Murphy, R. N. Director Division Laboratories L. 0. Vose, M. Sc. Director Scottsbluff Branch Laboratory Paul J. Lewis* ♦Succeeded Ben W. Hess, Sept. 1, 1928. BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE Chief Mrs. Emily P. Hornberger BUREAU OF EXAMINING BOARDS Director. .Mrs. Clark Perkins Director Nursing Education. . .Phoebe M. Kandel, R. N. B. Sc. EXAMINING BOARD MEMBERS [r. Henry J. Walker, Franklin Mr. Harry E. Raffensparger, Omaha Mr. Ed Wood, Lincoln Barber Board. Dr. L. VanEs, Lincoln*"* Dr. Bernard L. Sellmeyer, Omaha*** Prof. T. J. Thompson, Lincoln Basic Science . Prof. Irving Blake, Lincoln Dr. S. E. Isacson, Omaha Leonard 0. Vose, Lincoln Prof. Leo P. Clements, Omaha §. H. F. Gartner, Lincoln . F. F. Funder,* Omaha . F. E. Silvers, Omaha . C. F. Schmidtmann, Omaha Chiropody . fDr. S. L. Ashworth, Lincoln J Dr. J. P. Laub,* Chapman j Dr. F. H. Berhenke, Fremont [Dr. L. N. Carpenter, Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Dr. Ferdinand Griess,*** Sutton Dr. M. O. Fraser, Lincoln Dr. George Boehler,** Omaha Dr. E. W. Fellers,**** Beatrice Dr. W. A. Cox, Omaha Dentistry . Dr. Percy J. Hunter, Omaha Dr. B. F. Johnson, Wausa Dr. O. E. Newman, Aurora Mr. W. M. Hill,**** Hebron Mr. E. L. Troyer,* Lincoln .. Mr. W. H. Dorrance, Omaha Mr. E. C. Carstensen, Curtis Mr. W. R. Maloney, North Platte Embalming . (Dr. H. J. Lehnhoff, Lincoln Dr. E. T. McGuire^Mead Dr. J. E. Spatz,** Fairfield [Dr. Wm. R. Boyer, Pawnee City Medicine and Surgery . ("Miss Jennie Higgins,* Lincoln Miss Charlotte Burgess,** Omaha J Miss Edith Salin,**** Omaha ' | Sister M. Consolata, Lincoln Nursing. | Miss Lulu Abbott, Lincoln [Miss Cecelia Johnson, Omaha fMr. G. S. Dunlap, Lincoln Mr. Ray C. Kingsley, Omaha Optometry. ] Mr. M. L. Jones,** Fairfield [Mr. L. C. Hewitt, Neligh Dr. E. M. Cramb,* Lincoln Dr. J. T. Young,** Fremont Dr. R. H. Cowger,**** Hastings ' Dr. Ezra M. Ingham, Wymore Dr. C. B. Atzen, Omaha Dr. Anton Kani, Omaha Osteopathy. fMr. William Clayton,* Grand Island Mr. C. A. McVicker,** Gothenburg I Mr. Robert Hardt,*** Hastings Pharmacy. Mr. W. B. Walter, Beatrice Mr. Fred J. Creutz, Wausa Mr. Guy Butler, Lincoln**** Mr. A. E. Carlson, Dannebrog </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 11 Dr. H. L. Fiestner,* Auburn Dr. T. P. Rose,** York Dr. P. L. Cady,*** Arlington Dr. Carl. J. Norden,*** Lincoln Dr. Fred Collins, Madison Dr. S. W. Phillips, David City Dr. F. R. Woodring, Lincoln ■ Veterinary Medicine and Surgery Committee on Nursing Education- Miss Florence McCabe, R. N., President, Nebraska State Asso - ciation of Graduate Nurses, Omaha. Miss Lulu Abbott, R. N., President, Nebraska State League of Nursing Education, Lincoln. Miss Harriett Patterson, R. N., President, Nebraska Public Health Nursing Association, Seward. Miss Hazel Tubbs, R. N., President, Nebraska Private Duty Nursing Association, Lincoln. Rev. Emil G. Chinlund, President, Nebraska Hospital Associa - tion, Omaha. Father Bernard L. Sellmeyer,*** Creighton University, Omaha. Father T. H. Ahearne, Creighton University, Omaha. Miss Charlotte Burgess, R. N., University Hospital, Omaha. Mr. Harvey L. Freeland, Bureau of Vocational Education, Lin- coln. Dr. E. W. Rowe, Lincoln. Ex Officio Members include: Secretary of Department of Public Welfare. Director of Bureau of Examining Boards. Director of Nursing Education. Board of Examiners in Nursing. ♦Indicates term expired November 30, 1926. ** Indicates term expired November 30, 1927. ***Indicates resigned. ****Indicates term expired November 30, 1928. DIVISION OF ATHLETICS: Director Ira Vorhies STATE RACING COMMISSION: Secretary Mr. N. J. Ronin </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 APPROPRIATIONS Departmental: Salary $10,000.00 Total $10,000.00 Bureau of Health: Salaries 42,000.00 Maintenance 22,800.00 Scottsbluff Branch Laboratory 5,000.00 Total 69,800.00 To these funds available for the Bureau of Health should be added the money received by the Division of Vital Statistics for tran- scripts furnished Washington which amounts to approximately $1,200.00 per year; also the money received by it for certified copies of birth, death, marriage, and divorce records, which in the first 12 months after the law became effective in April, 1927, amounted to $414.50; also the money received by the Division of Child Hygiene under the pr vision of the Sheppard-Towner Act. Under the 1927 fund $11,000 w received from the federal government. Bureau of Child Welfare Salaries $13,000.00 Maintenance 5,500.00 Total 18,500.00 Grand Total $98,300.00 Kof Examining Boards: s to cover all expenditures. rsion of Athletics: Fees only. State Racing Commission: </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 A REPORT Of the Activities of THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE For the Biermium Ending June 30, 1928 By Lincoln Frost, Secretary The Department of Public Welfare is one of six civil administra- tive departments which have been organized under a law passed in 1919. This new law inaugurated the cabinet form of government in Nebraska. The executive officer of each Department is its Secretary, who is. appointed by and is directly responsible to the Governor. The Governor is also authorized to appoint all other employees. I This change marks the beginning of a strictly business form of jnagement of state affairs and embodies the principle of the short Hot. The Governor is directly responsible to the people of the state for the way their affairs are conducted. Centralization is its funda meats] feature. However, it is identical with the form employed today in all successful large business concerns. The efficiency of the civil administrative Departments has been tried during the interven - ing nine years. It is unfortunate that political bias has made it difficult for the people to get a right perspective. It is certainly true that the code form of government is more efficient than that which it succeeded and that if the tenure of the heads of bureaus and divisions who are in charge of the office forces could be made more stable, that its efficiency would take high rank. Experienced management is essential to best results. The secretaries, of course, must be subject to change at the will of the incoming governor be - cause they are his personal representatives, and must have his entire confidence. BUREAU OF EXAMINING BOARDS The work of the Department of Public Welfare has been organ - ized under three Bureaus, those of Examining Boards, Health and Child Welfare. These different Bureaus are in charge of officials, the head of the former being called Director and of the two latter Chief. ka total number of employees in the Department varies, but runs m 32 to 35 most of the time. kThis Bureau is organized to look after the examination and sing of applicants from eleven different groups. Prior to 1927 ; were but ten of these groups. In that year the Legislature </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 passed what is known as the Uniform Licensure Law. This law combined and codified the ten different practice acts under which these ten professions had theretofore functioned. These acts regu - lated the examination and licensing of \he following groups or pro - fessions: Chiropody, Chiropractic, Dentistry, Embalming, Medicine and Surgery, Nursing, Optometry, Osteopathy, Pharmacy and Veteri - nary Medicine. With the separate acts the conditions prevailing in this licensure bureau were very chaotic. With the widely dissimilar provisions the handling of the work in connection with the examination and licensing of applicants was rendered difficult. These dissimilarities and in - equalities also created jealousies. For example, the penalty imposed for the nonpayment of the annual registration fee varied widely, in some cases being unnecessarily severe while in others they amounted to practically nothing. In the latter classes the department could reinstate without limit as to time, with the approval of the interested examining board upon the payment of back fees, while in others a forfeiture though only for a failure to pay a renewal fee could not be set aside, but the defaulting licensee must take another examina- There was another reason that made it imperative to secure a uniform law. The Bureau of Examining Boards is supported entirely by fees paid in by the applicants for a license. Certain of these fees go to support the different boards of examiners while others are used to maintain the Bureau. The Bureau was largely supported by the renewal fees. These were paid annually but were only paid by six professions. These six therefore contributed the principal support while the other four were enjoying the benefits without sharing the burdens. It was especially resented by those paying that the strongest group among those licensed, namely, the doctors of medicine, did not pay a renewal fee. It therefore became very important that either the state should make an appropriation for the support of this Bureau or that all should be required to contribute their proportionate part. It was certain that an appropriation could not be secured for this support. Therefore the only recourse was to secure a law requiring all to pay a renewal fee. Under the terms of the Uniform Licensure Law, which was passed in 1927, all are required to pay such a fee. That law was not passed without a struggle. Many preliminaries had to be looked after before even the bill could be drawn. The several professions had to be interviewed and their differences with other professions reconciled. The Secretary of the Department early lecognized that it would be difficult to pass so complicated and lengthy law as would be needed to embody in one the provisions necessary </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 for the examination, licensing and regulation of all. For months the different committees representing the groups interested were called in one at a time and their several viewpoints obtained. The efforts of the Secretary were directed to bringing these different committees to an acceptance of the vital things necessary to uniformity. Many minor things were conceded in order to accomplish the broader purposes. Then the bill had to be drafted. The mere technical work of drafting a bill of 62 pages is no small matter. But when you remem - ber that the suggestions and opinions which had developed in these numerous preliminary conferences had to be put in shape therein so as to arouse as little antagonism as possible, it can be seen that the task was no easy one. Though the committees that represented the different professions cl'mg tenaciously to some provisions undesirable in a uniform law, i 1 is only fair to say of them that, after they had yielded and ac - &lt; epted what the Secretary felt he could concede them, they loyally supported the bill before the committees of the Legislature. The bill had the united support of the committees of nine of the professions and the support of a considerable number of the tenth. Some of the committees felt that it was all important to their profession that the Uniform Licensure Law be passed. They had tried repeatedly to get a satisfactory law and had uniformly failed. With some of the others the need was not so imperative, as they already had a very good practice act. It is only fair to say that the Uniform Licensure Law never could have been passed without the loyal support of these committees. Even friends of the bill in the Legislature were ready to throw up their hands when they saw the great length and com - plications of the bill. However, when a crucial period arrived and a call was sent out for help the response invariably was almost 100%. As it was, House Roll 551, now known as the Uniform Licensure Law, received its final approval at the hands of the two houses on the last day of the session. The Bureau has, therefore, been functioning under the Uniform Licensure Law since July 24, 1927. By its fair provisions many jealousies due to inequalities have been allayed. Some dissimilarities still exist, but they are not of a vital nature. The relations between the Bureau and the different Boards of Examiners have been clarified. The Bureau has become the ad - ministrative agency in the handling of the examinations while to the Boards has been left the functions of preparing the questions and reading and grading the answer papers; also of determining any technical question connected with the interpretation of any doubtful provision of a technical nature in the law relating to that particular </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 While the Uniform Licensure Law was battling its way through the Legislature two other bills were successfully breasting the storms of opposition, to-wit: The Barber Act and the Basic Science Law. Both of these were passed prior to the passage of the Uniform L'censure Law. Both might well have been embodied therein. How - ever, the friends of no one of the three, at the time of drafting their respective bill could know that either of the others would become a law, even had they been disposed to harmonize and consolidate them. Iowa, at its 1927 Legislature, passed a barber act by in - corporating it as amendments in a uniform licensure law which that state already had. This is pretty good evidence that Nebraska could well have done the same thing if the Uniform Licensure Law had then been in force. Some of the provisions of both these laws do not harmonize with those on the same subject in the Uniform Licensure Law. These dissimilar provisions have again raised some of the same troubles that existed prior to the passage of that law. Whenever it is possible amendments should be made that will remove these dissimilarities. It is only fair to say that the Board of Examiners in Basic Sciences as well as the Board of Examiners in Barbering have done much by rules to lessen the annoyances to the Department occasioned by the discrepancies in the provisions. The Basic Science Law has provided that the general technique of examination shall follow the general outline cf the Uniform Licensure Law, while the Board of Barber Examiners has provided more in detail as follows: "The provisions of House Roll No. 551 of the Laws of Nebraska for 1927, and the Rules made by the Department of Public Welfare in carrying out and supplementing said provisions in so far as they can be applied to the provisions of the Barber Act, also known as House Roll No. 37 of the Laws of Nebraska for 1927, shall be adopted and accepted as a part of the General Rules of the Board of Barber Examiners." The action of these two Boards was a recognition of the fairness of the provisions in the Uniform Licensure Law establishing relations between the Department and the Boards. It is a confirmation also of the position taken by the Department that the Bureau of Examining Boards should be the administrative agency in all licensure matters. Experience has demonstrated that board management is unreliable and inefficient and that even when it functions it is almost impossible to get it to act within a reasonable time. Boards will not keep to any given course, but waiver with every adverse wind. The members of a board look to the concrete situation instead of the broader ques - tion in the abstract. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 THE BARBER ACT As already indicated, it is my opinion that the Barber Act should either be embodied in the Uniform Licensure Law or its provisions amended so as to correspond with the essential provisions of that law. All administrative features should be taken from the Board and given to the Department or the Bureau. The law as drawn has some inconsistencies in referring to the relations between the De - partment and the Board. The examinations are entirely conducted by the Board. The provisions as to the handling of the funds are slightly inconsistent. If the Department is to assume any responsi - bilities, those taken over should be broad enough to justify it in directing its energies along that line. It is not good judgment to impose burdens without giving adequate means of working out from under them. The Secretary should not be held responsible for the funds without being given full control over the handling of them. Eny needed changes in the law are apparent upon a comparison h the Uniform Licensure Law. However, this is no place for :ussion of the details of these changes. I call attention to one nge which seems fundamental. In Section 19 of The Barber Act ta provision providing that the Board, with the consent of the Secre - •y of the Department of Public Welfare, shall have authority to iploy inspectors, clerks, etc. In Section 20 there is also a provision thorizing the Board members to inspect barber shops. The Attorney General has held that under this latter provision the Board members Kve the right to make inspections without the consent of the Secre - ry and receive ten dollars per diem. I question whether the Board of Examiners should also be inspectors. I am certain that other barbers could be found, wholly disassociated from the Examining Board, who would be more efficient in these inspections than would Smbers of the Board. In saying this I am not casting any reflec - ns upon the present Board members. I think the mere fact of ng a Board member is a handicap. There is a tendency to assume too much responsibility instead of allowing the law to be their guide. Then when we compare the cost of maintaining a Board member in the field at a per diem of ten dollars with the cost of our field in - vestigator in the Bureau of Examining Boards we find that the ad - vantage is in favor of the latter, by fully one-third. There has been some agitation to limit the number of apprentices in a shop to one. However, as only 144 apprentice certificates have been issued during the year that The Barber Act has been in force any such restrictions appear unnecessary. It will be ample time to impose restrictions after there has been an excessive number of ap - plicants for apprentice certificates. It now looks as if the supply in the near future would not be sufficient to meet the legitimate demands. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Subdivision 6 of Section 17 of The Barber Act provides for the separation of a barber shop from rooms used for residential purposes by a substantial partition of ceiling height. The exception, however, in this subdivision, which allows confectionery to be sold in barber shops is very objectionable. Nothing should be sold in a barber shop of an edible nature because it is impossible to keep the flying hairs from any part of the shop. There has also been some question raised about a barber shop being run in connection with a pool hall. Good taste demands that they be kept separate. Business reasons should be sufficient to bring about the separation since the women have be - come good customers of the barber. There are moral questions also involved in the separation. We do not allow our youths to frequent billiard halls, yet they must go to the barber shops. Where they are run in common it is impossible to keep the boys entirely away from the billiard room. There should be a provision forbidding the estab - lishment of a barber shop in connection with a billiard hall. Where they are already occupying a room jointly reasonable time should be given in which to make the separation. There is no provision in The Barber Act providing a penalty for t violation of sanitary rules adopted by the Board of Barber Ex - liners. The Act provides that such rules may be adopted, but they are ineffective if there is not a penalty embodied for their breach. There should be an amendment fixing the penalties or authorizing the Board to fix them. THE BASIC SCIENCE LAW »As has already been suggested, The Basic Science Law was passed the last session of the Legislature as an independent act. It is unfortunate that its provisions are not in harmony with those of the Uniform Licensure Law. As already indicated its Board of Examiners have recognized this mistake and have asked the Director of the Bureau cf Examining Boards to do for them the work that the law should have provided must be done by that Bureau. The administrative work in connection with the examinations and issuing of the licenses is done by a Director of that Bureau, practically as similar services are per - formed by her for the several professions handled under the terms of the Uniform Licensure Law. It is unfortunate that reciprocity, so far as it is involved in the Basic Science examinations, is not left as an administrative measure, to the Bureau. The Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare in his experience with the Examining Boards early saw that the de - lays connected with submitting reciprocity to boards were a great </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 handicap. We have doubted whether it is necessary to submit that question to the Basic Science Board, but as the Attorney General has taken a different view we have been constrained to acquiesce. The Basic Science Law gives the Board the right to pass on the prerequisites necessary to be established before an applicant can take the Basic Science examination. However, the Board has recognized that that was a proper function of the Department and therefore have delegated to the Director of the Bureau of Examining Boards authority to pass upon this question. The last sentence in Section 10 declares that a certificate issued to any person by the Board of Examiners in the Basic Sciences shall be automatically revoked by the revocation of any license issued to such person. That provision was put in the law without proper con - sideration. The mere fact that a license is revoked for some reason disassociated from the Basic Science examination should not nullify the effect of that examination. For example, the Uniform Licensure Law provides for the revocation of a license for the failure to pay a renewal fee. Why should that affect the results obtained by the licensee when he took the examination before the Basic Science Board? The passage of the Basic Science Law has caused no end of trouble. I say this notwithstanding I believe the fundamental prin - ciple on which the law is based to be good. This fundamental principle may fairly be conceded to be that everyone who practices any of the healing arts upon humanity must be grounded in the fundamental sciences which form the basis of the necessary knowledge to success - fully carry on such practice. The trouble has arisen because of a misunderstanding, largely due to the argument before the Legislature, that the Basic Science Law would raise the standards required of applicants for licenses. The effect of that argument on reciprocity was not appreciated. When it came to putting the law in operation the thought that the new law did raise standards doubtless led the Attorney General's office to take the position that Nebraska could have reciprocity only with states having a similar Basic Science Law. This conclusion was based upon the provision in the Uniform Licensure Law that Nebraska could have reciprocity only with states having laws fixing standards equal to those fixed in the same profession in Nebraska. This was disastrous to the administration of reciprocity, for there were but four other states that had basic science laws. When the Department submitted the question of whether the Basic Science Law had raised our standard so that we could not have reci - procity in medicine in these other states not having a basic science law the answer came unanimously that it had not raised standards and that Nebraska might have reciprocity with all states with which it had had such relations prior to the passage of that law. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 I Section 8 of the Basic Science Law provides that the Board may, its discretion, waive examinations upon satisfactory proof that an ilicant has passed an examination before a Basic Science Board or a Board authorized to issue licenses in another state. The Basic Science Board has been reluctant to waive this discretion in advance but has indicated that when submitted it probably would accept the results before such boards. This same Section provides that the waiver of examination shall depend upon the Board of the other state granting like exemption to applicants from Nebraska. This provision has been subject to differ - ent interpretations by members of the Basic Science Board. The ma - jority, however, have held that no contract for reciprocity need be entered into in advance and until the other state had refused to extend like exemption, Nebraska might assume that it would so treat her applicants. The Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare has taken a position, all through this controversy, in favor of a liberal interpreta - fn of the law to the end that reciprocity might be granted wherever could be done without materially lowering our professional stand - ards. The fact that Nebraska has two medical schools which are graduating a hundred or more would-be doctors annually makes it especially important that we have reciprocal relations with other states. If we will not accept their licensees from them we cannot expect them to accept ours. It is useless for an applicant for a state Einse in medicine to take the Nebraska examination in medicine ere he knows he expects to practice elsewhere unless he can get iprocity with the state to which he contemplates going. There is no good reason why Nebraska cannot have reciprocity with the other states of the union in medicine and surgery, osteopathy and chiropractic where the standards fixed by law or authorized rule of the Examining Boards are equal to those of Nebraska. However, it is only fair to expect that the Basic Science Board will have a greater reluctance in exercising its discretion to waive examinations in case of those professions that have been known to spend but a short time in their professional training. For example, until but recently in Nebraska the Chiropractic Board of Examiners has been content to require but 18 months of professional training for gradua - tion from its professional schools, while the curriculum of perhaps none of their schools covers all the subjects that the Nebraska Law names as Basic Sciences. I cannot believe, however, that the Basic Science Board will not fairly consider the claims of every application </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Kit is too early to know just what effect the Basic Science Law going to have upon the number of applications for examination in healing arts. The records of the Bureau of Examining Boards show that there have been fewer licenses issued the year following the passage of the Basic Science Law than were issued during the year immediately preceding. Probably this is a result that might naturally be expected. The following table will show the number of licenses issued in the professions practicing the healing art for the year immediately preceding the time when the Basic Science Law went into effect, July 19, 1927, and the year following: is almost certain that in the long run this falling off will not tinue. There will be a readjustment and applicants will learn to prepare themselves in these fundamental sciences. I have no doubt that the ailing public will profit by reason of this better training. There have been some just complaints about the repetition of the examination covering the Basic Science subjects. The Board of Ex - aminers in Medicine and Surgery have felt it necessary, under the law, as interpreted by the Attorney General's office, to require ap - plicants to repeat the examination taken before the Basic Science Board. It will take an amendment to the medical practice act to remedy this. However, the examinations given by this Board, judging by the results, are not particularly difficult. Of the 37 who took the examination in the spring of 1928, 31 passed with a general average of 82.5, while 6 who failed had a general average of 67.8. In order to pass both the Uniform Licensure Law and the Basic Science Law requires an average of 75%. In another respect there is a needless repetition. The Uniform Licensure Law very properly provides that the Department may ac - cept, in lieu of an examination, the certificate of examination issued by the National Board of Medical Examiners. The examinations be - fore this Board are said to be of the highest character. The Basic Science Law, however, does not contain a similar provision and there - fore the certificate of the National Board cannot be accepted. To prevent the needless repetition of this examination it will be necessary to have an amendment to the Basic Science Law. Profession Examin- Recipro- Total ation city Examin- Recipro- Total ation city Chiropractic Medicine and Surgery. Osteopathy 31 27 58 92 16 108 . 28 5 33 000 000 000 74 4 78 2 0 2 'otals 151 48 199 76 4 &gt;0 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 LICENSES ISSUED DURING BIENNIUM Something: of the extent of the work will be gained by glancing at the number of licenses issued for the biennium to the ten different professions that are handled by the Bureau: Chiropractic 58 Chiropody 3 Dentistry 122 Embalming 51 Medicine and Surgery 223 Nursing 611 Osteopathy 32 Optometry 10 Pharmacy 192 Veterinary Medicine 14 Total 1216 In addition to this, licenses have been issued to 3660 barbers during the year 1928. Also, the Board of Examiners in the Basic Sciences during this biennium have issued certificates of ability, which are a prerequisite to taking an examination in any of the healing arts, to 69 applicants. The Uniform Licensure Law requires every member of the ten professions covered by that law to pay an annual renewal fee. The number paying renewal fees in the several professions for the first year of its operation are as follows: Chiropractic 458* Chiropody 50 Dentistry 1,218 Embalming 782 Medicine and Surgery 2,756 Nursing 1,784 Optometry 470* Osteopathy 295 Pharmacy , 2,366 Veterinary Medicine 619 Total 10,798 •These figures are for August, 1928, rather than for August, 1927. There is a provision in the Uniform Licensure Law that provides that all moneys paid as a renewal fee in excess of one dollar per capita shall be kept in a separate fund to be used for the especial </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 benefit of the profession so paying such fee. It was left to the Legis - lative Committees of the different professions to say whether they wanted a one dollar renewal fee or a two dollar renewal fee. Five of these indicated a desire for the two dollar fee, to- wit: Chiropractic, Chiropody, Nursing, Embalming, and Veterinary Medicine and Surgery and such a fee was accordingly fixed for them in the statute. The original inspiration for this larger renewal came from the leaders in the nursing profession who were anxious to have funds with which to employ an educational director. The Secretary in drawing the law yielded to their insistent demand, a demand which was on their part commendable as well as generous. The Uniform Licensure Law provides for the revoking of licenses for the failure to pay a renewal fee. Before any license can be re - voked a second notice must be mailed to the licensee at his last ad - dress as it appears upon the records of the Bureau of Examining Boards. The number of licenses revoked for the nonpayment of re - newal fees in the ten professions during the Biennium was 5083, which are distributed among the different groups as follows: The number is very large in several groups, especially in medicine and surgery. This will be better understood when we bear in mind that there never had been any means of checking up the number of active practitioners at any time prior to the annual renewal in 1927. Many of those whose licenses were revoked had left the state or had died, but no information to that effect had been communicated to the Bureau. The revocation for nonpayment of renewal fees for the cur - rent year will undoubtedly be relatively small. There have been 52 applications for reinstatement of those whose licenses have been re - voked. The Uniform Licensure Law provides an easy method of reinstatement, but as only 52 all told have made application therefor it indicates that the causes of revocation just suggested prevailed pretty generally among the different groups. There is another reason chiropractic 01 chiropody -01 jentistry 63- Embalming 3' vledicine and Surgery 2,93: Cursing 1,381 Osteopathy 00&lt; )ptometry 001 10' /eterinary 0( Total 5,08 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 why the revocations were heavy during the first year the Uniform Licensure Law was in operation, there was no prescribed method of revocation therefor under the different practice acts prior to 1927. Indeed, many acts did not provide for revocation. The method has been worked out carefully in the Uniform Licensure Law, which serves as a guide to the Director of the Bureau of Examining Boards. GENERAL RULES GOVERNING LICENSURE Provision Made for Conditional Restoration of License: § Director of the Bureau of Examining Boards and the Secre - the Department have been working on a revised set of rules ig examination and the licensing of applicants in the several ons. These rules had been in process of development for a couple of years prior to their promulgation March 15, 1928. PThe Secretary has been especially anxious to provide a method jby licensees who had failed in their obligations to their profes - but had later repented could be restored to the practice and still safeguard the public. It is a seiious thing to take a license from a man permanently, for very likely his profession is his only means i t supporting his family. He concededly has committed a more or less grave breach of his professional obligations. He is less likely to re - peat that or a similar breach if placed on probation, preferably to a member of his profession of high ethical standards. Therefore, the new rules provide a definite method of restoration, where the facts justify, of a revoked or suspended license. So far as we are advised no similar provision is contained in the licensure rules of any of the state departments. It is more than likely that these rules or a de - velopment from them will appear in the revised rules of many of those departments. FINANCES The Bureau of Examining Boards is the fiscal agency for the De - partment of Public Welfare. Most of the moneys are paid in as fees and practically all of such payments properly go to that Bureau. It therefore appeared advisable to make it the financial agency for the Department and allow one clerk to keep all books. There is nothing complicated about the keeping of these records. If the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare is to be held responsible for the funds paid in as fees in connection with the licenses of apprentices in bartering and of barbers themselves, then he must have the control of them. Subdivision 3 of Section 7 says that </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 every applicant for an examination, among other things, shall pay to the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare the required fee. Section one says that the two classes named therein, to-wit: barbers and apprentices, shall not practice without having a certificate issued tthe Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare. Section 14 tes that the Department of Public Welfare may refuse to issue or renew or may suspend or revoke any certificate of registration for certain reasons thereafter enumerated. Of course this indicates that the purpose of the law is that all certificates of registration shall be tied by the Department. In Section 11 the classes named therein, king a license, are required to make application to the Secretary of Public Welfare or to the Department and pay the required fee. Everything in the Act again goes to show that its purpose is to require all fees to be paid to the Department. It is hardly fair to conclude, Ethat the provision in Section 19, requiring the Board to report ally to the Department of Public Welfare a full statement of its pts and expenditures, would change the plan in both of the prior isions of the statute. Neither can there be any need of the Board of Barber Examiners keeping a set of books if that Board is not the agency entitled to receive the fees. The Department has heretofore indicated its purpose to have but one fiscal agency, the Bureau of Examining Boards, and we see no advantage in changing that rule. REPORT OF AUDIT The State Accountant from the Auditor's office has made but one audit of the Department's books during the current biennium. Indeed, it has been two years and a half since the former audit was made. (is audit, therefore, covers the time from May 1, 1926, to October 1928. This audit shows the total receipts during that period amount $78,564.44. The expenditures during the same period were $62,404.52 an excess of receipts over expenditures of $16,159.92. There was a ance on hand May, 1926, as shown by the prior audit, of $11,026.03. Therefore there are moneys on deposit in the state treasury belonging to the different agencies in the Department and to the different board funds in the sum of $27,185.95, which balance agrees with that shown on the auditor's record. R These figures serve to indicate the financial responsibility im - sed upon the Department, or rather upon its Secretary, who is re - sponsible for the safe keeping of these funds until they reach the state </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF THE Table Showing Balances of Funds of the Several Bureaus, Divisions. and Boards of the Department of Public Welfare, November 1, 1928, as Shown by the Report of C. A. Sommer, State Accountant Cthe support of the Bureau bers' Division Basic Science Chiropody Examining Board Chiropody Profession Fund Dental Examining Board Chiropractors' Examining Board Profession Fund Embalmers' Examining Board Profession Fund. Medical Examining Board Nurses' Examining Board. Profession Fund Optometry Examining Board Osteopathy Examining Board. Pharmacist Examining Board. Veterinary Examining Board " Profession Fund Vital Statistics Division. . . . Credits Deduct Overdrafts. Net, Cash in Treasury. Note — While three items show as an overdraft in the Profession or Board fund, as the case may be, reference to the Board or Profession fund will show ample funds which may be transferred to offset the apparent overdraft. Cash on hand Overdraft Nov. 1, 1928. $11,955.52 4.673.3S 322.55 65.85 40.00 515.97 ,16.68 637.30 435.77 7.97 716.77 6,182.72 538.27 132.50 740.88 431.00 ■-' 375.21 $27,771.26 585.31 $27,185.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 NURSING In our biennial report of two years ago comments were made upon the large number of failures in the examinations in Nursing. This excess in failures has continued during the current biennium, but is appreciably less in 1928. The following table shows the number of failures at the spring examinations for five successive years and gives a fair basis for comparison. The columns in order give the following data: year, number taking examination, number of failures and per - centage of failures. Year No. Taking Examination No. of Failures Percentage ■ This table demonstrates that something is wrong with our schools nursing. It is important that we find out to what to attribute it. might be due to any of the several causes or a combination of one more. The schools may be taking in students who are not capable of taking the training required by the nursing curriculum; or the teaching may be inefficient; or possibly too heavy demands are made upon the students for service about the hospital; or, finally, the ex - amination may be too difficult. A set of questions was submitted to one believed to be a competent authority on nursing education. The report of this nurse was that the examination questions were not un - usually difficult. Naturally the teaching personnel in the several schools would vary in their capabilities. Some schools undoubtedly have not had teachers capable of giving the proper instruction. We also know that some schools have imposed too many tasks about the hospital upon their students in training. These schools have overlooked the fact that- their students were there to secure an education in nursing and that their tasks about the hospital at all times should have had that end in view. It is this that we stress and not that the nurses should not give adequate returns for the training which the school is giving them. §Of course, a preliminary education is not conclusive as to the ability the one receiving it to do a given work. However, we have a right expect more from one who has completed a high school course than we would from one who has but one or two years in such a course. The Director of Nursing Education has made a study of the number of high school graduates among the students admitted to the schools of nursing in the years 1927 and 1928. These figures place Nebraska ,4 41.9' c 41.4' c 38.47 C 23.5' c 925 . . 9:J 70 86 86 39 29 33 20 926 . . 927 . . 928 . . </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 high among the states in its standard of qualifications prerequisite for admittance to its schools of nursing. These figures show that in 1927, out of 606 admitted, 526 had at least a high school education, while in 1928, out of 525, 504 had at least such an education. This is particularly flattering in view of the fact that the law in Nebraska requires but two years of high school as prerequisite to taking the state board examination in nursing. The situation just related called for action. The more progressive among the nursing group were thoroughly alert to the situation. The Secretary of the Department has been thoroughly sold on the justice of the demand. He therefore appointed, with the approval of the Board of Examiners in Nursing, Miss Phoebe M. Kandel as Director of Nursing Education. Miss Kandel commenced her work January first last, and she has made a wonderful change in that time. A better balanced curriculum in the schools has been adopted. Additions have been made to the teaching force in some instances, while in others those theretcfore employed have been encouraged to take special courses in summer schools. Where the entire curriculum could not be given in an individual school of nursing that school has been required to send its. students, during a part of their senior year, to another school of nursing capable of supplying the necessary clinical training. {During the biennium four schools of nursing have ceased to func - m, one temporarily, three permanently. This has been due, in part, the demands of the Educational Director that they give the service quired by the curriculum. During all of this preliminary work both the Department and Miss Kandel have had in mind the conditions which existed in Nebraska. At no time has the unreasonable been asked of the authorities of the schools of nursing. We have been insistent that they give the services which their obligations to their students require, nothing more. On the other hand, the students should be encouraged to do their part, not only in training themselves, but in loyalty and service to the hospital maintaining the school. In arriving at the value of the services of the students the hospital should remember that they are much more amenable to orders and are more dependable than are the practical or graduate nurses. Committee on Nursing Education. In the spring of 1928 at the est of the Educational Director, the Department appointed a Com - ee on Nursing Education. This committee represented the nursing, medical and hospital organizations, university relations, board of ex - aminers in nursing, Director of the Bureau of Examining Boards, Director of Nursing Education, and the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare. This committee held two meetings at which rules and regulations covering nursing and schools of nursing have been recom - mended to the Department for adoption. This recommendation has been </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 approved and these rules have been promulgated by the Secretary of the Department with the approval of Governor Adam McMullen. The nursing profession is to be congratulated upon having the services of such a trained educator as Miss Kandel. The schools of nursing that are desirous of raising their standards have gladly ac- cepted her counsel and advice. She has a wonderful fund of theoretical training which has been supplemented by years of practical experience. When she studies the ailments of a sick school of nursing she is not only able to diagnose the trouble, but also is able to prescribe the treat- ment that will bring it up to a healthy standard. These schools, al- though reluctant at first, have generally in the end cheerfully acquiesced .airying out the required treatment. In some cases this has meant considerable financial sacrifice. In some cases it has required the in- stitution of a new department in their school, while in others it has necessitated the sending of their senior students to a distant state to get some training that their school was not equipped to give. Let it be said to Miss Kandel's credit that she has been able to bring these things about in the end without leaving any hard feelings behind; she has done this by reason of her knowledge of the nursing profession and because of her enthusiasm in carrying out its highest precepts. The following table gives a list of the Accredited Schools, of Nursing during the biennium: HOSPITALS MAINTAINING ACCREDITED SCHOOLS OF NURSING Hospital Location University Hospital Omaha Methodist Episcopal Hospital Omaha St. Joseph's Hospital Omaha St. Catherine's Hospital Omaha Clarkson Memorial Hospital Omaha Wise Memorial Hospital Omaha Nicholas Senn Hospital Omaha Paxton Memorial Hospital* Omaha Lord Lister Hospital Omaha Swedish Mission Hospital (now Evangelical Covenant) Omaha Immanuel Hospital Omaha St. Elizabeth's Hospital Lincoln Dr. Bailey's Sanitarium Lincoln Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Lincoln Sanitarium* Lincoln Lincoln Hospital** Lincoln Lincoln General Hospital Lincoln Bryan Memorial Hospital Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Hospitals Containing Accredited Schools of Nursing — (Continued) Hospital Location Norfolk General Hospital** Norfolk Lutheran Hospital Norfolk Lutheran Hospital York Lutheran Hospital Beatrice Beatrice Sanitarium Beatrice Mennonite Hospital Beatrice St. Joseph's Hospital Alliance St. Catherine's Hospital** McCook St. Francis Hospital Grand Island Mary Lanning Memorial Hospital Hastings West Nebraska Methodist Hospital Scottsbluff ♦Hospital closed. **Training school discontinued. THE BEDDING LAW The Legislature in 1925 passed "An Act denning bedding and to provide for the tagging and labeling thereof; regulating the use of sanitary materials therein; punishing violations thereof." No appro- priation was made to carry the law into effect. The law provided for certain fees for inspecting, but did not specifically appropriate them. This oversight was mentioned in the Department's report of two years ago and the Legislature at that session appropriated all fees that ac- crued from the inspections. However, it was found upon looking into the matter that the number of institutions to be inspected would be so small that the fees would not be sufficient to carry the law into effect. All that applied were assigned numbers in the order of their applica- tion. Below is a list of those who filed under the law and made applica- tion for a number which is required to be used by them on all the bed- ding and mattresses they manufacture. If this law is to be effective there will have to be some other method provided for caring for the cost of inspections. Possibly a larger fee for inspection might be the best way. No. 4. Capitol Bedding Company Lincoln No. 1. L. G. Doup Company Omaha No. 3. Jackson Mattress Company. Omaha No. 6. Johnson's Mattress Works Hastings No. 5. Lincoln Mattress Company Lincoln No. 2. Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Mattress Company Omaha No. 7. Stahn Mattress Company Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 BUREAU OF HEALTH The Bureau of Health is the State's agency for looking after its public health program. The importance of that program in guarding the health of the people can hardly be overestimated. There has been a great saving in mortality during the past centuries by reason of such efforts. The increase in the average span of life has been gradual. In the 16th century it was from 18 to 20 years, while at the close of the 18th century it had increased to 25 years and a century later to 45 to 48 years. By 1925 this average age had increased to 56 years in the United States, while in New Zealand it was 60 years and in India £5 years. The difference in civilization has much to do with the span of life, for the higher civilization has better health methods. During this time the limiting age of life has not materially advanced, the in - creased span being due rather to the fact that fewer die during the early years. tThe importance of better health methods is illustrated by comparing e city of Chicago with the balance of the State of Illinois. The city of Chicago spends about one dollar per capita upon its health program while the balance of the state spends but a few cents. The city of Chicago for a number of years has had a lower death rate than has the balance of the state, though you would expect to find a higher death rate there because of the crowded and unhealthy surroundings which prevail in any large city. However, in the year 1924, if the State of Illinois outside of Chicago had had no higher death rate than did that city, two thousand lives would have been saved. Two thousand lives are sacrificed because the people are not willing to pay a few cents additional in taxes! This reluctance to meet the additional cost will continue until those who pay the taxes can get a broader viewpoint and appreciate the possibilities in the conservation of health. The Metropolitan Life Insurance Company has recognized the im - portance to its policyholders, and therefore to itself, in bending every effort to lengthen their lives. It is spending more than one million dollars per year in health work among them. In doing this it is not only doing a service to its policyholders, but it is also adding to the income of the company itself, for the conservation and lengthening of life more than makes up what it costs the company. kThe saving of human life largely has been among the very young, re is a high death rate among children under one year of age, and icially among males; however, this excessively high death rate among males is largely made up by their greater birth rate. The decrease in the infant death rate has been rapid since Pasteur discovered that many diseases were caused by parasites. He declared that it was within </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 fe power of man to cause all parasitic diseases to disappear. While is may be an extravagant statement, still it has much of truth to commend it. It is estimated that one-fourth of all human mortality throughout the world accrues during the first year after birth. In some countries this mortality is as much as three to four hundred out of a thousand. In the registration area of our own country in 1900 one-fifth of all children born died during the first year of life and one-third died dur - ing the first five years. Twenty-one years later these death rates had decreased to 15.5% during the first year and to 21.4% during the first five years. Since the discovery of anti-toxin, deaths from diphtheria have fallen from 43.3% per thousand in the first registration figures to 12.1% in 1923. KThis lengthening of the span of the average life has been made the face of the fact that in the case of many diseases there has been increase in the mortality rate. This increase is especially noticeable in the respiratory diseases and in diseases involving the heart. An - cther fact is worthy of the consideration of parents. Children are in mere danger of contracting a contagious disease before they commence attending the public schools than they are afterwards. This is doubt - less because the schools pay more intelligent attention to the health of the child than does the parent. Fifty-seven per cent of the seven leading communicable diseases occur among pre-school children as compared with 24.4% among the school children. tSuch facts as these should cause the impecunious taxpayer to nge his viewpoint. However, that change will come only with the spread of the information showing the possibilities in the saving of life . PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION ORGANIZED f Nebraska has crganized a Public Health Association under the idership of Dr. W. H. Wilson, Chief of the Bureau of Health. The first meeting was held on May 14, 1928, and the Constitution and By - laws adopted at that meeting provide in part as follows: "The object of this association is to protect and promote public health by the closer correlation of all health activities, fostering and supporting constructive legislation, and aiding in the dissemination of correct information with regard to public health. I "Any person resident in the State of Nebraska who is interested the problems of public health shall be eligible to membership." The membership list has grown considerably since the first meet - ing and it is hoped and believed that the Association will grow into a large and effective organization. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 DIVISIONS IN BUREAU OF HEALTH I The work of the Bureau of Health is organized under four Divisions: il Statistics, Child Hygiene, Venereal Diseases, and Laboratories. se Divisions are each in the immediate charge of a director. I Division of Vital Statistics: The Director of the Division of Vital itistics or, as she is more generally called, the State Registrar, thers and files the certificates of births and deaths. These are re - ved from local registrars scattered over the state. These registrars ; paid a fee of 25 cents for each certificate by the county containing ! district in which they serve. A transcript of all these certificates made for the Census Bureau at Washington. It is important, there - e, that full and accurate information be obtained. Nebraska was :epted in the federal registration area in 1921. This means that the cials of the Census Bureau satisfied themselves that Nebraska was taining at least 90% of the births and 90% of the deaths. No state I admitted into the registration area relating to either of these sub - ts until the work becomes accurate enough to secure at least that ■centage. registration certificates sent in by the registrars are ulti - tely bound in chronological order by counties and under the name the father. Therefore, with the information as to the situs and date I birth and the father's name the clerks can quite readily find any uested record of a birth or death. I In these days of travel where passports are required, the traveling blic are learning the importance of these records. They are used ite extensively also in connection with schools to determine the age the children. The late war was also a means of spreading informa - n as to the value of such records because of their use in connection th the enlistments of the men. The first vital statistics law in Nebraska was passed in 1904. herefore, there are no official records back of that date. However, it las been the custom on receiving the needed information in proper orm, to file that certificate. This work has no official standing. It ould be worth while passing a law validating the certificates of the laracter already filed and authorizing the filing of others in future, lways insisting that those filed should give the information required ly the United States Census regulations on that subject. These irreg - lar certificates should also be supported by the affidavit of some person who is familiar with the facts relating to the birth in questions. The ersonnel of this Division during the latter part of the biennium has </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 REPORT OF THE consisted, in addition to the Director, of five clerks or stenographers. A large amount of detail work is done, as the following table covering the period from January 1, 1925, to October 6, 1928, will show: Total pieces of mail received 96,630 Total pieces of mail sent out 112,663 Total certified copies made 5,595 Total transcripts and reports made 176,606 Total certificates of registration made 101,246 Files searched to verify records 9,678 Some amendments were made to the Vital Statistics statute by the 1927 Legislature. The forms of the certificates were made more complete and in conformity with the federal census regulations. The certificates are a permanent record and the law was changed to require them to be "typed or written legibly in durable ink". There was a requirement that they "shall not be deemed complete unless they dis - close or satisfactorily account for omissions of items of information called for." There is a further provision that the local registrar, in case of an emergency whereby there is a certificate required by the Department, must supply it upon request of the State Registrar. The amendments also include a provision authorizing the State Department of Public Welfare to charge a fee of 50 cents for a certified copy of the record of a birth, death, marriage or divorce. Prior to this law becoming effective in 1927 for some years no such charge could be made. The curious public had learned this and the requests for certified copies became unduly numerous. Even now the Department is authorized to furnish two free copies "for soldiers' relief or the interest of their families." The Department also furnishes free, at the request of any parent or guardian, information for school purposes or for securing employment. This certificate is limite.d to a statement of the parentage and of the date of birth. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 35 NEBRASKA BIRTH AND DEATH STATISTICS OF NEGROES OMAHA LINCOLN 1926 - 1927 1926 - 1927 TOTAL DEATHS TOTAL BIRTHS 235 201 177 194 19 13 12 11 NEBRASKA 1926 - 1927 KAL DEATHS AL BIRTHS 293 237 220 23S OMAHA LINCOLN 1926 - 1927 CAUSE OF DEATH 1926 - 1927 Tuberculosis (All Forms) 46 37 .20 Syphilis 10 12 10 GonocoPcus Infection 2 2 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 BUREAU OF HEALTH— DIVISION OF VITAL STATISTICS MARRIAGES DIVORCES COUNTY 1926 1927 1926 1927 rtlaine 11 13 0 1 ioone 82 91 5 8 3ox Butte 106 140 10 23 Jrown 45 45 4 Juffalo 199 189 34 li 3urt 44 50 11 12 3utler 79 91 8 8 :ass 97 103 8 7s fi5 1 5 -hase 24 24 1 3 -herry 40 55 1 - Cheyenne 72 77 7 9 "lay 74 70 6 :olfax 90 84 ' - fuming 81 85 3 duster 136 152 24 Dakota 188 196 0 Dawes 84 74 9 15 Dawson 126 115 13 13 Oeuel 18 23 3 5 Dixon 34 32 5 Dodge 275 276 42 Douglas 1623 1680 Dundy 22 25 6 6 ? illniore 90 80 8 4 r ranklin 56 62 6 5 frontier 23 36 4 4 FHirnas 50 57 12 13 3age . : 200 199 19 26 ?xarden 28 IS 2 2 Sarfield 20 24 2 4 5osper 21 . 28 3 2 3rant 4 g i 6 5reeley 44 30 1 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 COUNTY 1926 1927 LTL V \Ji 1926 1927 .... Hitchcock Hooker 7 33 86 10 9 30 124 20 3 3 8 0 \ 81 73 6 4 .Johnson Keya Paha Kimball Knox Lancaster McPherson 120 43 77 38 8 43 80 850 171 10 17 6 109 55 61 51 9 38 85 828 175 18 26 5 4 3 1 1 4 4 5 168 34 1 1 0 1 17 2 fadi&amp;on errick Morrill e Nemaha . . . . . V k 11 Otoe Pawnee Perkins Pierce ... Platte Polk Red Willow Richardson 151 78 78 57 73 65 141 33 20 91 SO 163 31 125 91 158 80 81 48 58 61 135 46 18 74 83 181 34 118 96 18 6 6 2 12 5 15 1 1 3 6 6 5 10 13 2 1 1 2; 1 1 2 iunders 3tts Bluff eridan Sherman Kux nton Thayer rr I 103 333 137 204 135 55 55 21 66 9 81 336 143 224 139 59 53 25' 39 0 7 7 6 29 5 1 1 2 2 I </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF THE MARRIAGES DIVORCES COUNTY 1926 1927 1926 1927 Valley 61 66 6 Washington 100 82 6 15 Wayne H7 68 1 9 Webster 73 49 4 4 Wheeler 6 9 1 0 York 156 143 14 10 TOTAL 9662 9800 1394 16i'O </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 CRASKA STATE BUREAU OF HEALTH— DIVISION OF VITAL STATISTICS PRINCIPAL AND OTHER CAUSES OF DEATH 1926 thoid and Paratyphoid Fever let Fever 24 36 26 18 Measles Mumps Malaria 22 71 1 1 2 1 Small Pox 8 1 Whooping Cough Diphtheria 103 50 36 46 Influenza (AD Forms) Erysipelas 530 339 26 34 Acute Poliomyelitis 15 22 Lethargic Encephalitis 14 6 feingococcus Meningitis nus 10 7 Tuberculosis (All Forms) Syphilis 441 400 77 54 Gonoeoceus Infection 18 12 Purulent Infection, Septieemia Cancer i All Forms) 66 38 1198 1257 Diabetes Mellitus Pernicious Anemia 224 273 121 76 Alcoholism i Acute or Chronic) 26 19 Meningitis, Simple and Cerebrospinal 28 26 Cerebral Hemorrhage, Apoplexy 1165 1266 Endocarditis and Myocarditis (Acute) 110 99 Antrina Pectoris 189 186 Other Diseases of the Heart 1151 1840 155 170 .oriosciMi-usis Embolism ~"d Thrombosis (Not Cerebral) 79 78 Bronchitis (All Forms i 62 36 Pneumonia (All Forms) 1085 769 Ulcer of Stomach and Duodenum 67 73 Diarrhea and Enteritis 267 206 Appendicitis 259 223 Hernia and Intestinal Obstruction 153 157 Nephritis (Acute and Chronic) 666 648 Diseases of the Prostate 94 103 The Puerperal State 179 170 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Division of Child Hygiene: The Division of Child Hygiene, as operated during the biennium, has been the State's agency to carry cut the provisions of the federal law having to do with maternity and infancy. Approximately two-thirds of the funds used in this Division have come from appropriations made by the federal government to assist states in this work. The Sheppard-Towner law was passed by Congress in 1921 and in 1922 Nebraska commenced receiving funds under its provisions. During the intervening time up to June 30, L928, b total money expended in the hygiene and welfare program in action with maternity and infancy has been $98,460.88. Of this int, $68,914.78 has been received from the federal government. tThe work of this Division to meet the requirement of the federal rd is limited to the pre-schocl age child and its mother. The need this work becomes apparent when we recall that in one recent yeai 15,105 mothers died in the federal registration area from causes re - lating to childbirth. When a sympathetic public further recalls that 63.5% of these deaths were from causes that were largely preventable, it is simply appalled. A glance at the maternal mortality figures in other countries during the same year is a humiliation to any self - respecting American, for the United States loses more mothers in childbirth than any civilized country except Chile, South America. The protection of the motherhood of our State demands that Nebraska con - tinue its maternity and infancy program. It is definitely determined that the appropriations of the Sheppard- Towner Act cease upon June 30, 1929. Unless another law is passed by Congress, and that seems impossible at this short session, Nebraska most depend upon her own resources commencing with July first, next. With this situation in mind the Secretary of the Department has, in JAKLY INFANCY: Congenital Malformations Congenital Debility, Icterus and Sclerema . Premature Birth Injury at Birth iuicides: (All Forms) lomicides: (All Forms. Automobile Accidents tailroad Accidents itreet Car Accidents Leroplane and Baloon Accidents Excessive Heat Excessive Cold . 204 127 508 95 173 36 83 3 151 194 55 4 * 0 3 6 • •) 3 .■egal Electrocution 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 his estimates, suggested additional appropriations over what the State has been furnished heretofore. These appropriations will necessarily be considerable if the work is to continue on the basis on which it has operated during the last biennium. The expenditures for the current fiscal year will be considerably more than ever before for any one year in view of the fact that we have been unable to match all of the federal moneys which were available for matching. The federal moneys have all been available for two years. We have therefore matched the back funds to prevent their lapsing and this conservation has resulted in our being able to save until this time the $5,000.00 which accrue without matching for the year 1929. The following gives a few of the details of the work of the Division r the past biennium: L Through the year 1927 there were three public health nurses in Division of Child Hygiene. Health schools for women were held ii thirty-six communities giving four lessons each in prenatal, infant, and child care, and in prevention and control of disease. Lesson out - lines and bulletins added value to this instruction. Eighteen groups of high school girls received instruction, also in four lessons on infant and child care. The work with the girls has been so appreciated by both teachers and school superintendents that we are bending all of our energies this current year to increase the number of schools and groups in schools. We have now four public health nurses including the director. The greater interest of the girls and the application of lessons in their own homes with younger brothers and sisters shows how well the work is received. The teachers who usually have little training in infant care appreciate this help as a preparation for their own child care courses. » Child Health Conferences: During the biennium there have been 6 Child Health Conferences held, in which 5,514 children have had complete physical examination by physicians. We know that many ildren have been benefited immediately, but it is difficult to count corrections made later as many children are never seen again. The purpose of the conference is fulfilled if parents are instructed as to the needs of the child and go to the family physician for help. In the follow-up home calls the field nurses find the children improved as to nutrition and home care and also find a gratifying number of correc - tions of the various defects pointed out. Repeated calls by public health nurses would be of material assistance in improving the health of the child and of the family. Isolated parents in the sand hills have been most generous in their expression of appreciation for the personal work in their homes. Through home calls expectant mothers are found and instructions and special literature given them. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE Free Bulletins: Literature is sent out from the office daily; families registering births are supplied with booklets and many letters of gratitude are received. Two bulletins are supplied to many Nebraska obstetricians, one on prenatal and the other on infant care, while a special bulletin is sent to each senior student in Nebraska's two medical schools. The Division of Child Hygiene has had the cooperation of the Federated Women's Clubs, rural clubs, and of the P. T. A. in sponsoring classes and child health conferences. The Legion Auxiliary, the W. C. T. U., Royal Neighbors, Red Cross, and church societies have been most generous in their help. The Director, because of her official con - nection with public health in the Federated Clubs and the P. T. A., has had a very direct contact with local organizations. It is evident that interest in community health work is increasing. With the additional funds which are available for the last year's work in maternity and infancy we hope to employ a physician part of the time to advance our health program for mothers. SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES OF DIVISION OF CHILD HYGIENE Health Schools for Women ■&gt;•&gt; High School Classes ( Entire Year ■ (Two months, September and October l'.&lt;2* Child Health Conferences 56 100 Children Examined 2H49 Defects (remedial, found 4264 Home calls 2436 1928-NEW WORK Form letters with 1928 Vital Statistics sent to physicians ■ Form letters with 1927 Vital Statistics sent to physicians Letters to School Superintendents with lesson outlines — Child Hygiene Letters to County Superintendents with Book Lists Letters to County Superintendents with May Day Material * Letters to Ministers with May Day Material Requests for Literature Prenatal Letters flO in set) </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Division of Laboratories: The laboratories are maintained for the purpose of aiding in the prevention of infectious and contagious diseases. Their work consists of examinations to aid in the diagnosis of such diseases; examinations to determine freedom from the infectious agents prior to release from quarantine; examinations for the detection of carriers of infectious agents; and of water, sewage and ice. A more df-tailed description of the work done by the laboratories may be sum - marzied as follows: Wasserman tests on blood and spinal fluid to assist in the diagnosis and treatment of syphilis; microscopic examina - tion of pus to assist in the diagnosis of gonorrhea; microscopic ex - amination of throat cultures to assist in the diagnosis of diphtheria; blood tests to assist in the diagnosis of typhoid; cultures on spinal fluid for meningitis; microscopic examination of sputum for tubercu - losis; and the bacteriological examination of water to determine its fitness for drinking. The result of the water examinations are the only ones reported directly to the individual. In cases where water proves unfit for drinking, directions for sterilization are sent with the S Specimens to be examined are submitted by free clinics, state in - itutions, federal institutions within the state, local boards of health, schools and practicing physicians. During the years of 1925 and 1926 slightly less than one thousand physicians submitted approximately one-half of the specimens examined. The remainder of the specimens came from the sources just mentioned. The State makes no charge for this service and no doctor can ethically use what the State does to increase the fee charged his patient. Contrary to the general idea, the laboratories do not examine everything. The Rules and Regulations of the Bureau of Health clearly state that only those tests that assist in the diagnosis and control of infectious disease shall be made. This means that examinations for cancer, blood counts, urinalyses and complete chemical analysis of water for mineral content cannot be made. During the six years 1921-26 the laboratories made an average of 527 examinations per year. The examinations for the year 1927 reached 30,208 and they will undoubtedly pass that figure by from three to five thousand for 1928. fin April of 1928 a branch laboratory was opened at Scottsbluff compliance with an act of the last session of the Legislature. The e thousand dollars appropriated to equip and operate this laboratory were insufficient to equip and operate it for a full two-year period. The laboratory has been opened in rooms in the basement of the West Nebraska Methodist Hospital. We are not paying rent, but are meet - ing the other expenses out of the appropriation. If a laboratory is to </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 be operated for a full two years it will be necessary to have a larger appropriation. Seven hundred and twenty examinations were made in the branch laboratory during the first six months of its existence. Water tests are not made there, but the Wasserman examinations are made. Due to the advances in medical science and changes in prevalent diseases it has been necessary for the laboratory to add examinations for undulant fever and for tularemia. I The demands upon the technical staff of the laboratories have n so great that it has been almost impossible to examine all speci - is that come to the laboratory with the degree of promptness essen - tial to this class of work. Therefore, funds should be provided for additional technical help. The Director of the laboratories has been assisting in the work properly belonging to the Division of Sanitation, were one organized. If we had a sanitary engineer' that would assist somewhat in relieving the force in the laboratories. The assistant technician who aids in the examinations has beer carrying some work in the State University and has been only or five-sixths time with the Department. Doubtless in the near future he will want to go on full time if he stays with us and provision shouk be made to meet the increased salary which that will make neci The following tables have been prepared by the Direc laboratories : REPORT OF LABORATORY ACTIVITIES Examinations Made by the Division of Laboratories Since January 1, 1925 Nine Months 1925 1926 192 1928 Wasserman (blood) 16,769 16,481. 18,913 15.9S0 Wasserman (spinal fluid Comp. Fix. Gonorrhea. 422 466 5:32 121 160 197 435 229 Smears for Treponema none 15 3 21 a Blood Cultures 7 35 34 21 Agglutination Tests 243 316 388 309 Comp. Fix. T. B 73 244 263 126 Feces (Parasites) 1 5 1 9 Feces (Bacteriological) 43 45 89 17 Cultures for Diphtheria 2054 2094 3080 1510 Cultures for Meningococci 4 28 8 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 Eludes 720 examinations made in the Scottsbluff Branch Laboratory and itemized above. Division of Venereal Diseases: This Division is also called that of Social Hygiene. Its work is both medical and educational. By giv - ing prompt and adequate treatment new cases are prevented, while through dissemination of correct information, particularly by reaching parents in order that sex instruction may be started properly and early constructive progress has been made resulting in ultimate prevention. Ehas been increasingly evident that efficiency is handicapped h lack of a trained worker to deal with the social features of the il plan. The procurement of such a worker will greatly aid it, through prevention. The recreational phase of that plan must for the present be left to the local community and the other agencies which are gradually providing for the same. There is no economy in the failure to supply the recognized relief measures. Every preventive measure should be employed to the fullest extent in combatting diseases so insidious, destructive, far reaching and involving, not only the health of all classes of our population, but also involving great loss of life. Venereal diseases cause untold distress, misery, and their prevention justifies an aggressive program. By granting an adequate appropria - tion the Legislature will make a great contribution to the conservation of the public health. The Director of the Division of Venereal Diseases is a physician who does most of the field work in the Division of Epidemiology which, in the absence of having an express head is under the supervision of the Chief of The Bureau of Health. Sputum for Tubercle Bacilli Water ( Bacteriological | Water (Chemical i . . Ice ( Bacteriological Ice (Chemical Other examinations 438 490 1118 1433 14 35 18 17 none 14 13 2 none 2 217 978 453 355 1523 1325 30 2 4 6 none none none 1 none none 1292 1078 TOTAL FOR YEAR . 23,404 25,622 30,208 not completed First nine months period . . . . . 18,714 19,816 21,499 24,910* </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE (This Bureau is the unifying agency through which the state co - rates with individuals and organizations on matters pertaining to dren and to the families in which these children live. It is required by law to endeavor in every possible way to lessen and prevent penal trials and punishments of children. This is the State's authority for encouraging and building up the work of the juvenile courts of the State and of probation in connection therewith. The extent of the work in the field has increased very materially during the last four years. This was so noticeable that at the last session of the Legisla - ture the Department was given additional funds with which to employ a second case worker. We therefore now have two agents in the field much of the time. Most of the work consists of investigating cases referred to the Child Welfare Bureau by the juvenile courts, county attorneys and by other county officials. They must be experts in child welfare work in order to satisfy the obligations that these de - mands put upon them. The facts connected with any given case, so far as known at the office, are discussed between the field worker and her superior. However, the details in any given case are not usually known until the worker is on the ground and makes her own investiga - tion. It is therefore necessary for her to assume the responsibility. Both of our case workers are competent to do this and the Department gets nothing but the best of reports from the officials with whom these workers deal. The high character of their work has much to do with the increased confidence which the juvenile courts over the state have shown in the work of the Department of Public Welfare. Perhaps the fact that the chief of the Bureau of Child Welfare and the Secretary of the Depart - ment of Public Welfare are both experienced in juvenile court work, the former as a chief juvenile probation officer and the latter as a juvenile court judge, has enabled the Department to better meet the demands of the officials over the state. The practical experience of this group in handling cases doubtless has contributed to the results obtained. They thoroughly understand that it is not the province of the Department, through the courts, to disrupt homes except when that is absolutely necessary; they would rather rehabilitate those homes and make them a fit place where the children can be properly kSo far as the Department has had a response to the efforts of its workers it has all been laudatory. More than one judge has ten in, urging the return of the worker at an early date and kly stating that he makes this request because of the excellent </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 results obtained on prior visits. One judge was so enthused that he asked that the worker be kept in his district as much of the time as possible. Sometimes the rehabilitating of the family is impossible; but ordinarily persistence will overcome even a temporary defeat and the apparently impossible is accomplished. We look forward to the time when every community may have a case worker of its own so that she may be on the job all the time. A well trained person of that character not only would raise the moral standards of the children of the com - munity, but she would also lessen the financial burdens occasioned by improvidence. Many Iowa counties have had a vision of the possibilities of the accomplishments of such a worker. That vision has become a reality in some of the Iowa counties and those workers are functioning to the great advantage of their respective communities, financially as well as morally. As the law now stands the juvenile courts are authorized to ap - point probation officers in the several counties, but there is no authority to pay such officers except in Douglas and Lancaster counties. The County Boards of some of the counties have been providing for such pay. However, they are more reluctant to do this than they would be if there was an express law authorizing it. (There is also need of a clinic where the mental condition of chil - ■en can be studied and their mental as well as physical condition arned. Many of the cities of the country have such clinics. That in Chicago is a notable example and has been doing successful work. The experts there have learned that the delinquent recidivist is, in a majority of case, mentally subnormal. The converse is equally true, the subnormal delinquent is almost sure to be a repeater. 1 Wherever the state has assumed its proper place in caring for pendency as well as delinquency the result has been a general uplift of all of our charity and eleemosynary work together with that dealing with delinquency. The inefficiency shown in dealing with dependents at times seems almost incredible. For example, the feeble-minded should be taught to do what is within their physical and mental powers. I am not overlooking the fact that much work along this line is now being done. It should, however, be carried to a far greater extent and should reach a far greater number of our feebleminded. Many of them are still at large in every community in the state who are capable of being trained to be self-sustaining provided they have the necessary supervision. Such training would conduce to their happiness while at the same time it would relieve the state of heavy financial burdens. As it is now, many of the mentally handicapped are inter-marrying and the offspring is almost sure to be mentally defective. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 It is important that the delinquent youth feel the restraining hand of the state. However, it is impossible without the means of studying the mental condition of the subject to know whether he belongs in the institution at Kearney or in that at Beatrice. The delinquent youth ris normal should be dealt with severely, while it is inhuman to treat subnormal companion in the same way. In 1921 the Legislature passed a law providing for a Bureau of Juvenile Research. This Bureau was placed under the Board of Control and that Board was given authority to make mental and physical examinations of all children committed to it and then determine to what state institution they, should be admitted. That Bureau has never functioned because there was a question whether the law as passed ■was not vulnerable to the provision of the constitution that the subject matter in the law must not be broader than the title. The truth of it is that the bill was prepared by the Children's Code Commission and presented to the Legislature, but the title was amended, in the House of Representatives in deference to the idiosyncracies of one of its mem - bers. A district judge held the law invalid, but the question was never presented to the supreme court. It would conduce to the intelligent handling of our dependent or delinquent children if this bill could be passed with an adequate title or a bill of similar nature passed. It is a progressive step that Nebraska should take. One of our Child Welfare field workers on a return fron trip reported ten cases of feeblemindedness among children. The were scattered among six different families. There was no cha get any of them in the institution at Beatrice because it was alrea overrun. Ection 6511 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922 re - the census enumerators shall report to the county superintendents data, together with the names of all blind, deaf, crippli feebleminded persons and the superintendent in turn shall forward the information received to the Director of the Child Welfare Bureau. It is certain that this data is by no means complete. However, it is helpful. We have later in this report printed a table showing the information received along this line from the several counties. The longer one works with the underprivileged child the more he becomes convinced that lack of opportunity largely comes from ineom - petency and neglect of the child's parents, who do not measure up to the fundamental requirements of parenthood. A child thus handicapped must have more than the ordinary amount of intelligence and courage to successfully meet life's problems. Each failure is more discourag - ing:, more disastrous to him than it is to the child with a family of </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 standing back of him. He loses in association, in home comforts, in health, in school attendance and because of this often it is difficult to tell whether his mind is defective or whether his trouble comes from an arrested mental development due to environment. The under privileged child with this mental handicap especially is in need of the assisting hand of a trained and sympathetic probation officer. Fre - quently, as he grows, such an officer means for him the difference be - tween success and failure. Even if he has work, more than likely it is not suited to his capabilities. Intelligent guidance will adjust this, will readjust it as often as it is necessary until he very likely will be - come a self-supportinp citizen. DEFECTIVE CHILDREN IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FROM THE CENSUS ENUMERATOR'S REPORT 1927-1928 ■ County Blind Deaf Crippled Defectiv. Mind Banner Blaine Boon? Box Butte Boyd 1 0 0 0 0 2 0 0 0 0 o 0 1 1 1 1 20 7 1 0 1 9 4 5 . Brown Buffalo Bun Butler Cass Cedar 2 0 0 0 0 4 3 4 2 0 19 1 6 11 15 1 1 0 2 7 i 8 o "Cheyenne Custer . 0 0 0 2 0 0 Q 0 2 1 3 1 0 5 9 2 14 3 5 ] </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Defective County Blind Deaf Crippled Mind Dodge 15 7 5 Douglas 17 41 100 0 Dundy 0 0 0 3 Fillmore 1 2 5 3 Franklin 1 3 2 6 Frontier 0 2 3 1 Furnas 0 2 5 3 Gage 1 5 8 .6 Garden 0 0 1 0 Garfield 0 0 0 0 Gosper 1 2 0 3 'Grant. . Greeley 2 1 5 1 Hall 1 2 5 4 Hamilton 0 3 15 3 Harlan 0 3 0 Hayes 0 1 0 Hitchcock 0 0 l Holt.. 0 5 9 o Hooker . Howard o Jefferson 1 Johnson 0 1 6 Kearney ii Keith 1 0 *Keya Paha Kimball 0 Knox 0 3 4 Lancaster 12 Lincoln 0 3 6 Logan 0 0 i) Loup 0 0 1 1 Madison 0 1 &gt; McPherson 0 0 0 0 •Merrick. Morrill 0 4 4 5 Nance 0 9. Nemaha 0 0 1 0 Nuckolls 0 7 6 s i Otoe 2 0 7 6 •Pawnee Perkins 0 0 1 1 Phelps 10 8 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 51 * Defective Polk Red Willow 'Richardson . Rock Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward 'Sheridan Sherman Sioux . . Stanton Thomas . Thurston Wellington Wayne Webster TOTAL Indicates Countiei Not Reporting </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 CHILD PLACING AGENCIES tThe following Child Placing Agencies and Homes were licensed by Department of Public Welfare upon recommendation of the Bureau hild Welfare during the biennium and they have placed children in es to the number following their names: n- name M ELA.G11 Mrs. A. A. tin's il Kev. E. .! Luihiran Orphai I. F. Gihisp. ■.ska Child] W. Muuh Fletch« 147 or V. Schuli [. S. Pi Totals CHILD PLACING AGENCIES E following institutions have given the bond required by section the compiled statutes of Nebraska for 1922, authorizing corpora - place children within the state: Children's Aid Society of New York, New York City 21 35 56 Mrs. J. W. Swan, Sup2rintendsnt. Florence Crittenton Home, Sioux City, Iowa Mrs. Maud F. Swan, Superintendent. ri and Girls Home, Sioux City, Iowa 2 1 :i Alice E. Hopper, Superintendent. St. Monica's Home, Sioux City, Iowa Totals. GRAND TOTALS St. T ; ! ..-.i- ;&gt;! phana e, 1 Roys Girls Toril </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE ( SOME OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU Os and Maternity Homes visited 92 ar bienmur pitals for 192 pitals for 192 ni biennium Legitimate Illegitimate Bv Private Agencies rhildren placed during 1928: 3y Courts By Fn i ate Agencies Total number placed during biennium By Courts . By Private Agencies . ri-p^w.kp- 1 q*?si orp not included. Jren placed during 1927: By Courts </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 MOTHERS' PENSIONS R'he fundamental idea in aid to mothers is that financial assistance neans to an end, the end being the integrity of the family. The tary of the Department, together with the Children's Bureau, has been doing everything possible to secure aid for the indigent mother with children, where the family could qualify under the law. It is better that where aid is necessary it be given in that form rather than as a dole. The striking difference between mothers' aid and poor relief is that the latter has as its aim to prevent and relieve distress; while the former, when it has accomplished that, does not stop but goes on and builds up for the future by strengthening the home. This is frequently done by suggesting economies in buying and better dietary and generally by the rendering of helpful, personal service. To give this service we must develop our standard of supervision by the educa - tion of our probation forces. It has been said that if we had a large enough force of well trained probation officers we could eliminate crime from among our normal population. Although this is an ex - travagant statement, much is being accomplished where probation is intelligently employed. It can also be said with just as much truth that if we could have enough trained service of our social workers, call them probation officers, case workers, or what you will, to advise with the improvident and to rehabilitate broken families very little material aid would be required to assist the breadwinner in supporting his family. However, we have a different situation when the breadwinner, for any reason, is lost. Such families need the advice and encourage - ment of the case worker, but along with that advice must go the necessary funds to support the family. However, even in these families there are frequently some children of an age who can properly assist in the support and a probation officer can be helpful in planning for them. Then again, many of these families must be shown how to live; taught what to do and how to do it, and it is surprising the response which one may get to intelligent guidance. LFor four years the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare been sending out questionnaires for information relating to mothers' ions. We have never been able to get reports from all the counties. For 1927 we have reports from eighty-nine counties, which is the highest number we have ever received. The counties failing to report are Banner, Frontier, Logan and Rock. These counties have been sent five requests to answer our questionnaire. There should be a law passed putting mothers' pensions under the supervision of the Depart - ef Public Welfare and all officials administering aid to mothers be required to conform to methods suggested by the Department &gt;uld be compelled to report all information requested. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 For the year 1927 five counties report that they are not granting any mothers' pensions, as the county commissions are giving direct relief. This means in most cases that the relief is given as a charity and is stressed by the giver as such. Relief given in that way simply allays or prevents suffering, but does not do anything to cure the cause which has led to the asking for relief. Usually it is given without investigation and its expenditure is supervised in no way, except that the recipient is warned to economize. A welfare worker who is familiar with handling the indigent will save her salary many times in investi - gating cases where relief is asked and in supervising expenditures after the relief is granted. However, many of the county boards will persist in themselves handling the funds given out until public senti - ment is aroused and becomes alert to the need of a more sensible and economical method of handling such problems. Not until then will progress be made in the elimination of improvidence. It is important to relieve distress, but it is even more important to educate against continued shiftlessness while giving relief. The following table shows the amount expended by the several counties in payment of mothers' pensions during the years 1926 and 1927. The table also gives the number of children receiving benefits in the different counties. Eighty-nine counties have reported and these show an increase in the amount of mothers' pensions paid of 819,044.04 over the preceding year. This is almost a ten per cent in - crease. The number of children receiving benefit in 1927 was 3322 as against 3029 in 1926. Again we have substantially an increase of ten per cent. GENERAL SUMMARY OF MOTHERS' PENSION QUESTIONNAIRES FOR 1926 AND 1927 1926 1927 86 89 Number counties reporting (93 in state) . Total Number mothers receiving pension Total number children involved 1,103 3,029 3^322 Average number of children of pension age under 14 1 *in pensioned families 2.74 Total paid out as pensions 202,591.95 $221,635.99 CLASSIFICATION OF MOTHERS 701 or 63.5', 717 or 61.1', 162 or 14.68', 216 or 18.4' r 113 or 10.2', 103 or 8.7'; Widowed Deserted Divorced Unmarried . . 5 or .47% 5 or .42% Husbands Incapacitated . Husbands in penitentiary 78 or 7', 70 or 5.9 % 44 or 3.9 % 62 or 5.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 TEN COUNTIES PAYING LARGEST NUMBER OF PENSIONS 1926 1927 County No. Pensions County No Pensions Douglas 177 Douglas Gage 52 * Lancaster M Lancaster 48 Gage Madison 33 Madison Scotts Bluff 33 Saunders I Saunders 30 Platte Cass 29 Custer Custer Platte 28 Jefferson Cass 25 Jefferson .» Scotts Bluff TEN COUNTIES PAYINC LARGEST AMOUNTS Douglas $34,4S6.35 Douglas $43,576.16 11,387.61 Lancaster 10,390.00 Lair-aster Gaje Saunders 7,480.00 •),.*_.■}.'"' Gage 5,990.00 Madison Saunders Cedar Cedar 5,780.00 Madison 5,380.00 Knox 4,786.00 Platt« Scotts Bluff 4,780.00 Dawson Jefferson Knox 4,66 1 . ■"&gt;' ' Pierce 4,440.00 4.536.00 Custer 4,377.00 4,515.00 changing this to '"Under 16' 'A law became effective July 24, 192 AMOUNTS PAID OUT BY NEBRASKA COUNTIES FOR MOTHERS- PENSIONS IN 1926 AND 1927 1926 Number 1927 Number Amount Children Amount Children Adams $2,820.00 40 $3,350.00 54 Antelope 1,771.00 28 1,956.00 25 Arthur 120.00 1 120.00 1 Banner . * . Blaine 000.00 0 000.00 0 Boone 2,945.00 40 2,597.00 56 Box Butte 600.00 5 1,164.00 13 Boyd 1,850.00 26 1,260.00 13 Brown 876.00 38 978.00 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 1926 Number 1927 Number Amount Children Amount Children COUNTY Burt 415.00 29 2,500.00 27 Butler 2,150.00 20 2,490.00 21 Cass 3,604.50 63 2,867.50 64 Cedar 58 4,990.00 5S 5,780.00 Chase 2,540.00 22 2,040.00 IT Cherry 240.00 *2 660.00 Cheyenne 2,720.00 32 2,515.00 2 Clay 1,972.00 33 2,312.00 33 Colfax 3,390.00 32 2,995.00 33 Cuming 660.00 8 830.00 1 Custer 4,377.00 87 3,738.00 8 4,377.00 87 3,738.00 87 Dakota 2,532.00 30 2,384.00 2 30 2,384.00 24 2,532.00 Dawes 1,330.00 36 2,035.00 4 49 1,330.00 36 2,035.00 Dawson 4,661.50 4 49 4,661.50 Deuel 720.00 6 940.00 1 720.00 6 940.00 15 Dixon 2,700.00 29 3,045.00 3 2,700.00 29 3,045.00 36 Dodge 1,110.00 8 1,900.50 3 1,110.00 8 1,900.50 37 Douglas 37,486.35 17,486.35 665 43,576.16 76 665 43,576.16 767 Dundy * * 600.00 * 600.00 8 Fillmore 000.00 0 000.00 000.00 0 000.00 o Franklin 339.00 339.00 10 300.00 B 10 300.00 Frontier 655.00 17 * 655.00 17 * • Furnas 1,440.00 14 2,360.00 2 1,440.00 14 2,360.00 24 Gage 5,990.00 5,990.00 110 7,110.00 13 110 7,110.00 131 Garjen 1,305.00 19 610.00 2 1,305.00 19 610.00 26 Garfield 000.00 000.00 00 000.00 00 00 000.00 00 Gosper 870.00 10 1,138.00 1 870.00 10 1,138.00 12 Grant 360.00 360.00 3 360.00 3 360.00 3 Greelev 870.00 12 930.00 1 870.00 12 930.00 12 Hall 2,360.00 2,360.00 38 1,220.00 1 38 1,220.00 IT Hamilton 1,858.50 18 2,364.00 2 1,858.50 21 18 2,364.00 Harlan 1,365.00 15 1,180.00 1 1,365.00 15 1,180.00 16 Hayes 000.00 00 000.00 00 000.00 (10 000.00 00 Hitchcock 1,740.00 23 1,150.00 1 1,740.00 23 1,150.00 15 Holt 2,000.00 2,000.00 49 2,000.00 7 49 2,000.00 76 Hooker 50.00 2 150.00 3 Howard 456.00 8 1,106.00 1 17 Jefferson 3,096.43 43 4,536.00 4 4S Johnson 1,842.00 19 1,671.00 2 20 Kearney 2,420.00 23 31 2,480.00 Keith 590.00 10 1,740.00 28 Keya Paha 540.00 7 770.00 17 Kimball 240.00 3 540.00 6 Knox 4,786.00 50 1,515.00 50 Lancaster 10,390.00 169 11,337.61 163 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF THE 1926 Number 1927 Number Amount Children Amount Children Lincoln 3,660.00 55 4,056.00 53 * * * * Loup 000.00 00 000.00 00 Madison 5,380.00 75 7,060.00 97 McPherson 000.00 00 000.00 00 Merrick 1,505.00 25 2,340.00 28 Morrill 1,060.00 17 1,345.00 27 Nance 3,255.00 45 3,045.00 51 Nemaha 2,858.50 43 2,574.00 48 Nuckolls ** 36 2,220.00 38 Otoe 2,300.00 22 2,396.00 28 Pawnee * * 000.00 00 Perkins 930.00 18 2,040.00 21 Phelps 1,370.00 29 1,540.00 24 Pierce 4,440.00 40 2,925.00 27 Platte 3,710.00 59 4,860.00 89 Polk 2,720.00 33 3,420.00 30 Red Willow 2,100.00 28 1,404.00 20 Richardson 1,953.00 55 2,280.00 60 Rock Saline 2,759.67 16 000.00 00 Sarpy 000.00 00 000.00 00 Saunders 7,480.00 80 5,925.00 . 64 Scotts Bluff 4,780.00 72 3,544.00 Seward 2,400.00 27 860.00 Sheridan * * 1,960.00 30 Sherman 980.00 12 840.00 12 Sioux '690.00 13 900.00 8 Stanton 240.00 4 000.00 00 Thayer 1,710.00 18 1,860.00 21 Thomas 000.00 00 270.00 4 Thureton 2,145.00 29 2,115.00 26 Valley 000.00 00 000.00 00 Washington 3,620.00 42 2,926.72 43 Webster 1,280.00 20 1,150.00 14 Wayne 690.00 8 1,170.00 19 Wheeler 40.00 2 000.00 00 York 2,670.00 36 3,190.00 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 JUVENILE COURTS AND PROBATION fWhat has already been said under the subject of mothers' pensions regard to state supervision and reporting applies equally to both probation and juvenile courts. The Children's Bureau has attempted to systematize and make uniform the reporting of statistics on these subjects. It would be a great advantage if the plan suggested by that Bureau would be carried out. However, it seems hopeless to attempt to inaugurate such a plan without some representative who is familiar Kit visiting the individual courts and educating the officials of that t, not only in the details of the plan, but also in the importance of the work. The present juvenile court law is very much out of date. It was passed almost a quarter of a century ago when juvenile court methods were new. These have changed materially during the inter- King years. The Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare isted in the preparation of an up to date act which was introduced in the last session of the legislature. It was reported for passage by the judiciary committee, but failed to secure the approval of the House. tis quite important that the original law be amended in several par - llars, but such amendments would only partially meet the needs. 3 National Probation Association has prepared a model law which is excellent. This Department wishes that a law based on the one introduced in the last session or on the model act be passed by the present session of the legislature. SOLICITING AGENTS Many complaints have reached the Department about solicitors traveling over the state, collecting money for different benevolences. Many of these solicitors represent worthy institutions and the generous public desires to contribute. However, some of the agents represent institutions that are not entitled to receive public aid. There is no way that the would-be donors can select the good from the bad. The result is that after he has discovered that he has been contributing to an unworthy cause he becomes suspicious of all solicitors. Therefore, there has been quite a demand that some state agents be authorized to pass upon the worthiness of any benevolent institution proposing to solicit in the state. Kansas has a law of that character. That law vests in the Board of Administration the power to carefully examine and issue a certificate granting the privilege of soliciting throughout the state to the agents of any institutions meeting the approval of that board. No institution, without such a certificate, can solicit in more than one county in Kansas and can be prosecuted criminally when </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 OTHER NEEDED LEGISLATION At the last session of the legislature the Child Welfare Bureau sponsored two bills, one amending the present law relating to maternity homes and the other a new act regulating boarding homes for children under two years. Both these bills received the approval of the senate. were approved by the judiciary committee of the House, but failed of passage there. The discussion of these two bills and of the juvenile court bill, referred to above, on the floor of the House showed that the members had not gained a proper understanding of their purposes. There seems to be no method whereby such information can be imparted. The only chance that the friends of a measure have to present it is to the com - mittee to which it is referred. If the bill is complicated it is quite p- obable that no member of that committee can give it the necessary time to fully understand it so that he can explain and discuss its several provisions on the floor. It would seem that possibly the best remedy would be for the committee to give more time to the considera - tion of bills referred to it. However, the committees are overworked and usually, even if a member is interested, he has too many other bills demanding his attention. The result is that he is unable to master the details of all bills that he is called upon to present. NEBRASKA WELFARE BULLETIN The Department, in 1927, commenced the issuance of a quarterly bulletin consisting of sixteen pages. The purpose of this bulletin was to give information to the interested public in the work of the Depart - ment with the end in view that its facilities might be made of more general use. I Alma Morrison, the Chief Clerk of the Department, was appointed tor and has prepared the materials which have been published in se bulletins. We feel that this is one of the outstanding new features during the biennium. Morrison has shown an appreciation of what is of interest to readers of such a bulletin and is to be congratulated upon the result her efforts. rMARY BY FIELD SECRETARY OF THE NATIONAL PROBATION ASSOCIATION After this report was almost written, there was received by the Department a report on a survey of the Juvenile Court and Probation service in seven counties of Nebraska. Mr. Drowne, the field secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 of the National Probation Association, who made the survey, spent some four months in Nebraska and during that time visited the several counties covered by the survey. I copy in full the general summary which he himself makes of the survey: NEBRASKA JUVENILE COURT AND PROBATION SURVEY GENERAL SUMMARY The study was made at the request of Hon. Lincoln Frost, Secre - tary of the Department of Public Welfare, to show the needs of juvenile court and probation development, especially in the rural counties of Nebraska, and to stimulate local interest in the extension of these agencies. Nearly three months were devoted to the field work. The six counties surveyed and reported on herewith: Adams, Cass, Lancaster, Madison, Scotts Bluff, and Sheridan, were chosen because they seemed to represent certain types of county communities in Ne - braska, and we believe that from the information obtained from these six county studies, a fairly accurate picture can be drawn of the status of juvenile court and probation work throughout the state. In only one county, of the six studied, was the juvenile court equipped to function at all adequately; that is, with one or more full - time, paid probation officers to investigate and supervise the cases coming before the court. In one other county the local county Red Cross Chapter was attempting to handle unofficially some cases that would otherwise have gone to the juvenile court, but because of too much work and because there was no authority behind the worker, very little was actually being accomplished. In the remaining counties very little probation work is being done. Kit can truly be said that in no county visited was there anything e an adequate equipment for this work. The service, wherever car - ried on at all, is perfunctory, relying almost altogether on reports to the -office by the probationer, without any check-up on the home, the school, or on friends and relatives of the families. There has been developed very little community consciousness in the smaller counties studied in regard to the welfare of their young people. There are many counties in Nebraska that do not have enough juvenile court cases to warrant a full-time probation officer for that work alone, but in those instances there is in addition enough general welfare work, such as investigating and supervising mothers' pension cases, where the questions of alimony or custody of children are con - cerned, to keep one worker more than busy. We recommend County Welfare Boards, with one all-around, trained worker in the smaller </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 counties, as the only way to obtain satisfactory probation service as ■well as to cover the other important welfare needs. It would seem that in practically every county in Nebraska an educational campaign must be carried on to make the respective com - munities realize the responsibility they have toward their youth and their families that need help, — not the kind of assistance that will merely help them through some emergent situation, but the kind that will result in permanent rehabilitation. The Child Welfare Division of the State Department of Public Welfare is the logical unit to carry on this educational work. It should be given more authority and additional workers should be added to the staff to assist in carrying out a carefully planned state child welfare program. For this work more of the State Department's money should be diverted to the Child Welfare Division to be used in carrying on demonstrations in certain communities to show those communities the service that could be rendered by full-time, trained, paid workers. At present the larger part of the state seems quite unaware tha they have many problem cases in their midst that need careful, in - telligent attention, and unless these cases, juvenile and adult, are properly handled, conditions will gradually become worse. "A stitch in time saves nine," and the time has come when the Nebraska counties should realize this. To help them in coming to this realization, the State Department of Public Welfare has an impoi'tant part to play. The youth of today is more strongly beset than ever by tempta - tions. Not that these temptations did not exist years ago, but be - cause of the general breaking down of home life, the greater freedom that girls are "enjoying", because of automobiles, liquor, and the general unrest that prevails at present, the young people have a more difficult time in avoiding the many pitfalls that are always at hand. The old saying that "the younth of any community is its greatest asset," is still just as true as ever, and unless the communities through - out Nebraska soon begin some program of work with their boys and girls, conditions are going to become increasingly bad from year to year. RALPH E. DROWNE, Field Secretary, National Probation Association. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>      
  </text>
</TEI.2>