<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-Third Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-Third Biennial Report* OF THK Superintendent OP THE Nebraska School for the Deaf OMAHA, NEBRASKA Tc the Governor and tbe Board of Commissioners of State Institutions Nt-xt fullnwiuK tlie Inmrreotlv ilrnf|cnate&lt;t "Xlnti-entta" Biennial Report. For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">450 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS F. W. Booth Jane E. Jones Superintendent Matron Mary A. Christoffersex Clerk TEACHERS— INTELLECTUAL DEPARTMENT J. W. SOWELL W. H. Rothebt H. L. Welty Ida Hendee Emily E. Sauter Edith Wyckoff Lina Hendershot Bertha Sellner Ruth Wyckoff Mae McKinley Esther Sherwood Pearl Ridgway Elizabeth Warren Ethyl Rogers May Gregory Ota Blankenship Mabel Scriver Nelda Hughes TEACHERS— INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT P. E. Seely .Printing Jesse W. Jackson Edith Johnson Leon a Myers Manual Training Domestic Art and Domestic Science Art Manual Wm. H. Chapman Rachael Gladwin Gardening and Horticulture Laundrying f DOMESTIC DEPARTMENT Jane E. Jones Matron Alfred Jefferson Tillie Frahm Physician N'urse Frank Andrewjeski Mildred Sturdevant alma Hudson Supervisor Supervisor Supervisor Ida Carlson Eva Wood Stacia Kuta Clara Warden Selma Carlson H. E. Gladwin Jesse Dunn Supervisor Assistant Supervisor Assistant Supervisor Assistant Supervisor Assistant Supervisor Engineer Assistant Engineer B. M. Palmer FiremfT </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 451 NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF Omaha, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morekead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and SUa* A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: I have the honor to submit to you this as the Twenty - third* Biennial Report of the Nebraska School for the Deaf, covering the period from December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916. The number of pupils under instruction on November 30, 1914, was 168, of whom 82 were boys and 86 girls. Since that date 45 new pupils, 23 boys and 22 girls, have been admitted. In addition to these, 12 former pupils of this or other similar schools, 8 boys and 4 girls, and 1 girl transferred from another institution, have been admitted. Eleven pupils, 1 boy and 10 girls, have been dismissed by graduation ; two girls have been transferred to other institu - tions, — one to the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, and the other to the Hospital for Tuberculous; and three boys were expelled. The total enrollment for the bien - nium is 226, of whom 184, 95 boys and 89 jrirls, are now in 'Although it imntfiliiitHy follows the "Nineteenth" HmhW It'-port. thin report !« iMlpaaM Twenty -Tliinl. sinre mi error has heen ilisi-i mmt in the title* of some of the earlier in tin- sueiv.Nsinii tt reports. After two annual reports had been published. :if the Has* of the yeiirs lssi mmt M* a rc|&gt;ort rorerlns the hieiiniuni lsTl 1-7-' in wrongly ilesiL'iiKtnl HM "1MK Aimniil Report." anil likewNe the fourth niul tlfth report", althouirh ooverinic r«&gt; - pectivelT the biennial periods 1ST3-1W4 nml 1«TT&gt;.187&lt;1. were mlleil merely "Fourth Report" and 'I'ifth Uiport': Ik* sixth for the yenrs 1"&lt;T7 nml lsTS. wu named "BieiiTtifll Report" : and the next for the years 1*»Tlt and l.**8O, wa« inror rertly ileRici-nled the "St ml Bieliltinl Report", wherens. Ir was in trurh. the "Fifth Biennial Report. " The reports following &lt;*ontimie&lt;l the error tbn* xtarted. a* that although twenty one "nieniiial rep&lt;irt»" ha\e actually been pub linhed to (l«te only nineteen liaye been s,i MMi ami MjM| due to the flrot three heintf ignored as snrh in the enumeration. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">452 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF attendance. The increase in attendance shown over two years ago is sixteen pupils, or 9.5 per cent. Since the founding of the school in 1869, with an enrollment of twelve pupils during that year, there have been in attendance at the school 958 pupils, of which number 133 have completed the course and been awarded diplomas of graduation. Of the 133 graduates. 37 have taken more or less extended courses at Gallaudet Col - lege for the Deaf at Washington, an institution maintained by the United States Government and admitting deaf students from the various states passing the prescribed examination. The course of study followed in the school covers twelve grades and it requires for pupils of average ability twelve years to complete it. Both intellectual and industrial train - ing is given, it being the design to educate and equip the deaf child for a life of usefulness and happiness in the com - munity where that life will be spent. For the best results children should enter school at about the age of seven. Under exceptional circumstances children six years of age are accep - ted. Parents sometimes make the grave error of delaying to send their children to school until they are ten, twelve or fourteen years old, or even older. Such delay works invari - ably to the disadvantage of the pupil, he having passed, when he comes to us, the most impressible learning period, when the mind is plastic, the interest in primary work is natural, and the vocal organs are still in a pliable ?tate. Teaching to speak and to read lips requires the best learning condi - tions, and most important among these conditions is an early start in school. We have two boys in school at this time who Ctered, one at sixteen, the other at twenty-one, and both, DUgh men grown, are in the lowest class. Their progress is slow in the extreme, notwithstanding their eager efforts to master the tasks which the other younger children in the class do with ease. It is a species of selfishness on the part of parents, who, to save themselves the pain of separation, or to retain the profits from their children's labor, deliberately rob them of the educational opportunities rightfully theirs. Instances are known where deaf children have had to await the death of their parents before they could begin their schooling, one such case being that of a woman, now in </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 453 school in a neighboring state, who is fifty-one years old and yet is struggling with the most elementary work in a begin - ning class. Surely the crime committed in this case can be fully expiated only in another world, if there. Upon admission to school each child is placed under oral instruction with the view of teaching him to speak and to read the lips. Deaf children have natural, therefore perfect, vocal organs and by skillful teaching they can be trained to use them to produce intelligible speech ; and where they also possess good eye sight and good or fair mentality, they learn to lip-read to an extent that renders them largely independent of pencil and paper in communicating with others. More - over, a certain amount of mental development of necessity results from the studious effort put forth by the deaf child in learning to speak and read lips, and this fact doubtless accounts for the superior educational results secured through the oral method wherever it is properly applied. The first step in the training of a deaf child in speech is to teach him to articulate the non-vocal, or breath, con - sonants p, t, k, f, etc., the corresponding vocal consonants b, d, g, v, m, n, ng, I, r, etc., and the open vowel a (usually spelled or and pronounced ah). The consonants are then combined with this vowel (similarly with other vowels learned later), thus, pa(r), ta(r), fa(r), ba(r) , da(r), ma(r), a(r)p, a(r)t, o(?) m, etc. These are not taught as words at first, but merely as combinations of elements. Later they are used in teaching real words. The first real words taught are arm, thumb, tooth, mouth, and similar words made up of easily articulated elements. Lip-reading begins with commands, such as, "Stand up," "iralk," "run," "jump," "fall," "open the door," "open a window," etc., the children watching the lips and obeying the commands. Soon real language, that is, language that is spon - taneous and personally useful to the child, is developed. The sign-language is not used, as experience teaches that it forms a barrier to the best progress in the acquisition of speech and written language, and it tends moreover to limit think - ing, and consequently mental development, to the measure of its crude and meagre resources for thought expression. Natu - ral signs, or motions, are employed, as they must be, in the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">454 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF beginning stages of teaching, but they are abandoned at once upon the acquisition of words. Successive stages of instruc - tion give a growing stock of words with mastery of the vari - ous sentence forms that constitute for the child finally a ser - viceable language. Language learned is used from the start for all its purposes, it being recognized that use of language is the best teacher of language. All studies in the course are for the deaf child primarily language studies, their difficulties as they exist for him being almost solely language difficulties. Thus, geography is a language study, presenting its matter and thought in the vocabulary and special expression forms peculiar to that subject; likewise history as taught and stu - died, and natural history, physiology, physics, and even arith - metic and algebra, are but varied opportunities to use and to teach language as the essential thing, the subjects themselves baing mastered only to the degree that the language used is understood by the learner. The scholastic training of the school is given in eighteen classes taught by eighteen teachers, the classes thus averag - ing about ten pupils each. This number, with the difficult work to be done, is found to be a maximum not wisely exceeded in teaching deaf children. The oral method is employed with twelve classes, contain - ing 112 pupils, and the manual method with six classes, con - training 72 pupils. The primary oral classes, under the direc - tion of Miss Emily E. Sauter, with the intermediate oral classes, under the direction of Miss Edith Wyckoff, cover at present the first nine grades of the course of study ; the man - ual department, with the advanced classes under the direction of Mr. J. W. Sowell, covers the entire course of twelve grades. A post-graduate year of study is granted to pupils wishing to prepare to enter Gallaudet College, and at present one pupil is taking this preparatory work. The following is an outline of the course of study pursued in the intellectual departments at the school: First Grade Sense-training, Lip-reading, Articulation, Language, Numbers, Sunday School Work. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 455 Second Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Numbers, Sunday School Work. Third Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Geography, Arith - metic, Industrial Training, Sunday School Work. Fourth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Geography, Arith - metic, Industrial Training, Sunday School Work. Fifth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Descriptive Lessons, Geography (local and Nebraska), Nature Study, Arithmetic, Industrial Training, Sunday School Work. Sixth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Descriptive Lessons, Geography (Nebraska and United States), Nature Study, Arithmetic, Industrial Training, Sunday School Work. Seventh Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Geography (North America, South America, Europe), United States His - tory, Local Biographies, Nature Study, Arithmetic, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Eighth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Geography, United States History, Local Biographies, Nature Study, Arithmetic, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals. Sunday School Work. Ninth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, Political Geography, American Biographies, American History, Phy - siology, Arithmetic, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. , Tenth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, Political Geography, English Biographies, Universal History, Physical </seg>
            <seg id="p009">456 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Geography, Arithmetic, Industrial Training. Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Eleventh Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, American History, Physical Geography, Arithmetic, Physics, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Twelfth Grade Division A, Graduate Course — Language, Grammar, Com - position, Reading, Arithmetic. Physics reviewed, English His - tory, Civil Government, Algebra begun, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Division B, College Preparatory Course — Same course in English as above, Literature, Composition, Algebra, Industrial Training, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. The industrial departments of the school, while primarily aiming to train the hand and the brain in the use of tools and in the making of material things, also give opportunities for language teaching through the use of and drill upon the special vocabulary and language forms pertaining to the industries taught. It has been interesting to note since the teachers of the industries have come to look upon themselves also as teachers of language, that there has been, not only a general improvement in the pupils' language, but in the quality of the work done as well. In the nature of things, language expres - sion makes for precision of thought, and thought precisely expressed or apprehended is the more readily and precisely transformed into the material articles in process of construc - tion. The interest moreover of pupils in all their work is noticeably increased by this linking together of intellectual and mechanical activities. The several industrial courses provided include manual training, printing, wood-carving, farming and gardening for the boys ; and sewing, dressmaking, embroidery, fancy work, domestic science, wood-carving, basketry, leather-work, house - work, and laundrying- for the girls. The manual training classes, under Mr. J. W. Jackson, pursue systematic courses in sloyd, joinery, wood-turning, mechanical drawing, cabinet makine, and house carpentry, the plan being to give all the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">E I* SB If Sffl • r^ ! ■ ■ I - ,,S lr. ~^ I*" I* '1 M ."I ■■■ n ■t u </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 457 boya who enter school at least the primary work, teaching to handle tools, and to give boys wishing to become cabinet makers or carpenters the complete course. New wood-work - ing machinery in this department recently installed equips it for training the boys to meet conditions in shops and factories that they will seek to enter after finishing school. Additional machinery is needed to equip the department to give more complete training, and it is hoped that it will soon be pro - vided. The printing department, under the direction of Mr. P. E. Seely, gives a full course of instruction and training in the various branches of printing, including type-setting, job and press work. During the past year the department, be - sides doing the printing for the school, has by direction of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions done a large amount of printing for other state institutions. This work, including as it does letter heads, envelopes, all kinds of blank forms, time cards, pamphlets, etc., gives the boys abundant and varied practice in all departments of printing. The number of jobs of printing done in the office during the year December 1, 1915, to December 30, 1916, for state institu - tions including our own, was 249, of a charge value of $2508.21. A new cylinder press of the best make for doing fine work was purchased and installed in December, 1915, which permits of work being done rapidly and well. Other machinery is urgently needed, particularly a linotype and an additional job-press, to make the equipment fully adequate to the demands for doing work and training our boys to enter and hold places in the modern printing office. Most of the progres - sive schools for the deaf in other states are adding linotypes to their equipment, it being demonstrated that deaf men make first class operators, earning the highest wages. The farming and gardening work and the care of the greenhouse and lawns, under the charge of Mr. W. H. Chap - man, give employment and training to a dozen boys. It is regrettable that more land adjacent to the school was not pur - chased by the State in years past when it was vacant and cheap. With only twenty-three acres of land for all purposes, including campus and sites for buildings, the area remaining </seg>
            <seg id="p012">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 458 for farming and gardening operations is small, so that the work in this department is, and it must remain, restricted to the raising of vegetables, fruit, etc. We now have a small flock of chickens but with the construction of a new barn and poultry house which we are asking for we should be able to raise chickens and produce eggs nearly if not wholly to supply our needs. The market value of the products of the farm, garden, and orchard for the past biennium was $1204.62 ; a part valued at $812.55 being consumed, the remainder valued at $392.07 being sold for cash. The domestic art classes, under the charge of Mrs. Edith Johnson, receive instruction in sewing, dressmaking, dress fitting and cutting, embroidery and fancy work. The girls do all the plain sewing of the institution, and make their own clothing and do their own mending, all under direction of their instructor. The classes in domestic science are also under the direction of Mrs. Johnson and these classes receive train - ing in plain and fancy cooking, in interpreting recipes, and in constructing menus and in table service. The domestic science kitchen, with adjoining dining room and pantry are equipped with individual tables, individual gas stoves, and all necessary utensils for training girls to do the work that they will be called upon to do as home helpers and later as home makers. The classes in wood-carving, leather-working, and basketry are under instruction by Miss Leona Myers, and the pupils have in them opportunity for the exercise and development of artistic talent of which they may be possessed. Articles made are for the most part purchased by the pupils making them, to send home as presents, they paying for the cost of the material used. A natural motive is thus enlisted for the doing of the work well, securing the best educative results. The completion of the school course of twelve grades en - titles a pupil to a diploma of graduation. Two classes have been regularly graduated during the biennium, one in June, 1915, and one in June, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 459 The 1915 class consisted of nine pupils, as follows: Johanna Fredericka Stillahn Syracuse James Joseph Tamisiea Omaha One of the above graduates, Estella E. Maxwell, of the class of 1915, is now a student taking a course at Gallaudet College, Washington, D. C. As shown in Table VI at the end of this report, out of the total attendance of 184 pupils, 59 are residents of Doug - las county, 10 of Lancaster county, 6 of Saline county, and 5 of Gage county. Outside of these counties the residence of the pupils is distributed quite generally over the State, there being representatives in the school from 56 out of 92 counties in the State. Four pupils, two boys and two girls, are residents of the State of Wyoming, being pay pupils, their tuition to the total amount of twelve hundred dollars per year being paid by their State. This money is placed to the credit of the institution cash fund in the State treasury, and is drawn upon in regular course for general expenditures of the school. It may be noted here that of the 59 pupils resi - dent of Douglas county (Omaha), 15 board at their homes, going back and forth daily as day-pupils. This is of advan - tage both to the State and the pupils, there being some saving of expense to the State and at the same time a decided gain to the pupils in the preservation to them of all the advantages of a natural home life, including an abundance of practice in speech and lip-reading, which constant communication by speech in the home circle insures. essie Amelia Bauman Martinsburg Sdith Lena Davis Omaha Jessie Esther Hanchett Omaha Jessie Eugenia Isom Allen Catherine Magdalena Kilcoyne South Auburn istella Elizabeth Maxwell Ashland Lddie Loretta Parkhurst Omaha losa Margaretta Petersen Bennington Jellie E. Rutlege Inavale The 1916 class consisted of three pupils, as follows: Hen Eldred Cooper Hooper </seg>
            <seg id="p014">460 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF During the biennium the general health in the school was good, there being: about the usual number of cases treated in the institution hospital. Immediate isolation in the hospi- tal of cases of contagious diseases limits the spread invariably of such diseases to the first few cases; and attentive care on the part of our school physician, Dr. A. Jefferson, and our school nurse, Miss Tillie Frahm, insures the best condi- tions possible for early recovery in all cases cf illness. There were 358 cases of hospital treatment for various complaints during the biennium, with but a single death, that of Leonard Murray from scarlet fever. The following is a list of hospital cases treated during the two years : Adenoids removed 1 Affection sciatic nerve 1 Amputation of finger 1 Billiousness 2 Bowel trouble 5 Bronchitis 2 Chicken pox 17 Cold 1 57 Constipation 15 Cough _ 3 Diphtheria 8 Earache 1 Ear trouble and swollen face 1 Eczema 1 Effects of antitoxin 11 Elbow dislocation _ 2 Fever 8 Fractured leg set 2 Goiter 1 Grippe _ 6 Headache 7 Indigestion 22 Injury in back _ 1 Laceration of cords and swollen shoulder I Measles 21 Nervousness 1 Pain in side 2 Pink eye 4 Pneumonia 7 Quinsy 1 Removal of ingrowing toe-nail 2 Scarlet fever lg </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 461 Slight fracture and sprain of wrist _ 1 Sore eyes — -- 2 Sore face - 1 Sore throat - 21 Sore toe _ 1 Stomach trouble 25 Tonsilitis 1 Tonsils removed 12 Tonsils and adenoids removed - 22 Ulcerated tooth _ 1 Vaccinated 32 Whooping cough 2 Wounds 6 The resignation, at the beginning of the present term in September, of Miss Julia A. Schempp as matron, to take a similar position in the House of Hope, a home for aged people, made a vacancy that was filled by the appointment to the place of Miss Jane E. Jones, for several years clerk in the superintendent's office. Miss Jones' experience and famili- arity with all the affairs of the school give her exceptional qualifications for the new work which she is carrying on with every promise of success. The new primary building, completed during the summer of 1915, and occupied since then, is a modern building in every appointment. It has comfortable capacity for eighty children. Of re-inforced concrete construction, it is as nearly fire-proof as a building can well be. The youngest children are cared for here, remaining three or four years, when they are trans- ferred to the main building, where the intermediate and advanced pupils have their residence. All the children attend school in the central schoolhouse and take their meals in the central dining room. A new heating plant, with two boilers replacing and doing the work of the three old steam boilers and one old hot water boiler, was installed during the summer of 1915. Mechanical stokers attached and the employment now of the vacuum system in all the buildings have increaed the efficiency of the plant to an extent to heat all the buildings evenly and to render them comfortable even in the coldest weather. En- tirely new electric lighting machinery, including two engines </seg>
            <seg id="p016">462 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF and two generators, was also installed, giving us an abund - ance of both light and power for all departments. 1 he lowering by the city of the grade of Bedford Avenue, running along the north side of the school property, neces - sitated the removal of a double row of trees and the terracing down of our grounds, in places some ten feet, to the new street level. Several thousand yards of earth were removed in this grading and this earth with earth taken from the street and purchased of the contractors was placed to fill up and level low ground to the east of the new primary building. The repairs effected during the biennium were mostly for the general up-keep of the institution plant. They con - sisted largely of painting, plastering, and reflooring. The pupils dining room was entirely repainted and redecorated, and play and study rooms were replastered and refloored. A commo - dious porch was built on the west side replacing a small one. Concrete walks were laid to replace old and broken walks and to give a paved court about the new porch on the west side. The most important as well as expensive item of repairs was the entire replacement of the electric wiring in the main building, which had been pronounced defective and condem - ned by the Omaha Fire Warden, by new wiring running in metal conduits. This wiring doubtless has effectively removed all danger of fire, a danger constantly present under the old conditions that existed of exposed and, in cases, closely bundled wires. The needed repairs for the coming biennium include painting the outside of the main building, painting the roof of the primary building, reshingling of the hospital, also of a part of the main building which has begun to leak in places. The schoolhouse badly needs repainting, outside and inside, including all window casings, now quite bare of paint and consequently subject to damage from the weather. I estimate that an appropriation of not less than $10,000 for the bien - nium is needed for the item of repairs. Other improvements recommended are the erection of a new barn, machinery shed, and poultry house to cost $6,000; grading grounds, building roads, and laying concrete pavement about the new building, to cost $6,000 ; enlarging and repairing the industrial depart- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 463 ment building, to cost $4,000 ; painting and completing interior decorations of the school auditorium and putting in a shower bath in the gymnasium, to cost $700; purchasing for the printing office, a linotype to cost $3,000, a job press, $350, a steel imposing stone, $85, and a wire stitcher, $175; for the manual training department, a wood-trimmer to cost $125, and a surfacer, $150 ; for the kitchen, a dishwashing machine, to cost $245 and a potato peeler, $100 ; and for the Superin- tendent's office, an adding machine, to cost $100. *. There is urgent need for paving 45th street along the west end of the school property, and this will involve an expense, for the school's share of the cost, of $4,000. It is recommended that this paving be provided for to be done in the coming biennium. I would recommend a special appropriation for the salary of a teacher for two blind-deaf children whom we have, and who are receiving only partial benefit in the classes where they now are. Such pupils from the nature of the case require individual instruction, and in a number of schools for the deaf in the country, a single pupil receives instruction from a teacher giving her entire time to the work. Our two pupils, while not totally blind, have defective vision to an extent requiring that all their work be done individually and by their teachers at odd moments illy spared from their regu - lar class teaching. The marvelous progress of Helen Keller, as also the but little less wonderful progress of other blind - deaf children under individual teachers gives hope of our doing much for our two pupils by giving them the special teacher asked for. Twelve hundred dollars is recommended as a salary for this teacher for the biennium. The following schedule gives the amounts of appropriations recommended and asked for to meet the requirements for the conduct of the school for the coming biennium : For Current Expenses: ialary of Superintendent $ 3,600.00 lalary of Matron 1.200.00 ialaries of Teachers 40,000.00 ialary of Special Teacher for blind-deaf children 1,200.00 ialaries of Employees 15,000.00 laintenance 52,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">464 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF For Repairs and Improvements: Enlarging and repairing industrial building 4,000.00 Painting and completing interior decorations of auditor - ium, and putting in a shower bath in gymnasium 700.00 General Repairs _ 10,000.00 New Barn, Machinery Shed and Chicken House 6,000.00 For Machinery for Industrial Departments, etc: Linotype for printing office 3,000.00 A job-press for printing office 350.00 Steel imposing stone for printing office 85.00 Boston stitcher for printing office 175.00 Wood-trimmer for manual training department 125.00 Surfacer for manual training department 150.00 Wales adding machine for superintendent's office 100.00 Dishwasher 245.00 Potato peeler 100.00 For Extraordinary Expenses: Grading grounds and constructing walks and drives 6,000.00 Paving 45th Street west side of grounds, between street car tracks and curb, a distance of 750 feet 4,000.00 The estimate in the above schedule for salaries of teachers and employees, is an increase of about 10 per cent, and for maintenance of about 20 per cent, over the amount expended during the current biennium, the estimate being made thus higher in view of the general increase in the cost of living, also in consideration of the fact that the number of pupils is at this time 10 per cent greater than it was two years ago, requiring a proportionate increase in the number of teachers employed as well as of quantities of provisions to be furnished. Particular attention is directed to the Tables appended to this report, as a study of them will give information that could be gained in no other way. In closing this report, I desire to express my deep appre- ciation of your encouraging support and co-operation during the biennium in the conduct of this school. Respectfully submitted, F. W. Booth. Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">8 X I -&gt; I a OS o - s = -" ■SM — -r. X a ml — — 50 O 1 1 « 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 465 TABLl I. MOVHUNT OF POl'l I.ATION For Tear For Year ending ending Tout .Nov. 30. Not. 30, for MOVEMENT fur 1915 11)16 Bienoium M. r. T. ; M. F. T. M. F. T. l'resent at beginniug of period Admitted : 82 MS 1«8 m m 170 82 M1M Kor first tiuie.. •lie admitted ... 14 ll&gt; 24 9 12 21 23 22 46 1 -1 3, 5 4 » 6 6 12 1 1 _ _ 1 1 Transferred from other institutions.. Total enrollment 97 9U DM 108 10(2 20S 111 IIS at Dlsrharged : Graduated 4 4 1 « 7 1 10 11 Transferred to other institutions | 2 2 t S Expelled _ 3 3 3 3 Left acbool for otber reasons 4 » 13 7 5 12 11 M S Tiled _ 1 l I i i Total removals 8 13 21 S 13 21 16 38 42 Present at end of period S8 86 176 , 95 89 184 95 8» M* •Includes all pupils who had attended previously tbis or a similar school TABLE II. SEX AND RACE OF PIPILS ADMITTED For Tear For Year ending ending Total R.WE Nrv.30, Not. 30, tor 1915 1916 Bieonlum M. F. T. i M. F. T. M. F. T. White _ - - 15 13 2814 152»2»2S57 Xeirrn ' ' 1 1 1 1 Totala- 1A U 2814 M 30 » » M </seg>
            <seg id="p021">466 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE III. VI. K OF FIPILS VOMM 1 H&gt; For Year For Year ending ending Total .\ : .it. Nuv. 30, for AGE f..r mm Biennium W1S M. F. T. M. F. T. 1 M. r. T. 4 15112527 0 years 7 1 .-• « 5 5 I 1 10 11 years 8 yeara. » years. 0 year* 1 years. 12 je«r» 3 ye«r» 4 years 5 years. • years - years. is years » years.. 1 yean... 1 years_. 1 3 1 2 3 3 3 • I 1 4 2 1 3 5 J 7 1 :! 3 1 111 3 4 112314 1 1 1 1 4 1 1 | 1 ...- 1 1 II 2 2 11 3 4 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 _ 112 112 Over 21 year Totals 15 13 2ft 14 16 30' 29 » 96 TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF Fl'I'll.S ADMIT! Kll For Year For Year ending ending I'otal \"i v. 30. Not. 30, NATIVITY for 1915 1916 Biennium M F. T. M. F. T. M. r. T. Kebraaka 11 8 10 10 10 20 21 IS 39 I'nited States, otber tban Nebraska 4 4 »4 6 10 8 10 18 Total native l.i.rn 16 12 27 . 14 16 30 29 28 57 Knssis - 1 1 1 - 1 1 Total foreign horn 1 1 — | 1 1 Totals I 15 13 28 14 16 30 29 29 B8 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 467 I ABLE V. NAT1V1TV OF PAKE NTS OF PIPII.S ADMIT 1 CD TABLE VI. COIXTV OF UHHMI OK II I'll &gt; ADMITTED AND Or ALL II I'll.* Kt.MAIMM. AT IM&gt; OK HIKNMl M For Year For Year All ending ending Nov. 30. Nov. n&lt;). Total Remaining COIXTV for Nov. JU. U&gt;13 1»1* Bienniuiu ISM M. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. U. r. T. Neliraskii : Adania -.._ _ - _ 1 1 Antelope _ - — 11111 .... 1 1 D«-|l _ „ _ _ - — ~ - S Buffalo - — 1 1 Butler —m -—— 1 1 1 1 ' 2 3 Caa. - 1 ~- 1 1 — 12 i CUM. - 1 1 1 - 1 1 - - 1 Cherry — » « t III »•!$•« |* n |f ax m __ _ 1 .... 1 Cunilng j - - I — - - • § • j»ii ..*-»_ _ „ „ „ — ! ..— „ m — • il 4 D»m-Kon 1 • * - - * ;, ( ,,i Be ; _...._ _ 2 i a 62 8|5 5 10 | 11 T18U2T9* DouKla* 1 i Fillmorv Fr.nk.in.:: ._ — 1 »— 1 I- « t Frontier .. I 1 — 1 1 — 1 l — ' 2 1 1 Furnan 2 .;,*,. CJr^^l**j 1 .... Ill — 1 1 1 J Hall 1 1 Hamilton Harlan 1 1 , 1 1 1 1 Hitchcock — ! — - 1 — * 3 JelTcrnon 1 1 « Kearney Keith 1 I — 1 1 * * * Knox 4 • 1O Lancaster Lincoln Madlaon _ I .... 1 Morrill 1 1 Neman a NATIVITY OK I'ARKNTS For Ve«r ending Ncv, 30, 1915 For Year ending Not. 30. 19 IB Totml for Bieouium M r. T. M F. r. M. F T l'nil«*ii States, both parent*. Foreign, both pinfllts... Mixed - I " ukimw [i „. 1» ■1 ■1 1 . 1&lt;&lt; M I S 1 1&lt;&gt; V 1 2 J 5 1 ll» I 7 1 I ■ 11» 3» 3 4 T : J i ToUlt. 15 U -A 14 1« | 30 i a» a» 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">468 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF rABLE VI. (OINTV OF BKS1DKNCE OF PIPILS AllMIT TKII AMD OF ALL II I'll - ■— ilTttiTH AT K\l&gt; OF BIENNHM — •&lt; ontlnnrur For Year For Tear i All ending ending Total Remaining COUNTY Nuv. :«l. Nov. 30, 1»15 1016 for Not. 3ft 1016 Bieuulum i r.Mi 1 . M. r. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. I. !'. T. Otoe 1 1 1 11 3 4 Pbelp. 1 1 Pierce ! 1 1 Platte ... 1 1 1 1 2 t.l 1 1 Polk 1 l _ 1 ill 1 Ked Willow. 2 &gt; * ■ Richardson 1 1 ' 1 1 1 1 Sillne ..._ 1 2 3 1 2 3 3 3 Sarpy _ I i i Saunders 1 1 1112 1 Scott* Bluff 1 1 „ 1 12 2 4 Seward i i 2 i i a! i i s Sherman 1 1 1 2 3 3 3 t Thayer 1 1 1 III 2 I Valley 1 1 Wuhlnfton 1 I 11111 Wayne . 1 1 Webster _ 1 1 2 2 1 3 1 1 4 fork _ _ 2 I Other States Wyoming 1 1 11112 2 2 4 Totals 1.1 in »&gt; 14 1« 30 29 29 88 9ft W 184 TABLE VII. A(.E AT WHICH I'l I'lI.S ADMITTED BECAME DEAF Numbtc Per Cent AGE M. F. T. i M. r. T. Congenital _ - 12 14 ft* 30.7 24.1 44.S rnrter 1 year... 4 1 «.9 1.7 8.« 1 and under 2 year« _ 6 6 11 S 6 10.3 1&amp;» 2 and under 3 yeara _ - ._ I 1 2 5 5.2 3.4 &amp;4 3 and under 4 year* „_ ' 1 2 S 1.7 3.4 B.I 4 and under S years. 6 and under 10 yeara _... _ _ 2 1 I 3.4 1.7 6.2 10 and under IS yeara.. 2 2 — .. 3.4 3.4 I'nknown Not deaf _ i 2 1 3 3.4 1.7 S.2 Totals 1 at 2&gt; 58 BOO 60.0100 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 469 TABLE IX. EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED NoobH Per Ce«t EXTENT OF DEFECT U. r. T. M. T. No hearing _ Partial hearing Not de«f — -— m . 10 17 1 IS &gt; 1 9 M ».3 32 S «2 19 17.2 1&amp;5 «L' S 35 1.T 5. 1» 17.2 16J «.' 1 3 15 l.T SJ j * 58 1 80 0 90.0 100.1 TABLE VIII. ANKH.NfcD C'Al'ME OF DEIIXT IN' I'l III- ADMITTED AJfD OF ALL PI PUS KKMAIMM. AT END OF BltNMlX Kor Be wo years endlas Not. 30. 1»1« All pupils In school Not. 30. 1»16 (At SK Number IV r Cent Number Per Ccat M. r. K M. I- 1 . T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Abscesses I 1 1 t 1.7 1.7 3.4 1 2 3 0 6 1 1 L6 Adenoids „ .. I _ 1 1 2 OS OS LI Cold _ 1 X 1.7 1.7 2 2 1.1 14 Catarrh 2 * , 3.4 3.4 2 2 4 1.1 1.1 IJ Chicken-pox _ , __.. 1 1 0.5 OS Congenital U 14 36 20.7 24.2 44.8 33 34 «7 17.» 18-6 ML* 1 1 0.5 OS Congenital 1 1 0.5 0.3 1'ongestlon of lung*. Diphtheria - _.. . 1 ...... 1 1.7 1.7 J 2 J OS 1.1 1.6 Earache 1 1 1.7 1.7 1 2 3 0.5 1.1 1.6 1 1 1.7 1.7 J 2 3 OS 1.1 1.6 Fall 1 1 I 1.7 _.... 1.7 1 1 O5 0.3 Ferer _. _. I 3 3 1.6 _ . 1.6 Gathering In ears. 1 1 0.6 — 0.5 Kicked liv colt 1 1 OS OS 1.1 1.1 Lagrippe 1 1 1.7 — L7 2 Lang fever 1 1 0.5 «f Ifeasle* 3 S 3.4 5.2 «.« 2 3 5 1.1 1.6 17 Meningitis 6.2 8.6 13.8 18 12 30 9.8 6.5 IAS Humps l i o.5 as Mumps and measles 1 1 0.5 0.5 1 i 0.5 OS Overdose of chloroform 1 1 ] 1.7 1.7 3 3 l.« ..... L« Pneumonia Scarlet fever 1 1 I 1.7 1.7 3.4 2 4 0 1.1 U *.» Sickness .. 3 3 6 1.6 1.6 S.J 1 l 0.6 01 Small pox Smothered 1 1 0.5 0J Spinal trouble. 1 1 1.7 1.7 1 i as m Strangulation 1 1 1.7 1.7 i i as as Typhoid fever _ - 1 2 3 a» 1.1 16 Unknown .._ _ _ 1 1 2 1.7 1.7 ».4 9 10 1» 4» 5.4 10J 1 2 3 a5 11 16 Whooping cough 4 3 7 2.2 1.6 3.8 1 3 3.4 1.7 6.2 2 1 3 LI 0 5 1.6 Not deaf TotalK. 20 .-.• 68 5O.0 .V».O lOttO 96 6» 184 51.6 48.4 1000 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">470 SECOND BIENXIAL REPORT OF r VIII : \. PHVSII Al. ( IIMIITKIV OS ADMIHKION OF |-| I'll .-. ADMITTED Number Per Cent PHYSICAL CONDITION M. F. T. M. F. T Normal ■ii 26 53 46.6 44.8 91.4 2 3 5 3.4 5.2 8« iN-fiH-tiw Totals at 29 06 j 50.0 500100.0 TABLE XI. Pll'lLB ADMITTED HAVING Wlltllll RELATIVES WHO ARK OR HAVE BEEN IN LIKE INSTITUTIONS Number Per Cent RELATIVE M. F. T. j M F. T. Great grandfather.. Great grandmother Grandfather 1 1 1 1.7 1.7 1 1.7 _ l.T 1 1 .... 1.7 1.7 1 1 1.7 1.7 Grandmother Father 11 \ i 17 Mother 1 1 L7 17 Brother 3 3 &lt; 5.S 5.2 10.1 Grand aunt 1 1 1.7 1.7 Uncle 1 1 1.7 1.T Aunt 1 1 2 i 1.7 1.7 S.6 Cousin 1 1 1 1.7 _.. 1.7 (Wond Conaln 1 1 J 1.7 1.7 8i TABLE XII. FTPII.S ADMITTED WHOSE PARENTH AKE COISINS Number Per Cent !&gt;EOREE M. F. T. M K T S^-ond t'imiln 1 1 ll 1.7 1 1.7 1.7 1.7 TABLE XIII. I A1&gt;K OF DEATH For Tear ending Nor. SO, 1915 For Tear ending Not. 30, UK Total for Blennlum CAU8E M. F. T. M F T \1 F. T. 1 . ~ 1 . </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 471 TABLE XIV. At.E AT DEATH TAHI.K XV. 1)1-1 KI1U rllis OF ALL PI PILS IN -&lt; IHnil AT EMI OF BIKNMl'M GRADE m. r. t. Kiiul*-! u':i rt «*i i _ l s 9 1st frrade.. tmt u-nicli ■H u'rHde 4th .".ill i.-r:nlf tkh L r r;l&lt;lc. . 7th irrjHlt- Mh i-Tllile Itth jfrarie.- KKh L r r:i*lf lit li irr:ii!c 11th irrnilc 14 M - i.- ■&gt; t; 9 10 1« 2 4 4 8 .1 11 14 1 _.. 1 Pwl u-niilnatc Totala 9S » W InriiKtrinl &lt;lepartni«-iit» Art niMiiunl.. 1 27 3B IMunestic art I Mtte hImm F:irniiiitf Mi f ■mull j lag 14 -. 14 ■ Mil ii mi I trainiiik- mill Iioiim- construction Printing 17 __ 17 Totals 56 ITS MS For Yemr ending Not, 30, 1915 For Year ending Not. 30, 191S Toul for Blennlum M. F. T. M F. T. U. r. T :-.:, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">472 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XVI. n IIWnflTIlt* BY ORDINAL YKAR IN SCHOOL OF ALL I'l I'll.s KKMAIMM. AT END OK ItlKNMI M TABI.K XVII. M 'I'KKINTKMIENTM OF THE NKBRAsKA s&lt; HOOL FOR THE IIKAK FKIMI ITS OKI. AMZATION TO THE PBE8ENT TIME SITERISTKNDENT BefflnnlBC Terui End of Torin W. M. Freiifh. ... R. II. KiniH-y. . J. A. GillcsplF.. H. E. Dawcs April 1. I.xtti P.-.-. 1. 1K71 S.'|U 1. 1S7S Aim. Hk MM lVl.niiiry i;. l!xil R. E. St&lt;Wiirt C. E. Wliite. ii. k. Mawart - r. W. Booth... S«|il. 1, MM SepteiulHT 1. 1907 VVI.r. I. 1!X17 -T.m»- 1.".. l'.«« .Ink.- in. l!MKl .Inly 1, l'.Ul July 1. I'.til Hw-emlwr 1 1*71 S*-|&gt;t»-iiilH&gt;r 1. Mi Aubusi !."&gt;, 1S»7 Number Per Cent YEA It , M. F. T. M. r. T. l«t year iud ;rar 3rd year 4th year 5th year 8th year— 7th year — 8th year__ 9th year 10th year 11th year 12th year 13th year. 14th year 15th year.. l«th year I IS 14 . 11 6 « 4 I 3 ■&gt; 1 l.t IS .-. | 6 10 | | 4 1 6 4 1 I ■ ■ SI 1!&gt; ■ IB M n • 4 9 11 3 4 3 | 4.:! 7.1 11.4 i 8.1 65 14.7 M i.-, 10.3 till 4 11 1O.!I M :(.:( 6.5 3.3 5.4 8.7 4 '.i 1.1 7.6 J.-.' 4.3 6.6 U U 4.0 1.6 0..1 1.6 3.3 4.9 :i.t&gt; J.J 6.0 1.1 O.r, 1.8 0.3 l.i; '2.2 i&gt;..-i l.i I.ii Totals I U5 Uu 8U ] 1M 184 .-.l.i; 48.4 li ICL* 4.S.4 100.0 -si </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 473 TABLE XVIII. KNKIII.I.MKNT DIKING UIKWim BEGINNING DBC'EMBKB 1. 1»14, TO DEC EMBEK 1, l»l« Pl'PILM P. 0. ADDRESS .NATIVITY Date of Admlssloo Alexander. Bern ice Taliuage — Missouri Oct. 1SO» Anderson, Edith iusley Anderson. Kay..- — Ansley Anderson. Tena — Minden Andrews. Blanche — Lincoln Nebraska _ Z A Sept., 19 °* Nebraska ___ Sept.. MHO Nebraska _____ , 1 - 1906 Sept.. 1912 Iowa Ainett. Harvey Hartington Babcock. Arcnie |.\orth Loup Nebraska ' Sept., 1908 Nebraska - I" ■*»&lt;•-. 1912 •Babender. Mary -jOmaha Rassla ~J *'«■»•• »» Bacon. Esther.-..' Omaha Nebraska Sept.. 1912 Ball. Mary Louise -JOmaha Banks. Austin ;Omaba •Karber, William ; Angora Iowa ' Sept.. 191* Illinois ___ Oct.. 1916 South Dakota- Sept.. r.'H •Batbke, Pearl iBloomflelcl Nebraska ___ »»Pt.. »« •Bauman. Jessie- _jMartiniiburg Nebraska . Oct.. 1«H Barnes. Aranda _;Byron Kansas _ __J Sept.. 1916 Barnes. Harold lOmaha Missouri Sept.. 1!»14 Sept.. 1911 Oct.. 1«» Beebe, Gladys. R«l Clouri. NMWMfca FVers. Albert- _.. Alexandria Nebraska Bell. Hope IXehraska City [Nebraska Feb.. 1913 Reran. Victor Verdlare Nebraska Oct.. 1912 B,-rney. l..li:ninl 'Colnmbus Nebraska Sfpt . _M BUger. Mlllnrd thnaha Nebraska Sept.. 1U14 BllRCr, Ninn Omaha Sept.. 1914 Nebraska Bilgcr. VioVi _ 'Omaha Nebraska Sept. 1910 Blrk. Cecelia IGrnnd Islam! Nebraska Sept.. 1906 Blaha. John 'Omaha Nebraska Sept.. 1911 Sept.. 1906 Bobrer, Nary. ._- _H'i»erton Nebraska Bowen. twtmm - [lienuan Sept.. 191S Oklahoma Boyer. Lu.ille Boyer. Wayne—. Brlttain. I&gt;ale Killer Sept.. 1916 Nebraska Nebraska Sept.. 1!»11 Nebraska Sept.. 1915 Broeckmeler. George. Wlsuer Brown. Margaret JOmaha Nebraska Sept.. 1907 Canada Sept.. 190T Bumann. Edmund- JCs'iivniJ JOsmonil Nebraska Sept.. 1910 Oct.. 1908 Uuniann. Helena Nebraska •Busch. Peter Sept.. 1910 Russia •Bysel. Lillian _JOnwlm Nebraska Sept.. Mi Campbell. Marrln JjBroadwater Chase. Archie llamncloi- Nebraska Sept.. ltm Nebraska Sept.. 1908 Sept.. 1914 Chermok. Kndolph. J^arrl.oj Nebraska Chttwood, Lucille _Jo*rln* Chrlstensen. Harry MIm.Ipii Dec.. 191S Colorado Nebraska Sept.. Mi •Chrlstensen. Mamie Me-nlov Grove Iowa Oct.. !!«» Chrlstensen. ThorwtldJMludPn Clark. Katie Jl'rlMiii Nebraska Sept.. 19W I'lbl. Oct.. 1»1S •Clawges. Alice ]Brid)teport Nebraska Nov.. 1904 Commendella. Julia Jomaha Sept. 1914 Nebraska Cooper. Delbert Jlmperlal Jan.. 1916 Nebraska Cooper. Glen - — ..JHooper Nebraska Sept.. 19TR Cooper. Harriet |Omaha Iowa Sept.. Ml Cornelius. Katie Beatrice __ Cornell. Viola Homestead Cox. Arthur Loop City. H*M_. Sept.. 191S ] Oct.. 191S Nehraska Jan.. 1907 Nebraska CiiinmlnBs. Phnma _Jl&gt;orohester Sept.. 191S Oklahoms •Cummlnirs. Marlon JOmaha Towa Sept.. 190R CiinnlnchBin. Annie — _J Ayr — Nehraska Nor.. 1912 Pay. Ruth _____ _J&lt;-re« in \ew York. Sept.. 1910 •Purls, Edith JOmaha | Jan.. 190B Nehraska i Oct..' 1910 Decker. Glllis North Bend Delehoy, Bennle— Jpine H11L... Delehoy. Wilma |nine H1IL. Nebraska Nebraska Sept . 190» Nebraxk.i Sept.. 1»1S </seg>
            <seg id="p029">474 I \Hl.r XVIII. KNKOI.I.MKNT 1)1 KIM. BltNMIM BK«.INMN&lt;- UW KMBB« 1. 1MI4. TO 1IK( KMBKK 1. 1*16 — I ( uni inuKl I PLTILJS I'. O. ADDKE8S NATIVITY Date of Adnilsl I I'. o. ADDKE8S NATIVITY Date of Adiululou puribs Dieti. Heury Lincoln Russia »*ep'-. l yl&lt;) Drake. Violet MeOook Nebraska Sept.. 1U11 Drake. Violet AUK'ook Nebraska Sept., 1U11 Dyer. Caissle. Hertrand ..._ - Nebraska Sept., 1"ji»j Dyer, Cassle. Hertrand ...- - Nebraska . Sept., l~u Eggem Atrei". ... Loup City _ Nebraska __ April. 1915 Eggem Atrel Loup City Nebraska _ April. 1915 Emshoff. Henrietta I. in. ..In Nebraska _- Sept., WOB Emsboff. Henrietta Lincoln Nebraska _ Sept., 1MB Engel, Edward HZ Kriend Nebraska __ _ Sept., 1S11 Engel Edward . Friend Nebraska _ _ Sept., 1911 Estes,' Mary ...... . Lincoln _ Nebraska _ s&lt;-pt.. WOG Estei, Mary Lincoln _ Nebraska _ Sept.. 1906 Epley. Vivian Omaha Nebraska ... sept., luuit Epley. Vivian Umaba Nebraska sept.. l'JUt Evan's. Rath Omaha — Nebraska _ (Sept.. 19OU Evans. Rntk Omaha — Nebraska _ Sept.. l!««t •Fahrenholi. Arthur Norfolk Nebraska _ Sept., lyoi Fahrenholz. Arthur Norfolk Nebraska _ Sept., l«O4 Falrfleld, Evelyn Guide Uock Nebraska _... Sept.. m« Falbauin. Frank Omaha _ Nebraska _ *&lt;-|&gt;'.. 1912 Kalk. Charles. Omaha Nebraska Oft., 1908 Falk. Charles. „ jOmaba Nebraska _ Ott.. 1908 Fisher. Bessie Itroken Bow _... Nebraska __ Sept.. mi Fisher. Bessie llroken Bow Nebraska „ Sept.. 1911 Flood John Omaha .- Nebraska _ Nov., 1910 Flood. John I Omaha ._ Nebraska _ Nov.. 1910 Kolkern. Ella Frankun „ .Nebraska - Sept • 1 9 *« Folker*'. Elli'_.'.'Z______. Fr_n_,un I .Nebraska _ Sept.. 191« Freeman. Harvey iiiimha Nebraska Sept.. 1915 Freeman. Harvey Omaha N.-I.raska .. Sept.. 1915 Gabriel. Goldle Omaha Nebraska Sept.. 1913 Gabriel. Ooldie unubi .Nebraska _ Sept.. 1913 Gammon. Rns* Lincoln Nebraska __ Sept.. 1913 Gammon. Rnsn.II Lincoln _ Nebraska „ Sept.. 1913 iSeorire Dolly Omaha Nebraska _ Sept.. 11116 iSeonre. Dolly Omaha Nebraska _ | Sept.. l'.nfl Gomme. James!! - Kddyville Nebraska __ | Sept.. I'.oc, Gomme. James. Kildyville Nebraska _ Sept.. l!«r, Graham, George ...._ I'Jomaha — Nebraska - Sept.. Ml Graham. Georfte...._ __ Omaha — Nebraska _ Sept.. Ml Grimn. Wendell Omaha Kansas — , Nov., 1013 Criflln. 'wemlell Omaha Kansas „ Nov., 1913 ftrimm. Leo _______ Monowl _ _ Nebraska _ Sept., l'.MO Grimm. Leo Monowl _ _ Nebraska _ Sept., l'.MO Grow, Harry.... _.. Omaha Nebraska _ Sept.. W14 Grow. Harry.... Omaha Nebraska _ Sept.. MM Haase. Blanche Ainnerst - Nebraska _ Sept., 11)11 Haase. Blanche Ainber«t - Nebraska _ Sept., 1911 Hall. Richard Omaha l"»a Sept., 1913 Hall. Richard Omaha Iowa Sept., 1913 Hallquist. Leonard Stromsbur* Nebraska _ Sept., 191;j Hallquist. Leonard Stromsburg Nebraska _ Sept., 1915 Hamann. Lillian Htan — _ Nebraska Sept.. 191.1 Hamann. Lillian utan — _ Nebraska Sept.. 191.1 Hatnes. Jesse I'lattsmouth Vrkansas _ Sept., 1W14 Hames, Jesse I'lattsmouth Arkansas I Sept., 1W14 •Hanohett. Bessie Mnaha Nebraska Sept.. 1901 •Hunrliett. Bessie Mnaha Nebraska Sept.. 1*» Hargis Jimmie __ ' 'maha _ _ Kansas Sept., 1915 Hargis. Jimmie Omaha _ _ Kansas j Sept., 1915 Hart*. William.™.'" Mitchell _____ Nebraska Sept.. 190B Hnrti. William...- _ Mitchell Nebraska Sept.. 190B Hawklnr. Glen 'rafton Nebraska Oct., 1908 Hawklnp. Olen "rafton Nebraska Oct., 1908 Henry. Lloyd lolllnger _ ..Nebraska Sept.. 1014 Henry. Lloyd lolllnger _ _. Nebraska Sept.. 1014 Hendrii-knoii. Emil. . "inaha Nebraska Marrh 1910 •Herman. Frank Venus — Minnesota Sept.. 19tfi •Herman. Frank Venns — Minnesota Sept.. 1905 IliareiiiR. Aubrey -.hnyler .Nebraska Ort.. »1S MiirtriiiR. Aubrey -'hnyler _ i Oc-t.. 191S Hindman. Anmista '•'■ulah, Wyo li'olorado Nor., lltlfl Hindman, Anmiita ••'•ulah. Wyo Ic.l.irado Nov.. Wlfi Hitshew. Charles &lt;"«l Spri:i_'&lt;. Wv... Wyniiiinc Sept., MM II. .Mil.. Mary. nnaha _ Xnstrla 8ept.. 1912 Hook. Jackson imaha _ JMiwouri Oct.. — Horn. Gertrude (inalia Nebraska Sept.. vm Ilrwsrien. Florence _.. Alma _ H'oli.rado _ Sept.. 1916 •Isom. Bessie.. _«'nnrord ...._____' Nebraska — Febr.. 1M0S ..l.rn.lo Sept.. 191* .Ta.-kson. Neva iinaha .._ _ llmva , Jan.. W1O Jackson, Ollie. _iin:iha Khmwis Oct.. 191B Jensen, Mine. - Inmi.ton Nebraska — — Sept.. WOT. Johnson. Albert '.nurel' Nebraska _ Sept. 1905 Johnson'. Mabel Minatare _ — Nebraska _, Sept., 101S Knlina. Joe Western Jitobnaka Sept., 19(17 Kane. Williaml Omaha ..._ .._..... '..«a _ Sept., 1914 Kennedy. Mrln... Mlnden Nebraska : Sept.. 190B •Kilcoyn*. Catherine 'Ireeley Center Nebraska Sept.. 1902 •Killham.' Delia Oiiniba _ Nebraska Sept.. 19(M Kindred. Helen Omaha ..Nebraska — Sept.. 190B •Kindred. Orletta iu.,ili;i _ \elir.isk:i _ Jan.. 1901 •Koits.'h. Oscar— '"snibridir.. &lt;MM_ Sept.. 1913 KoitM-h. William "■mnbridire Nebraska Sept.. 1910 Kollar. Joseph.. Omaha Miinsary Sept.. 1911 Kriilui.' Albert \v.n.«:i I Nebraska - J Sept.. 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 475 T.IBI.K Will. ENKOI.I.MKNT DIKIM. BIEN'MIM BE&lt;.INMN(. IlKI KMBK1 I. Illlt. TO I&gt;K&lt; K.MBKK I. 1»1&lt; — . f..n( inur.1 1 PIPILS I*. O. ADDRESS NATIVITY BMi "f AdralMiOB Kudriiii. Henry _. Bee Nebraska Jan.. l'.tlti Kuicken. Mnttif Oauba Iowa Jan.. 1»1O Kuster. Bennie Mi.kmnn Nebraska Sept.. HUM Larsen. Hilda -Wayne Nebraska Sept.. 19W La«rcc Lula Valentine _ Nebraska Sept.. I'M.' Lee. Fred ■l.in.-olii Illinois N«-pt.. l'.«f, I.isv. Miriam -joinaba Nebraska Sept.. 1M&gt; Lydick. l-eo Tekamah _.. Nebraska Sept.. Ml Lynani. Christopher -Omaha .... Nebraska Sept.. 1916 McCarthy. Eileen - Thermopolis. Wyo. Montana Not.. 1914 McElroy. F.thel Wllber Nebraska _ Sept . Ml •MrQonlgaL Annie Wisner Nebraska OH VMH •McKennan. Virgil Fairmont Nebraska April Mi McLaut'liliii. &lt;}ilfonl Moon-Held Nebraska Nov.. Ml McNeil. I.ydia - Bailey Illinois Sept.. 1910 McNeil. I.ydia - Bailey Illinois Sept.. 1»H&gt; Makonski. Tillio Arcadia Illinois Sept.. 1916 Makonski. Tillic Arcadia Illinois Sept.. 1916 Marshall. Alfreil York . NV*raska Sept., 1913 Marshall. Alfred York . Nebraska Sept.. 1913 Marshall. 1-Mward York Nebraska Sept.. 1914 Marshall. IMward York Nebraska Sept.. 1914 ktamr, taw - I laenla Colorado Jan.. !*• Man*, Kimna - 'Lincoln Colorado Jan.. MX* Mnsnu. dm! |Oinaha Iowa April l'.mrt Mnsnn. OffMi jOuiaha Iowa April l'.tflft •Mn\w.ll. Kstella Ashland Tennessee Sept.. 1'.'14 Maxwell. Kstella lAshland Tennessee _ I Sept.. 1!H4 lillano. Francesco Omaha Italj _ Sept.. 1914 MiUno. Franceaeo Omaha Italy - Sept.. 1914 Mil&lt;v. Harrejr Omaha Inwa _ Oct.. 19rt» Miles, Barrej Omaha Iowa _ Oct.. 1WW Mitchell. Ethel Omaha Nebraska Sept. 1'xfl Mitchell. Kthel (Mnalia Nebraska Sept. 1'xfl ♦Morter. Silas — Lron* _ _ Nebraska - Jan . Mi •Morter. Silas Ljonn _ Vehraiika - -Ian.. Ml Mubl. Katie Linr oln Knnsia ..._ _.. Jan.. IMS Mubl. K:itie Lincoln Itnssia _.. Jan.. 1906 •Murray. Leonard Stanton Missouri Sept. V.I14 Mydland. John .._ Sheri.lnii. Wto Wjwmtmm Sept.. MB Mydland. John Sherl.tnn. Wyo Wynmiiii.- J Sept.. 1915 Nelson. Ktli.-I Oni.-lh;, Nebraska Sept.. 191« Nelson. Ktli.-l Omnha Nebraska ' Sept.. 191« Netmatl. Anton Omaha Nebraska _...! Sept.. lfHB Netusil. Anton Omaha Nebraska _... Sept.. 10(15 Nfiijalir. Hans Seward Nebraska Jan.. 1014 Neujalir. Hans — Seward wi.raska ' Jan.. 1014 Xenjahr. Itmli Seward. Nebraska Sept.. 19W Xic-ola.v. Marparet -lAlexandria . Nebraska Jan.. Ml Nic-olay. Marpraret -lAlexandria Nebraska Jan.. Ml •Nuial. I.imny Tarnov _ Nebraska _ Febr . lftirt ffiml I.onny Tarnov _ Nebraska _J Febr . MM •iiLeary. Margaret iHaatiBfl Xel.niskii _...i Nov.. 190T. •nl.eary. Margaret Baatted Nebr.-iskn _... Nov.. 1!W&gt; Orr. Geralil _.ll..vii"h Nebraska Oct. Mi Orr. Gerald l.vn-h Nebraska Oct.. Ml Oesterlink. Kmniett Omaha Beleinni "»pt . 1!&gt;12 Oecterlink. Kmniett Omaha Beltcinm __ ! "»pt . VH2 •Paden. Hale iHowells Wvinnins.' _ Prpt . 1011 •Paden. Hale iHowella Vnadai _ I Pept . 1011 l's«e. I'ella - iBartley Nebraska _ I S,pt.. 101.-. Pace. I'ella - IBartle.v Nebraska _ fc&lt;pt.. 101." •Parkhnrst. Addle i&gt;m;iha Iowa May. MO" Pearnon. Kvelyn I'remont (Nebraska s»pt.. 1011 mum, Nick - nenniiiKton ; Nebraska __ Sept.. «&lt;in • Pvterson. Rom Pennlngton _....! Nebraska ('"! . 1!M)O Peterson. Etna Valparaiso Wbraska _ Sfpt.. 1910 Peterson. Thomas .Valparaiso Nebraska _ Stpt.. 1011 IVttit. Orace Omaha Nebraska _ Sept.. 191S Petrowski. Joseph Omaha Poland | &lt; ct . Ml PmpML Barney —Plainvlew Nebraska «» pt . 1!«W T— «jl«ll. Henry Plninview Nebraska _ Sept.. 1908 •Past, Floyd _ -Wrdiere .... (Nebraska _... O&lt;t.. IMS ouiUin. Saiiders — Orand Island -...Nebraska _ .. ()&lt;rt.. 1»B Raatz. Anna Beatrice _ -..Germany _ Ian.. 1912 ♦Kady. Pearl Omaha Alabama _ Jan.. 1914 Keed.' John...- Lincoln Nebraska J Sept.. lftll Ree.l. Nettie .Wrnwm Nebraska | Sept.. 1«12 •Reider. Katie Lincoln Russia •Relder. Katie Lincoln Rnssla Nov.. 19U Revers. Oeor(te_ _ Omaha — Nebraska Sept.. 1912 Rewnllimki. Peter — \nhton __ Nebraska 1 Sept.. 1912 Rewolinski. Thomas — taktaa Nebraska Sent.. 191« Rieckcr. Rol&gt;ert Beatrice Nebraska Sept.. 1912 Rlppe. Clara Berlin 'Nebraska - ' Sept.. 1M» </seg>
            <seg id="p031">476 TABLK Will. h\K(HIMt\l HI KIM, II1KNMI M IIM.1NMM, l&gt;t( KMBER 1, 11114, TO DK( K.MBKK 1, 1S16 — (Continued) P. O. ADDRESS .NATIVITY ; Date of Admission PCPILS Rippe. John Berlin Nebraska Sept., 1808 •Ropliti. Fred- Lincoln Ropliti. Fred Lincolu Iow« Sept., 1MB Iow« Sept., 190B Rosenblatt. Abraham.... Omahl _ Kosenlilatt. Abraham.-. Omaha .Nebraska Sept.. 1913 Nebraska Sept.. 1916 .Nebraska Sept.. 1913 Rotlie, Lydia - 1'ontanelie .... Rotlie, I.ydia - 1'ontanelie Nebraska Sept.. 1916 Iowa „ j Sept., 1916 Ituliy. David Omaha Ituti.v. David Omaha _ Iowa _ i Sept.. 191« RuuiUtrum, Hilda -_ Vel'lleet Huudbtrum, Hilda. VVIifleet gafcmaka o.t., 1M3 Kutledge, Flo.vil _ Omaha ._ Kutledge, Flo.vil _ Omaha Nebraska Jan.. 1913 Nebraska Jan., 1913 •Rutlcdee. Nellie....— lu.nvale •Rutledee. Nellie....— lu.tvale . NVImmka Sept., 1908 Nebraska Sept., 1912 N&gt;l&gt;rn»k&gt; ' Oct.. 1911 Nebraska J Sept., 1911 Nebraska Sept., 1908 Nebraska ' Sept., W13 . Nebraska Sept., 1908 |\'ebraska Sept., 1912 Msbraaha ' Oct.. 1911 •Sare, Harold l&gt;«niphaii •Sare, Harold Dnpipbau Schmidt. Charles fcpriagMaM . Schmidt. Charles i-irfngfleld Sobeuemann, John Cullwrtsoii . Scheuemann, Joho— ...k'ulbertson Nebraska J Sept., 1811 Seller. Florence Buttle Creek. Sealer. Florence Buttle Creek. Nebraska Sept, 1908 Slocum. Katherlne On.sha SIoiMiin. Katherloe Ou.sha .. Nebraska ' Sept., 1!&lt;13 Smith. Oretta ; W sonvllle Nebraska ] Se|.t., 1911 Sorensen, Irene 'Omaha Stark. Hmrry jOmaha Colorado _ _ Sept.. 1908 Iowa _ Sept . l'.lCB Nebraska ' Sept.. 1918 stendman. George Hrownlee stops n. Ross Omaha Nebraska _| Sept., 1916 Stephens. Hertha Auburn Nebraska I 8ept., 1911 •Stillalm. Johanna Syracuse Nebraska , Sept.. 191)2 Stoner. Gweudolin Beatrice Nebraska Sept.. 1901 Suhr. Annie West Point. Nebraska Sept., 1014 •Tamtsiea. James Omaha Iowa Oct., 19&lt;» TerpenniiiK. Greeljr Arnold Nebraska _ Jan.. 1908 Thompson. Margaret Omaha Nebraska _| Sept., 1911 •Thomsen. Doris ;0maha Nelirnxka i April. 1K13 Tikslsky, Viola !\"erdl)fre Nebraska s.pt.. 1!HX Vslek. Francla. Minatare Nebraska Oct., 1915 Varga. Louis Omaha _ [Nebraska Sept., 1915 Vokoun. Louis Willier Nebraska | Sept.. 1MB Vltamvaa. Albert I.inwood Nebraska Feb., 1!H5 Wall, Ethel 'Neligh Illinois ' Sept.. 1918 Wedmore. Era Omaha California I Sept.. 190«J Whaley. Edward Caaarf Nebraska Sept.. 1918 Wbitmarsh. James Kalston Kansas Sept.. 191« •Williams. Amy Beatrice Winters, Belle Hartley YouriK. Frank Alvo Zabel. Floyd Daykln Zabel, Walter Daykin Zagurskl. John Omaha Zorn. Ruth Falls City.. Zltting. Hattle Ogalalla Kansas MarWi 1»1S Nebraska Sept.. 1911 Tennessee Sept., 1800 Wtiraxka J»"-. 1M3 Nebraska Sept.. 1904 NVbnmka Sept., 1»14 Nebraska Sept.. 1916 Illinois Oct., 1908 • Present dnrlux th« hiennium, hut not in school November 30. 191ft </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>