<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA For the Period Ending November 30, 1912 TO HON. CHESTER H. ALDRICH.  Governor AND The Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">I j l 1WT IV T J^. W^ OF THE Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA For Period Ending November 30, 1912 TO Hon. Chester H. Aldrich. Governor AND </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, Nov. 30, 1912. To the Honorable Chester H. Aldrich, Governor, and to the Honor - able Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Gentlemen: In compliance with the statutes, the fourth biennial report is herewith submitted. Very respectfully, H. Winnett ORR, Superintendent. J. P. Lord, Chief Surgeon. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. Chester H. Aldrich Governor Board of Public Lands and Buildings HON. E. B. Cowles Land Commissioner Hon. Addison Wait Secretary of State Hon. Grant G. Martin Attorney General Hon. Walter A. George State Treasurer Surgical Staff H. WlNNETT Orr, M. D Superintendent John Prentiss Lord, M. D Chief Surgeon </seg>
            <seg id="p004">458 I.AND COMMISSIONER'S RKPORT Nurses Head Nurse .Head Nurse Miss Clara Anderl Miss Matilda Thuman Assistant Miss W. A. Fuhrman, graduated Dec. 21, 1910 Nurse Miss Blanche Robertson, graduated. Oct. 27, 1912 Nurse Miss Laura Fisher, left Apr. 14, 1911 Nurse Miss Estelle Lawton, graduated Nov. 13, 1912 Nurse Miss Myrtle Patterson, graduated . . Sept. 22, 1912 Nurse Miss Carrie Lawton, graduated Nov. 13, 1912 Nurse Miss Elsie Johnson, left Apr. 12, 1912 Nurse Miss Emma Maurer, graduated Oct. 14. 1912 Nurse Miss Mollie Grimsbo Nurse Miss Ida Wade, left Apr. 11, 1911 Nurse Mrs. Alice White, graduated Nov. 30, 1911 Nurse Miss Lillian Caves, left Sept. 26, 1911 Nurse Miss Vera Kruse, left Aug. 17. 1911 Nurse Miss Mabelle Myers Nurse Miss Anna Amgwert Nurse Miss Lillie Nystrom, left June 26, 1911 Nurse Miss Katie Coane Nurse Miss Mary Long, left Oct. 21, 1912 Nurse Miss Velma Hoover Nurse Miss Zelma Biss, left Sept. 26, 1911 Nurse Miss Kathryn Stevens Nurse Miss Ethel Williams, left Nov. 10, 1911 Nurse Miss Lucille Keller Nurse Miss MaudeHawthorne (Plummer) left Feb. 29, 12 Nurse E Bessie Bascom, left. . Louie Corse, graduated Mattie Smith Mar. 11, 1912 Sept. 26, 1912 Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Nurse Miss Daisy Rough, left Miss Clara Rose, left Mar. 8, 1912 Oct. 21, 1912 Nov. 30, 1912 Miss Maude Jones, graduated Miss Rose Giffin Miss Zella Smith. . . Miss Ruth Freebern. Miss Ruth Wilkinson </seg>
            <seg id="p005">459 THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT Historical The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital was opened for the reception of patients October 1, 1905. This hospital was created by an enactment of the legislature of the same year by means of which an appropriation of $10,000.00 was made for the es - tablishment of the institution and its maintenance for the first biennium. The hospital was provided for the care of the desti - tute crippled and deformed of this state. The originators and those who aided in securing the passage of the law creating the institution were influenced by the belief that dependent cripples could be brought from various parts of the state and converted into selfsustaining and independent individuals. The law creat - ing the hospital provided that it should be located in a building at the Home for the Friendless in Lincoln. Before hospital work could be begun, however, it was found necessary to expend practically one-half of the original appropriation in remodeling the building set aside so that it would serve the purpose. The basement and part of the first floor of the building, which had been placed at the disposal of the new institution, were finally remodeled in such a way that fairly satisfactory quarters were obtained. I From October 1, 1905, to November 30, 1906, the time re - ling of the first biennium, 106 patients made application for tment at the hospital. Eighty-one of these patients were litted and treated. The activity of the hospital during these teen months may be indicated by saying that the patients d for represented a total of 8,850 hospital days. This large unt of work was accomplished in spite of the fact that during h of the time it had to be done in an incomplete building. s of funds, however, prevented further improvements which to be deferred until a larger appropriation could be secured. The amount of work done during the bienniums from Octo - ber 1, 1905, to November 30, 1906, from November 30, 1906, to November 30, 1908, and from November 30, 1908, to November 30, 1910 can best be reported by reprinting the following tables from previous reports which it seems best to insert here for com - parison with a similar table for the biennium just closed </seg>
            <seg id="p006">460 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT REPORT OF THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL Statistical Form for State Institutions Prepared in Accordance with a Resolution of the National Conference of Charities and Correction, Adopted May 15, 1906- Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital October 1, 190S, to November 30, 1906 Male Female Total Number of inmates present at beginning of period Number received during the period Number discharged or died during period 53 53 106 38 36 74 Number at end of period 15 17 32 Daily average attendance during period 23 Average number of officers and employees 5 Expenditures rent Expenses: 1. Salaries and wages 2. Clothing 3. Subsistence 4. Ordinary repairs . $4,684.91 307.50 5. Office, domestic, outdoor, drugs 894.99 Total $5,887.40 rrdinary Expenses: New buildings, lands, etc 2. Permanent equipment and improvements to buildings 4,957.55 Grand total . </seg>
            <seg id="p007">461 THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL November 30, 1906 to November 30, 1908 Male Female Total Number of inmates present at beginning of period 15 17 32 Number received during the period 72 79 151 Number discharged or died during period 70 72 142 Number at end of period 20 21 41 Daily average attendance during period 32 Average number of officers and employees 6 Expenditures Current Expenses: 1. Salaries and wages, about $11,000.00 2. Clothing 3. Subsistence, about 8,000.00 4. Ordinary repairs, about 1,000.00 5. Office, domestic, outdoor, drugs, about 3,000.00 Total $23,000.00 r ordinary Expenses: . New buildings, land, etc 2. Permanent equipment and improvement to buildings, about $21,500.00 $44,500.00 Grand Total </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 462 REPORT OF THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL November 30, 1908, to November 30, 1910 Male Female Total Number of inmates present at beginning of period 20 21 41 Number received during this period 86 85 171 Number on parole 15 12 27 Number discharged or died during period 68 54 122 Number at end of period 25 38 63 Daily average attendance during period . . 52 Average number of officers and employees . . 15 Expenditures Current Expenses: 1. Salaries and wages, about $16,800.00 2. Clothing 3. Subsistence, about 16,300.00 4. Ordinary repairs, about 800.00 5. Office, domestic, outdoor, drugs, about 3,500.00 Extraordinary Expenses: 1. New buildings, land, etc 2. Permanent equipment and improvements to buildings, about 1,600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">463 THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL November 30, 1910 to November 30, 1912 Male Female Total Xumber of inmates present at beginning of period 25 38 63 Xumber received during this period 145 139 284 Xumber on parole 7 16- 22 Number discharged or died during period 108 117 225 Xumber at end of period 53 47 100 Daily average of attendance during period 86 Average number of officers and employees 34 Expenditures Current Expenses: 1. Salaries and wages $27,785.05 2. Clothing . 126.79 3. Subsistence, laundry, heat, etc 28,859.05 4. Ordinary repairs 3,196.42 5. Office, domestic, outdoor, drugs 14,516.41 Extraordinary Expenses: 1. Xew buildings, land, etc 2. Permanent equipment and improvements to buildings 5,371.79 Grand Total </seg>
            <seg id="p010">464 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Itemized Statement of Expenditures for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1912 Salaries and. wages $27,785.05 Fuel and lights 2,823.10 Repairs on buildings 3,200.42 Water rent 838.72 Bread stuffs, flour and meal 1,049.69 Fresh fruit 968.92 Dried fruit 305.33 Canned fruit 406.11 Canned vegetables 694.77 Fresh vegetables 1,428.67 Sugar 777.99 Tea and coffee 332.89 Meat 3,419.18 Other food supplies 9,169.14 Carpets, rugs, pillows, bedding .curtains, furniture 4,380.04 Dry goods 948.78 Books, papers, stationery, school and office supplies. . . 1,465.65 Clothing 126.79 Land, new buildings, permanent improvements 7,371.79 Soap, laundry supplies and machinery 2,835.38 Kitchen and dining room hardware, crockery 971.26 Drugs, surgical instruments 6,414.48 Postage, express, telephone, traveling expenses 1,451.42 Not listed elsewhere Total . ..- $79,855.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">X-ray picture of severe spinal curvature. Note heart shadow entirely to the side </seg>
            <seg id="p012">r hands of patient suffering from multiple joint disease. (Arthintis deformans) Note how many of the joints are partly or wholly destroyed. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">X-ray of neck and upper chest to show straight spine, also fracture of clavicle collar bone X-ray of lower spine and hips to show straight spine and normal pelvis and hip joints. The dark oval object is a tin whistle swallowed by this patient the day before. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">X-ray pictures showing congenital dislocation of hip above. Hip on the right dislocated upwards. Below — Same patient an hour later after "bloodless" reduction of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Kind girl with severe spinal curve 18 1 making bead work purses, also does many other forms of I work — embroidery, lace mak - etc. Our telephone operator and librar - ian i age 20 1 in the hospital for five years under treatment for paral. (poliomyelitis! one upper and both lower extremities. Boy (age 18) with hip joint di&gt; - of ten years standing. He has been a patient of the Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital for seven years. Now does 3 to 4 hoars work a day in the brace Young woman with general joint disease (see previous x-ray of hands i doing water color painting. Three of her pictures were awarded prizes at the last Nebraska State Fair. </seg>
          
            <seg id="p016">Method and preliminary results of new Abbott method for the treatment of Curvature of the Spine. Upper row — R. 0. Age 6, pictures taken in July, September and November. Lower row — W. M. Pictures taken in July, August and October, 1912. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p017">465 I During the second biennium, by action of the Board of lie Lands and Buildings, the one entire building, of which, hospital had formerly occupied only a part, was placed at disposal of the Orthopedic Hospital and the amount of money cated in the tables above was devoted, in a general way, to following purposes: The rooms in the basement were con - ed into offices, operating and X-ray rooms, childrens' dining n, diet kitchen, etc. The first floor of the building was re - leled to provide a boys' ward, school room, quarters for the i nurse and three rooms for help. The second floor was .nged to provide two large wards, one for babies and one for &gt;, and two dining rooms, one for nurses and one for officers, third floor when remodeled gave three bed rooms for 3es, two store rooms, kitchen and two bed rooms for the i. and her assistant. I Three inside bath rooms were torn out and seven outside h rooms were built providing adequate and sanitary accom - dations for all the rooms and wards in the buildings. The irium at the south end of the building was extended up two ries providing two outdoor wards, one for girls and one for rs, which are devoted particularly to the care of tuberculous ients. Finally a modern push-button electric elevator of the omatic type was installed, which provides transportation to the floors of the building and which in the present state of our •k is an indispensable feature. I The legislature of 1910 and 1911 made more liberal provision the maintenance of the institution than formerly and gave special appropriations for the development of the plant and educational purposes. Accordingly during the spring of 1 the grounds which had previously been in very bad shape ■e much improved by the hauling in of more than one thousand ds of dirt, by the removal of a number of large unsightly trees I by extensive planting of trees and shrubs according to a n provided by Professor Duppert of the Forestry Department the University of Nebraska. At the suggestion of commis - ler of lands and buildings, Hon. E. B. Cowles, three ornamental ■d lamps were installed and these have contributed very much </seg>
            <seg id="p018">466 to the appearance not only of our own grounds but of the entire neighborhood. t About June 1, 1911, all the buildings formerly occupied by home for the friendless were turned over to the hospital and present superintendent appointed and installed as a resident er. Although these new buildings made a considerable ad - jn to our space the extra space so provided was rapidly taken Is suitable patients were selected from among the applicants. ;he buildings are at present we have comfortable space for it eighty patients but for the past six months we have aver - more than 100. Our present crowded condition together the fact that our children are compelled to occupy a building :h is in great danger from fire makes it necessary for us to that the present legislature make provision for a fireproof tional building which will serve primarily as a surgical build- Our most dependent patients could then be cared for in a way as to relieve much of our present anxiety regarding • safety in case of fire. PThe large amount of laundry work necessary to be done connection with a hospital of the character of ours became so much of a burden of expense when done away from the institu - tion that we began in May 1911 the operation of our own laundry. We already had a suitable building and some of the required machinery. By adding more machinery and one or two additional helpers we have been able since March 1912 to do all of our own laundry work inside the institution. This has enabled us to do more and better work and at less expense than formerly. Until the fall of 1912 oil was used at this institution as fuel in our heating plant. The gradual increase in the price, however, compelled us to make a change from oil to coal. This neces - sitated certain changes in our buildings and in the equipment of our heating plant which more than exhausted our already scant alteration and repair fund. Our alteration and repair expense is always heavy on account of the fact that our newest building is more than twenty years old and much of the wiring, plumbing, and heating as well as other parts of these buildings must be made an object of frequent repair. It is only fair to say, however, that the money expended during tne past four years has converted very poor buildings into very good buildings for hospital pur - poses. With a few further changes in the directions mentioned </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL 467 the buildings could be made wholly modern except for the fact that they are not fireproof. To off set this fire risk in our present buildings it is recommended that our alteration and repair fund for the next biennium be made sufficiently liberal so that an au - tomatic sprinkler may be installed to protect all portions not fire proof. I Two of the most important improvements which have been le during the past biennium are the spiral fire escape built Lpril 1911, and the cement tunnel, ninety feet long, connect - the two buildings built in June 1912. Bath of these struc - s are especially designed to meet the requirements of children are dependent upon wheel chairs and crutches. By this escape practically all patients in the institution could be oved with safety in five to ten minutes and the cement tunnel lecting the two buildings provides an outlet for those who h the basement floor and also an avenue of communication ;h serves in bad weather as a comfortable passage way for ie who must go back and forth. Some of the important changes in our hospital equipment during the past two years are; a complete new outfit of steri - lizers in our operating room, a new X-ray machine, and equip - ment for our new surgical dressing room and laboratory. A high pressure steam sterilizer for our surgical dressings was secured, a large untensil sterilizer and a new instrument sterilizer. The same apparatus as for the past seven years for hot and cold water is still in use but this will soon have to be replaced by new and more modern apparatus. IOur X-ray machine secured in the fall of 1911 represents best modern equipment in that direction. With this machine have been able to do a great deal of excellent work and it been one of the most important adjuncts to the proper care ur patients. We had gradually been accumulating for some time tools and machinery for our brace shop but we did not begin active work along that line until in July 1912. Since that time one of the older boys among our patients has been employed for a definite amount of time in this work, and a very considerable amount of creditable apparatus for the use of our patients has been turn - ed out. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">468 The tables submitted, herewith, will show the rapid and gratifying increase in the number of patients who are receiving treatment at the hospital. This in itself speaks well for what we have been able to do among our patients. Adm. Surg. Op. X-ray Plaster Dis- Paris charge Dec. 1910 3 2 ... 8 6 Jan. 1911 11 1 3 15 8 Feb 5 7 3 12 8 Mar 2 ... 1 12 2 Apr 8 10 1 26 7 r- May 9 8 11 26 2 June 6 3 1 26 7 July 16 3 5 24 6 Aug 16 5 4 30 10 Sept 18 3 11 37 17 Oct 10 8 10 20 10 Nov 7 6 11 33 15 Dec 14 6 12 36 22 Jan. 1912 24 7 15 24 10 Feb 14 3 25 32 7 Mar 12 7 25 30 16 Apr 19 14 29 35 13 May 17 9 23 38 19 June 11 10 31 35 13 July 18 12 52 38 16 Aug 12 15 29 39 18 Sept 10 9 15 38 16 Oct 9 11 41 23 3 N&lt;*v 4 6 38 32 3 Total 284* 165 396 669 254f * Includes readmissions. t Includes those paroled. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL 469 No. Pat. Gain Over Average (Jain Hosp. days Admitted prev. year At the time this report goes to press, January 15, 1913, there are 112 patients in the Hospital. As the officers of the institution visit more of the eastern Orthopedic Hospitals and get more closely in touch with what is being done elsewhere, we find that we are doing more and more nearly what we should for the crippled and de - formed children of our state. Our hospital care may now be said to compare favorably with what is being done elsewhere, but we are somewhat behind in the matter of affording educational faci - lities for our patients, more particularly along industrial lines. In the last legislature, however, a total appropriation of $4,600 was made for teachers' salaries, apparatus, and school supplies. Since that time we have kept four teachers employed most of the time. Two of these teachers provide instruction in the or - dinary school branches. Lessons are assigned and recitations are heard not only in our school rooms for those children who are able to be up, but individual attention is given to each child, even among the bed patients, whose condition is such that they can carry on any school work whatever. The two teachers who have this part of the school work in their charge, Miss Charlotte Wilke and Miss Willetta Mercier, have been quite remarkably devoted and enthusiastic with their work. The result has been a great surprise to the officers of the institution and to most of those who have come in touch with this work. It is found that the majority of these children handicapped physically though they are and devoting a limited time to school work are soon able, on account of this individual attention, to keep abreast of child - ren of the same age in the public schools and in a number of in - stances our children are actually further advanced than they would probably be if they were normal children of the same age in public school. We have also employed two teachers at different times, who have instructed the children in cooking, sewing, and . . 81 81 23 23 8,850 .151 . .171 .284 45 20 113 32 52 86 9 20 34 23,360 37,960 62,780 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">470 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT bookbinding. Many of our children have become quite pro - ficient along some of these lines but much more should be done in the direction of industrial training. Hospital care alone may relieve and ameliorate them physically but if they are sent away from the institution backward along educational lines and with - out any special occupation they may become dependents after tit is especially recommended that funds and facilities be ided for the teaching of stenography, typewriting, book - ing, printing and some of the other forms of industrial educa - which can readily be imparted to our patients while confined e hospital. It is also recommended that funds be placed at the disposal of the institution which may be expended in securing education for a few of our patients who may be able to attend one or more of the many excellent educational institutions available in It is also recommended that funds be placed at the disposal of the institution which may be expended in securing education for a few of our patients who may be able to attend one or more of the many excellent educational institutions available in Lin- § Education should be made a duty of the institution no less 1 hospital care. All of those who come in contact with this k are more and more impressed with the results obtained by educational methods so far used. While our funds and facilities have been very limited so far, we have demonstrated fully that the hospital and school combined are necessary to establish the complete independence of this class of the wards of the state. In the nursing department we have had a most satisfactory experience during the past two years. Miss Bessie Bixby, who was one of our own graduates and who was in charge at the time of the last report remained with us and gave us her loyal service and support until April 1, 1911, at which time she followed the example of her predecessor, Miss Hardwick, and left the institu- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">471 THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL Miss Clara Anderl, Miss Bixby's assistant, became head nurse at that time upon the approval of the Board and by her constant effort and exertion has contributed very much to the success of our work and the development of the institution. Miss Matilda Thuman came to the hospital as Miss Anderl's assistant on September 1, 1911 and has been especially valuable because of closer contact with the patients and nurses in the wards and her constant enthusiasm for the work. fThe massage and treatment rooms have been under the ction of Mrs. Carrie M. Benbrook since September 1, 1911. een to twenty massage and other treatments are given by i. Benbrook every morning while from twenty to thirty surgi - dressings are done by the surgical nurses. During the biennium thirty-five nurses have been admitted to the training school. Of this number nine have completed the two years of training required and have been given diplomas signed by the Governor, Members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings and the Officers of the Institution. Thirteen of those who began training have discontinued for one reason or the other. Thirteen remain on duty at the time of making this I The important task of harmonizing the hospital and house - ing departments of the institution has been largely in the Is of our Matron, Mrs. Vining. It has been no small task ire for the large amount of laundry work, provide three meals y for our children, and employees, and to present a modern ital appearance in our old buildings which are more or less tantly undergoing repair, but with her constant attention the assistance of her loyal employees it has been possible, nigh out the biennium, our housekeeping and nursing de - ments have worked together with a degree of harmony which contributed very much to the efficiency of the institution the satisfaction of the officers. It is a pleasant duty to acknowledge our obligation to the Governor, the members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings and the members of the Legislature for their interest in our work and for their support. It is certain that the institution could have enjoyed no such rapid growth, as has marked its progress so far, without the approval and encouragement of those who preside over the affairs of our State and our state institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">472 The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital is, in a way, particularly a ward of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, and to the members of the Board, particularly the Chairman, Hon. E. B. Cowles, the institution owes very much. The officers of the institution would be wanting in appreciation if they failed to acknowledge the assistance received from grateful parents, who have contributed in various ways to the development of our work. tand women in Lincoln have also taken an interest in the ren at the hospital and have made contributions to their ure and comfort. I Mrs. W. A. Poynter contributed all the furnishings necessary a room as a memorial to her distinguished husband, Ex - ernor Poynter. Mrs. Mary Phillips made a similar contribution in memory of her daughter Lucie. Many other contributions — fruit, candy, books, articles, of clothing, etc., are hereby acknowledged, but space does not admit of our mentioning the donors individually. Acknowledge - ment must be made of the special activity of some of our friends who conduct the Sunday-school exercises for the children every Sunday afternoon and who, with others, interest themselves in providing special entertainment for the children on Thanks - giving, Christmas and other appropriate times. I An important contribution to the educational as well as i entertainment side of the life of our children has come in i form of our institution library. As a result of the special iropriation secured by Miss Templeton of the library commis - a and the interest of Miss Waugh, institution librarian, the t institution library, was opened at the Orthopedic Hospital September 1911. Several hundred books and about twenty the current magazines have since been supplied by the library nmission. Eva Colby and Henry Egen under Miss Waugh's ection have since maintained the library strictly according to &gt;dern library ideas and it has been a source of the greatest p and satisfaction to patients and employees of the institution. The hospital with these various phases of its work has de - veloped more rapidly than any who were interested in its inaugura - tion eight years ago could have believed possible. It has done already a tremendous amount of good but it may be considered that its possibilities have only just been demonstrated. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">473 THE ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL (There are still hundreds of children in Nebraska who re - e the kind of care which can be obtained only in this or in a lar institution. It is hoped that the members of the legisla - and others in whose hands the destinies of this institution nil not only make provision for adequate funds but will con - e to provide that sort of moral support which has been so 9rtant a factor in the development of the institution up to present time. Respectfully submitted, H. WlNNETT ORR, Superintendent. REPORT OF THE CHIEF SURGEON To the Honorable Governor, Chester H. Aldrich, and the Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Honored Sirs: We will not presume that you or the people of our state are interested in the statistics of our institu - tion. We have full assurance, however, that all are deeply interested in what we are doing for our crippled and deformed. A brief statement is therefore submitted. tThe word "orthopedic" means to grow a child straight. &gt; growth of a child is so large a factor in the production and elopment of deformity that advantage must be taken of this or in the cure, hence, "to grow them straight" requires time, ce the partial explanation of the long time necessary to cor - ; the deformities of children which they have, often times, n years in developing. Some people are distrustful of hospitals, believing they are places where useless, unnecessary and dreadful operations are done, sometimes even against the will or wish of patients, parents or guardians. We wish to assure them that all of these impres - sions are erroneous. Full free consent is always obtained and unfailingly respected. As illustrating our conservative methods, it may be of in - terest to recite that no amputations have been done for bone or joint diseases, though several patients have been brought to us with that expectation. The fresh air, sunshine, forced feeding, fixation of the parts combined with prolonged treatment in bed have enabled us to avoid sacrificing lives and limbs. Indeed, </seg>
            <seg id="p026">474 K established that the only indications for amputation are to life and to remove encumbrance. I With increasing confidence on the part of the public, cases now brought earlier, hence, deformities in their incipiency arrested. Prevention is better than cure and this especially lies in orthopedics. I To prevent the return of deformity braces are oftentimes i and they contribute to the permanency of the correction or i. With our large number of accumulated cases the demands braces are frequent, and the necessity for braces and appara - will increase. To meet this situation our shop should be her equipped and a more experienced workman secured. It robable that under such circumstances one of our own young 1 patients would develop ability to fill this place. It would also be advantageous to have at least a moderate equipment of mechano-therapeutic apparatus and facilities for hydro-therapeutic treatments. I The necessity for new appliances, instruments and apparatus lops from time to time and funds should be available for purchase. It is desirable that the medical profession give more time and study to orthopedic cases. The State Orthopedic Hospital furnishes ample illustrative cases which are valuable object lessens to doctors and medical students. They are always wel - come and are urged to avail themselves of these advantages. tit may be of public interest to know that of the 163 opera - during the last two years there have been no deaths from ition. Many of the applicants are so hopelessly crippled that no treatment could be expected to afford relief. §A considerable number have been refused treatment because r were incurable and to admit them would soon serve to fill hospital with this class, and thus exclude cruable cases. I This emphasizes the need of an institution for the helpless hopeless, many pitiable examples of which have been refused ission. t Birth paralysis is relatively common and these children are lys defective mentally. Many are not only helpless mentally physically. The institution for the feebel minded dees not pt cases under five years. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">475 It is a hardship for many parents to provide and care for these children until that age*s reached. k Better results are obtained in patients who are under the inuous and uninterrupted treatment of our institution than ose who are irregular or transient in their attendance. Re - •s are more common in those who take vacations. On account of the epidemics of infantile paralysis and the frequent occurrence in recent years there have been amny vic - tims of this affliction who have sought aid at our institution. These patients usually require treatment for a long period and as a consequence about thirty percent of our inmates are under treatment, medical or surgical for the effects of paralysis. A considerable number of these will require institutional care, education and training during the whole of their growing period. (The growth of our institution has been most gratifying and a continued generous support from legislators, our results continue to show an increase of efficiency and service to the iically handicapped. The institution will also develop into of the great state hospitals for the prevention, amelioration cure of deformity. Respectfully submitted, J. P. Lord. Chief Surgeon </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>