<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Sixth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923-02-01">1923-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1 , 1923 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA ■'ill-: i.ii\i:iimm. imviiii RECENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY I Win- 1 ik. 1'if.siihnt, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 W. Ji n--&lt;«\. Vice I'rrx.. Omaha Term expires January, 1925 Term expires January, 1927 \\ Wakxkr. Dakota City Term expires January, 1929 LL. D., Chancellor far Illi: MTATION ill i ii i.K» Direct Director Extension 8crvu B. A., \ijniiittural Kilitor M Clirk THK ttiilihIM. WTArV M. Sr. Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry \ Aniikrmin. 1!. 8C., \xsixtant in Aijronomij IBM, 1 J M. I).. Clu m i. it III Ii. sc. i.x E. E., .\ssniintr in Agricultural Emptmrerimg St.. Sii/n-riiili mil nt Esiiiiiiinntnl Substation. Valentine 1 ii run n in it i Chin rm a n j .. M. Sr.. Imirii H iisliiiinlni (Chiiiriiinn) -o\. H A., iatittmmi in Entomnluini . A. M . Rural En/iimiiii -,i (C)nnriinin) .M. Be, iMsoHute in I'liint Pnthntntiii \iuiiiiil Huxbnnilnj K'huirtiinn) n. IS Si-.. sui&gt;&lt; mill iiilint F.Tpirimintnl Substation, Mitchell Kn. a. M., Horticulture iciininiiiin/ Ph. D., \iirunuiini Issittamt in Animal Unsbnnilni \ M . LL. Ii.. Mtteomlom B. S. A . Associate in Ihiirii Husbumli i/ i\ Ai.k.. Ax-sintiint at \iirniiniii a in. V M. I). Axxuitiint in \ninml I'lithnlniiii nnil //.//;/"»' hmthkv, M. Si.. ( Irnil noli Assistant in Dun ii H uxbnniiri) Imiistant in Duirii II iisbuinlrii II. Sc. Poultry H I'ubnnilni No \. M.. Associate in I'tirul Economic* taut in Annum M II. S\\i:nk. A II., h'.nloiiioliniii /Chairman I \ \n Km, M I). \ s. \iumat I'litlmloiiu ami Iliiimnr (Chairman) V. \\\ int. .\l S. \x\istnnl in Enloiiioloaii H. O. WhitxKit. B. Br M \xxixtaiii in Horticulture ('. C. \\pi.i.\n-. Ph. l&gt;.. issoriatc in Horln ultun xik. ]',. S( .. \ai',niimixl. North Ptettc. the Stati- «&gt;r NflM-asku. approval and in effect Uiainc (a offirio custmliun of the Experiment friim 'he Office .if Kty I^ml Agriculture. United States Department of Washinuinn. l&gt;. ('. Kljiin Term expires January, 1927 •ward Term expires January, 1929 I! Be. in A. E.. ImMotJ in Agricultural Einjinri rtwj Ph. I)., Plant PitthtiUwu Rl IMII l-ll S WII-.TKHT. Ii. S&lt; ., Alllll.USl W. H. S.\w\. M. S.. Ass i .sin nl in Annual Hltslniwliji O. W. S.iih.rkn. 1!. Be. in A K . Aunt ■iillurnl F.mjinft rnnj /fhiiiriiinn) \V. P. s\i mi:. M s.. sni» ■rinh ifh nl Kxperimmlmi sitbshttton. Nortli Platte July 1. 1H!&gt;!&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Ckmrkm W. Bryan, Gore nuir of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March SI, 1887. establishing and regulating experiment stations. I have the honor herewith to submit the Thirty-sixth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska Executive Departmen Lincoln. Februarv 1 rE. A. Iliinutt, Director Nebruskm Agricultural F. merit Station: I Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirty-sixti lual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station ol &gt;raska. Charles VV. Bryan. kE. A. IUrnktt, ruarv 1, VJS.). Dirt Goi( iiki </seg>
            <seg id="p005">V A I Y y i 1 1\ • v CONTESTS Station _ 3 4 4 5 7 Work 7 * Experiments &gt; of CroDS 9 or Growing Cattle _ __ 9 Injury Investigations _ 9 History of Several Common Cutworms _ 10 Jdy of Degeneracy in Potatoes _ _ 10 tein Requirements of Growing Cattle _ — _ 11 Hemorrbacie Septiceniia 11 uirementi of Growing Chicks _ 12 Knvironmental Conditions Influencing the f Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host i Barberry &gt; - 12 Fusarium Wilt and Tuber Rot of the Irish Potato the Relation of the Environmental Condi- Inleotion and Progress of the Disease — _____ 13 Principles of Ice Cream Making _ 13 \danis Projects _ _ 14 l Certain Chemical and Physical-Chemical s of Nebraska Wheat to its Milling and Bak Mineral Nutrients with Relation to Milk i not ion 14 Fat Soluble A as Present in the Milk of Four • i ds _ _ _ _ 14 Projects _ _ _ 14 Breeding, Acclimatization and Cultural all Grains _ 14 and Fertilizer Experiments _ _ 14 Apples. Pears and Small Fruit _ _ _ 14 II II Lamb. _ 18 &gt;ns~ _ _ 17 Fattening Hogs _ _ 17 ed Pu rposes _ _ _ 1 8 Prod net ion _ _ 1 8 ng Beef Cattle on Farms _ 18 Farm Tenure _ _ 1 8 Production - _ _ 19 Producing Farm Products _ _ _ 19 Draft Investigations for Farm Machinery 19 Poultry Diseases of Nebraska _ _ 19 Aridity _ _ 1 J p&lt; ta t i \ r Fertilizer Expcri men 1 9 _ 1 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">i tXJNTKNTS — (Continued) The Study of the Etiology of Blackleg I)i Grasshopper Cont rol Economic Studies in Price, Volume of I chasing Power of Farm Products Hog Cholera Serum Official Test for Milk and Butter Product North Platte Substation Valentine Substation Scottsbluff Substation Needed Investigation and Kquipm Changes in Station Staff Publications Acknowledgments Annual Report of the Agricultural Ext Publications _ Agronomy . Animal Husbandry Clothing Community Organization Dairy Husbandry Engineering Farm MuMgenenl Foods and Nutrition Home Health and Hygiene Horticulture Market Organization Poultry Husbandry State Fairs County Fairs Boys' and Girls' Clubs General Summary Outlook Financial Statements 100 Worth While Aero the Past Two Yean College of Agriculture and It Registration in All thi Col by Counties, for Registration In thi- Collet* Counties for the School Year 1JJ1 Counties Receiving Assistance From in 1922 (map I Peetings Held in Karh Or Agriculture, 1022 (map I Total Number of People Reached at Me Boys and Girls Enrolled in Clubs. 1 !» 2 2 Women's Work in Nebraska Counties, Distribution of Blue Prints. 1022 (mar Animals Treated for Disease. 1 ft 2 2 (mat !&gt; Publications of the Station (eompleti Extension Publications (complete list </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT 1 ear covered by this Report has been quite satisfac - n the standpoint of results obtained thru the in- utional work being carried on at the Experiment Sta- While some men have been transferred from the Station &gt;thers have taken their places. Readjustments have ade in the division of time of some of the members, have proved beneficial for investigational work, and n-ojects have been added along several lines. A limited ■er of projects have been inactive and are not reported this time. Good progress has been made in all other if investigation previously started. Much of the work progressed sufficiently to permit the publication of results, a considerable number of bulletins and circulars have been 1. Many of the results obtained are capable of imme - application and are important contributions to the agri- the state. lWKSTKJATIOXAI. WOltK The investigational work of the Experiment Station is uped under different headings, dependent upon the source Funds supporting such work. Hatch and Adams appropria - u are received from the Federal Government. State funds applied from appropriations of the State Legislature. \dams fund is appropriated for research purposes only. Hatch and State funds may be used for broader or less tech - nical lines of investigation. The following is a brief sum- mary of some of the more important lines of investigational work that have been carried on and shows mainly the progress that has been made during the past fiscal year. ■ clu. to Assistant Director W. W. Rurr for the prep- th the Kxpeiiment Station work, and to tport 'l.alirm with Agricultural Extenalon </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ADAMS PROJECTS Project No. 11. Com Breeding Experiments. I Work under this project has been under way for a number years, in an effort to increase the yield and improve the tlity of corn and, if possible, to establish corn improvement thods that may be employed by the practical corn grower. I A very important result has been a clearer understanding the importance of using seed well adapted to the locality, has been found that com well adapted to one section of state may prove almost a complete failure in another aec - i and that a proper adaptation to the local conditions is ! of the big factors in determining yields. Lack of adapta - i usually results in the com being too large or too late a certain locality or in being too small and early, thus utilizing the full season. I A very careful study of various methods of com brae failed to develop a method that may be recommended eral farm adoption where a well-adapted variety is alrt lg grown. During the present year more effort has I ie to establish pure lines by hand-pollination. It is h&lt; t by reducing corn to the state of pure lines some of ;rior characters may be got rid of and that the recoml i of certain strains may result in a high-yielding corn, -year test of 8 first-year hybrids between pure lines. rage yield surpassed the original com about 17.2 per ile the most productive hybrid excelled the original b; per cent. Further investigation may afford means increasing the corn yield thru breeding. Further work carried on in the state and at the Experi - ment Station concerning the relation of ear type to yield \\&amp;&gt; borne out the previous data that the rather long slender eai&gt; of corn, with comparatively smooth flinty kernels, give highei yields than the larger ears with deep starchy kernels. Tht difference here at the Station and out in the State for thf present year in more than 40 comparisons was an averagi of approximately 5 bushels per acre in favor of the ■moothei tThe work with corn has been assembled and a compr sive summary published in Research Bulletin No. 20. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 9 \ \ v t F&lt; ,»l; v f Pntjrct S&lt;&gt;. It. Water Requirements of Crops. In this project a study has been made of the relation of se of water to (1) the kind of crop, (2) the variety, he plant characteristics, (4) acclimatization, (5) soil ind (6) climatic conditions. During the past fiscal year approximately 500 potometers t&gt; used in this experiment. Emphasis was laid on the dy of the relation of soil fertility to growth, transpiration, \ ash relationships with corn. One hundred and sixty - ht potometers were planted to corn for studying the rate wth and transpiration relationship at regular intervals. purpose being to determine what proportion of the total nwth, total water usage, and intake of soil solutes is accom - shed at various stages of development. The results of the eason are in harmony with those of a number of pub - ns already put out by the Station. Project S' &lt;K is. Food Requirements for Growing Cattle. The project was discontinued as an active project and the /&gt; a! has been published in Bulletin 181. The publication vith the influence of light and heavy feeding upon the nvth of dairy heifers as measured by height of withers i gain in weight. Growth charts were prepared showing ains by months up to 24 months of age. The growth &gt;s indicate little change in the rate of growth up to 2 / No. 16. Winter Injury Investigations. The purpose of this project is to determine the factors, d the relative importance of each, that cause winter injury the root systems of fruit trees. In these studies of the lationship of midwinter temperatures to root injury a wide nation ii found in the hardiness of different apple stocks. i attempt has been made to propagate the various apple rieties by using the cion root of the known varieties as x-ks. The cion roots of 25 varieties were used upon which graft various other varieties. These grafts were made in 'bruary, stored in the cellar in the usual manner, and anted in the nursery in the spring. During the past year ry few of these grafts lived. Different methods are being used to get twigs of the apple strike root without the use of the rootstock. If this method getting apple trees upon their own roots is found to be </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station t 1 l successful it will be convenient to study the relationship interjjrafted varieties on known root systems. Project No. 69. The Life History of Several Commoi Cutworms. tThis project was begun in 1916 and takes up the study o! distribution, life history, natural enemies, injury, anc hods of control of the several species of cutworms whi&lt; I to be found injuring Nebraska crops. In 1921 and 192". Western Army cutworm was especially studied and duiinj ril and May of 1922 a considerable number of Dingy cut •ms were secured, by means of which the life histon iies of that species were practically completed. Fielc *k with several species is being done at the proper time is contemplated that this project will be carried for ; Knber of years before the formation of the final report rogress report is planned for 192:5. Project No. 81. The Study of Degeneracy in I The objects of this study are : ( 1 ) to determin ity with which degenerate strains of potatoes m grown on dry land and under irrigation in wecfc (2) to determine the factors causing this degen determine the most practical methods of produci ing seed potatoes, and (4) to isolate high-yieldin Much of the work of the past year duplicated viously done, and the results previously obtained w« out. Unit studies duplicated on dry land and undt tion with a total of 360 original units have been gn i the purpose of determining the extent to wJ for one or more seasons affects the peculiar 1 of several different varieties; also to determir tent various peculiar characteristics are transm generation to another. I Since 1918 two different strains of the Triumph variot; ve been grown on dry land and also on irrigated land ii istern Nebraska. Upon growing all of these strains in ; itral point under irrigation in 1922 the following yield &gt;re obtained: From dry land seed 100 per cent : seed (Yon tatoes grown under irrigation 1 year B5 to '.&gt;&lt;i per cent ;d from potatoes grown under irrigation 2 years 80 to 7 r cent; seed from potatoes grown under irrigation :) year to 65 per cent; seed from potatoes grown under irrigatioi </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 11 ( us generally less than 40 per cent. It seems quite prob - ihat most of this deterioration is due to one or more of ■called "virus" potato diseases and that degeneracy &gt;iaee more rapidly in irrigated fields because of the roximity of potato fields and possibly because of more conditions for some insect which probably acts as )f disease. Further studies are being made for the f determining more definitely which diseases are •cat, and to what extent and how they are transmitted; letermine the effect upon seed potatoes of various amounts soil moisture when disease is eliminated and to establish thods of seed selection that can be adopted for practical Project S'&lt;&gt;. *.*. Protein Requirements of Growing Cattle. For this study, 2 groups of closely related heifers were ed. The heifers ranged from 9 to 16 months of age; the eds used were alfalfa hay, alfalfa meal, wheat straw, oat HI meal, linseed oil meal, peanut meal, starch, and Two rations were fed — one a so-called "narrow" ra - ■ontaining 1 part protein to 5.9 parts carbohydrates; her, 1 part protein to 7.8 carbohydrates. The daily na were 1.417 pounds for the low-protein group and 1.315 inds for the high-protein group, indicating that the low- n feeding was more economical for the growing heifers. (■suits obtained in this project have been published as in No. 184. Project No. 87. Hemorrhagic Septicemia. This project has been actively carried on. Efforts to pre - e immune sera and studies relating to the degree of im- which can be secured by their use have been made. )ne phase of the work pertaining to the study of a certain erum prepared for use against the disease in cattle and wine has led to the following conclusions : 1. Of the sera against hemorrhagic septicemia of cattle nd swine examined, some show marked protective qualities which are expressed by preventing death in a considerable number of experimental animals, when the latter are inoc - ulated with virulent cultures, and by lengthening the sur - viving periods of those which succumb to the infection. In other sera examined the potency was not sufficient to prevent death of a considerable number of the animals injected and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the protective qualities of the serum were only shown by a more or less manifest lengthening of the surviving periods. 2. However marked the protective qualities of a given serum may be, the passive immunity conferred by it is of a rapidly evanescent character and completely vanishes within the space of a week. 3. Animals treated with serum and virulent culture do not become actively immune; in other words, the virus in - jected into a passively protected animal in no way renders the immunity more lasting. Animals so treated uniformly succumb to the subsequent injection of virus. 4. The fact that certain sera are in a measure protect ivt against infection by Baeilhu bipolar** tepticus warrants th* hope that it may be possible to so improve them as to cause them to be of practical value. Further study and investiga tion with that object in view are both needed and justifiable I Our investigations indicate that hemorrhagk ■epticemia only occasional occurrence in cattle and swine in Nebrask it occurs at all as a primary disease. Future studies w largely confined to the disease u it occurs in poultry. The nutritive values of 2 different kinds of anima tnmonly used for poultry feeding have been compared. Tht eeds used were meat meal and dried buttermilk. The Mm sal ration is used in all rations, with additions of 5 per rent 15 per cent, and 25 per cent of each of above mentioned. One combination, of 7 1 meal and dried buttermilk was also made. Grom ■es are checked against a lot obtaining no animal prote n The 15 per cent meat meal and 15 per cent dried buttt lots have given the best growth up to the present tirm t Project No. 100. A Study of the Environmental Condi - is Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Ab - ac of an Alternate Host (Barberrv). tTwo season-' work on th's project indicates that stem it of wheat does not overwinte" in the urediniospore stage ier conditions prevalent in the vicinity of Lincoln. Nebr. rberries were found infected on approximately the same je as the previous year, and some spread of the rust to ir-by grasses was reported. Stem rust infection of wheat Project .Vo. 9+. Nutrient Requiremen Chicks. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-Sixth Annual tomi 13 was first observed May SI, approximately 12 days earlier than the previous year. An experiment to determine the viability of urediniospores shows that these spores are viable longer at low temperatures and medium humidities and lose their viability rapidly at high mperatures and high humidities. A report on this project has been made in Research Bul - etin No. 22, but further work is contemplated, both under &gt;ntrol and under field conditions. Project No. 101. A Study of Fusarium Wilt and Tuber Rot of the Irish Potato in Reference to the Relation of the Environmental Conditions to the Infection and Progress of the Disease. During the past year this work had been carried on largely under control conditions in the greenhouse. A special study has been made of the relation of soil and air temperatures and soil moisture to the wilt disease caused by Fusaritini oxyspor- ,&lt;m Schlect. along with temperature studies of pure cultures in the laboratory. The results of this work have been pub - lished in Research Bulletin No. 23. Studies are also being made with other species of Fusaria which affect the potato. One of these, F. eumartii Carp., isolated last yea \ has been studied both in the field and undc- control conditions and has been found to be a very virulent parasite, causing a rapid wilt of the plant and a stem-end rot of ths tuber. Further investi - gations are being made with this disease. Project 10.',. Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Mak ng. Two phases of this problem have been worked upon, — first, the influence of percentage of total fat upon the yield, body consistency and quality of the resulting ice cream ; second, the influence of homogenization and emulsification upon the viscosity of the mix. Ice cream mixtures containing 6, 8, 10, 12. 14, 16, 18, and 20 per cent of butterfat, all other con - stituents identical, were pasteurized at 140° F. ; homogeniza - tion at 2,500 pounds ; aored for 48 hours at 30° F. ; and then frozen in 40 quart brine freezers. Results indicate that the 18 and 20 per cent fat mixture! produced the best ice cream, from the standpoint of yield, consi.-.ti ruv. anil Savon The 12. 14. and 16 per cent fat nixtnrea yieMed ?ee cream of good quality, but not equal to th;&gt; former, the low percentages of </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station fat yielding ice cream of |m4 lx&gt;dy l)iit lacking ■— nwh good flavor. tNew Adams Projects. The following projects were in - •urated during the past year and work started, but no orts are yet available. I Project No. 109. The Relation of Certain Chemical and ysical-Chemical Characteristics of Nebraska Wheat to its lling and Baking Quality. Project No. 110. A Study of Mineral Nutrients with I L Project No. 113. Studies of Fat Soluble A as Presei Milk of Four Dairv Breeds. HATCH AND STATE PROJECTS Project No. 19. Variety Testing, breeding, A ri and Cultural Studies of Small drains. Considerable amounts of Nebraska No. 21 oats, N Nos. 6 and 60 winter wheat, and Kan red wheat distributed. The work with the selected strains wheat is being carried on. Several hundred and Texas Red oats are being propagated in h&lt; a higher yielding strain from these early Project No. tt. Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Kxp Another year's data have been obtained plats used in this work. Thi work reral years' data, and no report is av Project No. 2o. Rodent Invest igatioi During the past year some farther work with pocket gophers. A report on this work pared for publication. Future work is contemplated study of ground squirrels. Project No. 29. Pruning Apples. Pears, and Small Fri object of this project is to determine the influence &lt;&gt;t' erent methods and degrees of pruning upon the growth. it-bud formation, regularity of fruiting, and general health plants. Some 800 apple trees involving &amp;) varieties are </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 15 used in the experiment. These trees are now 7 years d fruit-bud formation began this year. Measurements the trunk diameter indicate that trees pruned during ant season have made somewhat larger growth than K I'll i during the summer. \\ was started during the past year with grapes, to •itive merits of cane renewal as compared ne t! pur renewal. Two hundred and fifty 4-year-old vines ing used. Previously a portion of these vines had been d to single trunk and the remainder to double trunk, mr vs. cane renewal is being tested under both methods &lt;i No. ■!■!. Fruit Breeding. ar this project, the improvement of strawberries, ap - 1 pears has been attempted, several hundred crosses been made between commercial varieties of each. hybrid apples and 6 hvbrid strawberries have been d worthy of further trial and dissemination. Approxi- 100 young trees of the 1 hybrid apples and a large of the hybrid strawberries are being grown at the a ■ and will be sent to different sections of the state for r trial. Six individual pear trees, crosses between the ih nd Garber, are now 5 years old and up to the present .e shown no indication of blight. K Project S&lt;&gt;. il. Fattening Cattle. lg the past fiscal year 2 different experiments were mdei- this head, duplicating rather closely the work ious year. Experiment No. 1. In this experiment 40 head of steers ■e used, comprising ten 3-year-olds, ten 2-year-olds, ten . and ten calves, the object being to determine the ige upon rate and economy of gain. The cattle were fed a period of 200 days. All lots were on a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay, the feeds now ( ommonly used thruout the state for fattening cattle. The shelled corn was figured at 12 cents per bushel and the alfalfa hay at $10 per ton. The rattle were sold on the Omaha mar - ket May 17. The results obtained are shown in the following table: ' </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Experiment No. 2. In addition to the above experiment, 50 head of grade steers, averaging a little over 900 pounds each, were purchased on the Omaha market, October 10, at a cost of $6 per hundredweight. These were divided into 5 lots of 10 animals each and were fed the following rations: Lot 1, corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2, corn, oil meal, and alfalfa Lot 3, corn, silage, and alfalfa. Lot 4, com, oil meal, silage, and alfalfa. Lot 5, corn, molasses meal, silage, and alfalfa These feeds were figured at the approximate market price* at that time, com 42 cents per bushel, oil meal $50 per ton, molasses meal $20 per ton. silage $4 per ton, and alfalfa $10 per ton. The cattle were placed on feed October 26 and fed for a period of 150 days, with the following results : The average gain per head was 316, 339, 329, 318, and 319 pounds for Lots 1 to 5, respectively. The cost per 100 pounds of pain was $8.08, $9.68, $7.81.' $9.46, and $9.21, for the lots in the same order. The profit per head was $5.91, ?1.S1. $4.9 $4.22, and $4.59 for the lots, respectively. In addition one lot of 10 head of rather pla was purchased. These were fed corn and alfalfa. They had an average initial weight of 925 pounds. They made an aver - age gain of 293 pounds and showed an average profit of $6.91 Project No. $5. Rations for Fattening Lambs. k Under this project 6 lots of western lambs — 30 head pel -were fed from December 20. 1921, to March 22. 1922 y received the following rations: Lot 1, corn and alfalfa hav. Lot 2, corn, silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot 3. corn, oil meal, and alfalfa hav. Lot 4, corn, molasses meal, silage, and alfalfa hav Lot 5, corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa hav Lot 6, com, linseed oil meal, silage, and alfalfa hay. 3-year-olds 2-year-olds Yearlings Average Average Average Initial initial final min cnxt wfijrht weiicht |&gt;ounds per cwt. 1215 1737 522 $6.75 854 1260 406 6.75 635 1038 403 7.00 399 833 434 7.25 Selling price |'fl CWt. $8.20 8.40 8.50 8.60 Cost per 11)0 Iba. min $9.95 l.tl 7.43 5.33 Averan&lt; profit per head $17.31 13.43 15. 9« 11.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 17 In «t 1 $4 pi t I tl i 1 1 li 1 The various lots were quite uniform, the initial weights ing around 56 pounds. The average gains per head for the -day period were 35.6, 35. 38.6, 34.7, 39.4, and 37.1 pounds r head. For lots 1 to 6 the cost of 100 pounds gain was ., $4.02, $4.03, $4,26, $4.46, and $4.49, respectively. The ofit per head was $6.02, $5.66, $6.22, $5.45, $6.10, and $5.62 r the various lots, respectively. The feeds were figured at the following prices: Corn 42 nts per bushel, oil meal $50 per ton, molasses meal $20 per n, silage $4 per ton, and alfalfa $10 per ton. These were ie approximate market prices at the beginning of the ex - &gt;riment. Project No. 72. Forage Crop Investigations. This project was continued in a comparison of the various ops ordinarily used as annual forage crops, together with o study of the seedbed preparation, and rate and time of anting. A comparative test of clovers, alfalfas, and peren - •il grasses is in progress. Project No. 75. Tractor Testing. During the past fiscal year only 5 tractors have been tested, comparison with 68 tested a year ago. The last Legisla - re authorized a fee of $250 for each tractor tested, to be paid ■ the person or firm making application. Project No. 79. Rations for Fattening Hogs Six lots of 10 head each were fad on the self-feeder as lows : Lot 1, corn alone, 105G pounds required for 100 pounds i Lot 2, 459 pounds corn, 52 pounds tankage, required for )0 pounds gain. ■ ). 196 pounds com, 51 potmd^ tankage, 52 pounds hay required for 100 pounds pa»n. Lot 4, :?7S pounds corn, 63 pounds alfalfa hay required for )0 pounds gain. Lot 5, 366 pounds corn, SS pounds tankage, 101 pounds lis required for 100 pounds gain. Let (5. 442 pounds corn, 23 pounds tankage, required for )0 pounds gain. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station i tOom and alfalfa hay produced the cheapest gain, and coir hand fed tankage the next cheapest gain in this experi Project No. 80. Potato Selection for Seed Purposes I The work under this project is carried on at a number &lt;&gt;l ferent points in the potato growing area of western Ne iska and includes several standard varieties. The objed ight is to determine the relative values of western Nebraski d potatoes in comparison with seed from other districts ative values of seed from irrigated and dry land; and tht dy of cultural conditions in the production of seed potatoes is work has made satisfactory progress and some important ults have been obtained. A summary of a portion of th&lt; rk is given in Bulletin No. 182, now ready for distribution Project No. 82. Inheritance of Egg Production. tThis work has been continued with several breech :kens. Some improvement seems evident, especially \ lins of Single-Comb White Leghorns and Single-C &gt;de Island Reds. Individual birds have been obtained f have records as high as 281 eggs and the flock cant rly 100 birds with production records of 200 egfi or bd st of these birds have been bred from hens with pro i records of 200 eggs or better, indicating the possib of direct transmission of this charact Project No. 88. Cost of Producing Beef &lt; This project is in cooperation with the V. S. De of Agriculture and was continued during the past study is being made on farms in the vicinity of Oak braska. This is the third year for this project. N M graphed reports have been made, but no built Project No. 89. Farm Tenure Additional records have been obtained during the past year and are being tabulated. A portion of the material ob - tained under this study has been prepared for publication. The first bulletin of the series, "Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes," has already been published. Other manu - scripts have been prepared and submitted. Mimeographed circulars have been published on farm leases. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 19 / No. in. Efgg Production. been in operation for :&gt; .wars. The aver- diution for all breeds in the project last year was 154 &gt;r bird. This year the average production was 161 ird. This is probably twice the average egg pro - the hens on Nebraska farms. Project No. 92. Cost of Producing Farm Products. This project is being carried on in cooperation with county A record book has been prepared and furnished the for keeping a record of the horse and man labor used producing various crops. During the summer a fieldman ists the farmers in making their records. / &lt;-t S'&lt;&gt;. ;&gt;?. Draft Investigations for Farm Machinery, project is being carried under controlled conditions view to obtaining comparable data on the draft of farm implements. It is thought that such data might information that would lead to a reduction in the eceaaary for the various operations. I'm jit-t ffo. /".'. Survey of Poultry Diseases of Nebraska. This project was continued as a survey of the poultry rases occurring in the state. — their nature and distribu- The survey work is practically completed and a manu - &gt;t letting forth the data obtained is being prepared. Work has been continued on this project. The informa - i obtained indicates that soil acidity is not a serious prob - in Nebraska at this time, altho several strongly acid cases ■en found. A brief circular outlining the work done ■ information obtained will be prepared in the near i Project \&lt;&gt;. tO4. Cooperative Fertilizer Experiments. The past season concludes 3 years' work along this line in Hall County. Applications of manure on wheat have given increases ranging from nothing to 10 bushels per acre, depend - ing upon the type of soil. The average increase of an ap - plication of 5 tons of manure per acre in 11 tests has been 3.9 bushels of wheat per acre. No increase has resulted from applying manure to com land. This was probably due to the exceptionally dry weather which has occurred in July and Project No. tOS. Soil Acidity. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station August during all of the years of the trial. In tests of appli - cations of commercial fertilizer some response was found to applications of phosphorus, the average increase in wheat being 114 bushels per acre, tho on some farms the increase was as much as 3 bushels. This was not sufficient to show a profit from the use of fertilizers. Fertilizers increased the fodder production of corn, but not the grain. On rather poor sandy soil near Grand Island, potash increased the yield of potatoes 10 bushels per acre. t Similar cooperative work has been carried on during the t yea r in Ga^e and Washington Counties. In the 1-year in Gage County, manure increased the yield of com 5 hels per acre, and in Washington County 8 bushels. On r 1 farm did commercial fertilizer increase the yield in same proportion as did manure. Project No. 107. The Study of the Etiology of Blackleg Diseases of Potatoes. Investigations on the viability of B. phytophthonts under various conditions of temperature and moisture have shown the organism to he very susceptible to desiccation. At 100 per cent humidity this organism remains viable for at least H days at all temperatures from 5° to 30° C. At 90 per cent humidity with a temperature of 25 degrees C. it remained viable for only 3 hours. At 80 per cent humidity with the same temperatures the organism lived for only 1 hour. In - oculation experiments on tubers showed that at the optimum temperatures for injection no rotting ocelli led at humidities of 40 per cent and below. Low temperatures and low humid - ity in ordinary storage collars should effectively control this Project No. 111. Grasshopper Contro i During the past season 22 different poisoned bait mixtures re been tested at the Scottsbluff Station to determine their itive efficiency in poisoning grasshoppers, especially the ues of different materials when used as attractants and killing power of several arsenical poisons commonly em - yed in grasshopper baits. Data were also obtained on the t time to scatter the bait to obtain the most satisfactory ults. A progress report giving the results of these inves - ations has been issued. Bulletin 18:?, "Experiments with soned Baits for Grasshoppers." </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 21 / Prod 1 I) I I t I t t No. 1 1 .'. Economic Studies in Price, Volume of ction, and Purchasing Power of Farm Products. project is a study of the relations of volume of pro- (i the price and purchasing power of farm products. uacript giving the data resulting from these investiga - s in process of completion. H«M. (HOI. hit A KKIU'M ning the past year the State Serum Plant has continued ilicy of buying and retesting most of its serum. The t plant is not completely modern and conditions have uch that this course was deemed advisable. alizing that hog cholera virus is the most important in the immunization of swine against hog cholera, the has put forth a special effort to produce a pure strain ighly virulent hog cholera virus. The purchase of virus atisiactory and the retesting of virus is impractical. It med necessary, therefore, for the State Serum Plant to tuc to produce its own simultaneous virus. Thru the ance of the staff and laboratory of the Department of il Pathology and Hygiene, a pure strain of virulent virus ntained by nitration and pig inoculation. demand for both serum and virus was unusually heavy the months from June to October; in fact, many of the rcial plants were out of serum at that time. This de - ni not due to an outbreak of cholera at that time as to the fact that hog raisers are adopting the policy nixing their pigs early and not waiting until cholera the herd i ring the year 1922 the price of serum was maintained i ni pe • cubic centimeter. On January 1, 1923. the price •educed to 90 cents per 100 c. c. The price of virus ns at 1*4. cents per cubic centimeter. ie following shows the activities for the fiscal year, Jan - 1. 1922, to January 1, 1923: </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ted Number of pigs used in retestint; Number of pins used in the produc Number of pigs on hand January 1 Number of orders in 1122 Number of applicants for Government t Number of doses distributed, Governin The U. S. Department of Agriculture discontinued the \ duction of free blackleg vaccine July 1, 1922, on account of funds being appropriated for that purpose, and the supply this vaccine at the State Serum Plant has been exhausi Consequently those who have been using this vaccine will h to look for some other source of supply. (•ill, C( III I II: Serum on hand, January 1. lit! 1 :. 1 1,4* Serum bought, retested and pain tar .liiriim IM2. S,15i Total ions: Serum and virus sold, lost thru toimkaw*. n^=«-&lt; 1 by plan! anil for retestinK, by months. ;is follows: Virus, Sirittii. I'libn- I'iiIhi C'liliiin li n &gt;'&lt; Htimi hrx .January 14.: 1 ..",.". 4m'. Tim February TJM 1I142S March !'.h4." tlCMS April . I1&gt;M ZMJM May tMSC S66.4M June s.V 1.C75.V76 July M.7M 1.17.".. Hi'". Aujiii.st TI'.TM l.titiT.M.". MptMBkar .".."&gt;. :i.",i i 1,197,150 October 4 .". . s _' i • 1,019,700 November :'.4.74n I17.4M IV.elllbe, M.7M Total M7.074 »,471 Serum on lianil. January 1. 1*21 1. 11' Collections Horn ali sources, ironi Jan. 1. W22, lo Jan. 1, 1923, turned into Revolving Pund OEKKKAL STATEMENT FOB H'l'l' </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 23 OKI 1 I) If k innsidt which HIM. TKST KOIt MII.K AM&gt; III TTKIJ 1'KOIH CTIOX work is to afford the dairymen of the e opportunity for accurate information concerning the uil production of the cows of their herd. The number nations for official test was less than a year ago, as paining table, but was considerably more IJ-' iccordance with an Act passed by the 28th Legislature ng the Agricultural College to test for standardization glassware and weights, the following have been tested ring the past year very satisfactory progress has been m tin 1 various lines of investigation. The herds of live - ire in better condition than in any previous years. A erable increase in the acreage of alfalfa has been made, affords an opportunity for more work in the study of he put 2 yean -I l&gt; Nkkkaska J\\. 1, 1!&lt;1'1\ TO Ill i Jan. 1 I. 1923 day list (official) 30 day ttmt (official) 172 day test ( I114 \ ll 1 ) . 1LM8 Holsteln tests Il.-.ii li-otticial tests ( IM \ V2) UM offi&lt; iitl tests. ( M \ 11') 168 iiiofficial tests (7 \ U). 84 mi-official H'sts (1 \ 12). 12 semi official tests 1512 official lesis (as al&gt;ove).. I'll!' teats, Jan. 1. lltL'2, to Jan. . 1, I. IMS. 1714 esl mil V&gt;22 ■ t pieces. .69.801 M4U Hows: .61,773 4.-,.4J!t Hies cs . 4.357 L'.681 . 1.977 377 SOUTH I nj M ii i 1,694 1,825 Ml M II 1 iO\ o »■ K S </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station i pork production. Weather conditions were such as to produce rather marked differences in yields of grain from different methods of tillage. The improvements and equipment at the Station have been kept in a fair state of repair. M.IIIIMKn Rotation and TiOmgt. — Additional land was made available and laid out in plats for increasing the studies in crop rotation and tillage. The new work is intended to furnish more ac- tate information in the solution of the problems regarding tinuous cropping to various crops, rotation of crops, the use of summer tillage, early and late fall plowing, and fall spring tillage. Much of the work alon;r this line is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. As above mentioned the past season was dry and tillage practices which best scr\ to conserve moisture gave the highest yields. This cordance with the data obtained in tho past under sin climatic conditions. Dying seasons with different clir conditions, different results we obtained. The Stat now 16 years' records available on some of these probU During the past yea'' the early preparation » summer tillage showed to an advantage. r '-&gt;--v followii ,1 gave a yield of 89.2 bush°ls per acre for fall plowing and V» f bushels for spring plowing. Oats produced 1:5.4 bush fall plowing and 9.9 bushels for spring plowing. Ac plats of winter wheat gave 11.2 bur-hols on early fall plow and 4.8 bushels or&gt; late fa" nlo-v ; nT. Summer ti duced 35 bushels of corn, 24.:&gt; bush^h of oats, and 21 of winter wheat per acre. In rotations where land was cor tinually cropped, the yields were 26.2, 11.9, and 11.7 bushc for these crops, respectively. Th' 1 --otat'on. corn after con gave 5.8 bushels no'c per acre than corn after small grair Oats gave 25.8 bushels after potatoes, 22J» after corn, and 9.! bushels per ac"e pfte* vVi*. These differences are largely accounted for by the fact that in the cultivated crop the mois - ture is not so completely exhausted from the soil as it is bv small grain. The year's work pmpha tiws aTain that the big factor it crop production in th :^ vicinity is moisture and that cultiva tion methods and systems of rotation calculated to get th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-sixth Annual Report 25 i IN. i i i l i t i II In bet th pel ■aU'st etlkiemy from the moisture that comes are advan - vnus. Soil Fertility. — Studies in soil fertility have on the average )\vn very little increase from the use of barnyard manure green manuring crops. The 16 years' data on hand seem justify the conclusion that at the present time the soils are tkiently rich so that the question of fertility is almost com- ly obscured by the effects of an abundance or deficiency &gt;il moisture. Improvement. — During the past year work was ( rted in corn improvement. Typical ears of 7 varieties re selected and self-pollinated. The progeny of these ears 1 be inbred for a numbor of years in o"der to establish pure i strains that ntay later be crossed in the hopes of pro - ing a better corn for d&gt; - y land farming. \'&lt;i rirt its of Wheat. — There was little difference during the t vear in the yields from the different varieties of winter eat. In the o-vear test just completed Turkey Red and nred stand at the top, the latter having outyielded Turkey cl S times out of 5. Among the spring wheats the durum i]&gt; Rave 1.3 bushels per acre more than the common vari - s. Prelude, an early variety, gave 16.2 bushels per acre i was the highest yielding of the common wheats. Potatoes. — Two dates of planting Early Ohio potatoes v chosen, — April 21 and June 21. Good yields were se- ed from the early planting on both irrigated and dry land, i almost total failures resulted from the later planting un- )iiditions. I.I \ KATIH'K II, &lt; f ( 'uttle. — The herd of purebred Shorthorn cattle now ;ists of 20 females and 10 males. Experimental work has been carried on with the beef herd during the past year. the only sheds available were required for other purposes. Dni, tj Cattle. — The dairy herd now numbers 47 purebred )lstein-Friesian females, 12 males, and 23 grade females. the milking herd are 23 purebred cows, 21 of which have ?n admitted to the Advanced Registry, also 17 grade cows. The herd records for the year ending June 20, 1922, show it 27 cows and heifers which finished normal lactation riods produced 10,781 pounds of milk, containing 370 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Ends of butterfat. The average production of the 10 high - producing cows in an average lactation period of ."&gt;:&gt;&lt;» days i 15,404 pounds milk, containing 514 pounds butterfat. I Experiments are being conducted to determine the value silage and grain (corn 1 parts, bran 2 parts, oil meal 1 t) for dairy cows producing milk, compared with alfalfa ■ and grain, without silage. The trials consist of pairing rs that are quite similar with respect to breed, age, pro - :tion records, and time of freshening. One cow in each r is fed the silage ration and one cow is fed the no silage ion for 30 days. After a preliminary period of 10 days cows are reversed and the experiment is repeated. This ?rnation is continued thru three 30-day periods, or longer. Ki data are not yet sufficient to permit conclusions kHoga. — A herd of about "&gt;0 brood sows is maint rty-one brood sows in the year li»22 farrowed 320 ty-eight per cent of these were raised! to maturity. Yellow Corn vs. Wkiti ('&lt;&gt;,n for Feeding Pin*. — Th* ing values of yellow corn and white corn have been con for 6 weeks by feeding 6 lots of 10 pigs each, weighing 100 pounds average at the beginning of the experiment. ration consisted of the 2 kinds of eon above mentions supplementary feeds in a self-feeder. The average dail in the 2 groups was the same, namely, \.2H pounds. relatively equal results from the '1 doubtless due to the furnishing of suj cient to furnish all vitamine and prot VAI.KNTINK SI "liSTVI'ION tThe work of this Station has progi usly laid out. The early spring season wa E plant growth, but unfavorable conditions obtained du 2 weeks preceding harvest and materially reduced d of small grain. Forage Crops, Yaritttj Test. — The average yield of 1~&gt; sorghum varieties and strains seeded in rows was 20ti0 pounds of well cured hay per acre. Dorso and Dwarf Yellow Ifik) C. I. No. 332 each yielded 3750 pounds; Red Amber S. P. I. No. 17548, 2750 pounds; Minnesota Amber F. C. I. No. 7038, 2500 pounds ; Dawn Kaffir C. I. No. 340, 2500 pounds ; Kaoliang </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 27 I'. I. No. 38463, 2225 pounds; Feterita C. I. No. 182, 1750 .inds; and Sudan 1300 pounds per acre. Pride of the North corn planted with a lister yielded 2225 nds fodder, which was about 600 pounds more than where &gt;lanted. The high yielding millet was Siberian, pro- 1 ton per acri \ well established field of Grimm's alfalfa seeded in rows cultivated produced V&gt; tons per acre. Two cultivations m are usually sufficient to keep down weeds. •ding more than 2 pecks of Sudan or 4 pecks of Amber ter acre did not show a profitable gain in tonnage. The produced a good quality of forage. in Crass. — One-half acre was seeded to brome grass )od stand obtained. It was necessary to water the plat in order to keep the grass alive. / /&gt;'&lt; i us. — Ito San and Manchu yielded 5 and 4 bushels ;re respectively. The Manchu did not fully mature, h accounts for the low yield. As a hay crop 1200 pounds ten were secured where seeded in rows, but where broad- t the crop was a complete failure. Soy beans have not de a very good showing on this high sandy soil when with corn. C( real Crops. — Listed com outyielded planted corn 4 bush - per acre. On the heavier soils north of Valentine in a ieveral winter wheats, Kan red was first, yielding 24 14 and Miniturki second, yielding 22 bushels per acre. The yield of spring wheat was about half of the winter wheat yield, spring rye about two-thirds, and fall rye the same as winter wheat. Rosen rye outyielded the common 4 bushels per acre. The Station furnished 15 farmers with a bushel each of Rosen rye in the fall of 1921. All reports speak well for this rye ; increase in yield from 3 to 10 bushels was received. The highest yielding small grain at the Station was 19 bushels of common barley. Stnifloirers. — The yield of sunflowers was no more than corn, as a silage crop. About 40 tons were put into the silo this fall. Leaf rust destroyed all but a few r of the upper leaves, so there was not much to the silage but stalk and head. The daily cows do not relish the sunflowers like they do corn, but they show no appreciable decrease in the flow of milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Annual Pasture Crops. — Sudan grass has again demon - strated its value as a summer annual pasture crop. Dairy Herd. — With a small herd of 12 cows progress has been slow. One of the 3 heifers freshening this year shows a 30 per cent increase over her dam at the same age; the others show only a slight increase. Six of the most promising yearling bulls have been sold during the year to head local Holstein and mixed herds. Improvements. — The chief improvements during the fM consist of an open shed 18 x 40 feet, a single unit poultr house, and new corral fencing. srOTTSIILlKI- SMISTATION Satisfactory progress was made along all of the expei mental work at the Station. Weather conditions were qui favorable for crop production with the exception of potato&lt; and alfalfa. Extremely hot weather in August tended to r duce both the yield and quality of potatoes. This factor, t gether with low market price, made potato production durir the year unsatisfactory. Considerable damage was done to alfalfa by gnash They were more troublesome than any year since 1919 Potatoes. — Fair yields of potatoes were secured of the plats. As has been found in the past, the large increase from manured or alfalfa land. Tho untreated plats was 100 bushels per acre. an u red 142 bushels per acre, and on alfalfa land L36 bush* An 8-year average shows an increase of 57 bushe acre from applications of barnyard manure and of 1 12 els where the potatoes followed alfalfa, as compared untreated plats. In the rotations where potatoes were grown continuously they were so scabby as to be unmarketable. Those grown in 6-year rotation were generally quite free from scab. Those grown in 4-year rotation were affected with scab to a much greater degree than those in the 6-year rotation. Corn. — Very satisfactory yields of corn were obtained, especially where com followed alfalfa. The residual effect of alfalfa on yield of corn has been approximately 26 bushels more grain per acre than where the land has not been in alfalfa. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 29 Sugar Beets. — The time of planting is an important factor n beet production. It sometimes happens that the spring is : - old and wet and it is not possible to get the plowing done is early as it should be done. Tests have been made therefore as to the possibility of substituting disking for plowing. In an average of 4 plats each, the plowed plats gave a yield of 15.18 tons and the disked plats 15.03 tons per acre. This would indicate that when plowing is necessarily delayed the importance of early planting and the fair yield from disking would permit the substitution of disking for plowing. The average yield for the past 6 years where beets have been grown on untreated plats has been 6.36 tons per acre. Whore the plats have been manured the average yield is 16.75 tons per acre, and where the beets followed alfalfa 16.01 tons acre. Grmm Pasture. — In a study of the carrying capacity of ame grass under irrigation it was found this year that the •nying capacity of the pasture which had received an annual ipplication of manure for 2 years was doubled over that re- ving no manure. The land not manured carried 8 sheep acre ; the land manured, 16 sheep per acre. Sweet Clfinr Pasture. — Both sheep and cattle were carried on sweet clover pasture. This crop carried at the rate of 28 sheep per acre for a period of 4 months. In a 3-acre sweet over pasture 12 cows were put on in the spring. A shortage of water necessitated removing them for a period of 2 weeks. Had this not occurred it is felt that the 3 acres would have carried the 12 cows for the season. The popularity of sweet clover for pasture purposes is increasing rapidly, since at the me time it lends itself as a soil builder. Latnh Feed inn Experiment. — An experiment in fattening lambs was carried on with 12 lots, each containing 25 lambs. They were fed for a period of 120 days. They averaged 44 pounds at the beginning of the experiment. All lots were fed all the alfalfa hay they would eat. The experiment was made to compare the efficiency of certain supplementary feeds. Corn in each case made more and cheaper gains than dried beet pulp. Cottonseed cake, when fed with corn and dried pulp, increased the gains made and lowered the cost per 100 oounds of gain. Beet tops produced a little more gain at less cost than corn silage. The cost per 100 pounds of gain ranged from $6.17 for alfalfa, corn, and beet tops, to $11.81 per 100 pounds for alfalfa and dried pulp. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 30 I ! t i k l I The lambs cost $12 per hundred in the feed lot. Man I 28 they sold in Omaha at $9.75 per hundredweight. All lot; showed a loss. The lowest loss was 93 cents per lamb, fo the lot receiving alfalfa, corn, and beet tops. The grmtts loss, $2.98 per lamb, was from alfalfa and dried pulp. Dry Land Crops. — The work in studies of dry land crop ping at this Station which has been carried on for the pas 10 years was discontinued at the close of 1922. It was fel that the 10 years' study would probably serve the purpose fo which this work was inaugurated and the land was badl? needed for other purposes. It was deemed advisable, there fore, to discontinue it and put it under irrigation. It is nov sown to sweet clover for pasture purposes. Grasshoppi r Control. — During the past season considerabl was done in grasshopper control in cooperation with the Ei tomology Department. This work consisted largely in trial of various poison baits. A progress report of this work hji already been made in Bulletin 1S.°&gt;. NKKOKD IXVKSTHiATION \M&gt; Kyi II'MIM While several new linos of work wei the past year and satisfactory progress made in the lit work under investigation, there arc mam not now being adequately taken care of and mai dertaken at this time. Investigations in t of all farm products, including livestock, a la to the solution of the farmers" probler should be expended along this lino. It is hardlv do so with the limited funds now available. Wh is being done at this time, it is done largeh principal efforts are along other lines,— mainly ! Probably second to the above mentioned problem w&lt; come the study of certain phases of livestock and duction, which would include a study of various pasture p lems and the harvesting of crops with livestock. This woi cannot be carried on at the present plant, because of inadequate amount of land. The necessity for more land i emphasized by the fact that the Station is now maintainini upwards of 1000 head of livestock, including horses, cattle sheep, and hogs, on little more than 100 acres of land, neces sitating the buying of vast amounts of forage and grain feed? The purchase of additional land would greatly relieve thi </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 31 ind undoubtedlv materially reduce the cost of main- is livestock. The present greenhouse space available for investigational poaei is inade(iuate to the demand. A number of problems w under investigation cannot be carried to the full capacity the present personnel because there is not greenhouse space accommodate the work. 11 The demand for information concerning soil fertility is leasing rapidly and there is urgent need for more investi- gation along this line. The work is well under way at the Main Station and some work is being done out in the counties. This, however, has been carried with funds taken from other work and its importance would undoubtedly justify expenditure. The demands that are made upon the at ion for information cannot be adequately taken care of th the funds now available for experimental work. More nds are necessary so that the personnel of the Station Staff ncreased and additional necessary equipment pur- I publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Rcpi via ollows Thirty-fifth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February 1 CHANGES IX STATION STAFF Ir J. W. Hpndrirkson. Assistant in Dairy Husbandry, resigned Sep- •r 1. 1922. Ir. F. I). Keim. Assistant in Agronomy, has been transferred to lr. S. J Marsilcn. Assistant in Poultry Husbandry, lias been trans- I I to Collage work. Ir I. V Skidmorr. Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene, has Transferred to CoUcga work. Ir. Ii. 1. Masunnsky was appointed Graduate Assistant in Dairy anilry, January. IMS, I a Ir. Rudolph Sandstedt was appointed Analyst July 1, 1922. li K. F. Morgan was appointed Assistant In Dairy Husbandry ■&lt; 1. ItM. Ir. C. W. Ackirson was appointed Assistant in Agricultural Chem- s.|iienili«&gt;r 1. l'.&gt;2'2. ,Ir. I!. I" Crawford was appointed Agricultural Editor September PlItLK ATIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 32 Bj ( I HI \u &gt; Bulletin No. 180. Reading Matter in Nebraska Kami Iliimi- J. O. Rankin. June, 1922. r,.(iiiti copies. Bulletin No. 181. Growth St miit-s of Dairy Heifers: Effect of Li and Heavy Feeding; of Wide and Narrow Rations. By Department Dairy Husbandry. August. 1922. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 182. Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska. By H Werner. November, 1922. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 183. Experiments witli Poisoned Baits for Grasshopp. By M. H. Swenk and E. E. Wehr. January, 1923. 3,000 copies. Bulletin No. 184. Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers II; Protein 1 quirements for Growing Heifers. By Department of Dairy Husband January, 1923. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 185. The Nebraska Farm Family: Land Tenure Pha By J. O. Rankin. February. 1923. 5,000 copies Bulletin No. 186. Potato Diseases in Nebraska. By R. W, Qt February, 1923. 5,000 copies. Research Bulletin No. N. Corn In\ estimations. By T. A Kies bach. Accepted for publication January. IMS. June, 1M2. 5,0M cop Research Bulletin No. 21. Studies of Iniimiiiiiy Against Hemorrha Septicemia. By L. Van Es and H. M. Martin. August. IMJ. 4.0M mpi Research Bulletin No. L'L' A Study of the Environment Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alteri Host. I. The Viability of the Irediniospores of I'urrinm untniniix In Form III. By George L Peltier Accepted for publication July I, 1 Distributed September 1, 1922. S,tM copif Research Bulletin No. 23. Relation of tors to Potato Wilt Caused by him: in inn nrytpomm. l!&gt; U W n March, 1923. 3,000 copies Experiment Station Circular No Specimens as an Aid to the Dlamnosi and L. V. Sktdmore. June. \UT2. 16. The Preparatto of Animal I Mseases. opif Experiment Station Circular N 17. The Conn worm of Swine (\Kninn \mmhricoidri). By H. M. Martin. Jmu 5,000 copies Experiment Station Circular No. ltv Iimi Worth While Ac ments of the College of Agriculture the Past Two Y 5,000 copies. Experiment Station Circular No l!i Sum Wi College of Agriculture, as Told by Maps ill' &lt;«l I Mill IM III II \ | l«i\ New Species of Serica (Scarabaeidae). IV. By R. \V Haws Journal of the New York Entomological Society. Vol. XXIX. Nns. 3 ; 4, pp. 160-168, plates ix-xiv. New Species of Serica (Scarabaeidae). V By R. W. Dawson. Jo nal of the New York Entomological Society, December, 192:'. The Cost of the Credit System in Village Stores. By H. C. Fill. Proceedings of the Nebraska Academy of Science, Vol. 10, No 3. 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 33 New Method &lt;&gt;f Balancing Rations. Bj Benjamin I MiMUwnk) Practical Standardization of lee Cream Mixes. By Benjamin I. Masur- leal Properties of the lee Cream Mis. By Benjamin I. Masui- Milks and Creams. By Benjamin I riiidiinli/aii Masur.nsky. Milk Healer, Vol. XI. No. H. pa«e Up. June. KtL':' Nebraska Tractor Tests. Oscar W. SjoKren. Journal of the Society Automotive Engineers, Vol. V 1 1 1 , No file Honey Regions and Honey Plant! of Nebraska. By M. H. Swenk. rtcan Bee Journal, Vol LXII, No. ■'). pp. 197-201. \i on as ■ Factor Influencing tlie Quality of Seed Potatoes Werner. Potato Association of America. Boston, Mass.. I&gt;^ At 'KNOW I.KIMiMK.NTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly news - r&gt;) s. especially those papers located within the state, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Sta - tion by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. Vol. V. No. 3. May, 1922 Trade Journal. Vol. XXIII, No. 4. pane 57. April. 1«)J2 Trade Journal. Vol. XXIII. No. !). page 69. Sppt.ni- </seg>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035">EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SERVICE The decline in agricultural prices during the summer of li&gt;21 and the general depression which followed had its effect on agricultural extension work. It has arrested development in new areas and curtailed the work in some of the organized counties. The burden of heavy taxes was felt when the prices &gt;f farm commodities fell. Farm Bureau boards cut their )udgets as low as possible to help relieve this tax burden. Two counties discontinued the work during the year as a result of this retrenchment in expenditures. Decreased bud - jets resulted in 4 county club agents and 5 home demonstra- on agents being dropped. The discontinuing of the assistant jrents in these counties necessitated an increased emphasis on nplete extension program in each county altho but 1 agent iployed. It has been emphasized that an extension pro - i should serve the needs of the whole family and that the )b of 1 agent or more in the county is to serve the needs of all. The county extension agent now sees that his work has •ken on a broader scope and that he is responsible for the •ntire extension program in his county. He found that he can develop a program for work with women and girls as well as with men and boys, but he needs more or less help from a woman trained in home economics to carry out his program. This broader program for county extension work has brought out the fact that more home economics specialists are needed to aid in carrying it out. With the development of community programs has come an increased demand for women's work that could not be supplied. While the demand for rigid economy has caused a reduc - tion in the employment of women agents, there seems to be a natural division of the work along sex lines. As conditions U'conu' better, counties may be able to put on a second agent, who will be a woman who will assist in carrying out the program by carrying out the work with women and girls. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lHHLHATIOXS During this year 4 printed bulletins were published. 2 of which (31 pages) were new and 2 (20) pages were reprints. Of these, 1 was on clothing, 1 on marketing, and 2 on poultry. In the mimeographed line, 111 circulars (488 pages), part of which were new and part revisions, were issued. Of these, 90 circulars (400 pages) were especially for the instruction of club leaders and members and 21 circulars (88 pages) were for general distribution. Of the latter 21. 3 (12 pages) were on agronomy, 4 (22 pages) on animal husbandry, 4 (17 pages) on community organization, 1 (8 pages) on agricultural en - gineering, 3 (16 pages) on farm management. 1 (8 pages) on home management, and 5 (5 pages) on poultry. In addition to these more permanent circulars. 12 monthly poultry bulletins (24 pages) and 12 monthly reports of the accredited farm Hock project (48 pages) were mimeographed and 52 1-page issues of Agricultural College Extension Notes were multigraphed. All material for publication which is prepared by state ex - tension agents is reviewed by members of the resident staff who are teaching the same and closely related subjects and bv extension agents in closely related lines, and is edited by the general secretary of the Extension Service, who also super - vises publication and distribution. Extension material pre- i pared by members of the Experiment Station and reside] teaching staff is reviewed by teachers of related subjects an by state extension agents in the same and closely related line In distribution, the Agricultural College Extension Notes proes to the newspapers of Nebraska and the agricultural pub - lications of the Middle West and to members of the Agricul - tural College staff 1 week ahead of release date. It is mailed on release date to all libraries in the state, to all agricultural college libraries in the United States, and to miscellaneous individuals outside Nebraska, its circulation within Nebraska being confined to newspapers and members of the college staff. The monthly noultry bulletin goes to poultry raisers and members of the Extension staff. The monthly report of Accredited Flocks goes to the flock cooperators and members of the staff. No mailing list, other than libraries and the college staff, is maintained for the general mailing of bulletins and cir- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 37 c ( I A ulars. Their issuance is announced thru the Agricultural 'ollege Extension Notes and thence thru the newspapers, Experiment Station and Extension Service jointly main - ain a mailing list to which a revised list of available publica - ions is frequently mailed. All mail requests received at the college for publications handled by the Extension Service. Those which originate nthin counties having extension agents are complied with hiu the agents. A(ill()\(»l¥ Phe principal phases of agronomy work being promoted he state are: Community crop variety demonstrations, ater erosion, improved crops and their certification, pas - iiies, fertilisers and lime, and winter wheat seed bed prep - ration. The first 2 phases of work, community crop vari- demonstration and water erosion, have been stressed the t heavily during the year. Commttmitft Crap Variety Demonstrations. — This phase of oik is applicable to practically the entire state. Some crops pply more generally to certain sections of the state, but when varieties are considered there are at least some parts of i work which will apply in every county. The chief crops liich were used in these demonstrations were: Winter wheat, its, rye, bailey, sweet clover, soy beans, and corn. The demonstrations from which definite results were ob - cd are as follows: Druionttnttiona Countirt M 14 II M l l Winter w 1 i I U H 27 A summary of the corn variety demonstration work shows hi' following results: Number N tic- ■— IllftlJ While Yellow Rmi-'h Smooth Local Foreign 411.74 43.6 51.3 54.8 55.7 Note: The average of the white includes 104 varieties. The average of the yellow includes 140 varieties. Foreign varieties were samples furnished by the State Ex periment Station </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Water Erosion. — Water erosion is one of the most out - standing soil problems of the eastern part of the state. Many acres of good tillable land have been rendered unfit for culti - vation due to the washing away of the surface soil. Soil erosion work has been furthered thru the construction of brush and soil saving dams. A total of 25 brush dams have been installed, in addition to the demonstrations already re - ported under agricultural engineering. This makes a total of 52 demonstrations established in the eastern part of the state consisting of brush and soil saving dams and soil ter - races. Improved Crops and Their Certification. — During the past few years several varieties of new crops which have proved themselves superior in yields and quality have been introduced into the state. In order that a supply of pure seed of these varieties may be available, inspection and certification of these seeds has been promoted. Durin«r the year a total of 186,455 bushels of seed has been certified in S3 counties. The vari - eties inspected are as follows: Kanred wheat, 104,300 bush - els; Nebraska No. 6 wheat, 950 bushels; Nebraska No. tin wheat, 11,150 bushels; Nebraska No. 21 oats. 15,950 bushels; Burt oats, 350 bushels; Minnesota No. IS 1 barley, !&lt;•&lt;&gt; bud and Rosen rye, 3,555 bushels. \\IM\I HISHAMHiY Principal activities promoted under the animal hi project are, home butchering of meat, livestock breedi ciations, feeding of livestock, boys' and girls' livesto and general livestock improvement. Home Butchering of Meat. — Three months, Decen uary and February, were devoted to demonstration ijrs in the butchering and curing of home meat supplies. Fifty - three demonstrations with a total attendance of 2,120 were held in 23 counties. County Livestock Breeders' Associations. — Eight county livestock breeders' associations have been organized durinjr the year. This makes approximately 40 counties now having an active breeders' association. The principal activities of these organizations are promoting livestock tours, sales, ban - quets, and other get-together meetings. Feeding of Livestock. — Due to the great number of in - quiries coming to the College, asking for information regard- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 39 i 1 nj* feeding of livestock, 12 half-day feeders' schools were teld in 11 counties, with a total attendance of 391. It was he intention at these meetings to present experimental data iealing with commercial feeding and also to give the latest ithentic data in connection with the feeding of breeding tock. Hoys' and Girls' Livestock Clubs. — This has been one of most important methods of conducting animal husbandry •voik during the year. A complete discussion of results will w found under the heading of Boys' and Girls' Club Work. General Livestock Improvement. — This activity has con- isted primarily in promoting the "Pure Bred Sires Only" roject. In furthering this work the animal husbandy special- has held 41 meetings, with an attendance of 6,370. CM)THI\&lt;; Extension work in clothing has been conducted under 4 general divisions, as follows: (a) dress forms, (b) short •uts in sewing, (c) dress construction, (d) home millinery. Dtwm Form*. — This phase of the clothing work has been •onducted a sufficient length of time so that it is reaching &gt; radically every county of the state. Reports from extension igents indicate that the work was conducted in 44 counties during the past year. A total of 4,683 forms were made. The work has been accomplished thru the training of 291 local leaders at leaders' training schools conducted by the ex - tension specialists and extension agents. Short Cuts in Sewing. — The short cuts in the sewing phase &gt;f clothing work deal primarily with the use of the sewing nachine and its attachments. This work has been conducted in 247 communities in 38 counties. A total of 250 local leaders were trained thru community demonstrations held by the clothing specialists and extension agents. Available re - ports indicate that 1,848 women have actually made use of their sewing machine attachments and that approximately 1.044 women have been reached by this work. Dress Construction. — The dress construction phase was in - itiated during the year. Only those counties in which a suf - ficient number of communities had completed dress forms and short cuts in sewing work were considered eligible for this work. The construction dealt almost entirely with the mak - ing of the simple house dresses. In this work, 38 communi- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ties in 8 counties were reached. Incomplete reports show that more than 1,097 women have been reached thru this work. Sixty-three local leaders have been trained thru lead - ers' training schools. Home Millinery. — Home millinery has been conducted as a county-wide training school for local leaders. Counties in which a sufficient number of communities have completed dress forms and short cuts in sewing work have been con - sidered eligible for the work. During the year 8;&gt; women have been trained in home millinery thru millinery schools in 17 counties. A total of 1,621 hats have been made in the schools held by the specialists, the extension agents, and the local leaders. The estimated amount saved on these hats is $7,736.90. KIMMIMTV OIMJAM/.ATIOV Extension community organization work has been ec tered about the problem of assisting rural communities solving "what to do" when they do come together. Commui ties, both small town and rural, have been furnished prograi consisting of plays, debates, etc., which are of interest the immediate communities. Assistance has also been fivi communities in organizing after it is apparent that there sufficient interest in the locality for such an organization. A second phase of the community work has the farmer closer to his rural school and the rural school closer to its community thru a program which has been called "Vitalized Agriculture." The plan is built about the "Holden plan," making an additional requirement that the classes carrying the work shall be responsible for 1 evening prognur each month. These programs are furnished by the c&lt; immun - ity specialist and are prepared along constructive agricultural lines with an attempt at making them popular as well as edu - cational. Some of the programs planned are: Health, Open Forum, Poultry, Spelling Schools, Community Singing, and Twilight picnics during June, July, and August. Onlv 1 school in the state is carrying out this program in full this year. Thirty other schools, however, have been assisted by suggestions on a method of using the Vitalized Agriculture programs, not as a regular part of their course, but just suf - ficiently to popularize the school with its rural community. Another phase of work conducted by the specialist in com - munity organization is addresses before various communities </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 41 tnd agricultural organizations of the state. It is felt that he contact with these organizations does much to build up 1 life. The following is a summary of the activities in work during the vear: Extension work in dairy husbandry has been conducted the entire state, paying particular attention, however, the sections in which dairying is best adapted and more generally practiced. The work has divided itself into 3 main ihast's. as follows : cow testing associations, cooperative bull ations, and dairy calf clubs. Cow Testing Associations. — The Platte Valley Cow Test- injr Association has completed its first year's work. As a result of records kept, 30 unprofitable cows were detected and eliminated from the herds, and 8 members of the association who had previously been using grade or scrub bulls disposed of them and purchased purebred bulls to head their herds so that at the present time all herds in the association are headed by purebred sires. The following are changes made by other members of the association : Six members built silos, 2 built new barns, 3 remodeled and whitewashed their barns, 3 built milk houses, and 1 carload of oil meal was purchased coopera - tively by members of the association. Tht Platte Valley Association will continue work during the year 1923 and the prospects are good for 2 additional associations. Xumbrr Total Kintl of Mi, iniii meeting* attendance niniunily programs of work 7 75 .nil bureau annual meetings 8 640 '•nier.s' I'nion Locals 11 1,440 derated Farni Bureaus, precinct organization 17 3,850 ate Grange annual meeting 1 260 immunity meetings 68 10.300 immunity clubs 11 1,540 iys' and sirls' club achievement programs 5 500 lambers of commerce 7 420 iral church community programs 13 650 cnic (county wide) 1 1,500 lu«;ii Minal rallies 6 1,800 •a in dealers associations (state and county).... 6 2,085 li%ll'\ tl I wl&gt; 1 V lil'l </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Cooperative Bull Associations. — The first cooperative bull association was organized in Saunders County, consisting of 5 blocks with 14 members owning 240 cows. The 5 purebred bulls used by this association have replaced 10 inferior bulls. The association is now organized as a non-profit corporation according to the laws of the state. The Hamilton County Bull Association is organized some- what similarly to the Saunders County Association with the exception that purebred bulls are being loaned the association by the Experiment Station of the College. Three bulls in this association replaced 8 inferior bulls. Dairy Calf Clubs. — Sixteen dairy calf clubs, with an en rollment of 82 boys and 17 girls, were organized during the. year. This is an increase of 100 per cent over last year. The dairy calf club work has been a means of introducing dairying into communities which otherwise could not havi been reached. One community in which dairying had previously been practiced to any extent became sufficiently E •/ " ■ - "" f-~ .— -- — — — ~~- -^..^ ■ i ■■ » i ■ ■■■■■* waswiw— • »•»■ interested to ship in 2 carloads of high grade Holstein cows This was a direct result of the dairv calf club work community. K\&lt;il\KKRI\( Extension engineering work is of such require the cooperation of farmers who are interested struction work along the lines of drainage, irrigatio buildings, farm machinery, and home equipment. Du financial depression which has existed in the centra during the year there has been less increase in the a number of demonstrations along construction lines thar previous years. Engineering work, as conducted du year, has dealt with : Drainage Water sys Irrigation Farm pow Rural architecture Mm ban Farm sanitation Communli The results accomplished thru the Engineering work may be summarized as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 43 1 I 1 r of nuttings held 36 1.366 ii took blueprints sent out to cooperators.. 1,570 lock blueprints sent to other states 219 demonstrations installed including all icultural engineering work 86 2" U 4 27 7 I I Home e&lt;uiipment Fair unwinds layouts Wilier power KAIt.M MAX.WJKMK.NT The chief activities in farm management work have cen - ered around the needs of farmers for facts concerning their wn farm business, and have dealt primarily with (a) farm •ounts, (b) enterprise cost accounts, (c) a better balance the various farm enterprises; (d) a better understanding price tendencies and production trends, and (e) better irm leases. F&lt;n in Accounts. — Farm accounts were promoted primar- thru farm account schools held in the various counties. ■ farm management specialist held a total of 19 farm .ccount schools with a total attendance of 322 men and women. •\)llow-up work on these schools in 1 county showed that 40 cent of the farmers in attendance at the school were keep - accounts. The following report of the distribution of farm account ooks shows the distribution and use of account books as re - &gt;orted by the Extension Agents: 42 counties report the placing of 438 account books. 15 counties report 246 farmers keeping accounts. M counties report assisting 83 farmers with accounts. counties report 42 farmers making changes in farming operations as a result of keeping records. counties report 33 other farmers adopting new plans as a result of neighbors' records. 1 nunilMT nf c-ooperators usinK the blueprints 813 &gt;nst rations were as follows: iireliitwtur </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Enterprise Cost Account*. — The keeping of enterprise cost records has been urged in order that farmers might better study their farm business to determine (a) cost of producing crops, (b) relative profitableness of the crops, (c) most profit - able utilization of labor, (d) that they might become inter - ested in the keeping of more complete farm accounts, (e) that further studies of labor requirements for Nebraska crops might be made. A summary of work accomplished along this line during the year shows the following results : 23 counties report 474 enterprise records placed with fanners 4 counties report 50 farmer* aaalated with summarizi prise records Farm Account Clubs. — Prior to this year there has been no project in farm management which might be carried by the boys and girls of the state. This year lessons wen pre - pared and a few clubs organized to cany on the work m order that definite proposals for the work might be developed during the second year. Three boys' and gills' farm account clubs with an enrollment of 4:&gt; members closed the year, with 29 completing the work. Farm Leases. — There is considerable demand in th&lt; for better farm leases. In order that various form mi discussed, farm lease schools were conducted in 2 co One of the counties reports that approximately 2O0 ); had been interested in better farm leasts as a result school. The College has drawn up forms of leases win meeting with general approval over the state. The two are the grain-cash lease and the stock-share lease. MM&gt;DS AM) MTKITION Extension work in foods and nutrition has been built around the principal nutrition problems in the state, which are (1) lack of vegetables and fruit in the diet, {2) lack of milk, (3) unwise child feeding, and (4) school lunches. These problems have been attacked by constructive work in child feeding, meal planning, vegetable and fruit budget, meat can - ning, and hot lunch in rural schools. Child Feeding. — A total of 107 demonstration meetings, encouraging more regular food habits and the use of vege - tables, fruits, greens, and cereals in the diet, were held by </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 45 he extension specialists and agents. Then was a total at - endance of 5,146 at these demonstrations. Vegetable and Fruit Huriyet. — In many instances improper is the result of not having the proper materials available in the home. The vegetable and fruit budget is designed to meet the vegetable and fruit needs of the family during the entire year. Three counties definitely carried on the project during the past year. As a result SI families have adopted the budget. Definite results as to the success of this work will not be available until the end of the winter months. Hot Lunches. — The serving of hot lunches in rural schools has been one of the most important phases of foods and nutri- tion work. Hot lunch work has been conducted under 2 gen - eral plans, (1) thru organized boys' and girls' clubs, and (2) in schools where no club was organized. A more complete report of the hot lunch club work will be found under the li vision of boys' and girls' clubs. This portion of the report hi tains only to the hot lunches served in schools where no tb was organized. The following is a summary of hot lunch work : Number (if counties reporting 13 &gt;er of meals served as reported by 59 schools.. 68,341 &gt;er of pounds gained as reported by 5 schools 726^ Meat Cmmmmc ami Soap Making.— This project has been griven in combination with the home butchering project re - ported under animal husbandly work. During the season in which this work was conducted 52 communities in 28 coun - ties were assisted. There was a total attendance of 2,458 people. Available reports indicate the following results from the demonstrations given : Total pounds soap made 21,425 Pounds of beef canned 8,347 Pounds other meat canned 625 I'oumis of pork canned 3,077 Number of schools 62 Total number of pupils 1.351 Number of pupils under 111 years 728 Number of pupils over 10 years ... 623 Number of pupils umlor weight at iM-ginning of project.. . 692 Number of pupils gaining . 684 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station homi it i \i in and im. n m During the year, attention has been given to 3 projects, home nursing, home health habits, and child care. Home Nursing. — Home Nursing and home emergency de - monstration meetings were held in 5 counties. There were 20 meetings with an attendance of 1,182. At these meetings the reading of fever thermometers, the making of applicators, heel-rings, putting on bandages, and making the bed with special corners was discussed and demonstrated. Home Health Habits. — Six health talks and demonstration meetings were held in 6 counties with an attendance of S96. Child Care. — The child care project was conducted by the health specialist in 12 counties. A total of 52 demonstration meetings were held at which 1,633 adults were in attendance. At these meetings 772 babies were weighed and measured. During the year Dr. Caroline B. Hedger of the McCormk-k Institute was secured to assist in this work. During the 3 weeks she was in the state, meetings were held in 15 coun - ties. This work has done much to create a keener interest in child care and health practices. HOKTK I I.Tl I5K Horticulture work will be discussed und fruit growing and potato production. Fmit Growing. — Statistics show that home fruit growing has received a great setback during the decade 1910-1920. The 1920 census report shows that there were 1,500,000 fruit trees on the farms in Nebraska, while in 1910 there were over 5,000,000. In the case of grapes the 1920 census shows a decrease of 310,000. The important problem, therefore, in connection with fruit growing is to demonstrate the profit - ableness of home grown fruit. Bearing Orchard Demonstrations. — Demonstrations were conducted in 22 counties with a view of emphasizing proper management of orchards. These demonstrations consisted of a total of 107 pruning demonstrations and 157 spraying dem - onstrations. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 47 A summary of the results obtained from 9 demonstration »chards is as follows: other Yield I l.ushel- 1 Vulue Net 899 $3S0.63 $177.21 2.9 r &gt;4 $2,998.50 $2,440.16 Groin Culture. — This phase of the work has consisted in demonstrations at which advice has been given in pruning, training, cultivation, propagation, and winter protection. Twenty-three demonstrations were started in 10 counties totaling approximately 1,150 vines. The average production per vine wars about 12 pounds. Potato Production. — The western portion of the state is veil adapted to producing high grade potatoes of both seed and table stock. These potatoes are finding a good market in central and eastern Nebraska as well as in the southern states. The work, therefore, in connection with the potato industry has been demonstrations showing the value of good seed potatoes and methods of potato culture. Potato Improvement in Commercial Sections. — Two hun - dred growers in western Nebraska dry land sections applied for certification of seed for a combined acreage of 4,500 acres. One hundred fields comprising 1,800 acres passed the inspec- on, which represents about 85,000 bushels of certified seed. Distribution of Seed Potatoes. — A number of demonstra- were conducted thru central and eastern parts of the demonstrating the superiority of good seed potatoes. The results of a demonstration conducted in Dawson County ire given below. Those are typical results of such demon- rations. Yield W.-st Nebraska 322 bushels Porter- Northern certified 296 bushels Newman West Nebraska. 287 bushels Jones Northern certified 280 bushels si raw mulched 263 bushels Northern uncertified 230 bushels Home Grown cultivated 200 bushels ('.rowers in Louisiana, Texas, Oklahoma, and Arkansas were supplied with bushel lots of seed of various growers of ccitificd seed in western Nebraska. Those were tested out in comparison with other seed used locally. It was found that in Texas, Nebraska seed outyielded the other seed by </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 It 100 bushels per acre, largely because of the small amount mosaic present. In Louisiana the results show that west - i Nebraska seed equals or surpasses other lots of seed that I handled locally. Prior to 1921 very few potatoes went Louisiana. In 1921, 12 cars were used for seeding the 52 crop. At this writing more than 25 cars have already »n bought for use in 1923. MAIikKT OIHiAMZATION The activities in market organization have been confined principally to assistance in the organization of (a) coopera - tive grain elevators, (b) livestock shipping associations, (c) cooperative creameries, (d) egg grading associations, and (e) analysis of local market conditions. Organization work has consisted primarily in familiarizing the producers of farm commodities, so far as a judicious and efficient use of our El and facilities will permit, (1) with the agencies of mai - ng, (2) with the elements that enter into cost of market - and (3) with the relationship existing between the pro - es of different agencies that enter into marketing. Prior to the passing of the cooperative law in 1911. thei were less than 200 elevators in the state which could b claimed as farmer owned. At the present time there ai more than 465 farmer owned elevators in the state. Prac tically all organized since 1911 are organized under the c( operative law of the state. There are 122 cooperative orgai izations within the state shipping livestock. Much assistant has been rendered these organizations during the year. POU/TKY HUSBANDRY Poultry Extension work will be discussed unde i divisions, accredited farm flocks and boys' and girls' poutti clubs. Accredited Farm Flocks. —The accredited farm flock work had its beginning November 1, 1921, closing the first year's work October 31, 1922. This phase of poultry work has created such state-wide inteivsi tliat it seems best to report it somewhat in detail. The object of the accredited farm flock work is to increase economic poultry production thru the formation of flocks of </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 49 known performance. All accredited flocks conform to the following requirements: 1. All hens that (a) show a markedly inferior egg pro - duction, (b) lack of breed characteristics, (c) disease, (d) inferior size must be culled before November 1, each year. A flock of 50 or more producing birds, standard bred within the breed and variety. An average production of 85 eggs the first year, 100 eggs average the second year, 115 eggs the third year, MS eggs the fourth year, and 150 eggs the fifth year. I. Males used in breeding shall conform to the breed characteristics and have egg production blood lines representing not less than 125 eggs the first year, 150 ejrps the second year, 200 eggs the third, fourth, and fifth years. •&gt;. Hens shall be fed for egg production. ti. .Management of the flock shall be such as to promote the most favorable environment. These flocks are used for demonstration purposes, the principal work covered being standardization, proper housing and arrangement of equipment, culling, mating, the selection of better breeding sires, and sanitation and disease control. The following is a summary of the 131 flocks finishing the first year's work in this project: Total number of farms at beginning of project. No - v ember 1. 1921 270 Total number of farms finishing the project, Oc tober 31, 1922 201 Percentage of farms finishing the project 74 Total number of hens at beginning of project 42,265 Total number of hens at end of project 26,876 Average number of hens per farm at close of 133 Total number of eggs for the year 3,050,570 Average number of eggs per hen 113.5 Number of dozens of eggs produced 254,214 Number of cases of eggs produced 8,473 Number of carloads (4&lt;&gt;o casts each) 21.1 dross income in revenue on 131 farms from eggs only, al He per dozen $63,553.50 Revenue per farm from eggs only $316.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Total number of hens culled out as unprofitable (38&lt;7r) Light Breeds 5.847 Total number of hens culled out as unprofitable, (62^) Heavy Breeds 9,042 Amount realized from sale of 15,389 fowls $10.050.&lt; Gross Income from eggs and fowls $73,603.' Cost of feeding 5,847 light hens at 96c per hen.. $5,613.12 Cost of feeding 9,542 heavy hens at $1.03 per hen. $9,828.26 Total feeding cost $15,441.38 Net receipts, no allowance having been made for labor $58,162.12 Net income per hen $2.16 Boys' and QtrUf Poultry Clubs. — Poultry club work during the year was distributed over the eastern and east-central St of the state. Clubs were organized in 28 counties, 4 of ch were non-agent counties. There were 53 clubs 01 - ized with an enrollment of 536, with 274 completing the ject. Seven clubs that carried the poultry raising project during the summer of 1921 were reorganized and took over the farm flock carrying on the egg production project. STATK HIKS It has been the practice of the University activities in past years to hold an exhibit or display at the State Fair in Lin - coln. As the Extension Service grew, it first took a small space in the regular University exhibit, then finally asked for and was assigned a location in an entirely separate building: this for the reason that the exhibits as worked out by the Extension Service hejd an entirely different idea from the regular advertising display of the University. The gradual growth of the displays from the boys' and girls' clubs forced a location in which they would not be disturbed nor disturb others. As time went on the Extension activities were scat - tered pretty well over the grounds. Some were in good build - ings, some in buildings not so good, and some in tents. Recognizing that in this Extension work there was a draw- not fully realized, the Fair Board last year (1922) gned one of their large display buildings to Extension. This was 420 by 100 feet in ground area, devoid of all appur- Einces for display, and was simply space to lx&gt; filled. The ding was filled, pigs, calves, and chickens filled the north of the space, the south half was taken with booth dis - r s of club work — a space 40 by 50 was prepared for team </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report n demonstrations in homo economics subjects, and a space 70 by 100 was reserved for the general Extension exhibit. One booth was prepared by the specialists of each depart - ment. In line with the policy of the Nebraska Service, these booths made no attempt to cover the whole field of the de - partment, but each tried to drive home some one particularly needed lesson. As a center piece, there was arranged within a rectangle, 20 by 40 feet in extent, a community of farms. These 7 farms were laid out — good arrangements, bad ar - rangements, sets of buildings good and bad — all tagged, and in addition ribbons led from particular spots on the miniature layout to the booths which surrounded it. COIXTY KAIIIS For a number of years past the Extension Service has !x'en preparing and sending out to the county fairs an Ex - tension exhibit under a canvas 30 by 40 feet. When the prac - tice was first established 1 tent was sent out. The demand grew until 2 tents were sent and one year 3 tents were used to make up this exhibit. This work has been reasonably popular, as every year there have been, many more demands for it than we could supply in making up an economical rout - ing for the exhibit. During the years that it has been sent out we have visited practically 85 per cent of the fairs in the state. Five years ago the College of Agriculture was not recog - nized very strongly by the different county fairs in the state so far as judging of livestock and agricultural products was concerned. Feeling that this was a lack which should be corrected, the Extension Service started a direct drive to pro - cure for the institution the judging of livestock and agricul - tural products at county fairs. The popularity of the Exten - sion exhibit was used to draw such fairs as secured the ex - hibit to the College of Agriculture for fair judges. This ac - tivity has now reached the point where the College of Agricul - ture is serving about as large a proportion of the fairs as it is possible to serve. During the past 4 years 641 judges have been furnished to 219 different fairs. In 1922, 194 judges were furnished to 66 fairs. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ItOYS' \\|i &lt;.IKI.^ (1,1 Its In 1922, 591 Junior clubs enrolled 4,602 club members in 68 of the 93 counties of Nebraska. This is an increase of 1,043 boys and girls over the 1921 record. Three thousand two hundred sixty-seven enthusiastic club members completed the work by filing final reports with the Extension Service. This was an increase of 1,217 over the previous year's work in number finishing. The value of products reported by these club members was $115,307.23, produced at a cost of $64, - 784.51. This left a value above cost of $50,522.72. When divided among the 3,267 members completing, an average in - come of $15.43 came to each club member. Twenty different kinds of clubs were organized, including dairy calf, beef calf, cow and calf, canning, clothing, cooking, hot lunch, poultry, pig, sow and litter, sheep, garden, corn, potato, rabbit, keep well, baby beef, market hog, rope, and farm accounts. The most successful Boys' and Girls' Club Week hold at the University of Nebraska was staged May 29 to June :'». 1 1 J22. Two hundred and fifteen boys and girls from over the state were in attendance. The program consisted of lectures in the mornings, trips in the afternoons, and inspirational programs in the evenings. These boys and girls carried home with them an inspiration for doing bigger and better things for Nebraska agriculture. At the State Fair 53 demonstration teams competed for honors. This was a very large increase over the previous year. Four teams went to the Interstate Fair at Sioux City and two teams, poultry and daily, wont to the National Daily Show at St. Paul. One team went to the International Live Stock Show at Chicago. RKNKRAIi SIMMAItV During the past several years there has been a gradual change toward the elimination of the sectional idea as applied to Extension work with men, women, and juniors. Instead of a distinct division of these 3 lines of work there has been a unification of the Extension program and each worker has contributed to the development of the entire program. An effort was made to develop the idea of more extensive group work thru community and precind programs. During </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 53 he- year programs were developed in 401 communities in 35 ■ounties in the state. These programs vary from very simple mea in which but few projects are undertaken to elaborate hh's covering nearly all lines of work. Thru these programs wen developed a vast number of project leaders whose volun - ary services resulted in a greatly enlarged scope for extension work While the financial depression resulted in a decrease in he number of women agents employed, the activities of the men agents in carrying out a unified program resulted in a larger amount of women's work being done than ever before. Voluntary leadership among the women seemed more readily available than among the men, and the activities of women such as sewing, cooking, millinery, health, and home man- gement were promoted in all organized counties, and made ven more rapid progress than the meri's work. Ol'TliOOK The outlook for the coming year is far more favorable than it was a year ago. Financial conditions are slightly better. There is less discontent with prevailing conditions. While the prices received by the farmer are but slightly better than they were last year, he is prepared for the situation. He has made every possible cut in production costs, is using but little hired labor, and has tended more to diversification. He has shown an increased interest in extension, desiring help in dairying, poultry, pasture crops, etc., and his wife in short cuts in sewing. Home butchering, soap making, and canning have also been in great demand. Extension help has been in ■ater demand than in more prosperous times. This year several lines of extension have shown a financial return that has been appreciated. The certified seed potato work in west Nebraska is perhaps the most striking example. Table stock potatoes are a drug on the market and are hardly bringing cost of production but certified seed is in great de - mand and shows a good profit. The growers are well pleased with the service rendered. The enthusiasm is almost equally as great in the corn variety work altho its direct monetary value is not so evident, but it does point the way to more economic production. The past year marks the tenth year of organized county service altho a great number of the counties have been or- </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ganized but 5 years. There has been a tendency to look back at this time and profit by the experience of the past. While there was no tendency to discount the work of the past there has been a feeling that the past work has not shown as definite a policy as might be desired. This became the keynote of the annual extension conference where the need of a long time program was stressed. There was not the slightest doubt of the value of past work yet there was a general feel - ing developed that a careful study should be made of Nebraska conditions. From this study a long time program should be evolved. Immediately following the conference the specialists were asked to present from facts now available suggestions that might be formed into a tentative program for the coming year's work. This program was to serve as a base for study on a long time prog»am. The study for the tentative program led to a division &lt; the state into districts having similar agricultural conditioi and needs, the major needs of each district becoming the pn gram for that district and a part of the state program. It not the intention to exclude from the district any line of wor not included on the program, for which there may be son local demand, but rather to stress the work included on t\ program. This will tend to narrow the program and mu\ it possible to show some definite results whi clearly shown when too wide a field is covered. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 55 THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FIND llweipls i\cd l)&gt; I he State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer The I'niversity of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal il June 30, l'J22 under act of Congress approved 1887. Total .$15,000.00 Expenditures $14,580.00 420.00 $15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Iteceipts by the state Treasurer, who Is also the treasurer University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal iled June 30, 1922 under the act of Congress, ap- March 16, 1906. Total $15,000.00 K\|«'iiilitui-i's 15.90 5.50 Total \l Lincoln. Nebraska. January 31. 1923. •m &gt;, plants and sundry supplies $14,978.60 J15.0O0.0O L. E. GUNDERSON. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 56 I..1 FINANCIAL STATK.MKNT — Continued EXPENDITURES FROM STATE FUNDS Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Si Water, heat, light and power :'.444.47 Publishing, printing and advertising 1.072.07 Traveling expense 2.1! Miscellaneous 1 1 Total MATERIALS, PARTS AND REPAIR Buildings Grounds Autos and trucks Upkeep of property FOR I PKEEP 3,271 47 l.oir, S4 195.09 1.15 Total * 8.(101 of the University of Nebraska by accounting cl all State funds (exclusive of Federal funds). lassification units, and fr SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees I59.943.ll Temporary employees 894.98 Fees, claims, etc r.M Total $ «&lt;&gt;. m: SUPPLIES Office supplies Laboratory supplies Food $ 898.T.1 4.S7!) 67 1.318.62 Fuel 1. 26:Mi!. Educational supplies IfUl Agricultural supplies M.M2.1S EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ BUI Telephone and telegraph Freight, express and drayage m MUI </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 57 I'M K NT fixture M ii azlnes, etc * 19,590.82 s ANH ULILDINUS t 1,326.61 2,558.29 $ 3,884.90 r;il CHARGES us and refunds ratal | 125.00 $ 125.00 JU3.445.10 and Total includes expenditures Tor the central station at the Agricultural Mid the substations at ScottsblufT, North Platte and Valentine. i. Nebraska, Finance Secretary. 1. lttt. KINANCIAI. STATKMKNT — (-&lt;&gt;ntlnue«l $ 1,360.12 atory supplies 3,533.61 9,658.56 4.574.87 463.66 L. E. GUNDERSON, </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station N AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SERVICE OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL, STATKMKXT EXPENDITURES Fiscal year July Salaries Printing and distribution of publications Stationery and small printing Postage, telegraph and freight Supplies Library Tools, machinery and ap - pliances Furniture and fixtures Scientific apparatus Traveling expenses 8,994.19 12.692.74 I2.t29.74 Contingent expenses 7.89 167. »n 4!i.M M 89 lfi Totals $98,41 82 $85 *14 B. OUNDER Finai ■ March 19, 1923. In this statement the expemiiturps arc classif'u States Government classification. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 59 100 WORTH WHILE ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF THE COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE THE PAST TWO YEARS 1. Enrolled an average of more than 1,300 students each car in its college,, secondary schools, and short courses. 2. Published over 220 individual bulletins and circulars with an aggregate edition (including reprints of old bulletins) iver 800,000 copies. 3. Promoted the growing of seed potatoes in northwest Nebraska, which today equals any region of the United States r the production of seed potatoes. Only a few years ago growers were importing seed potatoes from other states to Nebraska, not knowing that superior seed could be grown here. Certified seed potatoes from Nebraska now sell for ipproximately $360 per car more than table stock. Over 1,000 acres were listed for certification in 1922. Nebraska dry land seed (certified) yields 100 bushels per acre more under irrigation than seed that has been irrigated two years. There are 10,000 acres of irrigated potatoes grown in Ne- Uraska each year. The best varieties of potatoes for both the dry land and the irrigated districts of the State have l)con determined. 4. Developed and promoted the Nebraska type poultry se. More than 200 of these poultry houses have been wilt the last two years from plans furnished by the College. ■"&gt;. Has the distinction of being the only college in the United States that has developed a cow that has produced more than 1,000 pounds of butter fat in a year. «. Enrolled 4,559 boys and girls in 1921 and 5,857 in WVl'l, in 15 different clubs, promoting a practical interest in things agricultural. 7. Completed tests of 85 tractors sold in Nebraska, under the provisions of the law passed by the Legislature. 8. Introduced a plan whereby dairy bulls are loaned to Nebraska farmers by the College for the purpose of raising the standards of milk production. Farmers making use of this plan must agree to keep milk and butter fat records on their herds and on the daughters of the bull. This is the most </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 60 generous and far-reaching plan of the kind ever offered farm - ers by an agricultural college. 9. Distributed agricultural news and information week - ly to over 700 newspapers and magazines. 10. Discovered that the farm tenant situation in Ne - braska is not as serious as has been represented. Approxi - mately 45 per cent of the so-called tenant farmers were found to be near-relatives of the owners, and did not belong to the strictly tenant class. A study was made of over 1,000 farms to secure these facts, which are now being published in bul - letin form. 11. Developed and supplied 140 rural women's clubs will courses of study. 12. Has shown that calves produce beef on one-fourth lea feed than older cattle. This work is now in its third yeai By a greater use of calves for feeding, more beef can b produced with the same amount of total feed. 13. Completed a test of 800 hybrid strawberries and now growing 6 of the best hybrids for trial in various ■ tions of the State. 14. Conferred the degree of Bachelor of Science in Ar culture upon 76 graduates, and the degree of Bachelor Science in Home Economics upon 46 women graduates. 15. Installed experimental flour mill and baking 1; tory to study the milling and baking qualities of N'el wheat. Mills are giving more attention to buying whi the basis of these qualities and the work of the Statio be of great assistance to Nebraska farmers in deve these qualities. 16. Answered inquiries regarding nearly l&lt; kinds of insects. Gave individual advice to at Nebraska farmers regarding insect problems. Answered 1H0 to 200 such letters a month. 17. Gave 115 live stock judging demonstrations in Ne - braska, with an average of 62 people in attendance at each demonstration. 18. Promoted the serving of hot lunches for school chil - dren in over 100 schools of the State. 19. Maintained a dairy herd of between 90 and 100 pure - bred cattle of the Holstein, Jersey, Ayrshire, and Guernsey breeds, with about 45 cows in milk. The average production </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 61 of 44 cows in 1921 was 9,448 pounds of milk (391 pounds butter fat), and the average of 47 cows during the first 10 months of 1922 was 9,291 pounds of milk (403 pounds butter fat). 20. Trained 17 agricultural college men for the profession of teaching and placed 13 of this number in Nebraska high schools as teachers of vocational agriculture. Trained 37 agricultural college women for the profession of teaching and placed 33 of this number in Nebraska high schools as teachers home economics. 21. Acted as host to 15 farmers' organizations meeting the college each year. 22. Introduced a plan of vitalized agriculture in 18 schools of the State, building toward a state-wide and prac - ticable system of teaching agriculture in grade and high schools. 2."). Placed college graduates in teaching positions or ex - perimental work in colleges in Georgia, Kansas, Colorado, Michigan. Oregon, Iowa, North Dakota, Maryland, California, md Virginia, as well as in the United States Department of Agriculture. 24. Completed barberry survey and eradication work in &lt;;"&gt; counties, doing away with this notorious harborer of wheat 25. Conducted 2 state high school stock judging contests, ach of which more than 20 high schools entered teams. 26. Conducted 4 cattle feeding experiments, 4 sheep feed - experiments, and 7 hog feeding experiments, looking to reducing the cost of meat production. 27. Trained student stock judging teams which won first ace at National Swine Show at Peoria, 111., in 1921, and second place at the International Live Stock Exposition at Chicago in December, 1920, with 21 college teams contesting. 28. Carried out 58 drainage demonstrations on Nebraska farms. 29. Distributed farm account books to 7,000 farmers. :'.(). Conducted short courses in general agriculture, veter - inary work, automobiles and tractors, poultry raising, and dairying for farmers who could not spend an entire semester in the college. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 31. Carried on over 175 pruning and spraying demon - strations in about 25 counties. 32. Exhibited champion grade and cross bred steer at International Live Stock Exposition in December, 1920 ; Cham - pion Galloway steer, Champion Chester White barrow, Cham - pion pen of Chester White barrows, and Reserve Grand Champion pen of barrows, at International in 1921. Ex - hibited Champion Hereford steer and Champion Shorthorn steer as well as Grand Champion beef carcass at Denver in 1921. At the January, 1922, Denver show, exhibited Grand Champion barrow as well as Champion Chester White, Duroc Jersey, and Hampshire: won 35 ribbons on cattle, including Champion Angus steer, Reserve Champion Shorthorn and Champion Herd of Shorthorns. Over $4,000 in prizes was won on stock at these shows. 33. Made inspections of dairy herds at 10 State institu - tions under the State Board of Control, an aggregate of 7 12 dairy cattle. Upon the recommendations of the college, soul) bulls at these institutions were disposed of. cows were better fed and cared for, methods of handling milk were improved. and milk production increased. 34. Answered 9,000 letters of inquiry regarding I from May 1, 1920, to October 26, 1922. 35. Offered correspondence courses in agriculture. S this work was established, 61 students have completed I courses. 36. Distributed information to 1,000 farmers regard ii treatment of weevil-infested grain. 37. Carried on a Nebraska National Egg-Laying Contest. Birds from different sections of the State and different farms were entered in a contest at the Agricultural College. Aver - age production per hen, 161 eggs; previous year, 154 eggs. 38. Carried out seed certification work. In 1922. 136,455 bushels of wheat and oats in 33 counties were certified for purity and freedom from disease, furnishing definite sources of pure strains. 39. Made more than 4,300 production tests of dairy cattle for advanced registry. 40. In cooperation with Federal Government, maintained county extension agents in 45 counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 63 41. Published a 150-page bulletin, "Com Investigations," giving detailed results of a long series of experiments with Nebraska corn. 42. Distributed sufficient hog cholera serum to vaccinate 400.000 hogs and blackleg virus sufficient to vaccinate 100,000 rattle. 43. Developed and advocated in Nebraska, plan of grow - ing soy beans in corn for "hogging down." Soy beans serve i-.s a cheap protein supplement to corn. In 1921, 250 farmers in eastern Nebraska were following the plan. By 1922 the number had increased to more than a thousand. 44. Developed within the last year a portable colony brooder house for chickens. Fifteen of them have been built within a radius of 10 miles of Lincoln within the last year. IB. Three hundred and seventy-eight judges have been furnished to 125 county and community fairs during 1921 and 1922, as follows: live stock, 151 ; poultry, 59; soil products, SI : home economics, 87. 46. Established the first cooperative bull association in the State, in Saunders County. 47. Graduated 109 students from the School of Agricul - ture at Lincoln, a secondary school of the College. 48. Carried on 44 farmstead demonstrations, showing the :&gt;est arrangement of farm buildings and fields for convenience wd profit. 49. Carried out health and nutrition campaigns for both hildren and adults. In 1921 over 30 health instruction enter- tainments were given especially for children and in 1922 40 lecture demonstrations to 9,070 people, mostly adults. 50. Promoted an accredited flock poultry project with over 400 farmer members to date. The members agree to put their poultry raising on a scientific basis, by culling, breeding, and feeding, as advocated by the Agricultural College. Flocks accredited when certain production records are attained. 51. Made a careful study of the types of reading matter which appeal to Nebraska farmers, thru a survey reaching 1,500 farm and village homes, and published a bulletin deal - ing with the subject. 52. Gave 15 demonstrations in shearing sheep, docking lambs, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 64 53. Promoted the growing of sweet clover in Nebraska. This plant doubles the stock carrying capacity of pasture over ordinary grass. Conducted demonstrations in 10 counties. 54. Enrolled nearly 100 army vocational students in Trades School in poultry, agricultural engineering, and dairy courses. 55. Started a comprehensive series of investigations and experiments in weed control. 56. Promoted the use of Kherson, Nebraska No. 21. and Burt oats. Ninety per cent of the acreage in the State is now made up of these varieties. Kherson was originally in - troduced to America by the Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station. 57. Carried on a grasshopper campaign in the North Platte valley, saving the farmers thousands of dollars. 58. Distributed 480 ounces of strychnine, sufficient, when prepared, to poison 292,000 prairie dog burrows. 59. Disseminated strains of Kanred, Nebraska No. 6, and Nebraska No. 60, early varieties of winter wheat. Forty per cent of the acreage in the State is made up of these varieties. 60. Introduced and promoted a fruit and vegetable budgt to encourage greater and more even consumption of tho* products as a means to health. Promoted an increased use i dairy products in diet. 61. Carried out 7 demonstrations to show prop struction of farm buildings. 62. Carried out experiments to determine the efficiency of tillage tools, as regards power requirements, different kinds of soils, etc. 63. Added 4 new boys' and girls' clubs, including farm accounts, to encourage the boys and girls to develop into busi - ness-like farmers; radio, to keep pace with that development; keep-well club, to promote health ; and the rope club, to teach methods of tying hitches, splicing ropes, etc. 64. Designed 9 complete plans of buildings and grounds for county fairs. 65. Carried out a campaign, urging late sowing of fall wheat in 1921, thereby avoiding a serious outbreak of the Hes - sian fly. 66. Carried out 14 irrigation demonstrations. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 65 67. Distributed 5,168 boxes of pocket gopher poison to farmers. This was sufficient to treat 30,000 acres. 68. Surveyed portions of the State for soil acidity. 69. Outlined and put into effect a comprehensive series of experiments at the State orchard at Union, designed to answer the orchard problems of eastern Nebraska. 70. Introduced and provided families with score cards in older to keep check on children's health. Four hundred fami - lies were thus supplied. 71. Answered 10,500 personal letters regarding the care, feeding, and management of live stock. 72. Carried out extensive investigation of the purchasing power of Nebraska grains and made studies over a long period of years of the relations between production and price. Also studied the factors affecting hog prices. These studies will soon be made available in bulletin form. 73. Inspected all shipments of plants from foreign coun - tries not previously inspected by the Federal Government at port of entry, to prevent the introduction of dangerous insect pests and plant diseases. 71. Thirty lessons in dietetics were given to the nurses ;it the University Hospital in Omaha by a member of the home economics staff. 75. Under the provisions of the State law, the College alibrated more than 100,000 cream bottles, more than 6,000 milk bottles, more than 2,300 pipettes, and more than 3,500 cream weights, thereby preventing the use of inaccurate glass- ware and cream weights. 7H. Conducted millinery and dress construction schools for leaders, who in turn held schools for other women. More than 5,000 dress forms were made, at a saving of $10 each, and more than 3,500 hats were made, at a saving of $5 each. 77. Compiled a carefully prepared history of the College of Agriculture from its earliest beginnings 50 years ago down to the present time. 78. Assisted in the organization of 8 county live stock breeders' associations. 79. Gave 90 butchering and meat-cutting demonstrations. Meat butchering, canning, and soap-making demonstrations were carried on in 20 counties of the State. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 80. Held 2 live stock feeders' conventions each year. 81. Introduced a "live baby" at the home management house, giving home economics girls practical training in child care. 82. Carried out 79 community tests in 82 counties, de - monstrating the type of seed corn ear best adapted to local conditions. 83. Conducted 25 farm account schools, showing farmers how to put their operations on a business basis. 84. Wrote over 3,600 letters to farmers answering ques - tions dealing with farm engineering and building problems. 85. Promoted the smut treatment for oats and wheat, th latter being a new project. 86. Carried on 60 soil erosion demonstrations, showing farmers by actual example how soil washing can be success - fully combated. 87. Introduced courses in institutional management, pre paring women for managers of tea rooms, cafeterias, insti tutions, etc. 88. Distributed over :?.000 blue prints of farm build and equipment. 89. Started experiments to determine the U practices in growing and curing alfalfa hay. 90. Carried on an infertile egg campaign and feeding campaign among poultry raisers. 91. Supplied a model farm exhibit to 12 conn 92. Carried out 12 farm water Ripply demonsti 93. Conducted 46 income tax schools for farnx 94. Assisted 500 farmers to begin keeping books and cost of production records dealing with one or more lines of fann - ing. This was to enable them to determine the most econom - ical methods of handling their farms. Supplied over 1,100 enterprise records to farmers, for keeping track of individual crops. 95. Members of the agricultural college faculty have visited more than 60 high schools to assist teachers of agri - culture and home economics in organizing their teaching work. 96. Examined twice all of the nurseries of the entire State to determine their freedom from dangerous insect pests and </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report n plant diseases, and issued 94 certificates to the owners or managers of these nurseries enabling them to sell and make !&gt;7. Supplied 100 communities of the State with programs for community meetings each month. This is a new line of 98. Published and disseminated lists of fruit plants, orna - ulal shrubs, and flowers best adapted to the different coun- the State. !&gt;!&gt;. Established practice teaching centers in the high &lt; hools of Waverly, Eagle. University Place, and Havelock, &gt;v the puiiwse of training teachers of agriculture and home onomics. 100. Attended 12 conferences of teachers of high school gricuKwe to assist in carrying agricultural education into the local farm communities. hipments into other states. </seg>
            <seg id="p068"/>
            <seg id="p069">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 69 i r " I p I 3 Z- y S o S 3 tj o — p ra I" a i ZT "^r I Eli r" o „ — . p _ip - |ii5 H |-"»fc| s Ei go ■ t. Q _j ~ »— ' &lt;^ — i—i "^^ 1 B 1 Jto &gt; if h if: pi- si i Pll!ll!l M(dc3^ w -Sega ilrillili o u a. x £ — •- « a &lt;• !*" g=£? £^-° Iiiliiiii s^ </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station S X. - I x I- I x I r~iroi j~tri S !\* If «/o |; i(L!ilj3fi! IO. ►• yrr - - J - ■■'tvl ' \- J " I ) L. ( |'HM'alja{ia^| I +■ Ai &lt;o J ; -s r-Hfr v ji j / * j_.__J/r&gt; I a e ■ ■ I M M it »1 ■ i 5 I I ii Is 8E £ y. X p I ■ ,. .;...,-&gt;-■-- ! 2 [!r /i! s\ "/ 5! *! ; — ■ A. . ■J. • </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 71 r s &lt;- HI / s Z X T. ' * " % 1 ? [ &gt;'' "S7 "'£'.&amp; sfof '" , if / 1 ii^yi!^ a \ aT^'JH i\ -La! *ij f /j [F^f TT \ r^- I t! &gt;; ;| /( / • !:....;; H-r L- 13 (j 71 { \ "I 3j "^w| o Si ?|i "&gt; I 1 • I Si £— it? — * " r )-iA h\ (N|i p :?| /&lt;&lt;» rasHSIS Lot! .„ • _ ii. ,1 A^C ) 1 y^ I; -^ c ! »j ji I jj *&amp;* II Hi / a $Pl 111 ■' 55| ■ ,5| 5|i| 13 j| ■o«»o 3 * u M Hi ill! &gt;&gt;— bc a, -Sis I oil — X - =- i - ~ i; I. O u x o -a f O » = s,5»- « i. — C — 1 a — is a I 4 I - I j — J--A- ~t 2 -Ml .....ir ' % A H </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 72 = = x 5 - x = </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 73 9 &lt;■ N •» -• x- :/ I L / iJ -HS l / L— If i y' j \ :' i! /f 9 • m WM n S^J ,J i pro ir I!" '9.* Itil a 5 a i3 Ills lip «• H * 5 ■3*2° t &amp; ■•o = ? ■ N a ft a c NcS t. = c = = c x: = £ -«~ 3CHs t&gt; o e b a) fllfi o •« &gt;.~. q C- 0- o £ s s 0 2 = ° « 1 o£ - e f5|2 ; i v y: 1 1 -y—-.o \±z / ii"* 1 I'*? ..!...[ ! ! &gt; Ii Si I ■- i 1 I i ; i s 8) ■ I 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station I r. . - •r. X s J. ? y — — </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 75 / s s f / if HPiiifPi! j t '"--\y/"{&gt; ;r^' t io ii^i « h.iZi iiajel 8 !! f / I . ISMM!,! / fa yLj?s it^ttti V II / I! &lt;!/■■ S'ki I liy ' 3 ; ■ / ►— ■&lt;}'&amp; i I {• -' it I '&lt;i* r \"i :; ; jrtjli I; |i ?1 *m \ Si ij ? ; '.' SIT CoJbs s a § s all 1 9 o &gt;&gt;js - |--" § x C ==u fil 1 ! Hit* 111!" 1 ■ ! V i K — * = ■ « a " ° ~ "" 3 » * rfHk Hi!! </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station X • MW.0 &gt;* • ]/j| ft ?! 'i ] JL.5. ; i"~lp k if it Spill I I r s. I n i x i ii I \ r ...&amp; l: / /■' | r {■ t |\«MTfS ' jLJu.i; y HM;.SJ I L-..!UpL H 'q ! T\LL * AJ ij JMM ii rd ° Si ol ,- u MJ \ I Ai "T t\ Wv b ! L.!I JL._^-?V- --' i f j a Aj ' iU * itit in .if ii^Jjr/1 ii &amp;ii Fjh | -u/_ ... A wlfi ■ || si 1 V-"- h i si i I— X r \i A— </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report :/ =i x is a i m x. u. 5: ki * u a M 00 T3 bf "O 2 i* x s to o a, « • O [a *- bt 9&lt; A — ti 1 s« » i «&lt; 2 00 i M — V J£ is JB « S - « • o a Sc" 3 *s£ I i|| l§i |lj || X S^ -2^ * i«i -s; °q^ "2 " 4 Bfl^ 2 • Q, "^ c 2 x a c bf° &lt; - o „ «;i art'O -* ■ Qi OQ r. • i 1 " SS? ■ M h i is * 2C "J -a T on PI p 11 11! Ill S I i*l vi£ 115 ::s £* «l, = "3fc2 O^T) J-0-T3 00 g i*i gc= ="= f »i -J.--3 — a- &lt;d on '* Ell ,i| i|! u x - « 1 ss </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station * • T' L/H^jff x Til:.:' L- i-'V^i-- iVfc-^' ; I'i^vJJ 1 / ■.■•*!»• /K-"y •v»*' l i»* « ■ (• l::LP8J:llj::fl:H::i it^-.igjH3 r |O^^V : \»ii-^iiJ::j lit i'd • : • i M L_y A_Lii Y'. *•. jj • /fi :■■: y- ~ - — I u - t: * ■ c ~ — a. ■- ~ '■ i£-£ i * i E "O fc | ■ z ~ - - ■= ~ c ~ — ~ 5 ■ * ~ r- :l ■'■ ' - 2i ■ i r _ u ~ =■ = _= 7 « .;. 'j : = c -2 •- — — ■ w ■/. ~ — z. ~ ™ — e S ■ a o ~ e c ** * Q 00 C ■ ■ - ~Z -. — £. i- — — — - i. *• — i, t. bt a •" — . 1 V — ~ 't- jz ~~ z s. = — ~. * — H ,1... </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 79 i! / •• / / * / J;.J:.)lFH|Pj AJL^ fLJffvxJ II &amp; i I! til! |] Lz| Ijff* i |/jl _^!?^ ) J jj i| jj v I [ || \0j I \ 5 ji /f i 3.-V ti.'"Afti f\ i ii a/fl 5 J O" ,i.°l *| A I... --' 1 rfV y*^ • irofi 1: i;?fi^| Jb«; -A:; o ? c; t P5J' cvA; '■ t&gt; j, oo ; I: 8 H 1' 1 / ; ; i \i i v Hi li Ji f| II I -g J B 2 ?s ? « i &gt;&lt; r ■- Sa cj 5 *JS • ! CO; ag p 'S * = ? o-f — - n- — ■* x = i = Z ~ u — n a u eg c i S a 1. 3 _ ■= » ■ X m * t gin | ■O O c B = ?••■- *" I **■ |||||f — *" J^ ~ * js a ■£ j= - a. a ■ - = « — ■ S I I I -.1 s |J </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 80 PUBLICATIONS OF THE STATION BII.LKTINS L "Irrigation in Nebraska — A Contribution frrm the Department Geology," by Lewis E. Hicks. 1888 2. "Twenty-two Ccmmon Insects of Nebraska," by Conway McMillan 1KSS 3. "Southern Cattle Plague and Yellow Fever, from the Etiologies and Prophylactic Standpoints." by Frank S. Billings. 1888. 4. "Swine Plague, its Causes, Nature, and Prevention," by Frank Billings. 1888 5. "On Certain Injurious Insects of the Year 1888," by Lawrenc Bruner. 1889. 6. "Report ol n»|li ■■. Including a History of the Fields, am Inscription of the Animals Available for Experimentation," by Henry II Wing; "Field Experiments and Observations for the Year 1888," by Jare&lt; &lt;;. Smith; "Meteorological Record lor the Tear IMS," by DeWitt I Brace. 1889 7. "Southern Cattle Plague and Yellow Fever, from the Etiologies and Prophylactic Standpoints." h\ Frank S. Billings. 1889 8. "The 'Corn-Stalk Disease in Cattle," by Frank S. Billings If 9. "The So-called 'Hydrophobia' in Cattle," by Frank 8. Blllll 1889. 10. "Contagious Inflammation of the Cornea in Cattle", "A Disease of the External Sexual Organs in Cows." by K 1889. 11. "The Smut of Wheat and Oats." t,y Joseph C, Ar Introduction by Charles K BasMjr; 'The Smut of Indiar Charles E. Bessey ; "A Preliminary Enumeration of the Rusts and Si of Nebraska," by Herbert J. Webber, with an Introduction by Bessey; "Notes on the Fungi ol Economic Interest. Okaat •a County, Nebraska, during the Summer of 1889." by Roscoe I servations on the Cottonwood (Populus monilifera Ait.)," by Al Woods. 1889. 12. "Field Experiments for 1889," by Jared Q. Smith. 18 13. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebra.s H. H. Nicholson and Rachel Lloyd. 1890 14. "Insects Injurious to Young Trees on Tree Claims." by Law Bruner. 1890. 15. "Meteorological Record for the Year 1889." by DeWitt B "Record of Soil Temperatures tor the Year 1889," by Jar "Farm Notes," by Jared O. Smith. 1890 16. Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska H. H. Nicholson and Rachel Lloyd. 1891 17. "Field Experiments and Observations for 1890," by Jared Smith: "Meteorological Observations for 189(1." by DeWitt B. Brace an Harold N. Allen. 'Mini af these buMrtiiu being publisbe'l mainly as a «»m|&gt;lctc utijmI ol publication*. Liatfl an- imhlishtil From time to time of available bulletins. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 81 ra IV II Ian w 18. "Preliminary Report on the Native Trees and Shrubs of Ne - ka." by Charles E. Bessey. 19. "Farm Notes for 1891," by C. L. Ingersoll. Meteorological Observations for 1891," by DeWitt B. Brace. 1892. 21. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska," II H. Nicholson and Rachel Lloyd. 1892. 1-23. "The Corn Fodder Disease in Cattle and Other Farm Animals, Especial Relation to Contagious Pleuro-Pneumonia in American England," by Frank S. Billings. 1892. :'4 "Notes on Certain Caterpillars Attacking Sugar Beets," by Law - .■ Itruner. 1891". Detasseling Corn," by C. L. Ingersoll. 1892 Meteorological Observations for 1892." by DeWitt B. Brace .7. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska, II H Nicholson and T. L. Lyon. 1893. 2v Southern Cattle Plague. (Texas Fever.) Third Edition. Re - il and much new material added thereto," by Frank S. Billings. 1893. Cost of Farm Crops," by C. L. Ingersoll and S. W. Perin. 1893. The Influence of Changes of Food and Temperature on the iv and Quality of the Milk of Dairy Cows," by C. L. Ingersoll and Huncanson. 1893. 1 "The Russian Thistle in Nebraska," by Charles E. Bessey. 1893. ■Wheat and Some of Its Products," by C. L. Ingersoll and Im E. Bessey. assisted by H. H. Nicholson and President F. S. John- late Millers' Association. 1894. 3. "Meteorological Observations in 1893." by D. B. Brace. 1894. 4. "Chinch-Bugs," by Lawrence Bruner and H. G. Barber. 1894. Alfalfa.— Farm Notes," by C. L. Ingersoll. :&gt;t&gt;. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska," H H. Nicholson and Edward E. Nicholson. 1894. ■ Nebraska Weather Review," for 1894, in 12 parts, by G. D. y and G. A. Loveland. "Nebraska and the Beet Sugar Industry. Report of Dr. Max Holl- Halle, Germany. Translated from 'Zeitschrift des Vereins fur die ■kt r Industrie des Deutsrhen Richs," " by H. H. Nicholson. 1894. Some Obstacles to Successful Fruit Growing." by Fred W. Card. 4n. "Preliminary List of the Honey-Producing Plants of Nebraska," ha lies E. Bessey. 1895. 41 "Water Supply in Nebraska," by O. V. P. Stout. 1895. 42. "Nebraska Weather Review" for 1895. in 13 parts, by G. D. ezey and G. A. Loveland 43. "The Conservation of Soil Moisture by Means of Subsoil Plow - ■ l»y T. L. Lyon. 1895. 44. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska," by II Nicholson and T. L. Lyon. 1896. 4.V "The Rainfall of Nebraska," by G. D. Sweiey and G. A. Love - d. 1896. 46 "Nebraska Weather and riiniate for 1896," 7 parts, by G. D. /.•■&gt; and (I. A Lo\ eland. 47. "Serum Therapy in Hag Cholera." by A. T. Peters. 1897. 4K. "Windbreaks," by Fred W. rani. 1X97. 49. "Suggestions for Chicory Culture," by T. L. Lyon. 1897. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station is lx 1 Tin i 50. "Notes on Pruning," by F. W. Card 1897 51. "Observations on the Codling-Moth," by Fred W. Card ] 52. "Cornstalk Disease," by A. T. Peters. 1898. 53. "A Preliminary Report on Experiments with Forage Cror T. L. Lyon. 1898. 54. "The Effect of Certain Methods of Soil Treatment L'pt Corn Crop," by T. L Lyon. 18!t8. 55. 'Ornamental Planting." l&gt;\ Fred W. Card. 1K!)K 5fi "Methods of Tree-»'lanting." by Fred W Card. 1S9X 57. "Proceedings of Agricultural students' Association 18!tx 1899. :&gt;S. "Annual Forage Hants lor BoMMf Pasture." liy T. 1 and A. L. Haecker 1*99. 59. "The Homemade Windmills of N&lt; hraska." l&gt;&gt; Erwin II Barbour. 6t&gt;. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar lln't in Nehl H. H. Nicholson and T. L. Lyon 1899 61. "Hungarian Brome Gra 1899 (Uroiiius inermis) T. L 62. "The Feeding V;tlu-' ol Sorghum us Shown |p\ Chemical A i« sis," by R. \V. Thatcher. 19u t*J I\. *&gt;. 1 ilitu llt'l iWV, 63. "The Fatal KfTect of Qram Sorgnum," K. S. Hiltne 64. "Proceedings of Agricultural Students' AMOCiatiO 18 19(XI. 65. "Blackleg. Its Nature, Cause and I 67. "Experiment.* in the Culture ol by H. H. Nicholson and T L. Lyon. 19 68. "Feeding Skim-milk to Calve*," by A I. H; 69. "Some Forage Plants for Summer Feed," A. L. Haecker. 1901 70. "Locusts or Grasshoppers." b) Lawrrm, Hi 71. "Sheep Feeding Experiments in Nebraak ment.)" I!y K A. Ituinett. 19til 72. "The Adaptation and Impro\ement of Winter \\ 73. "Experiments in the Culture by T. L. Lyon and A. T. Wiancko. 19 74. "Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hoj: Peters. 1902. 75. "Feeding Experiments with Cattle and 1'igs." bl E. A I and H R Smith. 1902. 76. "Experiments with Dairy Herri. Part I The Herd K Part II. Ration Tests for Dairy Cows; Part 111. The ISest Weei Cow's Lactation Period," by A. L. Haecker MM 77. "Poisoning of Cattle by Common Sorghum and Katir (ScrRhtim vulgare), by A. T. Peters. H. H. Slade. and Samuel \ver&gt; 78. "Macaroni Wheats," by T. L. Lyon. IMS, 79. "Experiments in Orchard Culture." l» K. A. Kmersmi. 1« 80. "Experiments in Mulching Garden VeaMaUaa," I •&gt; Ii A son. 1903. MM. 66. "Sheep Fettling Experiments in .\&gt;l&gt;r 1900. Lyon. 1902. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 83 Experiments in tbc Culture ot the Sugar Beet In Nebraska," .yon and A T. Wiancko. 1903. Kherson Oats." l.y T. L. Lyon. 1904. Variety Tisis oi Corn in 1902 and 1903," by T. L. 19(14 Paatai*, Meadow, and Forage Crops." (Cooperative Experi- States Department of Agriculture.) By T. L. Hitchcock. 1904 Feeding K\perinients with Cattle," by E. A. Burnett and H. R. m. Destroying Prairie Dors," by A. T. Peters and S. Avery. 1904. \ Test of (all Rations." by A. L. Haecker; "Methods of Con- : Containiiial Melick. 1905 Milk During Milking." by A. L. Haecker and Apple Scab anil Cedar Rust," by R. A. Emerson. 1905. Winter Wheat." (Cooperative Experiments with the United partment of Agriculture. ) By T. L. Lyon and Alvin Keyser. so a popular edition. Cattle Feeding Experiment," by H. R. Smith. 1905. Expert— tt with Corn," by T. L. Lyon. 1905. tr-tropx lor Young Orchards," t&gt;y R. A. Emerson. 190G. ie Feeding Experiments." by H. R. Smith. 1906. Fattening Pt0 on Corn and Tankage." by E. A. Burned. 19oti. Crop Production in Western Nebraska." Report of Experimental ittion. North Platte, Nebr. North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 1 w ivder. Superintendent, and E. A. Burnett, Director. 1907. me Insects Injurious to Wheat During 1905-1906," by Lawrence r and Myron H. Swenk. 1907. 1'otaio Experiments," by R. A. Emerson. 1907. Spraying Dt monstrations in Nebraska Apple Orchards." by R. A 1907. "Growing Hogs in Western Nebraska." Report of Experimental tion. North Platte, Nebr. North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 2. P. Snyder. Superintendent, and E. A. Burnett. Director. 1907. ■■Economical Rations in Beef Production," by H. R. Smith. 1907. W 1 "Part 1, Dairy Herd Record for Ten Vears; Part II. Cost of Fat Production." by A. L. Haecker. 1907. 2. "The Effect of Bleaching upon the Quality of Wheat Flour," by A I way. 1907. The Bud-Rot of Carnations," by F. D. Heald : "A Mite Accom- I Hud-Rot of Carnations." by Robert H. Wolcott. 1908. 4 "Part I. Cultivation of Small Grains: Part II. The Use of the ig Mill for Selecting Seed Wheat and Seed Oats," by E. G. Mont- rv. 1908 105. "Growing Cattle in Western Nebraska." Report of Experimental bstation. North Platte, Nebr. North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 3. Bj W P. Snyder. Superintendent, and E. A. Burnett, Director. 1908. 10B. "Does it Pay to Spray Nebraska Apple Orchards?" By R. A. Ki7 "Part I, Foods Supplementary to Corn in Fattening Pigs: Part II. The Effect of Food on Breaking Strength of Bones," by E. A. Burnett. IMS. 108. -Milking Machines." by A. L. Haecker and E. M. Little. 1908. Emeraon and F. E. Denny. 1908. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 84 :i 109. "Crop Production in Western Nebraska. Principles of Cultiva tion." North Flatte Subslation Bulletin No. 4. By W. P. .Snyder MM W. W. Burr. 1909. 110. "Report of the Nebraska Seed Laboratory," by E. Mead Wilco and Miss Nelle Stevenson. 1909. 111. "Changes in the Composition of the Loess Soils of Nebrask: Caused by Cultivation," by F. J. Alway. 1909. 112. "Experiments with Corn," by E. G. Montgomery. 19&lt;i9 113. "Oats." by E. G. Montgomery. 1910. 114. "Storing Moisture in I he Soil." North Platte Substation Hu letin No. 5. By \\ . \\ . Burr. 191". 115. "The Determination of Humus," by F. J. Alway. E. K Files, an R. M. Pinckney. 1910. 116. "Economical Beef Production," by H. R. Smith. 1910 117. "Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska." North Plan Substation Bulletin No. 6. By W. P. Snyder. 1911. 118. "Growing Crops in Western Nebraska " North Platte Substatioi Bulletin No. 7. By W. P. Snyder and W. W. Burr. 1911. 119. "Spraying as an Essential Part of Profitable Apple Orcharding by R. A. Emerson, R. F. Howard, and V. V. Westgate. 1911. 120. "Alfalfa Management." Extension Bulletin No. 1. B&gt; I u Pugsley. 1911. 121. "Growing Hogs in Nebraska." North Platte Subslation Bulletii No. 8. By W. P Snyder. 1911. 122. "Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska ." Extension Bulletin Ni By C. W. Pugsley. 1911 123. "Fattening Hogs in Nebraska " North Platte Substation B letin No. 9. By W. P. Snyder. 1911'. 124. "Fattening Hogs in Nebraska." North I'la letin No. 10. By W. P. Snyder. 125. "Wheat Breeding Experiments, " !&gt;&gt; K (i Montgomery. 126. "Native Seed Corn," by E. Q. Montgomery. 19U'. 127. "Competition in Cereals." by K. Cl Montgomery 1 128. "Studies in Water Requirements of Corn." by K &lt;;. M and T. A. Kiesselbach. 191^ 129. "Results of the Douglas County Cow Testing A. L. Haecker and J. H. Frandsen. 1912. 130. "Forage Rations for Growing Horses." North P Bulletin No. 11. By W. P. Snyder. 1912. 131. "Smuts of Nebraska Cereals.' Extension Bulletin No 7 I E. Mead Wilcox. 1912. 132. "Beef Production." by H. R. Smith. 191:' 133. "Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm." Extension Built No. 8. By J. H. Frandsen. 1912. 134. "A Dry Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber." by K. Mead Wileo - and George K. K. Link. 1913. Popular edition of Research Bulletin No. 1 135. "Growing Crops in Western Nebraska." North Platte Substa tion Bulletin No. 12. By W. P. Snyder and W. W. Burr. 1913 136. "Alfalfa Inoculation Tests," by C. W. Pugsley. 1913 137. "Growing Forest Trees in Western Nebraska; Shrubs and Orna mentals." North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 13. By W. P. Snyder 138. "Silo Construction in Nebraska." Popular and limited editions By L. W. Chase. 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">• Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 85 13!i. "Dairy Herd Record tor Fourteen Years," by A. L. Haecker Utd J. II. Frandsen. 1914. Hii. "Hie Storage and Vm of Soil Miisiure." Popular edition of seared Bulletin No. 5. North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 14. By W. W. Burr. 1914 141. "Irrigateii Field Crops in Western Nebraska." Srotisbluff Sub - lation Bulletin No. 1. By Fritz Knorr. 1914. 142. "Vegetable Gardens on Irrigated Farms in Western Nebraska." i.sbluff Substation Bulletin No. 2. By Fritz Knorr. 1914. 143. "Feeding Baby Beef." North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 15. By W. 1'. Snyder. 1914 144. "Ground Wheat versus Whole Wheat for Fattening Pigs," by K K Bliss and C. B. Lee. 1914. 145. 'Handling Silage," by L. W. Chase and Ivan D. Wood. 1914. 146. "Home Mulched v.s. Northern Seed Potatoes for Eastern Ne - rasKu," by K. A. Emerson. 1914. Also issued in a popular edition. 147. "Pork Production." North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 16. My W. P. Snyder. 1915. Limited and popular editions. 148. "A Handbook of Nebraska Grasses," by E. Mead Wilcox, George K K Link, and Venus W. Pool. 1915. Rais-ing the Dairy Calf," by E. G. Woodward. 1915. "Soy Beans and Cowpeas," by T. A. Kiesselbach. 1915. 151. "Corn Silage and Alfalfa Hay for Beef Production," by R. K. I and C. B. Lee. 1915. Limited Edition. "&gt;2. "Management uf Irrigated Land." ScottsblulT Substation Bul- No. 3. 1915. 151 "Lamb Feeding Experiments," by Howard J. Gramlich. 1915. 154. "The Prairie Dog and Its Control," by M. H. Swenk. 1915. 155. "Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska." North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 17. 1915. 156. "Farming Practice in the Sand Hills Section of Nebraska." Valentine Substation No. 1. 1916. Farm Management Studies in Eastern Nebraska," H. C. Filley. 158. "Why. When, and How to Spray." Popular edition of Research etin No. Id. By J. Ralph Cooper. 1917. l'.M. "Pork Production on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska." James A. Holden. 1917. Oats Investigations," by T. A. Kiesselhaih and J. A. Ratcliff. 161 "Methods of Controlling Blister Canker." Popular edition of Research Bulletin No. 12. By J. Ralph Cooper. 1917. 162. "Wintering Mature Brood Sows." North Platte Substation Bul - letin No. 18. By W. P. Snyder. 1917. 163. "Freezing Injury of Seed Corn." Popular edition of Research Bulletin No. 14. By T. A. Kiesselbach and J. A. RatclifT. 1918. 164. "Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran in Grain Ration for Dairy Cows. North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 19. By W. P. Snyder and E. A. Burnett. 1918. 165. "Growing Pigs in Summer." North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 20. By W. P. Snyder. 1918. 166. "Soy Beans," by T. A. Kiesselbach. 1918. 167. "Feeding Lambs in the Fall," by H. J. Gramlich. 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 I 168. "Sugar-Saving Substitutes in lee Cream." l&gt;y .1 II Frauds J. W. Rovner, and John Luithly. 191K 169. "Forage Crops," by T. A. Kiesselbach 1918. 170. "Fall Lamb Feeding." by H. J. Gramlich. 1918. 171. "Crop Production in the Northern Sand Hills." Yalent station Bulletin No. 2. By James Cowan. 1919 172. "Spring Grains in Western Nebraska." North Platte Sub* tion Bulletin No. 21. By L. L. Zook. 1919. 173. "Supplementary Feeds in Fattening Lambs," &gt;&gt;&gt; H. J. Graml 1919. 174. "Heel Production." by H. J. Gnunlich. 1919 175. "Experimental Hog Feeding." by H. J. Grainlich and K Jenkins. 1920 176. "Summer Hog Feed inn." by H J. Gramlirh. 192n 177. "The Nebraska Tractor Tests." by Hoard of Tractor Test E gineers: O. W. Sjogren. K. E. Ilrackett. and C. W, Smitli: and Aciii Manager of Tractor Tesis. F. R. Nohavec. I!t21. 178. "Winter Wheat Seed Bed Preparation " North Platt tion Bulletin No. 22. By L. L. Zook. 1921 179. "Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska " North Plat Bulletin No. 23. By L. L. Zonk. IM2 180. "Reading Mallei in Nebraska Farm Hones," by J. () K 1922. 181. "Growth Studies ot Dairy Heifers. I: Effect of Liul Feeding of Wide and Narrow Rations." by Department of bandry. 1922 182. "Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska, " by H O. W 183. "Experiments with Poisoned Baits for (Jrasshopi Swenk and E. E. Wehr. January. IMS; revised March. 192 184. "Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers, II; Protein I for Growing Heifers," by Department of Dairy Husbai 185. "The Nebraska Farm Family J. O. Rankin. 1923. Land Tenure P 186. "Potato Diseases in Nebrask I; \V i:i &gt;t \i;« ii in i.i.KiiNs 1. "A Dry Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber." In !■: Mead \\ K. K. Link, and Venus \\ . Pooi. 191 2. "The Inheritance of Quantitative Characters in M Emerson and E. M. East. 1913 3. 'Studies on the Relation ol the Nonavuil the Hygroscopic Coefficient," by F J. Alway 1913 4. "The Inheritance of a Recurrinn Somatic Variation in Variegate Ears of Maize," by R. A. Emerson. 1914. 5. "The Storage and Use of Soil Moisture." by W. W Burr. 191 6. "Transpiration as a Factor in Crop Production." by T. A. K R. A. Emerson. 1916. ami Baking." by F. W. Ipson and J. W. Calvin. l'Ut; bach. 1916. 7. "A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phasenlus Vuluaris. " I 8. "The Colloidal Swelling of Wheat (Mnten in Rctattoa in Ifillli </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 87 i. "A Physiological Study of Two Strains of Fusarium In Their al Relation to Tuber Rot and Wilt of Potato," by George K. K. 1916 Spray i us Experiments in Nebraska," by J. Ralph Cooper. 1917. ■Relation of Size of Seed and Sprout Value to the Yield of »in Crops," by T. A. Kiesselbach and C. A. Helm. 1917. tudies of the Etiology and Control of Blister Canker on Apple J. Ralph Cooper. 1917. Studies Concerning the Elimination of Experimental Error in i\e Crop Tests," by T. A. Kiesselbach. 1918. Fusarium Blight of the Soy Bean and the Relation of Various t Infection," by Richard 0. Cromwell. 1919 Farm Types in Nebraska, as Determined by Climatic, Soil, and Factors." by II. R. Spafford. 1919. Freezing Injury of Seed Corn," by T. A. Kiesselbach and J. A. "The Immunizing Value of Commercial Vaccines and Bacterins Hemorrhagic Septicemia," by L. Van Es and H. M. Martin. 1920. The Value of Commercial Vaccines and Bacterins Against Fowl by L. Van Es and H. M. Martin. 1920. The Regional Adaptation of Corn in Nebraska," by T. A. Kieaari- F. I). Keim. 1&lt;I21. orn Investigations," by T. A. Kiesselbach. 1922. •Studies of Immunity Against Hemorrhagic Septicemia," by L. and H. M. Martin. VX11 ■\ study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the De - nt of Stein Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host: I. The [ the I'rediniospores of Puccinia Graminis Tritici Form III," L. Peltier. 1922. "Relation of Environment and Other Factors to Potato Wilt plum Oxysporum." by R. W. Goss. 1923. ( IH( ILAItS Measuring Silage and the Capacity of Silos," by L. W. Chase. Pump Irrigation in Nebraska," by E. E. Brackett and O. W. 1917. toling Tanks and Milk Houses as Factors in Cream Improve- I H Frandsen. 1917. Reprinted 1917 and 1919. Fork 'Production in Nebraska," by E. A. Burnett. 1917. From Car Door to Consumer," by H. C. Filley. 1918. Dairy Barn and Milk House Arrangement," by J. H. Frandsen W. B. Ne\ens. 1919 Outline of Object and Plan of the Nebraska National Egg Laying im. Revised August, 1920. ■•Purebred Sires Effect Herd Improvement," by M. N. Lawritson, J. \V. Hendrickson. and W. B. Nevens. 1919. S Marketing Nebrufca Potatoes." by J. O. Rankin. 1919. in "The Nebraska Tractor I.a\v and Rules for Official Tractor Tests," Hoard of Tractor 'IVst Engineers, L W. Chase, E. E. Brackett, and \V Sjo^ien. and Manager ol Tractor Tests. Claude K. Shedd. 19U. 11. "Strawberries in Nebraska," by C. C. Wiggans. 1920; reprinted V.i-22 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 12. "How to Select Good Layers," by Frank E. Mussehl. 1920; re - printed 1921. K13. "The Nebraska Tractor Law and Rules for Official Tractor Tests." Board of Tractor Test Engineers, O. W. Sjogren, E. E. Bracken, and W. Smith, and Acting Manager of Tractor Tests, F. R. Nohavec. 1921. 14. "Hog Houses for Nebraska," by 0. W. Sjogren and I. D. Wood 15. "Insect Pests of Stored Grains and Their Control," by M. H Swenk. 1922. 16. "The Preparation of Laboratory Specimens as an Aid to the Diagnosis of Animal Diseases," by L. Van Es and L. V. Skidmore. 1922. tl7. "The Common Intestinal Roundworni of Swine (Ascaris lum - )ides)," by H. M. Martin. 1922; revised 1923. K18. "100 Worth While Accomplishments of the College of Agriculture Past Two Years." 1922. (From 36th Annual Report.) 19. "State Wide Activities of the College of Agriculture." 192£ (From 36th Annual Report.) PltKSS IU U.KTINS 1. "Organization, Work, Bulletins, Press Bulletins." 18911 2. "Wheat Rust," by Charles E. Bessey. 1890. 3. "Suggestions in Regard to the Sugar Beet Culture," by H. II Nicholson, 1890. 4. "Indian Corn." by Jared U Smith. 1891 5. "Suggestions to Beet Growers." by Hudson H. Nicholson. 189 6. "The Fall Preparation of the Land for Sugar Beds," by T. L Lyon. 1895. 7. "Rainfall of Nebraska. Past and Present," by &lt;; 1&gt; Swezey. 18J 8. "The Fuel Value ol Corn." by T. L Lyon and C. R. Richards. 18S 9. "The Agricultural Students' Association and Its Co-Operative K perlments." 1898. 10. "Instructions for Beet Culture." 1898 11. "Raising Calves for Profitable Beef Production," by C. H dorf. 1899. 12. "Chinch Bug Inoculation." by Lawrence Bruner. 19&lt;"i. 13. "Extermination of Prairie Dogs," by A. T. Peters. KM. 14. "The Danger Limit In the Use of Sorghum." by T. L. Lyon. 1* 15. "Winter Wheat for Nebraska," by T. L Lyon. 1900. 16. "Alfalfa Experiences," by T. L. Lyon. 1902 L17. "Feeding Experiments with Hogs." by E. A. Burnett and H. K th. 1903. B18. "Pig Feeding Experiment at the Nebraska Experiment Station,' E. A. Burnett and H. R. Smith. 1903. 19. "The Hessian Fly," by Lawrence Bruner. 1904 "Fattening Pigs and Wintering Brood Sows on Alfalfa and a n Ration," by E. A. Burnett and H. R. Smith. 1904. 21. "A Good Oat for Nebraska," by T. L. Lyon. 1906. 12. "Malarial Fever in Horses," by A. T. Peters. 1&lt;U»6 23. "Ergot and Ergotism," by F. D. Heald and A T. IVters. UK 24. "The Bleaching of Wheat Flour." by F. J. Alway. 1907 25. "The Seed of Cheat, Meadow Fescue and Brome Grass," by F. D. Heald. 1907. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 89 i I 1 II I h ( 26. '■The Fat Testing of Cream," by A. L. Haecker and E. M. ittle. lltiiT 27. "Losses from Cornstalk Disease in Custer County, Nebraska. tiring the Winter of 1906-1907. " by F. J. Alway and A. T. Peters. 1908. 8. "Bunt, or Stinking Smut of Wheat," by F. D. Heald. 1908. M. "Pocket Gophers," by Lawrence Bruner. 1908. 0. "Rolling Winter Wheal," by E. G. Montgomery. 1909. 31. "Production of Hog Cholera Serum," by J. H. Gain. 1909. 32. "Testing Seed Corn," by E. G. Montgomery and C. W. Pugsley. 10. Revised. 1911 33. "Construction and Use of the Road Drag," by L. W. Chase. 1910. 34. "How to Combat the Melon Aphis." by M. H. Swenk. 1911. Jo. "Catch Crops for Hay and Pasture," by E. G. Montgomery. 1911. 36. "The Distribution and Use of Hog Cholera Serum," by J. H. Bin. 1911 37. "Spraying Apple Trees." Extension Bulletin No. 6. By R. P. oward. 1912. 38. "The Selection and Care of Seed Corn." Extension Bulletin No. 9. Krwin Hopt. 1912. 39. "Pasteurization of Milk and Cream in the Home," by J. H. rundsen. 1913. 4ii "Potato Pointers," by E. M. Wtlcox and R. A. Emerson. 1913. 41. "Evils of Premature Creameries." by J. H. Frandsen. 1913. 42. "Some Suggestions Regarding the Care of Milk and Cream in Home." by J. H. Frandsen. 1913. 43. "The Distribution and Use of Hog Cholera Serum," by J. H. ain and Fred E. Johnson. 1913. 44 "Suggestions for Dairy Farmers," by J. H. Frandsen. 1913. 45. "How to Combat the Hessian Fly." by M. H. Swenk. 1914. 46. "Alfalfa Mixtures for Silage." by Fred W. Upson. 1915. I'HKSS III II I IIW i lid I l.\ll KKRIKM 1. "How to Kill Grasshoppers," by' Lawrence Bruner. 1899. "The Fall Army Worm, or Grass Worm. (I,nphygma Iruyiprriln \), by W. D. Hunter. 1899. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 EXTENSION PUBLICATIONS 1. Alfalfa Management. (Also called Station Bulletin No. 1 1911. 2. Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska (Alas Balled Station I letin No. 122.) 1911. 3. The Germination Test for Seed Corn 1912 4. Nebraska Boys' and Girls' dabs: Cooking and Sewing. 1912 5. Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs: 1. Judging Horses and Oattl II. Corn; III. The Home Garden. 1912. 6. Spraying Apple Trees. (Also called Press Bulletin No. 37.) 1!»1 7. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. ( Als;&gt; called Station Bulletin N 131.) 1912. 8. Care of Milk and ("ream on the Farm. (Also railed Station I! letin No. 133.) 191 2. 9. The Selection and Care of S.-t-il Corn lAiso called Press Bullet No. 38.) 1912. 10. Organization •* Nebraska Boys' and (lirls' Clubs 191 11. Cooperative County Farm Demonstrator*. 1913. 12. Nebraska Hoys' Potato Clubs Growing Potal 13. Agricultural Extension Short Courses 1911. 14. The Climate of Nebraska. 1913. 15. A Course of Study for Home Economic* Cl 16. Nebraska Boys' and titrls' Clubs: Count l. Twelve Lea 17. Nebraska Bays' and Girls Course I. Tweh . l.t Foods and Their Preparation. 1913 18. Simple Water Supplier tor 19. Inexpensive Silos and sihi 20. Saving the Corn Crop. 191 21. Filling the Silo. 1913. 22. Sweet Clover in Nebraska. Farm 1!»1 Machinery. 1914 23. What Is a Farm Demonstrator' 1914 24. Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 1914. 25. The Babeoek Test and Its Vwt in Hen 26. Directory of Nebraska Dairy CatUs lit 27. First Annual Report of County Cooper Work. January 1, 1914 28. Feeding Alfalfa to Horses. 1M14 29. Pruning Trees. Vines, and Shrubs 191 30. Neglected Orchards and Their Care 11 31. Cooperation. 1915. 32. Lunches for the Rural School. 191 33. Use of Hog Cholera Serum. 1915. 34. Second Annual Report of County Agricultural Ag«-nt Work 35. Woodworking Exercises for Home and School. 191 36. Rural Clubs for Women. 1915. 37. Short Courses, or Extension Schools in Ajrricnltur Economics. 1916. Hi,! 38. The Marketing of Mixed Grains 191&lt; 39. Pit. Semi-Pit, and Dank BUos. 1917 40. Wooden Silos Ised in Nebraska. 1917 41. The Farm Inventory. 1917. Sewing. 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 91 Vocational Education— IU Relation to School Gardening. 1917. 43. The Home-School Garden; The Nebraska Plan for School-Garden Home 1917 Her Own Merit: I. Individual Records; II. Co- rative Cow Testini: Associations; III. Junior Cow-Testing Clubs. 1917. A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard. 1918 Home Vegetable Gardening. 1918. Raising Dairy Calves. 1918 I'ork and Beef. 1918. A Housr&gt; for the Farm Poultry Flock. 1919 Standard Bred Poultry Pays. 1919. ■MM Factors Affecting the Cost of Milk Production. 1919. Dig lp I lie Barberry and Control Wheat Rust. 1919. A Several-Purpose Poultry House. 1919. ISacillary White Diarrhea in Chicks. 1920. Tin Kss.ntials of Blackleg Prevention. 1920 The Convenient Kitchen. 192" Synopsis of the Disease of Swine. 1920 Ksiablishing Hie Home Orchard. 19:'n. Tuberculosis in Poultry. 1921. ooperalive Klevators. 1921 lli.u to Select the Good Layers. IM1 The Payer Dress Form. 1921. KXTKNSION l»l lil.K ATIONS 1 (New Numbering) tern for Extension Specialists ted F'reniiuni List for County Fairs \ssembling and Judging Household Exhibits at County Fair: Community stock Pavilion Associations. Disinfection and Disinfectants Nebraska Birds and How to Know Them Climate of Nebraska. Meadows and Pastures. Pasture Crops. What to Plant Judging Oats. I Judging Wheat 5. Judging Barley H Judging Corn. 1 o7. Sweet Clover, los. Certified Seed. 1"9. Black Stem Ru llo. ('-real Smuts and Their Control 111. Growing Soy Beans in Corn in Eastern Nebraska iHimlM-'in^ rTtenninn publications whs introduced. Each liartirulm snap "f bulletins. This list includes rtvi«in— imlM ml mimi'riuraphe.l publications. Handling Silage. 1917 Feeding I&gt;air&gt; Cows. 1!M7 Farm PIiimii Mat It 1M17 Well-PlaniMd Meals. 1917. Ix.th </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Station I 112 Milling Qualities of Kanred Wheat. Seed Treatment for Stinking Smut. Nebraska Weeds. 113 114. 120. Wheat in Nebraska. Soybeans in Nebraska. Swtet Clover in Nebraska. 121. 122. 201. The Ewe at Lambing Time. The Sow at Farrowing Time The Sow and Her Litter. 202. 203. 204. Pigs on Pasture. 205. Common Hog Diseases Handling Wool. 206. 207. Market Ewes. 208. Judging Mutton Breeding BhMf Judging Beef Breeding Cattle. Judging Breeding Bag*. 209. 210. 211. Judging Draft Horses. Judging Mutton Sheep Jaigtag Fat Hogs. Judging Fat Steers. 212. :il3. 214. 215. The Lamb in the Farm Fteck Tanning Hides. 216. 217. A System of Eradicating Intestinal Worms in I Making Alum Tanned Lace Leather. 218. 219. Making Bark Tanned Sole and Harness Leather Making Chrome Tanned Leather. 220. 221. Some Important Factors in I're\ entiim if Swin Sanitation in Pig Raising. 222. 223. Treatment of Hog Cholera 224. Synopsis of the Diseases of Swim Bull-nose in Pigs. 225. 401. Fabrics — How to Know and Use Fabrics — How to Buy Them. Fabrics — How to Care for Then Designing of Clothing. 402. 403. 404. 405. Clothing Conservation. Sewing Equipment. Alteration of Patterns Color in Clothing. 406. 407. Mt, 409. Planning an Economical Wanlrolx Uses for Old Clothes. 410. 411. Economy in Buying. Economy in Footwear. Score Card for Sewing. Selection of Clothing. Making Sewing Easier. 412. 414. 415 416. 417. Dressing Stout and Slender Women. Attractive House Dresses and Aprons Clothes for High School Graduate. Millinery — Frame Coverings. 418 419. 431 £ General Picnic Suggestions Old Settlers' Program. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 93 Rural School Play Day. Better Livestock Program. ".IH Judging Dairy Cows What is a Cow Testing Association? Price List of Stock Blue Prints. Oils and Oiling Systems. Sewage Disposal for Farm Homes. Tractor Plowing Demonstrations. "t The "Midwest" Four Horse Sweep and Stacker The "Midwesf Branding and Dehorning Chute Kxercises in Forge Work and Carpentry. South Facing Colony Hog House 08 The Sanitary Privv 71 North and South Colony Hog House. Picric Acid— An Agricultural Explosive Pit, Semi-Pit, and Hank Silos Are You Studying Your Farm Business? Labor Requirements for Nebraska Crops Share-Cash Farm Lease. t Stock Share Lease Vegetables Mineral Content of Vegetables Meats. &gt; Quick Breads Yeast Breads reals Beverages Milk and Milk Products Eggs. Honev orn and Corn Products as Food, lassification of Foods. Homemade Chee Poultry. Hominy Emergency Meals. Whole Wheat Flour for White Flour. How &gt;w to Substitute Other Foods for Meat onomy in the Use of Fat*. Food Score Card. Sugar Conservation Christmas Cakes and Candies Pinto Beans. 928 Salads Potatoes as a Food Quick Breads. 93(1 »31 I lessens hool Lunches Use of Dried Fruits and Vegetables. I'se ol Rope on the Farm </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 934. Doughnuts, Pies and Cookies 935. Woman's Part in Home Butchering Making the Most of the Meal Hour 951. 952 Plan Your Meals 953 Menus Illustrating Variety &gt;f I m of Foods I'n &lt;1 954. The Buffet Luncheon 955. Invalid Cookery 956. Digestion. 957. Mineral Matter m Poods 959. Feeding of Children 960. Old Fallacies and New Idea? ItfKarriinu r'o 961 Food and Its Relation to II. alth 962 Menus for Banquets 963 Breakfast Menus 964. Hot Lunches for Hural School* 965 Childhood Malnutrition 966 Correction and Prevention 967 Caloric Estimates for thf r Wins Child 968. Food for Children from 9 to 14 Years 981 Egg Preservatio 982 Jelly Making 983. Questions ami Answers on Canni 984 Pickles and Relisl 985 Time Tahle for Cai 986 Drying of Vegetable 987 Saving Sugar in Canni !&gt;ss Vegetable and Fr Mill Aids in Honu- Nursi Mother and Baby Home Sanitation. ](MI- 1003 10(14 Health Habit.- for Hum. K. Home Care of the Sick Making the Patient Comfort Emergency Treatments 1011.1 10(16 1101 Budgets and Household Ai.oui Egg and Poultry Records Precautions with Canned Good (Number changed to MM). Household Account Form. Control of Household IVst? - (Number changed io MM). Home Making— A Profession Business Side of Housekeeping Marketing. 1102 1103 1104. 1105 1106 1107. 1108 1109 1110 1111 Cause and Prevention oi Hni Care of the House. 1112. 1114 Music, Reading and Pictures. Time and Labor Saving Devices. The Home Maker's Duty as a Citizen Soapmaking. 1115 1116 1117 it Malnuiriti( 1007. Emergency Treat i 1008. Prevention of I&gt;is&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Thirty-Sixth Annual Report 95 1118. Wliat Women Should Know About Business Affairs. I in. i lit- Nate litxik Habit by Fanners' Wives. Homemade Firelcss Cooker Homemade Tea WaKon. Homemade Iceiess Refrigerator Built-in Ironing Hoard. w I' Homemade Fly Tr The Mullen Drier olor and Design rnitur Block Printitif; t ion in House Furnishing Vrrangeinent of Furniture Number chanaed to IlMii) lie House. &gt;nsl ruction nd Tlieir Arrangement md Ventilation i Storage in Western Nebraska. Improvement by Hill Selection. II Nebraska Potatoes to Control Dry Rot ■eel Treatment. ■ed Considerations lor a Vacant Lot Garden Home Garden Hotbed. Farm Garden ■ and Preparation of Potatoes for Exhibition. Planting Table. Bluff County Seed Potatoes Ins Apples. Cherries and Plum KstablishitiK the Home Orchard. Mawirit "it" Home Orchard. inn the Home Grounds. )rnaniental and Forest Planting Material. Dist. 1 &gt;rnauiental and Forest Planting Material, Dist. 2 J4 tal and Forest Planting Material. Dist 44 Ornamental and Forest Planting Material, Dist. 4. 4:",. Ornamental and Forest Planting Material. Dist. 5. -47 Planting Kvergreen Trees in Nebraska. 248. Preservative Treatment of Fence Posts. M*. Fall Planting of Bulbs for Spring Bloom Clan for a Back Yard Garden Grapes L'46 Roses for Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 1251. Perennials for Hist. 1. Perennials for Dist. 2. Perennials for Dist. 3. Perennials for Dist. 4. Perennials for Dist. 5. 1252. 1253 1254. 1255 1301. Trade Terms Used in Fruit Articles and By-Laws for a Articles and By-Laws for a and Yegplabl 1302. Cooperative UN. Cooper Association. Baby Chicks— Their Care and Feed Cooperative Egg Circle. 1401. 1402 1403. Incubation Pointers 1404. Preserve Eggs for Home Use Confine the Cockerel. 1405. 1406. Poultry Disease Problen Dry Mash Rations. 1407. MM Pointers on Culling 1409. Appearance of Eggs on Candlin Feed Dry Masli. 1410. 1411 Graded Eggs Brine Better Prk Fowl Cholera 1412. 1413. Essentials of Poultry Hygiene. Tuberculosis in Poultry. How to Select the Good Layers Judging S. C White Leghorns Judging White Plymouth Rocks Judging White Wyandottes. 1415. 1416 1421. 1422 1423. 1424 Judging Buff Orpingtons 1425. Judging Barred Plymouth Rock Judging S. C. Rhode Island Km 1426. 1501. Destroying Pocket Gophers Directions for Poisoning Prairie I Directions for Poisoning K;its </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>