<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Vitamin E Content of Certain Dairy Feeds</title>
               <date value="1934-08">1934-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE t OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 73 The Vitamin E Content of Certain Dairy Feeds I. L. HATHAWAY AN.i H. P. DAVIS Department of Dairy Husbandry LINCOLN, NEBRASKA AUGUST, 1934 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SU MMARY A study was made of the vitair in E content of each of the ingredients of our dairy herd ration, excepting the salt," lime, and bone meal. Fe - male rats which were able to con :eive but unable to reproduce when fed a diet deficient in vitamin E weie fed the various feeds as a source of vitamin E during a second breed ng period. The presence of vitamin E in a feed was thus shown by th« ability of the female to cast a litter. The vitamin E content of bran, shorts, linseed oil meal, hominy feed, white corn, yellow corn, cottonseed meal, kafir, beet pulp, corn gluten feed, corn gluten meal, and alfalfa was examined. Twenty to twenty - five per cent of the bran, shorts, linseed oil meal, hominy feed, white corn, yellow corn, cottonseed meil, kafir, or alfalfa furnished sufficient vitamin E to ailow the rats to cast litters. On the other hand, forty per cent of the corn gluten meal the corn gluten feed, or the beet pulp furnished very little vitamin E. There was no significant difference in the vitamin E content of the white and yellow corn used. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">The Vitamin E Content of Certain Dairy Feeds I. L. HATHAWAY AND H. P. DAVIS Difficulties in breeding with the dairy herd at the Univer - sity of Nebraska have been experienced to a greater or less degree for nearly a third of a century. It is well known that there are many factors which lead to delayed pregnancy. The studies of Evans and Bishop (3), of Sure (11), and of Mattill and Stone (10), which have since been confirmed by many investigators, showed that rats are unable to repro - duce if maintained on a diet deficient in vitamin E. Although it has been assumed by many that dairy cattle require vitamin E for reproduction, as far as the writers are aware there have been no scientific investigations which have yet estab - lished this fact. In order, to obtain some idea of the occur - rence of vitamin E in our dairy herd ration and to obtain in - formation which might serve as a foundation for studies of the vitamin E requirements of dairy cows, a study was made of the vitamin E content of each of the ingredients of the herd ration, excepting the salt, lime, and bone meal. REVIEW OF LITERATURE A review of the literature pertaining to diet and sterility has been prepared by Kennedy (7), and Evans (2) recently reviewed the literature regarding vitamin E. Only material pertinent to our experiments is presented here. Evans and Burr (4) reported that vitamin E was present in animal tissues, bananas, lettuce, tea, peas, cotton, oats, corn, wheat, and alfalfa but was not found in abundant quantities in butter, Crisco, walnut oil, or cod-liver oil. Sure (12) studied the distribution of vitamin E in a number of oils and feed materials. He found this vitamin in olive, peanut, soy-bean, peach-kernel, palm, cottonseed, wheat, and corn oil. Linseed, cocoanut, sesame, palm-kernel, rape-seed, mustard-seed, and commercial corn oil (Mazola) and oil of sweet almonds were found deficient in antisterility properties. Kennedy (8) re - ported that crushed oats contain vitamin E. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE The dairy herd ration was composed as follows : Dairy Herd Ration Corn 200 lbs. Beet pulp 100 lbs. Oats 200 lbs. Cottonseed meal 50 lbs. Bran 150 lbs. Salt 10 lbs. Hominy 50 lbs. Lime 10 lbs. Linseed oil meal 50 lbs. Bone meal 5 lbs. Gluten feed 100 lbs. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 73 The average daily feed consumption per cow was approxi - mately 20 to 25 pounds of silage, 5 to 20 pounds of the grain mixture and 20 pounds of alfalfa hay. The management of the rat colony was essentially the same as that outlined by Davis *nd Hathaway (1) except where otherwise indicated. The b *eeding stock was maintained on the Steenbock Stock Ration, composed as follows: Stocl: Ration 1 Yellow corn 76.00} Ground alfalfa 2.0 r /, Linseed oil meal 16.0/% Sodium chloride 0.59^ Crude casein 5.0% Calcium carbonate 0.5 r A The materials were finely ground and then 5 per cent by weight of butter was addec . In addition to this ration the animals received lettuce several times each week. The rats used in these experiments were pied rats reared in our own laboratory. Fenale rats 24 to 28 days old, and weighing from 40 to 50 grams, were placed on a vitamin E deficient ration similar to that employed by Evans and Burr (5). This ration was composed as follows: Vitamin E Deficient Ration Casein i 16% Yeast ■• W/ r Corn starch 2 40% Cod-liver oil B 1 2% Lard* 22i% Salts (McCollum No. 185).... 4&lt;?f&gt; This ration has been fen to 225 females at this Station and in no instance has initial fertility been encountered. Evans and Burr (5) obtained only four cases of initial fertil - ity when a similar ration was fed to 200 females. The females were maintai ned on this ration until they were 90 to 120 days old and then mated for a period of 15 days to stock males previously shown to be fei'tile by matings with stock females. Each female was weighed three times per week during this period of mating and until 21 days after separation from the males. During this period of mating as well as during the second mating period the males were allowed only the feed allotted to the females. Only those females which showed reso:*ption of a fetus as evidenced by ■Purified casein (No. 453) was pur shaped from the Casein Comnany of America. Now York City. It was extracted continuously for five days with 95 per cent ethyl alcohol. 'Powdered starch was obtained from (he Corn Products Refininc Company. New York City. "Star Lard was purchased locally fr &gt;m -Armour &amp; Company. 1 Compressed yeast was furnished thr &gt;UKh the courtesy of the Standard Brands, Inc. It. was dried in a current of air at room temperature, finely eround, and fed without further treatment. * Standardized cod-liver oil from Meac , Johnson &amp; Company, Evansville, Indiana, was Used. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Vitamin E Content op Dairy Feeds their weight curve were used for the vitamin E tests. The weight curve of the pregnant female on a normal ration gen - erally shows a steady rise until parturition, at which time there is a precipitous fall in the curve. On the other hand the weight curve of the pregnant female on a vitamin E deficient ration shows a steady rise until about the fourteenth day. From this time on there is a gradual diminution in weight and the period of gestation passes without a litter being cast. During this selection 27 females were discarded, as it was not evident from the weight curve whether or not they had re - sorbed a fetus. Beginning with the twenty-second day after the males were removed from the females, the various feeds were incorpor - ated into the vitamin E deficient ration. This was accom - plished by replacing a portion of the corn starch with an equal quantity of the finely ground feed. After the females had been on the supplemented ration for four days they were again mated. During this second gestation period the females were weighed daily and watched closely to detect parturition. As our cages were not equipped with any special device, such as the one described by Long and Evans (9), for determining the number of young dropped, our counts may not be accurate since some pups are at times devoured by the mother shortly after birth. In six cases it was not possible to determine whether a litter had been dropped or a resorption had taken place. These cases, therefore, were not considered in the tabulations. The results obtained are shown in Table 1. Since previous studies from this laboratory (6) showed that 20 per cent of alfalfa as a source of vitamin E resulted in good reproduc - tion, the group of rats receiving 20 per cent of ground alfalfa was included in these experiments as a positive control group. The negative control group received only the vitamin E deficient ration. Since none of the females used in these studies dropped a litter during the first gestation period, it was evident that the basal ration was deficient with respect to vitamin E and therefore only three females were allotted to the negative control group. The bran and shorts were fed at 20 per cent levels, while the linseed oil meal, hominy feed, white corn, cottonseed meal, kafir, and yellow corn were fed at 25 per cent levels. Since this vitamin is a fat-soluble one and since the corn gluten meal, the corn gluten feed, and the beet pulp contained only from 0.5 to 1 per cent of fat, according to the manufacturers' analysis, these feeds were fed at 40 per cent levels. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Exp. Sta]. Research Bulletin 73 Table 1. — Summary of the number of litters dropped by rats fed various feeds as sources of vitamin E „ _ TJo««l« Females Litters Resorp- Younir Source of vitamin E i^evras Jn Broup dropped t!ons dropped P.ct. No. No. No. No. Alfalfa (ground) 20 18 18 0 132 Bran (wheat) 20 19 18 1 168 Shorts (wheat) 20 20 18 2 181 Linseed oil meal 25 20 19 1 185 Hominy feed (white)......... 25 17 16 1 129 Corn (white) (Iowa Silvermine) 25 19 19 0 168 Cottonseed meal 25 20 19 1 156 Kafir (red) 25 20 20 0 166 Corn (yellow) (Cattle corn) 25 19 17 2 160 Beet pulp 40 19 2 17 12 Corn gluten feed 40 18 1 17 10 Corn gluten meal 40 18 0 18 0 Vitamin E deficient ration 00 3 0 3 0 It will be noted that ea:h of the females in the alfalfa, white-corn, and kafir groups produced a litter and that all of the females, excepting one, in each of the bran, linseed - oil-meal, hominy-feed, and cottonseed-oil-meal groups pro - duced litters. All of the females, excepting two, in each of the shorts and yellow-corn groups produced litters. On the other hand, no litters were produced in either the corn-gluten-meal or the vitamin-E-deficient-r; ition groups, only one litter in the corn-gluten-feed group and only two litters in the beet-pulp group. Since practically all of the females in the alfalfa, bran, shorts, linseed-oil-meal, hominy-feed, white-corn, cotton - seed-meal, kafir, and yellow-corn groups produced litters, it is evident that these amounts of these feeds furnished suffi - cient vitamin E for reproduction in rats. The results obtained with the pure strains of white and yellow corn indicate that vitamin E, unlike vitamin A, occurs in white as well as in yellow corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Vitamin E Content of Dairy Feeds LITERATURE CITED 1. Davis, H. P., and Hathaway, I. L. 1931. The Vitamin A Content op the Milk of Holstein Ayr shire^ Jersey, and Guernsey Cows... Nebr. aJ£ Exp. s£ 2. Evans, H. M. 1932. Vitamin E. Jour. Amer. Med. Assoc, 99:469-475 3. Evans, H. M., and Bishop, K. S. 1932. On the Existence of a Hitherto Unrecognized Factor Essential for Reproduction. Science, 56:650-651 4. Evans, H. M., and Burr, G. O. 1925 ' ?9^56-36 T l ON ° F VlTAM1N X IN NAT URAL Foods. Anat. Rec, 5. Evans, H. M., and Burr, G. O. 1927. Vitamin E— The Ineffectiveness of Curative Dosage when Mixed with Diets Containing High Proportions of Certain l 1 ats. Jour. Amer. Med. Assoc, 88:1462-1465. 6 ' ?o^ a m ay ' jj L&gt;&gt; Davis ' H - P -' and Graves, R. R. 1932. The Vitamin A and the Vitamin E Content of Field- Exrsta N R D es A BT c 6 rjp. sr alfalfa hay - Nebr-Agr - 7. Kennedy, W. P. 1926. Diet and Sterility. Physiol. Rev., 6:485-503 8. Kennedy, W. P. 1926. Reproduction and Diet in the Rat. Quart. Jour. Exp. 9. Long, J. A., and Evans, H. M. 1922. The Oestrous Cycle in the Rat and Its Associated Phenomena. Uni. of Cal. Memoir, 6:15. 10. Mattill, H., and Stone, N. C. 1923. The Nutritive Properties of Milk with Special Reference I? ?fo P^rr UCTION IN THE Albino Rat— II. Jour. Biol. Chem., oo:44t&gt;-455. 11. Sure, B. 1924. Dietary Requirements for Reproduction — II, The Exist - ence of a Specific Vitamin for Reproduction. Jour. Biol. Chem., 58:693-701. 12. Sure, B. 1926. Dietary Requirements for Reproduction— V, The Role of Various Vegetable and Fruit Oils in Fertility and Lacta - tion. Jour. Biol. Chem., 69:29-40. [8U] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>