<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00035">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0035</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Control of Stored Grain Pests in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">April 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Control of Stored Grain Pests In Nebraska Circular 62 April 1940 University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station Lincoln, Nebraska W. W. Burr. Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Kinds ot Stored Grain Insects 3 How Grain Becomes Infested 5 Prevention of Infestation 6 Heating and Insect Infestation 7 Fumigation 7 Carbon Bisulphide 9 Mixture of Ethylene Dichloride and Carbon Tetrachloride 10 Determining the Amount to Use 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Control of Stored Grain Pests In Nebraska MYRON H. SWENK AND DON B. WHELAN Department of Entomology ¦jVTEBRASKA FARMERS, are well aware that the warfare against -* destructive insects is not ended when their grain is in the bin. The garnered crops become immediately, subject to attack by various insect pests of stored grain, commonly called "weevils." The loss from this attack becomes of special seriousness when unusually large stocks of grain are being held in the granaries and cribs on the farm and in warehouses. More or less at all times, but especially during periods when grain prices are low, it may be found advantageous to store the grain for an advance in price or for later feeding at home. Also, in taking advantage of recently enacted laws, the tendency is to hold grain in storage for a longer time than formerly. At the close of 1939 about twice the amount of wheat was in storage in Nebraska as compared to the dose of 1938. Frequently a new crop of grain goes into storage before the preceding older grain leaves the farm, and, due to inadequate storage space, the crops are not kept separated, thus promoting an early infestation of the new grain from the older grain that has become infested. Under such conditions the dam - age by stored grain pests becomes a matter of unusual importance. KINDS OF STORED GRAIN INSECTS In Nebraska there are nearly 30 kinds of insects that injure stored grain more or less. Some are beetles and their larvae, others are the cater - pillars of moths. To farmers and grain men most of these are dubbed "weevil," although that name is properly to be applied only to two kinds of beetles, the true granary weevil and the rice or black weevil. These are both snout-beetles, having the head prolonged beneath into a long snout or beak. The other species of beetles principally concerned are often called "bran bugs," and include the following: the cadelle; the. saw-toothed, the square - necked, the foreign, the flat, and the two-banded grain beetles; the confused, the rust-red, the black, the small-eyed, and the broad-horned flour beetles; the yellow, the dark and the lesser meal worms; the drug store beede; the "tow bug" or cigarette beetle; and the common, the black, and the varied carpet beetles.: The moths principally concerned are the Angoumois grain moth, Indian meal moth, meal snout moth, sorghum seed moth, and Mediterranean flour moth. v ¦ . The true granary weevil and the rice or black weevil are probably the most destructive of all the beetles infesting stored grain in Nebraska. The granary weevil is a shiny, dark brown to blackish snout-beetle, about one - sixth of an inch long, with spaced elongate punctures, arranged in rows, on its thorax (Fig. 1, c). It cannot fly, so does not infest grain in the field. The rice weevil is a dull brownish to blackish weevil of the same size and gen - eral appearance as the granary weevil, but usually with four light reddish or yellowish spots on the wing-covers and with dense, rounded punctures, not arranged in rows, on the thorax (Fig. 1, c). The adults of this species </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 62 readily fly from old infested grain to new grain in bins or standing grain in the field. Both of these weevils develop inside the grain and attack , , \jCd not on^ l^e sma^ grams an(^ corn t f but also various other kinds of seeds. /Wsmr V The several other species of /M^Wi beetles and their larvae that are J^^bf r A found in stored grain for the most *~^ {/ ly P art eet^ uPon broken grains. Somc - jL~ ¥&gt;~ &lt;sM&amp; 'imes feeQl within the punctures fc^frfKSlK^fck^l. 'Wra] produced by weevils. Mill and ele - r^^^ffifKlpHß^V nfr vator men usually refer to them as c The adult cadelle is a black, flat - i tish beetle about one-third of an inch F,c. I.—The grain weevils {sUophi- i ong that can hart u y mistaken for Jus)'¦ c the true granary weevil (5. r i i . j &lt; ¦ .» J»i) C nlar gc a abouV fix. natural ™V StOted S"" 1 size at side; c, the rice weevil (s. ory- (Fig. 2, a). The mature larvae are zae), same; a, larva, enlarged about broad and flattish, about three - 4x; b, pupa, same. (From Packard, fourths of an inch long, whitish 18 ' in general color, with the head, some marks on the thorax, and the rear segment black, the latter ending in two sharp, horny points (Fig. 2, b). The larvae of this insect are probably more commonly no- AY need than those of any BP^il other of the stored SrThe "auir^meal CH^?*^ S^W worms are dark brown __jHji!L to black beetles about JjßtL l^^^V^ five-eighths of an inch —^T^lL A larvae are either waxy '**"'\l^^^Bf — X§TOjt I yellow or brownish in ~~^te~-^M-^ I color, about an inch /Tl BtV Jv^ij^M I long when fully grown, Jf ifl I%w U&amp;_"#*-_ 1 with hard wire-like |fl H ~~~jF&gt;^&amp;!l bodies, which makes Jil Kk ' "p^Zjji-— - -them resemble wire- /H II ~~^P?~s3m worms (Fig. 3, a). The /II I%y B&amp;Z&amp;F various species of grain Wff beetles (Fig. 4) and flour beetles (Fig. 5) a '^9m[ * are smaller than the /yvT''\ cadelle or meal worms, Fie 2 _ Th( . adMl . {Tm&lt;;broiics natilitanicus ).. c , and are not so easily a du)r beetle, enlarged sx; i, larva, enlarged ix. (From distinguished from each Chittendcn, 1896.) other. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Stoked Grain Pests &lt;jjgjnggJ3H3J&amp;^ The Angoumois grain moth is a light grayish '"% w.~/2Lk brown °r bulffsr nlottled moth. with narrow, pointed N \W'/^"(^MkJ and nnged wings having an expanse of about Ywyi T J«| one-half inch (Fig. 6, c). Its larvae feed within the &amp; 4ffls gra «w» hollowing them out as they grow (Fig. 6, /^M\? «£? f' i^ey work commonly in ear corn, boring ¦/^^V- js3 into the grains and filling them widi holes (Fig. Flo." 3—The dark c a^t Indian meal moth has wings of two meal worm (Jenebrio colors, their basal third being grayish and their obsctmu):a, mca\ worm, outer two-thirds a reddish brown with a coppery fit ££ *S l*^ ?e^ nSe »-ly three-fourths of an rf, c, /, g, A. antenna men (Flg- °, c). The larvae are one of the more and mouth parts of meal common species found in grain or shelled corn oS$: r h LeenK f ere feed "P° n o"*™' «-k»w&gt; 1874.) for seeding purposes (Fig. 8, a). As the nearly mature larvae move over the surface of the grains they spin a web, until in some cases a tough, dirty, silken blanket is formed. The Mediterranean flour moth is more common in flour mills than in stored grain (Fig. 9). : Psocids, or book lice, are tiny, pale, soft-bodied, louse-like chewing insects about one thirty-second of an inch long that often occur in stored grain. Mites that infest stored grain are almost micro- js scopic:in size but about the same color as the psocids. They are seldom seen by the farmer or elevator man. \^B}h} While psocids infrequendy are of economic importance, \ iSs/h 3 mites may become so numerous as to render the erain i fee i '¦ '.¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ • I t^J»X unfit for food. am/mm*. HOW GRAIN BECOMES INFESTED Jpt:\V Infestations by the rice or black weevil and An- ' r wlw-|\ goumois grain moth may start with eggs being laid in the field. The adults of these two stored grain pests can Fio. 4. The fly freely from place to place. But usually the infestation «aw-toothcd grain starts in the bin, and frequently is due to the storing of tle Jo^"^ grain in bins that were infested previously. Original in-.... w), enlarged about festations occur through the introduction of infested 8x- (From Brunei-, grain from some other place, or by the pests entering the ; IB'3^ bin after grain has been placed in it. Infested mill feed and chicken feed in storage also start infestations. After the new grain is placed in a previously infested bin, or the insects find the grain, their increase is rapid. A single female beetle or moth may lay from 50 to 200 or 300 eggs. Some kinds require a year for a </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 62 v-. jm generation, while others require only a few \j Q f xO^f, weeks for a generation in the warmer part of a * *»-•. the year, and develop as many as six generations c?|la| J I annually. Rapid increase is often augmented y \jj &gt;¦ 1 y&amp;.' during the colder months by the natural heat - • . ing of the grain which results from excessive v^ 7 "feS' moisture content, and in this way the pests \) sometimes breed continuously through the year. F.c. 5 -The confused PREVENTION OF INFESTATION flour beetle (Tribolium conjusum): a, beetle; A, It is very important that new grain should larva — enlarged about (^ p[ acec i ) whenever possible, in thoroughly ¦Ix; r. outline side view 1 ¦ ¦ L ¦ 1 l • v xt of tip of abdomen of clean bins in whlch thf re wno ol&lt;? Bram- New larvae—much enlarged. grain should be put in empty bins that have (From Bruncr, 1893.) been cleaned and made as nearly air-tight as possible. In cleaning a bin, preparatory to put - ing new grain in it, it should first be swept thoroughly to get rid of all the grain dust and trash that have accumulated on the floor or in the cracks, crevices and burrows in the woodwork of the bins. These sweep - ings should be re - v moved and burned immediately. They should never be *j7 fr j simply thrown out, ynf^^ 4&amp; because the P ests ¦* QB e \»y: sP rayedor scrub - w NJi bed with some dis- Fig. 6-The Angoumois grain moth (Silotroga infesting liquid that cerealella): a. caterpillar, b, pupa, c, moth, d, wing Will not impart an of a paler form—enlarged about l'/ix; c, egg, g, odor to the Stored labial palpus of male moth, h, last segment of pupa Stain The Illinois —much enlarged; /, orain of corn cut open to show f! . ' , larva at work-natural size. (From Riley, 188-1.) Station has recom - mended a mixture of one gallon of miscible oil (such as is used for spraying dormant trees), three ounces of lye, and nine gallons of water, to make ten gallons of a spray, which is sufficient quantity to cover about 500 square feet of bin surface. Scrubbing the bin thoroughly with boiling hot lye water made by dissolving a pound of crystal lye to each gallon of boiling water, and working this solution into the cracks of the floor and the walls of wooden bins has also proved satisfactory. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Stored Grain Pests Wooden bins usually are not very tight, so *^rf^. where damage by stored grain pests is antici- fMU^^k pated and before the grain is put in, the floors and walls of the bin should be lined with build- ing paper or with several thicknesses of news- P^BH|ys'i*iK paper overlapped at the edges. Then if and when pests later appear in the grain stored in the bin, a J^^^SSSld?^ successful fumigation can be made with mini- mum trouble and cost. Stored grain should be in- "'ffiffiflflfczY? spected in the fall and subsequently once a month H3W?Ej&lt;*vi) during the warm weather of the following year BBkautm^^i to detect the presence of insect pests, and grain SJ^i^xVW, found to be seriously infested should be fumi- flßjJF^hr^^ HEATING AND INSECT INFESTATION jHpl£H!?»^W Heating of stored grain may be caused^ by JfisEHsr^lrX JJ too much moisture in the grain, and is often &amp;EE2 ":-"4L£]fJ*&amp; accompanied by stored grain pests developing MHbEI *-*&amp;y gM in it. Stored grain containing not over 14 per wßH^i« »~ySDtip cent of moisture is regarded as safe under all or- Wl^ Si&gt;^ "^ dinary temperature conditions. At tempera- iS2^ hires not higher than 70° F., the grain may J^J^^^^W safely contain 15 per cent of moisture, and 16 i^^BT^S^Cfcfl per cent at temperatures not higher than 60° F. H^&amp;l^tE*T\ If corn containing 17 per cent or more of mois- SMp^t^*r~^^\ ture is cribbed, it is saved from spoiling only JB^KStS-*%?kl by the low winter temperatures, and it may dry HB^J^tlsJal out sufficiently during I the winter so that when |^BBlEi§l-*23') the weadier warms again in the spring it will *'"*\*Jjffi be safe; otherwise theije is danger of spoilage in fl^S^-j^Q-^ the spring. Fumigation will not prevent nor H^^^SSiJSLSa/ stop heating of the grain if it contains an ex- cess of: moisture, but if the grain has been dried f^^^^OJlir^ thoroughly before storing, and heating due to WWHP^MM? insect pests breeding in it develops, fumigation will promptly stop the heating. . Fumigation is the standard method of con- vHttf trolling stored grain pests, and consists of apply- ing some chemical in liquid form and allowing Fie 7.—Ear of pop it to vaporize into a heavy, penetrating, insect- «&gt;rn showing work of killing gas which poisons or asphyxiates the fS Ri^T^ T*' insects. For the successful fumigation of a bin ' Y&gt; Sl) </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 62 of infested grain, a fumigant must be used the vapor of which is sufficiently heavy and penetrating to reach the pests well below the surface of the grain, and sufficiently poisonous quickly to kill all insect life with which moderate concentrations of the vapor come into contact. The ideal fumigant would be one diat does not injure the germination or palatability of the fumi - o* gated grain nor objectionably affect the bak - -^^^&gt;~-^a^--^^^^^ ing quality of the flour made from the treated grain. Also this fumigant should '^^rlil^^' readily form a non-inflammable and non-ex - rti^sljm^^^^ plosive gas that is not disagreeable or danger - fWi ' / \ TnrJSE?)^ ous to *^c °P erator &gt; an^ should be com- U|B | I'T'jl^m' merc'al'y available at a reasonable cost. ffl | «3?*S?r In fumigating stored grain with heavier - %s¦ '\*rfT%WtinrJ?~ than-air gases, there are certain requirements V /fossss'r£s!s3k that must be met if satisfactory results are r. o ~ n a ~i j- , to be secured. The bin must be made as Fig B.—The Indian meal .... ...,_. , moth (Plodia intcrpuncttlla): nearl V ™*&amp;l as possible. These heavy a, caterpillar; b, pupa-, c, adult vapors are very penetrative, and unless the moth—enlarged about 2'Ax; bin is quite tight they will seep out and the d, head and thorax of cater- effects q£ fumigation w ;u l arge l y be lost, pillar—much enlarged. (From ft. n • • l Riley and Howard, 1889.) The ordinary wooden bm usually is not tight enough without some special preparation. When it is lined with paper, as previously mentioned, it is ready for fumi - gation. Any crack allows the gas to escape, and the more that escapes the less effective the fumi- » constructed, leaky grain W^^^ 'iS* the fumigation of that \ \ &gt; grain will not be success- pic. 9.—The Mediterranean flour moth (Epheslia fill in killing the pests, kuehnulla): a, caterpillar; b, pupa; c and /, adult moth No fumigation should —enlarged 2x; i, head and thorax of caterpillar; ,r,ab - , j j dominal segments of same^ —much enlarged. (From Riley be attempted under and Howard _ 1889} such conditions. Tem - peratures of 70° F. or over usually permit successful fumigation, but the ideal temperatures of the grain for fumigation are 80° to 90° F. Where the temperature is less than 80° F.. the amount of the fumigant used must </seg>
         <seg id="p009">. . Stored Grain Pests be increased. In general, the higher the temperature the more rapid the evaporation and the penetration of the fumigant, the more the air will take up the vapor before becoming saturated with it, and the more readily the insects will succumb to the effects of the vapor because of their more rapid breathing. Another point is that the grain must be dry if the fumigation is to be satisfactory. Lastly, the fumigation should not be put on during a period of rapid air movement. .The methods of using any of these heavier-than-air fumigants are much the same. If the temperature of the grain is 80° F. or higher, the liquid may be evaporated from shallow pans or basins placed on top of the grain. At lower temperatures the liquid should be evenly sprinkled directly on the grain. If the grain is more than four feet deep, a piece of pipe should be thrust into the grain and some ot the liquid poured down through the pipe to near the bottom of the.bin, not neglecting the corners. Before: the. liquid is placed or poured, some arrangement should be made for covering over the treated grain to confine the vapor. A large tarpaulin is good for this, but several overlapped sheets of newspaper covered with horse blankets or grain sacks may be used effectively. The best procedure is to level off the top of the grain, lift the tarpaulin or other covering, place or pour the liquid, replace the cover, close up the bin and get away. The bin should be kept closed for 24 to 48 hours, according to the tem - perature and the tightness of the bin. At the end of the period of fumi - gation the bin should be opened and aired for a few days before the build - ing is entered for any considerable length of time or any fire brought into it. If the grain is to be used for seed, it should be shoveled over a few times to help the. fumes to escape. i .: Carbon Bisulphide For many years the standard heavier-than-air fumigant for stored grain pests has been carbon bisulphide. This comes in the form of a heavy, nearly colorless liquid that evaporates quickly on exposure to air, forming a very ill-odored vapor that is 2.63 times as heavy as air, and therefore very penetrating downward. It is highly poisonous to insects when used in moderate concentrations, not injurious to the germination of the fumi - gated grain, not dangerous to healthy operators taking reasonable care, and easily available at a reasonable cost. The currently, quoted cost in small quantities is around 25 cents a pound, but in 50-pound and 100 - -pound drums may be purchased for about 9 cents a pound, and in 550 - -pound drums for about 7 cents a pound. The objections to the vapor of carbon bisulphide arc that it is very'inflammable, and will flash and burn from a flame or even a static spark at temperatures as low as -4 °F., and at a temperature, without any flame, of 297° F. or above, which is a lower ignition point than that of gasoline vapor; that it is highly explosive when mixed with air at concentrations of 6 per cent or more; that it has an extremely disagreeable odor; and that being a sulphur compound it acts as a reducing reagent on wheat and flour, so that wheat that has had a </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 62 prolonged exposure or even repeated shorter exposures to the vapor pro - duces a flour that may cause much trouble for both the miller and baker. Where the wheat has been exposed to the carbon bisulphide vapor for only a short time, the effect of fumigation may be less detrimental and may be overcome by the use of moderate quantities of oxidizing agents in the baking formula. But unfortunately, a load of wheat that has been ex - cessively fumigated with carbon bisulphide, even when later mixed with several loads of unfumigated wheat, produces a flour very poor in baking qualities. Wheat fumigated with carbon bisulphide upon subsequent aera - tion gradually loses much of the undesirable effect of the fumigation, and after storage for some months may become considerably improved, but still remains inferior for milling and baking purposes to untreated wheat. However, when used properly and with caution, carbon bisulphide is not an unsatisfactory fumigant for infested stored grain, and as a matter of fact there have been but few fires and explosions resulting from the use of carbon bisulphide, in spite of the admittedly great inflammability and ex - plosiveness of its vapor, and most of these have been due to carelessness, where proper caution was not observed. No lighted lanterns, or lighted tobacco of any kind should be brought near to where carbon bisulphide fumigation is going on, and care should be taken about sparks from electric switches or made by striking metals together, and even about electricity produced by friction. Of course hot stoves and steam pipes are also danger - ous. With care, carbon bisulphide can be used effectively and cheaply, and with reasonable safety, in grain fumigation, especially in isolated build - ings. Another precaution, since carbon bisulphide vapor is a poisonous gas to people as well as insects, is to avoid inhaling the vapor in any large amounts, or even in small amounts for a prolonged period. If, in fumi - gating with this chemical, there is felt any dizziness or nausea, the fresh air should be sought at once, where the ill effects will usually pass away within a few minutes. Also, since the vapor has an accelerating effect upon the heart action, persons having any heart trouble or weakness should not take any extended part in fumigating operations with carbon bisulphide. Mixture of Ethylene Dichloride and Carbon Tetrachloride Because of the dangerous inflammability and explosiveness of carbon bisulphide vapor, and its deleterious effect upon the milling and baking qualities of flour made from wheat that has undergone an excessive ex - posure to heavy concentrations of it, for a number of years past efforts have been made to find a substitute fumigant that would do the work as well and with entire safety and satisfaction. Probably the most promising of these, and one now gaining wide acceptance in the milling trade, is an ethylene dichloride-carbon tetrachloride mixture, consisting of a mixture of three parts by volume of ethylene dichloride and one part by volume of carbon tetrachloride. There are numerous labeled brands of this pro - duct now on the market. While this mixture evaporates readily, though </seg>
         <seg id="p011">"""..¦¦'•: Stored Grain Pests rather slowly, its vapor has good penetration (being over three times as heavy as air), and a not disagreeable odor, with relatively little danger to the operator (though breathing much of it sAmetimes causes difficulties wheniresh air should be sought at once). Most important of-all, the mix - ture is not inflammable, ethylene dichloride requiring less carbon tetra - chloride to render it non-inflammable than does carbon bisulphide. Its killing power is considerably less than that o£ carbon bisulphide, requiring more material to accomplish the same results' which increases the cost, whic^currently runs at about 6'A to 9/2 cents a pound delivered in drums in Nebraska. Investigators report that this mixture has little or no effect on flour quality, in contrast with the effects of carbon bisulphide vapor. Determining the Amount to Use ' To determine the amount of liquid fumigant to use, first find the number of bushels of grain in. storage, or compute in cubic feet the con - tents of the grain bin (length x width x height, in feet). In large, tight, ordinary wooden grain bins, at a temperature of around 75 T., minimal dosages of IJ4 pounds of carbon bisulphide to each 100 bushels of grain or 1 pound to each 100 cubic feet of space, should be used. Where the bin is not entirely tight and there is sure to be some leakage, or where it is more than 5 feet deep, the amdunt should|be increased to 1% to 2V, pounds to each 100 bushels of grain, or VA to 2 pounds to each 100 cubic feet of space, according to the tightness and size of the bin. The mixture of ethylene dichloride and carbon tetrachloride should be used in very tight bins at the rate of about 5 pounds per 100 bushels of grain, more being required in less tight bins, up to 8 pounds per 100 bushels of grain. : ' - '¦' . '¦.;. ¦ ¦¦¦¦ .. ¦; .¦;'¦:.¦ &#132;! . . :.' ¦ ¦ (4-W-SM) </seg>
         <seg id="p012"/>
         <seg id="p013">¦jig q ¦ : (•¦¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p014">GRASSES arc important in the program of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Experiments de - signed to improve the grasses themselves through breeding, and the production of grasses through better management, have been expanded in recent years. As a part of this work considerable information has become available on buffalo grass and its adaptation to lawns. Since there is widespread interest in its use for lawn purposes," the following circular has been prepared. Lincoln, Nebraska May, 1940 CONTENTS 1 Page Methods of Establishing Buffalo Grass 3 (Jetting a Desirable Type 3 Obtaining Sod 5 Transplanting Sod Pieces 6 (lire of Buffalo Grass Lawns 7 The authors wish to acknowledge pictures furnished by L. C. Xewefl, in charge of grass breeding lor the Experiment Station in co - operation with the V. S. Department of Agriculture, and also to A. L. r-rolik.. Department of Agronomy, University of Nebraska, for helpful criticism. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Buffalo Grass for Lawns E. F. FROLIK.and F. D. KEIM j . . Department of Agronomy TT^URING THE YEARS since 1934 many bluegrass lawns in Nebraska ¦*-' have suffered serious deterioration as a result of drouth and'high summer temperature. As a substitute the native buffalo grass has been used increasingly for lawn purposes. Results of experiments and observa - tions indicate definitely that for certain locations buffalo grass has sufficient advantage over bluegrass to recommend it as a permanent lawn grass. Buffalo grass has a summer habit of growth and is more tolerant of dry, hot conditions than is bluegrass. It has a dry and somewhat unattractive appearance during the fall and early spring months, whereas bluegrass usually has a green color during this time. Buffalo grass can be maintained with little or no mowing or artificial watering; and for this reason its use is particularly attractive on farms where watering is often difficult and where little time may be available for lawn work during the busy summer months. It is the best lawn grass for central and western Nebraska, except for lawns which are shaded or which can be watered readily. Kentucky bluegrass continues to be the best for most lawns in the eastern part, but even here buffalo grass can well be used for terraces and parkways, for yards exposed to the sun, and for many farm lawns. Under average rainfall conditions in eastern Nebraska, bluegrass may invade buffalo grass lawns. r Methods of Establishing Buffalo Grass ¦;•".- ' Buffalo grass may be propagated in either of two ways: by seeding or by sodding. Establishing stands on a large scale by seeding is not practical, however, because of the high cost of seed. Seed is expensive because of the difficulty of harvesting. Since the seed burs are produced just above the surface of the ground (Fig. 1), ordinary harvesting methods cannot be used. Harvesting is. done chiefly by sweeping the seed burs with brooms or gathering them with a vacuum machine after they have matured and be - come detached from the mother plants. "¦..¦-'¦¦."'¦"\ '.'¦'. Where seeding is attempted it should be done on a well packed, pulver - ized, relatively weed-free, moist seedbed. The seed does not germinate in cold soil. Therefore planting should be delayed until the latter part of April or the early part of May. Prior to this, the ground should be worked as necessary to control weeds. Seeding in the fall is not recommended. Under average conditions, planting sod pieces is the recommended method of establishment. Stands can usually be established more quickly and more cheaply with sod pieces than with seed. The sod pieces planted at intervals of one to two feet in both directions will ordinarily result in complete ground coverage within one growing season. Getting a Desirable Type of Grass Buffalo grass, as it grows naturally, consists of various types. These types differ markedly in such characteristics as intensity of color, height, erectness </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 63 Fig. I.—Buffalo grass (Buchloe Aactylo'iAcs). Staminatc plant x Vt; pistillate plant X Vi\ staminatc spikclct x 6; pistillate spikelct x 6; ligule area x 6; seed x 6. Occasionally plants arc found with both staminatc and pistillate spikelcts. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Buffalo Grass for Lawns Tjflr"" :^^^B lE3I I Fig. 2. —An important use for buffalo grass—between, sidewalk and curbing. of growth, and rapidity of spread. If sod is secured from an ordinary field, the lawn may lack a uniform appearance because it is composed of these various types. Furthermore, both staminate and pistillate plants (Fig. 1) are ordinarily included if the sod is obtained under field conditions. This is not ob - jectionable if the lawn is mowed regularly since the difference between the two kinds of plants is then not apparent. A pure stand of staminate plants is not so desirable as one containing only pistillate plants because the male flowers borne on the relatively long stalks detract somewhat from the appearance. , . In order to get a uniform type of grass it may be necessary first to establish a small area of sod from a few plants of known habit of growth. This initial planting can also be made with seed from a good type unless one desires only staminate plants. In order to get the latter, the initial planting must be made with plants rather than with seed. The planting should be made on fertile soil in good tilth as in a portion of the garden. ¦ The entire lawn can then be planted with sod pieces from this initial small planting. : If sod is taken from ordinary fields, it should be taken only from thick stands of relatively pure buffalo grass. ¦ Obtaining Sod Buffalo grass sod can be obtained from native grasslands or from nurseries. Native stands are most abundant in the western and south - central parts of the state. Sod should be moved only when the soil is reason- </seg>
         <seg id="p018">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION CIRCULAR 63 ably moist. If the soil is excessively dry, it tends to crumble and leave the roots exposed. Exposure of the roots for any length of time may result in the death of many of the plants. The sod should be taken at a depth o£ •ibout three inches. A sod cutter pulled by a tractor or horses may well be used where a large amount of sod is to be taken from a field. Such a sod cutter can be constructed by bolting a sharpened U-shaped steel blade to a suitable frame. The cutter should take about a 12-inch strip and it can be equipped with a roller colter to further divide the strip of sod into two six-inch strips. The strips can then be cut crosswise with a sharp spade into desirable - sized pieces for moving. If the restoration of a grass cover on the land from which sod is taken is desired, alternate strips of sod should be left undisturbed. The denuded strips will soon be covered with grass propagated by stolons growing from the undisturbed strips. If it is desired to have the field level, the furrows can be filled with dirt or the sod from the undisturbed strips can be removed later. Where sod is removed from rolling land, it should be taken only on the contour. The English bulb-planting tool is a convenient implement for use in obtaining small quantities of sod. It is a sharp steel cutter built to secure cores of sod. Circular plugs, approximately two and one-half inches in diameter, are easily secured with it. An ordinary spade may also be used in removing sod for planting. Transplanting Sod Pieces A well-prepared seedbed is very helpful in getting a stand of buffalo grass. The ground should be plowed or spaded well in advance of time of planting. The soil should be reasonably free of weeds, pulverized, moist, and well packed. It should also be reasonably fertile. The most favorable time of the year to plant buffalo-grass sod pieces is from the first of May to the fifteenth of June. This period represents the beginning and early part of the growing season. When moved at this time the grass spreads rapidly and covers the ground in less time than if moved at any other period of the year. Since weed control is usually necessary until the ground is completely covered, the minimum amount of labor in weeding is required by planting during May or up to the middle of June. Planting can be done, however, from the first o£ May to the middle of August. Pieces of sod approximately three inches on a side are a convenient and practical size. The circular plug taken by the English bulb planting tool is also satisfactory. The sod pieces may be planted anywhere from one to three feet apart each way. Under reasonably favorable moisture conditions, spacing of 18 inches with planting at the recommended time usually results in complete coverage of the ground in one season. More time is required in getting complete coverage when the sod pieces are planted further apart. Also, </seg>
         <seg id="p019">¦ ; . Buffalo Grass for Lawns Fio. 3.—Rosc-garclcn walks sodded with buffalo grass on the campus of the College of Agriculture, University of Nebraska. The grass is clipped closely and stands up well under heavy use. the wider the spacing the more labor is required in weed control, since a longer time is necessary to get complete coverage. Unless the. soil is in unusually good tilth, it is well to dig small holes for planting the sod pieces. The pieces should be set with the top about level with the surface of the surrounding ground and the dirt tamped around each piece. Liberal watering immediately after planting, although not always necessary, helps a great deal to insure establishment. Care of Buffalo Grass Lawns Buffalo grass lawns ordinarily require considerable attention from the time of planting until the ground is completely covered/Weeds should be destroyed as necessary with, the least possible disturbance to the stolons from which new plants arise. Weeds can ordinarily be removed with least injury to the stolons by hand pulling. Artificial watering during pro - longed periods of drouth while the buffalo grass is becoming established is very helpful. It may reduce considerably the amount of time needed to get complete coverage of the ground. Established buffalo grass lawns can be maintained with very little at - tention. It is not necessary to water them. The surface growth may take on a dry appearance during extended periods of dry weather but the roots are not easily injured by drouth. Mowing is not essential. Weeds are usually not serious in good, vigorous-growing buffalo grass lawns. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">AcRIMLTTRAL ExPERIMLNT STATION CIRCULAR 63 1-K.. -1. —Hurtalo-^rasb lawn (in the campus of the College of Agriculture, established by Mnlilinji in I'JiH. Scxls were transjilantcil in May and the lawn was mowed, as shown above, in September. With the help at some weeding and artificial water - ing a dense cover was established in one season. Buffalo grass lawns are more attractive, however, if they are mowed and watered occasionally. Care should be taken not to apply water too frequently as this will favor the growth of weeds. The soil should be kept in a good state of fertility. Soils too low in fertility to maintain a bluegrass lawn are likewise unsatisfactory for a buffalo grass lawn. (10M) </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>