<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  ECONOMICAL BEEF PRODUCTION.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>   
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 116. (Bulletin No. 115 is a technical bulletin, issued in a limited edition, and is not sent oat to th regular mailing list, but mar be had on application.) The University of Nebraska BULLETIN OK THK AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXIII, Article I ECONOMICAL BEEF PRODUCTION. Distributed December 15, 1910. Rib from the Angus steer "La Preto," grand champion carcass (all breeds and ages), International Live Stock Exposition. Chicago. December. 1909. Fed and exhibited by Dept. of Animal Husbandry. University of Nebraska. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA IT R A By H. R. SMITH. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICOLTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the regents of the university ) HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President. Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director. B DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. Ead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. Alwat, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. 3. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bbuner, B. Sc, Entomology. E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry. Ebwin H. Babbour, Ph. D., Oeology. G. R. Chatbubn, A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture. BP. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. C. W. Ptjgsley, B. Sc, Soil Agronomy. ■ P. Snydeb, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. K Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. rrert Coons, A. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Trumbuix, A, M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). Kmsselbach, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy (Crops). s Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology M. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. R. F. Howard, B. Sc. in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture. fW. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in Boils and Crops, North Platte; Assistant Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture, V. 8. Department of Agri - culture. Jamxs Cowan, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. F. Knokb, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent. •Mrs. Neixe S. Scott, A. B., Scientific Assistant. Seed Testing. • Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">PART L ECONOMY OF PRODUCTION AS AFFECTED BY THE FOOD. While beef has been high in price during recent years, the price of corn has so increased that the production of beef offers the farmer no greater financial inducements than formerly. Notwithstanding this increase there is still no farm grain, in the corn belt at least, that can be had at a lower figure per hun - dred pounds, and there is none more serviceable for fattening purposes. Stock feeders will therefore continue to make this grain their chief dependence, but in the future, assuming that the price of corn remains high, as it is likely to do owing to the limited area of its cultivation and its increased use for purposes of human consumption, it will be necessary to so combine it with other foods that the ration as a whole will more nearly meet the physiological requirements of the animal, and beef will be produced on less feed and at a lower cost. The problem is there - fore one of supplementing corn to the best advantage. Cattle are needed on our farms to utilize cheap roughage and to assist in conserving fertility. It is an industry which should be en - couraged, for the benefit not only of the farmer but of the con - sumer as well, and we should strive to learn ways by which beef can be produced at a lower cost, which can undoubtedly be ac - complished after making a more careful study of rations and the individuality of the animal. In Bulletin 100, entitled "Economical Rations in Beef Pro - duction," published in 1908, a report was given of an experiment BUI,. 116, AGB. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XXIII. ART. I </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Economical Beef Production 4 carried on during three successive years, in which the ration corn and prairie hay was compared with corn and alfalfa and also with corn, linseed-meal, and prairie hay. The results each year showed very conclusively the importance of using with corn either a protein roughage such as alfalfa, or a protein concen - trate, of which linseed-meal is an example. The average of three experiments showed that 36 per cent more grain was required to produce a given gain, and at a correspondingly higher cost, with prairie hay than with alfalfa, when the grain ration con - sisted of corn alone. In the comparison of corn, prairie hay, and linseed-meal fed in small quantity and corn and prairie hay without such a protein supplement, the average of three experi - ments showed that 31 per cent more grain was required for a given gain without this meal than with it, and the cost of pro - ducing gains was 12 per cent greater without the linseed-meal, for which an average price of 928.33 per ton was paid. From these observations it would seem that large gains can be made on corn and alfalfa and at low cost without any so-called protein concentrate. Experiments made in other states show that corn and clover hay are also very satisfactory for fattening cattle, which we might expect, because the latter belongs to the same family to which alfalfa belongs. Very likely either legume con - tains enough protein to supply the deficiency of that nutrient in corn for fattening cattle, tho alfalfa contains somewhat more than clover. With the exclusive use of any other roughage ex - cept cowpea hay, another legume, it seems that we must supply additional protein, which may be purchased in the form of some by-product put on the market for that purpose, the choice de - pending ou relative efficiency as well as relative prices. In Nebraska, wheat bran, linseed-meal, and cottonseed-meal are available for this purpose, and it was thought advisable to make a comparison of these concentrates one with another and each with alfalfa fed as half the roughage, in which case no protein concentrate was used. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 While but a small part of the fifty million bushels of wheat annually grown in this state is manufactured into flour within our borders, still there is a large tonnage of bran produced. Linseed-meal (oil-meal), the residue from the extraction of lin - seed-oil from flaxseed. is made in large quantity in the more northern states, and because of its richness in protein and its high commercial value it can be shipped in with but relatively small additional cost per ton. For the same reason cottonseed - meal, a residue from the manufacture of cottonseed-oil from the seed of cotton, can be shipped from the South to compete on middle ground with linseed-meal from the North. Gluten feed, a by-product in the manufacture of starch and glucose from corn, is prepared in states farther east, where the demand for it among farmers is such as to make the price too high to com - pete here with the other products mentioned after transporta - tion charges have been added. Alfalfa can be grown on nearly every farm in Nebraska and may be used satisfactorily as a protein supplement to corn either by itself or with some other roughage. 11 the table below is shown the results of two experiments in :h four groups of steers with ten in a group were fed on as y rations, each of which contained one of the four protein Is mentioned as being available in this state. In the first, t and prairie hay formed the basis of each ration; and in second, corn and unshredded corn-stover, both of which, like i, are deficient in protein. Two-year-old grade Shorthorn Hereford steers from a ranch in Rock County, Nebraska. b used in the first experiment, and two-year-old grade Angus q Sioux Countv. Nebraska, in the second. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 o -(s^red , rBnbe)a8AO&gt;B-aioo g pu« X«q «JI«Jl« 'JU90 J3d 001 OJOQ 8 S S S SS SSSSS |g oj d « « cog £&amp;££ £$&lt; S S 38 S PS «S?g§5 |S gj ad » » «r^ SSSfe £5 X '*U8O J9d 06 5- :r I o s»5 ." ■o.c.e.-S'»&gt;5- a J|:.:!:!:|: ils-gi : I ! i « I 1 El pratxOjaAcs-ujoo 25 §? g § 88 SSS8 «8 -aioo 'tuao i&amp;d oi * -^ °c » °9 M . on « 25 25 m ■goo ,* -J0A(X»8-UJ00 «»U90 I WgJ g gg flg g « S 5g?gg3 eg I ■J3AOJS-UJOO 'juao jed 555 UBac l '?U9O jod 8Z, aJOO ij 3 *4 8 1O S3 3228 S i ! j 1 Si •(BIJBd I«nba) ifaq aunud pu« isq «JIBJI« '^nao jad QOT &lt;uoq o CO o — o 2£ B§?£g fS •X«q auiBjd 'juao Jdd oi fB9m -poasuajjoo ')uao jad r»6 ujoo poneqs CO o 25 O5 '•^ © I 5 auiBjd 'juao jad oj jBatn-paasuii 'juao j»d 06 ujoo'penaqg 5 CD £ N 5S5 2K B •X'eq aunud 'juao Jdd Q2 uuiq 'juao aad Qi ujoo psnaqs CD 00 si g — eg J2S 8S28 B « ! T </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Economical Beef Production 7 Table I shows that in both experiments the smallest daily gains were made with bran, a larger quantity of which was used than of either linseed- or cottonseed-meal because of its greater bulk and lower protein content. Cottonseed-meal was next lowest in both experiments. The highest average daily gains were made with linseed-meal the first year, and the highest with alfalfa the second year, the average for both being slightly in favor of linseed-meal. In cost of gains and profits, the alfalfa had much the advantage. In the first experiment, corn cost 35 cents per bushel, bran |15 per ton, linseed- and cottonseed-meal each $32, and alfalfa and prairie hay each $6 per ton. In the second experiment, corn cost 36 cents per bushel, bran $18 per ton, linseed-meal $29.50, cottonseed-meal $27.75, alfalfa $6, and corn-stover (stalks) $2.50. The low cost of alfalfa for roughage possessing such a high nutritive value, especially for the protein it contains, readily explains the advantages in its favor for com - bining with corn in beef production. In both experiments it n&gt; - turned a value of approximately $13 per ton in comparison with linseed-meal at $30 per ton. 1&gt;ld Pressed Cottonseed-cake. — During the winter of 1908 a of these foods was again made, six instead of ten steers g fed on each ration, practically all of which were two-year - grade Shorthorns, and cold pressed cottonseed-cake substi i for cottonseed-meal. In this experiment a new policy was gurated, namely, that of making records of feed consumed gains made by each animal of the several groups. For pur - s of comparision with the preceding experiments the follow - table shows the average by group. In later tables the in - lual records of each steer are shown : </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Table II. — Wheat bran, lintoed-meal, cold pressed cottonseed-cake, and alfalfa compared. :: Grain consumed for one pound of gain, lbs 8.37 8.62 7.56 Net profit per head including pork produced I $5.15 $3.44 $6.87 $8.16 The results of the third experiment, as shown in Table II, do not agree with those of the two former experiments, in that bran gave a slightly larger daily gain than linseed-meal at a lower cost and with a correspondingly larger profit. The new product, called Cold Pi-essed Cottonseed-cake, used in place of the cottonseed-meal of the former experiments, seemed to be a superior feed. The largest daily gains were made on cottonseed - rake and at less cost tho the profits were not finite so (Treat as ■ Experiment III. — February, 1908, to May, 1908, 12 weeks. Rations fed each group of six steers. gc § "* £• © « c fe^, 8- 1 &lt;\^ 8 4 . eg.g 8 ;5 8 85- "II s£! eIs s§§ e?| O?Sai Onoo O^jc o Mx o o o o .ge initial weight per steer, lbs . . 1033 1025 1034 n i4ti ige daily gain per steer, lbs 2.53 2 43 2.80 2.55 .ge amount of grain consumed y per steer, lbs 21.20 20 99 21.03 19 86 ige amount of roughage con- led daily per steer, lbs I 7.61 8.03 8.89 879 Roughage consumed for one pound of gain, lbs Total food consumed for one pound of gain, lbs Cost of 100 pounds of gain Value of pork produced a- a by- product for 100 pounds of gain on steers Net cost of food for 100 lbs. of gain . . Cost of each steer per hundred pounds (delivered) Net selling price per hundred I.M 11.37 $9.24 $0.91 $8.33 $4.60 $5.79 3.30 11.92 $9.64 $1.01 $8.63 $4.60 $5.69 2.70 10.26 $8.29 $1.06 $7.23 $4.60 $5.79 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 those on alfalfa because the alfalfa steers sold for a slightly higher price per hundred. Why linseed-meal should give the lowest gains is not easily explained, in view of the fact that in both previous experiments it gave most excellent results. The meal used in this experiment was coarsely ground, called "pea size," and was purchased from a Northern company for old process, at a price f 1.00 per ton below Omaha quotations. That it was inferior to the linseed-meal used the two preceding winters was shown by the presence of more fine material and the fact that it was less relished. The Station Chemist also reported it to contain but 3.1 per cent fat and 25.5 per cent protein, whereas the old process meal previously fed contained about 6 per cent fat and 32 per cent protein. The analysis of all foods used in this experiment as reported by the Station Chemist is as follows: Moisture Ether Crude Crude Ash Ni «EP n Moisture extract fiber prote in Aah e ™£. t Sample Per Percent Percent Percent Per ml ctnt Percent 12.09 3.57 10.11 11.53 6.80 55.90 Wheat bran. Cold pressed cotton 10.32 6.14 ! 22 37 32.85 4.43 23.89 seed-cake I »ld pressed cottonseed-cake, which gave the largest gains, highest in protein, and, unlike our former experiences with process cottonseed-meal, was consumed with more relish the linseed-meal fed Lot 2. The fact that in the manufac - of this cottonseed-cake the oil is removed by pressure and by the use of heat and chemical solvents is a possible er - ation of the higher value it seemed to show in this test, as uch preparation the albumen is not coagulated and it is jfore more digestible. The alfalfa fed during the first eight weeks of the experiment was first-cutting hay, very stemmy in character, and not well •inseed-meal M redded corn -stover 'irst cutting alfalfa 'hird cutting alfalfa 9.72 10.32 13.45 13.10 3 10 1.24 1.09 1.89 8.82 29.42 35.87 22.23 25.57 4.85 9.60 17.40 5. CO 6.85 6.95 8 51 II </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Economical Beef Production cured, many of the leaves having fallen off. During the last four weeks a much better grade of alfalfa was used. This was third - cutting hay, exceptionally well cured, and very unlike the first used in that all the leaves seemed to be present. Much better results came from feeding the better grade of hay, which is readily understood when the analyses of the two kinds are com - pared. The corn-stover used in this experiment was shredded, because the steers were fed separately in barn mangers too short for feeding the stalks entire. The corn was cut and shocked immediately after ripening, and the shredding wag done about two months later. This stover was of good quality, as one might infer by noting the gains made on this feed used as the sole roughage in three of the lots. The steers in the fourth lot were fed stover in the morning and alfalfa hay at night. There was a considerable waste of stalks, as is indicated in the table, the greater part of which was coarse butts, which tho shredded seemed to be unpalatable and practically worthless as a feed. While this refuse was weighed back, all stover fed was charged to the cattle just as tho it had been completely consumed. The prices on the feeds used were f. o. b. Lincoln in car lots at the beginning of the experiment, and were as follows : Corn, 52 centB per bushel (92.8 cents per hundred). Cottonseed-cake, $25 per ton Linseed-meal, $29.70 per ton. Bran, $22 per ton. Alfalfa, $7 per ton. Shredded corn-stover, $4 per ton While in the three experiments reported an effort was made to have one lot of steers average in size, quality, and condition with every other lot, some variation is to be expected due to the in - dividuality of the steers used in the test. For this reason it seems desirable to continue a given line of investigation from year to year or until the results may be considered fairly con </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Economical Beef Production 11 and lead one to believe that a good quality of old process linseed - ineal in which there has been no steam or chemicals used is slightly superior to old process cottonseed-meal by which the seeds are cooked and the oil is removed with a chemical solvent, and that, further, this old process cottonseed-meal is superior to wheat bran, both from the viewpoint of gains and from that of economy of production at current market values. The one test most recently made is indicative of the high value of the new cold pressed cottonseed-cake and the economy of its use. This test also puts wheat bran in a better light and would seem to discourage the use of an inferior grade of linseed-meal, which is quoted to farmers at a lower price than the best grade in order to make it a more attractive proposition. All three tests show that alfalfa can lie fed with corn and either prairie hay or corn-stover with exceedingly good results as to daily gains and with profits which seem to put it at the head of the list of protein foods for economical beef production, when it can be had at the usual price received for it on the aver - age Nebraska farm where grown. If the feeder grows his own alfalfa the price could be put lower and still the land would return a high rate of interest upon the investment. QUALITY OF THE CARCASSES. Pttle in this experiment were purchased by Swift &amp; Co. Omaha and slaughtered in their plant, where record* le on the dressing of each steer, the shape and covering rcasses, and the texture, color, and marbling of the meat, t furnished by the r-oinpany also appraised each carcass asis of existing market quotations on dressed beef. The average dressing of the six steers in Group I, fed on corn supplemented with bran, was 58.0 per cent; Group II (linseed - nieal), 58.05 per cent; Group III (cold pressed cottonseed-cake), 58.25 per cent; Group IV (alfalfa), 59.7 per cent. The caul fat taken from the steers of each group averaged per steer as fol </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Experts in Swift &amp; Co.'s coolers appraising each carcass. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 lows: Group I, 22.7 lbs.; Group II, 23.3 lbs.; Group III, 18.5 lbs., and Group IV, 22 lbs. The average value of the carcasses per hundred pounds as appraised was as follows by group : I, $ 10.12 ; II, |10.21 ; III, |10.29 ; and IV, $10.42. This valuation was made by the expert on the basis of shape, color, texture, and marbling without knowledge on his part of the previous manner of feed ing. The net price received per hundred weight for the steers (home weights on foot at the close of the experiment) was $5.79 per hundred for the bran group, $5.69 for the linseed-meal group. $5.79 for the cottonseed-cake group, and $5.89 for the alfalfa group. On the basis of dressing and quality of carcasses, with the bran steers worth $5.79, the linseed-meal steers should have brought $5.85, the cottonseed-cake steers $5.92. and the alfalfa fed steers $6.14. The buyer was therefore right in paying more for the alfalfa steers, but he should have priced them 22 cents per hundred higher than any other lot, rather than 10 cents higher. The rating on the cottonseed-cake steers as compared with the linseed-meal steers was approximately correct, but the bran steers should have been rated 6 cents per hundred lower than the linseed-meal steers instead of 10 cents higher. If the profits per steer were to be reckoned on the basis of dressed weights and quality of meat, alfalfa and cottonseed-cake would show even better than the table indicates. The wonderful value of the alfalfa plant, not only for producing large gains but also for its favorable effect upon the quality of beef, is here made evident. In this connection, to reinforce the observations made in this experiment, the writer wishes to call attention to the results of the awards in the carcass contest at the recent Inter - national Live Stock Exposition in Chicago (1909) in which cattle from different parts of the United States and Canada competed. In this contest the four highest prizes, including the grand championship carcass, were won by University of Nebraska steer* which had been fed on mixed grain rations supplemented with a liberal quantity of alfalfa. These carcasses were uniformly well </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">15 covered, nicely marbled, the lean bright red in color, and the texture good. The writer is of the opinion that alfalfa w;is n ini|M»rt;nit factor in giving this qaaHty. CORN-STOVER WITH ALFALFA MOST PROFITABLE. In I'.iillct ill 10(1 an experiment \v;is reported in which a heav\ feed of shelled corn ami alfalfa was compared with a heavy feed of shelled corn, alfalfa and corn stover, \\hen the stover waa i nroduced the avenge daily gala made by the ten steers was '2. I 11)8. as compared with -.'■&gt; lbs. made by the ten fed corn and alfalfa alone, and the cost of 100 lbs. of gala was fti.49 with stover and fti.Nlt without, the stover being figured at fli.oO per BM and the alfalfa f6.00. The followiag year, when a light feed Hauling shock corn for cattle. of snapped corn was used, the daily gain was 0.1 lb. less with alfalfa and stover than with alfalfa alone, but here again the of producing 100 lbs. of gain was 50 cents per hundred less by the use of both stover and alfalfa for roughage and the profit* </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 correspondingly greater. From these results it would seem less necessary to use stover when snapped corn is fed, very likely because the husk and cob serve to some degree the same purpose as the stover, lessening the tendency of the cattle to scour and at the same time giving more variety to the ration. From the entire series of experiments made it seems safe to conclude that beef in Nebraska can be most profitably produced on some com - bination of the corn plant and alfalfa hay. THE MOST ECONOMICAL PROPORTION OF CORN TO ALFALFA The next logical step was to determine the most economical proportion of corn to alfalfa — whether a heavy feed of grain, a medium feed, or a light feed with correspondingly more alfalfa Three experiments have been made dealing with this problem. In the first a little more than a half feed of shelled corn (13.9 lbs. daily to each steer) was compared with a full feed (22.3 lbs.), the roughage consisting of alfalfa and corn-stover. In the second, three different quantities of grain were used, 12, 17. and 19.8 lbs., and in the third 12, 15.6, and 18.8 lbs. The same kind of roughage was used in the second as in the first, namely, alfalfa and shredded stover, the latter being more convenient to weigh and feed than unshredded stover. In the third, only alfalfa was fed for roughage and corn-meal was substituted for shelled corn to eliminate entirely the pork factor as this seems to be more or less variable and less easily controlled. E following table includes the results of the three experi the figures representing the average for each steer by </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Economical Beef Production 17 OJ s a 3 ss s s § s s 2 C " »8 S S S S S ** 3 5 E sS 8 £ 5 3 5 &gt;o o io war- © r- &gt;f w 5 jige AAB»q) [■B9O1-UJOQ "J |^ aaA&lt;ns-ujoD'}uao £ S £-S? ? '(paaj oqaii) ujoq 54 g J I* -ujoo '%uao jad § E .e*£g OS «Jl«II« '&lt;PMj S S. feS- * mnip»ai)njoo §• W $ &gt;5m • * . ■ 7 •** JaAojB-ujoo '■juao [g 3 ? * '( paajXABaq) iuoq P&amp;S5-- luaojadot s &gt; - 1 .^ I Jd jaAajB-xuoo'^uao * 1 1 5° * '(paaj iqatl) ujoq |8J"g« -luaojados g" ".o. 1 m jaAojs-ujoo'juao I Z° '(paaj^ABaq)uJoo § r2 S S s S3 S S S S 3 aoao^cooi S S X S 3 71 — eg 8 8 S i58 {2S5S3S sssss 2 s 8 s ; t~ as t- •*» r- •* «o r- % •»«.*•!•» 2 00t " 1 8 SS3J8S S S S SZ 3 B S £ 5 2 5 • •» RSSSS t-O 00 IM £.S — t 18 CO (C I — .2 o-S_; is-s 1 01 I B H ~ •» 5&gt; W &lt;» * «• • - »« ■ i - *o -I ■ ■ i fl ■ •** • »a ■ *O • 1 £ • » ■ c • o • a ■ • &gt;&gt;•« • o • © . j, • o ■ •" a o c oSC^rt • t- -t. u • lSII|*Il[K*»i« ; n*ifl </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Economical Beef Production From Table III it will be seen that in Experiment I. in which the roughage consisted of alfalfa and corn-stover, the light fed steers gained 0.41 pound less per day for a period of twenty - four weeks than the heavy fed steers during a period of twenty weeks. The average gain of each steer of the two groups — one fed four weeks longer than the other — was the same, viz., 339 pounds. With corn then worth 36 cents per bushel, alfalfa $6.00 per ton on the farm where grown, and unshredded stover f2.50 per ton, the net cost of producing &lt;rains was 27 cents per hun dred pounds less with the light grain ration than with the heavy. Had the corn cost 34 cents per bushel the net cost of producing gains would have l«&gt;en the same in both groups. In 1908, when the second experiment was made, corn waB worth 52 cents per bushel, alfalfa f 7.00 per ton. and the shredded stover was valued at $4.00 per ton. At these prices the cost of producing gains was again least on the light feed of corn, but the profits were somewhat higher on the heavier fed cattle be cause they were all fed the same length of time and sold on the same date, the light fed cattle bringing 25 cents per hundred less than the heavier fed cattle. Had the light fed cattle been fed an extra month they would have undoubtedly shown as imuli condition of flesh and would then have brought as much per pound. On that basis the profits per steer in this group would have been $8.76 instead of $5.76. Had the alfalfa in this ex- I&gt;erinient been figured at $6.00 per ton instead of |7.00, the cost of producing 100 pounds of gain on the light feed of corn would have been |6.85 and on the medium and heavy feeds $7.36. In this experiment had the corn cost 32 cents per bushel with al - falfa worth |6.00 per ton instead of |7.00 as before, the net cost of producing gains would have been the same on the heavy grain ration as on the light. Ethe last experiment we have the best showing of all for the fed cattle. In this test the corn was ground to eliminate from the calculations and no stover was fed. On corn-meal </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Economical Beef Production 19 a full grain ration for two-year-old steers seemed to be about 3 pounds per day less than on shelled corn. From this it might be inferred that a steer's capacity is limited by the amount of grain assimilated rather than by the amount fed, as much corn passes thru undigested when the whole grain is used. In this experiment corn was figured at 56 cents with 4 cents added for grinding, making it 60 cents per bushel or $1.07 per hundred. With alfalfa at $7.00 per ton the cost of gains on the light fed steers was 81 cents per hundred less than on the medium fed group and $1.67 less than on the heavy fed group. With alfalfa at $7.00 per ton the cost of gains on the light and heavy fed cattle would have been the same had the corn cost 25 cents per bushel. With alfalfa at $6.00 the cost would have been the same with corn at 21 cents per bushel. In this experiment, however, the heavy fed steers were placed at a disadvantage because al - falfa was used alone as roughage. With a heavy feed of clear corn and alfalfa, cattle seem to be affected to a considerable de - gree with scours, much more so than when either corn-stover, prairie hay, or cane is fed with it. These cattle were off feed several times and a reference to the table will show that they consumed less in consequence and made a smaller daily gain than the medium fed cattle. Their average daily consumption of frrain and hay was but 26.5 pounds as compared with 30.7 pounds for the medium fed group and 29.2 pounds for the light fed group. The alfalfa was for the most part excellent in quality and greatly relished. The records show that with such hay remark - ably good gains may be made on 12 pounds of corn and all the alfalfa that will be consumed. That the medium fed cattle in Experiment II were just as good when finished is shown by the fact that both groups sold for practically the same price on the same day. The light fed group were in lower condition and undersold the other groups 25 cents per hundred. They should have had ap extra month's feed. The dressing when killed was as follows: Gronp I, 59.7 per cent of </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Economical Beef Production 20 live weight ; Group II, 60.1 per cent ; Group III, 58.3 per cent. In Experiment III the same thing was found true. The groups fed the medium and heavy grain rations dressed practically the same per cent with a slight difference in favor of the medium group. Those fed the light grain ration dressed somewhat less because of their lower condition. From the results of this series of experiments it seems safe to say that with corn above 35 cents per bushel and with alfalfa not to exceed |7.00 per ton, the old method of fattening cattle for market, namely that of crowding with grain and using but little roughage, is much less profitable than a more moderate use of grain and correspondingly more roughage. Not to exceed three fourths of a full feed of corn and a correspondingly larger quantity of alfalfa will give practically the same daily gains: the cattle will take on quite as good a finish during an equal length of time on feed, and will bring as much per pound as when given all the corn that will be consumed, and these things will be accomplished at a reduced cost of production with larger nrofits to the feeder. With a good nnalitv of alfalfa at $6.00 ppr ton or less and corn above 50 cents per bushel, something ai proaching half a full feed of corn is still more profitable if one is in a position to keep the cattle in the feed lot one or two months longer than the usual time given to a full feed of grain. Lengthening the feeding period increases to some extent the interest charges on the money invested and the labor connected with the feeding operations, but with the more liberal use of alfalfa the manure is more valuable and a larger market pro - vided at the farm for a hay crop, which at six dollars or more per ton in the stack or mow is exceedingly profitable to grow. Allow - ing $1.50 per ton for harvesting the crop, a field of alfalfa yield - ing 4 tons to the acre for the season — an average crop in Ne - braska — the net revenue per acre at $4.50 per ton would amount to |18.00, which is 6 per cent interest on $300 per acre. With the increased demand for corn and the limited area adapted for </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 I successful growth this grain is certain to command a much ler price in the future than it has in the past. Prom the ilts of this series of experiments it would seem advisable to le a larger use of roughage and less grain than has been done he past. Former experiments also show the advisability of ling with the alfalfa some cornstalks to lessen scours, to fur - 1 variety, and to lower the cost of production by the utiliza i of a cheap feed which otherwise goes to waste on the aver Nebraska farm. Stacking bundles of corn-fodder for late winter feeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 i DADT TT ECONOMY OF PRODUCTION AS AFFECTED BY THE ANIMAL. A large number of experiments have been made to determin.' the relative value of foods suitable for beef production, and it has been found that certain combinations that seem to meet fairly well the physiological requirements of the animal will make more pounds at less cost than other combinations not so well suited. Strange as it may seem, very few experimental data have been obtained to show individual differences in animals in their capacity to use food to the best advantage. It is a matter of common observation among cattle feeders that some steers gain faster than others, and numerous theories have been ;ul vanced to explain why this is so but as yet they are mere theories. In the work of improving animals by methods of breeding, the chief aim seems to have been to produce types that make the best carcasses and therefore bring a higher price per pound when sold, rather than those which make the most economical gains in the feed lot. Several tests have been made in which specimens of one breed have been compared with those of another, but the results would indicate that th£ matter of making economical gains is not a breed characteristic. Sometimes the best and poorest gains are fotind within the same breed. Most ex - perimental feeding has been done in groups, and there has been no opportunity for observing individual differences. Thinking that this might be a field for profitable study to determine whether or not there are external indications as to form, etc., which denote feeding capacity, the writer three years ago adopted a system of keeping individual records of weights and gains on «11 cattle fed experimentally. To show that there is a wide variation in animals, the records for the steers ueed in the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 experiments described in Part I are here exhibited. In each group of one experiment were six steers, the first three of which were reared at the Substation farm at North Platte, Neln-.. ami were somewhat smoother, more compact, and showed better breeding than the last three of each group. The better steers were figured at fo.OO j&gt;er hundred at the beginning of the ex- IKTiment. and the more common ones, all of which came from a Western Nebraska ranch, cost #4.20 on weights at the beginning of the experiment, which included the cost of the preliminary feeding in both cases. The selling price indicated represents the net price actually received for each steer on the basis of closing weights at the Experiment Station Farm. The profit given is therefore net except that nothing was charged for labor nor for interest on the investment. The value of the manure is usually considered an offset to labor in feeding practice. Each steer m tied in a stall when fed and the grain and roughage carefully weighed when put in the feed boxes and manners. The weights of each steer as given are the averages of three taken on sue cessive days, both at the beginning and at the close of the experi ment. The tables follow. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Economical Beef Production i "^1 '§§ 2 8 R S S S SS 8 S5SS 5S SS82 2 prtuuy — "S^SS^^^SSS Sis jg I l^T^, 2§38£§§cSSS28S £§S R I (pooai g~ g g R © •"?w 2§ * * * - J0 9*SJ8AV S " IN S § S S §3 5 2SS S S3 • • « SS S &amp;SS S I J §g §5 8 R 8 •I^H W lO lO -H S S S 8 22 S 5SP S 2 °° • " 22 g S5&amp; &amp; I »h C4 o v:- I e CC- » S3 cr e 8 £ R S S3SS S SS5 s a &amp;k k » » — M lO lC — 2 00 A n «O O SS jg 8 II -H M o «5 12" O 00 o5 M S3 — M IO &gt;O -" S 8 S S 3 2 S S SS5 S 2 «- r- M o 8 o Ka&amp; g »&lt; o P w « §■*■ S3 S R S «h «' nj H9 x' 2 2 3 2 S2 s S8S 8 2 • t&gt; n « g o gjjjj jj S3 2 5J S; R8 S 288 B 2 ° N ffl S S SJ83I S 8 8 8 S Sf: s $85 S » OS » &lt;# COO g SSS Si &gt; S ■- I «^&gt; ! i! ideiWil i &gt; Mi 111 i I : IJ^&amp;nlilMjfciiilisi^i^i i m SI 1 1 i I ill4lpii|l|Ii4tifiiflli|tt &gt; a H ■ aaiqi %ev[ ©S3 • ~ • "! T l . T T« ™ r , Oa *u8Av ~ S « - 2 «o « » 28 g &amp;3&amp;! g s </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 X I 8 \\* SN jo'aJtejaAv *"" 9 OC I 3§ aoao ■ S3 i 58 : «• IiuouiuiOD) ca jo aiJBjaA v — ( — ( 8 8 ! s ■* ocx ■ CO 3§ i 8SS£» I(pooa) ojo aajqi ijejg ©eg jo aaejdA v ~* ~* a S ! ad &lt; 8 S ! CO — t-00 eg o SAft£S I? or- -I S| 5 s S 8 « 2g 8 00 88 CM'* o It" I ■ — I 2 a» &gt; — i 2 ' 8 S S s 8 S eg eg eg &lt;n 8 ■ CO 8S ost- 5 eg eg CO I 2S 35 CO — t- o B o •^ o -r u~ — ao -^&lt; o u 3i •aoeg a&gt;» for- g^3 oof o I I 9 I |l CD §§ S 8 8 3 S 83 2g $8 S 8S§|S| «3 eg g eg -« pj t^t^ eg 0*5 -&lt; §2 §5 8 S 8 S SS G S£ 5 $8?JSS — — eg oo — o jj t^oci eo egg -j S^S^S mmmmm immmm iir-lllliililliffitliiliiili; </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Economical Beef Production I I :| : e^Sb • ■ to : o y*» S-° : 1 ■" : §fl$&gt;« : S'-S S 2*8. . a : a .gS«&amp; fe 5 | : t 1 ■• 1j1^lML«iili:H!!^ i l5!Ji!!! s 111!l1i!;i^i!!i £ Z *$ ■ £* 6tS ocra 6pS 6p« ° 2 _-*- c rs o £l o: i2*' I i |iy 4 Min|2|i|i|t|i||§||ip &gt; i 1^1 gE88S8g252 3$ 8885 ggj „ | || 8 = 3 § S 5J S SS SS SSSS; 8 ~^i ill~ 3 = 8 8 9 3 "8 5 S28B § "| '— " 5 5 3 - » " "£ S8&amp;S 8 a |§ 3 " 3 § ; : s s ss ssss s *| — - S « S S 2 SJ • 22 S28S S £ • s. ■• § jl-Sf : £s i^o ■■ o • § :£s : o ill ; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Economical Beef Production 27 ISJ99)S §| 8 $ 3 3 S S 5 §SP S 3S3 2 •* 5^1 3S ® 1^ X t* m -*m — i Mg I I(uooiujoo) jo aSejaA v •» "&lt; M 35 t» r» X X M Mr. — X-»i-- ■ I(poo3) JO 3&amp;BJ3A V |g {2- S S g 2 3 8 &amp;£ a 2SS 5 - -T 1 §§ 5 S § 3 2 = S 82 S 3°,S 5 -h— o r- t— =: oo n -"OS — r-'ficj s a - l 2j * S S 6 3 • — . i i S S . «a I" 8 of fa O ow • ~ "^ . ** . ?5 •?! t— — — — -« 00 » r~ t~ o ■«» ■* »« — &lt; o^l- - -- * a** 5 §8 I ? C • I 1 I SI X 888 I r»ac *j &gt;5 o «s 00 3; i~— -r r- = ?i c« grj K3 x 10 — S ■&gt;» — • «e-f m — B~ m ■&gt;-i»"e&lt;ix^r— xr-ciooc — ***!&amp;£ S — cogicxr^coi-Jxr- — SSS ** s I ! J sJl Ilibl J J life fii ■si's s : 1 ; t a =i : |8S-s « 1 HIIUHI J-ifijii ,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Economical Beef Production J 8J9St)S XIB \\V JO 9*BJ9AV ii 5. S «4 s t^ s S5 ■^ 88S 00 S 4- I (uotumoo) ' jo aJhusAy "I CM «4 3 oci ■ o a 1 =a 58S 8 (poo*) aajqi jsjij }O oJtejSAy *-^ vH 6 N 8 ■ co ad oo oo' 5 S ■^ sa 00 SS8 !i ! 8 I §| S S? 3 S P S S SSS 2 SS3 2 §| §S § S S 3 8 S? 2 Sap: §j •«53 N t» OS 00 O CO SO Of- g SSS M 5 S i = r it— - g S 3 §E S 8 3 3 88 S 8 S8 a S88 3 §g SS 8 9 SS 'Q E: 8 ?SS 3 88g 2 3SS 8 --Mefi^ooxt no&gt; ji JESS S §gS2S8=8SS8 2 S8S S : | || ;J || \d :* :* . :| :H : : :» : i !* if :■ : fc : I il if =1 ':!• i| :l«f '. I :| I :* if I :« :i -f :■* :i ilsl = i i i 1 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Economical Beef Production 29 i 1 U3»)8 118 n" g 8 i o P 00 8 — ■o {2 r^ g li-5 3 • i I (uomuioo) JO 8*8J9A V sl 2 8 N 2 B o X 3 — 5 10 SJ2 da {2 5 , . ..I 5 ! I(pooS) ! jo aiiBjaAV 8 8 3 — I X 9 •0 2§J 2£ {2 : - o ■i ■ C4 8 8 3 3 00 ■ I g ■ ■ coo S3 SS9 ! So • a 050 §§§ S 3 S 35 3 S 8 Ss {S 2S£ 3 — — (N CM CM O&gt; t- t— — :d O o«o m J Or- 3? s 10 — it; o -" «- m 10 — om t&gt; — p; S o t-- o 51 — -&lt; niS r- appac S •rti- -h m »&lt; o&gt; « 10 ad oi» d t~-oo •* ■**■** ei ej o 06 « to « jjaj o '"■gijS a |S 8 8 S S 3 S 8 g8 B i88S S sa n n o s n « « — 'a^ g s;sg. si : :£ :-8 :| ■% "? a :"S :"S : :8 :*S : : : » ' 1 ili r! Ill j 1 1ll Ll Iiiii^fl hi 5 K] II n i*n 1 n^nvm uiitti </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 From the tables it will be observed that the average daily gains in Group I ranged from 2.20 to 2.86 lbs. These steers were each fed the same amount of grain but roughage to the limit of their capacity. The stover actually consumed was approximately half the amount fed. The net profits per head raagtd from f2.93 to f7.99. In this group the three steers having the most quality ..vci-aged slightly larger gains than the three more common types. but the net profits were highest on the latter because the differ - ence in the selling price was but 45 cents per hundred, whereas the difference in cost was 80 cents per hundred. In Group II the average daily gains ranged from 1.63 lbs. to 2.96 lbs., a difference of 1.33 lbs. per day. A part of this wide variation is no doubt due to the fact that steer No. 12 was of a very nervous disposition and rather difficult to handle. &lt; &gt;f the remaining fire, all of which were quiet, the variation was 0.7 lb. per day. The steers of this group were fed all the grain and stover they would consume. No. 7 showing an inclination to eat somewhat less than the others. That some individuals are much more economical producers than others is shown by the fact that steer No. 9 required over one-fifth more food for a given gain than steer No. 8. Here again the average of the three good steers in daily gains was slightly higher than the three common, but this was due to the poor showing made by No. 12. the one inclined to be nervous. The largest gainer was one on the com - mon order and the two smallest gainers were good types. Here again the profits per head were larger on the common steers be - muse their original cost was 80 cents per hundred less and the selling price but 20 cents less. In Group III we have the widest variation in gains of all groups. One steer. No. It, gained but 1.41 lbs. per day, while another on the same ration. No. 17, gained &amp;Jt lhs. per day — just Iwice as much. This latter steer was a strong, vigorous type. rather heavy in bone tho not particularlv coarse. He was the largest gainer of the entire number in the experiment and it is </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">32 more or less significant that he had the largest heart girth (cir - cumference of body just behind the fore legs) and the largest middle girth of any steer, weight considered. No. 13, the lowest gainer, was somewhat handicapped by the fact that he carried more flesh than the others at the beginning of the experiment and this was very likely responsible in part, at least, for his poor showing. No. 16 was as thin as No. 17 at the beginning and gained 0.74 lb. less per day. He was on the coarse, angular order, narrow chested but no more so than No. 18. No. 16 was a poor seller as indicated by the table. In this group the three common steers made the largest combined gains because of the poor showing made by No. 13. They were also more profitable to feed because they sold relatively higher as killers at the close than as feeders at the beginning of the experiment. In Group IV the largest gains were made by one of the good types, No. 19, and the lowest by one of the common, No. 22, a difference of 1.32 lbs. per day. It was not due to condition, as No. 22 was fully as thin in flesh as No. 19 at the beginning. No. 19 was considerably wider in chest and larger in middle girth for weight. He was also somewhat smaller in bone and showed a more pliable skin. The next largest gainer in this group was one of the common steers. As in all previous groups there seems to be no regularity, the best and poorest gainers being very evenly distributed among the so-called good and common types, rho the better steers of all four groups made a slightly higher average gain. Ii the two lighter fed groups, V and VI, we find a variation he former as high as 0.73 lb. per day and in the latter 0.94 and these extremes in Group VI were both steers of the com - l sort in very nearly the same condition to begin with. &gt;r No. 34 showed more capacity for roughage than No. 3fi. this could not account for the wide difference in gains. The it and middle girth measurements were practically alike. 36 was less quiet than No. 34, which is very likely a partial lanation of the difference in gains. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Steers In Experiment I as they appeared when marketed. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Economical Beef Production In all six groups careful measurements were taken of every individual to determine if possible if there are external indica - tions of gaining capacity. These measurements included the fol - lowing: width and length of head, size of neck, chest girth, mid die girth, and rear girth, circumference of fore leg below knee, length from withers to hip bones, from last rib to hip, width thru uhoulder, width thru chest behind shoulder, width of body thru middle, thru flank and hind quarter, depth of chest, depth of middle, depth thru flank, width of loin, height from ground, pliability of skin, quality of hair, etc. THE 1909 RESULTS. The following year the same plan of keeping individual records and taking complete measurements was practiced with the three groups fed on different quantities of corn with alfalfa. These cattle were purchased in South Omaha as "hay-feds." They had been raised on the same ranch and none had been grain-fed previous to their purchase for experimental feeding. Those showing any tendency to be wild were rejected. The cattle used were uniformly quiet and very quickly adapted themselves to stall feeding, after which the records were begun. In this ex - periment there was very little difference in the condition of the steers but some were much smoother and more compact than others. Two of the low set, smooth kind were placed in each group and classed as good feeders; two that were heavier in bone, a little coarser thruout, and more leggy were also placed in each group and classed as fair. The remaining two of each group were decidedly off type, being very leggy, angular in ap - pearance, and in some instances more narrow in build. These were classed as common. This division in all the groups was merely arbitrary — a matter of general appearance at the begin ning of the experiment. The records by group follow. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Economical Beef Production 35 i iis ((« jo aJ8«i3Ay P 3 w 5 CO 2 s 2 I • (uouituoo) 9 PUB g JO 9J*BJ9AV m 95 s CM R -2 33 O « £ ?■ S ■ ft a - ■ ( I(J«J) Q PUB JO 0JS«J3Ay g 9 — CO 8 CM 2 I co o 28. a 1 s : I(poo3) z pu« i jo a£ui3AV i 3 ■M 8 8 X s ~ &amp; 3 i J,_ &lt;c &amp; § — IM JJ 2 "* "O 2 S 8 2 "2 o s % s p s 3 ft 2 5 X 2 s ai &amp; ti- i 5 — xoMeJjxar-aq X 8 CM H X ■ E a o X _i_ S 55 S s s * g X S 8 I ll: n s £ — psoioeocoascp !8ie©ocoi | -»x •" SM N "* ' «O 2 1 * s _i_ O5 — a £ s § s s at a s i 5 lO ?? 5 ! - gsS3ScS«»So — cMMcofcoot^ s = s ! w4 : i 1 3 "I 1 ] OO^OOODt^OX :» :1 :1 i-8 :• : • : •§ :| :| I I -S :s : § ;- : | : s .a : a : &amp; ; §. £.5 :«-S:3-Si 5 I j « £■&lt; •&lt;! ■&lt; o k tS o '&amp;*§ ■ : : 5 |j= : : -*» o 5 If I" ! f||| I </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 XI8 1IB jo a&amp;ueAy g s I oi 8 id s 2 •d ■d So o ■^ «» S£s| I , (aomaioo) U Pn« 01 jo a£hu0Av H 3 CM 8 id id V4 3 s id B 8 2 si; (JW) ZT P«« 6 }0 338J9AV s — S « jo 9 •a — 35 8 fe 3 s SIS! i (pooa) 8 Pn« i I ■a 8 lO 5 cb id 8 o 3 £ 8 Z -."§9 I I CM § 8 US CO s ■a ■^1 §3 si 8. sis 5l vH 2 w •a 3 lO 8. % &amp;^Si I I o I 5 04 3 *4 — 5 CD 5 CO s 8 JM I I 1M •2 3E — So g SIS e 8 pi 5 IO 6 •a 3 •o o s Hi r- 8 8 I CO at lO 8 d g i ! ! I i a I "S I | I 1 [1 1 } 1 1 i s iliiii t * - ye S" &lt;c _ J3c c o a? S © &gt;&gt; m t»-3 8 3 "3 "i "3 -s g* g^ g£ § bc^ be § &lt; &lt;&lt; &lt; O K O a&gt; • 1 S-i I s : Q. » 8 .g : I § : . 8. ' i E ° : a c : I si 1 I" *** I i </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Economical Beef Production ■a: 1 ~* CM ? 30 B 30 s eg 2 3 8 2 s a sir 1 ( uommoo) ]O 33BJ3A V I B IM 3 I 00 ■ oo S t~ S O 00 ~i&gt; — ■* SC- ■ ! i iTPa«9T jo aifeaaA v «4 X eg 00 5 35 x CO ■ f CD O — ■* 3S O 00 ■* -^ •*» T»^ ! (pooJ8) 81 P«9I jo aJSBjaAV M 2 35 s 2 P 3 2 S S in k 2 2 2 2J eg oo — s 0 O — 8 3 id eg eg N SI S3 3 * 8 S 051 s a a? 1« r i! « -£ r- O eg — ■ » t^ — CO 2 &amp; S S3 §2 ■o X 31 6 30 M 8 2 3 a a s ill H -T S5 C*5 3 CM ■ CO 00 30 3 s 00 S 2 5 x CD PI S S s ass » t&gt; a 30 K X 1 i BQ I I : : £ : "g : t : a ■ "3 : "S : | : *J] hill I l|ij ■a - ?. : 2 s ?* i ■ 4s i ° "2 s g r^ *f r+\ ft* f? r^ i I O 1 a. I </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Economical Beef Production In Group I of this experiment we see a variation in dailv gains ranging from 2.46 lbs. to 3.22 lbs. — a difference of 0.76 lb. Each steer was fed 12 lbs. of corn per day and all the alfalfa that he would consume. As a result there was shown a marked difference in capacity ranging from 14 to 20.2 lbs. of alfalfa, the largest amount being consumed by the heaviest gainer. The difference in gains, however, could not be attributed entirely to the roughage consumed, as the smallest gainer consumed next to the largest quantity of alfalfa. In this group the two steers classed as good sold for the highest price because they put on a little more flesh and were perhaps somewhat better in quality. Those called fair feeders made the largest gains. In this experi - ment the better steers show the most profit because all were purchased together and at the same price. Had the good feeders been sold by themselves they would have cost more. Steer No. 4 of this group classed as fair was the most remarkable gainer of all steers in this experiment, making not only the highest average — 3.22 lbs. per day — but this was done on the light grain ration — 12 lbs. per day. He was not unusually large in heart girth — 72.1 inches per thousand pounds as compared with 73.5 for No. 1 , the smallest gainer of this group. He was. however. 15.2 inches larger than No. 1 in middle girth and much larger than any other steer of the group, in fact the largest middle girth of the entire number in the experiment. By referring to his picture it will be observed that he shows great depth of body, which very likely explains his unusual capacity for roughage. It is significant, too, that No. 1, the smallest gainer of Group I and next the smallest of the entire experiment, had the smallest middle girth of the entire number, weight considered. No. 1. however, was the best seller of the group and No. 4 next the K Group II the daily gains varied from 2.41 lbs. for No. 10 lb«. for No. 7. tho No. 12 gained practically as much as No. .98 lbs., a larger gain for the size of the steer. Here again </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 it is significant that steers Nos. 7 and 12 had the largest middle girths of the group— No. 12 95.7 inches, and No. 7 90.8 inches, calculated on the basis of 1000 lbs. average weight. Xo. 12 was also largest in heart girth, but No. 7 was smaller than N&lt;&gt;. in. the lowest gainer. Steer No. 7 was a smooth, compact tjft while No. 12 was rangy. No. 11. which gained practically as much as 12, 2.95 lbs., was a low set steer, but heavy boned. N&lt;&gt; 8 — a grade Hereford, also a good gainer — was the smoothest and thickest steer in the experiment and sold for the highest price, making a net profit of |9.21. In this group we have also one of the poorest sellers in No. 10 and the least profitable of all in the experiment. He was a leggy, narrow steer and did not take on sufficient flesh to sell well. In this group the good steers made better gains on the average than the common, and much larger profits. In Group III the daily gains ranged from 2.44 lbs. to 3.18 lbs., a difference of 0.74 lb. The two biggest gainers were largest in heart girth and but one exceeded them in middle girth. Con trary to the results in Group IT. the good steers in this group made smaller daily gains than those called fair and common and it would seem that so far as gains are concerned the smooth, compact steers had little or no advantage over the rougher, more i - angy types. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Steers In Group I of Experiment II as they appeared when the records were begun. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Steers in Group I of Experiment II as they appeared at the close when </seg>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">Steers in Group III of Experiment II, as they appeared when the records were begun. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Steers in Group III of Experiment II, as they appeared at the close when </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Herdsman A. R. Blrelow taking measurements. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Boomomicml Beef Production 47 GENERAL DEDUCTIONS. Ej complete tabulation of all measurements of the individ n both experiments have been made, but it seems best to old these from publication until still more evidence has been (d. Only a few very general deductions can be safely made 8 time. While the so-called better types of feeder steers — those more compactly built, smoother, etc., did not seem to make larger gains, they did with few exceptions fatten more rapidly and sold for a higher price when finished. These types are therefore more profitable for the farmer who breeds the cattle he fattens and they are also more profitable to the man who buys feed - ers if they can be had for a small advance in cost over the more common kinds. The results of the first experiment show very conclusively that at the present time the market makes too much difference between good and common feeders. Since the coarser, more rangy cattle gain as rapidly, it would seem that the difference in the price of feeders should be but little more than their difference as killers, which is determined more largely by condition than by quality. If in the first experiment the com - mon cattle had cost 40 cents per hundred less than the good feeders rather than 80 cents, the profits per head would have been about the same. This should not be interpreted to be an encouragement to breed the common kind, but at existing market quotations it sometimes pays to buy that class to feed. The one who breedB and grows this inferior class of cattle is the real loser, for it costs but very little more to breed the better kind — simply the difference in the price of a good bull as compared with a so-called scrub. In the second experiment, where all steers were figured at the same price per pound at the beginning, the good types made a net profit of $6.17 per head as compared with $2.01 on the common kind. This difference of $4.16 per steer would make it profitable to pay $150 more for a good sire than a common one. even for one crop of calves. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Economical lice} Production 48 SIZE OF HEART GIRTH AS AFFECTING GAINS. It is still a matter of doubt in the mind of the writer as to how much the size of the heart girth affects gains. While there were several individual exceptions, the three best gainers of each of the six groups in Experiment I showed on an average larger heart girths than the three poorest gainers of each group, ex - cepting Group III in which the three poorest gainers measured 71.3 inches as compared with 69.7 inches for the average of the three best. This, however, may be explained by the fact that steer No. 12, a large chested animal but very wild and nervous, made a low gain. In Experiment II there were two groups that proved exceptions to this and there were a larger number of individuals with relatively small heart girths that made good gains. The size of rear girth seems to have less influence than the chest. Some of the best gainers were large in bone and some were small. In general it may be said that the best gainers were more closely coupled as determined by the distance from last rib to hip. Wide heads and thick necks seem to be also more in favor, altho there were a number of large gainers that were long in the head. Width of head does, however, mean earlier maturity in most in - stances. MIDDLE GIRTH AS A FACTOR. In all nine groups of both experiments the three best gaining steers showed on the average larger middle girths than the three poorest gainers and there were but few individual exceptions to this. It seems quite certain that steers showing greater depth and width of body in the middle, or region of the paunch, are larger gainers and more economical producers. It was also found that the larger nuinber of the best gainers had the more pliable skin, but there were several exceptions to this. PLAN OF EXPERIMENT NOW IN PROGRESS. Owing to the fact that condition, age of animal, nervousness, etc., influence results materially, this work is now being carried </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Economical Beef Production 49 forward on a somewhat different plan. Forty-eight steer calves, all born the same month, are being reared on skim-milk npple - mented with grain, each fed separately and in the same manner. so that whatever difference is found in individuals cannot be attributed to a difference of feed at any stage in the development of the animal from birth to maturity. There are widely con - trasted types, some from well-bred sires and some from common stock. They are fed in stanchions and it is thought this hand - ling from birth will eliminate any nervousness. Individual records of gains and measurements at different stages in growth will be kept until the calves are ready to sell at the age of two CONCLUSIONS FROM THESE EXPERIMENTS PART I — FOODS. EThe results of two experiments show that a good quality rsely ground linseed-meal (old process) has a feeding value y superior to old process cottonseed-meal, and that either «e feeds is better for supplementing corn for fattening than wheat bran at current market values. K2) The results of one experiment show a high feeding value cold pressed cottonseed-cake, which with corn and corn-stover e larger daily gains than any combination of foods used at station. E) The results of two experiments show that excellent gains be made by using corn-stover as roughage if the corn is srly supplemented with a so-called protein concentrate. I) The results of three experiments show that at current ?s beef can he produced in Nebraska more economically by use of alfalfa in connection with corn than by the use of ein concentrates — linseed-meal, cottonseed-meal, or bran, a the roughage consists of prairie hay. (5) The results of three experiments indicate that when corn is from 35 to 50 cents per bushel and alfalfa not to exceed $7.00 per ton, considerably less than a full feed of corn, probably 14 to </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 F.mnomivul Beef Production E&gt;unds per day for a two-year-old steer, is more profitable a full feed. If corn is worth 50 to 60 cents per bushel, some - approaching a half feed of this grain (10 to 12 lbs. per would seem most profitable if a few more weeks may be for the finishing process. EThe results of two experiments show that the groups fed Jly on alfalfa gave a better quality of meat as indicated lor, marbling, etc. PART II— INDIVIDUAL DIFFERENCES. (7) With respect to the animal, two experiments show a great variation in the capacity of individuals to make gains under similar conditions, and this variation, tho apparently not due to the quality of the cattle, is, however, influenced more or less by condition of flesh at the beginning. It is not unusual for one steer to make one-fifth larger gains than another on the same feed — both in the same condition of flesh at the beginning — and with correspondingly larger profits. E While in these experiments the smooth, more compact of cattle did not necessarily make larger gains than the er, more rangy types, they did fatten more rapidly and sold higher price per pound at the close of an equal period of E) Common feeders may sometimes be purchased at a price will make them more profitable to the feeder, but they are profitable to the grower or to the farmer who grows and ns his cattle. K0) Cattle that show a nervous disposition seem handicapped aking gains under confinement. Ill) Nearly all of the largest gainers of both experiments « steers which measured large middle girths at the beginning he feeding period, and it would seem that size of middle girth n important factor in determining future gains. bear anv definite relationship to rate of gain some of the best </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Eamomicml H&lt; &lt;f Production 51 Eire being large in bone and some relatively small; nor was any definite relationship between heart girth and rate of tho the large majority of the best doers of the several 38 were large in heart girth. With but few exceptions the gainers showed more pliability and softness of skin. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. The writer wishes to acknowledge the efficient services of Mr. A. R. Bigelow. a graduate of the School of Agriculture, who fed and weighed the cattle in these experiments and who took the measurements of all individuals. Were it not for the extreme care and precision of his work these results would be of little value. Acknowledgment is also made of assistance rendered by Assistant Professor Rail and J. H. Gramlich in compiling tables and checking figures. ;uid to L. W. Chase for taking the photo </seg>
            <seg id="p052">I So f &lt;&lt; • c &gt;&gt;•£ g 4 - * 9 ik. 1 I I "?z 2 I </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>