<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Protein Requirements for Finishing Turkeys</title>
               <date value="1936-04">1936-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 298 April, 1936 Protein Requirements for Finishing Turkeys F. E. Mussehl and C. W. Ackerson Part of Lot Y-32 used m the first experiment. The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY This bulletin contains reports o£ three experiments ' that were planned to yield data on the best-adapted protein levels for the "finishing" ration for turkeys — that is, the ration fed from the time turkeys are five months old until they are marketed. Young toms were used in two of the experiments and young hens in the third. The feeding period was six weeks. A 16.24 per cent protein level for the entire ration (including both mash and grain) was compared with 21.04 in the first test and 1-4.54 with 18.30 in the last two. The lower levels proved as produc - tive as the higher in each instance and much more economical. Three practical mash formulas arc discussed. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Protein Requirements for Finishing Turkeys P. E. MUSSEHL, Department of Poultry Husbandry and C. W. ACKER5ON, Department of Agricultural Chemistry Turkeys are like other animals used for meat production in that the most economical conversion of feed into gains occurs during the early part of the growth period. The feeding period must, however, be suf - ficiendy extended to produce a well-finished market carcass, since with turkeys more than with most other meat animals, quality influences demand and market value. The highest grade of dressed young turkeys is referred to as U. S. Special or U. S. Grade AA. The following description applies to this grade as used in marketing practice at the present time: "Young, fine-grained, soft-meated bird, . with broad, full-fleshed breast, and with the entire carcass fully covered Fig. 1. — U. S. Grade AA quality. Premium prices can be obtained for birds of this grade. with fat. Must be well bled, well dressed, and practically free of pin - feathers, and have empty crop. No flesh bruises allowed; and only very slight skin abrasions, bruises or discolorations permitted, none of which shall be on the breast. Slightly dented breast bone (not to exceed 14 inch in depth) permitted but no crooked breast or other deformities allowed. A broken or disjointed wing above the wing tip, or a broken or disjointed leg, not permitted. Must be dry-picked or semi-scalded and must be dry-packed." Rations and feeding methods which produce the largest proportion of birds of this quality in the shortest possible feeding period and at the lowest cost are naturally desirable. One of the specific problems is, How much protein should be used to insure good feather maturity and good fleshing? The protein problem is particularly important, because protein concentrates are usually the most cosdy items in the turkey ration. Experi - ments to contribute to an answer to some of the questions involved were conducted at this Station in 1932, 1933, and 1934. Data from these experi - ments are presented in this bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 298 FIRST EXPERIMENT One hundred vigorous, young Bronze toms, averaging 156 days old, were divided into two lots of fifty birds each for an experiment which was started on October 1, 1932. The two lots will be referred to in this report as X-32 (low protein) and Y-32 (high protein). Both lots received the same amount of grain mixture (whole yellow corn 50 per cent, wheat 25 per cent, and barley 25 per cent) daily, this being arbitrarily set at 28 pounds per hundred birds. The protein content of the grain mixture used was 11.7 per cent. In addition to the grain the birds had free access to a mash mixture adjusted for the lots to pro - vide markedly different protein levels. The variations in the protein level of the mash were produced by using different amounts of a protein concentrate mixture, which is referred to as 4-X, and which consisted of equal parts by weight of meat scraps, fish meal, dried buttermilk, and soybean meal. The high biological value of the 4-X combination of concentrates for poultry had been demonstrated in two experiments with growing chicks. 1 This combination of proteins was used in these experiments to establish a principle of protein utilization, and it is not to be concluded that this mixture is recommended for practical rations. The protein level of the 4-X concentrate was 55.1 per cent. The basal ration used in the mash mixtures X-32 and Y-32 was as follows: FORMULA BASE XY-32 Lbs. Yellow cornmeal 310 Shorts 210 Bran 110 Pulverized oats 110 Alfalfa meal 100 Salt 10 "850 The mash for lot X-32 was made of: Lbs. Base XY 900 Protein concentrate 4-X 100 liooo The protein level of mash X-32 was 18.3 per cent. The mash for lot Y-32 was made of: 1 Lbs. Base XY 700 Protein concentrate 4-X 300 1^000 1 F. E. Mussehl and C. W. Ackerson, Utilization of Protein Concentrates by the Growing Chick, Poultry Science, Vol. 14, No. 2, 1935. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Requirements for Finishing Turkeys The protein level of mash Y-32 was 25.4 per cent. Each lot of fifty toms received 14 pounds of the grain mixture as listed above daily and in addition had free access to the mash. The experiment was divided into two approximately equal periods, and the feed consumption, indi - vidual weights, and gains were recorded for each period. Table 1 pre - sents data on feed consumption and weight increase for each lot. There were no mortalities in either lot during the experiment. Table 1. — Feed consumption and gain, first experiment. Lot X-32 Lot Y-32 Item Low-protein ration High-protein ration 1st period 2nd period 1st period 2nd period . I 23 days 21 days 23 days 21 days "'• Lbs. Lbs~. Lbs Grain consumption 299 295 299 295 Mash consumption 599 70 o •?" l /^ Average weight at end of period.. 16.6 18 8 17 0 1 1 7 Average weight at beginning of 187 Av^gainper bw: :::::::• "•] x \\ "•« »™ Pounds feed per pound gain 9.4 9 ' x g~ 116 Total gain for the -M-day period per bird (lbs.) 41 Protein level of entire ration not including small amount of green feed in yard (p.ct) 162 21 0 tkJ.Z nty f ffOm C3ch ° f the tWO Iots wcrc drcsscd g«ded at SECOND EXPERIMENT SJ^'^IS^aV fced cons " raption a " d 81i " £ " - h </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 298 Table 2. — Feed consumption and gain, second experiment. Lot X-33 Lot Y-33 . Low-protein ration High-protein ration 1st period 2nd period 1st period 2nd period , 21 days 21 days 21 days 21 days Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Grain consumption 499 577 497 551 Mash consumption 499 577 497 551 Weight at end of period 16.5 19.0 17.0 19.1 Weight at beginning of period ... 14.3 16.5 14.3 17.0 Average gain per bird 2.2 2.5 2.7 2.1 Pounds feed per pound gain 7.4 8.8 6.0 8.8 Total gain for the 42-day period per bird {lbs.) 4.7 4.8 Protein level of entire ration not including small amount of green feed in yard (p.ct.) 14.5 18.3 All birds were dressed at the end of the experiment and graded by an experienced grader. One bird in Lot X-33 had been accidentally killed so that only 59 birds were available for grading. The classification was as follows: U. S. Special or Prime U. S. Choice Lot X-33 : 56 3 Lot Y-33 56 4 220 YOUtfQ BPOrtZE . 'yS \f yS 18 TOMS Otf OA-riOrtS— I X y\ S WITH VAI?YI/fci ppoTClrt j&amp;S&amp;S y^/cfir — fe#r — : — r — t^?^^5?Pr / / L J I yT S •— T Oil.— ■ Ill I I I I I I I I Fig. 2. — Growth curves for Experiments I and II. There was, therefore, no significant difference in the quality or finish, nor was there a significant difference in the weight at the end of the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Requirements for Finishing Turkeys experiment. From the standpoint of economy the advantage was decid - edly in favor of the low-protein lot. THIRD EXPERIMENT For the third experiment 166 females, averaging 148 days old at the beginning of the experiment, were divided fairly into two groups. The same rations and essentially the same feeding practices were used as for Experiment No. 2, for which young toms were used. Table 3 presents data on feed consumption and gains for the two 21 day feeding periods. Table 3.— Feed consumption and gain, third experiment. Lot X-34 Lot Y-34 Item Low-protein ration High-protein ration 1st period 2nd period 1st period 2nd period 21 days 21 days 21 days 21 days „ . Lbs - U&gt;s. Lbs. Lbs. Grain consumption 3 33 349 351 309 Mash consumption 306 349 343 309 Weight at end of period 9.1 l 0 4 p 2 ,„, Weight at beginning of period... 8.2 91 8 2 &lt;3 ? Average gain per bird 0.9 13 10 11 Pounds feed per pound gain 8.4 6.6 83 71 Total gain for die 42-day ' ' period per bird {lbs.) 2.2 2 1 Protein level of entire ration not including small amount of green feed in yard (p.ct.) 14.5 lg3 11 1 1 _l . ---" -*^" I 83 YOUNG HENS PER LOT Fig. 3.— Growth curves for Experiment III. Twenty representative hens from each group were dressed at the end of the experiment. Two experienced turkey graders indicated that there was no significant difference in the market quality of the two groups. CONCLUSIONS £. There appears to be no advantage in using mash mixtures with more than 17.5 per cent protein from the 150th day to the finish of the feeding periods for turkeys. When approximately half mash and half grain arc </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 298 fed, the protein level of the entire ration for this period with a 17.5 per cent protein mash will be approximately 14 per cent. PRACTICAL APPLICATIONS Just what feedstuffs can best be used in rations for finishing turkeys will depend upon relative prices. Prices vary from year to year, and in. different sections of the state and nation, depending upon availability of feedstuffs. Several principles which have general application may, how - ever, be illustrated with typical mash formulas, all of which will be ex - pressed in 1,000 pound batches, so that costs can be calculated more quickly. Table 4. — Suggested mash formulas. T ,. Formula Formula Formula Ingredients 12 3 Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. 1. Yellow cornmeal 350 ... 350 2. Shorts 200 340 3. Bran 100 200 4. Ground wheat ... 200 5. Pulverized oats or barley 100 200 200 6. Alfalfa meal 100 100 100 7. Meat scraps 40 30 40 8. Soybean oil meal 80 100 80 9. Pulverized limestone 20 20 20 10. Salt 10 10 10 Total 1,000 1,000 1,000 Formula No. 1 (Table 4) may be used when corn is relatively reas - onable in price, and when shorts and bran are cheaper than wheat and other competitive grains. White cornmeal can be used, but yellow is to be preferred. Use any of the common grains, corn, barley, wheat, kafir, to supplement this mash. Use formula No. 2 when milling by-products are relatively cheap and corn is high in price. Ground kafir and other sorghums may be substi - tuted for 200 pounds of the shorts in formula No. 2 when price relation - ships favor the substitution. When mash No. 2 is used, at least half the grain should consist of whole yellow corn. Corn which is too soft for grinding can be used for the grain part of the ration. A grain mixture of 50 per cent 'whole yellow corn, 25 per cent wheat, and 25 per cent barley may be used. When corn is the cheapest grain available, it may be used solely as the grain feed. Formula No. 3 is recommended when shorts and bran cost more than wheat. This situation rarely obtains, but when it does, more wheat should be used. Fish meal is not recommended as a concentrate for the last six weeks of the feeding period because of its effect on the flavor. Fish meal can, however, be used in rations during the first five months of the growth, period. ' I 6 "! </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>