<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>PROCEEDINGS OF THE TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL MEETING OF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association HELD AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 16-21 1905</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL MEETING OF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association HELD AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 16-21 19C5 Prepared by L P. LUDDEN, /ecretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">r a r v Nebraska State Poultry a I o fits excellency, John H . Mtdh ka: Dear Sir:— In compliance with the law in this case made and pro I herewith transmit the Annual Report of the Nebraska State Poultry Asso - ciation for the year closing January, 1904-5. Very respectfully, Secretary. ;.n, Nebraska. April - </seg>
            <seg id="p004">OFFICERS OF THE NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSO- CIATION ELECTED FOR 1905. ■ NORVAL Day President Seward Vice- President Secretary Fremont Lincoln Lincoln BLUDDEN 1.V.MAN Treasurer BOARD OF DIRECTORS. K. Campbell . H. Grekn Osceola Fremont K Smith Johnson Bowrrs Lincoln Holdrege Bradshaw </seg>
            <seg id="p005">PROCEEDINGS of the TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL COVENTION of the NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION held at LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 16-21, 1905. Auditorium Building. The Nebraska State Poultry Association met at four o'clock. The meet - ing was called to order by Hon. T. L. Norval, president. Roll call by sec- I.udden as follows; Norval, Bowers, Wheeler, Larson, Smith, Cham - ook. At this lime it was moved and seconded that the further call roll be dispensed with. Motion adopted Ecretary Ludden announced that there would be a meeting at Room niversity Building, on Wednesday evening, at which would be deliver - cture by Miss M. L. Smith and Hon. C. M. Lewelling. That the next regular business meeting of the Association would be held Thursday evening at the Commercial Club room. On motion the Association adjourned. Lincoln, Nebraska, January 17 Room 106 State University. Mr. C. M. Lewelling called the meeting to order and - Bt seems that our poultry people are slow in getting around but we are ready to begin and as it is time I don't see why we should wait any •r. I take pleasure in introducing to you Miss SI. L. Smith, who will l to you on the subject of "The A B C of Poultry Culture." &gt;mith: It is rather disappointing to me not to find a room full of members of your Poultry Association. I wish to present some matters which I consider important in the poultry industry of this country and as your members are supposed to be people of experience I am sorry that there are not more of them here. ' Lincoln, Nebraska, Januar </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 I n ■• the subject, ihe A B C of the poultry but when I go out in institute work, as I do in the State of Nebraski to speak to - who arc not much interested in this important subject, I speak up - on the fundamental principles of poultry and I hope I may be able to throw out some hints along that line this evening. As there are so few of you here l« hard for me to know just wh:i' each one of you, perhaps i not do better than to tell you a little of my own experience in the try busim I was a teacher and I gave up that business l&gt;ecause it was very hard ; mu.:h lurder on the nerves th in m inv oth;r kin 1&gt; of wjrk, and I de - 1 to engage in the poultry business We have a large farm in Michigan . 640 acres, which perhaps might not be: very large for Nebraska, but we . ill portion of it for poultry use. We had kept poultry in the irmy and took care of the poultry in the wintertime, not expecting any - but in the summer and spring time sold them hut did not exper e any money from them. We just expected to have enough to eat and some to sell. While I was horn and brought up on the farm I had not a - amount of experience in regard to farm matters but I started out in :iess with a determination to succeed and did meet with success. There ■ better instruction than one gets from experience. I had been intere e poultry business in town hut that is not so desirable as it is to en. in the business on a large scale with plenty of room, where yon can have a • run for the poultry. We never paid much attention to the sale of chickens but pai 1 more attention to the sale of egijs. The people would what kind of eggs have you got for sale on your farm, what kind of ejjijs art we told them that they were not altogether different from our hbors but while we were getting eggs every day most ot our neighbors getting but very few. In our country there was more money in eggs than neat, of course we were a little nearer the New York market and so it paid us to go into the business in a wholesale way. Perhaps you would like to know the method we used in gettin :t was not unusual but was what any poultryman would use. You understand there must be a certain amount of warmth to make the hens lay as it is natural for hens to lay in the summer. To make them lay in the winter you must make it comfortable and warm for them, you can have their houses as warm and comfortable for them in the winter as it is for them in the summer and that is very essential, and by giving them exercise, in order to have success. To my mind that is the best way for egg production. You know hens are somewhat like people happiest when working. Cackling hsns are the hens thit produce the ef ic hens are not good egg producers, they are large and like to set id in the sun but don't like exercise. The general productive fowl, like the Wyandotte and others, require a little more care and if the e that care and the proper feed they will produce more es-gs. The brown 10m and Minorcas are the fowls for me, they are energetic and a and they lay the most eggs; and that is the great reason why people in towns like a general utility fowl . Hens should not be kept in a room or building </seg>
            <seg id="p007">B there is a draft, if you have a cold room they might freeze their combs, have chickens with a heavy comb there uuch danger of their frozen . The subject of the hen house is very importair u make it warm anil comfortable for them, with the proper feed and care, there are :uls of dollars to be mill.' from eggs in the winter tin. Kperi - ■ that pullets are the best layers and to market the hens. We must not keep for production a hen over two years old. The hen must have thnt kind of food that will enable her to form the egg but she must have nurish - mentand water, and grit, and must have tc only needs enough of a fat and warming fo &lt;1 so as to keep her in good con t- 1 to have an old rule that the hen must not l&gt;e : wanted her to la you should not be feed too much of the fat producing food. The better the hen is kept the larger the egg, we used In the summer time the hen can forage and she forages and secures a balanced ration and she gets the p : grasses and grit, but in the winter we have to provide for that and balance her rations for her. There are various wavs in which it may be done, out in the pasture there are bones, they may be gathered and ground. If you are not able to get the ■ u can, however, get the poultry food that is manu - factured now, they have an ideal poultry food and it contains meat and blood and bones, it is an excellent food, I feed it twice a week, ! like to give it every day but rather I feed the scraps from the kitchei not want, however, to feed onions as it would taint the ( have in Nebraska a poultry food that is excellent and tl !fa, there is no food equal to it. It can be fed as meal. Clover is also excellent bu good as alfalfa. It there is no mill handy you can chop the alfalfa and then steam it and let it stand twenty-four hours and then stir in tome shorts or something to make a stiff, dry meal, a sort of mess, and feed it in that way. Chickens are verv fond of it, especially the leaves. In i: the alfalfa and clover man v leaves fall and drop off on the barn floor. These may be gathered up and used in this way. We rake them up and put them in a sack and when the sack is full take them to the lien There should be no waste on the farm where you have chickens, they :id pick up their own living, they are excellent foragt In the winter time, and for that matter at all times, it is necessar a hen to have grit or a sand pile to run to, it is very necessary for them. They run down without it and would die if they did not get it. There is lot of grit on the market. The commercial grit I think should be taken to the hen house and pounded up and in a very short time there will be none of it left. Oyster shells are excellent, is is quite necessary to have them about the place, an old plaster or lime pile broken dishes may answer. There are good substitutes for the commercial grit. The hen must have lime to form the eggshell, feed all the eggshells that you can back to the bens. If you think it will lead them to eat eggs crush them up well, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 but I don't think it will, we simply throw them out with the other scraps. The hens must have the delicacies because with them they will give greater returns than by giving them to the pigs, the pigs can get along without the delicacies or the scr t long a^o a cook at our house was caught in the act of putting scraps in the siove. I read her a lecture. I have great trouble with the cooks to have them save all scraps. All those must be for the chickens, they appreciate all attentions of that kind. It there are any here who keep poultry in town I want to make a suy to them. Mdny people ttiinic it it almost impossible to keep hens in town and have them do as well as those upon the farm and have them kept shut up. I think they can be kept in low* almost as well, of course you should put some hay or straw or something in the yard and then throw their feed in amongst the straw so as to have them scratch, and as we say, work for it, :ves them exercise. It is well sometimes to hang up some meat or some cabbage or something green so that they will have to jump for it, this M gives them exercise. Once more I wish to speak about the necessity of feeding hens egg pro. ducing feed. It is also very important that a hen should have plenty of water. It is overlooked by a great many people, water is a necessity for all stock as well as the human family. I would uige upon you the importance of feeding at a regular time, the hen should never be disappointed when she goes for water. The first thing in the morning the importance of water '. be estimated. In the winter time the best practice is to put warm water in drinking bottles. In the winter time I make mess for them, I feed mess twice a week, on other occasions I feed forage, cabbage, beets, apples, potato peelings. Occasionally I co&gt;k up small potatoes and sometimes put in turnips and then stir in some kind of meal or shorts. I thank you for your attention. Dr. Peters of the Iniversity, being called upon, said I came in here as a listener, I was very much interested in the talk and I feel that a large per cent of the diseases of fowls could be prevented by proper feeding. One point is this. With most people who claim they are fowls it is improper care. I have found this in going over the state, with a great mumber who make a business of marketing chickens and who are engaged in the poultry business. They will start out by subscribing for a number of papers, tht-v will see some particular picture of fowls and they are not well enough versed with the conditions to give fowls proper atten - tion but they will start in and in a few weeks after they have started and after their fowls have arrived they have trouble. Their trouble is largely due to the fact that they did not take care of their chickens in a systematic - al way. If you want to be successful in the poultry business you want to bear in mind, as has been emphasized, to do everything with system. If yon start out to feed at a certain hour you must feed at that time. If you intend to feed at eight o'clock you must feed at eight o'clock and not ten or eleven-if you want good results. This is not a theory, it is born out by practical re- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEKR 9 I noticed this year in i , n from Burwell I think it w., iv, a large number of fowls. I never in my life fat When they get so fat, that is a loss localise they do n packer does not want them that way either. The - not the a of meat on them. But if you try feeding some lime or proper fee would make eggshells or make egg building, you will soon 1 me from your hens. That is the way a great main dissatisfied. If you bear in miud the little points in feeding all make a success in the poultry business I think th&lt; of live stock that is so profitable as the breeding of chickens but, as I say. you have to be right there every day and that is where a majority of people fall down, in not tending to these little thiag ;.iy. Dr. Peters now took the chair and announced the next speaker. I take pleasure, Ladn ntlemen, in introducing to j our best speakers. He is a man well known in our association and th out the state and I have no doubt you will be much interested in what he has to say. Mr. Lewelling of IJeaver Cuy. Mr. Lewelling: Ladies and Gentlemen. This is supposed to be the annual meet. the Poultry Association but I see very few of the members of the Association here this evening. The fact is that the poultry show up at the the attention &gt;l our m&lt; these convention week.- - there showing their poultry. The difference between insti along the line of raising poultry and being entertained at a poultry show it so great that the people are mostly at the show, however 1 take i who are here have come lor instruction and 1 to their benefit. 1 shall take up the su also Dr. Peters. This is a branch of industry that more j than any other branch of live stock, of hogs, horses, cattk can take the world over and in every civilized country and in semi-barbar - arly every family is engaged in raiding poultry Mime claim to be raisiug it for pleasure. It seems to me that the niu-i ie in it is the profit. You may take &lt;i flock of well brt them in an enclosure and feed them all th.il they need, all the water they uid charge it up to them on tue ledger, and then on the olhei - the ledger give them credit for all they produce, you will find at the the year that the poultry has given you a large profit of what the illy and their keep. You cannot i .mount oi other branch of business that I know of, for a good flock of well bred poultry will give you a profit of five hundred per cent. I am going to talk to you tonight more on the line of poultry on the farm as there is so much poultry raised on the larui. The fartm have to shut his pcultry up in an enclosure an M nine-tenths t the pou </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 any day, with which you can buy any article at the stores that you want. is some one in nearly every town engaged in buying eggs and w to pay their gold for the eggs and for the poultry that you take to them. 1 want to say to you that the poultry industry stands nearer to the poor man and poor woman than does any other industry. The family has very little to to go into the piultry business and the cow and the hen have kept hundre Is of families in the western part of the state during the dry seasons, and they were permitted to stay on the farm and hold it by reason of the cow and the hen, and had it not been for them thev would have had t - their farms. There seems to be more money invested in large stock on the farm than in the raising of poultry, at the same time however, you will find more or less poultry produces large profits. The feed for poultry on the farm is as nothing, it is scattered around through the fields and is consumed f poultry so that there is no feed to be charged up to the chickens. If we would get the best results we must give them the best care. Smith emphasised this and I don't want to carry that any further. If you are not going to give them the best care there is not much profit in poultry. If you have the very best breed of hogs and cattle that there is in existence and do not keep them and care for them well and give them shelter, there would be no profit in them. There is profit in almost everything that is hmndled properly and more profit in the poultry business if it is handled properly than anything else. How shall we treat them? In the first place, when I was a boy I traveled around through the country in the eastern states and in passing by the farm houses we would see the chickens roosting in the trees and on the fences. That is quite natural maybe, and all right in summer, a chicken naturally seeks to get away from harm and the higher et the less harm. They would therefore get used to that manner of iij an 1 would stav there in the fall or winter until they had frozen their combs and feet and then they would hobble around. But at the same time I have seen these hens become profitable when it became spring and even with their frozen combs. When they got in good condition again they would seek their nest in the weeds, lay a nest full of egg hatch out a bunch of chickens and hobble around with them. The older members of this Association have seen that. But it does not pay t poultry that way. A hen can only consume a limited amount of feed, the first feed that she has is to keep her body warm and she must burn up a certain amount of feed for that purpose, to keep her body at a normal temperature of 103 degrees. If she is kept in a place where it is cold and her body requires an extra amount of feed to keep it warm that ener: erted. If you should set a stove up in a large airv barn it would re - quire so much more fuel to keep it warm, so with the hen, she must require a certain amount of feed for warmth and energy, after that the energy will produce eggs. Kow in regard to the size and location of the poultry house. The first you would look to if you were going to build a house. would be the lo - , naturally you would look for a site where the water would run away </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 and you would seek the best location on the farm as you would in ca - were going to build your house to live in. We want to look for a place that is best to construct a house for the hen. In the first place I will say that the ground should be sloping because it is better to shelter from the north wind. If you have it so you can dig into the bank so as to make a sort of a dugout you have got a still better site than to build right on top of mnd. Dig back into the bank and have one side so that the wind cannot blow through. The wind cannot blow through the bank and have it in that shape you will find it easier to work Probably there are not many wives who would like to live in a dugout today, we have outgrown the former days, but a dugout for a chicken house is very essential makes a good warm place, where the hen can take care of herself. There is only one thing I want to impress upon you and that is that the house should face the south. Here I have in this drawing a picture of a house, it is 24 x 14 feet. There is just one window one foot from the ground. It would not do to build a house like that for ourselves. Our wives would not be satisfied in a house like that. The fact is that the hen wants that win - dow down within a foot of the ground; and if she will give you better re - sults with it there that is a good reason for putting it there, and she will. The policy of the poultrytnan is to look after the wants of his hens and as their nature demands it we will build the house in that way. In connectijn with this we will take up one of the greatest enemies to the successful raising of poultry. I wish to speak to you about a very small insect called a louse. Many farmers think they have chicken cholera when as a matter of fact the death of their hens is due to nothing more than the louse. It is one of the worst enemies the poultryman has to deal with. The hen that is the worst will be the one to show symptoms the first. When she gets off the perch in the morning she looks pale and she is weak, if you pick her up and lift her there is no flesh on her. She will go to feed in th time and drink and sit on the perch at night, she goes to feed the next day and each day she is getting weaker and weaker. She is covered with lice. Thirty days is the generation of a louse. Before she dies the lice will leave her and go on her mate. They leave .her in a body and go on to her mate. In a week or two there are five or six of the other hens showing the same sytn as the one that died, they will show symptoms of cholera aud as a matter of fact, there is no cholera about it, and before they die the lice will go onto others. The next time there will be half a dozen and they will all drop off the perch together, before they die the lice will go off onto the other hens. So it is natural for the poultryman to think that he has cholera in his flock and he goes to town and gets some medicine, he buys cholera medic.: it does not do any good. Now the hen will destroy these lice if you will give her an opportunity and she has not an opportunity to do so in one out of ten of the poultry houses that are built for her. ■[f we study this matter we will find that nature has provided a simple essential way for the hen to rid herself of these insects or vermin and she may destroy them. Ir. the first place the louse does aot breathe </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 h its mouth but through the pores in the side of its body. It cannot live without breathin - that she has lice on her body. Uen whei. not have, she is inclined to roll in the dust. The duck plays in the water, the hen rolls in the dust. The hen will onl_\ the water trough when she wants a drink and when she wants to cle;i! i body of lice she goes right down into the fine dust, she rolls and fills her feathers full of it. You have all seen them and when they shak' ad straighten their f&lt; iith that dust she c of the louse so full that when he undertakes to breath he draws this fine dust into the porrs. and i e pores, the louse is unable to breath and it therefore dies, the natural destruction of the louse. How easy and natural it is ■ iv farmers and poultry raisers, when their hens I to the in e and buy cholera medicine whereas this rolling :ie that ever was invented. If we will !-n us and follow out the I the hen our efforts will be crowned with success along this line. The reason the hen wants the window where we have placed it in this will shine ifl there on that fine dust. There must be a dust box right there by the window. It is two feet wide and one foot deep. All it needs is a I x 12 piece of lumber across the front of tlv and fill it full of this fine dust. You should take time when the ro ler this dust and fill up the l&gt;ox and it would be •me l&gt;arrels of this dust on hand and a good thinj; to mix in with it is some fine astu-s from the stove, mixing it well in the dirt. If you put the dust I* e the hens may not use it very much if the weather is ;iey will not use it very much at all in winter if it is in th; put it right where the sun can shine through the window and t can shine right into t u will find that box full of hens dusting them nearly all the time. The sun will not be up half an hour in tht ing before the box will be full of he;. There are plenty of reasons why we should put the dust by the window. I he perches in your chicken house should be attached to the back 'ith hinges and ■ ■ that they may l&gt;e raised up out of the v make it handy for cleaning out. It is quite necessary to have a run nd if you have a run way for your hens they will take care of them you keep them warm at night in cold weather egg production provided you furnish Um for them - p themselves free of lice. I have had people write me asking what ailed their poultry, I m write back and say, I believe your poultry must be lousy. They would seem to be indignant, they woui when we gathered up the hen just as she fell from the perch we could find no lice, I would then t where the lice were, I told them that th~y were not on that bird wh </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Please explain in regard to ventila'. I here should be ventilators made of I x 6 fencing lumber that wil id then come down within six inches of the bottom. If \ hole in the roof you would have a draft of wind that would r or your poultry. If you put the ventilator in this way as shown here is poultry house, it will not make draft If I going to make this poultry house I would give ventilation in the i L&gt;use in the summer time and close it up in the winter. Question: Is the window in that picture supposed to have lr but it could l&gt;e arranged to have hinges on. Tt me when I undertook to tell at Institutes how such a house as this could be built, four years ago. I was simply giving the people an idea. It may n t have been my fault but they did catch the idea and the people got it from this picture, and in the northern part of the state when I was up there two igo I saw that they had rearran^ mucli after this one and they told me they were ret - poultry in the winter time. There is another thing I will speak of right here anrl that is the matter of grit. It is very important that poui 1 have plenty of grit near by. The farmer does not need to look for grit, if an have grit it should be the farmer. The natural grit lor every bird, wild or domesticated, is sand. We have it nearly everywhere. The farmer haul a load of sand and put it where the M run on it. He will he surprised to learn the amount of grit thit lock will use up. To ilia; I will state that on one occasion one o! house as he had some cattle to sell. I naturally m here at tl vould be in the corral and as we went out to the corral we passed by where there was sand all over the ground. The gentleman remarks that he had hauled a load of sand up there but that the children had played in it so much they had scattered it over I tie guessed he have to haul another here would not be e he commenced to tell me that he had hauled I presumed that he had hauled it for his poultry as he had a lar rar bv, and I expected him to say that the hens had eaten it all up. Kut v. I said that the children had played in the sand and scattered it so all ar d that he did not know where it went and I said to him, ' haul up much of a load?" "Oh yes," h 1 hauled i the children have played in the sand and scattered it." I M could you scratch up here?" and he began to look around and weigh in his how much there was and th. Well, it will hustle me I bushel sack full,' and that was just about the amount there was. He said to me, "what do you suppose has taken it off '' "Why" I said, chickens have eaten it." and he said, "Oh. pshaw, you will have to show me," and from the tone of his voice I saw that he was disi. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 1 «^ *i » tr xi I in ■ 1 L ' * . ' l ii 1 1 1 1 uOWC * tr i , I i i il l 1 1 Wh^ 3 IflCL ludi il IS had eaten the sand as r 5. We passed on in ittle and coining back we saw two Plymouth Rock i pile, it was just about sunset, I said, "W1 there?" He said he didn't know, we •-re eating sand. "Now," he said, "that • &gt;d thing. I will feed my hens on sand hereafter, thai ■ d I can get for them." He appreciated what I had told him and hoped he would profit by it. 1 told him hens would give better re- Bfor having plenu of grit near by, than they would if they had t&lt; , and that the eating of ■ ltd the htn to product- ii There is not a farmer who cannot afford to have a sand pile ne.r md a good sand pile is better than commercial grit. You wili i.it hens will leave commercial grit and go to the s»nd pile. iis house here in the exhibit that you ha\ It is seven feet high to the eaves Question: What kind ef a floor Bothing but earth. Karth is the best 8oor you can have, the htn is . well satisfied with it and it is cheaper. If you put in a board floor ill have rats and vermin and you also make it celder through dr., Question: What kind of a box do you recommend for nests 5 The best box for poultry i box from the grocery store, it should l&gt;e well nailed together. Some have a long box, sixteen feet long, with par - in it but we can't use that s.&gt; well as we can a little smaller bos can tell about the right size that will make the nicest nest. Before nailing her the boards should be dipped in a tub of brine. The brine fill- Iid no kind of vermin or mice will work in because they cannot lit. We bore two ho'es in the box and then drive two nails ten inches apart in the side of the house and then you can i the box right on the nails. The hens v. ill us. quick ler. The idea is that they ar ire all alike it will be very beneficial or helpful when you want to take ' these nests and hang it in the hatching hou- In order to make the nest conform the nearest to Nature, before n them together put in two and a half inches of dirt in the bottom of the box and take some of the brine and put in and then stir the dirt until it In thick mud. The most natural place in the world for a hen to make her nest is on the ground and barring accidents, she will hatch the greatest number s, they being fertile, with her nest on the ground than in anv other We cannot set her on the ground but we can put dirt into these boxes. Then put some straw in it and hang it up where they will find it. the first hen that comes aloug to lay will fix that nest nicer than we can. n that limit her nest on the ground and among the weeds will hatch B though it rains, but the hate! </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 farmer can afford to be without a hatching; house. I will (It- &gt;ne as best I can. It shjuld be inide after the manner of this one here * as possible, there should be only one door. T - amply iioujjh for one thousand chickens, with tb&lt; window, the hatching hen net ■ blinds so as to make it dark at any time. The hens in there will not their nests for two days if the house is kept dark, a hen don't leave her nest in the dark. When these boxes are all hung around on the si the building there will be several hens laying in one nest and to undertake i hen and have five or sir other hens laying in that box at the same ■is suicidal, some of ti. 11 be broken and we cannot expect a re - &gt;le hatch from th But when a hen arrangi one of the ind has full intentions of doil u can lift the box down "d all, the box l&gt;eing already prepared with dirt and straw, an the box and hang it in the hatching house, then you can hang another box in the same place that you took this one from. Place these boxes in the hatching house until you have as many as twenty, this relieves the fanner"s wife of going around different places, behind corn cribs and hay stacks. looking for the setting hens, and thev are ail there in one pl.t .oh one has her own nest In the hatching house she knows when every or to hatch. Pos - sibly the one in the straw or hay stack may be broken up and discourager! a t sooner by having her nest there but in the hatching house the good wife s where they are. and in the morning after getting breakfast for her Iind and he has gone out to his work, she takes the feed and goes ry house, opens the door, raises the curtain it, and hen that is in there, even from three to four days, will get right up on the nest and come out, they know that i feed them hey fly down, she puts the feed down and goes out. Every hen will eat, and drink and go back to the nest again, in about an hour the will go bnck and she will find every hen on her nest, pull down the cur - ind make it dark for the next twentv-tour hours and not one ot Kwill move. I know it is easier for a farmer to raise one thousand chick - 1 hatching house t: in the old hap- Question: How warm will the walls have t tor a hatching house you don't need a very warm house but if it is lablv tight vou must have some ventilation, of course there is some ventilation through the cracks Question: Would you have the walls plastered Kes, I think I would but there ought to be an ' air chamber or space if tiding is built with stone or brick walls. Question: What would you say in regard to These perches are 2x6 set up edgeways and they should be hii </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 time the fanner might want to work under them. The farmer has plenty of straw and the best way to handle his poultry is to put three or four inches of straw under the perches and allow it to stay there until he cleans out the poultry house, which should be once a week. Question: Would you prefer a hatching house to an incubator? I hardly talk on the incubater subject but I do speak in regard to the hatching house because most of the farmers prefer to use the hatching to an incubator. If you are raising a small brood of poultry and in a small space you might use an incubator. The incubator is a 'subject by itself. I will say however, that I have three incubators and have very good success hatching with them. Most of the people who use an incubator feel that when they have a nice hatch they are at the end of their trouble but I say that their trouble has just begun. There is not much trouble hatching from an incubator but there is trouble raising them after they are hatched. I am very slow to advocate the incubator Question : If you had chickens in town which would you prefer to buy W sand? K would rather have sand than any grit I know of. Pot the commercial own on the ground side by side with the sand and the sand will be before the commercial grit is. If that don't settle the matter I don't what does, it does settle it so far as I am concerned. Question: What kind of a floor have you 3 Well, I would like to have a floor sloping a little. I don't generally say much about it because not one out often would use it. If you put straw in the poultry house and under the perches in the winter time the poultry can use that as a scratching place, but as a general thing the farmer does not need a scratching place as bad as the person in town. The farmer has a scratching place all around his barn and premises, the poultr find a scratching place even in the orchard where they will find worms and vermin, poultry is the best friend the horticulturist has got. Question: What have you to say in regard to tar paper? I think tar felt will make as good a roof as you will want and tht can lath and plaster under that. You would then have it absolutely tight. In regard to protecting the poultry from cold, it is absolutely like a farmer who keeps a dairy, and the same principle or theory of protecting cows and keeping up the flow of milk by having good protection and shelter for his cows applies equally to the farmer or any one who keeps poultry. If the hen is not properly cared for she stops laying. We have had some very cold weather just recently and if any poultry has been exposed the combs will be frozen. It is better to have a good poultry house and throw the feed and grain in amongst the straw with plenty of grit and then they will not </seg>
            <seg id="p017">their living out of their poultry \;mls. Farmers raise poul; to town each week a case or two of i buy all the groceries they want for their tabl&lt; ly. There is not one person out of tweni j u 'lRe, who is keep - half the poultry that he could keep and keep with profit. I thank you for your kind attention Commercial Club I Ee annual meeting of the Nebraska State Poultry Association was ening in the Commercial Club p.r The roll was called and on reaching the fortieth name on th&gt; \ man moved that the further call of tin - l having been found to be present. Khe minutes of the semiannual meeting having been read at th - ! semi-annual meeting, it •vas not necessary to re-read them meeting Treasurer I. L, Lyman then read his report as follows To the Officers and Members of the Nebraska State Poultry Reporting on the condition of the treasury at the time of t 1 semi-annual meeting last September ( the Fair grounds meeting have the honor to report in detail all the expenditures from the treasury on account of the winter show for 1904, and further that there remained an unexpended balance in my haml- | that report I have received from the State on December 17th Total Of this sum I have paid on voucher lov. 1 n. NEBRASKA, Thursday, Januar- cK&gt;ck P. M ,&gt;&gt;th Voucher No. 21 to Oct. 27th Voucher No. 239 to Thorpe &amp; Co , sup] 119th Voucher No. 120 W. S. Russell. 1 19th Voucher No. 121 C. H. Rhodes, j iow... 19th Voucher No. 122 Adam Thompson, jud show 19th Voucher No. 123 I.. P. H Total paid since semi-annual meet Balance now in hands of Treasu: </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 and placed on file Motion adopted. Mr. Ludden:- The work has been very heavy in the secretary's department owing to manner in which we handled the premium list and it has entailed a large ; of correspondence especially on account of the breeders that were not at the show. Ne^riv every one had to write to understand why they had &lt; eond or third premium; that they didn't receive a larger amount of money. Then the premium list this year, we never have had such a call for premium lists. We had two thousand lists printed and weare mailing these lists. I mailed 1640 of these premium lists and have sent a small sup - rach show in our immediate neighborhood, leaving us less than two hundred premiums for the work of this present show. The correspondence, this year have run very nearly to a thousand. The programs for the weeks meeting are mailed for the allied agricultural associations am! own members. I did not mail to exhibitors nor to those who are on the mail- Perhaps I do more letter writing than you may think necessar illow any inquiries touching our work in this state to pass, no matter how poor the scholarship, or how blurred the writing is, or ill-stated the I always try and write them courteously and encourage them to keep in touch with our poultry association. It is surprising the number of inquiries I receive concerning the birds that might go to a poultry show or that have been there. The only thing our records are lacking, is not knowing what judged each class. Perhaps the secretaries book ought to be extended that much to show what judge judged the different birds and what judge judged any particular class of birds. It has never been done before — keep - ing the record to know what judge has placed the score on the different The work of the show room in the secretary's department has been kept as well up as ever. We are ready to begin tomorrow to figure the amount due each exhibitor. By tomorrow evening every exhibitor can have his premium money if he so desires. The finances of the show roughly stated are, — the entry fees have fallen some short of last year, they are about $400. The door receipts will probably go from $150 to $200 more than last year. We have had a splendid run today, very nearly a thousand people. I didn't look after the ticket slip immediately before coming — the number can be ascertained by looking at the ticket seller's slip day by day but so far there have been in the neighborhood of 2500 tickets sold. The receipts from advertising will pay for the printing of the premium It costs two cents sending them out this year. K might perhaps, explain why there was a little balance left in the hands treasurer, Lyman. I think four or five of the exhibitors of last year have framed their orders drawn on the treasurer and kept them as a nir of the show because they have never turned up for payment and </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 somehow. They have applied for a duplicate. The book shows that the order was mailed to them and that they received it. We h overdraft of between two or three hundred dollars of three years mn we are now breaking even. The indications are now that we will keep right along this line. The report of the president will be made later The secretary read the following communication Hastings, Nebraska, I,. P. Ludden, - if the Poultry Asso. Dear Sir: I am commissioned by the Commerciil Club of tl ciation to holds it-, next annual meeting at Hi braska We would be glad to furnish a building or r rficient ca - pacity with heat and light, and will appreciate your acceptance tation. urs, President of the Commercial Club. Mr. Ludden ■ am informed that the Commercial Club of this city will present some of a proposition this evening but as yet I have not received it. A delegation from Hastings consisting of representatives Saddler, John - son and Mr. F. J. Benedict from Hastings appeared at this time before the association, they were accorded a hearing. Representative Sadler said: We came to indorse the statement contained in Mayor Miles' invitation. We would be glad to have you hold your next meeting in Hastings and will treat you with all the hospitality that we know of, and believe that y he well satisfied with your treatment. We will guirantee you ample Mr. Benedict I do not know as I can add anything more to what has been saiil A feel honored to have your acceptance of our invitation and t" next exhibition there. If you do, I assure you we will do all we can to care of you in a right and proper manner. I know you will all meet a very cordial welcome. Mr. Johnson: If there is no further plan for the location for holding the next nnwl meeting of the Nebraska State Poultry Association, and as Hastings has made us a very substantial offer. I mow irman, that we accept the proposition received from Hastings and tint we hold our next annual show in that city. Mr. Ludden: Ehe secretary of the Commercial Cluh of this city will be here in a few es and will speak to us on this subject as he has an offer to tnakt I to our next annual meeting. Mr. Chairman. I would like to ask you w: ng they have in Signed} C. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 KKS for our show' I they will give us ample room. They mean a double deck. We need and should have proper and K&gt;m without double deck. iddler: Personally I could not say. 'old me that they had a I ing lar id that they could furnish just as good a room as here. I see that you have a single deck hen suppose that th leek then vill do ie says sh --he will . I treat. it, and I am willing to say, as far as I am personally con- I will guarantee it for them and I know they will do it. Bv out to Hastings and holding your next meeting you will reach people and m to come to ■ who will not come here. Lincoln ought to he satisfied to have your in hold their meetings in this city when ..i-slature is in session. We have no legislature to draw the people to ■ w but I lielieve we can get the people to attend it and give yo tnce. The railroad facilities are good and people get in and out ot any direction with great ease and we would like to on hold your next show there. We will give you a nice room « [■-ladder to get into it. 'iiber: The Association will remember that last winter when the ' ha proposition was bet'oi m that was dispo&gt;&lt; '.use of the linty. I think we should be very slow and careful to act at thi on that account. I was not at the Fremont show but I understand that ex - s had to be taken up anil down bv means of an elevator and that is in handling stock. •jd'ien Eulil not be here tonight. He came be - i an implement building, steam heated, well e Auditorium here, suppo- I Ie made that stau hilv to the board n &lt; Mr. Terwilliger: I think h communication of this . ■ to state definitelv the si i have the matter fully belore us in order to act honestly on the proposition. While this matter is up for con think it would be a good idea in case of future propositions that shall be made to this Association, for the secretary to require parties to stai and room capacity. I am opposed to double decking ought to have a room of ampl- proportion. The ne too large. Th narrow we have to crowd :th the floor space we now have. The probabilities are that we will ii.ni s ii», and if ao there will be a larger exhibit nei than this and we don't want to hold it in anv smaller building. I think we </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Mr. I.udden That if the reason I made the statement acd that is the fit n the Board asked Mr. Miles. We want to know whether tl. that the exhibitor would be satisfied I want to say that one of the reasons why our show is a litt . ;ir, is because of the extra cold weather we have had and because there are five hundred birds that have been kept away on account weather. Mr I,rman ■ would like to say for the city of Lincoln in s, that Lincoln has no selfish motive. It ba.&lt; &gt;est to &lt; mr annual show here in Lincoln whenever tli The Association had no selfish motive in bringing the show here ud we do agree that it mav go out into the state and be held al ilher city in what we call odd vears. and I do not know whv it shou! go to Hastings. Of course I do not know about the size of the room. The people from there ought to and do know the size of the room, and I w Bgain that we have no motives in trying to keep or hold it here in Lin in odd vears, as I have said. Mr. Renetlict of Hastings The implement room that Mayor Miles refers to in his commur.: feet and it has plenty of light. Mi I.udden Kow near is the proposed building to the center of town or the cen portion? Mr. Reriedic The building that Mr. Miles reft^ ck north and t i the Burlington new passenger depot. Mr. Ludden Bfhat is right in the territory of the basil i t of Ha&gt;: we would not have to go far to get our m&lt; Yes sir, it is the best portion or district of the city A Membe R Could not this matter be left with the future Board that shall be c instructions to them to in he matter and that the Aho i accept the Board's decision? Mr. Ludden I The way this matter was taken up last year was, that we discussed the tosition and then it was referred to the Board, and at the semi-annual ting it was discussed and again finally pet \e Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 i linson: It is not my intention to antagonize any part of the state. It does not any difference where our show is held, I will put as large a stock into trever it is. The present floor space is 90x90. The statement, maile Hastings is that their floor space is about 50x100. That will give us quare feet less, so that we could not help to double deck. I &gt;ay ; I think Mr. Johnson is mistaken in regard to the size of the Auditorium room especially in one way. I am superintendent of this show. stating the arrangements of the birds and aisles Mr. Day said: ) I can can put 400 more birds into the room today without double decking any of them. I could have taken out one row and left the alley still wider. That is one of the reasons we are so crowded but if the birds had been there I could have put 500 more birds on the floor without double decking anv of them. Last year if the show room had been properly distributed there would not have been any reasons for there being auy double decking on the President Norval: Kill the Association take action upon this matter this evening or shall it to a future meeting of the Association or refer it to the Boa Mr. Terwilliger: I move that the matter be left to the Board that the question of the location of our next exhibition be referred 10 the Board of Director^ The motion was seconded and unanimously adopted President Norval; K thank the gentleman from Hastings for extending this kind invitation Whoever may be on our Board of Directors for the ensuing year will : due consideration. Mr. Saddler: ■ would suggest thai the Board, before they locate, come out to Hast - and see what they have to offer. I am sure they will furnish ample and do all they offer to do. NEW BUSl Mr. Gurley: I'nder the head of the new business, in regard to premiums offered for, birds, where there is no competition or claim where they are scored as sec - ond, the score should be as first, second, or third and they should get first, second or third money whether there is competition or not. I do not know the reason why the premiums are awarded the way they are. Prob - ably there is some reason for it that I don't know of. If there is I would be glad to hear what the real reason is. I think the way the thing is at present it shuts out a man who has a new bird. Of course those are what we want. We want to make Nebraska the best state we can for poultry and if we do </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 not do the best we can and take aw iv that feeling of greed and shutting out who might make an exhibit, I think we are cutting ou heads off. In order for a man to cume in a show, birds that are not shown here, we must have some inducement, and I think the in h. ip at present are all the other way, to keep them out. For in - there are many birds not represented here that are good birds, such as English Red Caps, and others. There are a few of them, and then the American Dotninick. I could name many of them that are not represented here, and there is no inducement for them to come in with those birds. For myself, I would like to know why the prizes are awarded in the wmy Chairman N This matter has been discussed at prior meetings of the A . and the great question is for the Board to say how the premiums shall be I am not certain but what they have been given full and ex as to the number of entries in any particular class in order ti second or third prize. Since coming to consider this matter it is like going to have a garment made, we must cut the cloth to suit the garment. There should be at least four or five entries in a class in order to get first money, or we can reduce the amount of premium for first pen, or nr&gt;t cockerel, first hen or first pullet. After close consideration of the matter it was thought 1 ■ the larger birds had paid the most money into the treasury in entry n perhaps that would tie the better way. We may have erred in the matter. It is for this Association to say how it wants the premiums made. The pre - mium list was not intended to be made against any one particular \ There is no discrimination against these smaller varieties. All they have to do is to enter the four birds to come in under the rule. If they have not four birds they have not very many. If they enter four cocks they are en - titled to first prize and entitled to enter in any other class; that is they are not barred, and I think a good many of them have done it this year. As to the American Dominick, I think it will be found tint some in that class and soine in the Barred Rock class ought to be in the other. Ot there are some that are not. Mr. Lvman: I would say that our show has jutgrown our appropriation. It takes about f.vs to pay first money. With the influx of new birds we have increased our liability beyond the income that we derive from the stale. We aim to distribute the (1000 among the breeders as premium ■. peuses out of the entry fees and door receipts, that is what ac for the condition of the Association at present. They found themsei debt and it had to adopt some measure of saving by which they could stale down the expenses. Th lion needs J1500 as the increase in the number of birds continually coming in inak. vssocia - tion to have more money to distribute, or it will have to curtail its expenses. Therefore I think some action should be taken at this meeting to increase the appropriation from Jiouo to $1500. I was talking with a Representative </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Ea memlx- nittee and he promised to gi \ thing in his power to help us. II like to h.. imittec from this Association come before the ! Committee some evening next week and present the matt. With &gt;ur annual income we can r» premiums they v Mr. Ludden: ni; that line I would like to add this; there is not a member a ition here I hardly think but who could be ■ great deal of help that appropriation .h ch we ought to have. We compare very favorably with the agricultural and dairy industries of this state. The of our state is immense. Those of you who have not j can hardly realize the volume of I - in the poultry and egg busn If everyone when you no home, will write your senator and ask him to increase our ap - it him and keep writing letters and get others who rested in the subject to do t! the effect would be th nation would be in. and representative feels hound and out of court' letter written to them n and when the) find these letters coming in every ii ill come to the conclusion that it is far better to set ing the appropriation than to have to answer these letter&gt; and they will vote for that bill. This is an easy way and you can set forth in ■er that the nature of this work is along the line of agricultural edu - and state what tin- long the line ol increas - poultrv industry of the I it needs to have a building put in on the State Farm. I understand that the bill specifically contains a clause for the establishment of a poultry plant on the State Farm, similar to what :;i Rhode Island. We have been trying and trying to get that ition as in otht We have gone to the Chancellor and him that we must have that recognition or we will have to introduce a bill, and he said that he would help us. We have been asking also for a l'pultry ng on the State Fair grounds and I believe that we will get it. I think it is in the bill now before the legislature that we shall have a poultry ng upon the State Fair Groir If we do not stand up for our rights in this matter we will not get a all. It is not for a few men to go up before the legislature but we should all. each and 11 we c.\n and have our frie- I, Mr. Ly man and myself went up to the last - &gt;rked for matter and secured. I believe, recognition, but the appropri - long delayed that when it came into the final committee of the whole, it was cut out as a compromise. But if the members of t) islature know that it is our desire and the desire of their conatituti d in this State, I think tht be in favor re it. They do not realize the volume of busin. from the egg and hen industry- that it exceeds- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Biry industry of our state in several thousand dollars every yemr. is more than a million dollars that goes out of Denver into Nebraska year, as the poultry reports will show. Mr. Terrwilliger I realize the justice of the manner in which the awards are ma&gt;l&gt; year to a certain extent, but it does seem to me as though to get full money it would not be a great injustice to breeders to exhibit a number of hi - ust as much to exhibit one or two as it does more; and a man wl a bird that is not so popular is to just as much expense as the man «. a bird that is very popular. It is a fact that he is cut out simply because he is the only breeder who exhibits here. I admit that he ought not t. ue recognition as those who have a large number of birr ■.ill bring money to the Association. We ought to recognize the breeder who has a number of bir s on exhibition, for instant e, if he has birds that will average a certain score, say 90 to 92 in whatever class it may be, we should award him first, second or third money in proportion. In that way you will encourage and no doubt bring in more birds fron of the less popular classes, and I just throw this out as a remark that tbc Board nrieht consider it. Chairman Norval: The program for the next annual exhibit will not be made up after the semi-annual meeting of the Association and perhaps it might be well to wait until then and find out how our finances are before act liter. On the basis that we have been running this show we must cut our cloth accordingly, or a little bit better; so I suggest that we wait un til the semi-annual meeting and take this matter up at that time. If there is no other suggestion now we will let the matter pass, or a; until it is called up at the semi-annual meeting. . urley : Take for example a man who breeds White Wyaiidottes. We will say that he has some excellent birds to pass in, a cock and a hen, and they score ninety-five points and take first money. We will take another man who has, for example, Leghorn or Buff Cochins or some uncommon !r« ■ State. We will say he puts in two, a cock and a hen, they secure ninety-five points, which of these deserves the same amount of moi; ply because White Wyandottes have lots of competition is no reason whv they should win. any more than any other of the less commor. ■t doing justice to the breeder and not doing justice to the bir cause by doing that you are depriving the breeder who would show in th. t class; and in that way you are keeping that bird out of the State. I have -. of birds that I ha but next year I expect I lots of money if I have not lost them; and I am quite willing to put up with what the Association says. It is not a matter whether I win or lose, I stand for the good of the ' </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Iigo until we have all the birds that we can get. The more birds that itered the better the show and the more people there will 1* to attend ! are too few people here who have numbtrs of birds, we are too 1 to branch out. We want to get over that and get in all the birds we and when people come here and see the large variety they will come next year to see some different variety. I think it is a big feather in the f our Association to have as many birds as we can gather together. E 'hereupon it was moved and second -d that the question of the urn list for the next annual exhibit be deferred until the semi-annual \dopted. Before you determine about the m itter of advertising in our premium list. I presume you would like to know how we came out on thi&lt; year's program. The Superintendent who h.ul that matter in charge will u how we stand in that regard. I will therefore call upon Mr. Day: Mr. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: I got the advertising for our premium list by hard work. The big&lt;&lt;e,t pirt of it I got by going after it and paying my own railroad fare and expenses. I think that &gt;f advertising. I made a proposition t &gt; the Associition, as I got the advertising for the Dodge Poultry Association at home, (I got in our Count v $500 worth of advertising for their catalogue, and I got it in less tim I got the J300 for this Association. 1 I made the proposition to your secre - tary that I would go out and do the best I could for twentv-five per cent &gt; f what 1 received and collected. As I say. and I think as near as I can figure, I am somewhere near $30 or $40 out, and as far as I am concerned I would not undertake to go out again for advertising if the Association give me $50. Mr. Ludden: There has been some criticism on the mechanical execution of this premium list. The Board advertised for bids and receive. I bids from eight to twelve different firms and the lowest bidder received the contract of course. He was a genial good fellow and we give him the manuscript He Id it until after the time for our premium list to be out and I then hurried myself away to see him about it, he said, "Oh, I know know Judge Norval, you will give me up to the First of January to get out that premium list, I cannot possibly get it out before that time " Kthen hurried away to Fremont where the next lowest bidder lived, to hear him say, that I cannot possibly get it out, the third man said juld have to have eight days. These are some of the reasons why the auical execution of the list is not as good as it should be. That adver - lent in the center pages paid full rate for the advertising. He did the ing for those two pages, for which he got $7 a page, and he donated it : Association. That is why the execution of this part of the premium &gt; so much better in one pl.ice than it is in another </seg>
            <seg id="p027">s-&gt; much a page for his advertising and he did the work to suit himself If the entire advertising is paid for in cash it will pay for the prn i our premium list, the printing of the score cards, the entry blanks, and I think, all of the extra p- Whether in the opinion of the members the additional number of pages incorporated in the present premium list justifies an additional expenditure in producing the books, is the question. That is to say, that the number of that are given to the classification of the birds, as we have in the pres - ent catalogue or premium list, the small amount of room that we have to that classification. A Member: I am a printer by trade and I was surprised at the amall amount of space we were able to give to the different classifications in proportion to the num :&gt;ages that we had in the book, and I « «ed at the work - ip that they were able to give us. While I am not here to severely criticise the mechanical makeup of the premium list, I believe that a plain list such as has come to my desk at times during the past year containing advertising features, is a verv much better appearing proposition than the one we have at the present time. I do not know but I believe that with the average run of advertisers, that the opinion is that the premium list is not a paying proposition and I doubt very much whether there will be enough to during the coming year, to again endeavor to put out an adver proposition for our premium list. Albert Lemen Bmove that the question of advertising in our next premium list be re - to the in-coming Hoard of Managers The motion was seconded and adopted ELECTION OF OFFICERS nan Norval Inder our Bv-Laws the election of officers must be bv ballot. &lt; )n motion duly adopted the Chair appointed three tellers as follow cabrook, Mr. Lenien and Mr. Gurlev. It was moved and seconded that the Association he order to be elected as laid down io the By-Mws. The same wa* adopted. K'he chair announced that only those members of the Association titled to vote. The question arising as to whether numbers could vote by proxy ft moved that no proxies be allowed at this meeting. The motion being put Mr. Compto: I cannot see why any persjn, if fa kholder in tfa though he be absent, cannot vote. Why should he be deprived of h and taking part in th nent of th same as any member who was present. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 k . who would like to vote but she is now called upon to go away from eeting and I cannot see why she shoukl be deprived of her vote in naming the officers who shall run the Association. Mr. Terwilliger: E seems that our By-Law* have recognized the justice of the proceeding i«t proxies be not allowed. There are a number of men who are not nd have authorized someone to cast their vote for them. I think the r order of business should be pursued. Mr. 1 .fin en. I&gt;o the By-Laws specify anything that would cover this question Mr. Ludden: Kr By-Laws do not mention the matter of proxies. We have just sus - a resolution that no proxies be allowed and I think, the motion I ould be final. Mrs. Kirkpatrick: I have to go away from the meeting at this time, I know that Mr. Kirk would be very much disappointed if I am not at the banquet on time. I believe that proxies have always been allowed, and I do not undt why we should not be permitted to vote by proxies this year. Chairman Norval: There is a question before the Association whether proxies should be allowed or not. All those who are in favor of the motion made bj Mr. Har - ris, that proxies be not allowed, or that members be not allowed to vote by v, will please signify same by saying Aye, and those opposed N The Chairman announced the vote in the negative. liber: ■move that the rules be suspended and that we elect our President T. L. Norval, as President of this Association for the ensuing year :lamation. Chairman Norval Pwill have to declare the motion out of order. I appreciate the com - it paid me by the Association for the past two years and I have en - red to do the best I could. I rather feel that it would be wiser for the ation to select another person as your presiding officer for the ensuing A Member Kthe Association please, I move that the rules be suspended and that iretary be instructed to cast the ballot of this Association for T. L. as President of the Nebraska State Poultry Association. Kit motion was adopted udden : As your Secretary I have cast i for T. L. Norval for President Chairman Norval: </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 I &gt;t I can. I trust you will make a wise choice in the matter of chuoa - n assistant or Vice President, because the President and Secretary cannot make your show a success, neither can the Board of Managers i whom you may select, make it a success. A good deal depends upon individual member and exhibitor. If you have a good working Board tainlv lessens the work of the Secretary and President. There are men here and I hope you will make a wise selection. Compton: II will place in nomination for Vice President a gentleman who has as influential as any member of this Association could be in making show a success. He is one of the hardest working men in the Associ - i. He is a very geuial and hard working member. I nominate Mr . Day for Vice President, and I move that the rules be suspended and the Secretary be instructed to cast the entire vote of this Association lr. E. B. Day for Vice President. Motion was seconded and adopted. The Secretary cast the ballot for Mr Day and the President announced Mr. Day duly elected Vice President. Mr. Day I thank the members of the Association, one and all, for the honor they have conferred upon me tonight. I thank you also for the assistance I have received at the hands of each one of you as your Superintendent. I believe I can safely say I have never asked a favor of any member to assist me in any way but what he has willingly aided me and given me all the assistance possible. I doubt, since I have been a member of the Nebraska State Poul - try Association, if we have ever held a more harmonious show than this year. Whs? Because each one has been willing to give all the assistance and aid that is within his power. K appreciate as highly as any member of the Association could, the posi &gt; which you have assigned me and will endeavor to fill it to the beat of ility and to make the Association a success. Mr. Lemen: Kara not an exhibitor this year but I want to commend the officers of the iation on the very capable work they have done in handling the it. It stands without a parallel in the history of our Association and I ileasure this evening in nominating for re-election our present Secre - the Rev. Luther P. Ludden. Mr. Day: Kthe Chair please, I move that the rules be suspended and that the ent be instructed to cast the entire vote of this Association for L. P. n as Secretary. The motion is seconded and adopted. President Norval: I have cast the entire ballot of this Association, 387 votes, in favor of Rev. L. P. Ludden as Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 die' There seems to be nobody else you can fall back on. ( Laughter. ) Mr Ludden: I want to express to the members my thanks for their confidence in me. i I think, was my first work in this Association. I atten&lt; led|the meet - ings in 1890, '91 and '92 and every year since then, and have had something to do with the work in the Secretary's department. It is not an easy task to be always smiling when we are in the midst of hunting up some score card for some member in a hurry because he wants to sell that bird. That score card may have been mislaid. For instance today, one member insisted up - on finding his score card at once. He had it out in the show room and brought it back and in handling it, the card became misplaced in another envelope. I put the entire force of the office to work looking for that score card and when the hour came for supper I fastened the door and we found that card. And it is not always an easy matter to speak in the most pleasant and affable manner when working from four o'clock in the morning until twelve o'clock at night. There is however, a great pleasure and interest for your secretary in looking back over the record of our poultry work in Ne - braska during the past sixteen years and noticing the advancement all along the line and the growth of it from 240 birds exhibited to what we have now. If you could have seen some of our first score cards and compare them with the score cards of today you would appreciate the splendid growth and advancement in our Association. We have tonight a gentleman who started in the beginning of •ultry Association , one of the first men who helped to incorporate .ssociation, and who was also a prominent member of the Committee that got our first bill through the Legislature. I have reference to our es - teemed member I. L. Lyman, and I nominate him for our Treasurer. And Mr. Chairman, I move you that the rules be suspended and that the Secretary be instructed to cast the entire ballot of this Association for I. L. Lyman as Treasurer for the ensuing year. The motion was duly seconded and adopted The Secretary cast the entire ballot of the Association in favor of I. L. Lyman and the President announced his election Mr. Lyman: Kdo not feel like making a speech this evening. I will simply ex - my appreciation of the vote of confidence on th* part of the members ; Association, and will say that I will execute the duties of the office same faithful manner as I always have and will do the best I can for st interests of the Association. BOARD OF MANAGERS I would like to place in nomination Mr. J. A. Johnson of Holdrege a* </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 a member of the Board of Managers has never asked tor any office. he has been with us many years and J. C. Johnson of Omaha KVe want men on our Board of own business and I nominate as :has. H. Green, of Fremont. Directors who have made a success of a member of the Board of managers Mr. Trough of Minden K nominate Mr. J. Cook Johnson as a member of the Board of Managers ytnan: &gt;)ne of the old reliable breeders of the State and who has always been us and whose judgment has always been respected, is Mr. Ed. I of Minden, and I nominate him as a member of the Board of Man- Mr. E. E. Smith of Lincoln is nominated. Chas. M. Hulbert of Fairburv is nominated J. H. Trough of Minden is nominated. E. E. Bowers of Bradshaw is nominated Mr. Ludden I nominate Mr. H. H. Campbell of &lt; On motion the nominations were closed. Ewas moved and seconded that the five nominees who received the t number of votes be declared elected and who shall constitute the of Managers. Adopted. En motion duly seconded and adopted the Association re-considered the otion that the five nominees receiving the highest number of votes be ed elected and the same was rescinded. Mr. Lyman: I move you, Mr. Chairman, that the original motion be amended so as to state that those who receive the highest number of votes provided majority of all the votes cast, shall be declared elected and constitute the Board of Directors. The amendement to the motion was accepted and the motion as amended being put, the same was adopted. Ballot was had and announced by the Secretary as follows Of which J. A. Johnson received 37, Chas. H. Green 50, E. E. Smith 46, Rowers 36 and H. H. Campbell 53, all of whom having received a majority of the votes cast were duly declared elected to constitute the Board of Managers for the ensuing year. Chairman Norval: I In regard to the judges for your next annual exhibit, there have been t propositions submitted. Do you wish to take any action in that tnat - his evening or shall it be referred to the Board of Mana. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Mr. Albert Lemen: I move you, Mr. Chairman, that the matter of selection of judges for the next annual exhibit be referred to the Board of Managers. The motion was seconded and adopted. Mr. Ludden: I move the adoption of the following resolution: That a'vote of thanks be tendered to the Commercial Club of Lincoln for the use of their parlors for this evening's meeting; to the Western Passen - ger Association for the reduced rates given us; to Dr. A. T. Peters for the splendid help he has rendered us, especially in the program arranged for this meeting. The resolution was adopted. President Norval: At this time I wish to call your attention to a little matter. A year ago last September we called for the Nebraska Commission to Louisiana Purchase Exposition and asked them to make us a liberal appropriation and to ap - point a Superintendent of the Nebraska Poultry exhibit at the World's Fair. Up to that time we thought we would have two or three car-loads in our es - ■n and thought we ought to have (1800, but no action was taken until some time last summer when the Commission generously offered us $300. Shortly after that we had a meeting of our Board and we expressed our thanks to the members of the Nebraska State Commission for their liberality in giving us $300, and suggessed if they would increase the appropriation to $5co that we would do the best we could to make an exhibit. They acceded to our request and appropriated $500. Recently I have been informed by the Secretary of that Commission that less than one half of the appropriation set aside for the Nebraska Poultry Association was used and the balance re - mains in the hands of the Treasurer. I think a vote of thanks should be ex - tended again to the Commission, and I will entertain a resolution to that end. The following resolution was offered and adopted. Whereas, Many valuable contributions and constant assistance was rendered the Nebraska State Commission in the collection, installation and maintenance of the Nebraska Commission's several exhibits at the Ex - position by the State University, the Board of Agriculture, State Board of Horticulture, State Live Stock Association, the State Poultry Association and the Douglas County Agriculture Society, Kesolved, That the Commission does hereby extend to each of these itions and organizations, its thanks and appreciation for the valuable » and continued interest exhibited by these various organizations. Mr. Ludden: I would add to that resolution that a vote of thanks be tendered to the Nebraska Commission for the liberal appropriation made for the exhibit at the St. Louis Exposition, be also added a vote of thanks to the Superin - tendent for the faithful and efficient manner in which he administered the duties of that office. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 Resolution adopted. Mr. Ludden ■ think it well to incorporate in our record the action of the Nebraska liission and to give them a vote of thanks for the excellent help that gave us in making the Nebraska Poultry exhibit a success. Ewe could have a brief statement from Mr. Smith it would expediate s I think, at least the State Board of Printers have recognized our al appeal and will advertise for bids on reports printed and they have ted, or at least agreed, to advertise for I Mr. Smith, Superintendent at St. Louis Exposition, was called upon to make a report of the exhibit at St. Louis and spoke as follows: When the doors were thrown open, October 24, there had been collected about 12, 000 head of poultry and pigeons, from England, Canada and r.tarly every State in the United States. New England birds were found by the side of California and Texas birds. In point of number and high qua: this show will score 100 points. Regular and special prices were offered to the amount of $22,081. Regular prices, Class A, were fin. $6, $4; Class B, tl- .$5. $3\ Class C, $6, $4, $2. All with ribbons out to the fifth place. Specials ran from f 50, down to Ji . The White Wyandotte Club gave » divided into 50 $10 prizes. With the above liberal prizes and the honor of winning at the World's Fair one would expect to find some of Nebraska's enterprising poultrymen showing. After a good showing had been made to the Nebraska Commissioners in regard to the poultry industry in this State, they very liberally offered to give oveT to the Nebraska State Association (500. pay express and cooping charges on Nebraska ex - hibit. Feed and cooping cost $1 per head, $2 per pen. Entries had to be made before September 10, six weeks before the show opened. Quite a large number were entered, so Nebraska stood thirteenth in point of number of entries. But when the time came to ship, some lost their nerve and did not send losing their entrance money and a good chance to add honor to them - selves and Nebraska. Even the tenth place was considered better than a first in any show ever held before. Taking into consideration the number shown Nebraska rated far above the average. The following prizes were awarded to Nebraskans: EC. Buff Orpingtons, 150 in class — H. H. Campbell, Osceola, 3d 7th hen, 3d cockerel, 3d, 5th. 6th pullet. E. S. Jennings, Lincoln, ckerel, winning over the originator's imported birds. Rose Comb Brown Leghorns, 60 in class— J. H. Trough, Minden, 3d, 4th cockerel, 4th pullet, 3d, 4th pen. Partridge Wyandottes, 127 in class — E. N. Crittenden, Lincoln, 2d cockerel. Buff Wyandottes, 165 in class — E. B. Day, Fremont, 2d hen, 6th cock and special. White Wyandottes. 808 in class — F. B. Tipton. Seward, 3d cockerel, 4th pullet, 2 specials. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Barred Plymouth Rocks, 429 in class — T. L. Norval. Seward, 6th cock- 9th hen, 3d, 10th pullet. 4th pen. With only two or three exceptions every Nebraska exhibitor won prizes. According to the number of entries made Nebraska made a higher e winning than any state in the union. Only $159 of the amount ap - propriate'l was needed to pay all the expenses of this exhibit. On account 01 the extensive advertising giveu to the World's Pair winners Nebraskans have sold prize chickens from (25 to over $100 each from ocean to ocean. And will say it to the credit of the Exposition management that every cent of the premium ramev has been paid. Kefore I close let me say the next Exposition Poultry show •"ill be n Portland, Oregon, during October, 1905. Nebraska Poultry breeder notice. Crowd your young stock, meet with us at the State Fair, : arrangements will be made to send a large and winning exhibit to ind. Iis moved and seconded that a vote of thanks be extended to tht - perintendent, Mr. E. B. Day, for the efficient manner in which he iducted the show this year and th it we earnestly recommend him to isideration of the Bjard for the same position our next annual show. Motion adopted President Norval: There will be a meeting of the Board at half-past-one to-morrov that time some action ought to be taken as to who will be your ju the next show because those who have m3de propositions will be received ■ment elsewhere and it is proper that they should he advised of our . in the matter at as early a date as possible. Mr. Ludden: I give notice now that immediately following that meeting orders will be issued for your premiums; and I presume that Mr. Lyman will be some - where near by with his check book ready to begin paying those ordt - jut the ribbons. By the order of the Board the ribbons will not be 1 out until tomorrow afternoon. Chairman Norval: Iiut of Lancaster C juuty I do not like to make the motion but lair should appoint a Committee, to be known as the Legislature Com - ;, to try and secure such legislation as would be for the best interests : Association. If each one of you can get your delegation or represent - from your County working in this matter it would be pretty near a suc - &gt;r what we want. A Member: ■t move that the chair appoint a committee of five members, to be known :nmittee, wlios.- duty it shall be to see that our interests </seg>
            <seg id="p035">are properly and fairly looked after in the Legislature. The motion was seconded and adopted On motion the meeting adjourned sine die. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>