<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Second Annual Report of County Agricultural Agent Work</title>
               <date value="1915-08-20">1915-08-20</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">iuy BULLETIN NO. 34. J:T ;;;PKU£JIN OF THE tJNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE. SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENT WORK. 1914. By A. E. Anderson. Distributed August 20, 1915. SI 111 • 'vl ■*J n~'. I ' T~*¥*^ — ~r~i ■ ~vffij* ~*^ ji COuNTifS WITH |l I 1 I r I ■- — * — — — — " " a S • • ■ • — -^ , \ - COUNTlfS WITH T_* _ W^ • t ■ m*nm*r OKtwam 11 ■ • # • l™\ /"rPiAV^TD^I- /**t r/Vffi LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. The Farm Demonstration Work in Nebraska is conducted by the University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture, Cooperating. Distributed in Furtherance of the Cooperative Agricultural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE. THE EXTENSION SERVICE. THE GOVERNING BOARD. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, President, Valley. HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey. HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, Experiment Station. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF. C. W. PUCSLEY, B. Sc., Director. A. E. Anderson, A. B., Farm Demonstration Work. Maud Mathes Wilson, B. Sc., Home Economies. Huldah Peterson, Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Emma Reed Davisson, Women's Clubs. Frank C. Dean, A. B., Agricultural Editor. THE EXTENSION COUNCIL. (heads of oepartme E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. UP8ON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. H. C. FlLLBY, A. M., Farm Management. *W. J. MORRILL, M. For., Forestry. Alice M. Loomis, A. M., Home Economics. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. P. B. Barker, A. M., Instructional Agronomy. G. A. LOVELAND, A. M., Meteorology. H. E. Bradford, A. B., Principal, School of Agriculture. •Resigned. (ihi uiun o&gt; the u&gt;ivcisitt.) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENT WORK. 1914 By A. E. Anderson. The following is a brief summary of the work and accom - plishments of the county agricultural agents or farm demonstrators for the year ending December 31, 1914. The program of demon - stration work has varied with the conditions existing in the various counties. Those lines of work were taken up that seemed from the standpoint of the farmers and the county agent to need most attention under the local conditions. There will be included in this report only the results from work completed in 1914. In all of the counties there were projects of work undertaken of a nature that would not show definite results in one year but must be continued for a series of years. The report of those lines of work will be deferred until definite results have been secured. The county agent work is under the joint direction of a county farmers' association, the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture, and the United States Department of Agriculture. Its purpose is to develop the agriculture of the county. This is done by adopting improved and practicable methods in the production and care of crops and live stock and by finding better markets for the products raised. County agricultural agent work was in progress in eight counties in 1914. Four of the counties organized and had the work under way in 1913. Four new counties took up the work this season at various times. They are as follows: Madison County, March 10; Dawes County, April 1; Dakota County, July 1; and Kimball County, July 1, 1914. The eight counties together with the county agents are as follows: Merrick County Gage County . . . Thurston County V. S. Culver* 0. H. Liebers . J. F. Coupe Seward County A. H. Beckhoff Madison County Val Kuska* Dawes County C. S. Hawk Dakota County Hugh Raymond Kimball County Geo. 0. Unruh * Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin SU, College of Agriculture. A county agent has been employed in Boxbutte County since January 1, 1915. The demonstration work is undertaken by an organization of farmers in a county cooperating with the Extension Service of the Nebraska College of Agriculture and with the United States Department of Agriculture. The United States Department of Agriculture contributed $8,100, and $600 of Smith-Lever funds was used in 1914 in the maintenance of county agent work in the counties now organized. It is the plan of the Extension Service to secure $1,200 per year from Federal or State funds for each county if $1,200 or more per year is raised by a county farmers' association, either by membership dues, subscriptions, or appropriations of the county commissioners or supervisors. HOG CHOLERA CONTROL. The county agents have probably spent more time and effort in the control of hog cholera than in any other line of demon - stration work. By education and cooperation, an effort has been made to stamp out this disease, and many public demonstrations were given in the method of diagnosing and properly treating by the vaccination method. Sanitary control of the disease and the proper cleaning up of premises following an attack of hog cholera were emphasized. The county agents have kept an accurate record of the number of hogs treated, their temperatures at the time of vaccination, and the general condition of the hogs, and have published the results from time to time that the people of the county might know the value of treating hogs at the proper time when exposed to hog cholera. HOG CHOLERA VACCINATION BY COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENTS Vaccinated ). H. Liebers, Gage County iugh Raymond, Dakota County . F. Coupe, Thureton County . . i. H. Beckhoff, Seward County 'al Kuska, Madison County f. S. Culver, Merrick County Jeo. O. Unruh, Kimball County . 7,169 4,387 4,948 2,367 2,228 2,357 . 149 Total 23,605 Total saved Total well hogs saved . . . 89.8 per cent . . 98.48 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Second Annual Report of County Agric'l Agent Work, 1911* 5 Fig. 1. — Post-mortem examination of a hog affected with cholera. Kimball County. CROP DEMONSTRATIONS. A project undertaken last spring was the demonstration in the prevention of smut by the formaldehyde treatment of seed oats. Last year in Gage County the farmers and county agent found that by actual count an average of 12.3 per cent of the oats were affected with smut. This ranged in different fields from 2 to 48 per cent. Thirty farmers in different parts of the county last spring undertook, in cooperation with Mr. Liebers, to conduct demonstrations for the purpose of determining the value of treating seed oats for the prevention of smut. These farmers, with the aid of Mr. Liebers, would treat a part of their seed oats and leave another part untreated. The treated and untreated oats were sown in the same field under uniform con - ditions. Records were kept by the county agent. He was also present at threshing time to secure the yield. The results given here are taken from fields where conditions were exactly alike except in the use of treated and untreated oat seed. The report follows: Average yield per acre of treated portion of fields 48 J bu. Average yield per acre of untreated portion of fields 36 bu. Average difference per acre in favor of treating 12J tu. Value of average increase per acre at 35c per bushel $4,375 ■ 4 ' i^^^r </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin 81&gt;, College of Agriculture. •fill S ! s s * s I i^s^__| S_ s a 2 s § fi « 1 * I 3 2 i I pMj S 3 i I E I I -S3, | | H 1 i I s -i - - - - - ' I t .hi T . =£- * S 9 =: 5 » • S ft IP 1 1 l| S g 1 | | 8 ! I is* IT j If 3 ? S 5 | 5 i fi 5 1 5 1 5? » fc 5 1 S II r r 5 * I g j| L_L I ; S! 4 *-jiJs mil n </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Annual Report of County Agric'l Agent Work, 191 1 7 Second 3 3 3 « !C!COt-O- M«^&gt; ?! — «»-&gt;f — 3 s 35 •» 1 ■4 Sfi : « s Jill 2&lt;£« v :§ ■ &gt; „ a -a ■ ■ 'fli §««s,ofi ■ ■ ■ -ia : .2 § oO g : : '£% . 0 °-r S-a 2 t »- t °°-&gt;;Soissss| ** iiSilillJ M M be 6£ s M ._ v. ■_ •» b( a S 2 2i3 2 ° ° ° ° c </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Extension Bulletin 8b, College of Agriculture. 8 In Seward County similar demonstrations were carried on in 1914. An inquiry at the drug stores in various parts of the county revealed that they sold more formaldehyde that spring than ever before. In four smut treated fields the agent found the treated portion to be entirely free, while actual count showed that the untreated portions contained a minimum of 7 per cent and a maximum of 32.2 per cent smutted heads. In Gage County 32 farmers cooperated in demonstrating the value of northern vs. home grown seed potatoes. To en - courage the growing of at least enough potatoes for home use is very important in that county. In the past from 30 to 40 carloads of potatoes have been shipped into the county annually for food. Due to lack of time the county agent was unable to get the results from all the cooperators but the following is an accurate report of nine of the cooperators. These results certainly show that it pays to plant good northern seed. Had the rainfall been normal the past season the northern seed would have made a much better showing against the home grown than it did. The potatoes from the northern seed were much larger, smoother, and of better eating quality. There was more difference in quality than in yield. COMPARING NORTHERN GROWN SEED VS. HOME GROWN SEED. The following results are based on acre yields: Average yield Northern grown seed 105.34 bu Home grown seed 79.16 bu. Difference in favor of northern grown seed 26.18 bu. In Thurston County a demonstration was made in comparing home grown seed corn with that secured from a distance. This test was made on the farm of William Wingett, two miles east of Walthill. Previous tests at the State Experiment Station have shown an increase of 6.2 bushels in favor of home grown seed. The tests completed in Thurston County this year show an increase of about 16.6 bushels in favor of Thurston County seed. In Gage County where a similar test was carried on in several fields the home grown seed gave an increase of about 12.5 bushels above that of imported seed. DAIRYING. In Gage County the farmers thru their county agent secured 54 pure-bred sires and 108 dairy cows. Previous to the county agent's arrival in the county there were only three pure-bred dairy sires in that county. In Merrick County a cow testing association was formed. Under the direction of the county agent and the Dairy Depart- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Second Annual Report of County Agric'l Agent Work, 191 It. 9 ment of the University of Nebraska 349 cows were tested for profit in milk production. Before a year's test could be com - pleted 40 of the cows had already been sold because they showed a loss in milk production. At the end of the year there were cows still showing a loss, and these were practically all disposed of. DEMONSTRATIONS IN ORCHARDS. In several of the counties, work was undertaken in the proper methods of caring for orchards. In these counties field demon - strations in the proper pruning and proper spraying of trees were given. At the call of orchard owners, the county agents would go out to orchards and there prune and spray trees and explain the proper method of taking care of orchards. At these demonstrations the people of the community would meet. Mr. Beckhoff reports 22 such demonstrations in Seward County, each attended by from 10 to 30 people. In a number of the orchards the county agent, cooperating with the Department of Horticulture of the College of Agriculture, kept accurate notes on the value of pruning and spraying. Following are the results from the care of one of the orchards in Seward County: Sound fruit Picked apples — treated plats 84.69 per cent Picked apples — untreated plats 10.94 per cent Fig. 2. — Before pruning. Seward County. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Extension Bulletin SU, College of Agriculture. Table 2. — Results of several demonstrations in the proper care of orchards made in Gage County by the county agricultural agent and the Department of Horticulture of the University of Nebraska. Sprayed Fruit free from fungus or other injuries Salable fruit Per cent 80.82 Percent 4 times Unsprayed 95 30.19 M Fig. 3. — After pruning. Seward County. MARKETING. In the eight counties having demonstration work in progress, the offices of the farmers' associations have been used as a medium of exchange to the extent of $41,141 worth of farm products. This has been in the sale of live stock both within and without the county, and also in the sale and purchasing of farm seeds. An unusual crop of alfalfa seed was raised in Seward County in the season of 1913. The local demand could not take care of this seed, and the local price was very low. The county agent in communication with county agents of eastern States suc - ceeded in finding a market for $13,840 worth of alfalfa seed with farmers of those States at a price of approximately $1 per bushel more than the local price. The profit to the Seward County fanners in this one item alone was more than $1,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Second Annual Report of County Agric'l Agent Work, 191b. 11 AGRICULTURAL OBSERVATION TOURS. In every county there are agricultural practices in use by farmers which have exceptional merit but are little known to most people of that county. Agricultural observation tours were taken for the purpose of focusing attention on some method or practice of special value to the local agricultural conditions. Silo excursions were held in five of the counties. The farmers would meet at a starting point in their automobiles and make a tour including visits to from five to eight different types of silos at which talks would be made by the various silo owners and by the county agent or some other agricultural representative. As a result of such silo excursions in Dawes County, the num - ber of silos was more than doubled the first year. In Madison County such automobile trips were made to study the value of sweet clover as pasture under the prevailing soil conditions. These visits to such farms where sweet clover has been of exceptional value for eight years has brought to the attention of Madison County farmers the value of that plant for stock pastures. BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUB WORK. The county agents have assisted in enlisting farm boys and girls to take special interest in some phase of agriculture or domestic science. In their respective counties they have been Fig. 4. — Fanners' agricultural tour in Madison county. Inspection of a sweet clover field. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extension Bulletin SU, College of Agriculture. instrumental in the organization of 24 boys' and girls' clubs with a total membership of 480. All of these boys and girls have under - taken on their own responsibility some definite project of home work such as the growing of corn, potatoes, caring for a garden or work in sewing or cooking. In Thurston County one boy succeeded in growing 92.5 bushels of corn on an acre plat with a net profit of $35. In Dawes County a boy raised at the rate of 200 bushels of potatoes to the acre where the average yield this year was only 50 bushels. Girls enrolled in garden club work secured good results. A Dawes County girl made a net profit of $71.40 from one- tenth of an acre of vegetables with a total yield of 2,640 lbs. A Seward County girl produced 2,415 pounds of tomatoes alone on her one-tenth acre garden plat. COMMUNITY CLUBS. The organization of local or community clubs has been given some attention by the county agents. In Kimball County five such community clubs have been organized thru the help of the county agent, and each one holds monthly or bimonthly meetings at which discussions of farm subjects take place. MEETINGS The various county agents have arranged for many meetings in their respective counties. They would either address these meetings themselves or secure some one else to take part in the Fig. 5. — Corn club members assisted in the selection and storing of seed corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Second Annual Report of County Agric'l Agent Work, 1 91 U. 13 program. In many cases they have used a stereopticon lantern to illustrate their talks. A great many of these meetings have been held in country schoolhouses where the entire audience would take part in the program. Four hundred and six such meetings have been scheduled during the past year, at which 26,581 people have been reached. OTHER WORK. The above is only a brief summary of a very few of the activ- ities of the county agents. They are engaged in all lines of work looking to the improvement of agriculture in their counties. Below is a statistical summary showing some of the demands upon their time: SUMMARY ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF COUNTY AGENTS. Farmers visited on their farms 2,817 Total number of farm visits made 4,038 Office calls 4,720 Telephone calls 4,804 Letters written 6,240 Circular letters and bulletins distributed 21,365 Letters written 21,365 Meetings addressed 406 Attendance at such meetings 26,581 Community clubs organized 9 Total membership of such clubs 308 Agricultural articles published in county papers .... 387 Local short courses conducted 3 Attendance at short courses 725 Schools assisted in developing agricultural instruction 94 Pupils reached 2,915 Agricultural observation parties conducted 11 Total persons in such parties 767 Fanners cooperating in demonstrations 350 Meetings held to inspect demonstrations 47 Attendance 1,526 Total members in county farmers' associations 2,012 Farm buildings planned or improved 42 42 Silos constructed 66 Water supply systems introduced 9 Drainage systems planned 10 Irrigation systems planned 4 Registered stallions secured 4 Registered bulls secured 56 Registered boars secured 71 Dairy cows purchased 142 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Extension Bulletin Sit, College of Agriculture. ORGANIZATION FOR COUNTY AGENT WORK. An organization of farmers should be formed in the county and the necessary funds raised by membership fee or by sub - scriptions. At least 200 farmers should be secured in such an organization and they should represent every part of the county. Each precinct should elect from the members within its borders a representative to serve on the county board of directors who have the local management of the county farmers' association in charge. This board of directors representing the farmers' association should confer with the Agricultural Extension Service representa - tive in charge of demonstration work in regard to securing Federal and State funds and a competent man to act as county agricultural agent. The board of directors then make an agreement with a county agent and the work is actively begun. The board of directors meet once a month to direct the business management of the association and to advise with the county agent, who makes his report to the association and presents his plans for the next month's work. Under this method of organization the entire county is represented and each director will see that his precinct gets a just share of the county agent's service. To communities that are interested in the organization of a farmers' association for the purpose of taking up county agricul - tural agent work, the Agricultural Extension Service will send a man to explain the plan and method of work in use in this State. Before a county takes up active demonstration work, it should be thoroly explained at meetings in all parts of the county by some one in close touch with the work in this State, or by some county agent. For additional information in the matter of organization or method of conducting demonstration work, address inquiries to the Agricultural Extension Service, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. (S-15-'15, 10M.) leef cows purchased 31 urchasing and marketing associations formed 4 iusiness done by farmers' exchanges in buying and selling of live stock, seed, hay, etc $41,141 'ows tested for milk production 575 jiimals tested for tuberculosis 310 ilackleg vaccination 464 [ogs vaccinated for cholera 23,605 ml hogs in infected herds saved 98.48% 'otal hogs in infected herds saved 89.8 % </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>