<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908 THE WOODRVFF-COLL1NS PRESS </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE MOA1M) OF CONTROL H. M Eaton, Commissioner Public Lands A Buildings, Chairman Hns Geo. ('. Jcnkin. Secretary of State. Secictarv I., (i. Bmw Treasurer of State Hon. W. T. Thompson Attorney RESIDENT OFFKEKS \Y B. Kkk\. M. !) Superinteadeni \V. .1 urn Steward MEDK \\. 8TA I- I- \\ . B. Kkhn. M. 1) Superintendent V. H. KuBGLC, M. I) First Assistant Physician R. H. Fosteb, M. I) Second Assistant Physician I). M. .Iti)KiN&gt;. II. I) Third Assistant Physician </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I )«':ir Sn-Iu compliance with the legal ami custoniai quiremantfl 1 have the honor to submit herewith this, the Tenth Biennial report of this Institution, The Nebraska State Hospital, for t lie Biennial Period l&gt;eginning December I. I9&lt;)6 ami ei nit&gt;er :*(). 1908. At the beginning of this biennial period. December 1. 1906, there were nine hundred seventy-two (972) patients in this II" - pital. of whom six hundred sixty-four (664) were males, and hundred eight (.SOS) females. During the biennium four hui thirty-three (4.SH) patients have been admitted, of whom two hun - dred fifty five '_'."&gt;.-)&gt; were males and one hundred seventy-* females. In addition to this two hundred twenty-seven patient! have been returned from parole. During the biennium one hundred seventy (17.0) have been discharged as recovered, four (4) improved and two (2) unimproved, forty-four (44) on pan this time, t hi • aped, and one hundred sixty-three i 163 died, leaving ten hundred forty-five (104.")) patients in the Institu - tion today. During the biennium four (4) patients have transferred to the Lincoln Asylum, and one (1) to the Norfolk Asylum. (During this biennium a daily average of ten hundred tw&lt; • (1023) patients lias been maintained, at a daily av&lt; a cost of forty-three and five-sevenths (43 "&gt;-7) cent al per capita cost of one hundred fifty-nine dollars eiyhtr - ! ($159.83) cents. I During the biennium just closed the general health of tl • s has been exceptionally good, and the general sanitary n of the Institution of the 1» IMPROVEMENTS Numerous very important improvements have been made about the Hospital during the period covered by this report, a few of the most important being the following: The floors and wainscoting of the bath rooms and lavatories throughout the entire first and I floors of the Institution have l&gt;een replaced by mo vitreous tiling, and the plumbing throughout the entire first and </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">1 floors, and a good share of the third flour, h A building expressly for the accommodation of our nig! ployes lias been creeled one-third ($) mile south of the main I rhich accommodates all our night watches and night ii and adds very greatly to the comfort and convenience of ploy. ■Eight thousand (S.(HM)i feet of three (3) inch cast iron is. with the required number of lawn hydrants ted, have been installed. ■ The dairy Warns have been snt time accommodate the considerably enlarged and a&lt; ntire dairy herd consist ii hundred twenty-five (125) head of verv tine Holstein Freisian : number of these pun lired and registered. ■ The lawn has been enlarged considerably during approximately four thousand i4.(M)0) additional ■Ten thousand (10. m of manufactured atom installed, and considerable brick and manufactu ivalkfl added ■The exterior of all the buildings has been repainted, »i : time they are in exceptionally good condition. Kin addition to our usual amusements and entertaim ipened at the beginning of this bienniuni a large ball \ ufficient to accoran odate all patients who are able and wh&lt; e to attend hall games and other amusement- held tli&gt; HAN'IIE I \ N WIK \ \ 1) ( Ii \i; VI IK I The most important change by far that has ever come r Institution was brought about at the beginning of the pn bienpium following the enactment of a law changing the nam. n-ter of the Institution from that of "Asylum for the care of ( 'hronic and Incurable Insane " to its present title. " Nebraska - tal." When this change came the state was redistricte i the territory tributary to Insane Hospitals is concerned fifty-three (53) count i territory to this [nstitu Thk change placed the Institution in an entirely different ami a desirable class, and bn an arrangement he which vastly more good tl. ing don </seg>
            <seg id="p006">90 K THK I NSTITl'TION Bhe institution is very much in need of an additional detached ng for the care of female patients. In addition to this a pood modern tubercular Hospital Cot iblv located some considerable distance. from the main build - aith a capacity of one hundred fifty ( 180) or two hundred would indeed l&gt;e a very important acquisition to the place. The large number of tubercular and other eontagioui and infectious net in Hospitals of this kind requiring isolation is indeed lerable. and this can only l&gt;e brought about in the way above d. Kfhe offices in the administration building are indeed quite quate for a modern Hospital of this size, and it seems advis - td provide additional room in this department, hence it is miended that a suitable cottage be erected to be used ■nee for the Su|&gt;erintendent and his family, and the rood nt used for this purpose converted into additional office rooms. A new and modernlv equipped laundry building of sufl &lt;i meet the needs of the Institution is much needed at this ami is a thing which l*&gt;fore long will I* 1 an absolute nec&lt; Ehe Institution should have at least an additional on. •tion of land, which could !&gt;e operated very profitably and it the employment of additional help. \ \TIOX OF STKWAKI) Very much to our regret our former Steward. Mr. H. ('. Haverly. wIki served in that capacity so faithfully and efficiently for almost resigned his position I)eceml&gt;er 1. 1807. He was ! by Mr. (ieo. \Y. James, who in a very satisfactory way holds the position of Steward at the present time. E)uring my connection with this Hospital, extending over a 1 of ten and one-half (Hty) years, the last eight (Si as Superin - nt. no biennium has passed in which such uniform harmony 1 between the officers of the Institution and the men; 1 Medical staff, and the heads of the various depart m&lt; thers. as during the biennium just closed. CONCLUSION 1 wish in conclusion to express my earnest appreciation of the efficiency and loyalty of our competent Steward, the assistant muting our medical staff, and to the various I </seg>
            <seg id="p007">91 Entente ami other employes who have M willingly, carefully. Ili^ently performed their respective duties, and who have r much valuable assistance in the successful management flMN i «f the Hospital. I To His Kxcellency. the Governor, and to the individual mem of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. I wish ti sledge my obligation and to assure each of you of my appie on of your kindly and constant assistance and advice. Respectfully. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">X £ * </seg>
            <seg id="p009">HOSPITAL KOH INSANK. INGLESIDE S3&amp;S3838S » "i i : 2 •■* - 1 i- 3 5 r u &gt; I * ■" • ' j j j r ? x J 5 z -I •I z / «* • /•. - 5 -i y. »ic - XZZSZZZZZZ X x M / rii fc~i55ii- 7. - S I !2S i^S^iTi S S J - rl 5 5 5 ?i ~. - z' z' 1 Tl f "M ? I &gt; ■ / ;i / U C £ I- f I- — s 5 i § i~ 5 = ~. S ri 2 5 * .~ 5 5 2 - - 5 S 8 S 3 3 S S g ?! ;■- ~i vr -i '~" t-r ri T-i — r^ •- re t_' u' </seg>
            <seg id="p010">94 LAND COMMISSIONER'S RKPORT \ \l.l K nh 8TO« K, MACH1NKKY, KIKMII KK, SUPPLIES, I On Hand December 1. I90N Muck 117,550.25 i machinery, vehicles, etc 3,937.71 lets of farm and garden. 8,438 till nerv and supplies in laundry 5,761.85 linery, tools and supplies in engine room. ."&gt;il. s,t&gt; 71 Supplies and fixtures in drug room 1.SH7.63 ! v and furniture in telephone office and reception room 354 Supplies and fixtures in storeroom and cold storage 11,361.93 Supplies and fixtures in bakery and kitchens 3,351.79 KikI fixtures in paint shop and mason and rer'i department 174.23 and apparatus in fire department . .. 1,244 Furniture and supplies on female wards and dining room- 22,674.78 Furniture and supplies on male wards and dining rooms 48,288 80 Furniture and supplies in Administration Building. ... &lt; .'MA 41 Furniture and supplies in cottage, officer's and em - ployes' dining rooms, and employes' living room 4,080.70 and supplies in carpenter shop, greenhouse and m 5,575 87 Fixtures and supplies in sewing room 2,026 89 Furniture and fixtures in amusement hall 2,325.10 Furniture and supplies in night watch cottage. 4.157.06 Total $201.K45.69 GABDENER'8 RE POST OK PKODICK RAISED During the biennial period l&gt;eginning Decenil&gt;er 1. 1906. and ending November 30, l'.ios Product — Amount 1,189 bushels Bean- 246 bushels Celery 1.000 bunches Cauliflower 50 bunches ( * n \ ||^ftflpp 10 1 0^S llf*'i( Is 20 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p011">95 HOSPITAL Kin INSANE, INGLESIDE Lettuce :{«•() bushek Mushrooau 25 poundi broom 28 poundi Onions 50 1&gt; . Onions, green 3,150 down ms. gram 3,1M do* toes 8,029 bushdi Potatoes 8,029 bushels Peppers &gt;ers .-&gt;:•! but 53 bu nfps 2,798 bushels 2,798 bushels Pumpkins pkins 1.700 only 1,700 only Pie Plant Plant 1 ,349 dozen 1,349 dozen Peai ■_'() bushels _'() bushels Radishes ishe&gt; S,i78 dozen 3.67X da potfttOM 77 1)11- rt potatoes 77 bus Sweet corn rt corn :}.2fi0 dozen 3.260 dozen Spinach 460 bus aeh 460 inishels Salsify 120 bu fj l-jo bu Turnips lips 1,987 but 1,987 bu.- Toniatoes 1&gt;(M) bu atoes 1&gt;(M) but Squash ish 2.200 only 2,200 only Watermelons prinelons 100 only KMt onlv NEBRASKA 8T ATE HOSPITAL. [NGLESIDE, NEBRASKA 5RASKA STATE HOSPITAL. [NGLE8IDE, XKHHASK ' STEWARDS (ASH REPORT STEWARDS CASH HKPORT pts and &lt;lisburseinents for the biennial period ending Noi •ipts and &lt;lisl)iirseinents for the biennial period ending No ber 30, 1908 ber M). 1906 UKBPTI RECEIPTS 1906 1, To balance cash on hand $1.73 1. To J. \Y. Crisstnan. 1 days work of shredder 1, To J. A. Weirick. 1 grade heifer l."&gt; (Mi 6. To Earl C. Weatcott, boarding workmen . 90.00 Dec. 10. To Kauf Rinderspacher. 2240 lbs. hides _'.')7 (JO B, To Kauf Rinderspacher. 1624 lbs. hides 170 1907 Jan. 1. To Whitebreast t'oal &amp; Luml&gt;er Co.. unloading 1700 tons coal 170 oo Jan. 3, To \V. B. Kern. 2S physicians at banquet Jan. 5, To C. B. Havens A Co., unloading &lt;l_M </seg>
            <seg id="p012">X ; 7- M •«■_ e ■I m II '" ■.— </seg>
            <seg id="p013">97 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE Jan. 14. Jan. 19. To A. M. Pierce, difference in pay roll To I. R. (layle. difference in pay mil To H. B. Eubank, difference in pay roll... To A. H. Klliott. difference in pay roll. To Central Coal A Coke Co.. unloading 74s;. tons coal 181 94 Jan. 24. To Arthur Blake. 1654 lbs. hides 1M 94 Feb. 14, To Edith Hurley, difference in pay roll... Feb. 14. To I. L. Duncan, difference in pay mil.. Feb. 14. To Win. Defraties. difference in pay roll Feb. 14. To K. C Reese, difference in pay roll Feb. 14. To Anna Ro^o. difference in pay roll 1 61 Feb. 14. ToChrwtene Nelson, difference in pay roll.. 4.19 Feb. 14. To Peter Weber, difference iu pay roll Mch. 4. ToT. A. Shattuck. 4 hogs. 1670 lbs 108 Ifeh. .'). To J.T.Dorgan, unloading 1194| tons coal 11' Mch. 6. To .1. LePevre, 25 egg caaet Mch. 7. To ,1. LeFevre, 50 eases Mch. 7. To .1. Spellman, i &gt;1&lt; I rubber Mch. 7. To Kauf &amp; Etinderapacher, 1431 lbs. hid. 1"« Mch. 11. To Standard Oil Co.. 15 empty barrels. Mch. 12. To State Industrial School. 1 Holstein bull Mch. 16. To J. ('. Ackinan. to pay capture of Torbel Mch. 16. To Anna Hushnell. difference in pay roll Mch. 16. To F. Steinberg. 34 meals Mch. 20, To Moline Elevator Co., Lumber Mch. 20. To Moline Elevator Co.. 25 lbs. nails 1 25 Mch. 20. To Moline Elevator Co.. labor. Mch. 20. To Moline Elevator Co.. :&gt;■! meals J.10 Mch. 22. To H. LeFevre, 6 egg e* Mch. 23, To S. 1). Marsh. 15 old posts 1 IMI Mch. 2-i. To K. C. Westcott. 6\ weeks board workiip April 2, To H. LeFevre, 8 egg case April 2. To A. Spellman, 1500 It., old iron... April :i. ToThoe. Kerr. old windmill 40.00 April 3, To Kauf &amp; Hinder, paeher. 17.50 Ibe. hid, April s. To H. LeFevre. 5 egg ea April t&gt;. To L B. Mills, old barn 100 00 April 13, To Fulton Bag &amp; Burlap Co., 296 old sat "1 » ~ 'T* 1 I 1 t&gt; 1 \' ff ' -1*11 I ■ ) 1 * ) </seg>
            <seg id="p014">98 15 To Alex Nathan. 1.0(K) lbs. old iron 1.75 ■ 20. To Geo. Halm, stone in old foundations 22, ToW. H. Harris. 1 grade- BOW.. 20 15.00 35.00 23 To Frits Meininger. old buggy To H. F. Wright, difference in pay roll To Kdna Newbert. difference in pay roll... To Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher. l!&gt;20 II is. hides. To Christens Nelson, difference in pay roll. To Kva Neigbemonger, difference in pay roll To A. S])ellnian. old rubber June 12 June 12 June 24 July 15 July 15 27 15 29 To J. !'. Nelson, old horse To Bert Seobev. ilifference in pay roll 40.00 17 : To Maude Seobey, difference in pay roll.. To T. ('. Roaenmeir, difference in pay roll. 17 17 17 To Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher. 2039 lbs. hides To F. Wheeler, kindling wood 163.12 fi 1 .)(» 13 To Hose ('lair, difference in pay roll To lone Storey, difference in pay roll . To Ether Burnett, difference in pay roll. To Thoa. Hundley, difference in pay roll 13 VA 13 To .1. Snyder. 1 young pig 14 7 50 17 To E. Nathan. 1 .(KM) lbs. old iron To Geo. Knapp. slop for month of Sept. To Kauf &amp; Hinderspacher. 1S71 lbs. hides. To John Knapp. difference in cow trade... To .!. W. Gilmore, difference in pay roll. To I.. Hendricks. difference in pay roll.. To F. W. Neikirk. difference in pay roll... To Douglas Weir, difference in pay roll.... To Susie Weir, difference in pay roll To Lillian Dai ley, difference in pay roll. . . To A. Nathan. 1700 lbs. old iron zs i I l'.l l't 1(1 1«.» l'l Hi 2 20 To Standard Oil Co., 8 empty barrels To A. Nathan, kindling wood 1 00 12 rl u ( . i&gt;. ri ( o., milouuinp St&gt;(&gt; tuii&gt; . ... 28, To A. Nathan. 1700 lbs. old iron 3.40 ■Mi. To. I. H. Helms, old twdatted 100 30. To (I. B. Knap]), slop for 1 month. Oct. 5.00 6. To Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher. 1588 lbs. hi«Ws. . . . 111.16 s. To Standard Oil Co.. 8 empty barrels 8.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">99 Nov. Hi. Id A. Sutton, kindling wood 16. To To To To To To To To To To To To To To To A. Sutton, kindling wood F. \\ heeler, kindling wood Nov. 16. To F. Wheeler, kindling wood 16. Nov. 19, To Nannie Lvle. difference in pay roll... 19, Nannie Lvle. difference in pay roll... K. B. Story, difference in pay roll lone Storey, difference in pay roll I'. F. Patterson, difference in pay roll Nora Patterson, difference in pay roll. ('has. Moody, difference in pay roll ('has. Bean, difference in pay roll I'.- Meininger, yearling calf Nov. 19, To K. B. Story, difference in pay roll 19. Nov. 19. To lone Storey, difference in pay roll Id in l'l l'.t l'l •_&gt;'.! _".i Nov. 19, To I'. F. Patterson, difference in pay roll.. Nov. 10. To Nora Patterson, difference in pay roll. Nov. 19. To ('has. Moody, difference in pay roll Nov. 19. To ("has. Bean, difference in pay roll Nov. 29. To I'.- Meininger. yearling calf Nov. 29. .To American Tobacco Co.. allowance American Tobacco Co.. allowance .1. \V. Crissman. old manure wagon. Reimers A Fried Co.. hoard of workmen (i. Knapp. load of kindling Nov. 'M). To .1. W. Crissman, old manure wagon. ■i. To Heimers &amp; Fried Co.. hoard of workmen M). 5:2 3, Dec. 9. To (I. Knapp. load of kindling 9 Dec. 13, To(i. Knapp, slop for month of Now 190s 13, 1908 .Ian. 4. To (ieo. Knapp. slop for December 4, To (ieo. Knapp. slop for December KaufA Rinderspacher, ltiOr U&gt;s. hides F. H. Kuegle. difference in salary M. M. Keith, difference in pay roll M. Kielv. difference in pay roll... \Y. B. Kern, expenses refunded... John Bauer. I load kindling. John Cornelius, empty barrel 5 «... •Ian. (i. To KaufA Rinderepacher, l(»0(: lbs. hides li To 96 .00 L2.09 Jan. 8, To F. H. Kuegle. difference in salary To s Jan. 9, To M. M. Keith, difference in pay roll To (i '.i Jan. 9. To M. Kielv. difference in pay roll... To .Ian. 13, To W. B. Kern, expenses refunded... 13, To Jan. 1"). To John Bauer, I load kindling. 15, To Jan. 15. To John Cornelius, empty barrel. 15. To Jan. IS, To K. Nathan, old hone contract for 1 year is. Jan. 28, To Kauf A Rinderspacher. 3063 lbs. hi. : 28, 176 12 Feb. 10. To Edwin Hatton. 6\ pounds shaving soap 10. 1.63 Feb. 10, To Hoy Marsh, kindling 10, 2 IN) S. .]. Neel. difference in pay roll A. F. Meckenstock. difference in pay roll. Alice Meckenstock, difference in pay roll 10, To 10, To 10, To 10, ■To Nellie White, difference in pay roll. To (1. H. Seeley. difference in pay roll To (Jrace Seeley. difference in pay roll To Peter Reinberg, refund on bulbs.. To John Cornelius, slop Feb. 20, to Men. 20 To Otto Muller, difference in pay roll To Edna Fewson, difference in pay roll To John Cornelius, slop Men. 20 to April 20 * I* T \ I ' i I To 10, 10, :, 42 15, 1.50 20. 1.95 9, 20, </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">101 April 4. To Tim.-. A. Shattuck, 2 [■._- I April 9, To Griswold Seed Co., rebate on April :i. KM), April 15, To H. M. Brachear, II empty salt barrels.. 1 in 116. To H. If. Brachear, 15 empty salt barrels. . 1 .50 April IS. To John Cornelius, slop Apr. 20 to May 20 in on is. To .John Cornelius, slop Apr. 20 to May 20 10 &lt;M&gt; April 'in. ToT. M. Cook, difference in pay roll... 2 00 •20. To T. M. Cook, difference in pay roll.. 2 00 April 20, T&lt;&gt; Belle Cook, difference in pay roll 1 94 20, To Belle Cook, difference in pay roll 1 JM &lt;). To Kauf 4 Rinderspacher, hides 150 20 May 8, To Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher, tallow. 5 00 8, To C. I-. Smith, difference in pay roll.. May 8, To Belle Smith, difference in pay roll May 8, To .May Lake, difference in pay roll.. 2 45 May 8, To Dewey Van Fleet, difference in pay roll May 21, To John Cornelius, plop May 20, to July 20 Mav •_&gt;!. To K. Nathan, kindling 50 Mav -'2. To John Cornelius*, kindling... I. on May 27. To Standard Oil Co., empty barrels 10 in May 28, To Mr.— Wheeler, load kindling June 1"). To J. E. Johnson, difference in pay roll. 5 00 June 15, To Ks.-ie Burns, difference in pay roll June 15, To Ella Hubbard, difference in pay roll June 15, To Christene Nelson, difference in pay roll June 26. To A. K. Deffenbaugh. 12 hoes. 3950 lbs 21. 25 June 29, To E. Nathan, kindling 50 June 30. To Kauf A Rinderspacher. 22m lbs hide- i:i. 5H June 30, To Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher, tallow July 17. ToJ. S. Smith A Co., 1588 1! . hide [34. 8N July 20, To Edwin Hatton. difference in pay roll. 11.00 July 20, To Lulu Moody, difference in pay roll... July 20. To Ethel Hatton. difference in pay roll... 2.30 July 20, To John Cornelius, slop in no July 23, To H. \i. Brochear, 1 old table... 1 50 Aug. 20. To John Cornelius, slop Aug. 20 to Sept. 20 10 oo Aug. 20. To H. \t. Brochear. load kindling I .on Aug. 26. To Standard Oil Co., empty barrel :i !»4 23, To John Cornelius, slop Sept. 20 to Oct. 20. Hi oo 23, To YV. .1. Welch, rent press drill.. 2. ToJ. \Y. Crissman, load kindling. 1.00 Oct. 7. ToJ. \V. Crissman. load kindling 1 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">102 16. I" I.. Nathan. 25^0 ll&gt;s. old iron is. To Kauf A: RuKtenpaeher, 2S§0 lb». hides. 21. To John Cornelius, slop %5 I Hi 214.20 Nov. 28, To .las. H. Cook, service and expense *&lt;\ Mis; Carinody. special attendant 41 2u Total «fi.-_'v) 30 Total **i._'s4 30 STKWARDS (ASH KKl'ORT STEWARD'S (ASH REPORT DMBCB8CMENT8 DISBURSEMENTS 1. By Grace Dunnernian. labor $1.67 1. By H. F. Wright , salary &lt;&gt;•"&gt; 00 1. By H. F. Wright, salary 65 00 ■\. By Dewey Van Fleet, salary 4"&gt; 00 X. By Dewey Van Fleet, salary 4"&gt; 00 3, By R. L Heinzle. salary H4 «&gt;7 :i. By K. 1.. Heinzle. -alary :&lt;4 (17 :i. By lVter Webber, salary 32 t&gt;7 :{. By lVter Webber, salary 32 ti7 M. By Kugene Jonte. salary ii") nit ;{. By Kugene Jonte. salary 65 00 ■i. By Roy Hessinger. salai' 35.00 ■i. By Roy Hessinger. salary 35.00 8, By .1. H. Broer, salary M) 00 S, By H. T. Broer. salary 40 no I, By Win. Defraties. salary M\ IH&gt; :]. By Win. H. Harris, salary 10(1 OO A. By Austin Ryan, salary. 70 (H&gt; :{. By W. S. Ferguson, salary 3.1.96 3, By Clyde Thompson, salary 40 0O 3, By .1. I). Matthews, salary ."&gt;."&gt; OO .1. By Geo. W. James, salary KM) OO A. By Fritz Meininger. salary 60.00 :i. By Geo. E. Spear, salary 75 oo 3, By A. H. Hammond, salary 30 00 A. By liarney Jiuss. salary 40 no :-$. By H. Steelnian. salary 40 OO 1. By C. K. McMillan, salary 55 oo 7. By Klla (iillespie. salary 7. By M. A. C. Wright, salary 4 :&lt;o ■ Bv M. K. Johnson, salary.. * 10. By A. R. Hammond, salary 9.W </seg>
            <seg id="p019">103 12. Bv J. R. Helms, salary $65 (Ml 13, By Murl Hoyt, salary Die 13, By M. Shively. subscription 13, By Geo. Springer, veterinary services 19 (Ml IS. By Albright &amp; Co.. 1 bane! 1 (Ml 13, Bv .J. C. Walradt, 2 barrels 13, By Dr. K. T. Bowers, veterinary service*! in (Ml Dee. 14. By W. \V. Mapes, salary 12 67 14. Bv 1. N. White, labor. 5 nil 17, By A. H. Elliott, expense* 84 17. By .1. H. Lilley. orchestra music •"&gt; 00 17. Bv If. A. Ramsey, labor 12 ti4 17. Bv Mrs. K. A. Karr. 4*1 lbs. .Iressed duck ti 13 is. By Chicago Box A Label Co.. labels.. 29 15 IS. Bv The Beckman Co.. 5 blankets... is. Bv Carl Fischer, band music Hi 7s 20, Bv K. C. Stroeh. salarv 20. By J. H. Hoagland. drayage 16 (Hi 2H. Bv .1. H. Broer. r..s&lt;- 17 50 27. Bv J. Arvanette. Christmas l&gt;ells 1 90 2(1. By Clyde Thompson, salary 30, By (iaston Music Co.. tuning piano 1!H)7 .Ian. 1. By Stella Brown, salary M Jan. 4. By W. B. Kern, expenses 15 28 Jan. 5. By Mary Hildreth. salary Jan. 5. By J. W. Hildreth.. salary 4 (Hi Jan. 7. Hv K. Dreitzler. horse feed.. 13 75 Jan. 7. Bv R. I.. Heinzle. labor 9 03 Jan. 7. By J. K. Perry, salary Jan. ((. By 1). S. Jordan, salary 7 12 ■ Jan. !». By T. B. Stearns, salary Jan. I, By H. P. Wright, salary Jan. 11. By A. N. England, salary 7 n4 Jan. 11. By Alice Steppan. salary 8 Hi Jan. 11, By M. A. Steppan. salarv. . . 1 -i 4S Jan. 12, By Barney Buss, salary.. 40.00 Jan. 12. By Win. Defraties. salary Jan. 12. By H. T. Broer. salary 40 (M) I 1 •) R I R H 1 1 »' " I III </seg>
            <seg id="p020">* -/. f. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">'•&gt; „ By Dewey Van Fleet, salary 12. By Aileen Whitmer, salary 12, By Roy He singer, alary :;::;:: 12, 12, By Peter Webber, salary. . By \V. S. Ferguson, .alary :::: 12, 12, By &lt;i. W. .lame . alary By Frit i Meininger, alary 12, By Alfred Slack, -alary :::::;: 14. II. By Nebraska Telephone Co., p By E. C. Fisher, Christ mas bella &lt;E 14. 14. 15. By Dr. E. T. Bower, veterinary service By Harry Steel man. -alary By C W . Schmidt, sundries.. £ 1."). Hi. IB. By W. P. Lorehsen, expenses By P. R. Renner, blank papet . By I. N. White, labor 17. By Dorothy Flitciaft. salary :!;;::: 17. 19. By W. B. Kern. P. II., 250 stamp By F. I.. Houghton, subscription ::::: l'.i. 19, Bv R. W. Baker, salary By Erie Pie: . subscription. . ::::: 19, 21. By Ida Baker, salary By Western Valve Co.. ti unions 21. By Nellie Downing, salary &gt;z. L'S. 4. By -I. H. l.illey. music. . . By Jesse Van Horn, labor •"). By Singer Manufacturing Co.. repairs t). By .1. ('. Swartz. demurrage ti. I . I . 7. By .1. A. Atkinson, salary. By D. R. Eggers, photo By W. I!. Stele. 63 lbs. chickens By (ius Doer man, salary B V 8, 11. 11. By S. S. Byerly. salary By -I. H. Hoagland, drayage By .1. H. Hoagland. freight By .1. H. Hoagland. freight By .1. H. Hoagland. freight By Emma Roeder, salary By .1. R. Burnett, salary... Bv Delia Burnett, salan </seg>
            <seg id="p022">106 Feb. 1M. By (1. W. .la: ury $100 00 14. By Hoy Hessinger, salary 14. By Dewey Nan Fleet, salary 4o 00 15, By A. N. Clark. 6 barrels cider 18 00 15, By I. N. White, labor 2 SO 15, By O. K. Gregory, -alary 1"). By W . S. Ferguson, salary 32.50 1."). By Hastings Tribune. •_&gt;(&gt;.&lt; MM) note head- 2:\ 00 18, By Carl Fisher, band music _&gt;0. By Josephine Jackson, salary... 16 98 _'_'. By W. B. Kern, expense. _. . . 51 T'-\ 22, By Sarah McC.alliard. salary 22.50 27. By I'. V. Collins Publishing Co.. subscription. 1 *&gt;0 g By (ifn. W. James, balance salary Mch. _'. By |hm VtDers, -alary Mch. 2, By Kate Terry, salary 1 29 By Singer Manufacturing Co.. 8 dozen needles 1 60 By ft— on «fc Pratt, plumbing 4 % Mch. 5, By Hastings Typewriter Kx.. repairs 2 50 By Stein Bras., bunting • 11.10 Mch. 6. By Western Electrical Co., KM) carbon Mch. 6. By .1. A. Hose A- Son. lathe work 1 7.") Mch. 6. By H. B. Harrison, .-alary U minister 90.00 Mch. 7. By (i. I- Nance, salary 5.61 Mch. 8, By Carl Fischer, band music 3.35 v By Mary Ver million, salary. •I. By Hastings Transfer Co.. hack hire 4.50 '.i. By O. A. Smith, salary 21.45 «.t. By O. M. Smith, salary... 17 16 Mch. 9, By B. K. Ferry, salary Mch. 15. By H. I.. Heinzle. -alary 14. lit Hi. By (&gt;. I- Gregory, -alary 5 00 16. By Ceo. O'GalUgan, salary 16.00 16. By Alfred Slack, salary 15.00 16. By N. I- Che 15 00 IS. By A. Horsfall. salary 20 29 Mch. IN. By Win. Noder, salary.. 14 M is. By K. (i. Briggs. salary 16.45 Mch. 27. By .1. H. IJlley. music 4.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">107 .M c ! i . •&gt;(*, l&gt; v _' it 1 1 i (?nt in* v r u i* n i(*r. bu inscription . _' t &gt;. i Mch. 30, By W. B. Kern, I'. M.. 500 stumps. ... 10.00 Mch. 30, By W. B. Kern, I'. M.. 500 stumps. ... in 00 April 1. By H. ('. Btoll, KKt ear marks _' 111 April 1. By H. ('. Btoll, KKt car marks _' 111 April 1. By Baker Bros., (&gt; cuts... 24.60 April 1. By Baker Bros., (&gt; cuts... 24.60 April 1. By Gertrude Meyers, salary m do April 1. By Gertrude Meyers, salary m do April 3, By Emma Ferguson, salary I 80 April 3, By Emma Ferguson, salary I 80 April .'{. By H. L Hughes, subscription 6 25 April :i. By .1. .1. Conoughy, express April :i. By .1. .1. Conoughy, express April 3, By .1. H. Hoagland, drayage t no April 3, By .1. H. Hoagland, drayage t iiii April :&lt;. By J. H. Hoagland, freight. April 3, By J. H. Hoagland, freight. April :{. By Hastings Transfer Co., hack tare 1 50 April A. By Hastings Transfer Co.. hack tare 1 50 April 3, By K. K. Sprague, salar\ 1 s:; April 3, By .lennie Sprague, salary April 3, By .leimie Sprague, salary April 3, By W. H. Dieken, salary 10.00 April 3. By W. B. Kern. 1'. M.. postage 10. (N) April 3. By Harry Steelman. salary 12.00 April :■!. By L I). Johnson, salary 10. :M April 3, By Peter Thordsen. salary April H. By W. B. Kern, expense.... &lt;o »;s April 3. By (i. W. .lames, salary April 3, By !•'. A. Watkins. subscription.... 8 do April 3, By 1. H. Rickel. subscription 4 .')() April 3, By Megahan Fruit Farm, cherry tree _'4 (to April :*. By ('. K. McMillan, bass viol 40 ltd April :{. By Wahlquist Bins., large envelope- April 3, By 1). R. Eggers, photo view- April 3," By .1. H. McGrath Hardware Co., hardware 8 S5 A|&gt;ril 3, By ('. K. Lawson Hardware Co., hardware. April 3. By ('. \V. Bchmitz, sundries April 17. By Nebraska Telephone Co., toll... April 17. By Dr. Geo. Sprenger, veterinary service l(i (Ml April 17. By Dr. K. T. Bowers, veterinary service- 10 ltd April 17. By Hargreavee Mercantile Co., toilet paper. April 17. By The Bristol ('.... 200 charts 1 44 May 6, By Mayme Woolm, &lt; lamp shade- 70 May 8, By K. A. McElhinney, 1 barrel 7:. May 8, By Gaston Music Co., \iolin Bow _' 28 May 20. By Western Union Telegraph Co., sundries. May '2-S. By Wells Fargo Express Co., exi lt&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">HOSPITAL FOB INSANE, INGLE81D i 24, 24. 2-1. By The Metronome, advertising. By Stein Bros., 2 water jugs By M. M. Abbott, sundries. By Singer Manufacturing Co.. needles 1 25, 29, 14. 14. 14. By M. M. Johnson, 1 incubator By W. B. Kern. 1'. M., 500 Btamp By Win. King, expre By Win. King, expre By T. J. Thorpe k ('«&gt;-. rubber stamp* June 15, By C. A- Lawes Co.. blank .,:„ 21. By ('•. W. Lehr, Agent, expi ,;;;, 25. By A. H. Brooke, express June 25, By A. H. Brooke, express ::::;: 25, 25, By I'.. Dreitzler. horse tec! By .1. R. McMiUen, picture Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. Aug. i 28, 1. s. 15, 22, 26. 27. 31, 31, 1. 6. 6. 8, 12. 16. 16. 20. 20. 21. 26, 27. 27. 27. 28, By J. H. Hoagland. dray age By W. A. Strong. Agent, express By (I. W. Lehr. expre/ By F. &lt;;. Blake, salary By John Hopkins Press, subscription... By Kerr Kipp Co.. paper By I). R. Eggers, photo By W. B. Kern. 1'. If., postage By Fred -Blake. Jr.. meats By S. E. Howard, repairs. By L.G. Brian. State Treas. receipt No. 52010 By J. H. Broer, seeds By Criaaman fc Webber, threshing By Mrs. Kliza Benedict. 12 dozen eg: By J. H. Hoagland. freight By J. A. Rose iV Sons, repairs By Lincoln Freie Press, subscription By B. K. Howe, straw By J. H. Hoagland. drayage By Evening New . subscription By W. B. Saundeiv. Co. Medical Book By Florence Kindig. labor By Jessie Tipton. labor By A. Beck, repaii I &gt; in 00 20.00 10.50 3 oo </seg>
            <seg id="p026">110 LAND COMMISSIONERS KKI'olM" By (1. I). Webber, use &lt;&gt;f machine.. :&lt;7 50 :&lt;(&gt;. By .los. Marion, 24 pounds honey I, By Mary K. Person, salary.. •"&gt; 00 3, By Tyler &lt;V Brandt, plans 90.00 7. By Leonard Carroll, Bweet potatoes 7. By Kauf A- Rindenpaeher, meat -aw 1 ."&gt;n 8, Bv Louie B. Malaclii. music... 1 19 8, Hv Louis B. Malaclii. music... 8. Hv Fairbanks, Morse &amp; Co.. car mover.. :\ _'.') •t. By .1. H. Hoagland, freight 2&lt;i 90 10. By Nannie Lvle. salary 8 70 14. By W. H. Kern, postagi 5 00 14. Hv Gaston Music Co., violin strings 14. By L. Carroll, sweel potatoes 18, Hy J. H. Hoagland. freight J »». By ThoB. A. Shattuck. 4 hops. 4(1 (Ml 20. By H. I.. Hughes. Look 3 (HI 21. By Smith Premier Typewriter Co., repair- 1.75 21. By Stein Broe., bunting.... 4 '.mi 24. By Hastings Fuel Co.. blacksmith coal. 3 (Kl 24. By .). H. Hoagland. dray age By C. A. Heartwell. surveying. . 7.00 By Kauf \- Rinderspacher, sausage 1 •"&gt;•) 7. Hy \Y. H. Kern. I'. M.. postage 5 00 8, Hv I*. R. Rentier, stationery 5 nu B By C. A. McDougall. dishes 3 (Ml 12. By W. H. Kern. P. M.. postage 5 00 16. By W. H." Kern. 1'. M.. postage 5.00 16. Hv I'. Blakiston. Son A Co., hook.. L8, Hy-Holstein Freisian Registry. Year Hook _' 00 By Hastings Tribune, subscription 2 00 23, By J. W. Crissman. 6 days work with engine M) (Ml 2.V By H. C. Glissman, Registry fee 27. Hv K. .1. Tanner, transfer fares. 2 &lt;mi Nov. 29, Hv C. K. Lawaon Hardware Co., hardware 114 61 7. By Phillip Fuller, repairing furnace 2 (Mi Dec. 7. By Ellingnwood Therapeutist. 'A Medical 11 ( l( I Dec. 7. By Henry Hamerand. farm machinery repairs </seg>
            <seg id="p027">111 By A. M. (lark, drugs. ( Bv Wni. King, express i . By H. J. Russell, labor.. 20, 21. By Mrs. H. A. Karr. turkeys.. J. \Y. Pepper, sheet music 21. By Dee. 22, By J. H. Hoagland. drayage 24. By Stein Bids.. Christmas decorations . .. Louis B. Malacki &amp; Co., sheet music YV. B. Saunders A Co., Medical books. By 26. By 30, WON \V. B. Kern, express for patients Reuben Spargur. 5 days labor 4. By 9 Bv 10. Bv .J. R. McMillen. 2 picture frames Bessie Warner, salary H. F. Wright, subscriptions 10. By 11. By 11. By Holstein Freisian Worls. 3 years subscrip- tion. . 11. By Wm. King, express 17. By Wm. Schmitz. sundries.. Harry Coleman. sacred music Daily Republican, subscription Dr. (ieo. Sprenger. veterinary servii ■ II. 0. Bishop, sundries ('. K. I.awson Hardware Co., hardware Adams County Democrat, subscription W. H. Chapman, violin... Daily Bee. subscription (J. A. Miller By 25, 28 By 28, Bv 28, By 64 4.S By Bv 28, Bv 28, By patient) 28, Bv Elgin Gilbraith, repairing violin Fred Blake. Jr., turkey and oysters 20th Century Farmer. 2 subscriptions Holstein Freisian Register, subscription Poehlman Bros., rose cuttings... H. M. Alexander, tuning piano F. A. Wat kins, subscription Daily Repub- Bv 11. Bv Feb 11. lU- Feb 15. Bv By is. Bv is. lican 18. Bv Dr. Geo. Sprenger. veterinary services Bv Dr. E. T. Bowers, veterinarv services By Stein Bros., bookcase unit By T. A. Bhattuek, registered boar </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029">113 I _&gt;7. By E. E. (One. 1,000 cold tablets Ifch. •"&gt;■ By Stein Bids., .i screen.- 14 00 5, By H. I.. Hughes, subscription to Medical Journal ■' IMI Mcli. 5 Hv H. I.. Hughes, subscription to Medical Journ Mch. is. By -I. W. Cull "&gt; s do* II »&gt;'• lich. IN. By J. W. Cull •&gt; do» 1 1 M Mch. In. By Thos. A. Shattuck, 12 gallon hog remedy 20, By (i. W. Kdjjerton. 25 pounds chick food Mch. In. By Thos. A. Shattuck, 12 gallon hog remedy Mch. 20, Bv &lt;i. W. Edgerton. 25 pounds chick food Mch. 23, By M. S. Hill, castrating pip 2:i. By Carl Fischer. 2 alto horn? 21 50 Mch. 23, Hv M. 8. Hill, castrating pig _&gt;:i. Xi. Hv Carl Fischer. 2 alto horn? 21 50 S-"&gt; April 8, By .1. H. Hoagland, cartage April 8, Bv .1. H. Hoagland. cartage 4 '•"» April S. By (i. B. Alexander, expn I 00 April S. By *i. H Alexander, expre ' IHI April 1."). By I). M. Judkins, sharpening shears 1 30 April 15, By I). M. Judkins. sharpening shears April 22, By Pacific Express Co.. express..*.. 1 l"&gt; April 22, By Pacific Express Co., express • 1 15 April 23, By Queen City Laundry, 25J pounds starch. l 91 \pril 23, By Queen City Laundry, 25J pounds starch 1 91 ■)•&lt; April 23, By Lvon it Hcalev. Folia music hinders and rlips. . . ' '•' ''' April 23, Bv Lynn A Healey, FoKo music hinders ami clips. . . ' '•' ''' April 1A. By Jones A Brandes, difference in buggy trade April 2M. By Jones &amp; Brandes, difference in buggy trade 10.00 April 25, By Austin Ryan. 40 trained pictures 10 00 April 25, Bv Austin Ryan. 40 framed pictures 10 00 Mav I, By J. W. Culbertson, 45 dozen egp •_». By Musical Observer, advertising ■"&gt; 00 4. By Nebraska Poultry Co.. 4Q0 P. R. ej 24.00 Mav 1. Bv -I. W. Culbertson. 4"&gt; dozen e-js- 2, Hv Musical Observer, advertising ■"&gt; ll(1 Mav 4. Bv Nebraska Poultry Co.. 400 P. 1 24.00 May 4. By (&gt;. C. Zinn, repairs... May 4. By Pacific Express Co., express 8, By Thos. i\: Son. stall rent. ,. 1 ( i (l 12. By J. H. Hoagland, eartage Mav 8, Hv Thos. i\: Son. stall rent.... 1 (1(l Mav 12. Hv .1. H. Hoagland, cartagi May 12, By .1. E. Currant, expense 6 -4 Mav 12, Bv J. E. Currant, expense May 28, By J. R. McMillen. 62) feet moulding ' 4 7."&gt; Mav 28 Bv J. R- McMillen, 62) feet moulding ' * 7."&gt; Mav 28, By \Y. G. Brower, lantern L r lol&gt;es and burn - ers May 28 Hv \\'. G. Brower, lantern globes ami burn- er June 'I. By Hasting Furniture Co.. 1 iron bed.. * 85 June 'A. By Hastings Furniture Co.. 1 iron bed.. * 85 &gt; &gt; June •"). By H. A. Mikesell, expense June 5, Hv H. A. Mikesell, expense 5 •- June 11. By Carl Fischer, sheet music 1 43 .June 11. Hv Carl Fischer, sheet music. 1 43 June la. By .1. H. McGrath Hardware Co.. ice box 11.00 June 1."). By J. H. McGrath Hardware Co.. ice box 11.00 June 1."). By Hastings Fuel Co.. Blacksmith coal.. June 1.'). Hv Hastings Fuel Co.. Blacksmith coal.. June 15, Hv M. H. Conn, electrical supplies. June 1."). By M. H. Conn, electrical supplies June 16, By American Journal of Insanity. Bubaerip- tion. . June^ 16. Hv Carl Fischer, sheet music 13.14 June 16. Hv J. H. Hoagland. freight and drayage. i io h I H Ho- "1-uid freight and d </seg>
            <seg id="p030">114 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT June 20. By .1. W. Pepper, sheet muse.. $2.35 June 2d. By J. W. Pepper, sheet music... 2 10 June SO, By McGrath Hardware Co., ice box.. July 6. By H. L Polk &amp; Co., medical directory 6 DO July 8, By J. \V. Johnston, 43 tickets to circus 21 .'&gt;(» July 14. Bv Leu Feist, orchestra music 2 .'&gt;() July 20. By H. ('. Wheeler, expense- .'&gt; 80 July 23, By G. W. I-ehr. express 1 70 July 28, By J. \V. Culbertson, 4&lt;4 dozen eggs 7 20 Aug. B, By \V. R.Crissman. threshing 2460 bushels oats til ."in Aug. 12. By ('. \Y. Jacobs, 3 pair stocking.-... 1 "&gt;0 Aug. 13, By I. von &amp; Healev. bridge for bass viol.. 1 .06 Aug. 13, By Rennet Printing House, printing 11 SO Aug. 26. By t. J. Conoughy. express 2 .')ii 2. By H. A. Mikesell. expense 13.00 2.4. By Henry Wehnes. Jr., watermelons 111 00 23, By Blackman &amp; Fuller, wrapping paper. I M 28. By ('. L Barnhouse. sheet music 2 25 By J. H. Hoagland. cartage 1 50 A. By M. &lt; &gt;. Bishop, hog remedy.. ID 00 .'}. By S. E. Howard, repair work 4 !•."&gt; •"&gt;. By Hardy Furniture Co., chair spring... 1 28 ."). By Stein Bros., china ware.. 1 20 •"). By Singer Manufacturing Co., needle- lo I, By Hasting Fuel Co.. threshing &amp; B. S. coal 10 7."&gt; 8, By J. H. Hoagland. cartage 2 00 V By Carl Fischer, sheet music ."&gt; 44 IS, By Henry C. Btoll, ear mark- 4 12 13, By Dr. &lt;!eo. Sprenger. veterinary service- 17.00 17. By \Vebl&gt;er &amp; Crissman. 7 days work with engine 35. 0Q 30, By Singer Manufacturing Co., repairs ."&gt; 7"&gt; 2. By J. P. Nelson, admission patients to festi- val 3.25 4. By Holstein Freisian Association, bal. reg. fee 1 00 5, By F. B. Haviland Publishing Co., sheet music !». By F. V. Nash, difference in claim 11. By J. H. Hoagland. eartafii 1 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">115 14. Bv Jos. Marian :i.s feet 3-8 inch iron Nov. 14. By Jos. Marian, M loads straw... I ."in Nov. 17. By Singer Manufacturing Co.. 2 bobbin ca 2 00 Nov. 21, By Carl Fischer, repairing horn. Nov. J"). Bv Crissinan &amp; Webber, 5 days work with engine 25 &lt;M( Nov. 28, By Miss Carmody expense to Agate, Nebr as attendant to Mrs. Cook 11.20 Nov. 30, By Blackman A Fuller, 2 boxes aapolio. .. 5 00 Total Balance cash on hand l(l ( ?*&gt; Balance cash on hand, deposit with State Treasurer . &lt;iln ~&gt;4 &lt;4 30 GEO. \\ . JAMES. Steward NEBRASKA STAT.E HOSPITAL, INCl.KSIDK. NEBRASKA BEWINi; IKKIM HHPiiKT J ,i- 1 of articles made in 'he Sewing Room during the Biennial Period ending November 30. 1908 Aprons SI, 540 Blanket Tags 500 Bath Rol&gt;es 4 Ball Suits 11 Curtains Curtain Straps 2^2 • i Covers ( 'heniise Comforts Candy Bags 412 re for Stacks 4 Drawers (Men's) .7' 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">116 ■ Cloths Dish Towels Jump Laundry Sacks • Wagon Covers Ticks iWllS I Shirts ,11s IShanu Fa Top Tick tor Covers W SIp sr, Pain Sunhonnet K Coven Cloths Pada Transom Curtain Roller) Hand) Underskirts a? Window Shi i ides Mendin, K.cques </seg>
            <seg id="p033">: HOSPITAL KOK INSANE, IXGLE8IDE 117 MONTHLY ADMISSION &lt; &gt; K PATIENTS Admitted during the Biennial Period ending November Ml l'.ios Months Males Females Total December l'.HHi January l ( .»t)7 February 1 «m&gt;7 March l'.IOT April 1907 May l'.IOT 1907 July 1907 is! 1907 mber 1907 el- l'.XIT November l'.ior nber 1907 January l'.«)s February 1908 March 1908 June 1908 July 1908 August 1908 mber 1908 October 1908 November 1908 I ii 30 ii :;n 25 24 ■ &gt; ti 111 i !l s 12 15 l:; r, . &gt; 12 is ti Is I 1 16 .) l'.t 1 I 1(1 l'.t 'I 13 ,'tl 24 II 13 1 I I i 16 &lt;i i ! 1 1 i 12 M 21 6 S 1 1 15 Is in )■ &gt; I'.ital 133 RESIDENCE &lt;&gt;K PATIENTS BY COUNTIES fitted during the Biennial Period ending November 30, 1908 Counties Males Females Total Adam. 20 28 4s Buffalo 16 8 24 Butler 6 7 13 i •&gt; ii i 4 255 1 78 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">118 LAND COMMISSIONER'S KKl'ORT ."&gt; 4 Cumin* 1 o •_&gt; \A A Hi Dawgon I 3 Douglas 7 0 7 Duii.lv 1 0 1 Fillmure 4 S 0 Franklin .'&gt; 0 ."&gt; Frontier 3 2 •) Furna&gt; 4 5 *.' 1 0 1 •iel.1 1 &lt;&gt; 1 Gosper J 2 3 •&gt; lev 3 1 4 Hall 17 11 28 Hamilton 7 6 13 i •&gt; Have.- 1 1 ■-' Hitchcock 1 2 3 Howard 9 2 II Jefferson 7 10 17 ■ rnev (i H 12 Kirnhall 4 0 4 Lam 5 2 7 • &gt; Lincoln 5 :-! B I»up 3 o :i Merrick 3 2 ") 4 '.» 1 0 1 Nuckolls .'» 7 12 Ot.x- 1 &lt;• 1 kins .1 1 2 I'helps 5 7 12 1'r.lk 7 1 B Red Willow § 6 14 Hie 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">119 Saunders -\ (1 -i Seward 5 o Sheridan 0 1 1 Sherman '-\ 1 I Thayer 6 6 12 Valley 1 1 Webster 7 r_' l'.» Wheeler 1 it I 13 I I Total 265 1 78 \(.K OK PATIENTS AND WHEN ADJUDGED IN&gt;\\1. ■ itted during the Biennial Period ending November 30, 1908 Years — Males Female • iMi 10 to 15 13 4 Between 1"&gt; to 2~) '29 15 !1 Between 25 to 35 40 49 VI Between 35 to 45 "&gt; ( .) 54 \\'-i Between 45 to 55 ' 57 "-'7 x l Between 55 to 65 W 15 Between 6o to 75 IS 9 -'&lt; Between 7.i to 85 is 8 24 Total.. 255 178 Average Age 4o 40 12) KHUMS OK DISEASE OK PATIENTS Admitted during t he Biennial Period ending November .'&gt;o. 1906 Disea Males Females Total Alcoholism (acute) with psychosis 4 0 4 Alcoholism (chronic) with psychosis. .. .'&gt; 0 ."&gt; ebral Syphilis 1 0 1 Cretinism 1 0 I Deleiiuin (acute) with transitory psychosis 4 0 4 Dementia — uii Primary Curable 1 0 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">120 [ad&amp;ry I "erminal pntia Praecox u I ~ 1 ♦ &gt; 5 -1 Terminal 1 unania '_' 0 2 ■ : i- \ s ."&gt; ] :■! eptic Mania ti 1 ' 7 Epileptic Dementia s 1 9 Hallucinatory Insanity Priman 1 4 S Huntingdon's Chorea with psychosis _' 0 -' terieal psychosis 1 0 I Idiocy 1 1 cilitj \ i 11 Simple 4n 29 § t &gt; 14 ncholia tgitated _' 7 9 Ittonita 1 . s BypoehondricaJ 5 2 &lt; • ) R^lipouH I s Simple lit .")i 100 ihinism with psychoaia 1 0 1 cisthenic psychoaw 1 7 ioia ■ cut in y ti 0 1 L' (I 12 1' I lYncnlir Insaiiii 4 12 Hi Melancholia U ."&gt; 1 ircular Insanity I _' ndary Delusional Insanity 0 (i 6 Senile Dementia 38 1"&gt; Senility with Querulous Lnsanitj 5 0 5 Total .. 17s 433 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">121 CAUSE i&gt;K DEATH &lt;&gt;K PATIENTS During Biennial Period ending November 30, 1908 Disea Males Females I Acute Dilitation of the Heart 1 (I 1 Acute Nephritis 1 (I 1 Apoplexy 1 2 ■ &gt; Arterio Sclerosis 1 II 1 Bulbar Paralysis 0 1 1 Cancer uf the Breast (t 1 1 Cardiac Incompeteney 2 0 _' nal Hemorrhage 1 2 ipelaa &lt;i kustion from Agitated Melancholia. " 2 2 mstion from Acute Mania.... '■'&gt; 4 - Exhaustion from Chronic Mania •"&gt; '_' lixhaustion from Epilepsy.. 12 l&gt; I s Kxliaustion from Epileptic Dementia. 2 0 _' Exhaustion from Huntingdon's Chorea 1 0 1 . Degeneration of the Heart.. 1 (1 1 I Bronchitis. ()1 1 Hypertrophic Cirrhosis of the Liver... '_' u Inanition .10 1 Interstitial Nephritis 1 0 'iiml Obstruction (acute) 3 &lt;• Mitral Hejiurgitation 1 1 13 II 13 Peritonitis J it Pneumonia ti o Pulmonary Oedema. it 1 1 Pulmonary Hemorrhage 1 o I Remittent Fever 1 0 1 Senility 13 it 13 Senile Dementia Senile Gangrene 7 9 Hi _&gt; 0 Septicaemia S 2 ~ Suicide by Strangulation 10 1 TuN'rculosis (general) . fi 0 Tuberculoaaa (pulmonary) 12 12 -4 Tubercular Peritonitis .. 1 (t 1 Total 116 tf 162 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">122 LAND COM MI88IO NEBS RE POST NATIVIT1 &lt;IK PATH Admitted during the Biennial Period ending November 30, \\U)s I'nitod State- Males Females Total Arkansas- 0 1 1 Colorado '2 o _&gt; Connecticut 0 1 2 DKnoM 22 28 M Indiana § 4 1L&gt; 28 !• AT MM 3 . 3 6 Sucky 2 2 4 land 0 1 I gan 4 5 9 Minnesota 1 0 1 •uri 3 tt 10 M\ Hampshire M (t :i .Itisey 1 0 1 York 8 s Hi h Dakota 1 (t 1 Ohio 15 7 22 Pennsylvania 12 10 22 Tennessee 10 1 out 0 1 1 Virginia 0 1 1 \\&lt;-t Virginia 1 1 _' n N 6 14 Total 153 131 Foreign Oountri' Males Females Total Abaca 1 0 l • ia 3 3 I Bohemia 6 0 6 Canada 7 0 7 Denmark 12 6 Is uad 7 I 10 {Jermany 28 13 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">123 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLB8IDB 1 0 6 o 1 1 Hungaria Ireland - l 1 1 Moravia ■&gt; l I n l 4 : 1 it 13 12 3 ■&gt; 1 Switzerland 411 Total HI 9 1 l"n known 153 131 93 4(i Total of V. S. 4ti Total of F. B. l Hi it Jotal Unknown 265 17s Grand Total PATION OF PATIENTS riod ending November 30, 190K Admitted during Biennial Pf Occupation — Males Females Total 1 •) 1 Accountant 3 0 .i 1 (i ii i) ii 1 •&gt; ) Blacksmith Bookkeeper : 1 l ■ling Mover her 0 II n 0 II I 1 i ( 'arpenter Cigarmakev i 1 • &gt; .1 1 1 Dentist 10 (I I) Domestic 1 4 Dressmakers Druggist 1 1 it (I : 141 Farmer i i lener Hardware Merchant I </seg>
            <seg id="p040">124 se keepers .rer 1 (I 1 0 135 37 o 0 (I (I (I (I 0 1 1 ■ &gt; ■) anic 1 handise Broker 1 1 •&gt; ■&gt; ■) •) K. her an. 0 ;&lt;, ■"&lt; 1 (i ditor N-ciipatiiiii (I 1 l'.t 15 34 •) ■&gt; (i it (i it cians Plumber •&gt; ■&gt; I 1 l Printer ituu tt 1 RBrakeman Engineer Hand ii 0 II li (I (i ••&gt; 1 n Hands Herders grapher. Students ■&gt; ■&gt; 1 1 I) ■&gt; ■&gt; hers I ■A I Kraph Openton own (i .1 •&lt; •&lt; Total 255 17s HKHEDITAKY TENDENCIES «&gt;K PATH Admitted during the liiennial Period ending November M). \'M)s Males Females Total Aunt insane 3 4 . Aunt epilepsy and one aunt consumption 1 0 1 Aunt epilepsy 1 0 1 Aunt and one cousin insane 1 1 ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p041">125 Brothers (3) suicided 1 1 Brothers (2) imbeciles. 1 u | Brother epilepsy 1 II I Brother and one cousin insane &lt;&gt; Brother and one sister feeltle minded n 2 '_' Brother and two sisters insane 0 1 1 Cousin insane i X 10 Daughters (3) insane o 1 1 liter insane 0 Father insane R 1 1 er alcoholic 5 7 12 Father dipsomania) (i Father and mother blood relatives 1 (i 1 Father and mother syphilitic (i lather and mother insane 1 1 Father and mother illiterate 1 0 1 Father suicided 1 II I Father and daughter insane 1 n 1 er and brother insan* Father epileptic and uncle insane (• 1.1 Father and paternal uncle insane 1 1 Father and grandfather intemperate n I Father and uncle insane and maternal mdfathev insane (I 1 Father consumption 1 0 1 Father eccentric 1 (I 1 Father and grandfather alcoholic 1 II 1 lather had Huntingdon's Chorea 1 0 Father alcoholic and one brother insane.. 1 II 1 Father and brother suicided, and one brother insane 2 o _' •idmother insane 4 2 8 • &gt; ndmother. suicided . Oil ndmother and mother insane 1 0 1 ndfathers (both) alcoholic 3 &lt;• Grandfather (one) alcoholic 5 0 5 Grandfather and two cousins insane 0 1 1 Grandfather insane and maternal grand- parents both intemperate 1 0 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">126 uncle insane 1 0 1 ';er consumptive 7 0 7 ■ier insane 5 8 13 ier and sister insane J :i 5 Mother and maternal uncle insane 1 0 1 'ier and paternal aunt hypochondriacs 1 0 1 Mother imbecile 1 0 1 Mother suicided 10 1 Mother and two sisters insane, father intemperate (t 3 3 Mother and two sisters insane, brother suicided . 0 1 1 Mother and two insane, and one 1 &gt;rot her insane 0 1 1 Mot! ' and uncle insane 0 1 1 insane -i 3 pileptic 1 &lt;• 1 _') insane 0 1 1 r epileptic and one cousin insane 0 1 1 Be o 1 1 ted ancestry 0 7 7 I'ncle insane 4 4 B I ncle insane and mother tuliereuhir 10 1 I'ncle epileps 0 1 1 None so far as can l&gt;e learned 7o 163 Unknown 7."&gt; "J.t 100 Total 255 17s 4:« ALLEGED CAUSE OK INSANITY OK 1'ATIl Admitted during the Biennial Period ending November 10, 1908 Males Females Total rtion 0 1 1 Alcoholism 26 0 Alcoholism in ancestors B0 B Alcoholism and drug habit 10 1 Anterior polis myelitis 1 0 1 bral embolism. o 1 1 (erehrel hemorrhage 0 _' _' </seg>
            <seg id="p043">127 hial thrombosis 1 0.1 Childbirth. 0 13 1.1 Chronic gastritis 2 0 j Climatiric 0 8 8 Congenital imbecility 1 o 1 Convulsions in childhood 10 1 Consumption in ancestors 1 o l Corporal abuse 1 0 1 Cretinism 1 0 1 1 II 1 Diphtheria 0 1 1 ippointment in love A 8 Domestic trouble 7 '.' lti Epilepsy IS 1 • isure to cold 1 II 1 Excessive use of tobacco 1 o 1 B strain 1 0 1 if anger l 1 2 Financial trouble 10 1 Bt over l&gt;eing struck by lightning. 1 0 1 :il origin 0 9 Grief 0 7 7 Gunshot wound of eve 1 0 1 Gunshot wound of head 1 0 1 Gunshot wound and fright 1 0 1 Hard work and head injury in infancy 1 0 1 Head injury Q 0 Hr;it stroke 3 0 A Hemiplegia 1 0 1 Hereditary syphilis 1 1 _' Heredity. 44 23 Huntingdon's chorea 2 0 2 Hysteria 0 1 1 111 health and surgical operation 1 0 1 111 health 4 0 4 Injury 0 2 2 Invalidism and long confinement to bed. 1 0 1 Lactation. 0 12 12 T '1 lM*lI"H~lf* 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">128 Loss of sight and hearing irbation 1 I 1 ti (i ■&gt; : Meningitis ■) Morphine habit 0 0 o 0 ■&gt; •) ■&gt; iborhood quarrel 1 1 1 Bous prostration and worry irectony 1 0 •) ■&gt; ■tudy work 1 1 •) ti (» 0 0 6 E-ork and financial loam ng about weltnierisni excitement 1 ■ » 1 3 fi () 0 0 o 4 Senility 21 Mi and iiitcinpcraiic* iry living 1 1 itualism Batinii and exposure roke •) ■) ■) 4 hilis 11 i) 11 Typhoid fever Unknown i) 4 4 32 52 ; 4 , H ■) Total _'.-&gt;.-) 1 78 CIVIL CONDITION &lt;)K PATIENT Males Feniai' 110 56 [75 59 116 reed Unknown 0 is :: IS i) o 3 ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p045">129 RELIGION (IF PATIENTS Admitted during the Biennial Period ending November M). 1908 Males Females Total 166 134 MIX) Protestant Catholic 29 16 4.") Seventh Day Advcntist •) 0 ■&gt; 23 II 18 Id Unknown .) Total 2.V) 1 7s EDUCATION OK PATIENTS Admitted during the Biennial Period ending November M). 1908 Males Females Common School 58 44 102 : :«) 20 Poor "&gt;4 :&lt;s Illiterate 9 * 12 ■t .•&gt; Unknown 14 6 20 Collegiate 1 &lt;&gt; 1 Fair 89 61 l'&gt;&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p046">• </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>