<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00051.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00051.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Public Documents of Nebraska 1921-1922 Vol. 1</title>
               <date value="1921-1922">1921-1922</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The New York Public Library</seg>
            <seg id="p003">1. ( CONTENTS overnors' Messages Samuel R. McKelvie, Retiring Message, 1923. Charles W. Bryan, Inaugural Message, 1923 •cretary of State, Biennial report, 1921-1922 Auditor of Public Accounts, Biennial report, 1921-1922. a. Appropriations, etc., 42nd legislative session, 1923. Treasurer, Biennial report, 1921-1922. Department of Public Instruction, Biennial report, 1921 1922. Attorney General, Biennial report, 1921-1922 Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Biennial re - port, 1921-1922. Railway Commission, Annual reports, 1921, 1922. Board of Education, Biennial report, 1921-1922. Not published. VOLUME 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE TO THE FORTYSECOND SESSION OF THE NEBRASKA STATE LEGISLATURE Members of your Honorable Body: In delivering this, my final message to the legislature, I am con - scious, first of all, of the very great obligation that I owe to the people of Nebraska for the opportunity that has been given me to serve my native state during the last four years. It has 'been a rare privilege, and an honor that I deeply appreciate. Conditions incident to the war and the problems of readjustment have so greatly multiplied the duties and responsibilities of public officials everywhere that it has been unusually difficult to meet the ever arising situations in a way that would be generally satisfactory. I am iot surprised, therefore, that there should have been some complaint and criticism, nor do I cherish any ill-feeling toward those who have not been in accord with the course that the state has deemed it wise to lollow. I am conscious of having done the things that I thought were best for the state, and my only regret is that I could not have ac - complished more. There has been an interminable effort to remedy our economic and social ills through political action. In the larger sense this has been fruitful, principally, of more laws, poorer laws, poorer law enforcement, less respect for law, more state paternalism, less individual effort, in - creased taxes, more politics, more politicians, fewer statesmen, greater dependence upon the state, and increasing discontent among the people. It is time now to call a halt upon this rapidly growing tendency and fix the responsibility for economic and social progress with the people, where it primarily belongs. Therefore if you dispose of a few of the more important questions wisely and well, you will have served your constituents and the State of Nebraska in the most useful way. I have but few recommendations to make regarding new legisla - tion. Instead, I shall confine my message, principally, to a review of some of the questions of major importance that have developed during the lust four years. In this connection, I am not unmindful of the subjects that were given major attention in the late election. Some of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">2 BCBBBAGE* OF GO * ERN OR MclvELA IE rare the subjects that you will be called upon to consider first. It Is my desire to give you the advantage of any information at hand, to aid you In yiur work. REORGANIZATION OF THE 8TATE GOVERNMENT: The reorganization of state governments has been undertaken and accomplished in one way or another in a very large majority of the states. This was necessitated by the failure of state govern - fctal machinery to function efficiently and economically, and it was ised that the wastes and extravagances and inefficiency common to the handling of public affairs was directly traceable to the involved and complex forms of administration employed. Finally, this con - dition became pronounced in Nebraska that for ten years gover - nors, without regard to partisanship, called attention to it and urged the legislature to make a change. State legislatures, too, recognized t apparent defects in the plan that had grown up in the state over a period of years and recommended a return to the simpler form. The thirty-seventh sesssion of the state legislature recognized it both as a pledge and a duty to correct the inadequacies and incongruities of the state governmental machinery, and place it upon a generally accepted business basis. This was done through the enactment of the Civil Administrative Code. This law has been in effect three and a half years. The experiences of that period are now available to you, and I shall present them to you as an aid in deciding: First, whether yon shall continue the "Code" in its entirety; second, whether you shall amend it without violating the essential principles involved, or. third. whether you shall repeal it entirely and return to the old discredited form of administration through boards and commissions. Am we proceed to a consideration of this subiect, let me suggest that nyone in authority who would amend or repeal the "Code" should be peciflc in stating just how this is to be done. Realizing that general - ies will be of no service to you in the consideration of this subject. and la order that you may have a graphic understanding of the form government which existed before the "Code" went Into effect and f the form of government under the "Code," I am attaching hereto harts which clearly illustrate the two systems. A study of these charts nd of the act itself at once presents certain essential and highly Important facts. THE "CODE" DEFINED: erst The iCode" did not create new governmental activities. It collected and correlated certain activities of government that al- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">LINCOLN, NEBR-, JANUARY 4, 1913. 3 ready existed, arranged them for administration under the Governor, and eliminated boards and commissions that previously administered these activities. Second. The "Code" did not increase the number of state employes. Such increases as have occurred have resulted from the growth of state business, or the creation of new activities for which the "Code" was not responsible. Third. The "Code" did not increase taxes. This fact is dearly proven In figures that I shall present later. Neither will the repeal of the "Code" necessarily lower taxes. Fourth. The activities that existed when the "Code" went into effect, the administrative agencies that were responsible for them, and the manner in which they were grouped under the six Code De - partments are shown as follows: Department of Agriculture: Food, Drug, Dairy, Oil and Hotel Commission Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. Game and Fish Commission Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. State Veterinarian Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. Live Stock Sanitary Board Governor appointed five members. Department of Finance: Budget. Governor. Printing Commissioner Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. Department of Labor: Labor Bureau Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. Board of Mediation Governor appointed three members. Minimum Wage Commission Governor and three other members appointed, 'by Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 Bureau of Inspectors of Child Labor Governor appointed live members Department of Public Welfare Board of Health Governor, Chairman, Superintendent of Public Instruction and Attorney General. Board appointed State Health Officer and all employe*. Medical Advisory Board Governor appointed four members Board of Charities and Corrections Governor, Superintendent of Public Instruction, and Com - missioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Governor appointed four advisory secretaries. Board of Pharmacy. Attorney General, Secretary of State, Auditor, Treasurer, and Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Board appointed live secretaries Board of Embalmers Board of Health appointed three members Board of Dental Examiners Board of Health appointed five secretaries Board of Optometry Governor appointed three examiners Board of Chiropractice Governor appointed three examiners. Board of Osteopathy Governor appointed five examiners Board of Nurse Examiners Governor, Attorney General and Superintendent of Public Instruction. Board appointed five assistants. Board of Chiropody Advisory Board Bureau of Health appointed three members. Board of Veterinary Medicine Governor, Secretary of State and Auditor. Board appointed three secretaries. Department of Public Works Board of Irrigation, Highways and Drainage Governor, President, Attorney General and Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LINCOLN, NBBR , JANUARY 4, 1823. 5 Public Lands and Building*. Board appointed State En - gineer and all employer Department of Trade and Commerce Banking Board Governor, Chairman, Auditor, Attorney General, Governor appointed examiners, secretary and all employes. Insurance Board Governor, Chairman, Auditor and Attorney General, Board appointed Commissioner and all employes. State Trade Commission Governor, Chairman, Attorney General, Commission ap- pointed secretary and all employes. Fire Commission Governor-Appointed Deputy and all employes. Since the Code went Into effect one legislative session was held, In which a few new activities were created and placed under the "Code" for administration. For functional purposes the activities under the "Code" were sub - divided Into the bureaus and divisions, in order that the principle of fixed responsibility might be more clearly defined, and the processes of administration made more simple and direct: but this did not, in any sense, represent an Increase In the number of activities, nor did it increase the number of employes. Fifth. From the foregoing tabulation it will be seen that under the old system the governor had the sole appointing power, or was the chairman of a board that made the appointments in all of the activities that were brought under the "code." Under the "code" this is not true. The governor appoints only the six secretaries, with the consent of the Joint assembly, and the secretaries in turn appoint all of the sub - ordinates in their respective departments. On this point the con - stitution provides that — "The heads of all executive departments estab - lished by law, other than those to be elected as provided herein, shall be appointed by the governor with the consent of a majority of all the members elected to the Senate and House of Representatives, meeting in Joint session." And it further provides that — "Subject to the re - vision of this constitution the heads of the various executive or civil departments shall have power to appoint and remove all subordinate employes in their respective departments." Thus it requires no great stretch of the imagination to understand why professional politicians do not like the "code." </seg>
            <seg id="p009">6 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE Sixth. It the legislature feels that any of the activities under the "Code" are not needed, they may* be repealed by separate act without repealing the "Code," or if it seems desirable to limit the number of E lores, it can very easily be done by limiting appropriations and racttog the operations of these activities. Neither of these ends id be In conflict with the "Code." Indeed, they would be in happy &gt;rd with it It will probably prove true, however, that when the legislature enters upon a careful study of these activities, it will find very few, if any, that it will care to discontinue. For one thing, the cost of administering these activities bears no relation to the question of general taxation. These departments, taken as a whole, collected, in fees and licenses last year $1,129,689.02. This was a quarter of a million dollars more than it cost to pay salaries, traveling and other expenses incident to their ad - ministration. But more important still is the fact that 'the people have, for the most part, demanded the enactment and the enforcement of the laws that have been placed under this act, and the benefits that have accrued from them are so manifest in the great majority of instances, that you will soon be convinced of the unwisdom of discontinuing them. Seventh. The "Code" gives the Governor authority, or power, only to proportion to his responsibility as the head of the state government. He is at all times limited by the acts of the legislature and has no authority or power beyond that point. Eighth. This is the purest form of constitutional government that is known in this Republic. It is fashioned identically after the national cabinet, and instead of being a radical change, is only a return to first principles. Indeed, if any amendments are to be made to the "Code", I would suggest that its title be changed from "The ril Administrative Code" to "The Cabinet". If this had been done the beginning, I doubt that the question would ever have become a political issue at all, for the people could not have been misled re - garding its meaning and purposes. b Ninth. The "Code" does not deprive any of the elective officers their constitutional duties or authoirty. They all retain the functions that were delegated to them 'by the Constitution, and I am aware that they have all they can do at the present time in the performance of Ee duties. Consequently, they could not assume the duties that are performed under the "Code" without increasing the number of loyes in their several departments in a number equal to the number that is now employed under the "Code." Tenth. Under the plan of employment installed under the "Code" </seg>
            <seg id="p010">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 4, 1928 7 provision is made for selection upon a basis of merit, only. Salaries of the employes under the "Code", except the secretaries, are not fixed by law, but are limited by the appropriations of the legislature and are set up in the supporting schedules in the executive 'budget. Employes are classified according to the duties they perform, and a graduated scale of pay is applied, based upon tenure of service. Eleventh. The act which created the "Code" requires that each department under it shall be open for the transaction of business from eight o'clock in the morning until five in the evening, except Sundays and holidays, and that all employes shall render not less than eight hours of labor each day, except Saturday afternoon, Sundays and holidays. The employment record for all employes in the "Code" departments is available to anyone who desires to know how well these requirements have been complied with. No such record is available, with reference to the employes in any of the other departments of state government. Twelfth. When the "Code" went into effect the making of the budget and the control of expenditures was placed directly with the Governor. Under this plan of executive control, none of the Code Departments showed a deficiency at the end of the first biennium. Later when the amended Constitution was adopted in 192ft, the executive control of expenditures was extended to Include all state expending agencies. The savings then effected in a single year were enough to enable the calling of a special session of the legislature In January, 1922, appro - priations were reduced over $2,000,000.00, and the general fund levy for that year was reduced one-third. This is the first time in the history of the state that such a thing had even been done, and it is also the first time that the entire state government has been run without deficiencies. Under the old system of loose accounting and divided control, these things never could have been accomplished. Thirteenth. The accounting and bookkeeping for all of the Code Departments is done in the Department of Finance. This provides a system of uniform accounting and relieves the various departments of the keeping of separate sets of accounting records. Also, a system of weekly reporting is employed, which brings to the Governor's desk at the end of each week a full and complete report of the activities of each governmental agency under the "Code" for that week. This system of reporting, together with frequent conferences with the heads of the Code Departments, keeps the Governor intimately informed, at all times, regarding the affairs of the state government for which he is immediately responsible. Fourteenth. The "Code" gives the Governor authority, through the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE secretary in each department, to make a thorough investigation into the affairs of any person, firm or corporation, -when in the judgment of such department such examination is necessary to the proper per - formance of its duties and the efficient enforcement of the laws. This inquisitorial power has proven very valuable to the state in many instances of law enforcement. ALTERNATIVE TO PRESENT "CODE" SYSTEM The Constitution provides that "the Legislature may provide for the placing of the above named officers" (meaning constitutional officers) "as heads over such departments of government as it may by law create." Therefore, if the legislature desires, it can make the transfer of the Code Departments to the Constitutional Departments by the simple act of designating which activities shall be placed under the various constitutional heads. Such an act would preserve one of the central features of the "Code", — namely, fixed responsibility in individ - uals instead of dividing authority among administrative groups. It would also eliminate the code secretaries. This is the first alternative to the retention of the "Code" in its persent form, and is the only change that might be made that is at all practical. I tell you frank I do not recommend it, and this is why Article 4, Section 6 of the Constitution provides that — "The supreme executive power shall be vested in the Governor, who shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed and the affairs of the state efficiently and economically administered." If the activities under the "Code" were to be transferred to the constitutional officers, it would mean that "the supreme executive power" would be taken away from. the Governor and placed in the hands of the other elective officials. If such an act is not constitutionally inhibited, it certainly would be in direct contravention of the purpose of the Constitution Also, you well know that the people regard the Governor as the head of the state government, and he is held responsible for practically all of the acts of the government, regardless of the limitations that may be placed upon his authority. Therefore, to further limit the authority of the Governor would be to have the public attention centered upon an official who would be powerless to execute the popular will and the exe - cution of the laws would be left in the hands of elective officers, who are regarded as of secondary importance by the electorate. In order words, the state would have a Governor in title, but not in fact. If such a change were to be made, I would certainly recommend that you immediately submit to the people an amendment to the Consti - tution providing for the short ballot, wherein the election of executive </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 4, 1923 9 officers would be confined to a Governor, and an Auditor or Treasurer Such a proposal should have been submitted to the people when the amended Constitution was last voted upon, and no harm could be done by submitting it now. The actual repeal of the "Code" would be wholly impractical, if not entirely impossible. You understand, of course, that when the act creating the "Code" was passed, there was incorporated in it all of the substantive law relating to the various activities that were brought under the "Code" for administration. Thus the original act contained over 500 pages. Since then, new activities have been created, the old acts have been amended, and the entire act was incorporated in a complete section that occupies 384 pages in the Revised Statutes of 1922. The repeal of the "Code" would mean the repeal of all of these activities, and their re-enactment would require a rewriting of each law to conform to any new plan that might be adopted. Not only would this be an almost interminable task, but it would render the section Code" activities in the 1922 statutes obsolete. Of course you will not want to go to that unnecessary trouble, or put the state an unwarranted expense Perhaps there were those who advocated the repeal of the "Code" without knowing what it is. This is the only reason I can find for anyone recommending a return to the old plan of administration through boards and commissions. Such a course would be unthinkable, and there is not a single logical reason for it. That system of admin - istration had been tried in this state for many years and had been re - peatedly denounced by everyone who made any study of the state governmental machinery. Moreover, its serious defects have been recog- nized in nearly all of the states, and the system is being gradually discarded. Divided authority in the handling of public business is just as impractical as it Is in private affairs. Indeed, it is even more to be discouraged in the former, because of the many avenues it opens to wastes, extravagances, inefficiency, political maneuvering, and the shift - ing of the burdens of office. I am aware of the argument that will be used that the resnlU of the late election indicated a desire for a repeal of the "Code", but that argument is not tenable. The people elected a Governor who was pledged to its repeal, but they also elected a majority of the legislature who were pledged to the retention of its principles, and the responsi - bility for the action that may be taken rests primarily with the legis - lature. Therefore, if the. vote of the last election is to be considered as final, it is fairer to say that the people want the principles of the "Code" retained. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE Back of it all, however, is the fact that the average voter does not know what the "Code" is. This may be regarded as a reflection upon the intelligence of the electorate, but it is nothing of the kind. I have seen members of the legislature sit through an entire session without being able to explain the "Code", after it had been discussed for weeks. It Is hardly to be expected, therefore, that the average individual, who if well removed from the sources of accurate information, and who, at best, is not equipped to have a ready grasp of the machinery of govern - ment, would be sufficiently well informed to know what ought to be done. It is distinctly a legislative question, and you could not be charged with a greater responsibility than to inform yourselves fully and completely upon this subject, and then follow the course that will seem to result in the greatest service to the state. THE REASON FOR INCREASED TAXES I have already said that the increase in state taxes has not resulted from the enactment of the "Code". This fact is clearly indicated in the following tabulation, which shows the purposes for which the in - creased appropriations of the last four year period have been made: Bonds for Soldiers Relief.... $2,000,000.00 State Capitol.— _ _ 3,023,273.74 Increase in Roads - 5,062.101.47 Increase for University _ 2,003,587.90 Increase for Charitable and Penal Institutions 2,306,294.61 Increase Normal Schools 769,939.77 Eradication of Bovine Tuberculosis 310.000.00 Increase Vocational Education 257,775.00 Increase Salaries of Constitutional Officers 268,000.00 Paving State Institutions _ 200,000.00 Increase Aid to Schools _... 140,725.00 Increase Law Enforcement 125,OOO.HO Constitutional Convention 116,000.00 Establishing Trade School Industrial Rehabilitation. Soldiers and Sailors Certificates Welcoming Soldiers and Sailors Increase State Aid Bridge 67,500.d0 25,000.(0 25.000.(0 25.000.(0 63,820.20 Revision of Statutes For all other State Government Expense 40.000.CO 1,087,768.91 TotaL _ _ $17,916,786.60 Deduct for Activities Previously Maintained 393.9O0.C0 Net Increase , $17,522,8*6.60 ...$17,522,886.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">LINCOLN. NEBR.. JANUARY 4, 1923 11 Of above increase, $15,733,972.49 was made for Purchase of bonds for soldiers relief. New State Capitol. Roads 4. State University 5. Penal and Charitable Institutions 6. Normal Schools. Eradication of Bovine Tuberculosis Vocational Education. It is scarcely necessary to enter upon an extended discussion of these figures. Upon every hand and all about you is the evidence of the uses to which this money has been put. Nor have I any disposition to apologize for these expenditures, for I believe they were necessary. The money has been carefully and economically used, and the results to the people of the state will be appreciated long after increased taxes have been forgotten. rather a lamentable fact that with all the to-do about taxes, and the emphasis that is placed upon this subject in each political campaign, there is an apparent lack of appreciation of the small part that the state has to do in determining this question. During the year 1921. the state received only 19c out of every tax dollar. The balance was levied and used by the units of government within the counties. For the year 1922, it appears that this percentage was so reduced that only 14c out of every tax dollar went to the state. Therefore, the question of taxation is largely of local importance, and the promises of the tremendous relief that may be given by the state in lowering taxes will prove impossible of accomplishment. And while we are considering this question, I would draw your at - tention to the further very important fact that the State of Nebraska has been paying as it goes. Nebraska is one of only three states in the Union that have no debt, bonded or otherwise, and, in addition to this, this state has $11,773,019.25 invested in trust funds for schools and soldiers' relief. While the state has been following this conservative course and using only a very small percentage of the total taxes that are levied, the counties, municipalities and school districts have been bonding themselves for millions upon millions of dollars. These obliga - tions will be passed on to the next generation and will make it corre - spondingly more difficult to control the question of taxation in the future. Of course this does not remove the necessity for holding state taxes within the most reasonable limits, and you will be commended for whatever efforts you may make it that direction. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 MES6AGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVTE TAXATION: Of even greater importance than the amount of state taxes is the question of how this burden shall be borne. The burden of taxation on tangible property is too great Especially does this apply to farm lands and improvements. At the present time a very large number of the people do not contribute to the support of the state government, in proportion to the benefits derived. What with the constitutional exemption of $200.00 on household goods and the limited amount of other tangible property possessed by a large number of the people, it la r-ecessary to find some new sources of revenue that will tend to equalize the tax burden. This may be attained in a measure by the adoption of a moderate income tax. If such a tax is to be provided, it should not be made so burdensome as to discourage initiative and drive the financial resources of the state from productive to non-productive chan - nels. The very large amount of non-taxable securities now available for purchase makes it possible for anyone to avoid paying taxes if he so desires, and the effect of a burdensome income tax would be to in - crease the amount of money thus invested and decrease the funds available for productive enterprise. If an income tax is to be collected, I would suggest that a law be passed requiring the filing of income tax schedules with the state identical, or as near as may be, as to date and form, with the return that is now made to the federal government. Allowance should then be made lor taxes that are paid to the state in other forms. This would serve to equalize taxes among all of the people. A larger income should be derived from inheritance. Nebraska's laws relating to this subject are not well devised and are not in keeping with the progress that has been made by many of the other states. The relief of publicly-owned utilities from taxation should be dis - couraged. The value of such untaxed property in the state today is conservatively estimated at $30,000,000.00. The benefits from these publicly-owned utilities are limited to those who are in a position to patronize them, and this does not include the farmer. Therefore, the amount that is thus taken from the tax rolls of the state results in an increase in the tax upon all other property, and renders further in - equalities among the various groups of the tax-paying public. It is worthy to note, too, that if these publicly-owned enterprises were taxed, they would be placed upon a fairer basis of competition with private enterprise. The special session of the legislature that was held in January, 1922, gave the state tax commissioner authority to gather information and make a report to the next regular legislative session bearing upon the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 4, 1923 13 question of taxation. This has been done by Commissioner W. H. Osborne and the results of his study of this question together with recommendations will be laid before you. I urge you to read carefully what he has to say. REVENUE FOR ROAD BUILDING You are already advised of the recommendation made in the budget that if Federal Aid is to be accepted for the building of roads, the funds to meet that aid shall be raised from an excise tax of one cent per gallon on gasoline used In motor propelled vehicles. The argu- ments for this tax are as follows: The tax on real and personal property has become unreasonably and in some instances, is out of proportion to the benefits that accrue to such property. This applies to the building of state roads, and it is easy to conceive that a fairer method of raising revenue for purpose is to tax those who use the roads. Such an excise tax on gasoline cannot be properly compared with neral sales tax. for the latter is a tax that is levied upon, all the ties of life and the revenue therefrom is used for the general t of the government, while the proposed gasoline tax will fall )on those who use motor vehicles, and then only in the propor - at they use the roads. While lightening the tax burden on other taxable assets, the tax does not materially increase the burden of those who fortunately situated. For instance, assuming that the tax- ar payer of moderate means owns a car in proportion to his means, he will be able to drive at least fifteen hundred miles (at fifteen miles per gallon) for the amount of a poll tax, or $1.00. Surely this will impose no hardship upon anyone, nor do I believe that anyone will contend that the automobile user, regardless of his station, should be relieved of paying this small proportion of cost for the building of state roads. 4. The roads in Nebraska, in common with other states, are used every year by thousands of tourists who pay no part of the cost of building or maintaining them. It is estimated that one hundred thou - sand tourists travel through Nebraska every year. The gasoline tax would collect thousands of dollars from these tourists. 5. It is estimated that the cost of running the average automobile is (100.00 per thousand miles. Therefore, the amount of the gasoline </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE tax is saved many times over to the automobile user in the reduced cost of operating his car on good roads. (. The cost for collecting the gasoline tax is almost nothing, as the tax is levied against the wholesale distributor when the gasoline is inspected. In other states it costs only a fraction of one per cent to collect the tax. There is no reason why it should necessitate the addition of a single employe to the public payroll. 7. Sixteen states already have a gasoline tax. They are as follows: Arizona, Arkansas, Colorado, Connecticut, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, New Mexico, North Carolina, North Dakota, Oregon, Pennsylvania, South Dakota, Washington, Montana and Florida. Also, I am advised by the Governors of nearly all the remaining states that they intend recom - mending the tax to the next session of their legislatures. The Association of County Boards of Wisconsin has just recom mended such a tax in that state. Their arguments upon the subject are as follows: "The proportion of the total taxes paid by the motor vehicle is entirely too small, and bears only a remote relation to the ad - vantages derived. It is the motor vehicle that created the demand for better roads, for road maintenance and road marking. It would be difficult to cite any public enterprise in which the benefits re - ceived can be more nearly traced to the beneficiary than the benefits of good roads to the principal road users, the motor vehicle owners." "The tax upon the gasoline consumed in motor vehicles rep - resents nearer than any other factor that can be utilized the benefits derived from the actual use of the highways. It indicates in a fair degree the mileage traveled and marks quite accurately the following factors which make for highway wear: (1 The relative weights of motor vehicles and their loads; (2) The relative speed of motor vehicles; (3) The relative number of miles traveled by them. It is based on the theory that, where feasible, in determining taxation policies, the benefits received should not be overlooked in fixing the source from which taxes should be secured." ROAD BUILDING ENDORSED: I am in hearty sympathy with the building of good dirt roads, and I believe that the people of Nebraska have received a larger benefit from the expenditures that have been made for this purpose during the last five years than from any other investment, except the schools. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">UNCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 4, 1923 15 We now have 3,500 miles of the best dirt roads that may be found in any state in the union. I think It is altogether wise that Federal Aid should be accepted for the moderate continuation of road building, if some means can be devised, such as a gasoline tax, to raise state funds to meet it. The system of state roads that was defined by legis - lative act in 1919 embraces about 5,000 miles. This system should be completed, and the counties should also be encouraged to carry on their work, in a modest way. In the administration of road affairs, I recommend that the State and Federal road system be separated from all other systems of roads, and that the state shall have charge of the building and maintenance of the State and Federal system, leaving to the counties the entire administration and control over the building and maintenance of the county roads. This will avoid the conflicts of authority that have here - tofore occurred, and should produce more satisfactory results. It is nothing short of a deplorable waste to invest money in the building of dirt roads, unless they are to be properly maintained. At e present time, all of the automobile license money is used for the aintenanee of roads and is spent In the counties in which it is ■oted. The amount of the license fee that is now collected could well be lowered without so reducing the maintenance fund as to mpair and greatly injure the maintenance of the roads. The money must be raised from this source or from some other, and If this is ot done, I emphatically recommend the discontinuance of all dirt road onstruction by the state. STATE BANKING LAWS: Neither time nor space will permit nie to enter into a specific dis- n of the various activities of the state, for which the Governor is either directly or indirectly responsible. For information bearing upon these activities. I refer you to the reports that have been made by the heads of the departments having these directlty in charge. However, the question of banking and the condition of the state banks is of such very great importance that I feel the necessity of making some observations and recommendations here now on this subject: It is a matter of common knowledge that the state banks have suffered very seriously during the last two years. An unusual number of state banks have been closed and others are being suffered to operate under the most trying circumstances. Much of this is the aftermath of a condition that had been growing up in this state over a long period of years, during which time the state banking laws were inade - quate and the control by the state was not well enough directed to </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE prevent banking practices that were unsound. A period of inflation during and immediately following the war served only to accentuate this condition, and additional encouragement was given to speculation, over-loaning and unsafe practices, the full effect of which has been felt during the last two years, and is still pressing In * rather alarming degree. The Bureau of Banking has done everything that seemed possible or at all practical to overcome this condition and maintain the soundest condition of banking possible, without making unnecessarily heavy drafts upon the guarantee fund. This has required the exercise of the most careful Judgment and discretion, and it is only just to say that had the strict letter of the law been enforced, the number of banks closed would have been so great that the guarantee fund could not have borne up under the load. The purpose has been to close such banks as were evidently unable to survive, prosecute the officers in every instance In which the law had been criminally violated, and aid the weaker banks to stem the tide and regain a condition of soundness. With all of this, the drafts upon the guarantee fund have been very great, and it is nothing short of a very fine compliment to the system of state banks, that they have borne up so well under the burdens that have been imposed, upon them. In my messaage to the special session of the legislature that con - vened January 24th, 1922, I called attention to an amendment that I thought it would be wise to make to the Bank Guarantee Act similar to the South Dakota law. This provides that "when it appears that 'any bank is being conducted in an unsafe or unauthorized manner. or that it is unsafe or inexpedient to continue business, or that its reserve is below the legal requirements' the State Department of Bank - ing may 'take charge and control of the property and manage it as a going concern.' The Department of Banking is then authorized to draw against the guarantee fund and to 'use such fund, or any part thereof for the purpose of making deposits in the banks so being managed by him.' And it is further provided that the total amount of such drafts upon the guarantee fund shall at no time 'exceed fifteen (15) pen cent of the total amount in such fund.' Such banks may then be liquidated in an orderly way, or returned to the proper officers whenever the drafts upon the guarantee fund have been fully repaid, and 'the reasons for assuming control and management by the State Banking Depart - ment no longer exists.' " I believe that such an amendment would be worthy ot your most careful consideration at this time. Also, the direct drafts that it would have been necessary to make upon the guarantee fund have been lessened in a measure by the issuance of receivers' time certificates. These have stood as a first Hen </seg>
            <seg id="p020">LJNCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 4, 1923 17 against the guarantee fund and have been sold and the proceeds used to pay depositors. There have been times when these outstanding cer - tificates have amounted to over a million dollars, but the amount now is only about $600,000.00. I believe that legal provision should be made for the issuance of these receivers' certificates, under certain restrictions. Other recomemndations for amendment to the present banking laws are proposed by Mr. J. E. Hart, Secretary of the Department of Trade and Commerce, as follows: ulsory bonding of all active, executive, bank officers. er regulations and qualifications of directors, requiring all directors to qualify by taking an oath and to show the legal require- ment as to ownership of shares of stock In their own name and right, and not pledged for debt. More frequent directors' meetings should be requ 3. Provide strict regulations governing the sale and transfer of bank stock before becoming effective and require the purchaser to show financial responsibility sufficient to protect the Constitutional double liability. Also require Department approval where sales of shares would affect control and change of management. 4. Eliminate interest-bearing certificates of deposit from the protec - tion of the Guarantee Deposit Law, and limit savings accounts under the protection of the Guarantee Law to 10% of the capital and surplus and issue only in non-negotiable form and not transferable. 5. Collateral to bills payable should be limited to one and one-half times the amount of the load obtained. 6. Department consent should be obtained by state banks before being permitted to act as reserve agents for other state banks. 7. The Department should be empowered to make and enforce reas - onable rules and regulations and forms of accounting for state banks. Tbe Department should be given more examiners and the position should be made non-partisan. 8. Penalties should be provided for delays in rendering reports by receivers of failed banks. The only penalty now provided is re - moval which is sufficient in extreme cases but frequently inapplicable. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE A special auditor should be employed by the department in order to give more efficient supervision to receiverships. PROHIBITION ENFORCEMENT: State-wide prohibition in Nebraska was provided for in 1917. At that time Governor Neville requested the legislature to appropriate $50,000.00 to be used under the direction of the governor in the enforce - ment of this act. National prohibition had not been enacted then, and some of the state adjoining Nebraska were still wet. This made en - forcement more difficult. Consequently, the legislature of 1919 increased the appropriation for the biennium to $75,000.00 and this amount was used during the yean 1919 and 1920 with very satisfactory results. The 1921 session of the legislaure appropriated $90,000.00, but this was reduced by the special session of the legislature to $75,000.00. The re - sult of this state law enforcement in cooperation with the county and federal authorities during the last four years is shown in the following figures: Amount of fines taken 463,754.&lt; Value of automobiles confiscated 9.746.CK Value of stolen automobiles returned to their owners Garages investigated by State Sheriffs 1 428 ( Liquor investigations made by State Sheriffs Stills seized _ 624 Stolen automobiles indexed from all sources These figures in themselves indicate that prohibition enforcemen from the standpoint of the appropriations made and fines collected has been quite a profitable business venture for the state. Th - money that was taken in fines went into the funds of the school district- in which the arrests were made. This, however, has been ;u importance to the very great social good that has accr ar* and I am convinced that if enforcement of the prohibition act by state is discontinued, there will be widespread violation of the law. The local officials cannot, and in some instances will not, enforce the iaw without state cooperation. It is all very well to say that local enforcement can be brought about through the threatened removal of officials who do not do their duty, but this is a theory that cannot be successfully worked out in actual practice. Some officials who flag - rantly fail in their duty can be removed and several have been removed by me, but this a long and tedious undertaking at best, and does not produce results that are sufficiently prompt to remedy the evi The Federal Government is giving very worth while assistance to the state and will continue to do so. but here again is the inability to </seg>
            <seg id="p022">N X. NKBT .1 A \RY 3 19 ndle the situation without the prestiee. contact and activity that the xercise bt any oner agency. The State Law Enforcement Division has also had charge of the ws relating to automobile theft, and this has n of tremendous benefit to automobile owners in Nebraska. Dur- value of $361,428.00 have been recovered rs, and a very large number of automobile ve been apprehended, convicted and placed in the peni- With th» discontinuance ol the State Law Enforcement v. capable official at its head, the activity of bile thieves will be increased many fold, and the losses to the b. ent Division has been very serviceable in : of law and order throughout the state. Local ave repeatedly called upon this agency for asisstance, and th the most gratifying results. The trained officers, nited the number employed by the state, have been apprehend criminals in many cases in which local t would have failed NATIONAL GUARD National Guard has been one of the strongest arms of the is and insuring law and order. This organlza - very large number of whom served in the World War. did most excellent service in maintaining order during strike at Nebraska City, and its very presence in the state has t salutary influence in other instances in which general aw were threatened. This organization is main i received from the Federal Government, and I ti- ii • utmost importance that it be kept in its pres- h stat v STATE PARKS In each of my preceding message ture, I have recommended the to the regular sessions of the legi stablishment of a system of state parks. This movement has been developed gradually, and the last legis - lature passed an act creating a State Park Board, in connection with the Department of Public Work the Board has visited many prc nee this activity was created, pective sites throughout the state. id has already designated some of them as state parks. This work should be continued in a gradual and moderate way until a complete system of state parks will have been established throughout the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR McKELVIE To this end, I recommend that one-eighth of the money derived the licenses tor hunting and fishing be appropriated for the use State Park Board not to purchase sites, but to develop u those that are given to the state. Also, I recommend that the activi transferred from the Department of Public Works to the Depart of Agriculture, and that there be created in connection with the Park Board, and as Secretary of it, a State Forester If the money for this activity is derived from the source thiu I have alrtatiy recommended, it will lepiesent no increase in taxes and will result in a very great benefit to all of the people of the stat This is a movement that looks to the luture and contemplate conservation of the places of beamy and natural advant intended for the benefit and en In this connection, your attei by Mr. Joy Morton to the Sti known as "Arbor Lodge ground, including the Morton i. n Park, valued at not less than $200.0"0.00. T developed, and the only request that Mr. Mort u as a gift to the state is th tor its proper maintenance. The rominal. 1 do not know for Nebraska to accept t of J. Sterling Morton, the founder of Art of the United States Department of Agriculture In conclusion may I not assure you herein made are the result of rr ly fou during which the demands upon the state greatest, I believe, in the history of the statf your purpose to dispose of qustions confronting you in and conscientious manner, and I comn patriotic representatives of the people. SAMUl </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>