<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00036">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00036</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ice Cream Ingredients</title>
               <date value="1924-01">1924-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 22 Ice Cream Ingredients BY H. P. DAVIS. BENJAMIN MASUROVSKY. AND JOHN A. LUITIII.N DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY / THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS !"a&lt;;k Ingredient* Cream ... 4 Whole milk Skim milk.. I Condensed, evaporated or concentrated milk. Condensed whole milk Evaporated whole milk Condensed skim milk.. Evaporated skim milk H Powdered, dried or desiccated milk I Butter Ill Butter oil Stabilizer." 1(1 11 Gelatine Gums .. 11 Ice cream improvers Flavor* 1-1 u Vanilla 14 Lemon and orungr extracts Concentrated true extracts Syrups and emulsions Caramel Coffee extract... Chocolate flavor Miscellaneous flavors Fruits Nuts Sugar Colors Functions of ingredients Butterfat Milk solids-not-fat. Stabiliser* Flavor* Sugar Atari Water is tl IK M 11 It It lit 111 It It Appendix : Standard* for ice cream Federal Definition* ... Icp cream. Fruit ice cream Nut ice cream... Stat. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Ice Cream Ingredients IAVIS. BENJAMIN M ASl'ROVSKY. AND JOHN A. LUITHLY ICE cream has been defined as a frozen dairy product con - taining sugar, with or without natural flavoring, and con - taining a specified amount of butterfat as required by the laws or regulations of the various states and the Federal government. Ordinarily ice cream consists of cream, sugar, flavoring, and some stabilizer. These are the principal in - gredients, but rich cream may be thinned by the addition of skim milk, or skim milk powder may be added, to build up the solids-not-fat and thus improve the body. Ice cream is truly a frozen dairy product altho other products than cream may enter into its make-up. The different ingredients that go into the ice cream mix exist in different qualities, grades, concentrations, and forms and it is desirable, therefore, for the ice cream maker to know something of them if a success - ful product is to be made. States differ widely in their laws and regulations bearing on the constituents of ice cream. Most of them have a mini - mum requirement for butterfat and many also limit the quan - tity of stabilizer that may be used. Others specify the total solids and some the maximum number of bacteria that may be present per cubic centimeter. In the appendix there is a brief digest of these laws and regulations. While the chief attention has been given to the butterfat content of ice cream, from the standpoint of food value, the milk solids-not-fat deserve equal attention. Since ice cream is used as a food, the tendency in some states is to insist upon a high fat standard, but this is not justifiable from a nutri - tional standpoint. An excessive amount of butterfat in the ice cream is likely to cause digestive disturbances, especially in the case of children. The food values of 2 ice creams containing respectively 14 per cent and 12 per cent of butter - fat are given to show the comparison both in total energy as calculated in heat calories and in protein. 1 TtM author* daalr* tu ackrmwl«i«» thrlr iadtbUdiwM to Paul A. Down., E. O. And*»&lt;&gt;n. and Frank Logan for twlpful •uiswtionn. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 NlCHMUKA KXFKNIMKNT HTATION. ClNi'HI.AN 22 Ml* I M.nlMHt. •Iij«I.iu 1('m«I|{IMMV Ifynh'i IiunH vjilim ,...1 , I, I. H mm*9 '•♦!»• »ii |irii|icrl|itii wr milk auluU mil fni w id* tt , nun m (irMMta I hi! |n i lHiiil|ntliil m| KunntHl IiunIIIi MU II In In Iiii |ii •&gt;r*'i i •'!( THn i|iiMllly of It'M tirwim iIm|imim)n InikmIv u\mu I lit. um i»f raw iiiMlKrlnU of Ilii' l»i'«i irimlf li muti, tMNftft, Iw wti - pIim.u.mI UimI only |m - ni ii,. i.im'm-i 'immIIIv nIhm«IiI hvki lulu ih« mlk l'""i iiimmmIilmIii will .Kiidliily miHiii low • litNllly ltf« dfMim TIllN In »■-,».., ImIK I rui -I Hi, iIhIiv In INNUmIii whirl) imhI, ;S : , r " iwr i , I h. II,. ""'" N.Ml Mm lite. /.*. Mi Mi ■•■■ ■ tw Mr |M («»« M MMMI V0M9I I I iA4 4ft Mm ii Ml i ■■!.. i tmmi | k4 MM'IA 4 if Ktt V!w^ </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Id CNKAM tNOREDIKNTH 5 CNMM I &gt;«'nm in h nfinMifh. MWiwt roftdltlmt in 1 h#» Ideal prlnHpnl Innmllffit m •( th« l«« rm«m ml*. It nuppllim lh# MJWglfwt in I HMIffllfft whlth rncllltN(i&gt;fl Ihf pr#|miHHMii nl« iml hIiIa Iti nl.tHiniiiu &lt;l&lt;»*iri&gt;il fiinnlntptifv «ml i.n.ihi.-t It hI«« fut-tiMhM tnllk millila - vllll'll |(iM&gt; ImmIv III III*' it M (•fHMtti. Tfl glVP XIHIll rNuKt. Im ffitnt mmmI -im.mi.i hdiIhim Im* ihun n an ••••#• «t«t 'I l»» th« M*idiiy tMi. nmiI H«v«i m liiw tim&gt; ♦ ••f ImI Mill tin. HMItl -IimiiIiI lit- pHMfttflM^I »»#«fMt-». I'Hlttf MMMf k Hi ft" '"'Mm «UII, &lt;h«&lt; «&lt;ttllf«&lt; Ittlo ftHtillM m Mmmnmi,' Im thin *«*, Htc HMti^c r /•»&lt;»., i^th-^,.,,,, ,,. • IImin .Him l.»i-lHl« l« KllHtlNNlwl I Kif«tk, »l»*pfii/|liuj upMO lti»« \mi+ulnHf nt liul MuIMimHU M-MHl Iff N ItlHl) (/ff'MlMMi*' 'if lniMNffMI "lUMl III ItHtHllK fllMM' II »IH« |XM lltllk Will kfftt ifiMMfiiU win. 10 -h.i, miiik ViMNN'^MM ##r I»»M II I- HWftll »H f»HMH lll». •I.HlU (Hit fNl ...MM.I M '!"• M '••«»»"• Mini N IrtlniUllMii i.f tli»'«». I* |fiV' i HWIWI M'MI.I l.r Illlfll l|MNlll&gt; IMIIIIIIM » hlHh MfffMUM*' ,,i i i inMt i»&lt; im./.'ii •ulii nimI kwpi in iiiU ihkim nr • MMMMmlil' Him. will) IHIIk iIhIhiIiiimIIhii If |iimv|mii»Iv llnllu.l id liuniMKtMilMill, friM»K»i 'i»'«m In vmiv MNf (•fMl'iorV I | . , , . , u . , 1 1 1 ii L 1 1 1 u 4* i im mi miitnip- hi «i«m, |«i( r f l(&gt; &gt;*H«ft »wwnt« m» hMilim HUMMl ft*** &lt;rf »»i»» C»mI M.fJi.MNlw »M It.. i Mal.ii.hlM IIi.h M II II ll»|.»MWMil III 4tfHf.lll.ll&gt;. » i" i. ..... -W?:r «•■ -1 !' M MX ::: HwmnI VfMI hmli IIU»IM» iMlil.llilIlM H ItlMh linflMl </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 WHOl.fc MlUt Whole milk alone cannot be used a* the chief ingredient for a legal ice cream, because it does not contain enough butterfat. The uae of whole milk for commercial ice cream is almost entirely limited to the standardization of cream to reduce the latter to the desired percentage of fat. Milk must be clean, sweet, and of low bacterial count if good results are to be obtained in ice cream making. There is a great varia - tion in the composition of milk, depending on the breed, in - dividuality of the cow, season of the year, etc. It is difficult, therefore, to give the average composition. The figures given are believed to be representative: WHOLE MILK Wat,, 8 Butterfat Protein Casein 2.:. 0.7 Albumin :i.2 f..l Milk sugar. A«h Milk solids-not-fat Milk solids... 100 The average specific gravity is 1.032, water being 1.000. race a gallon of water weighs 8.34 pounds, a gallon of milk considered in commercial practice to weigh 8.60 pounds. SKIM MILK Skim milk, sweet and fresh from the separator, is a good source of milk solids-not-fat and a valuable diluent for standardizing the mix for butterfat. When it is not fresh or has developed any appreciable acidity, its value in preparing an ice cream mix is impaired and difficulty is frequently en - countered in obtaining a perfect emulsion during homogeniza- specific gravity of skim milk averages 1.036, at which re the weight of a gallon would be 8.64 pounds. Skim k from a centrifugal separator has an average composi - i' as follows : ■Modern Methods of T««tin« Milk and Milk Products. Van Slyke. Orange Judd Co., N. Y. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I. V. &lt; Kt.AM iNUKtCUlKNTS 7 CONDENSED, EVAPORATED, OR CONCENTRATED MILK Condensed, evaporated, or concentrated milk is the product obtained from the evaporation of a considerable proportion of water from the whole fresh lacteal secretion obtained by the complete milking of one or more cows. Skim milk is also condensed. Condensed milks are divided into sweetened and unsweetened whole milk, and sweetened and unsweetened skim milk. Sometimes the term " condensed " is applied to the sweetened and " evaporated " to the unsweetened product. Condensed Whole Milk. — Condensed whole milk (sweet- ened) contains not less than 28 per cent of milk solids, of which not less than 8 per cent is milk fat or butterfat. Ordi - narily this product does not have any wide use in ice cream making altho it is a good source of butterfat, milk solids-not - fat, and sweetening. The reason is that the price is usually too high to make its use economical. If it contains enough sugar, condensed milk will keep indefinitely; and if used in ice cream making, a proportional reduction of sugar in the mix should be made. The concentration of sugar in sweetened condensed milks may, under certain conditions, induce sandi- ness in the ice cream. The average composition of condensed whole milk (sweet- ened ) is as follows CONDENSED WHOLE MILK Her cent Water 26.6 Butterfat 9.0 100.0 ft Hulu-rfMt Protein Albumin :::::::o;w 2.T6 .SO Milk suKai Adi 8.66 fi.26 80 Milk solid* 8.70 Protein Milk .sugar Ash 8.5 1S.3 1.8 Milk solids Cane sugar. ... 32.6 40.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 The weight per gallon varies according to the concentra - tion, but averages 10.67 pounds. Evaporated Whole Milk. — Evaporated whele milk (un - sweetened) contains not less than 25.5 per cent of total milk solids, of which not less than 7.8 per cent is butterfat. In bulk this product is perishable and will keep but a short time except in cold storage. When canned it is generally too ex - pensive for use as a source of either butterfat or other milk solids. If the cost is low enough, it is valuable, particularly. for improving the body of the ice cream. The average com - position is as follows: EVAPORATED WHOLE MILK / KK*. x Mijk sugar Milk solids. 100.1 tThe average weight per gallon is about 8.88 pounds. Un - eetened, evaporated milk, either whole or skim, unless aerheated, sterilized, and preserved in air-tight containers, highly perishable. Superheated, evaporated milk tends to luire an undesirable flavor which may be objectionable in ; frozen cream. In unhomogenized ice cream mixes, super - »ted milks increase the viscosity and consequently the body the mix to a greater degree than milks not so heated. On ; other hand, superheated milks are not as satisfactory in mogenized mixes. Condensed Skim Milk. — Condensed skim milk ( sweetened ) contains not less than 28 per cent milk solids, and is a good source of milk solids-not-fat as well as of sugar. This product may be held in storage for a considerable period without spoiling. Its composition - of course varies, but a fair aver Condeiued Milk and Milk Powder. Hunziker. published hy the muthor. I.nCranm'. 1 ■ Manual of Milk Product*. Stocking. Macmillan. New York </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Ice Cream Ingredients 9 The weight per gallon probably averages 11.17 pounds. Evaporated Skim Milk. — Evaporated skim milk (unsweet - ened) is one of the best sources of solids-not-fat in the ice cream mix. This product is ordinarily purchased in bulk and is more largely used than the other concentrated milks. Legally it must contain not less than 20 per cent milk solids. The bulk goods usually average from 27 per cent to 33 per cent milk solids and weigh 9.30 pounds per gallon, on the average. This product is perishable and must be kept cold. POWDERED. DRIED. OR DESICCATED MILK Powdered, dried, or desiccated milk is made from whole, partly skimmed, or skim milk evaporated to dryness. Dried milks vary greatly in composition and solubility depending upon the composition of the original milk and the manufac - turing process employed. An average composition ' for these various powders is as follows : POWDERS Whole milk Partly skimmed Skim milk powder powder powder Per cent Per cent Per cent Any of these products may be used in the ice cream mix as a concentrated source of milk solids, and the first two may serve the additional purpose of supplying part of the fat. Since powdered milks contain a low percentage of moisture, they may be kept for considerable periods without spoilage. Dairy Technology. Limn and White. John Wiley * Sons. N. Y. i:ur*ucr&gt;iSfcL&gt; skim hujK Water Butterfat ... Protein Milk sugar Ash PeremU _ 30.10 0.76 11.03 15.76 2.B1 Milk solids Cane sugar . 30.06 39.84 100.00 Water Butterfat Protein (casein) Milk sugar Ash Total milk solids 1.40 29.20 26.92 36.48 6.00 98.60 5.00 15.10 33.30 39.70 6.90 95.00 7.00 1.00 37.00 47.00 8.00 93.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 Sometimes whole milk powder is called " cream powder " or " butterfat powder." In preparing milk powder for use in the ice cream mix, warm a little milk or water to about 80° F. and then sift the powder on the top, agitating constantly until the powder is completely dissolved. Another method is to mix the powder and sugar together dry, then add a little milk and stir into a paste, adding more milk until thin enough to strain. Before adding to the rest of the mix, strain thru a sieve to remove undissolved particles. Best results are obtained from milk powders when a viscolizer, emulsor, or homogenizer is used. Powdered buttermilk as made commer - cially is not suitable for use in ice cream mixes. BUTTER Butter for ice cream making should contain no salt and is called commercially " sweet butter." Sweet butter is not necessarily made from sweet cream. Butter may be the only source of butterfat in the mix but is best used in connection with some cream. Butter is much less perishable than cream, because it contains a smaller proportion of the milk proteins and can be successfully held in cold storage for a considerable period. Fresh butter usually gives the best results. Average composition of unsalted butter is as follow Butter oil (the milk fats separated from the curd and water) is a good pure source of fat for ice cream making. When properly prepared, the oil will keep indefinitely without deterioration. Usually the cost of the oil is such that it can - not profitably be used to any great extent as a source of fat in ice cream making. If either butter or butter oil is used in the mix, the latter must be homogenized, viscolized, or emulsified to obtain good results in the frozen cream. &lt;SALTED BITTER Vater lutterfat 'rotein (curd) lilk sugar ish I'rr cent 14.66 84.00 0.85 0.30 0.20 100.00 BUTTER OIL </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Ice Cream Ingredients 11 STABILIZERS Stabilizers, or binders, frequently misnamed " fillers," are essential in the manufacture of the best quality of ice cream. They bind the ingredients together, assist in producing a smooth body, tend to retard crystallization, and help prevent too rapid melting of the ice cream. Without their use ice cream is likely to be either fluffy, icy, or coarse in texture. Stabilizers include gelatine, various vegetable gums, and the so-called " ice cream improvers." They are not adulterants, but useful and necessary constitutents of ice cream. Gelatine. — Gelatine is a by-product of animal origin and is used in either leaf or powdered form, the latter being the more common. A good grade of gelatine is characterized by high congealing or jellying power, freedom from impurities, and low bacterial content. The federal pure food regulations provide that in a million parts of gelatine there shall not be more than 350 parts of sulphur dioxide (SO 2 ), 300 parts of copper (Cu), 100 parts of zinc (Zn), or 1.25 parts of arsenic trioxide (As.jO 3 ). The physical characteristics of different grades of gelatine can easily be determined by comparative tests for swell, jelly - ing strength, and bacterial content. The tests for swell and jellying strength are made as follows: Make a 3 per cent solution of each kind of gelatine (0.3 or about one-third of an ounce of gelatine to 10 ounces of water in a pint glass fruit jar). The measured quantity of cold water is placed in each jar and the powdered gelatine sifted on top. After standing undisturbed for 15 minutes the jars are observed to determine which sample shows the greatest swell or increase in volume of the gelatine. The gelatine upon being added to water slowly settles to the bottom and there the particles swell as they absorb water. The swell test can not readily be made with leaf gelatine. Next, the jars are set either on a false wire bottom or on wooden blocks, in a container of cold water which is gradually heated to 140" F., the gelatine solution in each jar being stirred constantly. At that temperature all the gelatine should be dissolved and each solution should be clear and free from odors. Cloudiness and odors indicate undesirable impurities in the gelatine. The jars are then set in the re - frigerator and observations made as to which sample congeals first. The gelatine that possesses the greatest congealing power will jelly first. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 ) These tests are useful to the practical ice cream maker but are not entirely reliable as indicating the quality of the gelatine for ice cream making. Gelatines frequently have a high bacterial count, which may serve as a source of contami - nation for ice cream. In certain states also there are lawn or regulations governing the number of bacteria per cubic centimeter (c. c.) permitted in market ice cream. It is im - portant, therefore, to know the number present in the gelatine. To determine the bacterial count of gelatine, plate cultures should be made using 1 c. c. of a 1 part gelatine in 1,000 parts of water (0.1 per cent gelatine) solution on agar plates which should be incubated for 48 hours at 100° F. Gelatine may be added to the ice cream mix in different ways. Perhaps the easiest way to add powdered gelatine is to mix it dry with the sugar and sift the mixture slowly into the pasteurizing vat while the temperature is being raised to 145° F., care being taken to see that the whole mix is stirred or agitated during the addition of the gelatine and sugar. In this way the sugar and gelatine both go into the solution very rapidly, lumps are avoided, and the gelatine is subjected to the pasteurizing temperature. The ideal way is to next run the entire mix from the pasteurizer thru the viscolizer, emulsor, or homogenizer and then over the cooler. tlf leaf gelatine is used or if the ice cream mix is not pas - irized, the method of adding gelatine is different. Leaf atine is added to a small quantity of cold water or cold m milk and allowed to soak for from 20 to 30 minutes, en the softened gelatine mixture should be heated in a ter jacketed heater or a double boiler to a temperature t above 160° F. if water is used, or 145 F. in case milk used. During heating, the mixture should be stirred con - mtly so that the gelatine will completely dissolve and not •m in lumps. Heating should continue for from 10 to 15 nutes at the high temperature to insure complete solution. When the entire mix is to be pasteurized, the hot gelatine solution is added slowly to the agitated mix at the time the temperature reaches 145° F. If the gelatine solution is to be added to a cold mix it should first be cooled to a temperature of about 100° F. and then added to a small quantity of the mix and thoroly stirred. Then the mix containing the gel - atine should be stirred into the entire mix and the whole set away to age. Powdered gelatine may be prepared and added in the same manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Ice Cream Ingredients 13 Gums. — Gums of various kinds are used as stabilizers, particularly for sherbets and ices, where a more compact body is desired. They are of vegetable origin and in general are not readily soluble in water. In consequence it is usually necessary to dissolve them in a sugar syrup. Gum tragacanth is one of the more common gums and it comes in chips or shavings. Like most gums, it is not readily soluble in water. It may, however, be prepared as follows:' " One ounce (gum tragacanth) in chip or shaving form when soaked and heated in a quart of water will cause the entire mass to become very heavy and tenacious. If to this mass l'/a quarts (3 pounds) of sugar is added, about 11.4 quarts of gum tragacanth stock will be produced." This solution will be usable for several weeks. One quart of this stock solution is sufficient for 10 gallons of ice cream. Another method which may also be used for other vege - table gums is as follows: - Prepare a completely saturated solution of regular cane or beet sugar in cold water. In other words, dissolve as much sugar as possible in cold water, add - ing sugar until some remains undissolved at the bottom of the container. Stir thoroly for 10 minutes and then allow to stand for 30 minutes, after which pour off the syrup, allowing the undissolved sugar to remain. To this syrup add commer - cial glucose, equal parts by weight, and mix thoroly. The resulting mixture is an excellent solvent for vegetable gums. The details for commercial making of this solvent are as follows: Into a 25 to 30 gallon vessel (stone is preferable) pour 4 gallons and 1 pint of water (33 pounds) of ordinary room temperature ; to this add 67 pounds of granulated sugar and stir vigorously and continuously until the sugar is all dissolved. Add 100 pounds of glucose to the sugar solution, stirring thoroly until the glucose is all incorporated in the syrup. This syrup will keep indefinitely. Determine the quantity of gum needed for the mix and take 12 times its weight of the solvent syrup. Stir the syrup slowly and steadily while sifting the powdered gum on the surface as rapidly as possible. As soon as it is completely distributed, pour it into the ice cream mix, which should be agitated steadily and thoroly. Mix the gum with the syrup im - mediately before adding to the mix. In calculating the sugar for the mix, the solvent syrup may be considered as having approximately one-half the sweetening effect of sugar. bulletin 156. Vermont Agricultural Experiment Station. ■ Heller'a Guide (or Ice Cream Maker*, pace 107, published by B. Heller * Co. rhumirii. 191*. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 Ice Cream Improvers. — Ice cream improvers are usually patented mixtures which may contain, among other ingredi - ents, rennet, pepsin, rice starch, corn starch, egg albumin. calcium sucrate, powdered milk, gums, gelatine, etc. Their purpose is to act as stabilizers and in some cases to increase the smoothness and swell in the frozen cream. FLAVORS k Flavoring increases the palatability of ice cream and pro - js variety. Flavors are essential to a satisfactory ice I'anilla. — Vanilla is the most common and is the basal r which is used in combination with other kinds. It is » in various strengths ancj in different forms, including ilcoholic extract and a paste. Ordinarily vanilla is used le alcoholic extract of the Vanilla bean, of which there are ral varieties. A United States standard vanilla extract Id contain in 1 gallon the. extractive matter of not less 13 ounces of normal beans. The finest is the native ican, after which rank the Bourbon, Java, and Tahiti. In tion to the above, wild vanilla beans are also used, but do not have the fine flavor of the true beans. The tonka is also used in combination with the other beans in the expensive grades of vanilla. It owes its flavor to cou - in, which, while not so pleasant when used alone, blends with the extract of the more expensive beans and imparts 1, fine flavor. So called imitation or synthetic extracts of lla lack the rich flavor of the genuine, and are frequently •ed with burnt sugar and sometimes with prune juice. Lemon and Orange Extracts. — Extracts of lemon and orange are made by dissolving in alcohol the respective oils obtained from the skins of the fruit. The United States standard requires a minimum of 5 per cent of the oil by vol - ume in the extract. Orange and lemon extracts are more largely used in ices and in sherbets, and frequently in con - nection with the juice or pulp of the fresh fruit. Concentrated True Extracts. — Concentrated true extracts of various fruits and berries are obtainable. They impart a rich flavor to ice cream and but a small quantity need be used. Usually they are expensive and imitations are sometimes used, and many of these tend to impart an undesirable so-called " perfume " flavor. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Ice Cream Ingredients 15 Syrups and Emulsions. — Concentrated syrups and emul - sions are also prepared from various fruits. The former have the concentrated extract diluted with syrups while the emul - sions are prepared by the use of certain harmless emulsifiers, such as gums or gelatine. Fruit emulsions and fruit syrups are becoming more common and are usually satisfactory as a source of fruit flavors. Caramel. — Caramel flavoring is obtained by heating dry granulated sugar until it melts at 320° F. and allowing the mass to solidify by cooling. During cooling the mass becomes crystalline and opaque. It is then reheated to between 374 = and 410 : F., during which process it changes to a brown, non - crystalline, thick syrup called caramel, which has the charac - teristic flavor. It is more satisfactory to purchase caramel than to try to make it on a small scale. Coffee Extract. — Coffee extract is prepared from a good grade of freshly ground coffee beans, by placing 1 pound of the ground coffee in 2 quarts of cold water. The water is heated to a few degrees below the boiling point and kept at that temperature for from 30 minutes to 1 hour, or until after straining the volume of liquid equals 1 quart. The extract thus obtained may be used directly or can be stored for future use by the addition of 3 pounds of sugar to each uart of extract. Chocolate Flavor. — Chocolate flavor may be obtained by using bitter chocolate, milk, or sweet chocolate, or cocoa. Cocoa differs from chocolate in that most of the fat or oil (cocoa butter) has been extracted, but it retains the charac - teristic flavor. Chocolate syrups may be prepared as follows : To 1 pound of chocolate or cocoa add 1 quart of water, heat to a temperature a few degrees below boiling, then add 1 pound of sugar and stir the entire mass while it is slowly heating, care being taken not to allow it to scorch. If prepared in a double boiler or steam jacketed kettle the danger of scorching is largely avoided. Some prefer to add about 3 ounces of vanilla extract, and if desired a half ounce of cinnamon ex - tract may be used. For deepening the color, add from 1 to IVi ounces of caramel. Miscellaneous Flavors. — Many other flavors not mentioned may be obtained for use in ice cream. Among the more com - mon ones are custard, tutti-frutti, Roman punch, synthetic rum, cider flavor, etc. Salt in small quantities is very useful </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station. Circular 22 16 t bringing out flavors in ice cream. The quantity used will &gt;end upon the flavor, but about a teaspoon level full for 10 Ions of ice cream mix is usually satisfactory. Fruits. — Fruits are used in season and may be prepared when needed. For sweetening fresh fruits, from Va to 1 part of sugar is needed for each part of fruit, depending on the kind and tartness. With preserved fruits no sugar need be added, but from 1 to 2 ounces of a 50 per cent citric acid solu - tion should be used for each 5 gallons of mix to help bring out the flavor. Fresh or preserved fruits may be put into the freezer when the mix is ready to draw or may be stirred into the frozen cream immediately after drawing from the INuts. — Nuts are commonly used in ice cream. English lnuts, black walnuts, almonds, peanuts, pecans, filberts, and tachios are the kinds that have the widest use. Each kind nut contains a high percentage of a characteristic oil which riches the mix but which readily becomes rancid and spoils s flavor. It is, therefore, of the utmost importance that ly fresh nuts be used. If there is any question about the sshness of the nuts they should be thoroly washed. Al* mds and pistachio nut meats must be blanched and the skin noved before use. The skins should be removed from pea - ts, which also should be roasted before use. Ordinarily all ts are chopped or ground immediately before use. Nuts s added to the mix in the same manner as fruits. SUGAR I Cane and beet sugars are identical in chemical composition are the chief sources of sweetening in ice cream. These ars are ordinarily used in the granulated or common table. m and should be clean and free from mold. Sometimes ert sugar syrups, prepared by treating cane or beet sugar h tartaric or other acids, are used in the mix. Such syrups useful where it is desired to use a sugar syrup, but they c the sweetening power of ordinary sugar.' Corn syrup useful source of sweetness in limited quantities in combi - ion with cane or beet sugar.- It is not desirable that more n 50 per cent of cane or beet sugar be replaced by corn up, since it has a distinct flavor which is disliked by many pie. Compared with cane sugar, corn syrup has from -half to two-thirds the sweetening power. Honey, together 1 Journal Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. Vol. 14. No. 6 • Bulletin IS*. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. umice </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Ice Cream Ingredients 17 with malt, maple, and other syrups, is sometimes used, but under normal conditions it usually does not pay to use any - thing but cane or beet sugar. Certain states have laws or regulations governing the use of other sweetening substances than cane or beet sugar and these must be complied with. COLORS Colors are available in the form of paste, powder, or liquid. Only those should be used that conform to the provisions of the Federal Pure Food and Drug Act. Common colors are strawberry red, blood red, yellow, egg yellow, lavender, blue, green, etc. If used with fruits, the kind and quantity used should be such as to harmonize with the fruit or flavor. Many ice cream makers like to color vanilla ice cream to a light yellow. If this is done, a color chart should be used to insure a uniform product thruout the year. A common color chart or rod consists of a sealed glass tube containing an unfadable colored paper and may be procured from creamery supply concerns. FUNCTIONS OF INGREDIENTS The ice cream mix normally contains the following ingredi - ents, namely, butterfat, milk solids-not-fat, sugar, water, flavoring, and some stabilizer. BUTTERFAT Butterfat is obtained from cream, whole milk, sweet but - ter, condensed and powdered milk, and butter oil. Its func - tions in ice cream are: A. To supply a nutritious, digestible and palatable food fat. B. To impart the delicious butter flavor and to enrich other flavors. C. To assist in the formation of a smooth body and fine texture in the frozen product. D. To give color to the ice cream MILK SOLIDS-NOT-FAT Milk solids-not-fat (serum solids) contain the milk pro - teins, namely, casein, lactalbumin, and other nitrogenous ma - terial; milk sugar (lactose) and various mineral salts that are normally present in milk and cream. The functions of the milk solids-not-fat are to give body to, and act collectively as </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 binders in the frozen ice cream. From 9 to 12 per cent of milk solids-not-fat usually give best results. Larger quan tities tend to induce sandiness because of the quantity of milk sugar present. STABILIZERS Stabilizers assist in holding the ingredients together, thus increasing the viscosity of the ice cream mix, and help to provide a cellular structure that will hold air incorporated during freezing. By their action in retarding crystallization and in preventing the formation of large crystals of either water or milk sugar, stabilizers help to produce a smooth, firm body. Thru a combination of the above, a frozen cream of quality is produced that does not melt down too rapidly upon being exposed to warm temperatures. FLAVORS Flavoring increases palatability and furnishes variety in ice cream. Without flavoring, ice cream would be a sweet, insipid, tasteless product. SUGAR Sugar supplies the sweetness in ice cream and thereby makes it more palatable. Too much sugar is sickening to tlv taste, lowers the freezing point of the mix, tends to induce sandiness, and makes it more difficult to obtain the desired overrun. From 12 to 14 per cent of sugar usually gives the best results. For soda fountain use, the lower percentage is advisable. COLORS Colors add to the attractiveness of ice cream by appealing to the eye of the consumer. WATER Water present in the normally undiluted ice cream mix acts as a solvent of the ingredients and influences both the chemical and physical properties of the mix as it passes thru the different mechanical processes involved in ice cream making. Excessive water lowers the food value and injures the quality of the product. The percentage of water com - monly varies from about 60 to 70 per cent, depending upon the content of local solids. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Ice Cream Ingredients 19 APPENDIX STANDARDS FOR ICE CREAM FEDERAL Definition!. — Ice cream is a frozen product made from cream and sugar, with or without a natural flavoring, and containing not less than 14 per cent of milk fat. Fruit ice cream is a frozen product made from cream, sugar and sound, clean mature fruits, and containing not less than 12 per cent of milk fat. Nut ice cream is a frozen product made from cream, sugar, and sound non-rancid nuts, and containing not less than 12 per cent of milk fat. STATE ' For the purpose of giving a general survey of the various state requirements, available information as to state standards, so far as those exist, is given briefly below. This information is not to be re - garded as free from errors, altho it has been compiled as carefully as possible without actual reference of the statements made to the indi - vidual state authorities for verification. Arkansas, Delaware, and New Mexico appear to have no standards for ice cream. Percentage of milk fat Additional information M\* Variety 10 10 Not over 0.6 per cent of pure vege - 8 table gum or gelatine in any. 2.4 10 Use of eggs, gelatine, and vegetable 10 gum permitted if not used to con- ceal inferiority. 8 Use of eggs, pure gelatine, and 6 vegetable gums permitted. Hirm- leaa . colors and harmless imitation flavors also permitted if declared. 8 Binders by regulation. 8 Bacteria by regulation. 14 Bacteria — 600,000 per c. c. maxi - mum. Gelatine and binder* 0.7 per cent. 8 Use of such other substances as have been customarily used in ice cream permitted, via, eggs, flour. starches, butter, gelatine, flavors, harmless color, nuts, berries, pas - tries, and condensed milk. 1 " Standards of Purity for Food Products," U. S. Department Agriculture Circular 1S6. Office of the Secretary, issued June. 1919. ■ J. T. Keister — Bureau of Chemistry. U. S. Department of Agriculture. Leaflet - July, 1921. with some additions. V.buma alifornia Federal standards unless fixed by legis- lation, which appar- ently has not been done. Plain Fruit and nut Plain Fruit and nut Ice milk Is Vl • 'lumilo Plain Fruit and nut .'unnecticut Plain Fruit and nut Florida Federal standards unless fixed by leg- islation which ap- parently has n o 1 been done. jeorxia Plain Fruit daho llinois Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 Percentage Variety of milkfat Additional information 8 Not leu than 18 per cent of milk All solids and not over 0.75 per cent of gelatine or vegetable gum in any. Pasteurization of all milk product* required. Plan, 12 Not over 1 per cent of harmless 10 thickener. Fruit and nut Acidity not over 0.3 per cent. Product containing foreign fats ■.hall be labeled " imitation ic« cream." The requirement does not apply, however, to nut ice cream or to ice cream flavored with chocolate or cocoa. •J 10 Twenty per cent of milk solids and pasteurisation of all milk product.* used required. Gelatine, vegetable gums, and such other wholesome stabilisers as dairy commissioner may approve permitted. Weight i.t gallon of finished product must rot be leas than l\ pounds Plain 10 Other harmless ingredient* permit Fruit and nut ted if properly labeled. Pasteurisa tion required Plain 10 Use of eggs and 1 per cent har Fruit and nut lesa Alter permitte Federal standards. except that a lim - ited amount of gel - atine, starch, egg. or other harmless sub - stances is permitted. Substandard goods may be sold as imi - tation ice cream. Plain Baa of eggs and T Fruit and nut of gelatine or vegetable gums p« mined. If imitation flavor i- u-. label must so stat SET- All Plain 111 Eggs required. 0.7 per cent of :elatine. gum tragacunth. or other vegetable gums permitted. ltonr acid, formaldehyde, saccharin, cop- Fruit and nut per salts, iron oxide, ochers. or deleterious coloring matters pro - hibited. Aii 12 Impure milk, cual tar colors, sac - charin, or any unwholesome sub - stances prohibited. Mississippi 41 Gelatine, gum tragacanth. or other vegetable gum to the extent of 0.5 per cent permitted. If below stand - ard in fat. product must be labeled " composition ice cream " and mini - mum fat content stated. Pasteuri - zation required. Missouri A, I Fillers and binders permitted but quantity not specified. Certified colon permitted. Substances dele - terious to health prohibited. « Plain 10 Mot over 1 per cent of pure gelatine n any. All shall have not less than 13 per cent of total solids and weigh lot leas than 4 lbs. to the gallon iacteria not over 500.000 per c. c. Gums or binders prohibited. Fruit and nut </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Ice Cream Ingredients 21 N Variety of milkfat Additional information 14 Any substance deleterious or detri - 12 mental to health prohibited. Pa«- &gt;raska Plain Fruit if urization required. N Federal atandard*. except that egg*. -tarch. and gelatine are allowed and product below standard in fat must be labeled Pasteurization required. mi 1 it ion i&lt; N Hitmp-htit Al 14 Use of eggtt and not over 0.2 per cent of fillers or binders permitted. Bacteria — 500.000 per c. c. maxi - mum. Gelatine, gums, or binders per - mitted. &gt; 8 Not more than 1 per cent of gela - tine or wholesome grume. h Cart Plain 8 Use of not over 4 ounces of gelatine » or gum tragacanth to 10 gallons of product permitted. " Compound ice cream " shall contain at least 4 per cent fat. Fruit and nut Plain 12 Gelatine ice cream shall contain not over 3 ounces of pure gelatine in 1 0 gallons . G u m ice c ream shal 1 contain only a small quantity of gum powder and be free from starch or other cereal, harmful in - gredients, and foreign color. Ail 8 Thickeners or stabilizers to the ex - tent of 0.5 per cent permitted. 10 All must contain at least 32.5 per Plain Fruit and nut 8 -ent of solids. All milk and cream mist be pasteurized. 8 None shall contain over 1 per cent 6 of harmless thickener and the acid - ity shall not exceed 0.3 per cent. Homogenized ice cream is that made from fresh whole milk, some un - italted butter, and skimmed milk or other dairy product homogenized and used in place of cream. Pu - tf urization required except milk from tuberculin test cows. Fruit and nut Homogenized Plain 8 Harmless color and not over 0.5 per Fruit and nut 6 cent of pure gelatine, gum traga - canth, or other vegetable gum per - mitted. Prohibited substances are the same as for Michigan. •\;i H Use of 1 per cent harmless vege - table filler or refined gum permitted. Kh Island i.iuth Carolina standards Federal outh Dakota standards All 8 At least 18 per cent of milk solid* required. Substandard goods must be so labeled. All milk products must be pasteurised. VbMHMM Texas Plain 8 Use of not over 0.2 per cent of Fruit and nut I harmless filler permitted in all. Food color permitted. Percentage Federm! </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 22 New York City has an ordinance which requires all ingredients ex Bthe flavors, fruits, and sugars to be pasteurized. Homogenized ucts, if used, must be declared. Ice cream must be kept frozen until tnsed. False statements as to the grade of cream are prohibited, t per cent of milk fat is required in all except fruit, nut, chocolate. and fancy ice creams. The city of New Orleans has an ordinance which calls cent of fat in plain and 8 per cent in fruit and nut ice creams. Thi same ordinance permits the use of 1 per cent "smoother. ' This is tf same or essentially the same as the state requireme State Variety Percentage of milkfat Additional information M Federal standards, unlesit fixed by lag. islation. which ap- parently has not been done. 9T Federal Olatine permitted, standards Washington Wat Virginia Wisconsin All All 8 Im of eggs, gelatine not to exceer 4 ounces to 10 cations, and suet colors as are allowed in food by th» federal regulations permitted. Con- ilensed milk may be used if the product is labeled. 8 Use of gelatine, vegetal. I, ■ itum- and harmless color permitted, in :. I ice crating. Ice milk may contain hurmless color and not over 0.6 per cent of thickener. " Gelatine, gum arable, or other harm- le»» stiffener not to exceed 0.7 ;&gt;er c*«t permitted. Bacteria — SOfl.OOO per c. c. maximum. 12 Gelatine, or gums or binders 0.5 per rent. Overrun — 100 per cent haaarf an weiirht per gallon. Wyoming All </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>