<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Soldiers' and Sailors' Home LOCATED AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENNIUM ENDING, NOVEMBER 30th, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Soldiers' and Sailors' Home LOCATED AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENN1UM ENDING, NOVEMBER 30th, 1906 COL. J. H. PRESSON COMMANDANT </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings of the State of Nebraska: Gentlemen — I have the honor to herewith submit to you the ■ith biennial report of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Mil - ford, Nebraska. tin keeping with the terms of my commission I assumed the mmand of the home March 15, 1905, succeeding Commandant larles Penn, who had conducted the affairs of the institution r four years preceding, who did all he could to acquaint us ith our new duties. I found the buildings greatly in need of repairs. There was no &gt;rotecti&lt;&gt;n from fire, such as is needed in a five-story building. proceeded at once to place a hose on every floor, attached to with standpipe pressure, to be ready at any moment or use. I also found that there was no provision for water in »e new hospital fit for culinary and drinking purposes. I caused y engineer to put in an independent system of pipe, leading rom the house tank (which is always supplied with pure water rom the well) to the hospital so that the best and purest water furnished throughout both buildings. The new hospital had &gt;een constructed at a cost of about $20,000, but it was without cupboard, closet, hook or anything of the kind ; not a place to ut a dish or package of any kind; it had never been used and found many of the sick and feeble men anxious to get into le new quarters. It was completed so far as the contract, was oncerned about the 15th of December, 1904. I found that about le holidays of 1904, a fire had been put in the furnace and the lot water heating plant tested, which proved satisfactory. That &gt;eing the first real cold spell of the season, but, unfortunately, irough the oversight or carelessness of some one, the fire in the urnace was allowed to go out ; the water during the night froze n the radiators, closet bowls, and water pipes, also in one section f the furnace, causing openings in all of these, and rendering &gt;em unfit for use. I reported these facts to the Board of Public jands and Buildings, and they instructed me to make the neces - ary repairs. I sent to New York for a section of the furnace, replaced the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">454 broken m pet ami radiators, put new closet* in the • of the broken ones, cupboard shelves, flour and o chests, m i windows and doon, and window curtains for the entire building; put rubber matting in the halls and stair - h'tted up tl with shelving, drawers, locker. »nd BOTed the j- ato their new quartan about the middle i and comfortable plac i of hospital '1 treatment. The laundry build- I floor and new and thi provided. I The floors of the assembly room, halls and stairs of the main ilding were without covering. 1 secured a cork carpet for the &lt;embl; r halls, and matting for upper hall - airs. I nditions in the working tables for the kitch - . and r the dining room in place of the old sanitary j tted up a new iary room, kalso - iicd the halls and dining room walls, repapered thi room, placed corrugated iron sheathing on the k tor for the keeping of butter d milk, fitted up the old coal room for vegetables, and p in a room adjoining the kr ith a number other minor imj it of the ilditiu' much mor« ble and convenient. Many of the it the building have been papered, painted and the member* who occupy them, and n renovated and repaired under my direction. II hav. • new closets in the building, and a lavatory th t\\ if them. On careful inspection. I found at tin ~ses on the beds were mostly worn out and unfit I. by direction of the Board of Public Lands and lildings, 1 porefcl lity new hair mattresses, made to der and of institutional size, at . • . This I a judic -tiditure for the reason that the '"d th* f their hours in bed. and need restful on which to sleep. 1 have purchased six new doubl. d mattresses complete for men with their wives — members of e home. I found the dam whi , Spring </seg>
            <seg id="p005">455 urposes, had been washed out and was of no good what proceeded to dredge out the creek and rebuild the dam so that is now secure and accomplishes the purpose of such a struc - lre. I have put in 1.600 feet of cement sidewalks, and have lade ilrivcways about the grounds of cinders; laid sod, put out rapevii and ornamental shrubs, cherry and plum 11 run division f&lt; ihe grounds in B rder for the use of the men and women of the home; have ided rustic seats under the various clumps of trees so that the nembers of the home enjoy the shade of the mo - us in the state; added a cement floor to the barn, built a hay led that will shelter hay enough for the nine head of cattle vo horses that we keep: our machinery is in good repair iroperly sheltered for the winter; had our carriage repai Hirchased a new set of carriage harness and paid for the - it of the cash fund of the home; put in a new windmil imping our drinking water, ai LOO— it pumps « to the tank for use of the home and hospital. debris left from the building of the hospital •ed over a large part of the grounds: this has all been cl ay and a beautiful lawn of blue trrass and white elo\. iis place. I The home gTOHBdl - bounded on the en i' Blue river, on the south by Spring creek and on the north a ravine: these are skirted by clumps of beautiful whit' •korv. walnut and asli trees. The buildings are situate ■ highest part of the grounds, about fifty feet above the the river, affording the -sible drainage. As a i ■ sanitary conditions are excellent. There has not been ;i in the home during the time T have been in chi ■n. though old. complain very little of urinary trouble lers incident to their acre. The water i* free from lime and ler dangerous deposits. DISCIPLINE. IThe proper administration of discipline in the home, com; 4 aged men with habits and pr - of years, is diffi- It. Justice must be tempered largely with mercy, no two MS, thousrh the offense may be similar, can be tr actlv ke. It rer|uic m study of human nature, and a kindli- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">456 ness of heart, to succeed so as not to abuse the authority that is placed in the hands of the administrator. I think I have suc - led fairly well in graining and retaining the respect and good will of the members of the home in the application of our rules. NEEDS OF THE HOME. ft the home for the eoming biennium. Id respectfully make the following recommendations: There should be a building sufficient for office room and li\ and sleeping apartments for the officers of the institution. This tin building and make room for twenty i there should be erected adjacent to the main building a number of living rooms to accommodate at least sixty people. A plan and estimated cost of this is hereto atta&gt; II be !)• to properly house those who will be c.ming to us within the next few years. We are receiving ap - •ioiis for membership almost every day, which we cannot for want of room. The plan contemplates that 1 1 be built plain and comfortable, supplied with hot and cold r and electric lights from the home plant. I The following sums should be appropriated for the mainte - ■ &gt;f the home, officers' salaries and wages of employ. Biennium. Emmandant _ $900.00 $1,800.00 500.00 1,000.00 gineer 750.00 1,500.00 Matron loyes^ — ;"•&lt;■ Assistant stewarc t/W.V/V AjWV.W $600.00 . 480.00 $ 1Z 300.00 m.m Laundryman 360.00 moo Laundrywoman 2-40.00 MO.O0 720.00 600.00 l',20OC0 Two assi- Four table waiters 720.00 150.00 TX2 One fireman One assistant (hospital) . 120.00 240.M (_/ijg tc&amp;mstcr 264.00 528.^ 180.00 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">457 MAINTENANCE. tluding food and clothing, beds and bedding, stock, feed and farm, fuel and light, electric sup - plies, drills and medicines, telephone and telegraph, express and postage, burial ex - penses printing and stationery, library $39,150.00 i;il repmin 3,125.00 PLANS AND ESTIMATED COST OF FLATS. The plan contemplates a one-story frame flat, 113 feet Ions: and !feet wide, lathed and plastered, containing eijrht rooms, each x22 feet, 12 feet studding with 9 feet ceiling, two windows and e door in each room, a bathroom in center of flat 12x22 feet otaining bath tub, and two closets. Each room to be furnished th wardrobe, wash howl, hot and cold water, electric lights i m radiator. A porch ten feet wide covered by roof extended from the build- aloag the entire front and one end. The whole to rest on a brick foundation. The estimated cost of said building complete, with door and window - window curtains and floor rugs, '0.00. A report showing amounts appropriated and expended during Ke bienniurn, the amount per capita for the maintenance of e home, and other items of interest, is hereto attached and made a part of this report. DEFICIENCY. In estimating the amount necessary for fuel and lights, my redecessor did not take into account the enlargement of the ilant that was put in for the purpose of furnishing light and leat and hot water for the large building, and an additional &gt;lant for heating the hospital; so that in the item for fuel and lights there will be a deficiency of a few hundred dollars — this n the only deficiency that will be found at the close of the fis - al year. In the management of the home I have endeavored to be eco - nomical without being stingy, believing that the people of the state want this place conducted much after the manner of an average home. We have varied the ration so as to have fruit, vegetables, poultry, etc., in their seasons. The meat, butter and </seg>
            <seg id="p008">458 tilk have been of the best quality obtainable. Our beds are furn - hed with blankets, conif. nd pillc are held every Sunday afternoon, and rit- K'h burial here. tby the local ministers living in lford. without compensation. I would reconiinend that $200.00 appropriated for the purpose of remunerating, to some ex - it, the minister who pi\ as servi. El have purchased ten lots in Blue Valley oemetery, located out one-fourth of a mile from the home, in which to bur ther. I made a requi - ral for he;. tied hefe : they now ;i ]-.- hi-' 1  - 11 be set immediately. In the matter &gt;r this institution 1 ha. that in tin ,t' fuel and liirht. as I have stai.,1 failed in asking fur a sufficient sum to meet th«- The threatened trike alt mate I find that there will 'X) in the various funds, after deducting mentioned: this. too. in the • •t t) ng this biennium. MATE FOR OFFICERS' BI'ILDING AND LAUNDRY ADDITION. (For i( fa building of auffl •■ to afford i r offices, living and sleep for commandant and mily. adjutant, matron and quar 1 ption i mi and i ue not t the sum of $7,000 &lt; I won nniend that our laundry bnilding be It was built when the lionie had but few meml)ers and is now entirely too small for out The en); ,nd the addition of needed ma - chinery will cost in the -1. 500.00. Before closinp. I i r forth my appreciation of the rnor, and Board of Public Lands and Buildinps. and others of the state officers with whom I have had • al. for their manifest willii i do all possible for the comfort and we: the home, and to </seg>
            <seg id="p009">459 Walsh, and other subordinate officers, for their fidelity to duty. and loyal support of the administration, and the general good dud of thi' entire membership of the Ik ctfully submitted. J. II. PRESSOX, Commandant. Nebraska State Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebr., x Col. J. H. Presson, Commandant — Colonel: In compliance with your request. I herewith sub- mit to you the statistical and financial statements for the ttition under your charge for the bieumum ending on Ni&gt;&gt; For myself, and in behalf of your other employes, I than! heartily for the courtesy and amity unstintintrly shown us, which hi red the performance of the duties of our re- ive positions a pleasure. led statements will be found in your semi-annual r&gt; to the governor during the biennium, showing the expendii of the various funds, tl per capita of maintenance, and ..ther special mat X. R. PEBSINGER, Adjutant. Condi atistical statement of the Soldiers' and Sailors' .iska State Home, for tin- biennium endii POPULATION. Male. Female. T of members Dee. 1. 1904 (Biennium) 115 3 118 Xo. received during the biennium 122 11 lischarged or died during the biennium 2 68 nil of biennium 171 V2 Dail lance during biennium 110 7 117 Average number of officers and employes ... 16 3 IS EXPENDITURES. Current expei Salaries and wages $11,9 2. Clothing 3. Subsistence 17:. 4. Office, domestic and outdoor expenses . *44.r </seg>
            <seg id="p010">rtraordinary expenses — New buildings $ 4,038.27 Permanent improvements 1,301.76 Repairs 2,109.61 Total $ 7,449.64 Grand total $51,567.67 Executive head — Col. J. H. Presson, Commandant. Made in accordance with request of National Conference of Charities and Corrections. unties in the state of Nebraska from which members have n admitted to the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Milford, ■raska. Now members. Since organization. Counties. Men. Women. Men. Women. 1 6 Antelope 11 11 Banner 2 n _1 1 ie 1 Box Butte . 1 tox Butte Buffalo _ 1 iuffal. Burt .... 4 5 turt Butler _ 4 13 tutler C- - 3 ry 1 1 Clay _ 1 1 Xv Cumin tr 2 uminp •t 2 2 Daw 1 Dawson Dawson 2 Do&lt;L DodL- ._ 3 ia&gt; 25 1 57 2 Furnas _ 2 Fillmore __ 1 Franklin Franklin 1 tier Frontier 2 Gag. . 3 9 m 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">461 Hamilton 1 Harlan 1 1 Howard 1 Jefferson 2 Johnson 4 5 Kearney 11 11 Knox 1 1 Lancaster 67 4 144 6 Madison 1 Xemaha - 6 Nuckolls 1 1 Otoe 3 1 Pawnee 1 Phelps 1 2 Platte 1 2 i a L" 4 ird 22 4 35 4 Sheridan 1 uton 1 Thayer 2 2 Thomas 1 Valley 1 Washington 2 Webster ."&gt; 8 York 4 1 12 1 After compiling this list one man has died, one been admitted tm Douglas, one from Lancaster, and one from York counties, king present enrollment 172 men and 12 women. And since organization, 392 men and 19 women. AVERAGE AGE OF MEMBERS OF THE HOME ON NOVEMBER 30TH. 1906. Men — Enrolled 172 Average _68 years Women — Enrolled 12 Average .66 years The oldest member is R. R. Pitney, 89 years old. The youngest member is S. Burgess, 34 years old. Spanish war. The youngest man of the war of 1861 is 58 years old. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">462 Averages at which members have died in the home during this biennium : A*, Men. Women. Men. Women. f&gt;s 1 11 3 61 11 T-\ 3 1 7r. 3 •1 66 1 79 1 1 1 1 94 1 71 77 o Months in the biennium in which members have died Month. Men. Women. Month. Men. Women. January . 1 July 1 1 August 1 1 1 5 September .") 1 her June November 2 1 December L" SURGEON'S REPORT. To the Honorable Commandant at the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Milford, Nebraska, Col. J. H. Presson. IDear Sir — As required by the laws of Nebraska, governing we will hereby submit our biennial report, rela - e to the department in which we are directly connected as ysicians and surgeons, covering the time from the last re - rt — Dec. 1st, 1904 — up to the present time, November 30th, 06. t During the interval above mentioned, we, or one of us, have en in daily attendance, remedying such ailments as was in our wer; ameliorating and soothing such as we could not benefit iterially. Our intercourse with both officers and inmates have en of the happiest nature, engendered by a feeling that we M all doing the best under the circumstances and conditions, d reciprocating each other's assistance and good counsel. About the usual amount of medicines have been prescribed, with varied results. Our sanitary conditions remain in about </seg>
            <seg id="p013">463 as good condition as is possible, leaving little to be desired in that line. Our hospital (which has been completed and oc- cupied since our last report), is in excellent condition, and ren- ders untold comfort to a great many aged, and all of the sick. It is ably presided over by our worthy stewards both of whom are tireless in their efforts I the the inm There has been very liti! ry, and that of a minor type, all of which were s il. There are no acute diseases at (•resent, but a number of chronics, such as we always ha\ institutions of this nature. Our hospital is full all of the time, but we manage, by chanprintr. to ?et along nicely. We hav. been visited by epidemics in the last two years. It has beei; misfortune to be compelled to send some of our men to the asylum — one as an alcoholic incorrigible. The following d&gt; have occurred in the home during this biennium : Age. Died. Burnett. James K. 71 Dee. 1. 1IMI4 heart failure Cox, Joseph 94 I ).■,•. 22, 1904 old age Cameron, Peter 75 Jan. it. 1905 para! Cornibe, Felix 79 Apr. 2, 1905 pan Brown. Oscar 77 Apr. 11. 1905 old ;i Knight*, Hinkley G. .78 Apr. I'd. 1905 dial Austin, George M _69 May 14, 1905 «lr McBrien, William til June 1. 11)05 brain para Riddle, Sarah .61 kng. 4, 190.") ... gall stone McClure, James P. 11 Aug. 11, 1905 spinal schl. • borough, Alex. .71 Sep. fi. 190.". dropsy, heart tr. Kiddie, James W. 7:! Sept. 13, 1905 dr Sherman. James D. 70 Oct. 2, 1905 par;: Bell. William II ". Oct. 21, 1905 rheumathid arthetis Hughes, George W. 78 Feb. 25, 1906 consuni] Kent. Charles Kent. Charles 7."&gt; Apr. 14. 1906 Willcox, Clark 72 Apr. 24. 1906 part 72 Apr. 24. 1906 par Smith. William P 66 Jun. 27. 1906 dropsy Hughes. Thoina^ - Jun. 8, 1906 heart failure (lark. Almeron P 65 July 16. 1906 dropsy Reid, John A. .»p. 3, 1906 paralysis Dunn. David I). top. 9. l!i&lt;Hi Bright's disease Martin. Daniel 77 Sep. 26, 1906 old age </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Lendowski, Michael J. 73 ..Oct. 11 1906 accidentally killed Brininger, Mary J. .58 Nov. 6 catarrh-stomach Johnson, James W. .62 Nov. 14, 1906 apoplexy ihers, John L 81 ..Nov. 16, 1906 . old age Bayles, Stephen 80 Nov. 28, 1906 .. old age &amp; injury Of these, H. G. Knights died at his own home in Milford, Neb. George M. Austin died at the home of his sister near Tekamah, Neb., while on furlough, and Capt. Thomas Hughes died at Detroit, Michigan, at the home of his daughter, while on fur- lough. I hear no complaint against executives, or conditions, except tch as you would expect of any organization of the kind. Your thority and commands are quietly obeyed, and respect en- gendered. We now conclude our report by wishing this great common- wealth of ours, prosperity ; hoping the state of Nebraska may continue to be under the supervision of as efficient officers in the future, as it has been in the past biennium. Respectfully, DBS. BRANDON AND WERTMAN, By Geo. W. Brandon, M. D. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>