<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seventh Biennial Report OF THE Asylum for the Chronic Insane AT HASTINGS, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR For The Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1902.</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Seventh Biennial Report -OF THE- Asylum ior tie Chronic Insane AT HASTINGS, NEBRASKA -TO THE- GOVERNOR For The Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1902. Thi Frimomt Tribune Fbmoxt, Nib. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">185 REPORT. To His Excellency, Ezra P. Savage, Governor of Nebraska. Dkar Sir: — I have the honor of submitting to you the follow - ing, it being the Seventh Biennial Report of this hospital, end - ing Nov. 30, 1902 : I assumed charge of the institution as Superintendent Feb. 1, 1901, having been appointed by his Excellency, Charles H. Dietrich, Governor of Nebraska, to succeed Dr. J. T. Steele. tMr. H. C. Haverly, of Hastings, was appointed Steward to :ceed James B. Barnes, and also entered upon the duties of 1 office Feb. 1, 1901. Dr. W. L. Carlyle was appointed First Assistant Physician to succeed Dr. D. S. Woodard of Aurora, whose term of office expired May 15, 1901. tDr. Hallie L. Ewing was reappointed Second Assistant Phy - ian Feb. 25, 1901, and on May 15, 1901, resigned to accept a ailar position in the Asylum for the Insane at Norristown, Pa. I Dr. A. J. Chapman was appointed as Dr. Ewing's successor, ad assumed the duties of the Second Assistant Physician May 5, i9°i- At the beginning of the Biennial period there were present seven hundred thirteen (713) patients, of which four hundred xteen (416) were males, and two hundred ninety-seven (297) emales. There were admitted during the two years, three lundred four (304) males, sixty-one (61) females. Total, hree hundred sixty-five (365). Died, one hundred thirty-five 135). Discharged, twenty-three (23). Of those discharged, ourteen (14) were dismissed as cured, nine (9) improved, eaving at the end of the Biennial period six hundred fourteen 614) males, three hundred four (304) females. Total, nine undred eighteen (918.) The general health of the inmates has been very good, and, considering the class of patients admitted here, the death rate </seg>
            <seg id="p004">186 las been remarkably small. The number of inmates has been much larger during the present Biennium than ever before, the nstitution for the past fifteen (15) months having been filled to its utmost capacity. The annex recently opened, and which accom - modates two hundred forty (240) male patients, has greatly elieved the congested condition of our male waids. A sick ward has been provided in both male and female departments which are well equipped, and will bear close inspection. I A large number of inmates are employed at light work in the irious departments, as laundry, sewing room, kitchens, bakery ning rooms, shops, garden, farm, yards, engine and boiler rooms he number of patients thus employed ranges from one hundrec ty (150) to two hundred (200). It is a conclusive fact tha nployment is decidedly beneficial to this class of patients, the bor thus secured is of much assistance to the Institution, and a reat saving to the state. We have now in operation a large sewing-room in which ten o more female patients are regularly employed, and in which are manufactured all garments, towels, bedding, etc., besides a large mount of general sewing and repairing for the male wards an&lt; ther departments of the hospital. We operate a large laundry where thirty-five thousand (35,000) pieces are laundered eacl week, requiring twelve hundred (1,200) pounds of soap that we manufacture at a very small cost. An addition, thirty-two (32 eet by thirty-eight (38) feet, has been added to our laundry build ng, the old laundry machinery has been largely replaced by new nd this department otherwise greatly improved. A large carpen er shop is maintained, in which is regularly employed one car &gt;enter and one patient, where numerous articles of furniture are manufactured in addition to a large amount of repair work alway ecessary in an institution of this kind. The unusually large mount of repairs and improvements carried on during the pas ighteen (18) months has made it necessary to employ two car &gt;enters most of the time. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. Much general improvement has been made. At the beginning </seg>
            <seg id="p005">187 of the present bienniutn the institution was found to be practically without fire protection. Steps were immediately taken to rem - edy this defect. A large well with an air-lift pump was put in, also a reservoir with a capacity of one hundred thirty-five thous - and (135,000) gallons, two direct pressure pumps, eighteen hun - dred (1,800) feet of six and four-inch water mains were laid, the required number of hydrants located, additional fire-hose pur - chased and other necessary equipments provided, which prob - ably makes the protection against fire at this Hospital the best of any of the state institutions. The electric wiring throughout the institution was found to be in very bad condition. In many places the wires were exposed, the nsulation having been destroyed, leaving the wire resting on lath or other wooden support. This dangerous condition demandec mmediate attention, as result of which the institution was rewired throughout, including the cottage, laundry, storerooms &gt;arn and other outbuildings, so that at the present time the insti ution in this direction is in first-class condition. New brick walks have been laid about the institution where most needed. Two first-class mechanics have been employed constantly for the past eighteen months in repairing, painting, and otherwise improving the wards, dining rooms, and the interior of he entire building, and at the present time they are all in excel - ent order. Numerous other improvements have been made. A new and commodious drug room has been opened, a pair of railroad-track scales put in, the lawn much enlarged and improved, drive-ways graded and otherwise improved, new sheds and fences have been put in about the stock yards, and a great many other much needed but smaller improvements have also been carried on. Twenty-five milch cows have beeen added to our dairy, yet the number is entirely too small for the needs of the hospital. The institution is constantly supplied with first-class meats furn - nished from the best beef cattle and hogs fed in our own yards and slaughtered at the institution. The present provision for amusements is entirely inadequate. The chapel and amusement hall was by no means large enough </seg>
            <seg id="p006">188 before the opening of the new annex, and an appropriation of six - teen thousand five hundred dollars ($16,500) is asked for the enlargement of our present kitchen building, and the providing of an amusement hall large enough to meet present demands. The regular Thursday evening dances, which are greatly enjoyed by the patients, have been in progress, and the wards supplied with games of various kinds for patients who are inclined to participate in such amusements. The institution has reached such a size that the services of a third assistant physician is necessary, and an appropriation for the payment of his salary is asked. The present number of boilers is by no means sufficient to meet the required demands. To remedy this, an appropriation of thirty-five hundred dollars ($3,500.00) is asked to purchase and install a new two hundred fifty (250) horse-power Marine boiler. The dynamo in use in the institution at this time is entirely too small, besides having been in use for the past twelve years, and an appropriation is also asked for a new dynamo. The present barn and cattle sheds are by no means sufficient, and an appropriation of fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000.00) is asked with which to build and equip a large and commodious brick harn. The green house is much smaller than an institution of this size demands, and should be replaced by a new one. The roofs on several of the present hospital buildings are in very bad condition, and an appropriation for general repairs and improvements is asked to repair the same. The state owns a half section of land in connection with this hospital, twenty acres of which are occupied by the buildings, lawns, grounds and drive-ways about the institution, the Mis - souri Pacific and Burlington Railways each have a right-of-way through the farm, also the sewer from the institution empties on the state farm and occupies quite a number of acres, leaving for garden and farm purposes only about two hundred (200) acres, which is by no means sufficient. For several years past the institution has been renting seventy (70) acres of pasture land near the hospital for which cash rent has been </seg>
            <seg id="p007">paid. With the large amount of inmate help we have, an additional section of land could be very nicely and profitably managed, and 1 trust an appropriation will be made for the purchase of at least three hundred twenty (320) acres addi - tional land. The per capita cost for the Biennium is as follow Daily average cost per capita, 39c. The general expendi- Kt during the Biennium just closed were considerably :ased by the payment of several extraordinary expenses, instance, there remained Feb. 1, 1901, (when the manage - t of the institution changed) twenty-six thousand nine hun- I eighty-eight dollars eighty-nine cents ($26,988.89) of unpaid as. The first month of the biennium (December, 1900) ity-four thousand six hundred forty-one dollars nine cents 1,641. 09) of the Board and Clothing Fund was expended, the month following, nine thousand five hundred eighty-six dollars fifty-eight cents ($9,586.58) of the same fund. No instance of such unusually large monthly purchases has ever occurred during the history of this hospital as in the two months just referred to. New pumps, a large well, reservoir, water mains and other means of protection against fire have been installed at an expense of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000.00 j. The new wing recently opened has been partly furnished at an expense of fifty-five hundred dollars ($5,500.00), and new steam pumps and laundry machinery installed at an expense of twenty-five hundred dollars ($2,500.00). Having no fund for repairs and improvements, all these unusual expenses have been paid out of our Board and Clothing Fund, and this has very materially increased the general per capita cost. In addition to this, the garden and farm products for 190 1 were very light, owing to a partial crop failure, which made it neces- irst semi-annual period $ 82.45 ■econd semi-annual period 58.84 'hird semi-annual period 68 66 'ourth semi-annual period 75.8 1 Total $285.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">190 sary to purchase a large amount of potatoes and other vegeta- bles, which are usually raised at the institution. Request for general maintenance is made on a basis of 37c per day per capita for ten hundred fifty (1,050) patients, which will be the number of inmates here when all the beds in the institution are occupied. Following is a list of the appropri- ations asked for the biennial period ending March 31, 1905: Salary for superintendent $ 5,000.00 Salary for first assistant physician 3,000.00 Salary for second assistant physician 2,400.00 Salary for third assistant physician j-i 2,000.00 Salary for steward 3,600.00 Employes' wages 60,720.00 Board, clothing, fuel, lights and all necessary expenses not otherwise provided for 268,275.00 Repairs and improvements 10,000.00 Postage, telephone and telegraph 2,500.00 Painting and re-roofing buildings and improving grounds 1 5,500.00 Enlarging present kitchen building and providing a chapel and amusement hall 16,500.00 One dynamo 3,500.00 For the return of patients 800.00 Three hundred twenty acres land 15,000.00 To the employes and officers with whom I have been associ- ated during the biennial period just closed, I desire to acknowl- edge my earnest appreciation of your kind and courteous treat- ment and the fidelity and zeal with which your duties have been performed. Nothing is more essential to the successful man- agement of an institution than faithful employes and officers who are in perfect accord with each other, and this condition has certainly prevailed. To you, gentlemen of the Board of Public Lands and Build- ings, I desire to extend my most sincere thanks for your unfailing support and hearty cooperation. It has been my earnest desire to faithfully, honestly and economically administer the affairs of this institution, and whatever success has attended my efforts, to </seg>
            <seg id="p009">you is due much of the credit. I fully appreciate the confidence you have reposed in me as superintendent of this asylum, and am under lasting obligations for your kind assistance and con - tinued efforts in promoting and extending the welfare of the hospital and thereby adding to the happiness and comfort of the unfortunate inmates, and improving the business interests of the institution. Bs my pleasure to acknowledge my sincere obligation to excellency, for your courteous treatment and advice, and ise counsel so generously given. Respectfully, W. B. Kbrn, M. D., Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">STEWA _RD'S REPORT. 'or Biennial Perioi d Ending November 30, 1902. as « o£h n § &lt; 1 1 I 5 0 loard and clothing. . 'elephone and tele- graph.... Imployes wages.... luperin- tendent's salary . . . 'irst Ass't Physicia's salary iecond Ass't Phy- sician's salary $48,987.24 183.49 9,144.49 1,000.00 $145,000.00 49,000.00 5,000.00 1193,987.24 183.49 68,144.49 6,000.00 $161,169.32 71.56 48,621.00 $2,123.60 $30,694.32 111.93 730.11 8,793.38 4, 750.00| 1,250.00 750.00 3,000.00 3,750.00 3,000.00 750.00 900.00 2,400.00 3,300.00 2,600.001 300.001 400 - 00 [$60,965.22 $204,400.001 l$265,365.22l l$220,211.88i $3, 265. 64'$41, 887.71 Value of stock, machinery, furniture and supplies on hand December i, 1902. Live stock on farm $ 7,550.00 Products of the farm on hand 2,934.00 Machinery, tools and supplies 25,250.00 Beds, furniture and clothing in inmate's departments. 31,235.00 Drugs, Drug-room fixtures and supplies 1,525.00 Fuel in bins 250.00 Library 500.00 Supplies in store-room 4,150.00 riningroom furniture and fixtures in patients depart - ments 3,050.00 rersonal property of State in Administration and cot - tage buildings ". 12,495.00 Total $88,939.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">v- HRONIC iNSANR ASYLUM^ n A STINGS* CASH FUND. Receipts Disbursements. 19 &gt;o. 1900. Dec. 1, balance . . . .$1,147.73 Dec. 31, for Dec . . $ 349.05 Dec. 31, for Dec. . . . 89.06 1901. Jan. 31, for Jan. . . . 73-8o Feb. 28, for Feb... 27.94 Feb. 28, for Feb . . . 399.01 Mch.J 31, for Mch . . 189.98 Mch. 31, for Mch... 500.51 April 30, for April . 14326 April 30, for April. . 18 &gt;.oi May 31, for May . . 159.86 May 31, for May .. 55-2O June 30, for June .. 254.19 June 30, for June .. 925.20 July 31, for July ... 172.59 July 31, for July. .. 191.64 Aug. 3r, for Aug.. 274.94 Sept. 30, for Sept .. 85.27 Aug. 31, for Aug. . 22.72 22.72 Sept. 30, for Sept . . 66.91 Oct. 31, for Oct. . . 195 .33 Oct. 31, for Oct... 81.85 Nov. 30, for Nov . . 162.88 Nov. 30, for Nov.. 77.90 Dec. 31, for Dec... 334-39 Dec. 31, for Dec . . 5.40 1902. Jan. 31, for Jan . .. 67.31 19 &gt;2. Jan. 31, for Jan. .. 148.61 Feb. 28, for Feb. .. 56.13 Feb. 28, for Feb... 58516 Mch. 31, for March. 101.26 Mch. 31, for Mch... 327.24 April 30, for April. . 139.47 April 30, for April. . 243.05 May 31, for May .. 347.61 May 31, for May . . 43 10 June 30, for June .. 276.04 June 3o,forjune.. 76.81 July 31, for July ... 165.54 July 31, for July Aug. 31, for Aug Sept. 30, for Sept 1. 362.1 1 Aug. 31, for Aug .. 484.64 Sept. 30, for Sept . . 243.28 57-9 1 Oct. 31, for Oct. .. 25.96 147.46 Oct. 31, for Oct... 2.00 Nov. 30, for Nov .. 1,057.23 Nov. 30, for Nov.. 73 7o Nov. 30, balance... 788.37 H. C. Havkrly, Steward. 1901. J an - 3!»^orjan ... 778.57 $6,884.09 1 $6,884.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">194 GARDEN REPORT. Vegetables used in 1901. Asparagus, doz. bunches 25 Vegetables used in 1902. Beans, bu 98 Beans, bu 2 Beets, bu 450 Beets, bu 88 Cucumbers, doz 1 30 Cauliflower, doz 20 Cucumbers, doz 32 Cabbage, heads 10,332 Cabbage, heads 18,000 Carrots, bu 70 Carrots, bu 700 Lettuce, doz. bunches.. 353 Lettuce, doz. heads. . . . 1,000 1 Lima beans, bu 9 Onions, doz. bunches ... 2,555 Muskmelon 564 Onions, bu 400 Onions, doz. bunches ... 941 Potatoes, bu 4,109 Onions, bu 40 Peas, bu 90 Potatoes, bu 450 Parsnips, bu 340 Peas, bu 33 Radishes, doz. bunches . 3,630 Parsnips, bu 75 Sweet corn, doz. ears . . 2,368 Salsify, bu 14 Plums, bu 5 Peaches, bu Spinach, bu 184 17 Radishes, doz. bunches. 1,144 Sweet potatoes, bu . . . . 100 Sweet corn, doz. ears . . 96 Turnips, bu 695 Salsify, bu 6 Spinach, bu 205 Sweet potatoes, bu . . . . 59 Turnips, bu 49 Tomatoes, bu 16 Watermelon 3»3 12 PRESERVES, JELLIES AND PICKLES Put up During Years of 1901 and 1902. Cherries, (canned) 30 quarts Grapes, (canned) 8 quarts Peaches 115 quarts Plum butter 18 quarts Plum jelly 9 doz. glasses Tomato pickles 248 quarts Watermelon pickles 26 quarts </seg>
            <seg id="p013">195 MATRON'S REPORT. Garments Made and Repaired in Sewing Room, from Dec. 1, 1900, to Nov. 30, 1902 (Inclusive). Aprons, bakery 36 Aprons, special 4 Aprons, bleached muslin 703 Aprons, unbleached muslin 239 Aprons, bib 66 Aprons, gingham 84 Aprons, ticking 161 Aprons, barber I7 1 Aprons, kitchen 178 Aprons, canton flannel 6 Aprons, calico 20 Bread covers 12 Bed ticks 219 Bibs, feeding 18 Blankets 6 Billiard table covers 2 Bed shams 2 Chemises, unbleached muslin 619 Chemises, bleached muslin 55 Chemises, special 4 Comforts 18 Curtains, cheesecloth 34^ Curtains, calico 18 Curtains, India linen 1 Curtains, silkoline 7 Curtains, creton ■ 3 Curtains, Swiss muslin 3 Curtains, radiator 4 Curtains, transom 20 Curtains, lace 6 Curtains special 3 Clothes bags 75 Camisoles 13 1 Curtain bands 154 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">196 " Coats 12 Cushions 4 Dresses, calico 800 Dresses, gingham 2 Dresses, special 56 Dresses, denim 15 Dresser scarfs 52 Drawers, unbleached muslin 151 Drawers, bleached muslin 46 Drawers, canton flannel 262 Drawers, special 14 Iron holders 264 Jackets, quilted 1 Kitchen holders 20 Laundry bags 26 Mattress covers 701 Mattress pads 4 Mail sacks 2 Mittens, duck, pairs 7 Mending ba^s 197 Meat covers 3 Napkins, linen 617 Night shirts, unb. muslin 76 Pillow ticks 86 Pillow cases 283 Pillow cases, unbleached 2,076 Pantaloons, denim 2 Pantaloons, quilted 1 Sheets, bleached muslin 216 Sheets, unbleached muslin 2,867 Sheets, single 22 Shirts, calico 2 Skirts, bleached muslin 50 Skirts, unbleached muslin 24 Skirts, Canton flannel 283 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">197 Skirts, special 39 Shrouds, bleached muslin 51 Suspenders, ticking, pairs 279 Splashers 3 Shades 931 Sunbonnets, gingham 190 Rug« 9 Table-cloths 332 Table-covers 114 Tags, duck 300 Ties, India linen 707 Towels, bath 625 Towels, roller 1,251 Towels, hand 489 Towels, tea 260 Underskirts, special 2 Undersuits, special 26 Waists, Canton flannel 524 Waists, special 13 MONTHLY ADMISSION OF PATIENTS. During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Months. Males. Females. Totals. December, 1900 9 9 18 February, 1901 1 1 June, 1911 1 1 July, 1901 1 1 August, 1901 16 1 17 September, 1901 68 15 83 December, 1901 41 12 53 April, 1902 12 1 13 May, 1902 1 I June, 1902 1 1 July, 1902 &gt; . . 12 1 13 October, 1902 1 1 2 November, 1902 143 18 161 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">198 RESIDENCE OF PATIENTS BY COUNTIES. Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Counties. Males. Females. Totals. Adams 5 5 io Boone 4 i 5 BoxButte 5 ° 5 Boyd 2 o 2 Brown o 2 Buffalo i 3 4 Burt 4 i 5 Butler 6 o 6 Cass 5 3 5 Cedar 4 2 6 Chase i o i Cherry 2 i 3 Cheyenne i o i Clay 3 ° 3 Colfax 7 i 8 o 8 4 *3 o 4 2 6 i 5 o i O 2 2 13 7 39 Fillmore 5 o 5 Franklin 2 1 3 Frontier 2 o 2 Furnas 1 1 2 Gage ' 6 1 7 Gosper 2 o 2 Greeley 5 J 6 Hall 5 1 6 Hamilton 2 o 2 uming uster 9 &gt;akota 4 &gt;awes 4 lawson 4 •euel i •ixon 2 &gt;odg- •ouglas II 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">199 Harlan 3 o 3 Hayes o 1 1 Hitchcock 1 o 1 Holt 10 6 16 Howard 1 1 2 Jefferson 1 o 1 Johnson 2 o 2 Kearney 3 ° 3 Keith 1 1 2 Keya Paha 2 o 2 Knox 4 o 4 Lancaster 8 4 12 Lincoln 5 * 6 Logan 1 o 1 Madison " o 11 Merrick O 1 1 Nance 202 Nemaha 5 * 6 Nuckolls 1 o 1 Otoe 5 ° 5 Pawnee 4 ° 4 o 1 o 3 o 2 o 16 o 4 Richardson 4 ° 4 Rock 2 o 2 Saline 4 2 6 Sarpy 1 o 1 Saunders 3 ° 3 Scott's Bluff 2 1 3 Seward 1 1 2 Sheridan 3 ° 3 Stanton 4 ° 4 Sherman o 2 2 Thayer 2 o 2 erkins helps 'ierce 2 latte ii Led Willow 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Thomas 2 o 2 Thurston i o i Valley 2 I 3 Washington 4 1 5 Wayne 4 o 4 Webster 2 0 2 York 1 o 1 Penitentiary 3 o 3 Unknown 6 2 8 Totals 304 61 365 NATIVITY OF PATIENTS. Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. United States. Males. Females. Totals. 1 1 1 1 4 2 7 5 26 1 4 2 12 o 3 Maryland • I O I Massachusetts 1 o 1 Nebraska 29 2 31 New Jersey 1 1 o I New York 14 2 16 O hi ° 15 3 18 t Pennsylvania 6 5 11 Tennessee o 1 1 Virginia 5 o 5 Vermont 1 o 1 West Virginia 4 o 4 Wisconsin 5 4 9 Foreign Countries. Austria 2 1 3 Connecticut o Delaware o 23 llinois 21 ndiana 3 VI issouri 10 Michigan 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Canada 3 o 3 China 1 o 1 Denmark 9 1 10 England 5 o 5 France 1 o 1 Germany 49 4 53 Ireland 10 5 15 Moravia o 1 1 Norway 5 o 5 Prussia 2 o 2 Poland 1 2 3 Russia 1 o 1 Sweden 21 4 25 Switzerland 2 o 2 Scotland o 1 1 Wales 2 o 2 Unknown 36 9 45 Total 304 61 365 OCCUPATION OF PATIENTS Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902 Occupation. Males. Females. Totals. Accountant 4 o 4 Baker 1 o 1 Blacksmith 2 o 2 Brick mason 2 o a Broom maker ... 2 o 2 Barber 1 o 1 Butcher 2 o 2 Carpenter 3 o 3 Coal miner 2 o 2 Cowboy 2 o 2 Cook 2 o 2 Cigarmaker 1 o 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">202 Druggist i o i Dentist I o i Domestic o u n Farmer 128 o 128 Fireman in smelter 1 o 1 Gardner 2 o 2 Grain merchant 1 o Horse trader 1 o I Housewife o 36 36 Jeweler 1 o 1 Laborer 78 o 78 Locomotive fireman 2 o 2 Lawyer 1 o 1 Merchant 2 o 2 Messenger boy 1 o 1 Miller 1 o 1 Musician 1 o 1 Mechanic 2 o 2 Painter 3 o 3 Peddler 1 o 1 Postal clerk 1 o 1 Prostitute o 1 1 Rai road engineer 1 o 1 Railroad conductor 1 O I Reporter 1 o 1 Sailor 2 o 2 Shoemaker 2 o 2 Saloon keeper 2 o 2 Stenographer 1 o 1 School teacher o 2 2 Seamstress o 2 2 Tailor 2 o 2 Tinner 1 o I Tramps 3 o 3 Teamster 1 o 1 Well digger 1 o 1 Wash man 1 o 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">203 Unknown 9 2 11 None 18 7 25 Totals 304 61 365 CIVIL CONDITION OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial, Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Single 197 21 218 Married 67 32 99 Widowed o 7 7 Widower 17 o 17 Unknown 17 1 18 Divorced 6 o 6 Totals 304 61 365 HEREDITARY TENDENCIES OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial. Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Total?. Brother Insane 13 3 16 t Brother and mother insane 1 1 2 Brother insane, mother epileptic 1 o 1 Brother and two sons insane 1 o 1 Brother and sister insane 1 o 1 Brother and cousin insane 2 o 2 Brother imbecile o 1 1 Aunt and uncle insane, father epileptic 1 o 1 Aunt and uncle insane 1 o 1 Aunt insane 3 1 4 Aunt had epilepsy 1 o 1 Aunt imbecile 1 o 1 Cousin insane 2 2 4 Father insane 4 o 4 Father has syphilis 1 o 1 Father nervous 3 o 3 Father had epilepsy 1 o 1 Father suicided 3 o 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">204 Father killed mother and suicided i o i Father drunkard o 2 2 Family tuberculosis o i i Grandfather insane 5 o 5 Grandmother insane 1 o 1 Grandmother had epilepsy 1 o 1 Granduncle insane 2 o 2 Grandmother insane, mother nervous, sis- ter paralyzed o 1 1 Mother insane 8 1 9 Mother nervous 4 1 5 Mother and two uncles insane o 1 1 Sister insane 8 1 9 Sister imbecile 2 o 2 Sister nervous o 1 1 Two cousins insane 1 o 1 Two brothers insane 1 o 1 Two brothers and three sisters insane . . . 1 o 1 Uncle insane 8 1 9 Unknown o 38 38 None o 4 4 Total 304 61 365 ALLEGED CAUSE OF INSANITY OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Alcoholism 19 o 19 Chorea o 1 1 Domestic trouble 3 1 4 2 Disappointment in love 6 1 7 Debility 2 o 2 Degeneracy 2 o 2 Disease of childhood 1 o 1 Despondency o 1 1 Childbirth o 3 3 Epilepsy 23 8 31 Financial trouble 12 1 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">205 Feebleminded o i i Grief 4 1 5 Heredity 67 12 79 Head injury 17 2 19 Ill health o 3 3 ? Masturbation ' 22 o 22 Morphine habil o 1 1 Menstrual trouble o 4 4 Meningitis o 1 1 Miscarriage o 1 1 Nostalgia 1 o 1 Over work 4 2 6 Opium smoking 1 o 1 Over study 1 o 1 Paralysis 2 o Prostitution o 1 1 Poverty o 3 3 1 1 Religious excitement 5 2 7 Rheumatism 1 o 1 Sun stroke 14 o 14 Syphilis 6 o 6 Solitude 2 o 1 Spiritualism 1 o 1 Shock 1 o 1 Senility o 1 1 Typhoid fevei 4 o 4 Unknown 82 11 93 Total 304 61 356 RELIGION OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males Females. Totals. Catholic 39 15 54 Protestant 145 28 173 None 57 5 62 Unknown 63 13 76 Total 304 61 365 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">206 CAUSE OF DEATH OF PATIENTS Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Aortic stenosis o 2 2 Acute nephritis i 2 3 Biliary obstruction o 1 1 Cerebral hemorrhage 5 4 9 Cardiac dropsy 2 o 2 2 Dysentery 5 6 11 Dementia, chronic 4 5 9 Diabetes mellitus 1 o 1 Diarrhoeic 2 o 2 Epilepsy 12 4 16 Gastritis 1 2 3 Hystero-mania I o I Idiopathic anaemia 2 o 2 Intestinal obstruction 2 2 4 Locomotor ataxia 2 o 2 Mania, chronic 13 3 16 Melancholia 1 o 1 Osteo-sarcoma 2 o 2 Peritonitis o 2 . 2 Paresis 15 2 17 Pneumonia 2 4 6 Posterior spinal sclerosis 1 1 2 Pulmonary oedeme 1 o 1 Uterine cancer o 1 1 Senile dementia 1 2 3 Septicaemia 1 o 1 Tuberculosis 8 4 12 Typhoid fever 2 1 3 Total 87 48 135 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">207 FORMS OF DISEASE OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Chronic mania 134 40 174 Chronic melancholia 9 7 16 Cerebral softening 1 o 1 Delusional insanity 33 1 34 Dementia o 1 1 Epileptic insanity 33 8 41 Emotional insanity 3 2 5 Epilepsy 3 o 3 Hystero-mania 1 o 1 Imbecility 1 1 2 Paresis 17 o 17 Paranoea 5 o 5 Recurrent mania 1 o 1 Secondary dementia 53 o 53 Senile dementia 10 1 11 Total 304 61 365 EDUCATION OF PATIENTS, Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Good 28 8 36 87 21 7 75 18 146 7 21 61 365 AGE OF PATIENTS WHEN ADJUDGED INSANE, Admitted During Biennial Period Ending Nov. 30, 1902. Males. Females. Totals. Between year* of 15 to 25 57 13 70 Between years of 25 to 35 79 10 89 Between years of 35 to 45 66 15 81 . ommon school 66 iair 68 »oor 128 «fone J 4 Total 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">208 Between years of 45 to 55 37 10 47 Between years of 55 to 65 16 1 17 Between years of 65 to 75 9 5 14 Between years of 75 to 85 3 1 4 Unknown 37 6 43 Total 304 61 365 Average age of patients when adjudged insane: Males, 38; females, 28. Total average, 33. Total number of inmates in the institution November 30, 1902: Males, six hundred fourteen (614); females, three hundred four (304). Total, nine hundred eighteen (918). Number of patients present December 1, 1900 713 Number of patients received since .... 365 Number of patients returned from furlough 25 390 1 103 Number of patients discharged 23 Number of patients died 135 Number of patients escaped 3 Number of patients released on furlough 27 188 Number of patients present Dec. 1, 1902 915 Number of patients present on furlough 3 Number of patients on books Dec. 1, 1902 918 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>