<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Home For The Friendless AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA For the Biennial Term Ending November 30, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Home For The Friendless AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA For the Biennial Term Ending November 30, /906. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BOARD UK CONTROL. BISTINO OF THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDI Hon. H. M. Eaton Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Hon. A. Galusha Secretary of State Hon. Peter Mortensen Hon. Norris Brown State Treasurer Attorney General EXECUTIVE OFFICERS. ■ Emma C. Johnston Anna Mundv Superintendent Matron ADVISORY BOARD. EW. H. AlcCreery, president, Lincoln, Nebr. F. S. Stein, secretary, Lincoln. Xebr. C. S. Bowman, Lincoln, Xebr. ■ J. W. Johnson. Lincoln, Nebr. H. J. W. Seamark. Lincoln. Xebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE ME FOR THE FRIENDLESS AT LINCOLN. Nl To His Excellency, John H. Mickey, Governor, and the He able Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Bitlemen — In accordance with the law of the state, I h onor to submit the fourth biennial report of the Home 'riendless. tthe 31st day of January. 1905, I was appointed by lickey, governor, superintendent of the Home for the ■ 1 Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus ned) and as - 1 control of the institution on the 1st of March, just &gt; later. Mrs. Anna Mundy was appointed natron b Win. Faulkner. I am pleased to say that I found everything in and around the ution in a neat and tidy condition. The buildings, how - were in a bad state of repair, needing reprinting and p new roof and gutters: the latter leaking so badly that the v. alls inside were damp and mouldy for weeks after a rain. This was attended to as soon as possible, pointing was done where iry and gotten mended. At the present time they n food condition. The school building must be repointed and the entire structure painted and an appropriation for this work asked for. The home consists of less than three acres of ground, which are erected two large, two story brick buildings: one an administration building and the other a school and dormitory building. The former contains the office, superintend - s. nursery, nurses' rooms, girls' dormitory, children's and employe*' dining rooms, play room, kitchen and store room. The latter building contains the schoolroom, boys' dormitory, officers' ■ad employes' rooms. Beside these, occupied by the orthoj ital. which was created by the last legislature and e - lished in the Home for the Friendless, are two large wi (formerly the schoolroom and second nursery), nurse - operating and X-ray rooms, offic &gt;tion room, dining r&lt; play room and sun parlor. We have also a two-story brick laun - dry, in the basement of which is located the boiler and engine </seg>
            <seg id="p004">376 ond floor for employes' rooms; a BKMrt dangerous place, indeed, for the seven enployea who occupy these rooms, being direct - ly over the boiler. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. The small, four-room cottage in the rear of the grounds, whic was built for a quarantine for the Home for the Friendless, I wa obliged to use for the aged women in the home in order to mak room for the nurses in the new hospital. This cottage is i charge of a home nurse who looks after the needs of these blin( crippled and helpless aged women. I have repaired the pore iat it is almost new and extends around three sides of thi cottage, that these help'' i may be wheeled out into th nine and pure air. This was done at an expense of $150.00 There is also a nice barn, large enough for six cows, four head 01 horses and carriage space, a good wood shed and a green - house. These buildings have been repaired at an expense $210.00. Later, a hail storm broke 300 panes of glass from the preenhouse and this was repaired &amp;i an additional expei other repairs and improvements have been made A new and larger water main, connecting with the city wmte main was the first improvement necessary. ;is our water supph was inadequate for the two institutions. New plumbing for the bath rooms and new steam and water pipes were plaeed through nut the basement of the school building at an expense ol sewer and water pipes, hot and cold, from the boiler roon to school building were laid later and 1278.00 was paid for this and grading around the building. Our smoke stack, which was struck by lightning, was taken down and five lengths of new pipe were added to replace the damage done The entire k was painted before being raised A small frame addition lothing from the hospital, was built at the rear of the laun - new wood shed was also built. The boilers were well ed and the old flues were replaced by new ones at an ex- M of $248.60. The engine was repaired at an expen - $84.90. New steel ceilings were placed in the girls' dormitory. h was also painted and papered. Three small rooms have been partitioned and plastered for the use of the home employes in the attic of main building. The porches have all been repainted. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">377 the woodwork inside the buildings revarnished or painted. Thus we have endeavored to keep everything in order and rep; as soon as it became necessary, for 1 deem it economy to the leaks while they are small. Our repair and improvement fund of $2,000.00 hi I t&lt;&gt; keep up the repair* of buildings and to help establish the new hospital in the ho at the present time is almost exhau \ balam it to do us until April 1st. 1907 and in traething un - foreseen occurs, I hope to be able, with the did of n and, h without a deficiency in this fund Ee electric wiring in our school buildim ciunced by expert electricians in a dangerous condition. ir fund should be increased to $5,000.00 for the next b that this work, the painting, reprinting and wiring )1 building may be done out of the repair and impn In May. 3!&gt;Ot&gt;. a mangle was purchased from Nelson &amp; Kre pany of Chicago, at an expense of &gt; and paid for r cash fund. This, with a new double geared washer bought a few months previous, and a fine new laundry stove. a pretty well equipped laundry, thus enabling us to do the work for both institutions. We need the second floor of this laundry building, (now used for employes' rooms i. for an ironing •ring room, which can be remodeled for this purpose at a small expense and paid for from the repair and impr fund for the next biennium. As we have but the one r for both washing and ironing, we can wash only two in the week, which ifficient to keep the - we are anxious to maintain throughout both institut THE FINANCIAL CONDITION. We have endeavored b.\ practicing the strict' i the end of this biennium without a deficiency, but find that Scieney in our maintenance fund is inevitable. When the appropration for the Home for the Frien i for jo. we had no thought of maintaining another tution. From an appropriation of $7.0&lt; p annum, w. deavored to maintain an av&lt; ( 116 persons: 5 nurses and lants in the orthopedic hospital. 55 children. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">378 light, board, clothing, drags, furniture, beddiug, « telephone rent, iu fact everything except salaries aix; in utter impossibility without incurring a Our maintenance appropriation of $14,000.00 for the bienniiun will be exhausted before the 1st of December, 1906. I earn the next legislature will see the necessity of liberally pro - ng for the institution th. aid training the dep and orphaned children of the state of Nebraska, for an &gt;rable and useful life and also for future citizenship. .Many a letter has been received from children grown to manhood anhood, filled with words of gratitude that our state le_ made it possible for them to have been lifted from their • undings and cared for and trained in the ways of useful - neas and right living in the Home for the Friend!. The home and the hospital should receive the heart from our legislature, that the orphaned, destitute jifflicted children may be given and treatment that may become a blet - and others. I why this home should not become one of the larire tate. It is the only state orphanage ve all the dependent and destitute children of braska who knock at our door for admission. Had it been bible for me to have cared for all who sought our prot&gt;-. during the past eighteen months, we would have as many more children in the honn now have. Money appropriated for &gt;aving and training of these little ones is given for a thy and noble purpose and the country will reap the reward day: not in dollars and cents, but in Splendid citizenship. The public has shown a deep interest in our home which has fly helped and encouraged us in our work. The and* any another institution and be held responsible for the maintenance of same, without having authority in any way the institution, has made my burden heavy. I would rev fully recommend that if the two institutions are maintained from one appropriation that they be under one management. Twenty-three iron beds and blankets, comforts, linen, etc thjrty-nine 1 n furnished ipital. I </seg>
            <seg id="p007">379 Bry donation received by us I, i shared by the if the hospital. Our Christm; t by the kind la - ! our city and others interested in the Home for tin- Pr ere divided as equally as possible, each child reeeii vy or box of candy : at other times when donations wen- re - . the crippled children were not forgotten. NEW APPROPRIATION. Owing to the advanced price in nearly all provision, it will require a maintenance fund of % &gt;0 for the Home for the text biennium or $34,000.00 if both the ortho - pedic hospital and the Home for the Friendless are mainta l'roni one fund. My estimate for the necessary appropri. is based on an average maintenance of 1&lt;&gt;&lt;*, (90 children and In aged women] at a per capita cost of 25c per day for the Home for the Friendless and on an i maintenance of 160 in - m in both institutions, (a per capita of 35e per day for 60 patients in the hospital). The expense for maintaining a hospital is much greater than ior maintaining a home, because of the greater variety and more usive diet required for the sick, the greater amount of heat, tight, bedding, etc.. necessary for their comfort. We have found that the capacity of our home is insufficient two institutions : separate wards are needed for the open cases and other deformed children. Our school huildin. suitable in any way for a hospital and I deem it a matter of great importance that the orthopedic hospital ha\ building with broad verandas where the crippled might be w ed into the sunshine and fresh air. I am sure it is not to the interest of either institution that the sick and the well chil - dren be housed in the same building We need the spa*-. d by the hospital I irry on the work n sary in the home. boo! building in which the orthopedic hospital is placed, would need nearly as much of an appropriation to remodel it ior the purpose of a hospital as it would cost to build a cottage exactly suited to their The same heating plant could be used to heat both institutions, and I think it would be as cheap, if not cheaper, to have our light furnished from the than to run our own dynamo. The institutions are lighted by </seg>
            <seg id="p008">380 the Lincoln Gas &amp; Electric Light Co., at the average cost of $600.00 per annum. We could not hire an electrician for that money, to say nothing of board and other expenses attendant on running a dynamo, besides having all night as well as all day service, which is quite an object because of our dark stair - basemenf kitchen, dining rooms, operating room, etc. other improvement absolutely necessary is the building of a bath room for the girls' dormitory on the south side of the nal building. From twenty to twenty-five little girls from Jour to twel p in this dormitory and all have the need of a bath and toilet near at hand; in case of i wckness. these little girls are obliged to go down two 11: of stairs to the basement bath room. This addition, 14x20 ft.. itory and basement, would give three rooms very much need - ed in the institution, i. e.. girls' bath room on the second floor, matron's linen room and dry goods store room on the first floor: [at the present time we are using a part of an enclosed porch) and a cold - room in the basement. This latter, the in - stitution should never li n without. The quantity of ice melted by havii in the hot kitchen for the past ten years, would nearly pay for the building of the whole addition, to say nothing of the great saving to the state in the of purchasing our butter, e . when cheap and keep - hem in cold storage. We could also buy meat in larger quantities at cheaper prices and it would allow greater store i capacity so that we could purchase our groceries in larger quantities, instead of giving a small order each day to retail dealers, as it is necessary for us to do at the present time. I am that both our governor and your honorable board will not ate to make this recommendation, for you certainly will •ee the great necessity for these improvements for the h addition could be built for $2,500.00 and would not only f much comfort for all concerned, but would be a great saving to the state as well. Inasmuch as the time for small wages for competent help has posed. T would recommend that higher salaries be paid our offi- were made by statute ten years ago. Our 'icr. who has carried the extra work of kindergarten with ]&lt;• work ith kindergj </seg>
            <seg id="p009">381 per month. I would urge that a salary of $40.00 per mouth or an appropriation of $960.00 be allowed the teacher for the biennium ending Mar. 31st, 1909. The engineer has worked for $40.00 per month and has also ided to the greenhouse and looked after the gardening, without extra pay. I would ask that he receive not less than $50.00 per month or $1,200.00 for the biennium. Ehead nurse, whose salary was also made by statute were low, is receiving a salary of $25.00 per month be a nurse of experience and her salary should be raised i.OO per month or $840.00 for the biennium. K superintendent's salary should be restored to $1,000.00 inum, the amount made by statute for salary of sui it when the Home for the Friendless became a state in - on. An appropriation of $3,500.00 per annum was allowed by legislature of 1904 and 1905 for employes' wages for the II for the Friendless and when the new hospital was placed i felt the great need of more help and a consequent greater appropriation. A few facts will enable your honorable boa? readily see the condition that confronted us. Our two cooks, who did the work for the home, were asked to prepare meals for forty (40) more people, diets lor the sick. etc.. without e help or pay. Our three women in the laundry were asked to do the laundry work for the hospital, which more than doubled their already heavy work, at the same pay and with one extra employe. Our dining-room girls took an extm iiurden and if will compare our pay roll and our salaries with those of other institutions, you will find we pay a much less salary to our teacher, engineer, head nurse, head laundress, head cook and other employes filling similar positions. In order to get through without a deficiency, our little chil - ciren, (none of them over ten years of age), were detailed to help in departments where help was most needed, and by hiring mothers at a low wage and caring for their children. I shall be able to reach the end of the biennium without a deficiency in this fund. Properly, our monthly pay roll amounts to $392.00 and we should have at least $9,000.00 appropriated for empl' wages for the biennium, to meet the advanced wages pa'd all </seg>
            <seg id="p010">382 cure. Children are imitators and we must have a good moral ent in our institution as the little ones are ofttii d -with the help in the various department*. A little i ne years of age had charge of the superintendent s dining umer and I venture th&gt; on that there is not Eing lady twice her age in the city of Lincoln who could on a table with greater nicety and composure than did this girl. When school opened, 1 was obliged tu hire an em - to fill the position. MORE GROUND NEEDED. I would respectfully call the attention of your honorable rd of Public Lands and Buildings and the legislature which will soon convene, to the necessity of purchasing grand b uaed for a garden for the on. The five lota adjoining home on the west and extending from the home grounds to 14 gn1 for $2,000.00. The purchase of property would open the alley to us from 10th str of land thirty feet wide adjoining the home ground the west and extending from South street for several block* us from the use of the alley and ofttnnea een blocked. Our only entrance and exit pr "iir gate on 11th street and our cramped room in, it almost impossible for learns with loads to turn around. The eight (8) lots adjoining on the south can be pureh at the present time for $1,800.00 and the chance of securing them should not be allowed to pass. The purchase of this prop tefnl and profitable employment to the chil I have rented these adjoining lots for the past two years for a ■ n and feel the great need of having this property for the There is not a garden spot in the home grounds In the year. 1905. the children raised on these lots all the I't potatoes, that were used in the institution early spring until the middle of September. We r •adishes, lettuce, peas, beans. \&lt; nach. cabl encumbers, and tomatoes. This past year. litoti. 1 1 1 • was not so favorable and we had many more to feed, but it has helped us greatly in our living expena The nineteen ). r lying it to the h groir ludintr two neat lit in be bought for </seg>
            <seg id="p011">383 E &gt;0.00. This is exceedingly cheap, being less than $3( t and should become the property of the home. I \ ore recommend that $10,000.00 be appropriated for the ( this property. CHILDREN IN THE HOME. I the 1st day of March. 1905, then m and seventy-nine ildren in the home: dm alf of this number were children placed here temporarily such times as their hard-working, widowed mothers could lish a home for them. The amendment to the appropriation bill for the II the Friendless in 1905, eat off from the support of the ! half orphaned, destitute children for whom the home was ■lally (1. Fur a quarter of a century, the Hom&lt; the Frieiidh - I for the deserted and dependent, half - orphan children. It .is the pioneer institution for the destitute children of the state of Nebraska. In 1897. it became a - ution. Many of its wards are living in different par and are among our most useful and respected citi Eore placing a child in a he • mmendations are re- I from people who know the home life of the parties de - to adopt a child and who can vouch for them as good, and temperate people, cap, a child and ially able to care for one. 1st.. 1!H(4. I have received into the home. 154 chil - dren and placed out in homes for adoption or indenture others placed in homes to work for their board, schooling clothing, 104, making a total for whom homes were font* Sixteen deaths occurred during the two years. Our ea teaches us that children from five to ten years of age are riot desirable in homes for adoption, hence we have them to for and educate until they are old enough to return - service for their board and clothing. When children are placed in homes, a trial period is given, during which time the foster parents have the privile - turning the child to the home, should it prove unsatisfactory. We reserve the right to recall the child if it becomes i in do sii atter tour months trial. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">384 I consider th. -ibility of placing a child, ver tur I feel that the destiny of the child, in a great measure, lies in my hands and great care has been exercised in the placing of our children. We cannot always depend upon recommendat are sometimes easily secured, so it becomes my dui the home of each child placed, before the final papers are tirawn up. A child placed in a home for adoption should be under the supervision of the home until he is at least six years of age, to guard against any possible ill treatment ■ d at least once a year by the superintendent or Tinting agent. I have visited most of the homes and feel that the ma - jority of the children placed during the past eighteen months have indeed been fortunate ; but six of the number placed in homes have been returned, which shows that the people are satisfied with their choice. Of this number, three were recalled ie superintendent because of failure to live up to agreement. Besides the wards of the state eligible for adoption, we have endeavored to care for a number of half-orphaned, destitute children who came to us from different parts of the state with nowJiere to call home. Time and again have poor motli&lt; to our door, accompanied by four or five little ones whose pit and haggard faces told too plainly the story of cruel abuse, pleading that her children might have the care and protection of the Home for the Friendless until such times as she would i«e able to establish a home for them. Then again, a father would bring a young, motherless babe and ask that it be cared for until he could find work, after « spent in caring for a sick wife. We have in our home, a fam - &gt;f four motherless little children under ten yeart of age, whose father after successive years of financial misfortune and suffering from the effects of a recent stroke of apoplex unable to provide a home for them. It was the last request of wife .ind mother that her little ones be not separated and the father is still hoping that some day he will be able to maintain his little family. Vowing is a letter sent by one of the county judges in our pleading for a destitute family : </seg>
            <seg id="p013">385 MAY 11. 1906. IioME FOR THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN, NEBR. I &gt;'-ar Madam We have a family of tive children in tk tie oldest of whom is about seven years of age. The father is a drunken, worthless fellow. The mother has left him, but holly destitute of means to support the children and her - self. She is able to work and could probably support thti they were not so young as to require the constant care of • 1 Mease let me know if this condition of affairs bri: within the rules for admission to your home. Upon inqu: that the family during the past winter have slept on straw without ticks and have had very little to subsist upon and this i parent from the appearance of the children. They are of Bohemian nationality and nothing was known of their con - ■lition until the woman cap wn the other day, carr of the children and presenting a most pitiful si*rht. If the children are admitted t&lt;&gt; your institution, the woman would Ike to know if she could get them back again in case she be - able to support them. Very truly yours. County Judge. These are the half-orphaned and destitute children for whom ;. revision was made by the last legislature. I could not my heart against the entreaties of these unfortunate poor, particularly the little helpless children whom I feel it my on to save. Realizing the worth of a child and knowing the temptations that come to children brought up on the street, hided that rather than have them sent to other institutions l-ecause they had fallen into crime, I would, open our doors and place them under the care and guidance of kind and inter - ested instructors who encourage a general development of char - acter, until such times as they may be placed in homes where they could work for their board and clothing and go to school. tadeed feel grateful to you, gentlemen of the Board of c Lands and Buildings for your kindly advice and assist - in this matter by approving rules and regulations for the that allowed me to assist these dependent and destitute ones. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">386 1 haw "i into a cash iuii'i 1 proride these littl &gt;d until such timea i of earing for and pro1 &lt;&gt;r mother thildren. I have d thought that if our law makers could but witnei brought to our door, their generous hearts would respond and the doors of th&lt;- Home for the Friend - less would swiii_ -i it tit«- and dependent child 1 would therefore respectfully urge that the Home for the i- dependent arvl d children and that the county judges li county in by the superintendent who shall such Prom the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, that tution will of charge, any dependent ■1 or maltreated child living in the state of Nebraska, u age of fifteen years, of sound mind and body and who ha* BOntagibu* &lt;! ill the little dependent or nial - •ed children 1 from the alarming traffic in children helped through the derating influences of the home, into honor and usefulness. SANITARY CONDITION. I sanitary condition of the home is good with the exception bath room that has no outside ventilation. We hav' iy little sickness considering that we have the two es in life under our care: our youngest, a bal old. the oldest, eighty-two years and both almost equally th no place in the institution for isolating or quarantin - &gt;ur sick, we have been fortunate in not having more serious ss and more fatal results. Anyone familiar with the work and who has seen the frail little pieces of humanity that to us. cannot but realize the difficulty in making them strong children who will be desirable for adoption. We are proud, however, of the number of little ones scattered in homes through - out the state, who were saved by untold labor and watchfn jind to the nurses who have spared no effort in doing all that 1 be done and have worked for small salaries, belongs un - stinted praise. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">387 \\ hen a child recovering from measles, came to our nur&gt; confronted with the problem of nowhere for detei elation and it was but a matter of less than two w&lt; D seventeen babies broke out with measles and oh, the pity of it. In less than five weeks time, one by one suecumbe -les or its complication, until six of our were laid side by side in the Home for the FriendlflM lot at \V.\ Our physician. Dr. May L. Flanagan, was out of the state, but &lt; ther physicians responded to the call and all that medical skill and human hands could do was done, but to no avail, all the eenrring unong those less than seven months old. Iain, having: nowhere to isoli • typhoid fever, recourse was to move his bed out of the dormitory into the vhere twenty-five b&lt; &lt;l many times daily. A trained from the city was hired and every possible means of ion was used. To the credit of both physician and nurse, id recovered after an illness of five weeks and not an&lt;&gt; - of fever developed. K scarlet fever patient als' red and I am plea - ds was the only case we had in the home. At the me there is not a case of sickness in the home. B conclusion. I desire to thank the officers and emp ome for their uniform courtesy and kindness and commend for their fidelity and zeal in serving the best inte istitution. To our matron, Mrs. Anna Mundy, am I deeply grateful for the services she has rendered in the economical management of her department and for her hearty co-operation in all that tains to the best welfare of the home. Dr. May L. Flanagan, the home physician for the past years, has shown a deep interest in her work and has been most faithful indeed, rarely a day in all this time that she has not ■ 1 the institution one or more times. She has played rare skill in her treatment of the sick and I render thanks tc her for her efficient aid. To our Advisory Board, I extend my heartfelt thanks for the words of encouragement and cheer they have given from time to time and for the deep interest manifested in our work among </seg>
            <seg id="p016">388 \\ e are indebted also to many ol our cil s of Lin - coln, and the mil f our city for their many kindly acts that have brought so much cheer to the hearts of our little children 8ud for their assistance in religious services. I wish to ackii' my appreciation of the honor conferred t.nd the confidence imposed in me by his excellency, John H. governor, who appointed me superintendent of oi the most important institutions in the state: that of home and ■ &gt;1, where children are raised from lives of neglect and error, iimed and trained for the future citizenship of our state. To you. ge; &gt;ard of Public Lands and Build, &gt;r whatever measure of I nay have ar :iy efforts. Our crowded condition, coupled with inadequate financial rapport to care for two institutions, has made my bur - inusually heavy. Your valuable aid so eheerfully given ?our hearty co-operation in furthering the interests of our insti - been greatly appreciated. For the many eouri :ne in the past, for your kindly sentiments and interest in our work. I tender m t'ul acknowledgment FROM APRIL 1, 1907, TO MARCH 31, 1909 Officers' salaries — Superintendent $ 2,000.00 ~\/~i/~\ f^f\ sincere EMMA C. JOHNSTON, i Sopt. APPROPRIATI" fHK BIENNIAL PERIOD iv. 30. is**i - = - 1~ 2 m i a 3" a O (Beers' sa: es' wapes. ■ Def. 14&lt;H).0&lt;&gt; 2000.00 i8.27 17:'. * 6.V $1114.38 UO7. M tance and im- 31H3.91 3004 73 lio.aJ :od. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">389 Head nurse 840.00 I.mployes' v 9,000.00 Maintenance 18,000.00 Hepairs and improvements 5,000.00 "1 and chapel supplies and traveling pxi 400.00 Total $40,000.00 SPECIAL APPROPRIATIONS. Brick additions. 14x20 feet, for bathroom and cold storage $ 2,500.00 Nineteen lots adjoining Home for the Friendless grounds 10,000.00 HOME FOK THE FRIKXDI ■ REPORT FOR THE BIBNNIUM. BEGINNING DECEMBER 1. 1904, AND ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906. CASH RECEIPTS. Dec. 1, By balance cash on hand Dec. By cash received for cinders and board 61.25 Jan. Board i Feb. Hogs, cinders and board Mar. Cinders and board 88.82 Apr. Old tank and board May. Cinders, old iron and board June. Cinders and board July. Board Aug. Board and sale of peas and beans Sept. Cinders and board Oct. Board 107.15 Nov. Board Dec. Board and sale of ho&lt;?s 136.65 Jan. Board 32.75 Feb Cinders and board 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">390 Pay patients in Orthopedic Hospital and board 159.90 June. Pay patients in Orthopedic Hospital and board July. Board 10 ■ i in Orthopedic Hospital, board and sale of hogs and einden 177 7.") Board 104.75 Oct. Cinder- 121.50 Board, einden and Iiol's Total Total expended 2,019.56 by balance cash on hand EXPENDED 1. Miss Hoppe, for 16% It) butter. $3.30; 2 doz. eggs, •"&gt;"&gt;• 1. Telegram to head nurse at Palmer. Kansas }Deq. 1. Hack hire from depot to Home to bring ;&lt; baby 1. Car far- Id ukesbury, for % day in laundry Dec. 3. Mrs. Mary Cokely, for 5% days laundry work 6. Mrs. Mary Cokely, for 1 day in laundry 1.25 Kva Harris, for 4 days relief in kitchen 2.50 8. Miller &amp; Paine, for yarn 13. Postage stamps S.&lt;&gt;0 13. Rip .uenzel. for 10 13, Car fare M ■ 14. B. (&gt;. Kosika. for 1 glass cutter. 15e; hi; board slating. *•"&gt;&lt;• l.'XI ■ 14. Hall Bros. Co.. for solder. 25c : repairing tin - ware. 2^ hours. $1.50: 1 flour 2.&lt;H) ■ 14. .Johnson &amp;. Lind. for I Tb peas. L5e; maple syrup $1.20 1 :{."&gt; 14. Barley Drag Co., for 1 catheter. 35c: 1 bot - tle Swamp Root. $1.00; 1 doz. medicine drop- Ders 50c </seg>
            <seg id="p019">HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN 391 14. Budge &amp; (iiien/.cl Co., for 1 doz. nc-ivw •")&lt;•; 1 padlock, 2 ."&gt;&lt;•: ti bottlt-s polish. (1.50 k fare bringing baby from depot ■ •")&lt;•; 1 padlock. 2"&gt;c : ti bottlt-s polish. (L50 14. tar tare 15, Car far, 116. Miller &amp; Paine, for paper arl Plenz. for 2 gaL kraut lti. Singer Mfg r 1 doz. domestic needli 17. (ilolic Delivery Co., for freight and delivery of bbl. comp. ..75 ■ 20, H. &lt;). Folks, for toning piano 20. H. Herpolsheimer Co.. for candles. 20e; for holders. 25e ■ 20, Miller &amp; I'aine. for tarleton 21. B. K. [ngraham, for carpenter work A 21. Mayer Bros., for 1 suit Dec. 22. Mrs. Mary Cokely, for I 1 -, day* hnmdry work 'i F. Orth. for 7 U&gt; butter .* ■ 23. II. H. Hoppe. fm :&gt; dm -! &lt;»&lt; . 7' , It, butter. |1.45 ,« ■ 2:i. Carl Plenz. for 1 bu. turnips. 80e; 2 gal. saner kraut. 40c ; 1 bu. parsnips. :l."»c - 2'\. Car fare ■ 24. II. Herpolsheinier Co.. for tissue paper 24. Miller &amp; Paine, for -i rolls of paper, 21c: 13 yds. flannel. $1.35 24. Ode E. Hector, for :l nipples 24. Kostka (Jlass &amp; Paint Co.. for 11 nipples 27. .Miller &amp; Paine, for ."&gt; yards swis-. s 27, Globe Delivery Co.. for delivering brushes 28, Postage stamps Dec. 28, Car fare 2!). Louis Veith. for 3 tti Kn&gt;:lish walnuts. .Vm- ; ■ sweet potatoes, 30c: 25 Ib butter at _' 7i: 10 doz. J2o 2'J. .(. F. Robinson. Omaha, for bnishe- Dec. 29. Money order Bending above Jan. 1. Car fare </seg>
            <seg id="p020">392 LAN! ir.S REPORT light Jan. 4, Sears Employment Agency, for securing help 2.00 Jan. 4, Car fare .10 Jan. 6, Car fare .10 t7, G. Wendelin, for 3 gal. sauer kraut and 1 bu. turnips .85 Jan. 7. Korsmeyer Co., for 6 basin plug! 1.50 t~. Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 2 in. galv. unions % .33 Jan. 7. Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 2 — H in. galv. coupling Jan. 7, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 2—% in. reducers .06 ■ 7. Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 2— ' , in. pet cox .38 ■ 7, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 25 ft. cut lacing 25 - credit of 50c Jan. 7. Miller &amp; Paine, for 2 sk. yarn .50 Jan. 7. Harry Porter, for 1 1-2 doz. tablets Jan. 7, Johnson &amp; Lind for 2 Christmas trees L20 Jan. 7. Johnson &amp; Lind for one box ginger snaps L78 Jan. 7. Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for one mattress $4.50 ■ 7. Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for three M door locks 1.95 Jan. 7, Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for one eombinette 1.00 Jan. 7, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for one bowl &amp; pitcher .90 8.35 Jan. 7. Harley Drug Co.. for two hot. lactopeparata 2.00 ■ 7. Harley Drug Co.. for one oz. ox trail and 3 lb sugar milk 2.00 Jan. 7. Harley Drug Co.. for one catheter Jan. 7. Harley Drug Co.. for exchange on nipples .10 .Jan. 7, R. M. Tidball. for lumber Jan. 7. Car fare 10 Jan. 10. L. V. Quick, for 3 gal. hominy .50 Jan. 10. Postage stamps 3.00 Jan. 10. Ode Rector, for 5 It) rosin Jan. 10. Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for 5 po- .40 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE FRIKNDLK- 393 H 6, T. W. Raglitz. for mending furnace scraper ti. Expense taking child to Cambridge, Nebr. •I an. lU, Cflr iaro Jan. 12, G. F. Orth, for 10 ft butt.i Jan. 12, G. F. Orth. for apples Jan. 14, Car fare Jan. 14, J. D. Schrader, for potato*-- Jan. 14, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for srlue and wire Jan. 14, Care fare 117, Mrs. Anna Bronsmi, for 2 da. laundry work 17, Expenses visiting child in Pickrell, Xebr 20, Mr. Wendeline, for turnips and parsnips 20, Lincoln Tank Line for 20 pal. gasoline and ■ coal oil ■ 21, L. V. Quick, for 3% gal. hominy 25, Car fare s 127, Ode Rector for cousrh cure 27, Lincoln Telephone rent. Dec. and Jan. 27, Car fare 29, Car fare 1, Xebr. Sanitary Food Co., for 100ft cereal coffee Feb. 1, Rudge &amp; Gtaenxel, for one joint ■ galv. pipe 6x8 ...$ .50 1, Rudjre ft Gnenzel. for ini ■ galv. pipe 10x8 .60 1. Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for one-half ■ joint galv. pipe 6 in. .40 1, Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for one 6-in. elbow 20 1, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for one one- half in. union .11 " ■ 1. Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for one one- half in. ell .05 , II, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., for 17 ft. V2 in. galv. pipe 1. Harry Porter, for one do*, pencils 4, Mrs. Cokely, for % day in laundry 4, Louis Veith, for one bu. corn Feb. 6, G. Wendeline. for sauer kraut, parsnips and turnips </seg>
            <seg id="p022">394 pr. rubbers Feb r fare .10 10, Nebraska Electrical Co.. for electrical suppl : two da. laundry work imps 13. Harry Porter for tabl- -ncils and colored straws 2J2Q Feb. 13, H. Herpolsheimer Co.. for 2 pr. woolen hose .90 13, Car fare .10 15, Care fart- in 16. II. H. Hickman. for 10 IT) butter ■7. T. J. Cokely, for tearing out wall and re - plastcrinir 5.00 17. Mrs Cokely. for five da. laundry work 18. L. V. Quick, three and one-half gal. hominy .55 Miller &amp; Paine, for f&gt; baby hose and 2 suits underwear or two suits for bo; 5.40 ■•tor. for H doz. brushes J-Yb 22. Car far. .10 okely, for 3 da. laundry work Guy Wendetin, for parsnips, carrots and tu nips 1.06 r&gt; Employment Ajrcy., I inir - i. r irls 1.00 r, for 6 (i/. lac. sulph &amp; HK» pro - temene tab. 1.35 Standard (Jil Co., for 1 f Under oil 4.ini Feb. 25, R. L. Smith, for repairing washing machine 4.00 Harry Porter, for letter copy book and lead pencils 3.12 Feb. 25. Care fare Feb. 25, Postage stamps 3.00 M II. Hiekman. for 10 tb butter (a 25c Lincoln Telepl for 'phone rent for Feb 3.00 Feb. 28, L. V. Quick, for 4 pals, hominy .64 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">395 Mch. 6. Budge ft Guenzel, for 1 oommode, 1 dresser, 1 table Mch. 6. \V. X. Rehlauder, for 1 pair crutches 1.00 Mch. 8, Geo. H. Hennergardt, for lolderiiif leh. 10, Prank E. Lahr. for gaaolinc stove 10, Postage stamps 3.00 11. Knsika (ilass &amp; l'aint Co., fur 1 pt. paint Mch. 11, Lincoln Traction Co., for street car tickets 1.00 Mill ]&lt;. Carl Plenz, fur 2 bu. parsnips .80 Mch. 2o. Warner &amp; Reckman. for 1 pr. narrow sh. 1 25 Men. 20. Frank E. Lahr. for sweet pea seed .15 Mch. 20. Lincoln Traction &lt; *... for street car tick. Mch 21. &lt;» C. Asa. for 20 qta. home canned cherries 4.00 Mch. 22. Miss Adda Smith, for 1 bu. parsnips .40 Mch 24. Mayer Bros., for 1 hoy's suit, shirt, suspen - ders, caps, pants, waist 6.11 ''ch. 24. Lincoln Tel. Co., for telephone rent for Mch. Meh. 24. Weste-n Butter Co.. for 1 gal. cottage ehet &gt;ich. 24. Frank K. Lahr. for bii i and nails .60 Mch. 24. R. W. Smith, for 15 tral. trasoline and 4 &lt;ral. .\pr 10. GriawoM Sf*-&gt;\ Co., for rose baahea Apr. 12. Lincoln Traction Co.. for street car tickets Apr. 13, G. S. f'amhridjre. for plowing 1% lots I.imI Apr. 13, Frank E. Lahr. for window brush and pole Apr. 17. Mayer Bros., for neckties and collar Apr. 17, Fitzgrerald Dry Gooda Co.. for handkerchi' Apr. 17. Cash triven to two bo; in \ W* f 1 1 00 coal oil B27. &lt;i. WVndelin. for turnips 27. &lt;; Wfiidi'lin.f or plowing 3 lots and harrowing t28. Postage stamps 1. John Spanton. fur plowing 2 lots ■ •"). Dr. Flanagan, for patent medicine for old lady 10, Oriswold Seed Co., for prarden need Apr 10. Xebr. Paper &amp; Bajr ('&lt;&gt;.. for lead pencils and tablets ■ 10. Postage stamps 10. Orwwold Seed Co. for flower and garden d </seg>
            <seg id="p024">396 Apr 17. Whisk broom .25 If. Davis, for mattress for old lad&gt; l!t. Hardy Furniture Co., for mat 19, Expense of taking two boys to Indianola 6.66 Apr 19. Mrs Sohus. for seal frame 1.00 Apr. 1!». State Treas. Mortensen, $1.00 19, Co. Clerk. $2.50, for notary commission 3.50 19. T. J. Thorp, for seal 1.00 Apr. 19, T. J. Thorp, for rubber stamps and ink .65 ■ Shirley, for cash paid for exchange on lock 35 Apr. 20, H. Herpolsheimer &amp; Co., for child's (-oat 1.00 Apr. 21, Li i Co., for telephone rent for April 3.00 Apr. 25. Street car tickets 1.00 ■ 25, Fitzgerald Dry (Joods Co.. for ehild'i dress pattern 1 5 Apr. 26, Harley Dri or three porous plasters .45 Post a ire stamps 3.00 Apr. 26, H. Herpolsheimer Co.. for window cleaner .25 Apr. 26, Miller &amp; Paine, for curtain stretcher L75 ■ 26. Rudge &amp; Guenzel. for brass bed for superin - tendent 's room Apr. 29. Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for 1 box envelops May 8, Traetion Co., for street car tickets 1.00 May 8, Plowing for corn 1 •"&gt;" May 8. Fitzgerald Dry Qooda Co., for eutienn soap ."&gt;4 .May 8. Phclps Burruss Lumber Co.. for sand 1.20 May 13, F. Chrisman, for drayage to asylum for little pigs LOO May 16. John Spanton. for plowing garden May 16, Traction Co.. for street car tickets L'imi May 16. !'&lt;■- 3.00 May 16. Frank E. Lahr. for carpet stretcher .75 May 18. J. Kremmark, for parden rent t22. The Lincoln Tel. Co., for telephone rent for May 3.00 May 23, J. Trickey, for alarm clock for cook 1.50 May 25. J. M. Beams, for rent of lot 1.50 May 25. U. P. R. R. frt. on stationery from St. Paul. r and dravatre </seg>
            <seg id="p025">397 May 25, W. II. MeGowan, for carpenter work done Apr. 12th May 25, Harley Drug Co., for rubber tips for crutches .50 t25, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for envelopes, type - writer paper ami twine L'ti. Rudge \ Giienzel, for children's sailor hi L'ti. Rudge «.&lt;: Gnenzel, for infants' dresses May 30, Dr. Gr&lt; him, for six little pigi 15.00 .May 31, Postage stamps May 31, Street car tickets 2.00 31, Mayer Bros., for 1 I - 2.95 31, H. Herpolaheimer Co.. for shoe repairing .45 31, II. Herpolaheimer Co., for half soleing and re - pairing June 3, Repairing electric door-bell, two new batter - ies, switch, socket and car fare June 7, Lincoln Tank Line, for 15 gal. gasoline $2.40; 5 gal. kerosene, 75c; 20 ft paraffine $1.60 4.75 June 14, John Spanton, for cultivating corn June 15, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for mem. books June 15, The Lincoln Telephone Co., for telephone rent 3.00 June 16, Mrs. Mary Cokely. for three days laundry work .Mine 17. "Warner &amp; Beekman, for half-^ June 17. W. A. Doggett. for needles and machine belts .75 June 17, Ode Rector, for asthma cure .89 June 17, Harry Porter, for carbon paper .25 June 20, One truss, for old lady 1.50 June 20. Traction Co.. for car ticket! 2.00 June 20, St. Louis Depository for Sunday school sup - pi' 1.74 June 20, Jennings &amp; Graham. Kansas City, for school journal .60 June 23, Mrs. Mary Cokely for ; i days laundry work 3.75 ■ 1. Alta B. Peyton, for blackboard for Fred Han - sen 1.00 July 10. Nebr. State Journal, advertisement for help July 20, Cowen &amp; Gold, for children's dresses 1.96 July 20, Lincoln Tank Line, for coal oil and gasoline 2.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">398 L VND (JOMM - currants 4.5C Mayer Bros., lor boys' waists 4.05 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for fruit can rubbers Julj r A; l?;i- OT fin-works 5.58 July 28. Telephone rein for July 3.00 - Flower &gt;r the home from Carl Funke .67 ■ .ubber dolls for children and baby com - fort er 28, .Mayer Bros, for ' - doc straw hats (a" 10c 1.14 July 31, 3.00 July 31. Lincoln Traction Co.. for street ear tickets 2.00 July 31. .1 &lt;&gt; Alt in.-, for repairing shoes 1.70 Julj Enploymeni Agency, for help 1.00 1. I*' utrht July loth 12, F Chrisman. for dray;iL r i- 12. Mrs Cokely. for l 1^ da. laundry work 1.88 ■ ■ City for Sunday school supplies ■ 14. Expenses of visiting children at Wymore, -onville. Kearney. York ami Benedict. Xebr . as per receipts on file 13.31 20. Lincoln Tel. Co.. for telephone rent 3.00 21. I'"- 3.00 21. Traction Co., for street car ticket-* 2.00 ■ 21. Mayer Bros . for two suits, ties &amp; waists for children 21, Mr. Altine, for mending and soleing shoes 1.00 ■ 31. Kxpenses to Palisade and Indianola to visit children placed in homes 17.00 31. Lincoln Tank Line, for oil .65 ■ 1. Frank Lahr. for galvanized trough made in laundry ■ 1. Frank Lahr. for % doc mouse traps 1 J. O. Altine. for repairing slims .60 ■ 16, St. Louis Depository, for Sunday school son leaves Iw Sizer. I\ M.. for postage stamps 3.00 • 19. Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent 3. 00 wen &amp; ' r two child's dr 2.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">399 W Tit Branch &amp; Miller, for fruit at a sale Sept. 27. W. B. .Ji'iikins. for watermelon! Western [Jnion Telegraph Co., telegram to 24. Stackhouse &amp; Tyrell. for plants 1.35 2. Rudge &amp; (ruenzel. for cap for little pirl (go- ing away) _ , \ I J cl 1 1 1 MJl vf&amp;m a A \J L lull I/O 1^1 X CC11 XA\/ UOv " ■-■■■■■■«■ IKearih 6, .Mayer Bros., for -.'rip. strap and hata «. Nebr. Paper ,V; Bag Co., for Ubleti 6, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for paints and bru- 7, J. 0. Altine. for mending shoes 10, Traction Co., for street ear tickets 110, Postage stamps &gt;rn, 24 l.u. 20 tt&gt; '- 44c per hu. 12. Expense visiting children near Alliance. North Platte and Ord as per receipts on file 20. Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent 2ft. Maxwell Ice (ream Co., f&lt;&gt;r 4 &lt;ral. ice cream ■ bought July 4th 20, Bodge &amp; (iuenzel. for collar 15c: tie 25c 126, I'' 27, T. J. Thorp, for piston rod 1. I). Blodgett, for hotel expenses in York 2. Ticket from Schiiyl i-and Island to t children in homes ■ 2. Livery team out of York 2. Mr. (arten. for team at Grafton a Hack at Grand Island d three meals $1.50 1.75 I'K Stephen Gardiner, for wall paper 10. W. TT. Sawdon, for 3 bu. apples 11, R. R. fare in connection with mileage 11. Harry Porter, for letter and stick file ■ I s . Postage stamps 18, Traction Co., for street car tickets a ■ 18, Lincoln Tel. Co., for telephone rent 23, Nebr. Paper &amp; Ratr Co., for receipt books and u. 1 gr. pencils </seg>
            <seg id="p028">400 A. M. Davis Co., for bed, springs and mattress 18.00 2, A. M. Davis Co., for bed-room suite for C. &amp; D. hospital 18.00 Tucker, for clock for nursery 1.25 2, Money order sent to St. Louis .07 ■ 2. Money order sent for Sunday school lesson she. la 1 ; 5t; 2, Cash paid for vinegar pitcher 5. Postage stamps 6, J. O. Altine, for repairing shoes L46 Dec. 6, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for slop pail Dec. 6, P. O., for postage due. held on deposit . .50 ■ 9, Carl Funke. for syrup pitchers, $1.76; wash bowls and pitcher, $2.1 f) Dec. 9, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for jardiniere and desk sup- plies f4. Armstrong Clothing Co., for suit, $2.98; 2 pr. pants $2.00. 4 waists $1.49, total $6.47, dis - count 10 per cent, 64c 5.83 ■ 15, Mayer Bros., for four children's suits and waists 4.00 ■ 15, Paine Clothing Co., for 2 suits, $6 ; waist 25c; 2 suits $6; 2 suits $5; 3 caps $1.25; total $18.5' n per cent discount. *1.85 16.65 - Chapman's Drug Store, for glue 19 Traction Co., for street car tickets 4.00 Dec. 21, L. V. Quick, for hominy .75 Dec. 21, Lincoln Telephone Co., for telephone rent 3.00 ■ 22. Ru«ip izel, for beads and toys for nur - sery .60 Dec. 22, Postage stamps 3.00 23. Thomas Farrell, for draya&lt;r&gt; .50 Dec. 23, Miller &amp; Paine, for netting for candy .25 Dec. 23, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for school tablets and pencils Dec. 23, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for 12 ft nuts, $1.92; pk. hickory nuts 25c Dec. 23, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for 15 ft candy @ 7^c 1.13 J. O. Altine, for mending shoes .50 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">401 to Dr. I from pay patients and others not 'ed with ('. &amp; D. hospital, but maintained at hos - pital Dec. 29, Cartage of hogs sold to Weiler Pk_- 2.00 Jau. 4. L. V. Quick, for hominy Jan. 10, J. H. Ouderkirk, for six pigi 13.00 Jan. 13, Poa Jan. 17. P. Chrisinan, for drayauv Jan. 17, Harry Porter, for rubber bands .50 18, W. A. i for machine needles Jan. 18, Lincoln Tel. Co.. for rent 3.00 Jan. 18, J. 0. Altine, for mending shoes ■ 20. II. HerpoUieimer &lt; ■ • 'hristma - and nuts 4.10 Jan. 20, Lincoln Book Store, chalk and slate pencils .35 24. Traction Co., t I car ti&lt; 124. Expense of visit" children at Cambridge and Indianola. as per receipts on file, railroad far .mi from Cambridge, IS miles 00; hotel expei Cambrid hotel expense at [ndianola (1.00; team out from [ndianola $1.00; lunch at depot. II,, ing. 25c; total Jan. 29, II. Herpolaheimer Co., for girl's coat ■ of trip to Nelson and Hebron, visit - ing and placing children, as per receij R. U. fare and hotel expenses t;. l Pew, for t; do/, eggs 1-eb. i. (iriswold Seed Co., for Feb. !&gt;. GoM A Co.. for 2 [prls and 3 m^ Feb. 9, Postage stamps 3.00 10, Two cans condensed milk for nursery Feb. 10, One electric shade Fell. 15, Cups and lancers for old ladies for Christn Feb. 15, F. Chrisman, for drayage 16. Traction Co., f I car tickets 4.00 Feb. 16, Weiler Pk^r »r berries bought June. '05 17. Board of T in, for school hooks 2* </seg>
            <seg id="p030">402 niey and expense to visit child 8.39 ■ 21, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for y 2 doz. child's sup - por 21. II. Herpolsheimer Co., for 6 pr. infants' pants 1.50 l!4. .1 O AJtine, for mending 2.15 for telephone rent 3.00 ird of Education, for arithmetics Mar. 2, Traction Co.. for street car lickets 5.00 Mar. 5, M. P. R. R. for freight on goods .25 :i Union Tel. Co., telegram to Dem Harry Porter, for 1 bo m paper Mar. 9, Postage stamps 3.00 for baby rap K K. Johnson for □ 11.05 Lincoln Tel. Co.. for rent Mar. 20, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for hair ribbons 1.65 y Garbage Co., for cartage 1.50 Mar. 21, Melick's Stables, for livery and hacks 4.00 Mar. 24. Harry Porter, for chalk .10 Louis 1 y. for money order 1.36 age stamps 3.00 Apr. 3. Street car tickets from Traction Co. 5.00 4. Dybbro Bros., for meat for broth ■ 5, Visiting child at York. R. R. fare $3.14. hack . hotel exp. 50e Apr. 5. Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for hair ribbons .20 5, John Spanton. for plowing 1.00 .Apr. 5, J. J. Lichty, for apples 2.65 Apr. 5, Paine Clothing Co., for pants .50 Apr. 12. Expense trip to Fairbury to visit child 3.65 20. Lincoln Telephone Co.. for rent 3.00 21, John Spanton. for plowing 3.50 1. Traction Co., for street car tickets 4.00 May 1, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for pencils .25 May 1, Carl Plenz, for pie plant .50 May 1, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for ribbon 1.36 May 1, Harry Porter, for 1 box clips .20 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">403 May 5, Frank E. Lahr, for onion sets May 8, Lincoln Local Expr for drayage ■ 9, Expense visiting children at Omaha and Plattsmouth 7-36 .May 9, Xebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., paper supplies 2.88 May 9, Gold &amp; Co., for bonnet .20 May 9, John Spanton, for plowing 3.00 May 9, John Burke, for rent of three lots 2.50 9, Mrs. M. R. Davey, for rent of six lots 15.00 9, O. J. King, for strawberrit - ■ 11. Lincoln Trai r frt. and dra; of mangle from &lt; 11, Mrs. Ludeman. for 1 day's ironing 11, Carl Plenz, for pie plant .60 14. P. .1. Darner, for maple syrup 15, Frank E. Lahr, for tacks May 15, W&lt; oion Telegraph Co., for telegram .50 15, Ru fuenxel, for lawn settee 5.00 15, Ru&lt; /el, for gasoline 2.50 ■ 15, Rudg ozel, for : brush han - dle 15, Bu&lt; iiienzel, for couch cover 1.25 15, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, for gowns for old lady 1.00 16. Griswold S I 16, James Beegan, for 1 bu. apples 17, Carl Plenz, for pie plant 17, P. Spanton, for plowing and harrowing 17, Postage stamps 3.00 17, Traction Co., l t car tickets 5.00 May 17, Mayer Bros., for caps 1.00 L'l'. Mrs. Ludeman. for night nursing 2.00 May 22, Keystone, for strawberries .75 22, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for hair ribbons .50 23. Lincoln Transfer Co., for drayage May 23, Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent 3.00 May 26. Frank Spanton. for cultivating May 26, Nelson &amp; Kreuter Co., for mangle 200.00 May 26, George Wendeline, for tomato plants .40 May 26, O. J. King, for mdse., as per bills on file 1.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">404 m Jun&lt; ir. Paper &amp; Baj liool supplies _ .75 June 4, Traction Co., for car tickets 5.00 June 4. Diamond Compour &lt;r boiler compound 33.36 rl Plenz, for pi&lt;- plant 1.50 7. .1 0 Altine, for mending shoes \niia Kuorr. for special nursing 7.00 ■ A. I). Grow, for 2 bu. ekerriea • 13, John Sjianton. for cultivating A: &lt; ruenzel, for patterns lit. II. Herpolsheimer Co., for patterns 1~&gt; Iwhool and K;. L'n. Joknaoo &amp; Lind, sui&gt;j)Ii« js. St. Louis Depodi l.r for cabbage and celen .tune 21. Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent '{.&lt;ki -sun, for tomato plants nton, for plowing 1.50 II. Prey, for i' bu. eherriea 4.00 ~: iikesbury. for 4 days laundry work ■ and Friend visiting children, hotel exp 00, liven R. I, 4 51 ■ lardy Pnrniton springs and ma Hress !&lt;v July •"). Tn ireet car tickets JL 5.00 ■ wbr. Hardware Co.. wringer and jfashing niachinc Lincoln Transfi for draj Jul\ - i.oo Lichtei r berries July ♦;. Bodge &amp; &lt;;uen/el. for Manilla rope .'uly 6, Mayer Bros., for two cotton suits 1.60 i '&lt;).. for garden seed Mrs. Mary Fredrich. for cabbage and cucum- •fuly 7. Miller &amp; Paine, for 1 pi ie, and snp - poi </seg>
            <seg id="p033">405 July 9, Armstrong Clothinj ir i \&gt;v. trousers ■ 11. 1 do/., cabbage and cueomben from .Mrs. Fredrieh .85 July 11, .Mrs. Stukesbury, for 1 da. laundry work July 13, Carl I'k'ii/. for pie plant July 14. J. ( ). Altine, for mending 14. I'm 3.00 ■ 17. Elmer E. Clary, for expense returnii boy July 17. Kosika &lt;;lass ft I'aint Co., for i»;iint 3.00 July 17. Mrs. Hanson, for 1 sack gooseberries July Is. Lincoln Transfer Co., for &lt;lr, July IS, .Mrs. I,. I'. Sutler, for 1 &lt;la. laundry work July !!•. Mrs. Fredrieh, for encumbers and cabbage July 21, Farmers Grocery Co., for peaches and berr 1 25 July 21, Worrell Mi for ins«- minator 10.00 July 2:5. Branch &amp; Miller, for crab applet .60 July 24. Lincoln Tel. Co.. for rent July 25, R. Conn, for apples July 30, J. Trickcy. for repairing glasses July irs Employment or help .50 Am.' 2. Mrs. Heath, for 1 nighi nursing and car fare 2. Traction Co.. for street car tickets 5.00 Aujr 4. Mrs Heath, for 1 niirht nursing 1.00 Aug. ti. Pos' nips 5.00 .\u«. r 7. Samuel Brooks, for 2 bn. apples 1.00 7, Mrs. Randolph, for 4 nights nursing 4.00 7, Cartage of four hogs 1.50 Aug. 8, L. M. Russcl. for 2 bu. peaches Aus. 11, F. Chrisman, for drayage .25 Aue. 11, Mrs. Stukesbury, for 2y» days laundry work 3.10 - 13, Myers-Dillon Drug Co., for disinfectant 30.00 Aug. 13, Draft for the above ... .10 Aujr. 14. John Spanton. for plowing potatoes AiiL r . 17. Franklin I mi Co.. for ice cream Aug. 18, Mrs. Stukesbury, for I 1 ';, da. laundry work 1.88 Aug. 21. F. Chrisman. for drayage Fields &amp; Johnson. Nebraska City, for apples 3.00 Aug. 25, Money order for same .10 • O "" ~\ f\ CC </seg>
            <seg id="p034">406 E. Anderson, for 2 bu. apples 1.00 B. &amp; Q. R. R. Co., for 1.000-mile book 25.00 .Aug. 28, Mr. Garten, Graf ton, for teams 3.25 An? -h over Y. P. K. R. Kearney to Gnd. Island 1.30 L'*. lintel expense at Grand Island 1.00 E28, Hack to depot EL Herpolsheimer Co., for pattern 28, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., for pattern . 1~&gt; .10 28, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., for pattern .10 Aug. 28, Harry Porter, for marking pens .30 28, Harry Porter, for marking pens .30 ■ 28, J. W. Moore, for tomatoes and celery 28, J. W. Moore, for tomatoes and celery 28, J. 0. Altine, for mending - _ 1.80 1, E. H. Munson. for melons 3, Carl Plenz. for vegetables 3. Tracti' for ear tickets 5.00 4. Leslie Burns, for 2 bu. gr 10, Leslie Burns, for plums and grape&gt; 10, Mrs. Fredrich. for 3 bu. tomatoes at 60c 1.80 11, W. H. Richards, for 6 bu. apples 1.50 Burns, for melons 1.70 11, Harry Porter, for school supplies .90 11, Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent for August 11, F. W. Woolworth Co., for strainers 12. Maxwell Ice Cream Co., for ice cream in August ■ 14, Railroad fare, Pittsburg to Kansas City and return 7.80 ■ 14. Hotel expense and street car fare on trip to visit children 14. Western Union Tel. Co., for telegrams 17. Hoard of Education, for books 9.45 br. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for tablets .86 18, Good Luck Grocery, for berries .50 ■ 19, Jacob Lichtensteiger, for 1 bu. peaches 1.00 19, Hack fare from depot with infant 50 ■ 19, St. Louis depository, for Sunday school supplies 1 62 21. F. W. Woolworth Co., for dolls and elastics .40 Hoard of Education for books 1 05 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">407 r, Jacob Lichtensteiger, for tomatoes and melons 5.40 Sept. 22, W. O. Wiloes, for y 2 bu. plums .60 24, Lincoln Telephone Co., for rent 3.00 i 24 W. O. Wilkes, for. tomatoes and sweet po - tatoes 2.10 Sept. 26, A. Flanagan Co., for kindergarten supplies and money order . 4.30 Sept. 29, Edw. Cerf, for 2-3 doz. caps at 25c each 2.00 Oct. 1, Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets 5.00 3, Nebr. Paper &lt;5c lin&lt;: Co., for paper blanks 3, John Burke, for rent of three lots 3, J. H. Foreman, for five bu. apples 4. I'd- mps 4. Frey &amp; Frey, for flower pots. 2 doz. Oct. 8, W. Sidders, for 2 bu. apples @ 50c 1.00 Oct. 8, H. Herpolsheimer Co.. for infants' reubens 2.70 8. State Journal Co., for want advertisement ■ 1"). The Chapman Drug Store, for rubber tips for crutches .50 Oct. 24, Alex Wolpa, for 120 bu. potatoes (&lt; 69.00 25, R. E. Ferguson, for one load straw 5.00 Howard, for 29 bu. 55 It) e.orn (a 38c 11.24 26, S. A. Jameson, fur 12 bu. apples 5.50 _ ( 7. N. W. R. R. Co., for freight and dray;, 1 25 27, Lincoln Transfer Co., for drayae:e Oct. 28, Lincoln Transfer Co., for drayage Nov. 1. U. P. R. R. Co.. for fare to David City 3, Alex Wolpa, for 25 bu. apples bfl 13.13 Nov. 3, Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets 5.00 Nov. 5, Griswold Seed Co.. for garden seed Nov. 7, Postage stamps 5.00 ■ 7, Chapman Drug Co., for rubber bands and polish 13, W. G. Doggett, for machine needles .!•"&gt; Nov. 14, Lincoln Transfer Co., for drayage 1.15 Nov. 14, H. Herpolsheimer Co., for ribbon Nov. 14, W. A. Vogt, for onions, to pickle 120 Nov. 15, Lincoln Telephone Co., for telephone rent for two months 6.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">408 ■ mperintendeni ii&gt; II and hi file P. J. Darner, for Maple syrup 17. Jol ton, for plowing poi Nov. 21, Paine Clothing 9.75 lion Telegraph Co., for telegram II. Buner Tor sold&lt; coin Ti for draj i ■ II. Hun. i for soldering - John Murray, for seven shoals ■ ly, etc. for Tim giving W. A vinjr machine oil locking caps or eotton suiis and caps II. Ooderkirk, for 2 5.00 ■ [rich Bi on voucher fur gro oucrhi in Novenil 13li 44 Total expended GARDEN* PRODUCTS. FROM DEC. 1ST, 1904, TO NOV. 30TH, 1906 Beans, bushels 18 s, dozen 194 n, dozen 622 ;mbers. bushels 4 age, dozen 94 ice, bunches 710 Potatoes, bushels 69 Spinach, bushels 3 atoes, bushels 17 Turnips, bushels 6 Onions, bunches 851 Peas, bushels 7 n I* ,l i » i —1*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">409 MATRON'S REPORT. MADE IN THE SEWING ROOM DEC. 1, 1904 TO N 30, 1906. infants" slips ■ Infants' dresses ■ its" diapers ( tuldren "s d Children's nitrht gowns Children "s skirts &lt; hildrens aprons - ' shirt waists s' under waists Children's table napkins 110 Children's skull caps 19 shiri waist suits I night di 6 dressing sacques •» Ladies' aprons 8 Ladii t eorera Ladies' shirt waists 2 - i ■ s' wrappers 5 ■s' flannel skirts s es 1 muslin skirts 6 Curtains, pairs 28 Table c-Ioths I Table napkins 60 Towels, roller Towels, hemmed Waiters' aprons 10 scarfs 1^ Pillow cases 50 Sheets 100 forts 32 30 Bed ticks for feathers 1 Pillows made, pairs 8 , , i A 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">410 LANDCOMMISS1 -REPORT 4 Tea towels hemmed Garments repaired CANNED FRUITS. Canned fruits, quarts 76 Fruit jam, quarts Fruit jelly, glasses Hum butter, quarts Sour pickles, gals. et pickles, gals 10 Mango pickles, gals. Tomato catsup, pints 33 9 Tomato relish, gals. 7 v chow, gals. RESIDENCE OF CHILDREN IN THE HOME FOR THE FRIEND - LESS BY COUNTIES. Aged County— Male. Female. Women. Table cloths repaired Douglas Hamilton Jefferson .aneaster </seg>
            <seg id="p039">IE FOR THE FRIKNI 411 Males. Females. Women. No. of children in the home Nov. 30, '04_ 44 25 7 No. received since 88 66 Total 132 91 7 No. placed for adoption or indenture 31 17 No. placed in homes to work for board and schooling 60 44 10 6 No. of deaths since Nov. 30, 1904 No. of children in the home Nov. 30, '06 31 24 7 Total No. inmates in the home Nov. 30, 1906 . 62 STATISTICAL FORM FOR STATE INSTITUTIONS. KARED IN ACCORDANCE WITH A RESOLUTION OF THE NA - TIONAL CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND COR - RECTION, ADOPTED MAY 15, 1906. NAME OF INSTITUTION— THE HOME FOR THE FRIEND - LESS. POPULATION. Male. Female. Total. Number of inmates present at beginning of fiscal years 44 32 76 Number received during the years 88 66 154 Number discharged or died during the yrs. 101 67 168 Number at end of the fiscal years 31 31 62 Daily average attendance (i. e. number of inmates actually present) during the years _ ... 34 29 63 Average number of officers and employes during the years 2 22 24 EXPENDITURES. Current Expenses — 1. Salaries and wages $13,543.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">412 ; maintenance 16,979.98 4. Ordinary repairs 2,000.00 Total $:«,523.78 Extraordinai . ses — 1. New bin 2. I nt improvement! Ming bit Total si. i. Grand total $ 1 S;il;iiir&gt; ami w. old include sal. or dirt I any. 2. Clothing include* o materials for clothing and shoes if t! manufactured in the institut 4. Ordinary repairs include all of those which simply a tain the buildings in condition without adding toll. Any repairs which are of the nature of additions should be classed with "permanent improvements." 5. This item inelu. rything not otherwise proi lot furniture, bedding, laundry luppliet cines, engineer's supplies, postage, freight, library, etc. Executive h' perintendent, warden or other title) Super- intendent. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>