<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00011">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00011</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
		             <date value="1903">1903</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
B U L.L.C1 1 1.N NO. 76. 

The University of Nebraska. 

BULLETIN 

OP THE 

AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA. 

Vol. XV, Article II. 

EXPERIMENTS WITH DAIRY HERD. 

Part I. • The Herd Record 

Part II. Ration Tests for Dairy Cows. 

Part III. The Best Week in a Cow's Lactation Period. 

Distributed Janoamy 24, 1903 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, 
U. S. A. 

By A. I,. Haecker. </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

THE HUNTS Or TMC UMIVCHSITv) 

GEO F. KENOWER, resident, Wisner 
B. v. PORELL, Kearney 

fN C. RICH. Omaha 
L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
CALKINS, Kearney 
ERNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

§ BURNETT, B. Sc., Directorand Animal Husbandman 
LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
DALES, M. PH., Financial Secretary 

WM W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist 
Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist 

S. Avbry, PH D., Chemist 

tHAECKER, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman 
ENCB Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist 
H. Barbour. Ph. D., Geologist 
Emerson, B. SC., Horticulturist 
P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
Swezet, M. A., Meteorologist 

¦ . Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman 
GAllf, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
. Perin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
EXPERIMENTS WITH DAIRY HERD. 

Part I. 

THE HERD RECORD. 

The dairy herd was founded in October, 1896, by the purchase 
of ten grade Jersey heifers. These young heifers were 
all about two years old and due to calve in the late fall and 
early winter. As but a small amount of money was set aside 
for the purchase of this herd, it was found necessary to obtain 
animals at a nominal cost, and the ten heifers were 
purchased in southern Wisconsin and delivered in Lincoln 
at |32 per head. The breeding of this herd can be described 
briefly as follows: Full-blooded Jersey sires of the same 
family were used on native stock for several generations, thus 
producing high grade Jerseys of similar breeding and type. 
Aside from the ten heifers, two animals were obtained from 
local parties and were bred differently, one being a fullblooded 
Jersey, and the other a crossbred with Jersey dam 
and Shorthorn sire. 

From the day the herd arrived at the Station, careful records 
were kept of each individual, not only as to milk and 
butter production, but also as to amount and weight of food 
consumed and weight of animal. In order to obtain accurate 
weights, the animals were weighed each Monday morning 
before being turned to water, thus avoiding variation caused 
by large and small amounts of water consumed. Each milking 
was weighed and a sample taken of the same immediately 
after milking. The milk was tested by the Babcock method, 
and each week's production was recorded as a separate unit 
in the record book. Under this method it was possible to 
obtain a weekly balance as to the cow's performance and her 
condition. 

During the five years covered by the records, many changes 

BULL. 76, AGR. BXP. STATION OF NEBS. VOL. XV, AST. IL </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 

Experiments xcith Dairy Herd. 

were made in the herd as new animals were purchased and 
some of the old ones sold. Different breeds and grades were 
introduced, but jiot with the intent to carry on a breed experiment. 
However, the aim was to select representative 
specimens of each class. 

In the following tables a year constitutes a lactation period 
within the limits of twelve consecutive months after the 
cow's calving. The amount of "estimated" butter is determined 
from the butter fat by adding the regular one sixth 
overrun to the butter fat In order to avoid a great number 
of figures, the entire record of each member of the herd is 
condensed and the totals for the year are given. 

'ablb 

r eu 

recoi 

tn mi. 

r or ft 

i7- 

Name of Cow. 

Milk. 

Fat 

Butter. 

Breed of Cow. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

SS*.::::::::::::::: 
Diana 
Eloise 
Gertie 
Hattie 
Io 
Juno 
££::::::::::::::: 

6977.25 
8073.82 
5357.92 
6172.66 
5169.35 
5784.80 
4742.68 
5213.08 
6734.70 
8074.22 

313.39 
352.32 
267. 5M 
293.43 
254.83 
273.79 
208.47 
238.58 
247.09 
473.24 

365.62 
411.04 
312.19 
342.32 
297.30 
319.42 
243.21 
278.34 
288.27 
552.11 

Grade Terser. 
41 «&lt; 

M &lt;c 

k «t 

M II 

II It 

II II 

II II 

Shorthorn-Jersey cross. 
Jersey. 

11300.38 

2922.73 

3409.82 

6130.04 

292.27 

340.98 

Ethe members of the herd in the yej 
their first calf, except the Jersey a 
years old and with her second call </seg>
            <seg id="p005">
r 1897 were heifers 
&gt;w Ruth which was 

r 


Expenmcr, 

4s with 

Dairy Herd. 

Table II.— Herd re, 

:ord in m 

ilk and butter for 1898. 

Name of Cow. 

Milk. 

Fat. 

Butter. 

Breed of Cow. 

- 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Annie 6907.19 
Be* 7528 30 
Cora 7302.15 
Diana B536.70 
Eloise 6912.10 
Gertie 5584.81 
Hattie 5627.45 
Io 5702.56 
Jnno 6711.36 
Mabel 7635.21 
Ruth 6385.69 

0907.19 
7528.30 
7302.15 
6536.70 
6912.10 
5584.81 
5527.45 
5702.56 
6711.36 
7535.21 
6385.69 

314.64 
373.78 
313.26 
3U8.51 
337.23 
284.26 
268.56 
269.52 
259.53 
329 12 
409.73 

367.03 
436.08 
305.47 
383.26 
393.44 
331.64 
313.32 
302.77 
302.78 
383.98 
478.02 

Grade Jersey. 

.. .. 

- " 

1 1 «i 

(4 tl 

• I (I 

Shorthorn-Jersey ci'OM. 
Jersey. 

Total 71633.52 

71(33.52 

3478.14 

4057.84 

Average 6512.14 

6512.14 

316.19 

368-9 

I , 

The record for 1898 sh 
five years' tests. This ca: 
able condition of the hei 
lactation and in the best &lt; 

1OWS th( 

n be ex] 
rd. Th 
t&gt;f healt 

best average of any in the 
Gained largely by the favor- 
;y were all in tbeir second 
i, while they received rather 

heavy rations during th&lt; 

; wintei 

• 

Table III.— Herd r 

ecord in &gt; 

ii/k and butter for i8gg. 

'/&lt; t\ 

Name of Cow. 

Milk. 

Fat. 

Butter. 

Breed of Cow. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

cr e .:::::::::::::::: 
Diana 2d 
Eloise 
Fannie 2&lt;1 
Hattie 
Jnno 2d 
Katbeleta 
Lill 
Mabel 
Mabel 2d 
Olive 
Ruth 3d 
** • 

5250.39 
7(i99.52 
4971.66 
5529.47 
O8B.se 
6936.74 
1278.76 
3977.25 
4407.47 
6964.86 
3446.74 
3668.55 
3402.92 
4332.99 

251.85 
295.92 
261.10 
251.49 
246.29 
329.53 
52.77 
138.65 
159.37 
310.10 
171.66 
134.21 
210.58 
150.93 

293.82 
345.24 
304.62 
293.40 
287.34 
384.46 
61.55 
161.74 
185.93 
361.78 
200.26 
156.58 
316.67 
176.07 

Jersey grade. 

¦ ) «i 

it it 

Hereford grade. 
Shorthorn grade. 
Jersey-Shorthorn cross. 
Jersey-Shorthorn cross. 
Hereford grade. 
Jersey grade. 
Hereford grade. 

65446.18 

2964.45 

3458.46 

4674.73 

211.74 

247.03 </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

Experiments vcith Dairy Herd. 

During 1899 many changes were made in the herd, as, the 
introduction of new cows and the disposition of some of the 
original animals. The cows Katheleta, Lill, Olive, and Sady 
were range cattle obtained in western Nebraska and had 
not only beef breeding, but a natural tendency to fatten when 

The herd made its poorest record this year as a result of 
the above animals and the cow Juno 2d, which made a very 
poor yearly record. 

The cows Annie, Eloise, and Fannie 2d aborted at seveu 
months, which also caused a shrinkage in their records. 

ABLE 

W 

ret 

vr, 

in m 

lift, 

'er for /goo. 

Name of Cow. 

Milk. 

Fat. 

Butter. 

Breed of Cow. 

Pounds. 

Pound'. 

Pounds. 

Diamond 
Diana 2d 
Hattie 
Mabel 
Nymph 
Ruth3d 

7088.90 
2772.25 
2447.36 
5963.23 
7779.70 
5062.96 
4546.38 

298.68 
157.78 
142.32 
265.46 
318.60 
253.33 
240.54 

348.46 
184.08 
166.01 
309.66 
371.70 
295.55 
280.57 

Jersey grade. 
Jersey. 
Grade Jersey. 
" 

Shorthorn- Jersey cross. 
Jersey. 

35660.78 

1676.71 

1956.03 

5094.39 

239.44 

279.35 

Through lack oi 

' barn room the herd was greatly reduced 

in 1900, and but 
obtained. 

seven complete yearly records were 

The cowb Diam 
which made it nee 
calving. 

ond and Diana 2d were in poor health, 
essary to dry them off at six months after 


during this year, giving 9,419.10 pounds of milk in eight 

Experiments with 

Dairy j 

lerd. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">
7 

Table V. — Herd record in m 

;/* and it 

\tterfor igoi 

• 

Name of Cow. 

Milk. 

Fat. 

Butter. 

Breed of Cow. 

founds. 

Pounds. 

Ptmnds. 

Bessie McKinley 
Diamond 
Diana 2d 
Hattie 
Mabel 
Maude 
Ruth 3d 
Snowflake 
Whitelick 

8518.90 
7319 00 
7065.10 
5434.10 
eaB.n 
'.Ml UU 
9789.20 
7481.20 
3380.80 
4048.23 

292.37 
321.10 
373.44 
28S.54 
309.17 
402.50 
332.54 
294.98 
179.61 
231.13 

341.10 
374.61 
435.66 
336.63 
360.70 
4 9.58 
387.96 
348.81 
209.54 
269 65 

Holstein-Friesian. 
Grade Jersey. 
Jersey. 
Grade Jersey. 

Shorthorn-Jersey cross. 
Holstein-Friesian . 
Jersey. 

•• 

69284.13 

3029.38 

3334.29 

6928.41 

302.94 

.•15.T43 

In the year 1901, two Holstei 

n-Friesia 

in cows were added 

Ps herd — Bessie McKinley, 
ears old with her first calf, 
welve years old failed to be 

live yea; 

rs old, and Maude, 
•w Snowflake which 

. The cc 

; a profit; 

able producer. Ma- 
ide her best record 

Ik?1. the crossbred Shorthoru-Je 

xsey, ma 

ABLE VI.— 

Ot 

an 

average p, 

'O., 

'ion 

&lt;trt 

'•IS 

it years. 

¦ 
. a 

a s 
— T3 
I 2 

s . 

t-2 
H 

n 

h 

if 

h\ 

1901 10 

Pounds. " Pounds. 

P, unds. 

Pound*. 

Pounds. 

61300.38 6130.04 
71633.52 6512.14 
65446.18 4674.73 
35660.78 5094.39 
69284.13 6928.41 

2927.73 
3478.14 
2HC54.45 
1676.71 
3029.38 

292.27 
316.19 
211.74 
239.44 
302.94 

3409.82 
4067.85 
3458.46 
1906.03 
3534.29 

340 96 
368 89 
247.03 
279.35 
353.43 

Average of 52 
yearly records . . 

5833.17 .. 

270.70 

315. 83 

i 

ied from this heri 

are not abnormal and </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 

Experiments tcith Dairy Herd. 

can be equaled if not surpassed by any farmer or dairyman 
in Nebraska. No effort was made to crowd or force any ani 
nial to a high record, but on the contrary they were fed light 
rations, and, very often to their disadvantage, were changed 
suddenly from one feed to another as the character of the 
feeding experiment might demand. The young stock were 
principally disposed of in the form of veal, but exceptional 
heifers from some of the best cows wore saved. It will be 
seen from Table VI that the average of fifty-two yearly records 
was as follows: 

This includes an average 
which contained both good 

of «11 the members of the herd, 
and poor producers. It might 

Erefore be interesting as well as instructive to single out a 
• of the members that made the best records and also 
ers that made the poorest records. 

CORA. 

[ilk I 
iutter fat 

5,833.17 poun 
270.70 " 
315.82 " </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
Experiments xcith Dairy Herd. 

9 

TABr.K VII —Record of the cow Cora, a high grade Jersey 

Year 

Milk. Butter fat 

Butter 

The cow Cora was born November 1, 1894, which makes 
her eight years old this fall, and it is safe to say she is in 
her prime. She came fresh August 6 and is now giving 
eight pounds butter fat per week. Cora is a small cow 

now 

weighing on an average 725 pounds and is a most economical 
butter producer. A good example of type is shown by contrasting 
the cow Cora with Juno 2d, a cow of similar breeding 
but very different in form. Cora is wedge-shaped as 
viewed from side and top, and has a deep, well-developed 
barrel, but at the same time light shoulders and withers. 
On the other hand, Juno is steer-like in build, with heavy 
shoulders, and is narrow through barrel. 

The mammary glands, especially the milk veins, in the 
cow Cora are exceptionally well developed, branching in several 
veins before they enter the abdominal wall. She has 
light bone and is fine in quality, perhaps too much so, for 
she has difficulty in holding her own in the herd, being timid 
and averse to fighting. She has been a regular breeder, 
dropping a healthy calf every year from the time she was 
two years old, and keeping in the best of health. She is no 
doubt a very profitable cow and will probably continue to be 
so for some years to come. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Total 
Average 

8073.82 
r. 7307.15 
7099.52 
7088.90 
7319.00 
36P88.39 
7377.68 

352.32 
313.26 
296.92 
298.68 
321.10 

365.47 
345.24 
348.46 
374.61 

1581.28 

1841.82 

sM.a 

368.96 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 

Experiments with Dairy Herd. 

HATTIK. 

Table VIII. —Record of Ihr cow Hattie, a high 

grade Jersey. 

Year. 

Milk. 

Butter fat. 

Butter. 

Pcow Hattie is bred very much tl 
little Holstein-Friesian blood seve 
which accounts for her black and white 

same as Cora, but 
1 generations back, 

the 

several 

color. 

She is a little 

more nigged than Cora and is coarser of bone, but has much 
the same type. Hattie weighs on an average about 750 
pounds. She is also in her prime and is making her best 
record this year. 

Pounds. 

winds. 

¦bunds. 

1897 6784.80 
L896 5527.45 
L899 6836.74 
LflOO 5«63.23 
L901 6828.50 

273.79 
268.56 
329.53 
265.46 
308.17 

319.42 
313.32 
384- 46 
309.66 
360.70 

Total 31040.72 

1446.51 

Average 6206.14 

289.30 

337.51 </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

MABEL. 

She has the best five-year record of any cow in the herd 
M may be seen by a comparison of the tables, giving her highest 
yield in 1901. She is at the present time giving a large 
flow" and promises to make her best record this year. 

Table IX. — Record of the cow Mabet 

', a cross* 

&lt;rc- 

'ersey-. 

\om. 

Year. 

Milk. 

Butter fat. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

5734.70 
7535 21 
eau m 
7779.70 
9419.10 

247.09 
329.12 
310.10 
318.60 
402.50 

288.27 
383.98 
361.7:* 
371.70 
469.58 

37423.57 

1607.41 

1875.31 

7484.71 

321.48 

375.06 

Mabel shows her Shorthorn 

ing about 950 pounds and ha 
gives a rich flow of milk, in tl 

blood in size and color, weigh- 
ing a dark red color, but she 
is respect resembling the Jer- 

soy. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
gaperiimeuU with Dairy Herd. 

12 

JUNO 2D. 

Table X. — Recordof the cow Juno id, a grade Jersey. 

Year 

Milk. Butter fat. Butter. 

Pounds. Pounds. Pounds. 
1278.76 52.77 61.65 


Ecow Juno 2d makes a contrast to the other animals 
, but offers a good example of poor type for dairy pur- 

Dairymen, look out for the Juno 2ds! They are expensive 
to keep and worse to breed from. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
Experiments icith Dairy Herd. 

13 

Ehere. This cow had a fine dairy type and large ca. 
She unfortunately died after her second year and we 
it in possession of her picture. * 

'able y 

'ecort 

if cow 

, a 

'erst 

Year. 

Milk. 

Butter fat. 

Butter. 

Pounds. 
8074.22 
6385.69 

Pounds. 

473.24 
409.73 

s a 

14459.91 

144.7.1.91 

882.97 

1020.13 

— ¦ 

7229.95 

441.48 

51008 

As the record of the cow Ruth is exce 

itionall 

nod, it is </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

Experiments with Dairy Herd. 

Part II. 

RATION TESTS FOR DAIRY COWS. 

During the past few years the dairy industry has received 
much attention throughout the entire State, and in western 
counties where but a few years ago dairying was practiced 
to a very limited degree we now find a progressive enterprise. 
This condition has no doubt been greatly stimulated 
by the establishment of markets for both milk and cream. 
Through the development of the skimming stations and the 
hand-separator sysfeni, milk, and especially cream, can be 
marketed as a farm product at nearly any railway depot in 
the State. With the increased interest in dairy husbandry, 
much information has been called for regarding native foods 
and the feeding of them to dairy cows. 

ALFALFA VS. WILD HAV. 

P'he chief grasses used for hay in the State are alfalfa and 
irie or wild grass. These are generally fed as roughness 
the feeding seasons and many farmers either have an 
abundance of each kind or can obtain them with little difficulty. 
The question as to which hay is the best for milk and 
butter production is therefore an important one to dairy - 

PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT 

On January 1, 1902, after the dairy herd had been on dry 
feed for eight weeks and were in a normal feeding condition, 
twelve cows were selected and divided into two lots. In 
making the division, care was taken to have each lot about 
equal as to their production of milk and butter fat. 

P,ot I was put on a ration of alfalfa hay and Lot II on 
i hay. Besides all the hay they would eat up clean, each 
received 16 pounds of beets daily and a small grain ration 
me-half bran and one-half corn by weight. 

i \|-|rt 1 r\f" yfto f f*f\ *1 1 f '1 1 f '\ SlYl(\ t ll (* Ot ll f*T* U'j \t\ \\i\ V tl\l* SI V </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
15 

weeks and then changed about, Lot I getting wild hay and 
Ix)t II alfalfa for another period of six weeks. 

RESULTS. 

At the end of twelve weeks the experiment was closed 
with the following results: 

Table XII. — Alfalfa vs. wild hay for dairy cows. 

Period I. 

Lot I. Six cows fed on alfalfa hay for six weeks 
Lot II. Six cows fed on wild hay for six weeks. 

Difference in favor of alfalfa hay 
Period II. 

¦ Fed wild hay for six weeks . . 
Fed alfalfa hay for six weeks. 

Difference in favor of alfalfa. 

tl. I/Ost in changing from alfalfa to wild hay 
II. Lost in changing from wild hay to alfalfa 

Difference in favor of alfalfa. 

Lots I and II when fed alfalfa hay produced: 
Lot I. First six weeks 

Lot II. Second six weeks 

Twelve cows produced in twelve weeks. 

Lots I and II when fed wild hay produced: 
Lot II. First six weeks 

Lot I. Second six weeks. 

Twelve cows produced in twelve weeks. 
DiftVrence in tavor of alfalfa hay 

Eie decrease of milk and butter pra 
veeks of the test was largely due 1 
from advance in lactation, but it 
hrinkage was greater when wild h 

When Lot II was changed from wild hay to alfalfa in the 
starting of the second six weeks, they were at a disadvantage, 
having been reduced in the first six-weeks test. It is 

Milk 
produced. 

Butter 
produced. 

*ks. 
:ks.. 

Pounds. 
5062.40 
4l«2.20 

Pounds. 
260.75 

120.11 

f 

4760.20 
4780.34 

«... 
243.12 

20.14 

,„ 

lay. 
Ufa. 

322.20 
221.95 

a 

100.25 

9.40 

d: 

508-2.40 
4780.34 

« 

98d2.74 

""¦ 

4982.29 
4760.20 

» 

9722.49 
140.25 

pnx 

ue t 
t it 
Id h 

luction in the second 
o the natural shrink- 
will be noticed that 

ty was fed. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
Experiments icith Dairy Herd. 

16 

therefore safe to assume that alfalfa gave even better results 
than is shown in the above tables. 

Elie quality of both alfalfa and wild hay was of the best, 
latter being exceptionally fine as a result of the dry 
Bon of 1901. The animals in both lots had free access to 
ter and salt during the experiment. 

It required a little more wild hay than alfalfa hay. This 
was due to the larger per cent of waste in the former. 

In live weight the animals changed but slightly, showing 
a slight increase when on alfalfa. 

P conclusion, it is evident from the results of the experithat 
normally cured alfalfa hay is more conducive to 
and butter production than wild hay. 

CORN ENSILAGE VS. SUGAR BEETS. 

It is well known among feeders of dairy cattle that green 
or succulent feed is favorable to milk secretion, and a suitable 
substitute for grass during the winter season is an important 
factor in the ration. 

Corn silage and beete are the most common crops used as 
succulent food stuffs during the feeding period, and to find 
if possible the comparative value of the two was the aim of 
the experiment 

In the winter of 1897, after the herd had been on dry feed 
for four weeks, they were divided into two lots, of five in 
each, the lots being about equal as to milk and butter pro- 

Lot I was given 30 pounds of sugar beets per day, while 
Lot II received the same amount of corn silage. The balance 
of the ration was composed of 10 pounds alfalfa hay 
with a grain ration made up of two parts oats, two parts 
corn, and two parts wheat bran, and was fed according to 
the capacities of the cows, ranging from six to ten pounds 
per day. </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
Period I, which was the result of the five weeks before the 
test started. 

Keriod II, which comprised the time covered by the test, 
ral shrinkage took place in both lots, due to advancen 
lactation. Lot I, it will be seen, produced a little 
more milk and butter fat than Lot II, but only a very little 
more compared with the time required and number of animals 
used. This test, then, shows a slight difference in favor 
of corn ensilage, Lot I producing 92.20 pounds milk and 
5.02 pounds butter more than Lot II, the beet fed lot. 

This difference might be accounted for by the variation in 
the individual animals through the many conditions that 
affect dairy cows. The test, however, was made during very 
favorable conditions of weather and good health of all the 
animals in the test. The herd was uncommonly uniform, 
all being two-year-old heifers with their first calf. 

Pto the quality of the food given, the sugar beets were 
rage grade, while the corn silage was good, all mouldy 
r top silage being rejected and only the good ensilage 

As to the relative cost of production corn ensilage is cer- 

Experiments with Dai, 

ryHerc 

Table XIII.— Results of five weeks' feeding test w 

&lt;itk sugar 

Milk. 

Butter 
fat. 

Butter. 

Period I. 
iot I. Production of five cows for five weeks 
before test when fed on ensilage 
Lot II. Production of five cows for five weeks 
before test when fed on ensilage .... 

Pounds. 

3212.50 

Pounds. 

154.30 

Pounds. 

180.01 

3083.30 

148.60 

173.37 

Difference in favor of Lot I 

129.20 

5.70 

6.64 

Period II. 

3040.60 
2819.20 

147.20 
137.20 

171.73 
160.07 

tl. Five weeks on ensilage 
II. Five weeks on sugar beeti 

Difference in favor of Lot I 
Difference between Lots I and II, I eriod I ... 

221.40 
12!*. 20 

10.00 
5.70 

11.66 
6.64 

Difference in favor of ensilage 

92.20 

4.30 

5.US 

I 

In forming the two lots, it was imp 

losaible to divide them 
ind butter fat produc- 

&amp;o that they would be equal in milk a 
tion. It was therefore thought advis; 

able to give record of </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
Experiments uith Dairy Herd. 

18 

tainly much cheaper than sugar beets, but the former requires 
expensive machinery for cutting and a silo for storing, while 
sugar beets need only be put in a place where they will not 
freeze. Ensilage will keep until fresh grass comes in the 
spring, while it is difficult to keep sugar beets after the last 
of March. 

While corn ensilage gave slightly better results than sugar 
beets when fed to dairy cows, the difference was so small 
that it is safe to say they are quite equal in feeding value. 

CONCLUSION. </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
Experiments uitli Dairy Herd. 

19 

Part III. 

THE BEST WEEK IN A COWS LACTATION PERIOD. 

tit is often of much importance to know at what time in a 
w's lactation she is liable to make her best record. Nearly 
all of the associations of our improved dairy breeds favor 
the animals making large milk or butter records. In some 
cases certain fixed standards are set, as, for example, in the 
American Jersey Cattle Club Association where fourteen 
pounds or over of butter is required to admit animals to 
what is known as the "tested list." 

In looking over the herd records, it was found that a great 
variation existed as to the best week of lactation. This variation 
was not only among certain individual cows but it also 
existed with the same cow from year to year. 

In order to get reliable data it was quite evident a large 
number of records would be required to overcome the varying 
influence and find a fair average. Minnesota Experi 
ment Station was therefore called on to co-operate with the 
Nebraska Station, and they were able to furnish 155 records. 
This, combined with 84 records from the Nebraska Station, 
gave a total of 239. Out of this large number of carefully 
compiled records the following table and results are drawn. 

It was found that nine-tenths of the cows made their best 
records during the first ten weeks of lactation and that over 
one-half made their best records during the first month. 

The first week is calculated beginning four days after calving, 
thus making the end of the first week eleven days after </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
01 

ex 

I 

5 

I 

A 

? 

I 

o 
CJ 

1 

•? 

&gt; 

•4 

* % » j jj 

3 

r» •• « 5 -~i 

00 

h 

-c 

ecr'WN 

«6 </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
21 

It will be seen from this table that the greatest number 
of cows on experiment made their best milk flow the third 
week, while the best butter production was made in the 
second week. 

CONCLUSIONS. 

From the results obtained in this test, which bid fair to be 
average, the second and third weeks of a cow's lactation are 
the best, and there is not much difference between the two. 

A cow reaches her highest production of butter fat at an 
earlier period than she does her greatest milk flow. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>