<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Cause and Prevention of Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes</title>
               <date value="1931-08">1931-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 260 August, 1931 The Cause and Prevention of Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes H. O. WERNER Department of Horticulture t ~~ ~ &gt;,n isjßkS^r nSjan - "f • ' *-, ityv'l lemO" |K|JH iglv^^ ~ i^M^SjWbSS^WC'V. g*[jgj^gr.. .v^^||p^V4SSJg-Mgjgj ggeaj Largfj i mT-gg° : . 4^ "^fr-**?- w' " fl filnfit""*" "*"-" " ■, Handling Potatoes by the Half-sack Method on a Large Potato Farm in Western Nebraska THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">I CONTENTS Inti-oduction . .j Types of Mechanical Injuries " 3 Losses from Mechanical Injuries..' . .1 Factors Affecting Occurrence of Mechanical Injury in Commercial Fields : ... ". -, Studies of Factors That Affect Susceptibility to Injury 7 Variety and strain difference? g Maturity as a factor influencing tuber injury ■. S Rate of tuber growth as a factor influencing. tuber cracking 11 Effect of exposure to air immediately after harvesting upon tuber cracking ( Tuber size as a factor affecting cracking M Susceptibility of various portions of a tube:- to cracking ir&gt; Depth of planting as it affects the cutting of potatoes at digging time &#132; ; Miscellaneous factors influencing mechanical injury IG Studies of the Causes of Injuries 17 Cracking caused in digging J7 Cracking caused in picking „ ; t _ jp Pouring the potatoes from the picking basket into a sack... "."...21 The Wound Healing Process in Potatoes 00 Factors affecting the development of the protective cove£ing!...l";.22 The effect of hot formaldehyde on wound healing and «torage quality &#132;..; „., Discussion and Recommendations &#132; Maturity of vines or tubers ."r Soil and cultural conditions ; ',- The potato digging machine gfi Potato picking opei-ations 7 yi) Handling potatoes from field to storage cellar 30 Tuber infection at harvest time .' V . J4 Management of the storage cellar -. *, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Cause and Prevention of Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes H. 0. WERNER Department of Horticulture Mechanically injured potatoes amounted to 31.1, 16.0, and 16.6 pei- cent, respectively, of all potatoes in the bins of cer - tified seed potato growers in 1928, 1929, and 1930, according to the inspection reports of the Nebraska Certified Potato Growers Cooperative. These reports are based on inspections of from 174 to 304 lots of Triumph potatoes each year. These potatoes had received no sorting other than the discarding of badly injured potatoes by the pickers. Each year these mechanically injured potatoes constituted approximately 67 per cent of all the potatoes that were discarded in prepar - ing certified seed potatoes for shipment as U. S. No. 1 grade stock. On the basis of the percentages reported above and the annual car-lot shipments reported by the U. S. Depart - ment of Agriculture, it is safe to estimate that the total amount of Nebraska-grown potatoes that were damaged too much for shipment as U. S. No. 1 grade amounted to about 2,?&gt;80, 910, and 1,820 cars respectively during these three years. Many of these potatoes were marketable, but at a reduced price as No. 2 grade stock. A conservative estimate would place the money loss due to mechanical injury to west - ern Nebraska potatoes at not less than $200,000 annually. Mechanically injured tubers are undesirable because of the direct loss they cause in preparing potatoes for the table and because of increasing shrinkage, rot, and other losses, which are discussed later. TYPES OF MECHANICAL INJURIES Injuries are generally spoken of as cuts, cracks, bruising, and feathering. Of these, cuts are the most apparent and cracks and bruises probably the most serious. Probably all except surface cuts are more serious than most growers realize. What appears to be only a simple, shallow bruise caused by a short drop on a digger rod or a slight cut from a picking-basket wire is actually a mass of badly torn and crushed tissues with several to a number of internal cracks radiating in many directions (see Figure 1). Cracks of the type produced by a mechanical shock at digging time are much deeper and frequently longer than casual observers suspect. Measurements of cracks in a number of Triumph potatoes revealed that cracks %, 1, 114, and 2 inches long were respectively %, l/fc, % and V-i to % of an inch deep. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 ' ■ Fig. 1. — Types of injury as they appear under the microscope. Cut A was made by a small wire on a picking basket (see Fig. 8 at left) • B was made by the top ring of a picking basket; C was made bv falling on a digger rod; and D was caused by a fall on a flat iron surface. These views show condition after one week. • All were much more extensive than they appeared on the outside. The tension forces within a potato increase the size of the crevice after the skin is broken. This increase in the width of cracks has been found to continue for from 3 to 10 days m a dry atmosphere, after which the cracks partly close up because of water loss and reduced tension accompanying the shrinkage. The width of cracks increases very little in a moist atmosphere. An interesting fact observed was that cracks spread to a greater extent at the bud (apical) end than at the stem end of a potato. LOSSES FROM MECHANICAL INJURIES Mechanical injuries are responsible for many losses other than those which are very obvious when preparing injured potatoes for table use. Immediately after being injured potatoes lose weight unusually fast because of more rapid evaporation from the injured surface and more rapid res - piration. As the wounded surfaces heal, weight losses from both of these causes decrease until they are no greater than from normal tubers. In an experiment in 1930 it was found that in a moist atmosphere one set of potatoes with long, deep cracks lost only 0.5 per cent of their </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes weight in two weeks, in comparison with a loss of 6 2 per cent in the set held in a dry atmosphere. With severely in - jured potatoes the large amount of carbon dioxide and heat liberated while potatoes are respiring rapidly may be injuri - ous because of retardation of healing processes, thus provid - ing more favorable conditions for disease infection and in - ducing abnormal sprouting habits. ; Probably the most serious loss resulting from mechanical injuries is the rotting caused by various organisms (fungi and bacteria) which gain entrance to the potato only through these injuries. Such organisms are unable to penetrate the unbroken skin. One of the most common of these organisms is the one causing most of the- dry rot in western Nebraska potatoes. 1 If the injury heals quickly and completely the entrance of these organisms may be prevented. Sometimes conditions are more favorable for the organisms than for the wound-healing process, in which case infection occurs The amount of damage done thereafter will depend upon the tem - perature and other atmospheric conditions of the storage place. The relatively slow healing of cracks renders them especially dangerous as sources of rot infection. FACTORS AFFECTING OCCURRENCE OF MECHANICAL INJURY IN COMMERCIAL FIELDS Soil and climatic conditions materially affect the amount ot mechanical injury done to potatoes handled by commercial methods. When the soil is hard and dry at digging time, as it was in 1928, less cracking occurs than usually, but the bl-uising from digger rods and clods is very much greater. In Scotts Bluff and Morrill counties in 1928 the percentage ot injured tubers was low because this condition was avoided by proper irrigation,' while the low percentage in Box Butte county was due to a rain which occurred at the opening of J£? o£^ inff season &gt; thus improving soil conditions (Table 1) ine 39.6 per cent loss in Kimball county was due to a com - pact cloddy soil at digging time, which in turn was the result o± driving rains during the growing season and dry weather preceding and during the digging season. In 1929 and 1930 the soil was moist at digging time and the potatoes were more tender than in 1928. Less dam - age was done, however, because the moist dirt adhering to the digger rods acted as a protective cushion. In 1929 in Kimball, Banner, Scotts Bluff, and Morrill counties the per - centage of injured tubers was low because low temperatures accompanying an early September snowstorm killed the vines ' Fuaarium trlcholhccioidcs. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 Table 1. — Mean percentage (weighted) of cut and cracked tubers produced in certified Triumph seed-potato fields in western Nebraska, during three different years County 1928 I 1929 1930 : ; 1 l_ j Percent Percent I Percent Box Butte ...., [• 20.5 17.2 ; 18.5 Sheridan 28.6 18.9 ! 9.1 Dawes ". 31.3 22.2 19.7 Sioux 34.6 18.9 19.4 Kimball and Banner 39.6 10.5 13.6 Scottsbluff and Mori-ill 22.7 9.6 19.8 All counties—^-weighted mean percentage | 31.1 16.0 1G.6 j Bushels | Bushels Bushels Total cut and cracked tubers .-.„ 85,570 i 110,324 j 179.961 . and permitted greater ripening of the tubers than occurred in the other counties. In the counties where the vines were not killed at this time tuber growth was greatly stimulated. The low percentage of damaged tubers in Sheridan county in 1930 was largely due to early maturity of the vines as a result of a rainfall shortage during the end of the grow - ing season. Although the complete elimination of mechanical injury might seem impossible, much of it can be prevented as has already been done by some growers. Referring again to data from certified seed inspections, we find that in 1928 2.6 per cent of the lots had less than 5 per cent of damaged stock, while in 12.3 per cent of the lots' over 50 per cent of the tubers had been mechanically injured (Table 2). While the mechanically injured potatoes were le.ss prev - alent in 1929 and 1930, the general variation in percentage of fields with different percentages of damaged tubers was about the same as in 1928. ' Table 2. — Distribution of certified seed-potato lots accord - ing to the percentage of mechanically injured tubers found in each lot during the bin inspection i ~ ■ Number Percentage of lota in whioh the mechanically injured Weighted Crop of lots potatoes fell within given percentage ranees annual season I inspected | 1 to | 6 to I 11 to 21 to |~31 to I 41 to rsf~to I mean ! | 57c ■ i lOTr I 20 1 :; :i0^ | 40*-; | BO'; | 8Q&lt;&gt; | Vl -rcent 1928 174 2.6 6.7 17.5 24.2 18.0 18.6 12.3 I 31.1 1929 311 10.3 13.2 47.8 20.2 8.0 0.4 16.0 I" 3 " 271 S.7 I 21.0 45.5 15.1 9.6 1.5 0.7 16.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes While local soil and climatic conditions had much to do with this variation in percentage of injury, they were by no means the sole cause, the methods of handling used by the growers having been important factors. Extreme differences were observed in the same communities every year. It is inter - esting to note that in each of the three years the percentage of mechanically injured tubers generally decreased as the number of bushels in the field or lot increased. With the 1930 crop only 25.1 per cent of the lots of less than 4,000 bushels contained less than 10 per cent of mechanically injured tubers in contrast to 55.5 per cent of the lots of more than 8,000 bushels (Table 3). Of the lots consisting of less Table 3. — Relation betiveeri number of bushels of potatoes produced in a lot and the percentage tJiat were mechan - . ically injured in the 1930 crop | Percentage of lots in which mechanically Total bushels No. injured potatoes fell within given produced in of | . percentage range - lot concerned | lots | l to 10% | 11 to 20% | 21 to 40% | 41 to 60 % Percent Percent Percent I Percent 100 to 4,000 18T 25.1 45.5 26.2 3.2 4,001 to • 8,000 6G 27.3 50.0 22.7 8,001 to 35,000 1 18 55.5 2TL&amp; 16^7 .... All lots 271 27.7 45J5 24/7 1.8 than 4,000 bushels, 29.4 per cent had more than 21 per cent of mechanically injured potatoes in comparison with only 16.7 per cent for the lots of over 8,000 bushels. Better equipment, more experience, and more intelligent management probably had much to do with the production of these differences. STUDIES OF FACTORS THAT AFFECT SUSCEPTIBILITY TO INJURY In order to determine where and how most injury occurs and also how conditions affect the susceptibility of the pota - toes to injury, especially to cracking, a number of tests were made in September and October, 1930, with potatoes of different degrees of. maturity. Potatoes were tested individually by two general methods. By one method the potato was dropped a given distance on various kinds of surfaces. By this method, because of differ - ences in weight, each tuber was tested with a different force. To eliminate this error, what is designated as a standard </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 shock test was also used in 1930. A rod 0.4 inch in diameter and weighing about 3.5 ounces, was dropped on potatoes from a height of 9l/ 2 inches. 1 This is called test No. 1. If this test shock caused a crack, the length of it was recorded and if it did not produce any cracks the potato was subjected to test No. 2, in which this same rod was dropped 19 inches. The most severe shock used, No. 3, consisted of dropping a 7-ounce weight a distance of 19 inches. Data were also secured con - cerning the total amount of injured potatoes occurring in various experimental lots when the harvesting procedure was the same. VARIETY AND STRAIN DIFFERENCES When potatoes from green vines of the same age were sub - jected to the standard shock test about four times moi-e Triumph than Irish Cobbler potatoes were cracked and the severity of the cracks (as measured by number and length of cracks in the tubers tested) was about nine times greater with the Triumphs. When large areas of each variety were harvested com - mercially in an irrigated lield at North Platte in 1929 and 1930, the average percentage of potatoes cut during both years was 1.74 per cent with the Irish Cobbler and 4.28 per cent with the Triumph. When stored for a few days most of the cut surfaces of the Triumph potatoes were infected with rot, whereas most of those of. the Cobblers were healing very nicely. These differences, greater susceptibility to cracking, greater liability to cutting in digging, and slower healing of injuries, are serious shortcomings of the Triumph variety. In 1930 the percentage of potatoes cracked in harvesting amounted to 9 per cent with one strain in comparison with 20 per cent from another strain grown in the same experi - mental block. Similar differences were observed but not so definitely recorded in 1929. The principal difference between these strains was the length of the period of growth (See page 11.) MATURITY AS A FACTOR INFLUENCING TUBER INJURY Maturity of potato tubers is a somewhat intangible or in - definite condition rather difficult to evaluate. Potatoes grown on the same plant are not necessarily equally mature when considered physiologically. Although all tubers on one plant are set on at about the same time, the growth of some of these is more or less completely checked quite early in the 1 Rod weighing 100 grams dropped 25 centimeters. ....... </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes season, while others continue to increase in size. Large size is therefore not an index of tuber maturity but may more frequently indicate a greater rather than a lesser degree of immaturity. Immature tubers differ from more mature tubers in containing a higher percentage of water and sugar, in having a higher internal pressure, and in containing a lower percentage of starch and protein and a skin less per - fectly developed and less suberized. For the purpose of this discussion, mature potatoes are con - sidered to be those which were probably not increasing in size when harvested from vines that were dead or practically so and immature tubers those that were very probably still expanding and were harvested from green or partly green vines. Maturity differences due to time of planting. — In 1930 large quantities of commercially dug potatoes were sorted from several lots differing in maturity. It was found quite gen - erally that with all strains the percentage of potatoes that were both cracked or cut in digging increased with the de - gree of immaturity, as caused by late planting (Table 4). When the potatoes injured in digging and picking amount to from 6 to 15 times more from late than from early plantings, as in this case, it is quite evident that growers might be able to reduce some of their grading difficulties by altering the planting date. When potatoes from different planting dates were subjected to the standard shock test immediately after digging, both the percentage of tubers by the lighter tests and the severity of the cracks generally increased considerably as planting Ah TOmC t-CNOTH Of CeACATS //V t .so i /oo /so B t/ov* / — — — — i^f^^M MMBgai^!; /" s/u/v£ / 7 HHHHH^IHHH HHHHHHHflME """'^IMfflffl/W* 00 *^ v/a Pee Ce/vr or Total Weionr a- Tuoe*s Tesrco so ■ao eo bo 7 /y.«&gt;*£g)BMMBB^&lt;&gt;4' &gt;wtmw&lt;&gt;MW(^^ '"7V / / / a 8 Juft / ■■■■■■■§ ■■■■■■^■■■■■■^■■■■■K lammiMuuiwv-t jo jvm/7 p— — wxgasat;s///M CKMCxeoSf &amp;3T / ■ T*3t£ m Tesr 3 m AforCe*aceD C2 Fig. 2.^Amount and severity of cracking of tubers varying in maturity because of date of planting. Standard tests applied September 17^ 1930, immediately after tubers were harvested. Similar results were obtained from lots harvested September 26 and October 3 and 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 time was delayed (Fig. 2). Even after being subjected to the most severe shocks, over 20 per cent of the tubers from May 20 plantings did not crack. Table 4. — Percentage of potatoes from different planting dates ttot were injured in harvesting in 1930 | Pounds Percentage of total weight Date planted I sorted I Cracked | Cut I ! I May 20 | 520 ■ 1.8 I 0.1 June 11 ; i 1,575 14.4 1.8 June 26 1 1,088 I 23.5 j 5.7 Maturity differences due to time of lmrvesting. — Generally the percentage of cracked and cut potatoes decreased as harvesting was delayed. In 1930 cracking in commercial harvesting was cut down from 24 per cent when dug on Potatoes Cracked or Caf /n fYarresf/ng oate &lt;?/* Toto/ W&amp;or/jf j ■ Horresfca/ ■ /p . . j?p October r Cut . o 9^. Pig. 3. — Reduction in cracking and cutting of Triumph potatoes from June 17 plantings when harvest was delayed 8 days. The vines were estimated to be 40 per cent mature on September 29 and 70 por cent on October 7. September 29 to less than 5 per cent when dug 8 days later — - on October 7 (Fig. 3). A similar difference between potatoes harvested from vines that were still green on October 3 was found when the standard test was used on three dates. Some - times, after a period of cool, damp weather, during which the potatoes grew rapidly, they actually became more rather than less tender. Such was practically the case in 1930 when Table 5. — Cracking of potatoes harvested Ion different dates in 1930 , Total length of cracks in Date tested Cracked tubers foch 100 t/ubers tested Per cent Ihichcs September 16 : 96.7 / 108 September 26 86.7 / 95 October 3 85.7 / 125 October 6 : . 60.0 j 80 Note: The test consisted of dropping a rod 0.4 ' inch in hiamctcr. wciehinR 3.5 ounces, 9V4 Inches on each potato. All potatoes were from June (27 plantinex. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes almost as many potatoes dug October 3 were found to have cracked as when dug on September 26, while the cracking was more severe than in those dug September 16 (Table 5). RATE OF TUBER GROWTH AS A FACTOR INFLUENCING TUBER CRACKING In 1929 the potatoes from the most mature strains cracked more than those from the most immature strains. This rather peculiar condition was probably due to the unusual weather conditions. The 39 tuber-line strains were planted on June 24. • Before September 4 the weather was hot and dry and while potatoes weighing from 2 to 4 ounces had been produced by the early-maturing strains, the plants of the late strains bore potatoes which were much smaller and most of them had hardly begun to enlarge. After a snowstorm and rainy period, which occurred between September 4 and 7, con - ditions were very favorable for the manufacture and storage of starch by the plants and consequently there was a very rapid increase in tuber size. Under these conditions the rather small tubers of the late - maturing strains could increase in size both by increasing the number of cells and by enlarging the cells already pro - duced. In contrast the tubers on the plants of the early - maturing types, which had already developed considerable size, were probably at the stage where new cells could not be formed and where increase in size could be accomplished only by increasing the size of the cells. As a consequence the potatoes from the early-maturing strains were placed under a greater tension by the rapid influx of starch, water, etc. in mid-September and were more susceptible to cracking than potatoes of the later type strains which were less mature but still growing. As all tubers "set" at about the same time, the early-maturing strains could not relieve the situation by pro - ducing any more potatoes on the plants. The potatoes of the most mature strains not only cracked more easily than those from the least mature but the cracks /^prce/if of Tofo/ Wc/?/?? /Vof CrocJteaf . . Croc*:&lt;?a * r i I " — I : ' 1 yr-y^vjaanHBEM //nmorcrtr I | . .. \' \&lt;-' r-y-^ggagy | Mot Croc/tec/ y&lt;rryj*plt / Mt&amp;tum \ TfeyJfw- Fig. 4. — Percentage of tubers cracked in various degrees of severity when the six most mature and the six most immature strains planted June 24 were harvested- October 2, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 were also more severe, as shown graphically for bushel samples from the six earliest and six latest strains that had been harvested by commercial methods in 1929 (Fig.4). That same year similar results were observed in other strain tests at Alliance and Scottsbluff. With the most immature tubers the skin slipped very easily but the potatoes were not cracked. In 1930 there was very little difference in cracking in these same strains. Apparently maturity cannot be used as a safe criterion of the susceptibility of tubers to cracking under all conditions. The pressure within the tubers and the speed with which tuber size is being increased are apparently factors of con - sequence and may at times cause the more mature tubers to be most susceptible to mechanical shocks. Terminating growth by cutting vines. — On September ■ 29, 1930, the vines of 10 vigorously growing Triumph plants were cut off at the surface of the ground. Six days later tubers were harvested from these plants and tested at once with the standard shock tests. During the six-day interval after cutting the vines, changes occurred in the tubers of the cut - vine plants which increased the resistance to cracking by 20 per cent as measured by the percentage of tubers cracked by test No. 1, and reduced the length of these cracks per 100 tubers by 34 per cent (Fig. 5). When vines were cut, 3.3 per cent of the potatoes were not cracked by any test. A killing frost prior to digging time probably brings about similar changes. The difficulties often encountered in effec - tively cutting off potato vines with a machine may render Jfoff/nenf Toto/ Length of Crocks per /00 Tubers -/nches farcer}? of Tota/ /Vv/r&gt;6er 7c?sted Cat M/7C*, |BBBlBBpMBB^^^j^%g%s^a^a%i^'^y^i Grachedby rest / m r&lt;?st£ m r&lt;?stj m Not cracked m FIG. 5.— Reduction in amount and severity of tuber cracking as a result of cutting the vines one week prior to harvesting. The standard shock test was used and the vines that were not cut were about 95 per cent green on the testing date, October 5, 1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes early cutting impractical, but vines might be killed with a spray solution which will kill the vines but not damage the potatoes underground either directly or indirectly. Some means of slowing up tuber growth by root pruning, such as deep September cultivation or root cutting, might be a prac - tical method of causing tubers to mature and toughen. EFFECT OF EXPOSURE TO AIR IMMEDIATELY AFTER HARVESTING UPON TUBER CRACKING Tubers lose weight rapidly immediately after being taken out of the ground. This results in a decrease in size and con - sequently reduces internal pressure and lessens susceptibility to cracking. That the skin of tubers is tougher after ex - posure to air and sunshine is also quite commonly known. However, very little is known .concerning the rate at which these toughening processes take place. or how the rate is in - fluenced by tuber maturity, temperature, and humidity. On several dates in the. fall of 1930 potatoes of different degrees of maturity were subjected to standard cracking tests at once and at various intervals up to 27 hours after digging (Table. 6). When testing was delayed the tubers were left in the field on top of the ground. In all lots tested the tubers cracked considerably less .is the time between digging and testing was increased. With all lots of tubers tested there was a decrease in the number of tubers cracked by test No. 1 and a general decrease in the number of cracks and in the mean length of the individual cracks per tuber. The total Table 6. — Decrease in cracking as a result of exposing pota - _ toes to the air after digging Tubers cracked Length of cracks Time after ; ' — — — diKKinn when planted Planted June 27 Planted ' Planted June 27 test was made June 1, June 1; ~ harvested Harvested Harvested harvested Harvested Harvested Sept. 17 . -Sept. 17 Oct. 3 Sept. 17 Sept. 17 Oct. 3 Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent At once 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 30 minutes.. 82;6 82.7 99.5 77.5 76.7 93 5 1% hours.... 60.9 .... .... 31.3 3 hours I 39.1 34.4 75.8 28.2 36.6 700 5 hours 21.8 .... .... 8.4 8 hours 4.3 .... 79.2 12.8 .... 59.4 .27 hours 4.3 j ■ .... 3.7 Note: Tests at intervals after digging arc reported as percentages of the number of cracks or length of cracks in potatoes tested at once after digging. Test. same as described in Table 6 (standard test No. 1). </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 crack length decreased much more rapidly than did the num - ber of cracked tubers, indicating a decrease in the severity of the cracks as tubers were exposed for a longer time. The more immature tubers developed more "resistance to cracking in a given period of time than did those that were more mature. When the air was cool and damp all day as on October 3, less reduction resulted from a given exposure of the tubers than when the air was relatively dry and -warmer as on September 17. On all days the first hour of exposure was the one of great - est value in reducing cracking and on the bright, sunny, reasonably warm days the greatest reduction was accom - plished during the first 3 or 4 hours- However, on Octo - ber 3, a cold, damp day, much more time was needed to develop resistance to cracking. In fact on October 3 tubers were cracking much more after 8 hours of exposure than on Sep - tember 16 when they were tested after an exposure of onlv 3 hours. On the basis of these data it seems that on clear warm days it is reasonable to expect a 25 per cent reduction in cracking after an exposure of one hour and about 75 per cent reduc - tion in 4 or 5 hours, with relatively small additional reduc - tions by exposure beyond 5 or 6 hours. This greater suscepti - bility to cracking on October 3 may have been due to the slower toughening of the skin in the moist air or to the lower temperature. When tubers are easily tracked, 5 to 8 hours of exposure should be considered the minimum on cool cloudv days. TUBER SIZE AS A FACTOR AFFECTING CRACKING As the size of potatoes increases, not only are their chances of receiving mechanical injury quite obviously increased but the potatoes are generally more susceptible to cracking. When several thousand commercially harvested Triumph potatoes were examined individually for mechanical injury in 1929 it was found there was a very distinct increase in the percent - age of cracked potatoes as the size of the tubers increased. Of the tubers weighing over 100 grams (3*/&gt; ounces), which comprised 45.8 per cent of the total weight, the percentage of cracked potatoes amounted to between 43.3 and 54 per cent. Furthermore as the size of the potatoes increased the percentage of more severely cracked tubers increased dis - tinctly and that of sound tubers decreased proportionately This is graphically depicted in the data from the samples of the six most mature strains harvested in 1930 (Fig. 6). </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes 3 - '_ In 1930 when tubers \ [} ■ ~ &gt; were dropped 20 ' \% . \ inches on a plank the ■&gt; t « 4— - - — t * number and length of £{ l| cracks was about ; _:__ - .\ . — z= -}^ twice as great in 6 - |c j — ~_ I}* ounce as in 3-ounce ?^« ■•-■■- -..r .- .- .- ■■ ~'"~~ jllll^' }"* crease in the severity *| j||||f BJ . immature than in the -svar 5 "*"-- »~" ~~— '-^ smaller tubers seemed /v^b^ «-«■»»«■ v«*w ~~ | to develop s Hghtly FlG, (&gt;. — Increase in severity and total more resistance to amount of cracking in commercial nraoVincr hv a oVinrt - harvesting as size of tubers in- cracking by a snoit - creased. Data from 1,837 tubers time exposure to air .' weighing 259 pounds harvested in than did the larger October, 1929 (28 gr. per oz.). tubers. Because of these facts the size of the tubers becomes a very important matter in connection with this problem. SUSCEPTIBILITY OF VARIOUS, PORTIONS OF A TUBER TO CRACKING As growth does not take place uniformly in all portions of a potato, it seemed advisable to determine the relative crack - ing susceptibility of various portions of growing potatoes. When tubers were dropped 20 inches on a solid plank the cracks occurred most frequently and were most serious when the tubers were dropped on the narrow edge of the longi - tudinal axis, almost as much when dropped on either end, and least, by a greater difference, when dropped on the flat Table 7. — Susceptibility to cracking of various portions of Triumph potatoes — immature tubers dropped 19 inches upon a plank immediately after digging on September 29, 1 930 Portion of tulier Tuhcrs Crnckod Mean no. ot Total lenKth of \vhiih struck vUnk testi'il tubers cracks per cracks in 100 * 100 tubers tested tubers _ — — j : p— j I Number | Percent | Number Inches Lower side ! 20 80.0 | 194 25.1 Either end 1 1 CO 96.7 255 44.8 Edge ..:.....„........ 1 ■ 20 1 100.0 275 51.5 1 These conclusions ore -in line with those observed in a detailed inspection of several thousand tubers that had been cracked in commercial harvestinR operations. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 side, or the wide portion of the longitudinal axis (see Table 7). Observations indicated that tubers were more susceptible to cracking at the apical than at the basal ends but with the number of tubers used. (30 in each test) it was impossible to establish any significant difference. The upper side of the tubers was not tested but because of exposure to more variable conditions this side is undoubtedly more resistant than the lower side. DEPTH OF PLANTING AS IT AFFECTS THE CUTTING OF POTATOES AT DIGGING TIME During each year a higher percentage of potatoes was generally cut in digging where potatoes had been planted deep than where they had been planted rather shallow. The Table 8. — Effect of -planting depth upon cutting of potatoes with digger at harvesting time at Alliance — data based on 8.-bushel samples of each lot ( ==================== Planting depth Percentage of total crop cut in digging ZHHZ 1928 ■ :'~T929"~ l»30~~ ■■ Three-year av. 1 I Shallow i 8.42 0.26 1.56 ,3.25 " Deep ....| 12.00 l.GO 3.84 C.I 5 ■ most cutting occurred with the deep planted (3.5 to 4.5 inches) and the least with the shallow-planted (2 to 3 inches) (see Table 8). The differences from year to year were partly due to soil conditions and pai ; tly to the variable efficiency of the digging machine. , MISCELLANEOUS FACTORS INFLUENCING MECHANICAL INJURY Direction of rows. — When potatoes have been planted in rows running east and west it has been observed that fre - quently more potatoes (generally also larger potatoes) are produced on the north side than on the south side of the row. Consequently, unless the operator of the digger is very cau - tious, a number of potatoes on the north side of the row may be cut. . Soil conditions. — In soils that develop hard clods very easily the addition of organic matter will afford considerable relief from injury to potatoes at digging time. In light, sandy soils which are well aerated and which generally have a limited water supply, the skins of the potatoes toughen more rapidly than do those of tubers grown in a heavy soil which is cooler </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes and retains more moisture. Because of these conditions, generally less cracking occurs with the lighter soils but digger damage in the form of bruises is greater than with tubers produced in the heavier soils. (The effect of soil moisture is discussed on pages 5 and 6.) Rhizoctonia infection at the end of the growing season frequently results in the girdling of the stems or stolons. This interferes with the movement of reserve food into the hew potato. Consequently tuber growth is slowed up or ceases. With the Triumph variety the tubers take on a darker red color and are tough and rubbery instead of firm and brittle. It was sometimes almost impossible to crack such potatoes, whereas tubers on healthy, stolons of the same plants were cracked very easily. In some tests conducted in 1930 the ci-acking of tubers the growth of which was checked by Rhizoctonia was 30 per cent less and the severity of the cracking 50 per cent less than with normal tubers. STUDIES OF THE CAUSES OF INJURIES CRACKING CAUSED IN DIGGING Freshly dug potatoes from green vines were dropped 9^ inches on the middle of a bare rod 0.4 inch in diameter! This rod was 12 inches long and the ends were supported on firm soil — the center being unsupported. This test was com - parable to the shock potatoes receive when dropping on the second or rear apron of a commercial digger. It was repeated with tubers exposed to the air for various lengths of time as specified later. All potatoes tested in this way were cracked, even when ex - posed to the air for 20 minutes or for 8 hours before testing. The total length of the cracks in the freshly dug tubers was slightly more than three inches per tuber (Fig. 7). When exposed to the air for only 20 minutes the average length of the cracks was 5.8 per cent less and when exposed 8 hours they averaged 24.3 per cent less than when tested at once after digging. These tests were conducted on October 3, a cool, damp day when tubers did not toughen rapidly. Since the rods on a digger being operated in damp soil are always covered with dirt, tubers were dropped the cus - tomary 9V£ inches on a rod which was covered with a layer of dirt about 1/16 of an inch thick. This thin layer offered much protection. While it prevented the cracking of only 5 per cent of the freshly dug potatoes, it reduced the severity, that is, the total length of the cracks, 38.4 per cent when com - pared with the cracking of freshly dug tubers dropped on a bare rod. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 *&lt; &amp;*Jce JeonJPoo V -. ** o«)2«« La^ri* ■»»»»» . ■*/ 3r**a*M O rtsr Hal arQ^T^j^^^^^^^^^^^^^ j FlG 'J^1^ n^ ° f Cra^S ns a result of shocks similar to those that ™,mi y # t °, 0ccur machine digging. Percentages of the total number of tubers cracked, m each lot were as follows: Lots 4fi 47 49 MVt t 19 ? ; &lt;.n. Ot T 4 !' K 9 a 5! L0t 52 ' ° 3; L0ts 44 and 45 ' 100 Lot mad 7 e 6 Octo L b O er f iflb.^ * b ° ttOm The tCsts Were When potatoes were dropped on a rod which was iying on a plank and which would be comparable to a firmly at - tached rod which a potato might strike on. a digger the dam - age done was much greater than when dropped on a rod of which only the ends were supported on dirt (Test 44 com - pared with 46). All the potatoes'were cracked and the length of the cracks averaged approximately 3.9 inches each or were 40 8 per cent more severe than when the rod was 'less firmly placed (Test 46). .Covering a firmly placed rod with one layer of burlap (Test 4 , 5 ' d , lcI 1 not reduce the number of cracked potatoes at all but it did decrease the number of cracks 35 per cent and: the severity about 6 per cent. While one layer of burlap afforded some protection it was not nearly as effective as was a thin layer of dirt. Sometimes potatoes fall on or strike against solid flat sur - taces on the digger or on clods or on other potatoes on the ground. To determine the probability of cracking under such circumstances freshly dug potatoes were dropped 9U&gt; inches 77 Sir" ? f" + r e + C \ Of P l ank ( T eSt 49) • Such a dr °P ca «^l 77 per cent of the tubers to crack. The severity of the cracks was only 38 per cent as great as when tubers were dropped on a bare rod lying on a plank (Test 44) or 20 per cent as ?tw 1%\ v\ dropped . or [ a bare r °d rigidly fixed (lest 47). Tubers were not cracked as readily when falling on a flat surface as on a rod, because the shock was distributed over a greater area of the tubei\ •». • These results indicate that it is extremely important to avoid having potatoes dropped or jostled around on a digger apron. This is especially important in a dry season when.the i ods are not covered with dirt. They also demonstrate the fan- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes portance of padding all surfaces which are likely to be struck by potatoes as they are being dug. Occasionally potatoes drop on each other in digging. Crack - ing is likely to occur in. either or both of the potatoes but not to as great an extent as when they fall on rods, planks, or similar solid surfaces. When potatoes that had been dug 10 minutes were dropped on each other, only 30 per cent of the potatoes, both those dropped and those struck, were cracked, in comparison with 77 to 100 per cent when potatoes were dropped on rods or planks. The total amount of crack - ing in the lots of potatoes was also much less. The cracking of the potatoes on the ground was about 38 per cent more severe than on those that were dropped. When potatoes were exposed to the air for 8 hours the number of tubers cracked was greatly reduced, as was also the severity and extent of the cracking. In 1930 twenty farmers who used tractors and power-take - off diggers were found to have averaged 16.2 per cent of mechanically injured potatoes in contrast with 24.8 per cent damaged by twenty-seven farmers who used horse-drawn diggers. These percentages were determined by the inspect - ors of the Nebraska Certified Potato Growers Cooperative. CRACKING CAUSED IN PICKING Much, damage may be done to the potatoes as they are picked up and hauled to the cellar. Triumph potatoes handled at Alliance on October 5, 1930, in several types of picking baskets that are used in picking potatoes, were inspected for cracking damage, as reported in the following paragraphs. . ] .--.■• : . "• . - - : ■ , .-^2__ -&gt; t ■r'-.i::.:--:..'- '■■'.. . ■_ ■ -, .' ".;....-. ■..-' ■ j Fir,; 8. — Types of baskets used in picking potatoes. The two baskets at the left are most commonly used. The one is padded to prevent in - jury. In the center is a very desirable type. The ring around the top has been wrapped half way around to prevent damage from sharp ends of vertical rods where they are welded to the frame. The galvanized-iron baskets at the right do not cut potatoes but they cause serious cracking and should be padded somewhat as' shown. The baskets at the left and right' were used in tests reported in Fig. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 Unlined wire picking baskets. — As the potatoes were taken out of the ground they were tossed about 12 inches, with about the force that a reasonably careful picker would use, against the side of an unlined wire picking basket (Fig. 8) , the wires of which were about 1/16 of an inch thick (Lot 71, Fig. 9). Of the 71 tubers thus treated 45 per cent were cracked. In almost every case the skin was broken and. shoved into the interior wherever the tuber hit the wire, but cracks were not always produced or at least were not always apparent on the surface. The cracks were less numerous and less severe than when tubers were dropped on iron rods, planks, etc. (Fig. 7). However, the number of cracked tubers was 80 per cent greater and the total length of cracks 37.3 per cent greater than when tubers were tossed against the sides of lined wire baskets (Lot 64) . Burlap-lined wire baskets. — Burlap lining in wire "baskets (Fig. 8) afforded considerable protection to the tubers. With freshly dug tubers 25 per cent were cracked (Test 64, Fig. 9 ) . Tubers exposed to the air for 25 minutes developed resistance so that only half as many (12.5 per cent) were cracked (Test 63). These were decided decreases from the 45 per cent that were cracked in unlined baskets. The severity of cracking, as measured by total crack length of all tested tubers; was de - creased 27 per cent by padding the baskets. When tubers were not picked up for 25 minutes the cracks were small and the aggregate length was only 21 per cent of that of the freshly dug tubers. Galvanized sheet iron baskets of a new type (Fig. 8) were used for the first time in 1930. These baskets are very sub - stantial and do not have any sharp edges. They were, how - (A Bun.** lmco _ /irUvtY lai^BaaLau 63 H,*cB*3JaT fSMrwrtj 7I_ UmwMea«g /}rO~cr ■■■BMBHO^aiB Fig. 9. — Extent of cracking as a result of picking operations. The per - centages of the total number of tubers cracked in each lot were a? follows: Lot &lt;&gt;2, 58; Lot 61, 40; Lot 64, 25; Lot 63, 12.5; Lot 7)", 45; Lot 66, 60; Lot 65, 13; Lot 69, 20; and Lot 70, 5. The tests were made October 5, 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes ever, responsible for much more cracking than occurred in either lined or unlined wire baskets. When the freshly dug tubers struck the solid surface of one of these baskets im - mediately after digging, 58.3 per cent of them were cracked and the total length of the cracks was greater than with either of the wire baskets (Lot 62). Cracking was reduced less by a 25-minute exposure of the tubers than was the case with the burlap-lined wire baskets, for even then 40 per cent of the tubers were cracked by the galvanized iron basket (Lot Evidently these firm-walled sheet-iron baskets when not lined may be even less desirable than unlined wire baskets while lined wire baskets are very preferable to both types ot unlined baskets. As potatoes which were dropped only 9i/ 2 inches on to a plank (Lot 49, Fig. 7) cracked more severely than those thrown 12 inches against the side of either ot the types of baskets used, one might seriously question the advisability of using crates for field picking if pickers are at all careless. In 1930 the writer observed that at least 50 per cent ot the tubers were being cracked in one commercial field where crates were being used by pickers who were being paid by the bushel. - . • p When freshly dug potatoes were tossed 12 inches so that a potato always struck the potato that was tossed in just betore, more potatoes were cracked (59.5 per cent) than when the potatoes were tossed against the sides of any of the baskets, and the cracks were also more severe (Lot 66) A delay of 40 minutes (Lot 65) reduced the percentage of cracked tubers 77.6 per cent (13.3 per cent cracked) and re - duced the total length of cracks or severity by 93.6 per cent Evidently with freshly dug potatoes a great deal of damage can be done by tubers striking each other while being picked into the basket, but much damage from this source is elim - inated when potatoes are exposed to the air for a short time alter digging. POURING THE POTATOES FROM THE PICKING BASKET INTO A SACK As rapidly as they were dug with a fork the undamaged tubers were carefully placed in a wire picking basket. As soon as the basket was filled the potatoes were poured into a sack from a height of about 12 inches, but not one of the tubers was cracked. They were then carefully put back into the basket and when again poured from a height of about 30 inches, 197 per cent were cracked (Test 69). The extent and severity of the damage was very similar to that occurring when freshly dug potatoes were tossed against the sides of a burlap-lmed wire basket (Lot 64, Fig. 9). </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 22 Another set of potatoes was picked into a basket after 30 minutes of exposure to the air and was then poured into a sack (Lot 70). When poured from a height of 12 inches only one tuber was cracked and when dumped from a height of 30 inches only 4.9 per cent of the tubers were cracked (Test 70) This delay of 30 minutes reduced the number of cracked tubers by 73.2 and the total length of the cracks by 79 9 ner cent. *••.?_*• In view of the practically complete absence of cracking when potatoes were poured 12 inches in comparison with the serious percentage occurring when tubers were poured out from a height of 30 inches, the importance of care in this operation is self-evident. THE WOUND HEALING PROCESS IN POTATOES A potato tuber that has been wounded is capable of healing the wound by laying down a protective covering, providing proper conditions prevail. This protective covering consists first of a fatty-like material (called suberin) which is de - posited upon the walls of several layers of cells just beneath the wound and this is followed by the development of a new protective layer of . corky cells. This covering is practically impervious to air and water (or other gases and liquids) as well as to microscopic organisms which would attack the delicate cells of the potato and cause their death and the rotting of a portion or all of the potato. Whether this layer develops quickly, slowly, or hardly at all depends upon temperature, humidity, light, condition of the tuber, and variety. Under ideal conditions with the Triumph variety the entire healing process requires from 7 to 14 days. FACTORS AFFECTING THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE PROTECTIVE COVERING With the Triumph variety wounds have been found to heal m °re slowly and less satisfactorily than with the Irish Cobbler. Healing takes place most rapidly at what are con - sidered high storage temperatures for potatoes — that is 75° ™, 85 ' F - at which temperature, other conditions being favor - able, the healing process is completed in Triumph potatoes in about one week. About 10 days to 2 weeks are required at a temperature of 55° to 65° and two to four weeks at tem - peratures between 40° and 55° F. Below 40° F. healing takes place very slowly and incompletely, for a matter of two months or more. High humidity is necessary for most rapid wound healing ; especially is this the case at high temperatures. When the air is dry, healing occurs in patches, thus leaving some wounded areas entirely unprotected. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes Sunshine exerts a very unfavorable effect upon wound healing, retarding and causing a very patchy development of the protective covering. When fresh cuts on Triumph pota - toes were exposed to direct sunshine for 8 hours and the potatoes were then stored in a cellar, the first steps in the healing process were delayed several days and the entire heal - ing process was slightly retarded throughout the next two weeks. Most rapid healing occurred in the portion of a wound located close to the skin or close to the sap tubes. Clean-cut wounds made with a sharp edge heal more quickly than the torn, ragged cuts made by a blunt edge. Healing is also rather slow in the case of bruises where the wound is very irregular and cells are crushed. Surface cuts heal much more quickly than do deep, narrow cracks or cuts penetrating into the tuber (Fig. 10). Consequently these latter types of wounds serve as excellent places for infection by rot-producing or - ganisms and may be more serious when potatoes are stored than the large surface cuts. Fig. 10.— View under microscope of a crack one inch long with a max - imum depth of about one-fourth inch, showing healing which had occurred one week after the crack was made. Dark lines indicate the first step in the healing process, the deposit of suberin in the walls of the cells nearest the surface. The extent of healing has diminished toward the center. The cells along the interior half of this crack were still unprotected one week after being injured, thus providing an excellent place for organisms to initiate an infection. Enlarged about 16 times. THE EFFECT OF HOT FORMALDEHYDE ON WOUND HEALING AND STORAGE QUALITY Sometimes the opinion is expressed that if potatoes were treated with a disinfectant just- after digging or before storing, the wounds would be disinfected and the potatoes would not rot. In Idaho dry rot was prevented by a two - hour treatment of either cold formaldehyde or corrosive sublimate providing it was applied within 48 hours after </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 digging. The length of time required for these treatments and the difficulty of drying the potatoes render these cold treatments undesirable. Corrosive sublimate is a dangerous poison and should never be used on potatoes for storage as they might at some time be used for food. As the hot formaldehyde is relatively inexpensive and has also been found to be the most effective seed treatment for common scab m Nebraska, and as the potatoes dry off quickly after it has been used, several experiments were conducted to determine the effect on healing of wounds on potatoes and keeping quality of such disinfected wounded potatoes. Potatoes with surface cuts that had been made with a blunt knife were treated with hot formaldehyde. When treated immediately and at intervals of 1, 6, and 24 hours after cutting, the healing processes were delayed and heal - ing was more "patchy" than with the untreated cut sur - faces. The treatment was actually injurious to the cut surfaces, as was evident by the hard surface layer which formed on the cuts and which when inspected tinder the microscope was found to consist of a number of layers of cells that had been killed by the treatment (Fig. 11).' These layers were thickest on the wounds . which were treated r4v«»{v»-.-';/.v soon after cuttin £ ancl B ~^ ™£jf3sj&amp;"$!tg£&amp;'i developed least when i . ' treating was delayed 21 ?%MVsJ*^i4p &lt; with not formaldehyde. W&amp;Qk&amp;Cffitft ¥&amp;Q&amp;$^M$&amp;. Treatin 2 the potatoes *23L$fc$&amp;$^ three days after cutting f$^^^^n^^ had no retarding effect ■ ~ already so far along in Pig. 11. — Effect of hot formaldehyde such cuts that the treat - treatment on the subsequent wound- ment could do no dam - healing process. A shows a cut un- al? p treated and B shows a section of a cut that was treated immediately When potatoes cut in a j ter^ l1: T Wa ?&gt; cut - (Cut was alon £ tf) P diKKine were treated edge.) In B note the greater thick- •+? ? . W ?- ,*, .Jf te . a ness of the layer of dead cells and in W"" not formaldehyde A the greater thickness of the pro- the percentage of tubers techve layers of suberized and un- rotting in storage was suberized cells. _^i _? , . . not decreased appreci - ably; in tact rotting was sometimes increased. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes discussion and recommendations The complete elimination of damage at harvesting time may be- impossible but the experience of potato growers, some of whom are damaging less than 3 while others are injuring over 60 per cent of their crop, and the experi - mental results reported in this bulletin indicate that much of the damage can be avoided with proper attention to methods of handling and the use of proper equipment. The suggestions and recommendations which follow are drawn up with the idea of meeting the rather acute problems en - countered in handling the Triumph variety as it is grown in western Nebraska, where the crop is harvested in late September and early October. MATURITY OF VINES OR TUBERS The potatoes should be reasonably mature. Tubers are easily cracked when they are still growing rapidly or when they are very turgid because the roots are absorbing mois - ture from a very damp soil. This damage can be reduced considerably by avoiding late planting. However, in some districts the best means of avoiding loss from scab and Fusarium wilt » appears to be late planting (after June 20). Then either cutting the v.ines or pruning the roots by a very deep cultivation in late September are suggested as methods of slowing up or terminating the growth of tubers produced by such late plantings. If a ridge is thrown on the row by this late cultivation (September), the potatoes will be given additional frost' protection and can be dug more easily than when the field is practically flat. The vines are of course killed by the early fall frosts, but some - times the first frost is so severe that the damage done by freezing tubers is greater than the saving resulting from reduced damage to tubers harvested several days after the vines have been killed.- Vines may be killed by spraying with some material which will not injure the tubers. SOIL AND CULTURAL CONDITIONS When the soil contains a large amount of moisture the growing period of the tubers is prolonged, the tubers are more turgid, the skin more tender, and the stolons are likely to be longer. Consequently the tubers are more easily cracked and cut in harvesting than when the soil is dry. On the other hand when grown in a dry soil tubers do not crack as readily because of a slower growth rate and 1 Fusarium cumartii. 'Durinit 23 years (1907-1929) at ScottsblufT. temperatures below 20° P have occurred prior to October B durine five years, prior to October 10 in 6 seasons, "and on ■or before October 20 in 14 seasons. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 tougher skin, but they are damaged more in digging, re - ceiving many bruises from the clean digger chain or from the hard lumps of dirt which are jostled over the chain with the potatoes. Excessively moist soils at digging time cannot be pre - vented by the grower except when they are due to late irrigation. A hard, dry soil at harvest time can be avoided to some extent by cultivation so as to prevent soil baking and cracking, which might occur after a pounding rain, by improving the physical conditions of the soil by the addi - tion of organic matter or, if available, by the judicious use of irrigation water. . Some tuber cutting can be eliminated by throwing the dirt slightly toward the rows when cultivating or by throwing up a ridge late in the season so that the wheels of the digger will be a little lower. When the soil is damp, many tubers are cut because the dirt collecting on the digger wheels prevents the digger from running at the proper depth. This is especially the case when the second trip is made through the field to dig the alternate rows that were skipped on the first trip. THE POTATO DIGGING MACHINE The potatoes are handled by the digger when they are very delicate and most of the harvest damage is often done by the digger. Consequently a great amount of care should be used in selecting a digger and in adjusting it. It should also be watched very closely to make certain that it is con - tinuing to do proper work as the field conditions are chang - ing. A careful check-up will convince every grower that the proper operation of the digger may sometimes be the most important operation of the entire season. From North Dakota, Hastings reports that they were able to reduce the digger damage between 12 and 38 per cent, with an aver - age of 29 per cent, by making changes on the diggers with a view to reducing damage. 1 None of the modern types of diggers in common use is as satisfactory as it should be for digging Triumph potatoes. The essentials for a good digger for this variety are: (1) that it be wide enough, preferably not less than 24 inches ; (2) the conveyor belt or chain should not be too steep, otherwise potatoes will roll down on it unless the chain is equipped at intervals with offset or drop-bar links or with special angle bars so as to prevent this rolling; (3) it should be possible to operate the two chains as one unit if so de - 1 Hastings, R. C. Mechanical Injury to Potatoes and Its Eradication in North Dakota. American Potato Journal, May, 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes sired; -(4) it must be capable of operating at a sufficient depth so as to get all of the potatoes without cutting in all kinds ot soil, whether the soil is moist or dry; (5) the rear end of. the digger should be adjustable so that it can be raised or lowered as necessity demands to separate the dirt trom the potatoes in order to prevent damage to the tubers in dropping (Fig. 12). The efficiency of any digger can be increased by proper adjustment or by a few simple improvements. Some of the most useful and important are the following: 1. Equip the front end with a pair of revolving disks placed at an angle or with small plows so adjusted that they will deflect back on the digger the dirt and potatoes that are frequently crowded out at the side where the latter are either bruised or smashed by the digger wheel (rig. 12) . . • Fig. 12— A digger with a power take-off, ' disks in front, and padding on the deflectors on the rear end. Note that the rear end is lowered to reduce the distance the tubers must drop." 2. Use plenty of power so that the digger can be run deeply, enough to prevent cutting and so that it can carry enough dirt over the chain to prevent bruising and crack - le* iT s 1S loose or dam P may be impossible to do this because of insufficient traction. In that event lugs of extra length might be used on the wheels. However a tractor and digger equipped with a power take-off or a small gasoline engine mounted on the digger to provide power would probably be more efficient solutions. With a power take-off or separate motor it is also possible to regulate the speed of the chain in accordance with the con - ditions prevailing. . 3. If potatoes are being bounced around on the digger chain too much or if the dirt is sifting through too rapidly, </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 some or all of the elliptical agitators under the chain can be replaced with rollers and the speed of the chain should be reduced. m 4. The digger chain should be padded, especially when immature tubers are being handled. When the soil is moist the amount which sticks to the rods may provide sufficient protection. When the soil is dry so that it sifts through the chain or belt, some other method must be. used. Pieces of rubber hose can be split and fastened with wire, or burlap can be securely wrapped around about half of the rods. If too much dirt is carried over the chain some potatoes may be buried, but these may. be of less value than those that are a loss because of damage done to them when in - sufficient dirt is carried over an unpadded chain 5. Removal of the rear chain or apron eliminates many bruises and is quite satisfactory except when many clods are present or when many potatoes are covered, in which case a canvas or burlap belt completely around the rear chain provides another solution. 6. When the two digger chains are combined . and Fig. 13.—Construction used to support digger chain to keep it from dragging when only one continuous chain is used. ( Wheel removed to permit showing of detail.) </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes operated as one long chain, much of the damage resulting when tubers drop from the first to the second chain is eliminated (Fig. 13). .7. The rear end of the second chain should be lowered close to the ground so that the potatoes will not be dropped more than a few inches. 8. All parts of the digger against which potatoes are likely to strike, such as rods, bolts, or solid surfaces, should be padded. Waste materials available on every farm make excellent padding. Pieces of 6-inch belting or old inner tubes ripped open and applied one or two layers thick, or several thicknesses of burlap will generally be sufficient. 9. The deflectors attached to most diggers for the pur - pose of laying all the tubers in a narrow row render a valuable service, but as the potatoes strike these deflectors many are seriously cracked. (The deflectors shown on the cover page should have been padded.) If they are thickly padded and properly adjusted, the potatoes will be laid on the ground in rows and can be picked more easily, and the number lost by being missed in picking or damaged when the digger comes through the field on the next trip will be reduced. 10. The drive wheels of a tractor often travel outside the center of the space between rows and it is often desirable to remove the outer row of lugs to prevent cutting and smashing of potatoes while still on the plant in the adjacent row. POTATO PICKING OPERATIONS Proper management of the picking operations may pre - vent the bruising or cracking of many tubers. To the care - ful grower the precautions described here will probably suggest many more improvements. 1. Potatoes should be left on top of the ground for several hours after digging. On warm, sunny days a delay of 3 or 4 hours will be practically as useful in toughening the potatoes as a longer period. Leaving potatoes out more than 8 hours was found of no value in increasing resistance to cracking. Over night the tubers apparently absorbed moisture from the air and- became more turgid. On cool or damp days a longer exposure is necessary in order to accomplish the same results. Exposure permits the thorough drying of the skin and dirt on the potato. Such thorough drying is very helpful in preventing infection from fungi that would later produce rots. These recom - mendations are intended specifically for the fall crop when cool weather prevails. If the temperature is unseasonably high, 80° F. or higher, it may not be wise and should not </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 be necessary to leave the potatoes on top of the ground for more than about one hour. Long exposure to bright sun - shine at high temperatures is dangerous, as it may cause sun scald. Frequently the temperature of the potatoes is raised to a point where certain bacterial rots will cause much damage. The drying off of potatoes, which prevents some infection,, and the reduced cracking from the later handling operations will more than offset the retarded healing of surface wounds and cracks as a result of ex - posure to sunshine for several hours. 2. The sides of all potato-picking baskets should be lined or padded to reduce the shock when the potatoes are tossed in. One or two layers of burlap ordinarily give sufficient protection (Fig. 8). 3. Care should be used in placing the potatoes in the baskets, since tender potatoes are very likely to crack if they strike either the sides or other potatoes. The pickers should not toss the potatoes into the baskets for a greater distance than is absolutely necessary. Unless the pickers are yery careful, picking directly into wooden crates mav result in a great deal of crackinge 4. Pickers should stoop over and carefully pour or roll the potatoes from the picking baskets into the sacks so that none of the potatoes will drop more than one foot. Very few potatoes will crack when poured out in that manner but when carelessly dumped from the customary height of three feet or more many tubers are severely cracked. 5. After the potatoes have been poured into the sacks many pickers skin or crack a large number by jarring or jostling the sack to settle the potatoes so that the half-filled sack will stand up easily. With newly dug potatoes one can hear many of these tubers cracking. Much of this jostling is unnecessary and the half-filled sacks can be made to stand up by pulling up with a back-and-forth twisting motion, which will pull the sack tight and cause the potatoes to settle more compactly without causing any skinning, bruising, or cracking. The same precautions should be observed if potatoes are being put into sacks which are filled to capacity and sewed shut at digging time. . HANDLING POTATOES FROM FIELD . TO STORAGE CELLAR Since there is always danger of doing damage to tender, newly harvested potatoes when they are handled, harvest - ing operations should be planned with a view to subjecting the potatoes individually or in sacks to no more movements or transfers than are absolutely necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes Handling in bulk, that is, dumping potatoes into an open wagon box and then scooping them into the bin, is the most unsatisfactory method of handling Triumph potatoes. Many are bruised and cracked when dropped two or three feet over the side of the wagon box to the solid floor or on other tubers. The scooping, even when done very carefully, re - sults in more cracks. Several other methods are so much more efficient and satisfactory that if given a thorough trial some one of them will certainly be adopted by the progressive grower in preference to this out-of-date method. The "half-sack" method, that is, pouring two baskets of potatoes into a two-bushel sack and then hauling -to the cellar, is probably the most popular method. (See cover page.) Precautions to be observed in order to avoid doing damage with this method are as follows: (a) when pour - ing potatoes into the sacks do not drop them more than one foot; tb) do not jostle the potatoes about in the sack by unnecessary "shaking down"; (c) when loading on the wagon hold the sack firmly immediately above the potatoes so that they will be securely held in place, for when they roll about inside the outer skin is easily peeled off; (d) do not drop the sacks on the floor of the wagon, for that causes the crushing of many potatoes in the bottom of the sack — if the first sacks loaded on the wagon or truck are properly slanted, the later sacks can be loaded without having to drop or force them into, place; (e) never step or walk on the potatoes during any of the harvesting operations, for even though the potatoes are inside the sacks damage is done although it may not be seen easily at the time; (f) padding the floor of a wagon box or truck with straw or old burlap sacks will protect many of the potatoes from bruising when loading and when the load receives jolts on a rough road; (g) a low wagon preferably with ohly a floor (no side boards) will reduce the labor in hauling potatoes, and since sacks of potatoes can be more easily handled with such a wagon less damage will be done ; (h) in some of the eastern potato regions the potato-hauling wagons are equipped with springs, which, in case of rough roads, are a wise precaution. Filling the bins in the cellar is more of an operation than merely dumping out the potatoes. If a flat wagon or truck is used, one man may be able to unload the potatoes into the bin in a satisfactory manner but if the sacks must be lifted over the sides of the wagon or truck or unloaded from the rear, two men are generally necessary, one on the vehicle and one in the bin. The following procedure will be found practical in the average farm potato cellar: </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 (a) When picking up and carrying the sack, hold the sack securely so the potatoes cannot move around inside. (b) Carry the sack to the rear of the bin and with the least possible disturbance roll the potatoes out of the sack. Cover the floor of the bin with one layer of potatoes to a depth of about one foot, working from the rear to the front. (c) When ready for the second layer, extend a heavy plank from the front boards of the bin to a strip nailed to the uprights or posts in the rear. This plank should be about 2 or 21/2 f&amp;et above the floor of the cellar. The next layer should be carried back and emptied from this plank. As the bin is filled the plank should be raised to succes - sively higher levels. Some growers prefer to pad a plank very thickly and then lay it on top of the tubers. This is satisfactory if the plank is padded sufficiently. (d) Never walk over or stand on the potatoes. Do not drop them or throw them into the bin. (e) Dumping potatoes from the wagon into the front of the bin and allowing them to roll down into the rear as the pile is built up in front is undesirable, because in rolling over each other the potatoes will be badly skinned. The "full sack" method of. handling potatoes at picking time is very popular in some sections. Sacks are commonly filled by dumping the potatoes out of the picking basket on a slatted sorter which is taken through the field on a small horse-drawn sled. As the potatoes roll down over this Fig. 14. — Picking potatoes and hauling out of the field in full sacks. The use of a shaker sorter in filling sacks is not to be recommended because of the damage to freshly dug potatoes. A sloping table made of slats and mounted on a sled is better. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes ■ _____ ' ' . :• ,',;., ■ . ... . ■ . - •'-._ ; __^ l^j^^^^^^l ___________________________ j H^^^lfe_j_l_lfifi_^^^^^^^^^^^_^^^^^Mv^^^^^^l^^V^^^^4^^^^^^^^L k—^Jl^P I Fig. 15. — Hauling potatoes from the field in crates — an excellent method if used properly. sorter most of the dirt is shaken off and the cut and badly bruised potatoes can be thrown out. The space under the bottom of the sack should be heavily padded to prevent bruising and cracking when the first potatoes roll off the sorting table into the bottom of the sack. As the first half of the potatoes in each sack will drop two feet or more on each other, much cracking may occur unless the potatoes are quite tough. Another method of avoiding this damage is to fasten the sack on the sack holder in the regular man - ner, then pull up the bottom of the sack and hook each side on a nail or hook in the sorter so that the potatoes will drop only half the depth of the sack. When this portion of the sack is filled it is unhooked and the potatoes are allowed to roll into the bottom of the sack. Filling sacks in the field by running them over an iron screen of a shaker sorter or any other sorter is very unde - sirable, as the potatoes are not sufficiently tough to with - stand all the handling involved (Fig. 14). If the sacks are filled carefully and are then handled carefully by two men so that they are never thrown or dropped, very few pota - toes will be cracked. The amount of skinning will be greatly reduced because the potatoes are held in place firmly and cannot move about in the sack. As the potatoes are stored in these sacks till sorting at shipping time they are under better storage conditions because they receive more ventilation than when stored in bulk. The saving in labor and the fewer damaged potatoes are considered as more than compensating for the 20 to 30 per cent decrease </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 260 in storage capacity of a cellar when the potatoes are stored m sacks. The sacks are likely to be weakened in storage and should not be used for seed potato shipments or for shipping high-grade potatoes. It might be best to keep the sacks for storing crops in later years, and use new sacks for marketing the crop. : Wooden crates, if used properly, are very satisfactory for getting the crop from the field into the cellar (Fig 15) Pickers must, however, be careful in pouring the potatoes into the crates or many of the potatoes will be cracked The crates should also not be filled more than level full or the potatoes on top will be smashed by the crates placed on top. The main advantage with crates is that thev pro - tect the potatoes from bruising in hauling more than do the sacks. If potatoes are hauled to a cellar on the farm about as rapidly as they are picked up, 200 crates will be suf - ncient for a crew of five pickers. In emptying the crates into the bins the same precautions mentioned with the "half sack method should be observed. All pieces of wood used m making the crates should have rounded edges. In some sections potatoes are stored, in the cellar in crates. TUBER INFECTION AT HARVEST TIME About the only disinfectant for preventing wound infec - tion which could be considered practical or safe for use on ?x?- 1 t S that mi £ ht be used for food is hot formaldehyde With the tests that were made this treatment when used on injured tubers within the first two days after harvesting did considerable damage that resulted in increased rotting No serious damage resulted when injured potatoes were treated two days or more after harvesting or after being injured, but by that time the treatment was too late to pre - vent infection. MANAGEMENT OF THE STORAGE CELLAR The humidity of the cellar air should be quite high when potatoes are brought into it so as to hasten wound healing and reduce water loss from the potatoes. Adequate ventila - tion the first few weeks is very important to prevent the accumulation of moisture on the potatoes and also to prevent some undesirable consequences resulting from the accumula - tion of the gases being given off by the potatoes. If moisture accumulates before the protective covering has been developed on the wounds they are very likely to become seriously in - tected by rot-producing organisms. Very low temperatures (below 40° F.) immediately after harvesting are not necessary and probably are not desirable </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Mechanical Injury to Potatoes because they delay or prevent wound healing without pre - venting the growth of certain rot-producing organisms. Cold storage within a week after digging is for this reason considered undesirable. A temperature -of 55° to 65° F. for about one week after harvesting, with adequate ventilation, is probably the most desirable. After about a week or ten days the temperature should be dropped as rapidly as pos - sible to the vicinity of 40° F. After potatoes have been in storage for some time they are not cracked as easily as when taken out of the field. However, they are still quite tender and care should be used to avoid rough handling in sorting, loading, haul - ing, etc. At all times when handling potatoes one should remem - ber that they are tender organisms. If they are handled with care there will be few mechanical injuries. • &gt;• [GM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>