<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  STUDIES IN WATER REQUIREMENTS OF CORN.</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION or NEBRASKA Vol. i ui XXIV, Aistu IE VI. STUDIES IN WATER REQUIREMENTS OF CORN. B\ K. (I \1"\ U.iHIHM AMI T. A. KlESSKI -l-.Al II IIBI TO -May s. 1912. 1 111 I nivkksity &lt;&gt;k Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION IW. Mi kk M S&lt; 4w North Pla I iltai ist. ii cult,, W. H. Swenk. A. 11., Am$&lt; IE K. K. Link, S. B.. tmillant H Till MB! I.I.. A. M I Hopt. B. Sc.. Assiftant i» Agronomy &lt;• Barker. A. B., Assistant in A, iron"" Rail. B. S&lt; iJOt. B. S&lt; .. A**i*t&lt;nii STITOWVANT. A. M.. M. I).. Assistant Howarii. B. 8c. IN Ai.i:.. Assist- Westgate. A. M.. Amtmtnnt in Hortu nil • Jambs Cowav. M. E.. sup.rint.nd, ,,t ETfrrimnttal Habitation. Val. Pbitz Kndkr. B. S. W. Pekin. Farm Sup- rn,t, ndrnt * Re*len-&lt;1 ''i &gt;i ijunnnna. THE GOVERNING BOARD &lt;?h£ me*-.™ o* thi laan ' uRABLE CHARIJB8 S. AI.I.EN, Pmident, Lincoln. ORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Lincoln ■RABLE GEORGE COIPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE WILLIAM &lt;;. WHITMOKE. Valley. &gt;RABLE VICTOR G. LYFORU, Falls City. HONORABLE FRANK L. HAI.I.KR. Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVKrtV. I'll. l&gt;., LL. D for, « x offi. E. A. BUR.VETT, H J 8. DALES. M. l'i \VM \V MARSHA1 THE WORKING STAFF E. Mkai. Win on. I'll F. J. Ai.»av. I'll I) III v-L. H - I'l C.SLET. B. I • H R. Smith Husb-m J. H. Cain. M. I J. H. Fkamisen. M 1 Law k&gt; \. I Mm nek. I moloijy. • E G. \lu\ k... T. A. KlESSElKAl II. 1 H. Bakihii k. I'm. 1 1 ■ IIATHIKV A. M. // R. A Emkkxin. I O V P. Si. &gt;n. ■ G. A. l.o\u anip. A. M W P. S\M&gt;H:. M Plan. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">STUDIES IN WATER REQUIREMENTS OF CORN. (,. MONTMOMEBY A.\"l» T. A. K1KSSKI.I: v&lt; 1 1 . SUMMARY OF PAST WORK AT THIS STATION. I ..i &gt;e\eral veins this Station has Ihh&gt;u studying the water ii-&lt;|iiiiTiin-iitN nf eon. In the Twenty Third Annual Report, one ol tin- writers reported a Hlifi &lt;&gt;f results secured liv giawiag coin hi in torn gill— jai-s. The priar ipal conclusions were, that mi ~ -•&gt;■&gt;■ the plant is doselv correlated with water lo*w i free water sm-fai-e. ariag iarreaaad or datfaaaad l&gt;\ the climatic tectors. An tX[Wli«W&lt; in whieh similar ean - were uiiiwn for 2^ iiiimths in pure river sand watered ,i |.|ete nutrient solution showed oulv a sli&gt;;ht relation ■ in the sti-ensjjth of solution and the i|iiantitv of water re - ■il to |trodtn-e ■ unit of drv matter. In ihe Tweati Fourth Annual Report, pp. !H-107. h further ' is made on work in IMt. A s|H'eial can was devised for a. «rk. and a lirass coil was tu»ed to distribute the water ilm i the soil mass. The cans were kept at five different de ..t saturation. The lowest water requirement par unit drv i was found to Im- with a saturation of U to fill per cent: In- tin per cent saturation was found to l&gt;e the optimum for rpp* \ield. llourl\ and dail.v records were kept on water rum the plants and on evaporation from a free water sur The records show a verv close correlation. The daily water loss fluctuated several hundred per cent. l&gt;ut was cloael.v i or related with changes in teni|K'rature. humidity, and wind \e|.»cit\. In all cases "transpiration" appeared to be essentially e\ a|M&gt;ration." </seg>
            <seg id="p004">II I In- I ll\ Wl-llll Kl. II in- factoi in Inniiiil rci-nlioii run in .lilt r til i krili 1 1 &lt; r»;it;i have ;ils&lt;i Im-cii &gt;&lt;-.iinil fors«-\&lt;-ral yean tar loss t&lt;&gt; li-.if ami ;ui&lt;l t« drj »i*iyfct. vv In- more rlox'h irhui-il in leaf art-a than l&lt; 'I I THKU IN 191 AT1ON ill ItKI.A I I \ i: \\ A I Kl: I.USS Ttl ITT. Ill tilt' |iiist it hils Imi-ii iiiiIi-&lt;I thai \v:i Ij related to Imniitlin th;in to . « 1 1 \ otlit'i ■nw iata regarding t In- relation of this los&gt; following i\|wiiiiM-iit was |iI;iiiihmI. Tim | |i| Out ».i&gt; li-fi often i the experinieni »nm . tliiit it liiul 1 lie liiimiiliiv of tin- &gt;ui In ill*- oiht-r an atteni|M was maili- in mill as [mm Tin- inon w-n- k&lt;-|ii .mixers wmt atta&lt;ln-il to tli&lt;- «rat&lt; •i-iiioiiu'tt-rs ami kTgrm w k«-|&gt;i riitmii .- i.-iii|»-iatiir&lt;- ami Bttn - wm Ml tw ii lioiis&lt;-s so that |i|-ai I i""lll\ all illtii-lc I asi-riU-il to &lt;lilli-iiiM • ■* in ri-laiivi- hlllllitlit v. III II rl I 1 . Kl I'll Kin nl null i /&lt;/'■" &lt;iir. tiiin jilmilx i/rnir/i hi t!u \ebni*k hi,,,, toil. Dry jfrefn house H Mean temperature VI am. of night Mean temperature 12 hre. of day degree* Y HI Mean relative humidity \'l hra. night (percent* Mean relative humidity 12 hrs. day (per cent i Total weight of eight plants grams &gt; . Average leaf area per plant ■ &gt;■) . inches 1 ,079 (Kl Total water used (kilos) Grams water to gram dry weight 340 0 Grams water per s&lt;{ in. leaf area Water evaporated from :&lt;6 aq. in h water surface fgTams \JM </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Corn plants (trowing in dry green house. TW i ans were watered from the bottom liv |ila' int watii' in the stone </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The pl:tiii&gt; in the liiiiniil i:iT«iiliiiiis«- attained i lit- greatest dn lit. Inn tli&lt;- total leaf am wmm approximatelx the same The ratio of water used t&lt;&gt; dr\ veifJBi was :UM in tli&lt;- dr\ house .ui.l l!tl in tin- liuiniil house, at th&lt;- idathrc praportiaa aetWMa the rafeer Pet|uirein«'iitn in iht- iwo aaaaea would Im- m 1 to " ."&gt;'• At the same time. i»|H-ii jai&gt; oi water were kept in tile liouaee. lire the evaporation froin a fl-ee water surface. The ratio 'iiiH in free water evaporation was exact I V the same as with I he plan The water n-&lt;|iiireiuents oj tTO}M uniloiihtttllv \ar\ wuli ferent BMtiaaa of the eeaattrj ami in iaVereal yean I illustraleil U\ the ralio of two mcceaaire \ears. l'JKI au&lt;l l'.M I The Kiinie raiis wen- useil 111 I he same I«h it i inn wilh all siiri'oimii iugv |iraeti&lt;all.v tac auae, except ihai tar soil had btwu ■ li. - bat tin- fertility wa&gt; abaal M|aal. Twelve cans an .n. I '.• In ami l«i rails iu l'.Ul in i lit- rulluwiuy laiile. Tir.l.i: '_'. I 'i iiiiI urn in null i iii/hi 191" Ratio wafr required to dry weight gTa&lt; Mi w«ter loss from satne free wa surface k 13 KKI.ATKIN OF WATKH RBQriREME&gt; JOII. P^KRTlI.ITi ihe soil tans used in 1!llO : \m ie nptill used in Mill r&lt; water re&lt;|iiirements when naiixe soils were us..! nii-e and when manured. Three soils wen- used, rpp til of low fertility, one of medium fertility, and i \. • Four cans were tilled with each soil, tillin}: tin- ran with inch lajnen in the order found naliirallx in the soi nid set of cans was |&gt;re|iared with the ilirif s.iils in ihe e wax. and to eaih ran in the semiid &gt;. t \\;is .idded L' 4 lids of nioislure free s|iee|i mailliri' which ■ i» ei|i|i\alelit to \" c t • a I ;t \ i linixl, . Stnt inn </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 &lt;|iiivalent Tt&gt; 4 i&gt;ouiids |«t can. &lt;&gt;r i&lt;&gt; .!" inns par mr, as it came from Hw \ards. 'I'lic soils niii\ Ik- l»ricri\ deacriaed as follows: N'o. l. A rcaJdwU aiadataaK soil, daaaad us sandy loam. This la ml had Imi-ii cropped for main rears, and was producing an • Id of about lti bushels of ron |*r men. In. i\ This soil was prepared to raprcaeari a soil of \mttr - iate fertility li\ tilling: the aattaai two f«-«'t in the ran with siil&gt;soil of No. 1. and far th»- snifaiv foot mixing No. 1 and 3. half ami half. The yields indiratt- that a soil of inti-r iate fertility was secured, as the average vield |»er ean for three iagrcea af tertilitj were ll'J. 1S4. and 270 &gt;rraii «ei&lt;r[,t rtappttinly. E. .'!. A Mack allmial soil 1 from a piece of cn-ek Ixittoiu on the Iniversitv Farm. The soil was Idaek alluvial for te»t and contained a £ood supplv of Imth organic mattei - ■itluglM in the third foot. The land was in pasture and m-\ei- Im-4-ii crapped, Imt a similar j&gt;iece in erop across the would make from SM to M bushels of corn under average &lt; iinditions. K. is |. :,. gad 'i were exa&lt;t l\ the same as 1. "_'. and -i. except J.A |Miunds of sheep manure had l&gt;eeii adde«l to the upper in each ■ T»Me '■'&lt; gif« tin 1 analysis of these soils for nitrogen, potash ptHMpaoric acid, and lime.- Wabash silt loam, adordins to Bureau of Soils, I". S. D.partment of .Iturn. ■ i.v Dr. K. .1. Alway. Ch- -fation. Kill. 111. N'cbr. Kxi </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 I i Taw.k ."!. [noiv*iM at Soiln I iiinl Total -oluble Acid soluble phospt, acid P(» L * ( Nitrogen |'Ota.~h K 0 Per real Pn &lt;rn I I', 46 ■ W'l.AN TA ■■b in Z, 1H 1^ hi 8beep manure II inn in 1 1 hull Hum in litituxli. films /ill I i Plant 'n ■lion of N 1. In • 177.' iil J Hi* i 2. Medium fertility :t. F.&gt;rtilf soil 142 »i«r 1 Int'ertile soil and manure Total i «oil i'i 1 1 and manure Total 1 lnli 1 MM H Fer' 44r»i and manure 0372 JJ^i. Total 4!»4» « liidi tu Rventiif • follow ini: i ;i I &gt; i - ' In- nctii i millllllt' lllilli'l'.l i I'll-lll Imuhh] &lt;&gt;ii flu- ;m TIk-Ii- wrri- fcim- cjilis of &lt;-:i.li suil I \ |m- and ;ill I JPMth. i-\.c|.I ill oik- ijisc w i 1 1 1 soil Xo. •! « Ik-it uih- phuil il v«*lope&lt;l smut .- 1 1 1 &lt; 1 \\;is discarded. Ic.-uins: onh •'! plant </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 - .1 |&gt;llolo&lt;;ra|&gt;ll nf I III- nin &gt;i' Ull-ll In earll ( .IHO ,-| ,\as |i|i»lin«'il Hr«ttrdiH|&gt; li&gt; llic frrtilit.N of llic soil. mini fur was |piimIihimI. Photograph* m» MhiHtrtttiRf t Ik- awi-ayc size of |il;mi in rack &lt;as«-. wiitt nnitf hoi :hmI ilr\. :inil ilu- water loss was much ii ;in\ |in\ioiis yrar sinii- data Iiim- Im-»'ii taken, i \\i-ii;li&lt;il ia.li dav at 7 I". M. ami waii-r ail&lt;li'»l to in saturation n th. lasts, grouped •eeordiag to mM ft id right ) upper row: I. Infertile soil: lower row: 4. Infertile soil plus manure; •'■. Fertile soil plus manure. &gt;i F.rtil oil plus ■ . a&lt; h. All ears were well |&gt;ollinateil «rmtlve pre4*rtlTe &lt;-ai&gt;arity of the &lt;lir Ih-iii to the nii-riiiiil wi-ijrln. Tli&lt;\\ »n» all krpt at To </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 % — a ■..__■ .fill 1 i isii i iiii i bh i*E?5 S«»C I gSJSi i MSItl Slit* i ISii I S rtieil iH,^ | gcjsi i M88I ?1H? I Sis* i - c lib .ise hhi mi r I ill ij^siSMiew ii66i x i- z -- all 1 : IK r 7 i~h it \ \ ~ 5= 5 i-~ I- Jk I BMSI P 2 POMS = * -5 1 ■='S*c'§c5 _ -?SSS i 1 il" t — — JU 1 _ 9iiei * B8ss 1 — nr-f .- i - x &lt; ' 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 1 5 8 if. sssa s??7r: a ins s i5 3 SS5 3 : HSSs il^ I §iEI r» i." t- a — / Bflll l rlS^'x 5" 5 Si i r i 2§§5 I * SSS § x S r- 1- S j •» — —..•* — — •*■* •"» M?l?l?l ?1 - .S - &lt; : ?! »i:23 « RS!S H £E59 B BSIS 2 5?i? ?, E: b'SS S gs2 5 S cc i^x^ Tirt- 1 * - - &lt; •re -- — ■=. x -c=x I 53 HI 3 - |^5ii 3 S SPSS 3S=S P =£2* — — Tin — — — — -^- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 minis i. Mini !t give reraltfl oi greateal mieiesi. Tin- i&lt; - .ilili- i-il«-ii uf ;i small i|iiantitv af iiianiuv is shown in limn B, i Ik- average yield ix-iny; practical M doahled. The I &gt;i-&lt;&gt;] mum ioiia 1 increaae is with tin- pmireal soil. A|&gt; tnil\ i h&lt;- am n of nitrogen au&lt;l arid sotaMe minerals Mil in the snils was much less available tliau dial pn Bin- manure, since the application &lt;&gt;f humr to either the li' &lt;&gt;r the medium soil, while nor giving a total quaatiti of t.u&lt;- • utiaeraJ eajwU u&gt; that of the soil of naiural fertility, i &lt;l a mill h nrpater j i«-l&lt;l. tii- irlaiion ot water retniiri-iiicnts to dry weight is shown in urn it. ami ina\ Im- mimiiiarized as in Table u. '. &gt; a hi mm II : SlmniiKi rililliri ilnj trcighi Utlil until The aililiiion ot iiianui'c to (he infertile soil had a marked in deomMiag the water raaaiireweata, inn ■ less aflaet aa tile soil. li is ui»t known just what results would Im- ah - ■ I under tield conditions. Inn in all probability they would ~s marked than in the aliove case where cans are used. The imlicaiions an- thai on sterile soils the addition of manure would resuli in a inure economic use of water, hut not much • llf i would he e\|iected on soils sufticienth fertile for a pood normal growth. Ema&gt; Im- of inieresl to note at this point that inanv invesii is have seemed a decreased waler re&lt;|uirement where ma ■ was added to soils in cans. &lt; Iften i|iiite sterile soils have . • i,n nix i, i •■hi ii mi tin il iff crent xnil ////»&lt;■■&lt; in 1911. Dry we l(?h tperp.anc W-yjjg-gjp . | ffram- Kframs I 'nmanureil I Manured l T nmanure- Manured 112 75 Hi »1 549.5(1 :W1 :*» i.ii. 1S4 :W 113M 47s 9(1 *41 ■in. 270 (W 172. M :«n </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 lli»- ainoiiiit of available fertiliiv nun vt-t I*- limitiMl. l&gt;e;|ther. ilt I'lisjl. India. h;is reienllx re|iortei| results. \\ lit-i-a - ■tMnl sizi-s uf rails wi'lv llseil : also il was ;H lflii|i|iil |o clici-k is with tit-lil |.l;iis. With tin- smallest jars the rater rr i|llirement was nun h larger tlian when larue jars w ere used, ami uinliT tii-lil iiiinlii imis tile water requirement was a|&gt;|&gt;ar&lt;-ntlv aUmt oiM-half that nf the small j:il-s. The addition nf fi-ft ilizcf &lt;&gt;r maiimv iMTCMni tin- water ni|iiii-*-im-tit in th&lt;- jais. Inn had ih&gt; inarknl ctffit on th&lt;- tit-Id pint*. Tin- results ai-«- siimma in the folliiw in}; table Small jars Larg« .jars Field plat- «•»"• N,fer,i,izer So M KHi »i7 7TJ 5111 Kteg also sit 1 1 rii I souk' dala iimler Held fonditimiN mi - having differeni treatment, smne bring iiiitnared and •• MUintm-r falluwiil II i&gt; resnl- ingulr. Imt tli&gt; it-Milis were about the same in In.t ■ Sl'MMARY Cam "limn in a ke|&gt;t art itiiiallx humid, comp « ith a greenhouse &gt;&gt;f natural hiimiilit \ . the ditfi'i-eini- Ix-inj: alM&gt;ut 20 ]&gt;*-r Mat, required onlv alMiut half as ininh water for a fina &lt;lr\ weijrht. B leather. J. Walter. Water Rtquii Crops in India. 1'ait II iirtnifni &lt; if Ajtriiiilturr In India Chen ical a , I* r, 'I ii in&lt; mi null r &gt;' '/" nf mi/ix. nx I'iixh. linliii I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 W hen 1 1 1 : 1 1 1 1 1 1'&lt; - \\;is iiddfri to soil nf ihm* desjrefS of fi-rlilitv, tin- w;iter i-i-«|iiiivnioni \v;ts decreased, the gNBtHl iMMM o&lt; - iiii-riiii; with ili&lt;' Iciisl fcrlilf soil. For tin- fcrtilt- soil tin 1 dc nail. ;iinl There is some doubt whether, under field ■ Idini: 1 1 i;i ii in**- to soils of good fertility would de </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>