<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00035">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0035</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Households Steam Pressure Cookers</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 99 The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Household Steam Pressure Cookers Arnold E. Baraga! Department of Home Economics LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY, 1938 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Experimental Apparatus 3 Experimental Procedure 5 Tests ot gauges 5 Tests of safety valves 5 Tests for leaks y Results o Gauge pressure calculated from temperature . 10 The accuracy ot pressure gauges 13 Safety valves 14 Cover seal and leaks 15 Conclusions i*» </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Household Steam Pressure Cookers ARNOLD E. BARAGAR* In a recent survey o£ the processing methods used in canning meats in Nebraska, it was found that 2.04 per cent of the meats and 3.27 per cent of the nonacid foods processed by pressure cooker had spoiled. 2 In contrast to this, the spoilage was 1.51 per cent for meats and 6.0 per cent for nonacid foods when the water-bath method was used. The greater spoilage of meats by the pressure-cooker method raised the question as to what might be the cause. Ultimately the success of the pressure-cooker method depends upon two factors, namely the proper processing tempera - ture and the proper processing time, and„when once.these factors are fixed by the bacteriologist, spoilage should be the least by the pressure - cooker method. It is easily seen that of the two factors the proper pro - cessing temperature is the one which depends} upon the pressure-cooker equipment used. Therefore, an investigation was begun to determine the dependability of pressure-cooker equipment. In the pressure cooker, high temperature is obtained by using steam under pressure. Since the pressure gauge is used as the indicator of temperature it is essential that the gauge register the correct pressure. Hence, this paper deals mainly with a study of the accuracy of both new and old pressure gauges used on steam pressure.cookers. At the same time, four other phases were investigated: (1) the proper functioning of safety valves, (2) the various methods of sealing the lid to the cooker, (3) the proper evacuation of air from the cooker, and (4) the use of a thermometer as a temperature indicator. The results for the accuracy of steam gauges used on domestic pressure cookers are based upon the tests of 23 new and 30 used gauges. The old gauges varied in age from 2to 24 years of use. Since the new gauges were ! obtained from regular stock equipment and the old gauges"were collected at random from cooperators in different parts of the state, it was felt that the gauges tested were fairly representative of those available and being used on present equipment. The results of the first and setond phases of this study are based upon tests conducted upon eight new and three used pressure cookers. The third and fourth phases-were conducted while the gauges were being tested. EXPERIMENTAL APPARATUS The apparatus used for testing the gauges is shown in Figure 1. A commercial twelve-quart cooker was fitted with (1) a mercury thermometer 1 The author wishes lo express his appreciation 'lo Mils Mary-Ellen Brown, Miss Leans Davis, and Miss Mabel Dorcmus of the Agricultural Extension Service lor their cooperation in securing old liaugcs and lo acknowledge the sußßtstion of Dr. P. A. Downs of ihe Dairy Husbandry Department for the installation of an automatic air release valve.. ¦; 'These results are quoted with the permission of Mrs. Edna B. Snyder of Ihe Department of Home. Economics, who'collected the unpublished data. j -;. '"777:: 77; '¦¦7-...' 'i 7 :=.- ¦¦¦ r 7;'._ |.... ¦ '..- • </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 which registered from 170° to 270° F. in two-degree divisions, 8 (2) a copper-constantan thermocouple for measuring temperatures within the cooker, (3) a safety valve which "popped" at 24 pounds per square inch of pressure, (4) an automatic air-release valve, (5) a petcock tor releasing steam, (6) an opening for the gauge to be tested, and (./) a mercury manometer to be used as the standard for comparisons. The thermocouple was made of No. 28 gauge enameled covered copper and constantan wires. The cold junction was kept in melting ice and the hot junction was inserted in a brais tube wh.ch had the lower end sealed. The installation of the S couple in the cooker is shown in Figure 2i The electromotive force generated by the couple was meas - ured by a Leeds and Northrup portable potentiometer. By this method a temperature difference of 0.7° F. could be determined. The automatic air-release valve was a Hdftman Specialty Company valve No. 1. This valve is ordin - arily used on iow-pressure steam heating systems. It was installed during the latter part of the in - vestigation when the effect of air in the cooker was studied. The safety valve was of the "ball and socket" type. This valve was chosen for two reasons: First, it released the steam with a def - inite "pop" and closed abruptly at 15 pounds pressure, and second, the spring in this valve seemed to be more rigid and less liable to dis - tortion than the springs in other safety valves studied. This safety valve was not a necessary part of the research equipment, because it was being watched constantly when the apparatus was being used. It was considered advisable, however, to have this insurance against blowing the mercury out Flo. 1 .-The Range lc S „n ß apparatus. h rf manomcte -. The petcock finally chosen was of the needle-valve type, which is crdinarily used on household steam radiators. This cock was chosen in ' MTTiTTi. a V.y'm lh*-rn*o*_*ci designed especially lo be used on small pressme cookers. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">7- Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers preference to the ground-joint plug petcock because it was easier to operate and was not as subject to leaks as the plug cock. The mercury manometer was constructed in the form of a U tube, of eight-millimeter glass tubing with the scale placed between the two arms. It was deemed sufficient to u_ ordinary laboratory meter sticks, calibrated in millimeters, as the scale. With this manometer, the greatest problem occurred in connecting the manometer to the pressure cooker. It was found that if the tubing connecting the cooker and manometer had too small a bore, water would collect in the tubing at pressures between 15 and 20 pounds per square inch. This water column was sufficiently high to create serious discrepancies in the pressures as read by the mano - meter. It was found that %-inch copper tubing would eliminate the collection of water. However, since steam began to condense at the upper bend in the copper tubing, it was necessary to install a water trap to pre - vent the accumulation of water on top of the mercury column. This trap is shown on the upper right-hand side of the manometer. All fittings be - tween the pressure cooker and the manometer were of either copper or brass. Radiation fins were fastened to the copper tubing leading to the trap. These fins helped to dissipate the heat created by the steam in the tubing and thus let most of the condensed steam drip back into the cooker. The connection between the glass and copper tubing was secured by means of a packing nut. Similar connections were used between the trap and the manometer, and between the cooker and the trap. All of these connections were tested under 30 pounds of air pressure and found to be free from leaks. It is essential in using this gauge that the entire system be absolutely leak-proof. As constructed, this manometer may be easily dismantled for cleaning and repairs. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE Tests of gauges.—For convenience, the gauges tested will be divided into class A and class B gauges. The feature which distinguishes the two classes is the method of coupling the Bourdon tube to "the pointer. In the class A gauge the coupling and magnification of the tube movement was made by a combined system of a lever and a gear operating a small pinion. The restoring force was furnished by a hair-spring. This method of coupling allowed the scale from 0 to 20 to be spread through 180 degrees of arc on the dial. On this scale the smallest marked division was one pound per square inch, but readings of one-fourth pound per square inch could be easily estimated on a two-inch dial. The coupling and magnification in the class B gauge was made simply by means of a lever. This type of coupling was found in several mechanical forms, but for each only 37 degrees of arc on the dial were used. The scale was calibrated in divisions of five pounds per square inch and it was difficult to estimate divisions of one pound per square inch since the dials were only two inches in diameter. The difference between the two scales is clear when it is noted that from 0 to 20 on a class B gauge corresponded to from 0 to 4 on a class A gauge. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 I The initial procedure for testing was the same for both classes. The cooker was heated by means of a small gas hot plate. Until the automatic air-release valve was installed, the following practice was used. The petcock was left open until the temperature indicated by both the thermo - couple and thermometer registered the boiling point of water. At this point the petcock was closed and simultaneous readings of time, tempera - ture (both thermocouple and thermometer), and pressure (both gauge being tested and manometer), were recorded. Manometer readings were /Thermocoupk taken 'n millimeters of mercury and / iniertedhtre converted into pounds per square inch. The heat was adjusted so that about four minutes were required to cause a difference of five pounds per square inch in class A gauges, and from two to three minutes for ¦" difference of five pounds per I /i'pifX square inch in class B gauges. Ter - n perature and pressure readings were I taken for each pound per square i^!^ inch mark on class A gauges and, lr^*W for each five pounds per square inch mark on class B gauges. The gauges were tested from 0 to 20. After the air-release valve was installed, the petcock was used only ,* t0 release the steam. Use of the air - /% brass tubty r _l e ase valve also eliminated the tin - s' certainty of knowing when all the air was out of the cooker. For each test, gauge readings were compared with the pressures determined from the manometer |j and with pressures calculated from IS the thermocouple temperatures. II Thermometer readings were not j /Solder seal use&lt;i as a check, because the ther- II / mometer temperatures usually had \y a slight lag unless the heating rate J-'.,.. 2.-Th_.mo.„u,,'. inflation. was very low. This lag was due to the large thermal mass of the pro - tecting sheath around the thermometer. Tests of safety valves.—The release and closing pressures of the various types of safety valves were checked with a Bourdon-type gauge which had its calibration checked against the mercury manometer. Both new and old safety valves were used in these tests. The valves were taken apart and examined for the possibility of easily changing their characteristics by </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers deforming the spring. After the valves were reassembled, pressure tests were repeated. "Blow-off" and closing pressures were recorded. .) Tests for leaks.—Ten brands of pressure cookers were tested for leaks. Seven of the cookers were new and three had been used for a few yeirs. . All of the new cookers had been heated several times before being tested. The characteristics of the cookers are listed in Table 1. The leak test was performed as follows. The pressure gauge was ' removed and into the cover was fitted an assembled checked gauge and tire valve. (An.old-style, brass, tire valve was threaded with 'A-inch pipe threads and screwed into one opening of a tee that was fastened to a six - inch nipple.) The cooker was loaded with blocks of iron and the cover ;. then sealed as tightly as possible with only the fingers used for tightening : the nuts. The cooker was then placed in a tank of water so that every- '. thing but the gauge was immersed. An ordinary tire pump was used tb attain a pressure of 20 pounds per square inch unless the safety valve blew off before this pressure was attained. As soon as the-peak pressure was reached, a stop watch was started and the time and pressure noted at . various intervals. The production of bubbles indicated the location of . leaks and the time rate of decrease in pressure showed the rapidity of the leaks. . RESULTS .-. ¦¦7;:.'&lt;-;; V. Check of the calibration of the Bourdon test gauge.—At the beginning of the investigation, a Bourdon gauge which was advertised by a leading pressure-looker company as a test gauge to be used by Home Demonstra - tion Extension agents for testing gauges on pressure cookers, was purchased for the purpose of comparison with regular pressure-cooker gauges. ' This gauge was used extensively as a check gauge while the manometer was being designed and checked. Henceforth, the mano - meter will be designated as the "master gauge" and this Bourdon gauge ¦ as the "test gauge." In Table 2 are listed seven tests used in determining the calibration check of the test gauge. These tests were made while the proper connection between the cooker and the manometer was being determined. In test 22 the connecting tube was 8-millimeter glass tubing. Glass tubing was used so that the effect of condensation could be observed. The test was terminated at 16 pounds per square inch of pressure because water began to collect on top of the mercury in the manometer. From the results of this test it was concluded that %-inch copper tubing could be used successfully. Tests 23, 24, 32, and 33 were made with the copper tubing connected directly to the manometer and in test 33 the cooling fins were added. In test 35 the trap was added and in test 53 the set-up was that shown in Figure I. From the results shown in Table 2, it was concluded that dependable readings could be obtained with the master gauge as finally designed. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 j 8 Table I.— Characteristics of the coolers. Cooker Capacy Material I— -S^ . Guogr^^ Safely valve —J J [ l&gt;l*c..U-laln|..ni&gt;J Jjo^j^n, N „. I &#132;,,„ '•&lt;-"-'&lt;"-'k - | '' Quarts ' " I V|&gt;c Tinned steel ever, enamel- Single band wilh tamihiiu-il -. - - 1'' 1 "eel P.'l one boh Rul.lx.-r uaslc.-i -&gt; I &#132; . ' **i,:t &gt; ¦¦ Needle "-~^ 7—; - *•' zl. 1' valve v-ilvp Six bolts on — valve &#132; &#132; cooker. Uakeliu- Combined - Li Aluminum thumh nuts Ground in „ , iaf '-''&gt; '' Needle S- 7.—: — '" H valve valve tight clamps -— va' v&lt;: with nakclite Combined - li .Aluminum knobbed screws lie.-..l &#132;.,! &#132;. 17 with safety 6 Ball and ' -— ' valve socket |, ,„ &#132;.. Hinged spring Combined ?!! ' limed srcel damns Ru bber kc| with safety 2 Ball anil Bolts on cooker ' — socka _ P .o .. w'un brass &#132; &#132; — Aluminum thumh nuts Ground x Needle valve 5 Ball and Bolts on cooker ~ -i_J_L_ — Aluminum thumh nuts (.round I? so Nccd&gt;c ""« 10 Ball and One central ~ ~ ***** r. ii a , ¦ sere' v tishtcning .. „ k1 1 _ArWmiim eight arms Ground v „ Nccd,c va,vc ' Bal &gt; •"" l Bolts on cooker _ " ~ *___ H .n &#132; . •V,i'' l bra« ni - ¦ LQ Aluminum thumb nu.s Ground if, „ plu S WC 4 Ball and " — — ii! A ground mini socket I m &#132; . Hinged band with XT „ , Aluminum one bnlr Ground 7 n NKalc valve 3 Ba &gt;' and Three bolts on " : ~ sock^ i , n &#132; cooker with „. '- 1° Aluminum brass thumb nuts Ground &#132; . ""S-VPe.- - Six clamps with ~ ~ --"¦ y°"" d '°' nt i 1 gg-5! . X &#132; .. . " Bakelite knobbed Combined ii 12 Aluminum thumb *rr,sv. Ground v « &gt;V,' h safc '-*' 7 Nc«', &lt;- ¦ -~^ ~ ~ ::-~ ¦ il A valve valve </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers 9 Table 2.—Chec\ of the calibration of the test gauge (pounds per square inch). _ ¦ Master gauge pressures in pounds per square inch Gauge ————— • —— reading Test Test Test Test Test Test Test 22 23 24 32 33 35 53 Average 0 ... 0.21 0.14 0.39 0.12 ... 0.23 0.22 1 0.97 1.03 0.93 0.97 ... ... 0.93 0.97 2 1.97. 1.97 1.93 1.88 ... ... 1.91 1.93 3 2.94 3.02 2.92 2.75 ... ... - 2.84 2.89 4 3.91 3.89 3.87 3.79 ... . ... 3.83 3.86 5 4.87 4.95 4.83 4.80 4.85 4.89 4.93 4.87 6 5.86 5.90 5.80 5.71 ... ... 5.72 5.80 7 6.8. 6.83, 6.77 6.75 ... 6.77 6.79 8 7.79 7.79 7.74 7.74 ... ... 7.75 7.76 9 8.80 8.78 8.64 8.68 ... ... 8.80 8.74 10 9.77 9.71 9.67 9.61 9.67 9.73 9.75 9.70 11 10.77 ,10.79 10.69 10.69 ....... 10.79 10.75 12 11.74 11.74 11.68 .... ...... 11.84 11.75 13 12.70 12.72 12.61 12.70 ... ... 12.69 12.68 14 13.67 13.67 13.65 13.58 13.65 13.64 15 14.64 14.66 14.66 14.70 14.62 14.66 14.70 14.66 16 15.70 15.63 15.61 15.64 .... 15.72 15.66 17 16.57 .16.55 16.59 .... .... ,16.61 16.58 18 .... 17.52 17.50 17.60 .... .... 17.69 17.58 19 .... 18.51 18.54 18.54 .... ..!..'. 18.64 18.56 20 -...., 19.47 19.43 19.55 19.74 119.57 19.55 19.55 21 20.48 20.44 . .... .... ' .... 20.60 20.51 22 21.45 21.41 '.Pp.: .i... 21.50 21.45 23 ...¦¦ 22.39 22.41 .... .... 22.49 22.41 . After a check of the calibration of the test gauge through the use of steam, the test was repeated with air. This calibration check is shown in Table 3.; .... Table 3.— Comparison with air.of test gauge with master gauge (pounds _ per square inch). 7 Test j Master Test Master Test Master gauge 1 gauge gauge gauge gauge gauge 0 : 0.0 9 7 8.88 1 0.81 10 10.00 18 18.08 2 1.93 11 10.93 19 19.03 3 2.77 12 11.97 20 ¦' 20.07 •¦»'.¦ 3.85 13 13.00 21 21.10 5 -.-78 ;.14' , ¦ 13.90 22 22.10 6 5.88 15 14.95 . 23 23.11 7 6.92 16 ' 15.99 24 24.11 8 7.87 • 17, 17.00 25 25.24 It will be noted that this check does not agree with the average reading listed in Table 2. To show that the difference was due to neglecting the thermal expansion of the Bourdon tube when the gauge was calibrated for. steam, the following experiment was performed. Gauge 14, which </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 was identical to the test gauge, was connected to the master gauge and brought to a pressure of 20 pounds per square inch and the corresponding master gauge reading noted. Then the gauge 14 was heated around the stem with a gas flame, slowly enough so that the glass and protecting case were not injured. The results of this heating in pounds per square inch, were as follows: Difference be- Difference be- Approximate (&gt;au;*c 14 twecn bot ami Master tivccn hot and temperature con - cold readmits K au«e cold readings dition of saURC 0 F. 20.00 ] 9 .4H 75 -•''¦"s 0.75 19.7-1 0.30 125 20.''0 0.90 19.7S 0.3*1 135 The results are self-evident. Gauge 14 was then again checked with Nleam and found to be uninjured. Since it was desirable to know the effect of heat on the test gauge and since the gauge 14 was not injured by heating, a similar heating was performed on the test gauge. As before, the pressure was brought to 20 pounds per square inch and the corresponding master-gauge reading was 19.92 pounds per square inch. The test gauge was then heated and the pressure released enough to bring the test gauge reading back to 20 pounds per square inch. The corresponding master-gauge reading was 19.43 pounds per square inch, or a difference of 0.49 pound per square inch between cold and hot conditions. In Table 3 the pressure for gauge reading 20 is 20.07 pounds per square inch and the similar average reading in Table 2 is 19.55 pounds per square inch or the difference is 0.52. This difference is comparable to the 0.49 pound per square inch above. Since the effect of thermal expansion appears to have been neglected when these gauges were calibrated it may be expected that when pressure cooker gauges are hot they will not indicate the true pressure but will read higher than the actual pressure in the cooker. This difference between hot and cold calibration should be taken into account when this type of gauge is used by field workers as a test gauge. Gauge pressure calculated from temperature.—Gauge pressures may be calculated from the temperature of the steam within the cooker, provided the barometric pressure is known. The distinct disadvantage of this method of measuring pressures is the necessity of obtaining very small temperature differences. With the apparatus used to measure temperatures in these tests such small differences could not be obtained. When the rela - tion between pressure and temperature of steam at from 15 to 25 pounds per square inch is observed, it is readily seen that a small difference in temperature will make a corresponding large diflerence in pressure. The thermocouple was more accurate than the thermometer for measuring temperature because, first, it had a finer calibration, and second, velocity readings could be taken. If the rate of heating is too fast the thermometer temperatures will lag a few degrees behind the thermocouple temperatures </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers but if a slow rate of heating is used, good agreement between master gauge and thermocouple readings may be obtained, and the thermometer agreement will be fair. As an illustration of a typical test, a complete data sheet for gauge 13 for a slow rate of heating is shown in Table 4. Table 4. — Test data for gauge 13 (barometric pressure 14.21 — a1l pressure ¦ data in pounds per square inch). Pressure Pressure Thermo- Thcrmom- "Temper- Gauge Master- computed computed Thermo- , * autre com - -13 gauge from . , from couple mner. r ' puted: , pressure pressure thermo- thermom- c. m. f. . from total' couple ctcr *"ure 3'ure pressure Mt&gt;. ° F. . . °F. "F. 0 0.17 0.15 0.19 4.22 210.8 211.0 210.9 7 1 1.06 1.32 0.49 432 214.8 212.0 213.9 2 2.09 2.07 1.54 4.38 217.2 215.5 217.2 3 3.21 3.39 ; 2.48 4.48 221.2 218.5 220.7 4 4.00 : 3.93 3.66 ' 4.52 222.8 222.0 223.0 5 4.87 5.06 " 4.52 4.60 226.0 224.5 225.5 6 5.86 5.60 5.60 4.64 227.5 227.5 228.2 7 6.85 6.75 6.57 4.72 230.5 230.0 230.7 8 7.74 7.35 7.35 4.76 . 232.0 232.0 232.9 9 8.72 8.33 8.37 4.82 234.4 234.5 235.3 10 9.57 9.34 9.21 4.58 236.8 236.5 237.3 ; 11 10.60 11.12 10.53 4.98 240.8 239.5 239.7, 12 11.66 11.48 11.43 , 5.00 241.6 241.5 242.0 ' 13 12.69 12.24 12.37 5.04 243.2 243.5 244.1 14 . 13.65 13.39 13.10 5.10 245.6 245.0 246.1 15 14.62 14.93 14.07 5.18 248.7 247.0 248.1 16 15.57 16.62 15.09 - 5.22 250.0 249.0 249.9 17 16.49 16.46 16.17 5.26 251.6 251.0 251.6 18 17.40 17.31 16.95 5.30 253.2 252.5 253.3 19 18.43 18.76 18.03 . 5.36 255.8 .254.5 255.2 20 19.59 19.66 18.59 5.40 257.4 255.5 257.3 Even for this slow heating rate it is evident that the thermometer readings lag slightly behind the thermocouple readings. The superiority of the master gauge is more noticeable when first differences of the pressures are computed. The differences are quite uniform for the master gauge, whereas the differences are very irregular for the: pressures cal - culated from temperatures. The uniformity of readings obtained with the master gauge is due to the fact that this gauge is more sensitive than the portable potentiometer with which temperatures are recorded. Even though the mercury columns are moving slowly, they may be read easily to ± 1 millimeter. Thus the maximum variation for the difference between the left and right columns would be two millimeters. A difference of two millimeters of mercury amounts to 0.039 pound per square inch. To ob - tain this same sensitivity when pressure is calculated from temperature, it would be necessary to measure temperature differences of o.l° F., or with a copper-constantan couple to within 0.0025 millivolt. Since electromotive force can be read only to 0.02 millivolt on the portable potentiometer used, </seg>
         <seg id="p012">= T^^^—T^calibratwn chect\ of te n _new_andjhir,y_ old gauges. "il7 i iTTT " 77; '- -tAZ2 'PL "'- i.i his 1,. | 7 - ii -5 jj-— 111 1 il.lW ¦ _&#132; ¦•¦ . . \2.2S &#132;"« ,-„-¦; 'II ,„w IMJ ... _¦£ •¦• 11.1* ' ¦ ¦¦•¦ „i) IBM ¦¦-- 2«0 511 7 11..1 ... ". ¦ ... 1.'.11 l ... ,Vi 21.85 S S T SiS :.. :;; ¦ | ::: ::: ::: ::: S :'::.: .... ¦¦•¦ •¦¦¦ | ¦¦¦¦ "" :::: :::: jS *Batl leak in Dounlon tube. _, _ _ _ ! </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers it is easily seen that the master gauge lis eight times as sensitive as the thermocouple. The thermometer can be read accurately only to 1° ,F. Hence the master gauge is ten times as sensitive as the thermometer. Therefore, in testing the gauges listed in Tables 5 and 6, only the master gauge readings are given, and temperatures were used only as a rough check. The accuracy of pressure gauges.—ln Table 5 are listed the results of a check on the calibration of forty pressure gauges. ¦) These represent both old and new gauges. The new gauges were obtained as regular equipment upon nine new pressure cookers purchased at the.beginning of the investi - gation. An exception was gauge 33, which was tested for a cooperator who purchased the new gauge to replace an old one. The old gauges were obtained from cooperators in various sections of the state. It will be noted that the gauges listed in Table 5 have been arranged so that the master-gauge readings for gauge reading 15 will be in a descend - ing order. Gauge reading 15 was chosen for this arrangement because it is at this pressure that most processing is done. Only one gauge, No. 9, approached the true calibration, and this gauge had been used eleven years. .'-. ¦¦'-¦-' Not only should it be possible to build these gauges to be correct with - in ±0.5 pound per square inch but the test results on twelve new Class A gauges indicate that it is possible for the calibration to be within this limit. These results are shown in Table 6 ,-.. '{¦¦ If 0.5 pound per square inch ;is used as the l-mit of correct calibration, it is seen that only seven gauges in Table 5, numbers 8 to 15, were satis - factory at 15 pounds per square inch of pressure, j :•'¦- Table 6.— Calibration chec\ /or] .22 new, class A. gauges (all pressures in pounds per square inch), i Gauge. - Aclual pressures in pounds per square inch for gauges 41 to 52 icail- __: ' I • inn '1 '2 -13 ''¦- j?_______J £ _JL_J *••* 5° 5I s2 S 4.65 5.40 4.80 5.20 5:40 5.40 j 4.90 (4.90 1 5.40 5--W 4.50 5.30 10 9.30 10.20 9.70 9.90 .030 10.20 9.80 .9.807 10JO 10.00 9-30 &gt;"-'0 15 14.15 14.90 14 35 14.65 14j65 14.40 -14.40 14.40 14.75 14.65 14.15 14.65 ' Very interesting cases are those of gauges 33 and 37. The two-year-old class B gauge No. 37 was submitted by a cooperator living in Box Butte county, Nebraska. Taking into consideration the altitude correction for an elevation of 4,000 feet, it would be necessaiy to use a gauge reading of 20.75 if this cooperator were to be sure that; she would! be processing at 250° F. Since this reading could not be determined easily! on her gauge, No. 37, the cooperator was advised to replace this gauge with a new one. At the cooperator. request, the new gauge, No. 33, was tested. It is evident from comparison that the new gauge was not much better than the old one. ' The superiority of the class A calibration over the class B calibration is evident when it is necessary to apply the correction necessary for increase </seg>
         <seg id="p014">N-BRASKA AORL. Exp. Stat.ov R ... r&gt; _. „„ -&#132;.__„.„w . uuu.[ll.\ W »^'_____.-_,.,_-- i?%: •"™ 3» - «... i, A_. _sT__f^_Z,_ &lt;" «"«¦¦ •"d '*«*: _ =i.j=r: I_S_^=ksS.^ r__i-;-^^"-iiSSfti.2. - r -1. mSt* r-ti7_ ar.-•ss- Tab.. 7.-A./..,,, w /„„ (pressure in pomds saua^ _i_kr "" ~^^ ======= ======== !^^ &lt;____ pressure Remarks 1 -"¦'&gt; pi I ' ~ 2 IN.-, ,*••,, Sharp pop ' 2i.1l M ' s Sharp pop ' 7-I.I) , 5(l &#132;harl' 1»P ¦&gt; 22.11 ]-', .Sharp pop h 2J.il ?j' 5 S"-"'P l»P 2-1.1 ;„'„ gentle W '-Win to leak at 21 and clcitml when heal was ?H.. removed » 21.5 -¦ SI„«- fcafc 10 21 U -', B«*t!an to leak at 21 11 1« 5 '¦" 1% leak — . 1% leak l Y ith -'- •- » "&gt;e .lean. „,*_ reachal and th v 1„ &lt;L e J'l,,^ whf n .*_. bW°* P™»u«r »_s The action of valve 6 waTllTn " C md' Cate L d shut"°ff P r«sure* However, this valve did not d„ ' "T^u t0 th« «** the first five, remaining valves bL„ toTe.t T ""J the, h! at Was removed- The blow-off pressures an JS, el S'ight'y bdoW the «««W higher th P an th_e Tndi at_"" T aD T "f^ .fT g° "° determined by removing the hear fr iV Shut"°ff PreSsutes were «to be preferred is Lbabl„" ™f f - Whfch of valve factor is that the vafve doeJ Wow off f„ f°^ T im P°rtant was satisfactory. V °ff and 0n th,s basls every valve tested nel^Tltj^ t£ " dean ' "^y *¦ W « corroded and Jet .team c.caw W* I"* maC l KssiWe ' they become Cape' Some valves »« better in this respect </seg>
         <seg id="p015">I ¦ Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers than others. Valves 5, 10, and 11 were old valves and in rather bad condi - * tion when received; they leaked badly and pressures above 16 pounds per square inch could not be maintained in the cooker. After cleaning with ordinary kitchen scouring powder the results were those listed in Table 7. The springs in valves 1, 3, 4, 5, and 10 (Table 7) could be removed. With the exception of the one in valve 4, the characteristics of the spring could be changed by. compressing the spring with the fingers. This caused the valves to blow off at from 15 to 20 pounds per square inch. By slightly stretching the springs, results approximating those in Table 7 were again obtained. 7 Coyer seal and leaks.— The time rates of leak for the eleven cookers listed in Table 1 are shown graphically in Figure 3. The following notes should supplement the curves. These notes explain the different rates of leak. Cooker A: The salety valve blows off at 18 pounds per square inch. There was a very small leak in the safety valve and a small leak around the rim. Cooker B: A very slow leak around the rim and an Occasional bubble from the petcock. The safety valve had been removed from this cooker. * 11'-iV ' ¦¦'¦ 7 I - &lt;J v \ . I I I ; ° •&gt; Tir. *&gt; to ~~&amp; Jo js -jo 53" — -io js to Ttme - minutes " Fig. 3.—Time rate o£ leak with cookers under air pressure. Cooker C: Safety valve starts to leak badly at 18 pounds per square inch. Very small leak at rim.7. Most of the leak in the safety valve. Cooker D: Occasional bubble from rim. Most of the leak in the safety valve. No leak from rim after 15 minutes. Cooker E: A small leak in rim. Greatest leak from safety valve. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 Cooker F: Very fast leak in safety valve. No other leak observable. Cooker G: Leak around rim. Clamped as tightly as possible. Cooker H: Very fast leak around rim. An occasional bubble from safety valve. Cooker I: Small leak around rim and from safety valve. Cooker J: Occasional bubble from rim. Safety valve and petcock leak badly. Cooker X: Not tested for leaks. Used with the master gauge. As far as physical effort was concerned, cookers B, C, E, F, H, /, and X were the hardest to seal tightly because of the small mechanical advantage available with the knobs. The easiest seal was made with band and bolt on cookers A and I. The tension on the clamps on Cooker D makes this clamp somewhat more difficult to operate in comparison with the clamp on A or I, but it makes a very satisfactory clamp. For convenience the central screw on cooker G outranked all the others, but it was hard to seal tightly and tended to wear excessively in one place on the screw. Exhaustion of air from the cooker.—With most operators of pressure cookers there exists an uncertainty as to just when all the air in the cooker has been exhausted. The usual procedure is to let steam escape vigorously from the petcock for a few minutes before starting to process. Even then there may exist a variation in opinions as to what constitutes live steam. During the operation of a pressure cooker it would be advantageous to eliminate this uncertainty of air exhaustion. Table B.— Exhaustion of air by means oj automatic air-release valve, determined by agreement between master gauge, thermocouple, and thermometer (pressure data in pounds per square inch). ¦¦ Pressure Pressure T . Tiler- Temner- Time, linn- lev \|,„. c ,. computed compuled Thermo- &#132;T' mom- -rare .Me. and t-aui-t jjau w /ram from couple , J clcr comt ,_.-.i .ccon.l pressure pressure itiermn- ihermom- c. m. f. "™V"- , cm . I ""Pic cer *""r per.- - . rare H.iromctrk pressure 14.2fi pounds per square inch M... ° p. = F o f __-," " 00 -O-" -OH 4.20 210.0 110.0 210.5 _-« &gt;&gt; 0.2, 11.119 OH 1.21 210.S 211.0 2114 —» . '-82 4.7J 3.94 4.58 225.2 2230. 5255 l+-*6 I" 9-69 9.64 9.73 4.90 2)7 6 "*7 8 1377 «-j0 I. .'¦&lt;&gt;» H.W 14.53 5.16 248.0 24 SO .7 "— "&gt; » '•¦'&lt;¦ l.«» N-53 5.18 248 7 -48 0 248 1 25—15 15 14.56 H.SB KM 5.1» 4 S ' 7 "w 248 1 *-» » "¦*¦ &gt;___ &gt;___ 5.18 2487 MM 248 1 ' R|« in rempcrature vu, lon rapid, makinn Ihermomcler lj« hehin.l llierm..couple - Readme uken when j&gt;re.,ure wa, decreasing. The air valve previously described met the necessary requirement as far as the testing of gauges was concerned. It was given many tests and agreement within experimental error was always obtained between thermo - couple, thermometer, and master gauge. A typical set oi test data is given in Table 8. It should be noted that a change of 0.01 millivolt in any of the electromotive force readings would make the thermocouple temperatures agree closely with temperatures calculated from total press- </seg>
         <seg id="p017">II Pressure Gauges on Steam Pressure Cookers ures. Thus, thermocouple temperatures are within the experimental error. I At the 15-pound-per-square-inchmark the heat was regulated as closely as possible to keep the pressure constant, but there was a slight fluctuation | in pressure and the thermometer lagged behind the other readings in some j cases. Enough tests were made upon the air valve to make sure that the ":.-. use of such a valve is practicable. The only necessary change would be , to design the valve in such a way that it would not be injured by grease from meats. If such a valve could be designed it would be practical to have it on all cookers because then the uncertainity of air exhaustion would be eliminated. COtiCLUSIOSS i; In order to check the calibration of a pressure gauge on steam pressure . jj;.. cookers by the use of steam it is necessary that the gauge used for compari - son will not be affected by temperature. The mercury gauge described in this paper meets all the necessary conditions for being a master gauge. Furthermore, it is simple to construct and can be made at low cost. | From the test results on the Bourdon test gauge, it is evident that comparable repeat readings may be obtained with the mercury master 7 Sau_ e* The test gauge results show further that when steam is used, the V Bourdon gauge will read higher than it should because of the thermal :';i expansion of the Bourdon tube. "." 7i.-¦'.-' 7 ¦¦'; The tests on fifty-two new and old gauges showed that many gauges ;'..; being used on pressure cookers are seriously off-calibration. Since these 7- gauges represent a cross-section of what may be expected in actual use, 77 one of the conclusions to be drawn from these tests is that pressure gauges | used on steam pressure cookers should be periodically checked. Further, since the temperatures indicated on pressure gauges are only true when . 7: the gauge calibration is correct and readings are being taken at sea level, the use of these temperatures as a processing guide is misleading and the markings of temperature on pressure-gauge dials should be discontinued. . '¦¦'! All temperature readings should be taken with a reliable thermometer. - -¦' 3 gauges should have at least a two-inch dial with the *'i scale from oto 20 spread over at least 180 degrees of the dial face. The ?,'¦&gt; scale should be marked in one-pound-per-square-inch divisions with space J'| enough between divisions to estimate to within a half pound per square J i inch. Gauges should be accurate to within a half pound per square inch when new and they should be built in such a manner that they will 7, retain this accuracy when carefully used. ?;'; Safety valves appear to be dependable as long as the characteristics of V; the spring remain unchanged. 7 Some valves are hard to clean and unless 7; i the valve and valve seat are kept clean and polished, leaks in the safety iv; valve are liable to develop. jg; Only two of the cookers leaked badly around the rim. In both cases ?f 7; the cause for this may be attributed to inaccurate grinding of the joint. In :"A; all the other cookers the major leaks were in the safety valve and petcocks. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 99 As far as physical effort is concerned the cookers sealed with a band are the easiest to operate. Thumb nuts usually do not furnish enough mechanical advantage. The installation of an automatic air-release valve eliminated the un - certainty of knowing when all the air was out of the cooker. If such a valve could be so constructed that it would not be made inoperative by contamination from grease, it would be practical to have it as regular equipment on all domestic pressure cookers. nam </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>