<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS</title>
               <date value="1933">1933</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS With the close of the testing season for 1933 came the end of the fourteenth year of tractor tesfing at the University of Nebraska. The numbers of complete tests conducted a|nd re - ported for these years are as follows : 1920 1921 1022 1023 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 19! 3 Total 65 16 6 J2 10 8 12 15 7 16 10 14 12 9J 210 This bulletin summarizes the results of 80 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported by their manufacturers as on the market January 1, 1934. If a tractor has been tested but is not listed m this bulletin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discontinued. AH tractors tested are certified by their manufacturers as being stock-model machines, conforming to specifications filed with the application for test. No special or high-test fuels are used. All results shown m reports are' those actually attained m tests and are without corrections or allowances for friction, temperature, altitude, etc. These results are accomplished with the tractor m charge of skilled operators employed by the University. Beginning with 1928 the "one carburetor setting!' was adopted and all results shown on reports of tests made m 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, and 1933 were obtained with the carburetor adjustment remaining unchanged throughout all parts of- the complete test. In determining the highest drawbar and belt ratings permissible under the A. S. |A. E.&gt; and S. A. E. rating code, runs are made at a 100 per cent maximum carburetor setting. All other runs are made! at an "operating setting," which may be 100 per cent, or, as is usually the case, some percentage less than that. The "operat - ing setting" appears m Column 10 of the folded summary sheet. A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test is completed, and this bulletin is compiled from these re - ports and from the specifications filed with the application for test. Copies of the original three-page reports are {avail - able at 5 cents per report (on one tractor) from the Djepart - ment of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. By remitting $1.00 those desiring future reports without delay will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 4 Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4. Beeman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 22 to July 2, 1920. Heinze "AX1" magneto. Kingston "J" carburetor. Don - aldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, Uhead, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 4W', width 3%", rotates at engine speed. Chassis: Two drive wheels in front, 2 caster wheels in rear. Clutch own make, both external and internal ex - panding. Rated Speeds: 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced carburetor. Test No. 29. LA CROSSE 12-24. La Crosse Tractor Company, La Crosse, Wisconsin. August 2 to 5, 1920. Atwater-Kent "K3" magneto and dry batteries. Stromberg "MB3" carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11", width iy_", rated speed 900 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, own clutch contracting band type. Open gear drive. Rated Speed: 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 lines. Replaced fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. Test NO. 70. MINNEAPOLIS 17-30. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. March 28 to April 2, 1921. Dixie "46" magneto. Kingston "E" 18/4" carburetor. Bennett 1V_" dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft crosswise, Detroit mechanical lubricator. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; own make disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.06 miles per hour; high, 2.70 miles per hour; reverse, 1.97 miles per hour. Comments: Fan belt shortened. Clutch and valve rods adjusted. Light weight on front wheels when drawbar load is heavy, interfering with steering* Test No. 73. WETMORE 12-25. H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa. April 6 to 12, 1921. Splitdorf Aero magneto. Schebler "ATX47" IVi" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. Weidely fly-ball type governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Tractor Tests 5 Engine : Vertical valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 63,4", rated speed 1088 R.P.M. j Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate! 3V£ miles per hour ; high, 5.9 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand operation of throttle was necessary to control engine speed withih safe limits of loads three-fourths rating and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING "FARMALL." International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. Sep - tember 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf "Aero" 937950 magneto. Ensign "3DA600F" 1" carburetor. Pomona Model 118 oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 6V2", rated speed 696 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 118. THE MINNEAPOLIS TYPE B 17-30. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Min - nesota. October 21 to November 12, 1925. American Bosch "ED21TC" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler "A" II/2" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Dutroit lubricator. | Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15%". width 7%". rated speed 825 R.P.M. I Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive: disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.23 miles per hour ; high, 2.84 miles per hour. Comments: It was necessary to drill 8 holes before the left extension rim could be attached. After the limbering-up run and before any official data were taken the engine head was removed, the carbon cleaned out, and all valves ground. During the limbering-up run and the rated drawbar test, the fuel line clogged up, requiring stops for cleaning out. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 6 Test No. 121. TWIN CITY "TY" 17-28. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 17 to 21, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Bennett dry cen - trifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Holly "257" carburetor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16", width 6", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, disc clutch, 6" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.75 miles per hour. Comments: During the drawbar tests it was necessary to place two small bolts in the gear shift lock to keep gear's in mesh. It was necessary to adjust the governor several times on drawbar test to maintain proper engine speed. Test No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler "A" carburetor. Donaldson Duplex oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21", width 8V2", rated speed 466 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.87 miles per hour. Comments : During bot hthe rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be read - justed. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. September 7 to 16, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. , Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15V&amp;", width 8", rated speed 666 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.47 miles per hour; high, 3.48 miles per hour; reverse, 1.94 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests 7 Test No. 134. WALLIS 20-30. J. I. Case Plow Works, Racine, Wisconsin. April 29 to May 10, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Kingston "L 3" car - buretor. Wallis dry "cloth screen type" air cleaner. Picker - ing fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter isy 2 ", width 7", i rated speed 476 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, ! clutch dry plate with disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.75 miles per hour; high 3.331/3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: The rate of travel of this tractor is : Low, 2.88 miles per hour; high, 3.49 miles per hour; reverse, 2.88 miles per hour. The above speeds are calculated at the rim of the drive wheels and at 1050 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. May 17 to June 24, 1927. Eisemann "G4" magneto, Ensign "A" carburetor. Pbmona oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/ 2 ", width 9%"J rated speed 733 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.00 to 3.50 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.75 to 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after ap - proximately 25 hours running, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble! The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing gland nuts pn the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 136. SHAW MODEL "T2S." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7to 22. 19(27. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS6A" carburetor. No air cleaner. No governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 8 Engine : Vertical, F-head,. mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 5y 2 ", width iy 2 ", rated speed 275 R.P.M. •&gt;; Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain and gear drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds : Low, 0.50 to 1.50 miles per hour ; high, 1.25 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: During the brake tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The exhaust valve stem was found to be sticking. It was removed, polished and the valve ground. The exhaust valve push rod was adjusted to give more clearance and the guide reamed out. The inlet valve spring was found to be somewhat weaker than a standard spring. The inlet valve spring and cage were replaced with a new assembly. Before the official brake tests were run both piston rings stuck in their grooves. The lower ring was broken in removing and was replaced with a new ring; both rings were given slightly more end clearance than they had previously. During the drawbar tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The caster wheel arm was broken and replaced with a new one. The clutch shift lever broke and was repaired. The fuel line broke off at the car - buretor and was repaired. During the limber-up run a stop clip on the cultivator beam control broke. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifica - tions for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test: Ex - hibit "B" page 15 ENGINE SPECIFICATIONS. "POWER RATED CONSERVATIVELY AT 1 H. P. On tests develops about iy 2 horse power." Exhibit "B" page 8, "Figure 18 showing SHAW DU ALL Model T25 running in low gear pulling a road drag with scales indicating 450 pounds direct pull on the drawbar, which is sufficient to pull a ton load on a cart or light wagon." Test No. 137. SHAW MODEL 'T45." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 23, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS7A" carburetor. No air cleaner. Own make pneumatic type governor. Engine: Vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 3", width 2y 2 ", operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.00 miles per hour; high, 1.43 miles per hour. Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the following </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests 9 claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test- Exhibit "B" "T45": "DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a iy 2 ton load on a light cart or wagon.T' Test No. 141. OIL PULL 20-30. MODEL "W." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. September 15 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own maki car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7y»", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make double disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; intermediate 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.7 Imiles per hour. Comments : After the limber-up run and before the official belt tests were made, the lubricator could not be regulated properly. It was disassembled and cleaned out thoroughly. During the drawbar tests the compression on number 1 cylinder was found to be somewhat less than number 2 cylinder and there was considerable leakage by the rings on the compression stroke. The piston on number 1 cylinder was removed, the carbon cleaned out from around the ringd, and all valves ground. Both spark plugs were replaced with new plugs; the porcelains were found to be defective. The fuel valve and water valve required frequent adjustments during the drawbar tests. Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. Inter - national Harvester Company. Chicago, Illinois. October^ 3 to 8, 1927. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "R" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oil spray type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 151,4", width 7", |rated speed 661 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make multiple dry disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 143. OIL PULL 25-40. MODEL "X." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 6 to 13, 1927. I </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 10 American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 181,4", width 8%", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Fpur wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 144. ROCK ISLAND 18-35. Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. October 12 to 19, 1927. Dixie "46C" magneto. Stromberg "M 3" carburetor. Buda fly-ball type governor. United dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18", width 71/2'% rated speed 660 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 32 horse - power. Test No. 145. OIL PULL 30-50. MODEL "Y." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 13 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21^4", width 10", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc Rated Speeds : Low, 2.3 miles per hour ; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.9 miles per hour. Comments : On the rated drawbar test the water pump lost prime for short intervals. At the end of the test and during the inspection of the tractor both intake valve springs were found broken. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests 11 Test No. 146. JOHN DEERE 15-27. MODEL "D.» Ijohn ?9T1!2? ra ° r Company ' Waterloo, lowa. October 24 to Splitdorf "246 C" magneto. Schebler "DLT" carburetor fc.SC*"™"- DMialds ° n «WSS Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft dja^asskssiiijii*-* enciosed — and pJSSSSJiSiSa^sSrr hour; hieh ' 3 - 25 r" les Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. MS£; in^o,^^ w lS^- ron J »&gt; Jar, ca?^wi^L &gt; W^ 1S p,afe dr ' VerS ' CnClMed **« dri ™' t n ? a J c m i ?i &gt;eeds: i L ' &gt;w&gt; 214 *° 2Vs &gt; miles p« h »&lt;"-; Welt 34 to3i.iimlesper hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. "'&gt;•■' AtttHS rf A.l Wl P J° g "? were ad J»sted to 0.025". At tile end of the belt teats number 2 cylinder had a lpslru T&amp;SbSSr fl^t^r Were ,^ und aL n Sb?n d reUv a e k d y ihe carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 149. CLETRAC "40" 40-55. Cleveland Tractor Company Cleveland, Ohio. April 24 to May 10? 1928 "AT' £?hXn batt ! ry igDit -r System - Wheeler-Schebler fl^ll^ r g coe ov r ernor OmOna « ir Cleaner ' Taco TOI -S ngi 5 c iV V^ ical " 1 " head, mounted crankshaft length - wise k Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 aSrtiSggß^ssr' enclosed gear drive - ciitch: JS'SrC'LIU 1 .! 2 1? } ileS Pc ?: hOUr; inter m^iate, 3.5 hour m Per ; reverse &gt; 3 miles Per iJ^^^A 7 h^ att . er3 [ cable ™ulation became defective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 12 shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crankcase where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test. Test No. 151. ALLIS-CHALMERS 20-35. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 26, 1928. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson and Allis-Chalmers centrifugal and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Owen make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8.5", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2y 2 , high, 3J4 ; re - verse, 314. , Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 152. TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Mnineapolis, Minnesota. October 1 to 8, 1928. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carbu - retor. Donaldson and own make, centrifugal and cypress - moss type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width iy_", rated speed 651 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.36; intermediate, 3.17; high, 4.45; reverse, 1.74. Comments: Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 153. JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE" 10-20. John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 22 to 29, 1928. Fairbanks-Morse "John Deere" magneto. Ensign "BJ" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil - fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 6V2", rotates at crankshaft speed. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests 13 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch : Own make, disc type. Rated speeds: miles per hour: Low, 2V&amp;; intermediate, 3% ; high, 4% ; reverse, 2. • I Comments: Before the operating maximum belt test, oil was found to be leaking from around the flywheel end of the crankshaft. This was repaired by readjusting the gasket and tightening gasket cover plate. Test No. 154. ADVANCE-RUMELY "DO ALL," Ad - vance-Rumely Thresher Company, La Porte, Indiana. Octo - ber 29 to November 24, 1928. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "Ml" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 5V£", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.625; high, 3.75; re - verse, 2.875. I Comments : On the rated and maximum load drawbar tests, it was necessary to improvise a method of locking tie gear shift lever m place to prevent the gears from slipping out of mesh under load. Test No. 155. CASE "L" 26-40. J. I. Case Threshing Machine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. March 16 to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L 3" carburetor. Own make oil fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8%", rated speed 780 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.5 ; intermediate, 3.25 ; high, 4.00 ; reverse, 2.75. Comments: Before the official belt tests were r { \m, the weighted air valve m the carburetor was given a few thous - andths inch end clearance. Approximately 5/32 inch was re - moved from the crown of the belt pulley. Test No. 156 McCORMICK-DEERING (Model 15-30) 22-36. International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. March 30 to April 9, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 14 Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "RW" carburetor. Pomona oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16.75", width 9", rated speed 593 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.50; intermediate, 3.25; high, 3.75; reverse, 2.25. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 157. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 15-25 (Distillate). Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. April 24 to May 3, 1929. Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6y&gt;", rated speed 675 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. ! Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.75; intermediate, rione; high, 4.00; reverse, 1.75. j Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. i Test No. 158. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 18-30 (Gasoline)., Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. May 4 to 8, 1929. Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6y 2 ", rated speed 675 R.P.M. Chassis: Foor wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.75; intermediate, none; high, 4.00; reverse, 1.75. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. &gt; Test No. 161. BAKER 43-67. A. D. Baker Company, Swanton, Ohio. May 16 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. . - </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests 15 Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15y 2 ", width 8y&gt;", rated speed 774 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2 to 2.5 ; intermediate, none; high, 3 to 3.5; reverse, 2.5. Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in| mesh during the high gear maximum and rated load drawbar tests. Test No. 162. MINNEAPOLIS 27-42. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. May 28 to June 11, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "UTR" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15y 2 ", width 7y 2 ", rotates at crank - shaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.69; intermediate, none; high, 3.42; reverse, 2.52. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 163. MINNEAPOLIS 39-57. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. June 5 to 14, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air c eaner. Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 20", width 8y 2 ", rated speed 620 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 3.00; intermediate, none; high, 3.90; reverse, 2.49. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the fan b^lt was tightened. During the low gear maximum drawbar test the gears slipped out of mesh several times. It was necessary to lock the gear shift lever in place with a block of wood. I Test No. 164. WALLIS 12-20. The Massey-Harris Com - pany, Racine, Wisconsin. June 18 to 27, 1929. American Bosch "U4Ed2" magneto. Kingston "L3y" car - buretor. Own make oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 16 Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - ,wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 17", width 6 5/16", rated speed 1 540.5 R.P.M. I Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry, three plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2y 3 ; intermediate, 3!/3; high, 4y 8 ; reverse, 2y 3 . Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the car - buretor and fuel tank were removed and the entire fuel system thoroughly cleaned. Test No. 167. CASE "C" 17-27. J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. August 12 to 19, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto. Kingston "L3" carbu - retor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 101/4", width 6y 2 ", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.30; intermediate, 3.28; high, 4.50; reverse, 2.59. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar test, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged up and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36. The Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. August 19 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Donaldson oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 17", width 8V2", rated speed 616R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate type. . Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.32; intermediate, none; high, 3.08; reverse, 1.83. Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC." J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. September 10 to 18, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carburetor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball. type. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests 17 Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lungth - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 101,4", width 6V2", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.60; intermediate, 3.72; high, 5.14; reverse, 2.95. T Comments: It was necessary to raise the oil level m the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. Test No. 170. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UNITED" MODEL "U." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. October 21 to November 7, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Schebler "HD" carburetor. Donaldson, and own, centrifugal and oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Continental, centrifugal type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lungth- T^ql'u?^ pulley: Di ameter 10", width 7y 2 ", rated [speed Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rockford, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2VJS; intermediate, 31/3; high, 5; reverse, 2%. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 171. MONARCH "35"-30. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. November 4 to 9, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Zenith "6C" carburetor. Own make oil filter and centrifugal type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. No belt pulley. Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.84; intermediate, 2.76; high, 4.01; reverse, 2.13. •- T Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests the econ - omizer jet on the carburetor became loose at its lower end and had to be soldered twice. Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene). Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 11 to April 8 1 1930 Robert Bosch "FU" 48R529 magneto. Kingston "MD2" carburetor. Own make, water-type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9V 2 ", width 6V 2 ", rated speed' 1100 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 18 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 13,4; intermediate, 3y 8 ; high, 7% ; reverse, 3. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was replaced. The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt test. Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline). Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 20 to April 10, 1930 Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto. Zenith "IN5F" carburetor. Own make, water-type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9y 2 ", width 6y 2 ", rated speed 1100 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2y 8 ; intermediate, 3V8 ; high, 7V4 ; reverse, 3. Comments : During the rated load belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifth turn. Test No. 175. TWIN CITY 11-20, MODEL KT. Minne - apohs-Mohne Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Min - nesota. March 24 to April 12, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2V7" magneto. Stromberg "UT1" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit air cleaner centrifugal and oily fibre type. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", widht 7", rated speed 715 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.1; intermediate, 3.13; high, 4.15; reverse, 1.8. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 176. OUVER HART-PARR "ROW CROP." Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Hart-Parr Division, Charles City, Iowa. April 14 to 24, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Ensign Model "K ,f carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length- 1 toop p m pulley: Diameter 14^,", width 7y 2 ", rated speed * \JVJ JL \ . JLZ • *'L • </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tractor Tests 19 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.6 ; intermediate 3.2 ; high, 4.15; reverse, 2.9. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. In the advertis - ing literature submitted with the specifications and applica - tion for test of this tractor we find the following claimfe are not substantiated by the results of this test : Exhibit "B" — Folder A 135 — "they do end wheel slippage" and "they dbnot slip." Exhibit "C" — Folder A 143 — Same as above. Exhibit "D" — Folder 4 144 — "Positive traction at the tiptoe wjieels assures delivery of every ounce of engine power to the draw - bar." Exhibit "F"— Folder A 146— "They do not slip." I Test No. 177. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PUR - POSE." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin. May 5 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Zenith "94T0" car - buretor. Massey-Harris, oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Governor, Hercules, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed 802 R.P.M. j Chassis: Four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.20; intermediate, 3.20; high, 4.00; reverse, 2.50. ■ Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 179. MONARCH "50." The Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois. June 27 to July 3, 1930. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Zenith "C-6" carburetor. Own, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12i/ 2 ", width B*4", rated speed J0.6 xv*Jt*JYL&gt; Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own, single disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.82: intermediate, 2.76; high, 3.99; reverse, 2.06. Comments : During the rated drawbar test, the water pump packing gland was tightened. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 20 Test No. 180. OLIVER HART-PARR (2-3 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa. July 7 to 15, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Ensign "KZ" carbu - retor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, weight type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14^4", width 7y 2 ", rated speed 726 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.6 ; intermediate, 3.2 ; high, 4.15; reverse, 2.9. Comments: During the rated drawbar test a lug bolt was lost and the lug bent. The lug was replaced with a new one. Test No. 182. CLETRAC 80-60. Cleveland Tractor Company Cleveland, Ohio. October 2 to 23, 1930. Delco battery ignition system. Two Schebler "HDX12" carburetors. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston governor, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 24", width 15", rated speed 477.3 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks. Enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.75; intermediate, 2.5; high, 3.6; reverse, 2.1. Comments: After the rated load drawbar test and before the maximum drawbar tests were run, four exhaust valves were found to be leaking. The cylinder heads were removed, all of the valve seats reconditioned, and the valves ground. Due to a change in weather conditions, the S. A. E. No. 50 oil was drained from the transmission, differential, and crankcase at this time, and S. A. E. No. 30 was used in its place. Test No. 183. OLIVER-HART-PARR (3-5 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa. October 13 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4" magneto. Ensign "K" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshafe length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1684", width 8Vi"i rated speed 596 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Tractor Tests 21 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers. Enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.23; intermediate, 3.3; high, 4.33; reverse, 2.63. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 184. EAGLE "6A." Eagle Manufacturing Com - pany, Appleton, Wisconsin. October 21 to November I, 1930. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Zenith "96ATO" carbu - retor. Pomona- Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry, double plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2V£ ; intermediate, 31/3; high, 41/2; reverse, 2V 2 . Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 185. RUMELY "6A." Advance - Rumely Tnresher Company, Inc., La Porte, Indiana. October 28 to November 19, 1930, and April 7 to 14, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Zenith "156" carburetor. Two unit Donaldson and Pomona- Vortox dry centrifugal and oily spray type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted|crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 13", width B'f , rated speed 892.5 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, single plate type, lubricated. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.82; intermediate, 3.66; high, 4.72; reverse, 3.44. Comments : After the belt tests were completed but! before the drawbar tests were run, the valves were ground. the maximum drawbar tests the stationary adjustable mag - neto breaker point was found to be broken. Both points were replaced with new ones. Just before the completion of the rated load drawbar test, the portion of the fan hub which carries the front bearing broke and the fan damaged the radiator. A new fan and radiator were installed and ";he test was completed. Test No. 186. BATES STEEL MULE "35." Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Company, Chicago, Illinois. April 6to 18, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Schebler "HDX"| carbu - retor. Pomona- Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Waukesha governor, centrifugal type. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 22 ■fcJ&amp;felJ^^Hf* v ? rtica1 ' " L " head &gt; mounted crank - spfed 920R?M y '' Diameter 12 "&gt; ™ dth 9 " rated Twte a dis s c ; &lt;S a pk!te yer ' 2 tracks ' encIosed gear drive - Clutch: ZM^JFTtt! mil * s per 0 *° ur: Low &gt; 1-90; intermediate, 4.85; high, 3.80; reverse, 2.65. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. n Teatt i°-J 8 h fi ATES STEEL MULE "45." Foote Bros. 28 1931 Maclune Com P an y&gt; Chicago, Illinois. April 8 to American Bosch "U6" magneto. Schebler "HDX" carbu - retor. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Waukesha governor, centrifugal type. oW?^iv S *~ cyl l n&lt; ? er vertical, " L " head &gt; mounted crank - sp^edl^OR^PM Beltpulley: Dia meter 12", width 9", rated Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: twin disc, dry double plate. 9 Q^fj^Tfe miles P er , h f" r: L °w, 1.92; intermediate, -.92; high, 3.87; reverse, 1.40. Comments: After 15 hours of operation a leak was dis - covered at the connection between the oil line and the pressure gauge. The connection was tightened and the leak stopped. Four quarts of oil had been added prior to this time. Teat No. 189. ALLIS-CHALMERS "ALL CROP." Allis- Apr^ffto Ma^S! U SSf . Company ' M «waukee, Wisconsin. Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Zenith "C5E" carburetor. Donaldson and own centrifugal and filter type air cleaner. Continental governor, centrifugal type. D *3^ ne l/°. ur ~ cy i in _ er Y ertical . "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 7Vo" rated speed 1095 R.P.M. /_ ' Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Rockford, dry plate type. Ql?? t l?dlf P i eds, miles n p , e / hour: Low » 21 /s; intermediate, d'/a; high, 5; reverse, 2%. Comments: After 25 hours of operation it was necessary to tighten the fan belt. (The belt tests had been completed.) T J^ 1 * 0 - 1 r 90 ' JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE." ik i 0 E eere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. May 4 to uift?* 18 ? Jol ?J De fre "R2" magneto. Schebler JJL.TX5 carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit dry centrifugal and </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Tractor Tests 23 oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Two-cylinder horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13Vb", width 6 7/16", rated speed 950 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 214; intermediate, 3; high, 4y 8 ; reverse, l 3 /_. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 191. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PUR - POSE." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine Wisconsin. May 22 to June 12, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Zenith "T094E" car - buretor. Own, oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6i/2",j rated speed 802 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.2; intermediate, 3.2; high, 4; reverse, 2.5. Comments : Just before starting the rated belt test, the key which holds the belt pulley bevel gear to the power take-off shaft sheared off. The shaft, gear, and key were replaced with new parts. During the preliminary drawbar tests one of the differential brakes was found to be dragging and was adjusted at this time. During the 100 per cent intermediate maximum drawbar tests the connection on No. 3 spark plug was broken. A new plug was used in its place. Thej spark plug in No. 2 cylinder was cleaned twice during the maximum drawbar tests. During the drawbar tests three lug bolts were lost and replaced by new ones. Test No. 192. BRADLEY "GENERAL PURPOSE." The Bradley Tractor Company, Chicago, Illinois. June 10 to 18, 1931. United American Bosch "U4ED4V3" magneto. Kingston "7s" carburetor. Pomona-Vortox oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Waukesha governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted (crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed, 798 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1%; second, 2\'_; third, 3; fourth, 4y 2 ; reverse, \y_ and 2. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 24 Test No. 193. ALUS-CHALMERS "EK." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to Eisemann "G4" magneto. Zenith "C6EV" carburetor Donaldson and own centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, weight type. D v,?« gi i ne L^°^ lr " cyl i nder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width %V&gt;" rated speed 1000 R.P.M. y2 ' Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2i/ 2 ; intermediate, none; high, 31,4; reverse, 3y 4 . Comments : During the preliminary drawbar runs the head gasket on cylinders Nos. 3 and 4 was found to be leaking and was replaced. * ..nlV*}*?' 19 t' McCORMICK-DEERING INDUSTRIAL t i on? ot?5?^ Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. July &lt;_u to d_YI 9 1931a Own "E4A" magneto. Zenith "C5FE" carburetor. Own, oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1514", width 7" rated speed 742 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2y 2 ; intermediate, 3y_; high, 5; reverse, 3. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 195. CLETRAC "40-30." Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. July 28 to August 17, 1931 Declo-Remy battery ignition. Tillotson "Y7A" carburetor. Pomona-Vortox wet sump and wire mesh type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8¥&gt;". rated speed 943 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.06; intermediate, 3.05; high, 4.42; reverse, 2.28. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests 25 Test No. 197. MINNEAPOLIS-MOLINE "UNIVERSAL" MODEL MT. Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Com - pany, Minneapolis, Minnesota. September 30 to October 8, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED4V2" magneto. Schebler "TT" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit dry centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 14", width 7" J rated speed 715 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.1 ; intermediate, 3.13 ; high, 4.15; reverse, 1.8. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 198. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F 30." International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 9 to 23, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto. Zenith "K5" carburetor. Ov[n, oil - washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrif - ugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14%", width 7", rated speed 682 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2; second, 2%; third, 3J4 ; fourth, 3% ; reverse, 2y 2 . Comments: The pin which holds the splined end of the steering rod in the splined sleeve sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during the rated-load drawbar test. Each time the pin was replaced by another. Test No. 199. McCORMICK-DEERING TRACTRAC - TOR. International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 10 to 26, 1931. Own, "E4A" magneto. Zenith "K5" carburetor. Own, oil - washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrif - ugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15J4", width 7", rated speed 682 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate, dry disc. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1%; intermediate, 2%; high, 3%; reverse, 2. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 26 Test No. 200. ALUS-CHALMERS MODEL "L." Allis- Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois. March 17 to April 11, 1932. Eisemann "GV6" magneto. Two Zenith "C6EV" carbu - retors. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 20", width 15", rated speed 580-1232 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, double disc. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1.94; second, 2.45; third, 3.05; fourth, 4.10; fifth, 5.20; sixth, 6.47; reverse, 1.45-3.07. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test, the fuel flow was restricted by a flake of solder partially covering the outlet in the bottom of the supply tank. The obstruction was blown away from the outlet and the test completed. Test No. 201. CLETRAC "25." Cleveland Tractor Com - pany, Cleveland, Ohio. April 9 to 30, 1932. Delco-Remy battery ignition, Model "643V". Tillotson "Y8A" carburetor. Pomona-Vortox wet sump and wire mesh type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6V 2 ", rated speed 937 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Long, double disc. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1.95; second, 2.80; third, 4.00; reverse, 1.83. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 202. CLETRAC "15." Cleveland Tractor Com - pany, Cleveland, Ohio. April 9 to May 4, 1932. Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Tillotson "P1B" carburetor. Vortox wet sump and wire mesh type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10i/ 2 ", width 6y 2 ", rated speed 1042 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1.95; second, 2.80; third, 4.00; reverse, 1.83. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests 27 Test No. 203. CATERPILLAR "25." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. May 16 to 23, 1932. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "AeLc" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter liys", widthl &amp;W, rated speed 836 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 1.8 ; second, 2.6 ; third, 3.6 ; reverse, 2.0. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 204. CATERPILLAR "50." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. May 18 to June 11, 1932. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "Ke" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. ; Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13%", width 10"; rated specd 1 753 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 1.6 ; second, 2.4 ; third, 3.4 ; fourth, 4.7 ; reverse, 1.9. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, a valve rod tube yoke was found to be loose. This was tighter cd. Test No. 205. CATERPILLAR "20." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. May 20 to June 22, 1932. | Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "BeY" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10 V 2 ", width 6V2", rated speed 950 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 2.0 ; second, 2.6 ; third, 3.6 ; reverse, 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 206. CATERPILLAR "35." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria Illinois. June 6to 24, 1932. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "AeSc" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 28 «i,S? 8 _ le ifi, Fo - Ur " Cy S nd . er 1 ' "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 8y&gt;" rated speed 850 R.P.M. ' yg ' Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own dry single plate. • o s? a J* d JK e^ i f.» miles per hour: First ' W; second, 2.5; third, «J.Z; fourth, 4.6; reverse, 1.9. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 207. CATERPILLAR "15." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. June 7 to 29, 1932. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "BeT" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine :Four-c3'linder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9V_", width 6y»" rated speed 1050 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2.0; second, 2.6; third, 3.5; reverse, 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 210. McCORMICK-DEERING "W 30." Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. July 26 to August 10, 1932. Own, "E4A" magneto. Zenith "K5" carburetor. Own oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrif - ugal type. Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 !4", width 7". rated speed 681 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry disc single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2y 2 ; second, 314; third, 384; reverse, 284,. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 211... McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor "T 40." International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 11 to 20, 1932. Robert Bosch "FU6BRS 540" magneto. Zenith "K5S" car - buretor. Own, oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1634", width 9", rated speed 603.8 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, dry disc single plate. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Tractor Tests 29 Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1%; second, 2!4; third, 23/ i; fourth, 3^4; fifth. 4; reverse, 2%. | Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was found to be leaking and was replaced with a new one. Test No. 212. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F - -12." International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. May 1 to 10, 1933. Own "E4A" magneto. Own "A-10" carburetor. Own, oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrif - ugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12%", width 614", rated speed 800 R.P.M. I . Chassis: Three wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rockford, single plate, dry disc type. | Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 214 ; second, 3 ; third, 3%; reverse, 2^,. . :■ -, . . .. . Comments: Before running the varymg-load belt tekt, it was necessary to adjust the governor cross rod. Test No. 213. CATERPILLAR "SEVENTY." Caterpil - lar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. May 15 to June 6, 1933 Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Ensign "Keb" carburetor. Own, under Vortox patents, combination centrifugal, oij, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 11", rated speed 700 R.P.M. _;. _ Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate, dry type. j o ■ , Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1.7 ; second, 2.3; third, 2.7; fourth, 3.1; fifth, 3.7; sixth, 5.0; reverse, 1.7 and 2.7. Comments: The exhaust valve spring on No. 2 cylinder failed at the end of the rated-load drawbar test after 51 jhours of operation. Test No. 214. CATERPILLAR "DIESEL FIFTY." Cater - pillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. May 17 to June 2, 1933 Own fuel system. Vortox combination centrifugal, oil, and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13%", width 10 , rated speed 753 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 30 Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate, dry type. _ „ Ra i ed _l_ e ®?5' miles per hour: First « !••» second, 2.4; third, 3.4; fourth, 4.7; reverse, 1.9. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 215. ALLIS-CHALMERS SPECIAL "K." Allis- Cnalmera i Manufacturing Company, Springfield Works, fcpringfield, Ilhnois. September 21 to October 4, 1933 Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Zenith "C6" carburetor, vortox oil washed wir efilter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 834". rated speed 1050 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2.08; second, 3.10; third, 4.50 ; reverse, 2.39. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 216. ALUS-CHALMERS "M". Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield Works, Springfield, Illinois. September 23 to October 9, 1933. Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Zenith "K-5" carburetor. Vortox oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal tpye. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 834", rated speed 960 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rock - ford, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2.23; second, 3.20; third, 4.15; fourth, 5.82; reverse, 2.55. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 217. CATERPILLAR "DIESEL THIRTY - FIVE." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. October 10 to 25, 1933. Own fuel system. Vortox combination centrifugal oil and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Three-cylinder vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 8y 2 ", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate, dry type. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska Tractor Tests 31 Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 1.7 ; second, 2.5 ; third, 3.2; fourth, 4.6; reverse, 1.9. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 218. CATERPILLAR "DIESEL SEVENTY - FIVE." Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois. October 10 to 31, 1933. I Own fuel system. Vortox combination centrifugal oU and matted wire type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 14 7/16", width 13", rated speed 820 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own, single plate, dry type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : First, 1.7 ; second, 2.3 ; |third, 2.7 ; fourth, 3.1 ; fifth, 3.7 ; sixth, 5.0 ; reverse, 1.7 and 2,-7. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 219. MASSEY-HARRIS "3-4 PLOW." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 24 to November 10, 1933. American Bosch "U4ED4" magneto. Kingston "L-3-L" carburetor. Own, oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Kingston governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 19", width 7V 8 ", rated speed 525 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate, dry type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2V£; second, Zy±, third, 4; reverse, 21^. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the spark plug m No. 1 cylinder was replaced with a new one. Test No. 220. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F - -12" (Kerosene). International Harvester Company, Chi - cago, Illinois. November Ito 16, 1933. Own "F4" magneto. Own "A-10" carburetor. Ovpn, oil washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrif - ugal type. I Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 123/ 8 "» width, 6i,i", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis: Three wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rockford, single plate, dry disc type. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 285 32 n Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 2^4; second, 3; third, 3%; reverse, 2%. Comments: During the belt tests the spark plug m No. 3 cylinder was replaced with a new one. On the rated-load drawbar test a bolt connecting the drawbar to the drawbar adjusting plate was lost out. This was replaced. [SVJM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>