<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS</title>
               <date value="1931">1931</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS With the close of the testing season of 1931 came the end of the twelfth year of tractor testing at the University of Nebraska. The numbers of complete tests conducted and reported for these years are as follows: 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 Total 65 15 5 12 10 8 12 15' 7 16 10 14 189 This bulletin summarizes the results of 77 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported by their manu - facturers as on the market January 1, 1932. If a tractor has been tested but is not listed in this bulletin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discon - tinued. All tractors tested are certified by their manufacturers as being stock-model machines, conforming to specifica - tions filed with the application for test. No special or high-test fuels are used. All results shown in reports are those actually attained in tests and are without corrections or. allowances for friction, temperature, altitude, etc. These results are accomplished with the tractor in charge of skilled operators employed by the University. Beginning with 1928 the "one carburetor setting" was adopted and all results shown on reports of tests made in 1928, 1929, 1930, and 1931 were attained with the carbu - retor adjustment remaining unchanged throughout all parts of the complete test. In determining the highest drawbar and belt ratings permissible under the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. rating code, runs are made at a 100 per cent maxrmum carburetor setting. All other runs are made at an "operating setting" which may be 100 per cent or, as is usually the case, some percentage less than that. The "operating setting" appears in column 10 of the folded summary sheet. Another column has been added to the summary to show the code drawbar and belt rating and a set of three columns to accommodate the fourth gear on two tractors tested in 1931. A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test fs completed, and this bulletin is compiled from these reports and from the specifications filed with the applica - tion for test. Copies of the original three-page reports are available at 5 cents per report (on one tractor) from the Department of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agri - culture, Lincoln, Nebraska. By remitting $1.00 those de - siring future reports without delay will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 A mimeographed pamphlet containing the full text of the Nebraska tractor law, the procedure followed in the test, and the A. S. A. E. and S. A.. E. rating code is also available at 10 cents per copy. SUMMARY OF SPECIFICATIONS AND COMMENTS The following are extracts from the reports and spec - ifications of tractors tested and now on the market. Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4. Beeman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 22 to July 2, 1920. Heinze "AX1" magneto Kingston "J" carburetor. Don - aldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 4 1 /-:", width 3%", rotates at engine speed. Chassis: Two drive wheels in front, 2 caster wheels in rear. Clutch own make, both external and internal ex - panding. Rated Speeds: 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced carburetor. Test No. 29. LA CROSSE 12-24. La Cros?e Tractor Company, La Crosse, Wisconsin. August 2 to 5, 1920. Atwater-Kent "K3" magneto and dry batteries. Strom - berg "MB3" carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11", width 7\/»", rated speed 900 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, own clutch contracting band type. Open gear drive. Rated Speed : 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 lines. Re - placed fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. Test No. 43. AVERY 25-50. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to 30, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 22", width 81/2'% rated speed 700 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers.. Open gear drive, ex - panding shoe clutch, own make. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska Tractor Tests . Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 milos per hour: reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: Clutch adjusted twice. New governor spring put in to replace old one which was too weak. In the test the cab needed additional bracing to hold it rigidly to the engine frame. n,. 1 * 6 ** N T °\ 44 - AVERY 45-65. A very Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to August 3, 1920. K-W. "UK" magneto. Kingston "'Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. . Engine: Horizontal, yalve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 26", width 10", rated speed 600 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, own make expanding shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments : The rating of this tractor was changed from 40-80 to 45-65. Test No. 70. MINNEAPOLIS 17-30. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. March 28 to April 2, 1921. • Dixie "46" magneto. Kingston "E" 1%" carburetor. Bennett 1'V' dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft crosswise, Detroit mechanical lubricator. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; own make disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.06 miles per hour; high, 2.70 miles per hour. Comments: Fan belt shortened. Clutch and valve rods adjusted. Light weight on front wheels when drawbar load is heavy, interfering with steering. Test No. 73. WETMORE 12-25. H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa. April 6 to 12, 1921. Splitdorf Aero magneto. Schebler "ATX47" 11/4" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. Weidely fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6%", rated speed 1088 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3V*j miles per hour; high, 5.9 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station. Bulletin 265 Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand opera - •JL- tnrottle was necessary to control engine speed within safe limits of loads three-fourths rating and under, when carburetor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 104. BEST "S30" 25-30. C. L. Best Tractor iQ^i pany ' Leandro, California. September 15 to 22, American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Stromberg "MP3" li/o" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed 850 RiP.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multi - ple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.75 miles per hour: intermediate, 2.63 miles per hour; high, 3.63 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 105. BEST "A60" 50-60. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 29. 1924. American Bosch "ZR4Edl8" magneto. Stromberg "Ml" Special 1%" carburetor. Pomona, oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft. lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 10", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multi - ple dry disc clutch ; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1% miles per hour; intermediate, 2% miles per hour; high, 3% miles per hour. Comment: At the end of the test the vacuum tank leaked at the bottom seam. Exhaust valve on No. 1 cylinder would not hold compression. Test No. 110. CASE 25-45. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 28 to Novem - ber 9, 1924. Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Kingston "L" 2" carburetor. Own make water type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16i/&gt;", width 8V-&gt;", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; expanding shoe type clutch. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Tractor Tests Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 3.2 miles - per hour. ' Comments: During the rated drawbar test the right cyl - inder head gasket burned out and both gaskets were then replaced. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING "FARMALL." international Harvester Company of America, Chicago, Illinois. September 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf "Aero" 937950 magneto. Ensign "3DA600F" 1 carburetor.^. Pomona Model 118 oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 6M&gt;", rated speed 696 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 118. THE MINNEAPOLIS TYPE B 17-30. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. October 21 to November 12, 1925 American Bosch "ED21TC" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler A ll/ 2 " carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Detroit lubricator. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15y 2 ", width 7V 2 ", rated Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.23 miles per hour; high, 2.84 miles per hour. Comment: It was necessary to drill 8 holes before the left extension rim could be attached. After the limbering - up run and before any official data were taken the engine head was removed, the carbon cleaned out, and all valves ground. During the limbering-up run and the rated draw - bar test, the fuel line clogged up, requiring stops for clean - ing out. Test No. 119. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 22 to May 5, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 860 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments : During the half load brake test the oil pres - sure line sprung a leak. During the rated and low °-ear maximum drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to : Low, 2.13 miles per hour; high, 4.23 miles per hour; re - verse, 1.66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No 120. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 30 to May 5, 1926 Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make flv-ball type governor. . . Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6" rated speed 860 R.P.M. Chassis : Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated and low gear maximum drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles per hour; high, 4.23 miles per hour; reverse 1 66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. e JestNo 121. TWIN GITY "TY" 17-28. Minneapolis bteel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 17 to 21, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Holly "257" carburetor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, disc clutch, 6" extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments: During the drawbar tests it was necessary to place two small bolts in the gear shift lock to keep gears in mesh. It was necessary to adjust the governor several times on drawbar test to maintain proper engine speed. Test No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler A carburetor. Donaldson Duplex oiled fibre tvpe air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine:.. Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21", width 8i/ 2 ", rated speed 466 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive twin disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.87 miles per hour, Comments: During both the rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be readjusted. ■ Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. September 7 to 16, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/ 2 ", width 8", rated speed 666 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.47 miles per hour; high, 3.48 miles per hour; reverse, 1.94 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. Test No. 128. HART-PARR 18-36. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 25, 1926. Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MB3" car - buretor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Donaldson dry centrif - ugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Dry plate clutch. Seven-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 miles per hour; high, 3.00 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Comments: Before the half load brake test was run the spark gap in the spark plugs was adjusted to 0.020" gap During the maximum drawbar test one spark plug was re - placed. Two small screws were lost out of the carburetor air connection during the test. The crankshaft speed of the rated load and first maximum drawbar tests was low due to an error in calculation made by observer during test which was not discovered until too late for correction. Test No. 129. HART-PARR 12-24. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa, October 18 to 28, 1926. Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MBS" car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, dry plate clutch. Six-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.66 miles per hour; high, 3.33 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comment: During the varying load brake test both spark plugs were replaced with new spark plugs; one had a cracked porcelain and the other a defective gasket. During the low gear maximum drawbar tests the gears slipped out of mesh. It was necessary to improvise a method of holding gear shift lever in place. The low gear train of gears was burred slightly due to the gears slipping out of mesh. Test No. 134. WALLIS 20-30. J. I. Case Plow Works. Racine, Wisconsin. April 29 to May 10. 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Wallis dry "cloth screen type" air cleaner. Pickering fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve- in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18i/&gt;", width 7", rated speed 476 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch dry plate with disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.75 miles per hour; high 3.33 V:\ miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: The rate of travel of this tractor is: Low, 2.88 miles per hour; high, 3.49 miles per hour; reverse, 2.88 miles per hour. The above speeds are calculated at the rim of the drive wheels and at 1050 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. Mav 17 to June 24, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "A" carburetor. Po - mona oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/&gt;", width 9W. rated speed 733 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.00 to 3.50 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 to 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the ra.ted drawbar test and after appi-oximately 25 hours running, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing gland nuts on the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 136. SHAW MODEL "T25." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 22, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS6A" carburetor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, F-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 5i/&gt;", width I*/*", rated speed 275 R.P.M. . Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain and gear drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds: Low, 0.50 to 1.50 miles per hour; high, 1.25 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: During the brake tests the following repairs and adjustments were made : The exhaust valve stem was found to be sticking. It was removed, polished and the valve ground. The exhaust valve push rod was adjusted to give more clearance and the guide reamed out. The inlet valve spring was found .to be somewhat weaker than a standard spring. The inlet valve spring and cage were re - placed with a new assembly. Before the official brake tests were run both piston rings stuck in their grooves. The lower ring was broken in removing and was replaced with a new ring; both rings were given slightly more end clear - ance than they had previously. During the drawbar tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 caster wheel arm was broken and replaced with a new one The clutch shift lever broke and was repaired. The fuel line broke off at the carburetor and was repaired. During the limber-up run a stop clip on the cultivator beam con - trol broke. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifica - tions for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test : Ex - hibit "B" page 15 ENGINE SPECIFICATIONS. "POWElt RATED CONSERVATIVELY AT 1 H, P. On tests develops about 11/2 horse power." Exhibit "B" page 8, "Figure 18 showing SHAW DU ALL Model T25 running in low gear pulling a road drag with scales indicating 450 pounds direct pull on the drawbar, which is sufficient to pull a ton load on a cart or light wagon." Test No. 137. SHAW MODEL "T45." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 23 1927 # Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS7A" carburetor. No air cleaner. Own make pneumatic type governor. Engine: Vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crank - shaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 3", width 2* / -&gt;" operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.00 mile per hour; high, 1.43 miles per hour. Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the follow - ing claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" "T45": "DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a IV* ton load on a light cart or wagon." Test No. 138. CONTINENTAL CULTOR No. 32. Con - tinental Cultor Company, Springfield, Ohio. August 6 to i- If X x) £ I m Ford Model "T" ignition system. Holly "Ford" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine : Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. No belt pulley. Chassis : Two wheels, both drivers, open chain final drive, multiple disc clutch. Rated Speed: 3.00 miles per hour. '.. . Comments : During the rated drawbar test the left main drive chain broke. The broken link was replaced with a new link. During the same test two teeth were broken on the main drive sprocket; the test was completed without repair. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 139. MONARCH 10 TON MODEL F. Monarch Tractors Corporation, Springfield, Illinois. August 15 to 26, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Zenith "L7T" carburetor. United 1%" twin, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive, enclosed gear transmission, chain and sprocket final drive. Clutch own make disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.6 miles per hour; high, 3.3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. . Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 140. HART-PARR 28-50. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. August 17 to 31, 1927. Robert Bosch "ZU4" magneto. Schebler "D" carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine : Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: After all tests were completed and during the final inspection, number 4 cylinder was found to have little or no compression. The piston was removed and the top ring was found to be stuck in its groove, also a small hole through the wall of the piston in the top groove at the lap of the ring. The ring was released and the hole plugged up. The water passage between the cylinder head and engine block on this tractor had been enlarged to permit freer circulation. It is understood that this change is to be made standard on all tractors of this model. Test No. 141. OIL PULL 20-30. MODEL "W." Ad - vance-Rumeley Company, La Porte, Indiana. September 15 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7V&amp;", rotates at crankshaft speed. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make double disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.7 miles per hour. Comments: After the limber-up run and before the official belt tests were made, the lubricator could not be regulated properly. It was disassembled and cleaned out thoroughly. During the drawbar tests the compression on number 1 cylinder was found to be somewhat less than number 2 cylinder and there was considei-able leakage by the rings on the compression stroke. The piston on number 1 cylinder was removed, the carbon cleaned out from around the rings, and all valves ground. Both spark plugs were replaced with new plugs; the porcelains were found to be defective. The fuel valve and water valve required frequent adjustment during the drawbar tests. Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 3 to 8, 1927. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "R" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oil spray type air- cleaner; Own make fly-ball type governor. " . Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 1 /}.", width 7", rated speed 661 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. clutch own make multiple dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate. 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 143. OIL PULL 2S-40. MODEL "X." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 6 to 13, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make carburetor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1814", width 8V&amp;". ro - tates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 144. ROCK ISLAND 18-35. Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. October 12 to 19, 1927. Dixie "46C" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Buda fly-ball type governor. United dry centrifugal tvpe .air cleaner. Engine: Vertical. L-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley : Diameter 18", width 1U-," ', rated speed 660 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments : In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricul - tural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers* the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not ex - ceed 32 horsepower. Test No. 145. OIL PULL 30-50. MODEL "Y." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 13 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 2114", width 10", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.9 miles per hour. Comments : On the rated drawbar test the water pump lost prime for short intervals. At the end of the test and during the inspection of the tractor both intake valve springs were found broken. Test No. 146. JOHN DEERE 15-27. MODEL "D." John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 24 to 29 1927 Splitdorf "246C" magneto. Schebler "DLT" carburetor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson Simplex oiled fibre type air cleaner. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise.- Belt pulley: Diameter 15Y4,", width 7%", ro - tates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make disc. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Rated Speeds: Low, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 148. LAUSON "S12" 20-35. John Lausoin Manufacturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin. April 2 to 16, 1928. American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carbu - retor. Taco fly-ball type governor. Taco water type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 697 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2*4 to 2 1 /-&gt; miles per hour; high 3!4 to 3 1 /* miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: All spark plug gaps were adjusted to 0.025". At the end of the belt tests number 2 cylinder had a leaky exhaust valve. All valves were ground and carbon re - moved. The carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 149. CLETRAC "40" 40-55. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 24 to May 10, 1928. Delco-Remy battery ignition system. Wheeler-Schebler "AT" carburetor. Pomona oil spray type air cleaner. Taco fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3.5 miles per hour; high, 5.5 miles per hour; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comment: The battery cable insulation became de - fective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crank - case where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test. . • Test No. 150. CATERPILLAR "20" 20-25. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 17 to 29, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "AE" carburetor. Po - mona oil-spray type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11%", width 6V2"» rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch, own make, single-plate type. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.79 miles per hour; intermediate, 3.07 miles per hour; high, 4.67 miles per hour; reverse, 2. ,35 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 151. ALLIS-CHALMERS 20-35. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 26, 1928. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson and Allis-Chalmers centrifugal and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. . Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8.5", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2Vj&gt;; high, 314; re - verse, 3 J4. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 152. TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Oc - tober 1 to 8, 1928. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carbu - retor. Donaldson and own make, centrifugal and cypress - moss type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7 1 /&gt;"&gt; rated speed 651 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.36 ; intermediate, 3.17; high, 4.45; reverse, 1.74. Comments : Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 153. JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE" 10-20. John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 22 to 29, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station; Bulletin 265 Fairbanks-Morse "John Deere" magneto. Ensign "BJ" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil - fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 6i/&gt;", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: 'Low, 2i/ 3 ; intermediate, 3i/ 8 ; high, 41/3; reverse, 2. Comment: Before the operating maximum belt test, oil was found to be leaking from around the flywheel end of the crankshaft. This was repaired by readjusting the gasket and tightening gasket cover plate. Test No. 154. ADVANCE-RUMELY "DO ALL." Ad - vance-Rumely Thresher Company. La Porte, Indiana. Oc - tober 29 to November 24, 1928. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "Ml" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lonpth - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 51/.", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels,. 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.625; high, 3.75: reverse, 2.875. . ■ Comments: On the rated and maximum load drawbar tests, it. was necessary to improvise a method of locking the gear shift lever in place to prevent the gears from slipping out of mesh under load. Test No. 155. CASE "L" 26-40. J. I. Case Threshing Machine-Company, Racine, Wisconsin. March 16 to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carbu - retor. Own make oil fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8 14", rated speed 780 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.5; intermediate, 3.25 ; Tiigh, 4.00 ; reverse, 2.75. Comments: Before the official belt tests were run, the weighted air valve in the carburetor was given a few </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests thousandths inch end clearance. Approximately 5/3* inch was removed from the crown of the belt pulley. oo^ est t Nq - 156 - Mc CORMICK-DEERING (Model 15-30) ?? u i" terna A tl0nal Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. March 30 to April 9, 1929. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "RW" carburetor 1 omona oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. ' Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length- Belt pulley: Diameter 16.75", width 9", rated speed Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, single plate type. -Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.50; intermediate 3.25; high, 3.75; reverse, 2.25. Comments: No repairs noradjustments. Test No. 157. ROCK ISLAND "G2» 15-25 (Distillate). Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. April 24 to May 3, 1929. Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor Waukesha, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed o i 5 xv . Jr . J\l . Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.75; intermediate none; high, 4.00; reverse, 1.75. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 158. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 18-30 (Gasoline). Rock Island Plow Company,. Rock Island, Illinois. Alav 4 to 8, 1929. Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha, fly-ball type. ' Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6Vo", rated speed 675 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch : Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.75; intermediate none; high, 4.00; reverse, 1.75. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Test No. 159. CATERPILLAR "15" 15-20. Caterpillar 1929 Company ' San Leandro, California. May 9" to 14, Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "BeV" carburetor make, n ny'b a °n type 0 " ***** t7Pealr Cle3ner ' G °vemor, own Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length- U S&amp;K 1^ 1 }?* 1 Diameter IQWi width 6%". rated ri,?f^ SSi n Trackla y e . r ' , 2 enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, single plate type. 9 iS**™ l Pe Q e^ S « Q miles P^ r h o 0u . r: Low ' 1 ' 985 ' intermediate, 2.58; high, 3.568; reverse, 2.06. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. ■ Trl^* N n m 16 °- CATE T R PILLAR "10" 10-15. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 6 to 21; Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "BeV" carburetor. Pomona Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length- KPif Dimeter 9i/ 2 ", width 6^", rated speed Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Olutch: Own make, single plate type. 9 SPtf £ P Q e S' mileS V er A our: Low &gt; 2 - 02 : intermediate. 2.59; high, 3.50; reverse, 2.07. Comments: After the limber-up run and before anv of the official tests were made, the equalizer spring under front of engine was adjusted. 1 . 61 - BAKER 43-67. A. D. Baker Company. Swanton, Ohio. May 16 to 24, 1929 Eisemann "G4" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Pomona Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. .Engine: Vertical, "J" head, mounted crankshaft length - 7ltd 774 K 1 p l M y : Diameter 151/2 "' width 81 /^"' rated Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour:' Low, 2 to 2^5; inter - mediate, none; high, 3 to 3.5; reverse, 2.5 mm £ nt l : - ? Was neces . sar y to lock the gears in mesh during the high gear maximum and rated load drawbar tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 162. MINNEAPOLIS 27-42. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. May 28 to June 11, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "UTR" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley : Diameter 15i/ 2 ". width 1W, rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.69; intermediate, none; high, 3.42; reverse, 2.52. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 163. MINNEAPOLIS 39-57. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. June 5 to 14, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 20", width 8i/*&gt;", rated speed 620 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 3.00; intermediate, none; high, 3.90; reverse, 2.49. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the fan belt was tightened. During the low gear maximum drawbar test the gears slipped out of mesh several times. It was necessary to lock the gear shift lever in place with a block of wood. Test No. 164. WALLIS 12-20. The Massey-Harris Com - pany, Racine, Wisconsin. June 18 to 27, 1929. American Bosch "U4Ed2" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carburetor. Own make oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley : Diameter 17", width 6 5/16", rated speed 540.5 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry, three plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2%; intermediate, 31/3; high, 41/3; reverse, 2Va- Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests the car - buretor and fuel tank were removed and the entire fuel system thoroughly cleaned. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Test No. 167. CASE "C" 17-27. J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. August 12 to 19, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto. Kingston "L3" car - buretor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10J4", width, 6V&gt;", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.30; intermediate, 3.28; high, 4.50; reverse, 2.59. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar test, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged up and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36. The Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. August 19 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Donaldson oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Wau - kesha fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 17", width 8i/&gt;", rated speed 616 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.32; intermediate. none; high, 3.08; reverse, 1.83. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests- the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC." J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. September 10 to 18, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carbu - retor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1.0 !4", width 6i/»", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.60; intermediate, 3.72; high, 5.14; reverse, 2.95. Comments : It was necessary to raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 170. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UNITED" MODEL "U." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. October 21 to November 7, 1929.' Eisemann "G4" magneto. Schebler "HD" carburetor. Donaldson, and own. centrifugal and oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Continental, centrifugal type.' Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 7i/&gt;", rated speed 1095 R.P.M. Chassis': Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rockford, dry plate type. Rated speeds,, miles per hour: Low, 2i/ 3 ; intermediate, 3V-. ; high, 5 ; reverse, 2%. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 171. MONARCH "35"-30. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Novem - ber 4 to 9, 1929. •■'•.; Eisemann "G4" magneto. Zenith "6C" carburetor. Own make oil filter and centrifugal type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length* wise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.84; intermediate, 2.76 ; high, 4.01 ; reverse, 2.13. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the economizer jet on the carburetor became loose at its lower end and had to be soldered twice. Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene). Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 11 to April 8, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto. Kingston "MD2" carburetor. Own make, water-type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9i/&gt;", width 6i/&gt;", rated speed 1100 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1%; intermediate, 3i/ H ;. high, 7-'&gt;4; reverse, 3. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the cyl - inder head gasket was replaced. The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt test. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline). Ford Motor. Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 20 to April 10, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto. Zenith "IN5F" carburetor. Own make, water-type air cleaner.. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9*/*", width 61A", rated speed. 1100 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, mile's per hour: Low, 21/8 ; intermediate, SVs ; high, 7!4 ; reverse, 3. Comments: During the rated load belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifth turn. Test No. 175. TWIN CITY 11-20, MODEL KT. Minne - apolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. March 24 to April 12, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2V7" magneto. Stromberg "TJT1" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit air cleaner, centrif - ugal and oily fibre type. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 715 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.1; intermediate. 3.13; high, 4.15; reverse, 1.8. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 176. OLIVER HART-PARR "ROW CROP." Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Hart-Parr Division, Charles City, Iowa. April 14 to 24, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Ensign Model "K" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14%", width 7V£", rated speed 700 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.6; intermediate, 3.2; high, 4.15; reverse, 2.9. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. In the adver - tising literature submitted with the specifications and ap - plication for test of this tractor we find the following claims are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" — Folder A 135 — "they do end wheel slippage" </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Tractor Tests and "they do not slip." Exhibit "C" — Folder A 143 Same as above. Exhibit "D"— Folder 4 144 — "Positive traction at the tiptoe wheels assures delivery of every ounce of engine power to the drawbar." Exhibit "F" — Folder A 146 — "They do not slip." Test No. 177. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PUR - POSE." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin. May 5 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Zenith "94TO" car - buretor. Massey-Harris, oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Governor, Hercules, fly-ball type. . Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12,", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed 802 R.P.M. - . Chassis: Four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.20: intermediate, 3.20; high, 4.00; reverse, 2.50. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 179. MONARCH "SO." The Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois. June 27 to July 3, 1930. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Zenith "C-6" carburetor. Own, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12i/ 2 ", width 8Vo", rated speed 952 R.P.M. - /»•■»■ Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch : Own, single disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.82; intermediate, 2.76; high, 3.99; reverse, 2.06. Comments: During the. rated drawbar test, the water pump packing gland was tightened. Test No. 180. OLIVER HART-PARR (2-3 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa. Julv 7 to .15, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Ensign "KZ" car - buretor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, weight type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1414", width 71/2". rated speed 726 R.P.M: Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.6; intermediate, 3.2; high, 4.15; reverse, 2.9. Comments: During the rated drawbar test a lug bolt was lost and the lug bent. The lug was replaced with a new one. Test No. 182. CLETRAC 80-60. Cleveland. Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. October 2 to 23, 1930. Delco battery ignition system. Two Schebler "HDX12" carburetors. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner Kingston governor, fly-ball type. ' Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 24", width 15", rated speed Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks. ' Enclosed gear drive Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.75; intermediate 2.5; high, 3.6; reverse, 2.1. Comments: After the rated load drawbar test and be - fore the maximum drawbar tests were run, four exhaust valves were found to be leaking. The cylinder heads were removed, all of the valve seats reconditioned, and the valves ground. Due to a change in weather conditions, the S. A. E. No. 50 oil was drained from the transmission, differential and crankcase at this time, and S. A. E. -No. 30 was used in its place. Test No. 183. OLIVER-HART-PARR (3-5 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles Citv, Iowa. October 13 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4" magneto. Ensign "K" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, "mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16%", width 8.1/1", rated speed 596 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers. Enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.23; intermediate 3.3; high, 4.33; reverse, 2.63. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 184. EAGLE "6A." Eagle Manufacturing Com - pany, Appleton, Wisconsin. October 21 to November 1, 1930. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Zenith "96ATO" car - buretor. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner* Hercules governor, centrifugal type. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry, double plate type.* Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V-&gt;; intermediate, 3Vh; high, 41/2". reverse, 2i/&gt;. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 185. RUMELY "6AJ' Advance - Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., La Porte, Indiana. October 28 to November 19, 1930, and April 7 to 14, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Zenith "156" carbu - retor. Two unit Donaldson and Pomona-Vortox dry cen - trifugal and oily spray type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine : Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 13", width 8", rated speed 892.5 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type, lubricated. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.82; intermediate, 3.66; high, 4.72; reverse, 3.44. Comments: After the belt tests were completed but be - fore the drawbar tests were run, the valves were ground. During the maximum drawbar tests the stationary adjust - able magneto breaker point was found to be broken. Both points were replaced with new ones. Just before the com - pletion of the rated load drawbar test, the portion of the fan hub which carries the front bearing broke and the fan damaged the radiator. A new fan and radiator were in - stalled and the test was completed. Test No. 186. BATES STEEL MULE "35." Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Company, Chicago, Illinois. April 6 to 18, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Schebler "HDX" car - buretor. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Wau - kesha governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 9", rated speed, 920 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.90; intermediate, 2.85; high, 3.80; reverse, 2.65. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Test No. 187. BATES STEEL MULE "45." Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Company, Chicago, Illinois. April 8 to 28, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto. Schebler "HDX" car - buretor. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner Wau - kesha governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 920 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive Clutch : Twin disc, dry double plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.92; intermediate 2.92; high, 3.87; reverse, 1.40. Comments: After 15 hours of operation a leak was dis - covered at the connection between the oil line and the pressure gauge. The connection was tightened and the leak stopped. Four quarts of oil had been added prior to this time. Test No. 189. ALLIS-CHALMERS "ALL CROP." Allis- Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. April 17 to May 13, 1931. Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Zenith "C5E" carburetor. Donaldson and own centrifugal and filter type air cleaner. Continental governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 71/2", rated speed 1095 RlP.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Rockford, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2'/j; intermediate 3H; high, 5; reverse, 2%. Comments : After 25 hours of operation it was necessary to tighten the fan belt. (The belt tests had been completed.) Test No. 190. JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE." John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. Mav 4 to 15, 1931. Fairbanks-Morse John Deere "R2" magneto. Schebler "DLTX5" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit dry centrifugal and oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Two-cylinder horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter lStfc" width 6 7/16", rated speed 950 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own, disc type. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2%; intermediate, 3; high, 4Vs; reverse, 1%. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 191. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PUR - POSE." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin. May 22 to June 12, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto. Zenith "TO94E" carburetor. Own, oil. circulated over wool type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6V 2 ", rated speed 802 R.P.M. . . Chassis: Four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.2; intermediate, 3.2; high, 4; reverse, 2.5. Comments : Just before starting the rated belt test, the key which holds the belt pulley bevel gear to the power take-off shaft sheared off. The shaft, gear, and key were replaced with new parts. During the preliminary drawbar tests one of the differential brakes was found to be drag - ging and was adjusted at this time. During the 100 per cent intermediate maximum drawbar tests the connection oh No. 3 spark plug was broken. A new plug was used in its place. The spark plug in No. 2 cylinder was cleaned twice during the maximum drawbar tests. During the drawbar tests three lug bolts were lost and replaced by new ones. Test No. 192. BRADLEY "GENERAL PURPOSE." The Bradley Tractor Company, Chicago, Illinois. June 10 to 18, 1931. United American Bosch "U4ED4V3" magneto. Kingston "Z" carburetor. Pomona-Vortox oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Waukesha governor, centrifugal type. Engine : Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed, 798 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First, 1%; second, 2V&amp;; third, 3; fourth, 4Vo ; reverse, lVfc and 2. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 193. ALLIS-CHALMERS "EK." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 25, 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Eisemann "G4" magneto. Zenith "C6EV" carburetor. Donaldson and own, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, weight type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley:. Diameter 13", width 8V-&gt; , rated speed 1000 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch : Own, expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V-&gt;; intermediate none; high, 3'/» ; reverse, 3Vi. Comments: During the preliminary drawbar runs the head gasket on cylinders Nos. 3 and 4 was found to be leaking and was replaced. Jf»t No. 194 McCORMICK-DEERING INDUSTRIAL 20. International Harvester Company of America Chi - cago, Illinois. July 20 to 27, 1931. _ Own "E4A" magneto. Zenith "C5FE" carburetor. Own oil washed Wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15!4", width 7", rated speed 742 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Own, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2i/&gt;; intermediate 31/2; high, 5; reverse : 3. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 195. CLETRAC "40-30." Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. July 28 to August 17. 1031 Delco-Remy battery ignition. . Tillotson "Y7A" carbu - retor. Pomona-Vortox wet sump and wire mesh type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine : Six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8i/&gt;" rated speed 943 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borp &amp; Beck, dry single plate. o £ at t^ ! pe f d ll' miles per h °ur: Low, 2.06; intermediate, 3.05; high, 4.42; reverse, 2.28. Comments:- No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 196. CLETRAC "15." Cleveland Tractor Com - pany, Cleveland, Ohio. July 28 to August 13, 1931 Eisemann "GL4" magneto. Tillotson "P1A" carburetor Pomona-Vortox wet sump and wire mesh tvpe air cleaner Hercules governor, centrifugal type. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine : Four-cylinder vertical, "L" head mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10 */&gt;", width 61/.", rated speed 1040 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.95; intermediate, 3.05; high, 4.37; reverse, 2.20. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 197 MINNEAPOLIS-MOLINE "UNIVERSAL'] MODEL MT. Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Com - pany, Minneapolis, Minnesota. September 30 to October 8, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED4V2" magneto. Schebler "TT" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit dry centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 715 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.1; intermediate, 3. 13: high, 4.15: reverse, 1.8. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 198. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F 30." International Harvester Company of America, Chi - cago, Illinois. October 9 to 23, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto. Zenith "K5" carburetor. Own, oil-washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. Engine : Four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 14%", width 7" rated speed 682 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own, dry single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: First 2; second, 2%; third, 314; fourth, 3%; reverse, 2i/&gt;- Comments: The pin which holds the splined end of the steering rod in the splined sleeve sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during the rated-load drawbar test. Each time the pin was replaced by another. Test No. 199. McCORMICK-DEERING TRACTRAC - TOR. International Harvester Company of America. Chi - cago, Illinois. October 10 to 26, 1931. Own, "E4A" magneto. Zenith "K5" carburetor. Own, oil-washed wire filter type air cleaner. Own governor, centrifugal type. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 265 Engine: Four-cylinder, .vertical, "I" head mounted "viS 8^* i en 2t hwis e- Belt pulley: Diameter 15 V?? width 7", rated speed 682 R.P.M A ' singlTSe^ df s r r ' enCl ° Sed gGar driVG - Clutch: Own ' 23/f ; tigh?3 e 3^e m ve?ser e 2: h ° Ur: W ' 13 /^ Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>