<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00048.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00048.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tenth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="1920-11-30">1920-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Tenth Biennial Report oltlM Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 1920 1920 THE BEACON PRESS Lincoln. Nebraika </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Public Library Commission MALCOLM G. WYER, President Librarian of the University of Nebraska S. AVERY Chancellor of the University of Nebraska J. M. MATZEN State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY State Librarian C. A. SOMMER, Lincoln NELLIE WILLIAMS, Acting Secretary Librarian for State Institutions RUTH E. WARRICK Librarian for Traveling Libraries LORA E. BOLTON Reference Librarian and Cataloger LOUISE OTTEN, Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OP TRANSMITTAL Hen. Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sir: Complying with the requirement of the law, I herewith present the report of the Public Library Commission for the biennium ending November 30, 1920. Respectfully yours, MALCOLM O. WYER. President </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">5 NEBRA8KA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION Secretary's Report December 1, 1918, to November 30, 1920 Personnel A number of changes In the personnel of the Commission took place during the put two years. On December 23, 1918, Juliet M. Vore died following an attack of influenza. She had been in charge of the traveling libraries since Octo - ber, 1914. The loss sustained by the staff and by her friends in general was keen. In March, 1919, Lora E. Bolton, a graduate of Simmons' library course, accepted a position with us as reference librarian and cataloger, Helen G. Mathewson taking over the work of the traveling libraries. In December, 1919, Charlotte Templeton, who had been Secretary ot the Commission for thirteen years, resigned to accept a similar position in Georgia. It was with great regret on the part of all library people In Nebraska that Miss Templeton left a work which has developed so largely because of her labor and enthusiasm. Miss Mathewson left us at the same time to become Miss Templeton's assistant in her new field of work. Nellie Williams, who had held the position of Librarian for State Institutions for four years, was asked to take temporary charge of the department. In May, 1920, she was made Acting Secretary for a period of one year. By the addition of Louise Otten, as stenographer, Misa Williams was able to continue her supervision of the institutional libraries. In January, 1920, Ruth E. Warrick, also a graduate of Simmons, suc - ceeded to the position made vacant by Miss Mathewson and is now Librarian for Traveling Libraries. On January 9, 1920, Supt W. H. Clemmona, ex-officio member of the Commission, died and the vacancy was filled by J. M. Matzen, his suc - cessor as State Superintendent of Public Instruction. Activities The activities of the Commission divide themselves into three lines of service, ield work, traveling library and special loans and institutional library supervision. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Field Work As in former years, a considerable part of the Secretary's time has been given to field work. Her aim to visit every library during the biennium has not been attained. This is due to insufficient help, to quarantine and coal restrictions and to the necessity of a repetition of visits to some libraries in early stages of progress. These visits are intended to create library spirit, to give initial aid in organization, to assist librarians in administrative and technical matters, to advise library boards and to give friendly encouragement. They have varied in length from a few hours to one or two weeks' rime. From December 1, 1918, to November 30, 1920, 107 public library visits have been made, a summary of which is here given: Traveling Libraries and Special Loans Our means of service by traveling libraries and individual loans continue as formerly, except that the demand for books increasingly exceeds the supply. There is an ever-growing request for individual loans covering an interesting variety of subjects. During the past two years we have served 86 counties with traveling libraries and have sent books to 798 towns. We have loaned 7,597 more books and filled 895 more requests during this biennium than the pre - ceding one. September, 1920, was a record month in our history, the loans being 300 volumes more than in any previous month of any previous year. bin point of time and cost, the parcel post system is most satisfac - y, helping Njs to reach people promptly and cheaply with reference terial. As aids to making the Commission known to people desiring its services, there are always a number of assisting agencies. We feel that our work is greatly strengthened by means of the allies to be found among county superintendents, teachers, preachers, club women, county agricultural agents, librarians, University Extension departments ind American Legion Posts. 'reliminary to organization 4 'or organization , 6 'or reorganization 2 'or cataloging 12 'ollowup visits 83 107 'o institutional libraries 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">II 4 I i- a- ii 5^ OB PS * 00 | 1 3 o 8 s 4 M 3 S » s m M ■ II s- &gt; X 2 S 4 *- rf * - Iff oo it | ■a a. II — 2 4 5 *&gt; eg j] S- ih 2 •1 LI 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 State Institution Libraries The work in the Institutional libraries has progressed In about the same manner as in former years. In some cases we may have taken no special steps in advance. In others we have made perceptible growth. The most notable instance of progress is at the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane where a beautiful room 30 by 50 feet, centrally located, opened six hours a day, furnishes very good library facilities to patients and employees who are its constant patrons. This splendidly equipped and supervised library was made possible by the Superintendent, Dr. W. 8. Fast, who felt the urgency of a better location for the library than it had had formerly. We point with special pride to this working out of a plan whereby an out-of-repair building was remodeled to make so attractive a library. Our inmate population in the Institutions is about 5,000. A con - servative estimate places half of these among those mentally or physic - ally unable to read. Add to this 2,500, 675 employees and it gives us a possible patronage of 3,175 in the 13 institutions where we are maintain - ing libraries. Our circulation of books for the biennium was 70,634. Instead of ranking with towns of equal population in circulation, we compete favorably with the largest towns in the state outside of Lincoln and Omaha. A record of periodical literature is kept only at the Penitentiary where 16,686 magazines were loaned during the biennium. To show the attitude of those concerned, we herewith present trib - utes to the institutional libraries from the viewpoints of the Board of Commissioners, superintendents, librarians in charge and inmate readers. L. C. Oberlies, Chairman Board of Commissioners of State Institu - tions: "I wish to express our appreciation of the good work you have done for us in helping us with our institutional libraries. They are a source of great satisfaction to this Board. They afford instruction and diversion to our patients and relieve much of the tedium of confinement. Their circulation is evidence of the keen appreciation with which they are held. I trust that you can supply us with more books during the coming biennium and we assure you we will give them housing and the best of care." Dr. D. G. Griffiths, Superintendent Lincoln Hospital for the Insane: "I believe the library is very beneficial to quite a large number of patients In this hospital. The fact that we are not accomplishing more is due to our inadequate library room. We hope this will be remedied soon, as I thoroughly believe there should be a large, cheery room de - voted especially to the library " Librarian: "We have about 150 books circulated monthly among the patients besides the many magazines which they enjoy. On some </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 of the wards the older patients are read to every other day for an hour. This they look forward to with a great deal of pleasure." Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent Ingleside Hospital for the Insane: "In my opinion a library connected with a state hospital is a most valuable adjunct to the institution. Hundreds of patients at Ingleside take advantage of their opportunity to secure books and periodicals. The date of beginning improvement in many mental and nervous cases corresponds to the date they first began reading. Employees are also benefited by having access to a well selected library and all the library activities are improved by having a full time librarian, she being on duty daily at regular library hours." Librarian: "I believe the library affords more real pleasure to the patients than any other entertainment provided. Patients who come daily to read periodicals appreciate this privilege much." A patient representing the ladies of her ward, without suggestion from any one, writes: "We wish to express our appreciation of the Ingleside library. We feel that we have an especially good selection of books and that they are distributed cheerfully. We are thankful for the cheerful service of our librarian." Another patient says: "For myself the library has been a great benefit. I have read most of the fiction and think it would be a good thing if books could be exchanged with other libraries. The other patients also get enjoyment from them. Instructive books are also read on the wards." Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent Tuberculous Hospital: "Great stress should be laid on furnishing patients in an institution of this kind all the reading matter they can reasonably use. All of us appreciate very much what the Library Commission is doing for us and I trust support will be given this excellent work." Patient: "The library in this institution is appreciated very much. We have a varied selection of books, which most of the patients have found suitable to their tastes. Books are in constant circulation, being exchanged daily, by one of our patients who is in charge. Occasionally we get new books and we usually get a variety so that everyone Is pleased." Dr. B. A. Finkle, Superintendent Orthopedic Hospital: "We wish to express our appreciation for the work which the library Is doing in this hospital. Our room is nicely equipped and considerable reading is done by both employees and patients. To the casual visitor, it may seem that the library is not used as much as it might be, but many patients are confined to their beds who without the books and periodicals would pass many lonesome hours." Commandant J. O. Moore, Soldiers' Home, Milford: "I am a strong </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Eocate of the library and am proud of our little library- My observa - i is that Uie 'old comrades' and their wives and employees make good of it" k Librarian: "I think the library is a great acquisition to this Home, ere is a growing interest in the library and all seem to enjoy this at privilege." A comrade says: "Have been at Milford Home for a year and have enjoyed myself mostly by getting books from the library. Hope it may continue to grow better and more of it" EDr. 8. J. Stewart Superintendent Institution for Feeble-Minded nth: "We consider the library one of the greatest assets to the uttes of this institution. We appreciate very much the interest mam - ted in selecting our books." Librarian: "About sixty books are issued each week and are read by the children on the wards. The older girls who do not go to school ■how a marked interest in the girls' stories. Since the boys invariably ask for histories and biographies their books are more than a pleasure. The smaller children like to hear stories read. The library is well supplied with books best adapted to the class of children using them." Supt. F. W. Booth, School for the Deaf: "The service rendered our school by the Nebraska Public Library Commission is, I feel, of inestimable value. In the nature of the case our deaf children, in order to get the most out of life, must read, and they must, here at school acquire not only the ability to read, but also the habit of reading, and both are made the easier to give through the use of the abundant supply of well bound and printed and beautifully illustrated books that come to us from your selection." Librarian: "It is with great interest that I watch the readers of t library books who come under my observation. I continually note r eagerness to read and make a part of themselves, the good books which our library affords them. The books are especially adapted to the rs of children, and are constantly in use. The number of readers is on the increase, which is, I think, a proof of their appreciation." One of the children: "There is good and fine language in books and I want them to help me have fine language. That is why I want to read. I want to read a great deal like Benjamin Franklin did. My father and mother want me to be a very smart man. That is why I read the books Librarian, one of the girls. Industrial Home for Women: "I have been greatly Impressed by the part played by our little library in the lives of our girls. There is hardly a need it does not meet and their patronage certainly voices their appreciation. If they require entertain - ment our 800 volumes of fiction and poetry supply the best quality; if </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 instruction in household arts, elementary nursing and care of children or art of entertaining, they are sure to find something to fit the occasion. Even their higher needs are met by ethical works of Marden, Myers and others." R. V. Clark, Superintendent Boys' Industrial School: "The library in our school has been kept in good shape. Old books have been re - bound, practical volumes provided and the boys wonderfully helped by the excellent advantages furnished by the library supervised as it ia by state control." Librarian: "The readers, as they come under my observation, appreciate the opportunities afforded by the library. Especially do the boys like the various magazines that are sent to the school." One of the boys: "No boy lives to himself. All delight in com panionship. Good books are good companions." W. T. Fenton, Warden Penitentiary: "I find that our library meets our requirements fully. Thorough investigation convinces me that it has a decided influence for good. Last month over 1,400 books were asked for and received, 30 per cent of which were standard works." Librarian: "I believe the library is one of the most potent factors in the reformation of the inmates. As you know from our monthly records, there is a very good percentage of standard reading done. Our fiction is good wholesome reading which all the men appreciate." One of the men says: "During the last eleven years I have read a great many books from the prison library. I don't know of a single book that has not helped me in some way and I know this reading has helped all the men to a considerable extent." Publicity For a number of years it has been the policy of the Commission to advertise by means of an exhibit at the State Fair. In the fall of 1918 this was discontinued. In its stead county and district fair advertising was substituted. Miss Williams visited fairs in Franklin, Nuckolls and Saunders counties and a district fair in Frontier county. This more direct touch with the people, acquainting them with our aims and means of service, brought definite results. Another method of publicity has been the loaning of exhibits. Besides filling requests of librarians over the state, we sent a collection of posters to A. L. A. headquarters in New York to be used in their publicity campaign. An exhibit was used in connection with a talk at the A. L. A. conference in Colorado Springs and at our state meeting in Lincoln. In 1919, a personal letter sent to each county superintendent brought considerable response from rural teachers. Traveling libraries were on exhibit at several teachers' Institutes. We also sent an exhibit of books </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 on rural sociology to the State Conference of the Methodist church at University Place. ▲ letter explaining the method of obtaining books from the Com - mission was inserted in our widely-read Nebraska Farmer. It brought prompt and overwhelming returns from Nebraska and a few requests from adjoining states. During the past year, the Secretary attended the A. L. A. conference in Colorado Springs, the State Library meeting, State Federation of Women's Clubs, State Teachers' Association and Conference of Superin - tendents of State Institutions, at all of which she had some part on the program. She has also given talks at a Girls' Vocational Conference, the School for Rural Pastors, to a University History of Education class and the Wesleyan Educational Council. She talked on county libraries and met library boards and town councils in several places. Miss Warrick also appeared on the state library program In October, 1920, on the subject of the Library Commission. Needs The Commission has a primary and a secondary need at the present time. The latter is for an increase in our book supply to meet the demands upon us to furnish traveling libraries and reference material to organizations and individuals who legitimately look to us for help. Primarily, we need an increase in the number on our office force. This is, in part, that we may effectively take care of the volume of busi - ness by serving the people promptly. In particular, we need an addition to the staff that the work over the state may be given more attention. The request to the legislature for a Field Agent arises from the knowl - edge that not enough time is spent in creating enthusiasm for more and better libraries in Nebraska. Public Libraries The past biennium has not been a favorable one for the establish- Ct or growth of public libraries. The building situation, the general icial condition, difficulty to secure librarians and a lessening in hours of service, have affected the entire field of library activity. There has been a cessation of library building in the state. The Carnegie Corporation discontinued its gifts prior to the war and has not as yet resumed its donations. As several places are in a state of progress needing buildings, this is a somewhat serious handicap. Scotts - bluff alone has a building under consideration, $14,000 having been promised them by the Carnegie Corporation before the date of restric - tion. No gifts of individuals for library buildings have been reported. Two years ago we had 108 tax sustained libraries in Nebraska. During the biennium, Arnold, Bayard, Chappell. Gering, Kimball, Nelson. Oakland and Wausa have been added to the list making the present </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 number 116. Of these, Arnold and Wausa are township libraries. Bayard and Chappell seem specially worthy of banners. After only a year of organization, under the auspices of the Woman's Club, Bayard was taxed five mills for the support of its' library. Funds not being available until May, 1921, Chappell raised $1,300 by subscription and the library is in a very encouraging state of progress. They are agitating the question of county support. Two of our libraries suffered recent loss by fire, Weoping Water only partial, well covered by insurance, and Ansley an almost complete loss of building and contents. A few library boards are beginning to realize the seriousness of their meager maintenance and the inadequate salaries paid librarians. In most places the situation is critical because the amount of the levy is insufficient. Even in case of levying the five mill limit of the law, the funds furnish little hope of growth, if the unit is to be the municipality. I'ayard, Cozad, Fairfield. Guide Rock and Plainview alone report a five mill tax. Excepting these towns, the average support is 2.4 mills. The combined reported income by tax of our 116 libraries is $210,726, Lincoln and Omaha furnishing $78,261 of this amount. This leaves f 132.4G5 to provide free library facilities for our population of 1,295,502. $40,839 dollars is the total amount spent for the purchase of books of which there are 133.129 volumes in the public libraries of the state. Is it much wonder that an unfortunately large per cent of the people in Nebraska have no library service except that furnished by state supported libraries? We have 35 counties in the state without libraries in their county seat towns. The hope of the future in library development lies in a materially increased financial support We feel that this can be done only by enlarging the unit of organization from the municipality and township to the county. There has been some agitation along this line in the counties of Deuel, Colfax, Kearney, Nemaha and York but at present no county In Nebraska has put itself in such line of progress. The county library law in Nebraska authorizes the establishment of such a library by vote of the people at a general election. The following is the text of the law: 3792. Section 16. ESTABLISHMENT— TAXES.— The city council of any city, the board of trustees of any incorporated village, the county board of any county, and the electors of any township at their annual town meeting, shall have the power to establish a public library free for the use of the inhabitants of such city, village, county or township, or to contract for the use of a public library already established, and may levy a tax of not more than 5 mills on the dollar annually to be levied </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 and collected in like manner as other taxes in such city, village, county or township, and to be known as the library fund: Provided, when the county board makes a levy for a county library, it shall omit from the levy of the library tax all property within the limits of any city. Tillage or township in such county which already maintains a library by public tax: Provided further, before establishing such county library, or levying such tax, the county board shall submit the question to the voters of the county, and a majority of the voters voting thereon shall have authorized the establishment of such county library and the levying of the tax. Such question shall be submitted at a general elec - tion only, and when so submitted and carried, it is hereby made the duty of the county board to include the county library in its next succeed - ing estimate and levy. The legislature of 1918-1919 made two changes in the state library law, changing the maximum rate of levy from 3 mills to 5, and reducing library boards from 9 to 5 members. Interest always centers about our association libraries. These are usually mothered by the Women's Clubs until sufficient library spirit is created for them to be fathered by the towns. Libraries thus fostered are in the following towns: Adams, Alexandria, Beaver Crossing, Bridgeport, Brock, Dorchester, Elmwood, Eustis, Hemingford, Herman, Keystone, Minatare. Mitchell, Murray, Oak, Ogallala, Oxford, Page. Palmyra, Polk, Potter, St. Paul, Salem, Shubert, Valley, Valparaiso and Waterloo. Correspondence shows a library Interest at Arapahoe, Deshler, Grant, Humphrey, Inavale, Mason City, Monroe, Nora, Oshkosh, Pilger, South Sioux City, Springfield and Trenton. Library War Service As Nebraska's quota of Library War Service books, the Commission has received 3,162 volumes, consisting of many duplicate titles. They included books on Agriculture, Banking, Business, Economics, History, Journalism and Mechanics. Of these we have added 564 volumes to our own collection for use in reference work. Upon request, we have distributed as gifts to American Legion Poets, Institutional and Public Libraries. An addi - tional shipment not yet arrived will be similarly apportioned. Many of these books were bought by the American Library Asso - ciation and they will be a valuable acquisition not only to the Com - mission but will greatly aid the small libraries over the state. Nebraska Library Association The Nebraska Library Association met in Omaha for its annual conference in 1919. We had with us Mr. Chalmers Hadley, at that time President of the American Library Association, and Miss May Massee. editor of the Booklist. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Preceding this meeting, Miss Templeton conducted a three days' library institute for the new and inexperienced librarians. There were 22 librarians in attendance. They all remained for the Association meeting and the week proved a very profitable one. In October, 1920, the annual meeting was held in Lincoln with Mr. William J. Hamilton, Secretary of the Indiana Library Commission, as the principal speaker. In line with the present trend of thought, he talked on the County Library as the best means of library extension. Nebraska was unusually fortunate in having the American Library Association hold its 1920 conference in Colorado. Twenty-four ot our librarians attended the Colorado Springs meeting. This furnished an interesting feature of the state program, in October, several people giving "Impressions and benefits from attending A. L. A." </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes accessioned to December 1, 1918 22,333 Volumes in library December 1, 1918 19,685 Volumes added from December 1, 1918, to November 30, 1920 3.855 23,540 Volume* withdrawn to December 1, 1918 2,648 Volumes withdrawn from December 1, 1918, to November 30, 1920 — Foreign language, by legislative action transferred to Univer- sity library 1,562 Destroyed 669 2,231 Volumes accessioned to November 30, 1920 26,188 Volumes in library November 30, 1920 21,309 EXPENDITURES DECEMBER 1, 1918, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1920 From From Appropriation Appropriation 1917-1919 1919-1921 Books $ 13.60 S 6,315.26 Office expense 354.46 1,614.67 Binding 191.00 870.27 10.80 Printing 83.04 Travel 96.95 555.76 Extra help 153.13 403.43 Institution libraries 532.86 3,546.07 Secretary 500.00 2,500.00 Librarian 300.00 1,66665 Assistant librarian 300.00 1,666.65 Stenographer 145.83 1,500.00 $ 2,670.87 119,549.56 2,670.87 Total $22,220.43 Appropriation 1919-1921 ._...»23,000.00 Balance 3,450.44 Expended April 1, 1919, to November 30, 1920 19,549.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATE LIBRARIES SCHOOL Location Vols. Librarian Cotner College Bethany 6,609 Mrs. Bessie Johnson Creighton University Omaha 51,500 W. T. Kinsella Doane College Crete 14,585 Nora Hjelm Franklin Academy Franklin 5,800 R. Kretsinger Grand Island College Grand Island 9.000 Gertrude M. Suess Hastings College Hastings 7,500 Flora Fisher Lincoln High School Lincoln 2.000 Jessie J. Glass Luther College Wahoo 3.500 Erik Wohlstrom Nebraska Wesleyan Uni. Place 11,022 Ethol M. Langdon Omaha Central High School.. Omaha 7,332 Zora Shields Omaha Com'l High School Omaha 3.000 May Ingles Omaha South High School Omaha 2,897 Clare Mackin State Normal School Chadron 5,965 Lillie Cilley State Normal School Kearney 17.360 Anna V. Jennings State Normal School Peru 30,000 Elva E. Rulon State Normal School Wayne 8,000 Jessie Jenks Union College _. College View 7,350 Mertie Wheeler University of Nebraska Lincoln _ 148.000 Malcolm G. Wyer York College _ York 3,500 Joyce Cushman DEPARTMENT Location Vols. Director State Library Lincoln 80,000 Public Library Commission.... Lincoln 21.309 Legislative Ref. Bureau. Lincoln 11,000* State Historical Society Lincoln 55,000 "Chiefly pamphlets and clippings. H. C. Lindsay Nellie Williams Edna D. Bullock Mrs. C. S. Paine SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES </seg>
            <seg id="p018">y, i 5^ is Mill : i : i ! : : : i i i : iJJ M C a - iQOOOio :oia : : in © 10 : t^ri«oi» • to o i ! &lt;e o&gt; v ! nnoih : ci •»• : ci : •» ... : * 1 p 3 OB 5 I ! u ■ x § amis :eH«n«Hoona : nsioo :i-iioino)iooix»&lt;e j o o i- :i«aoooou3iOrtn : MICffilCtBr-MNI-NlClCl- • •— — ~- »— ■ — C I r— r- N H — fill nil l&gt;Micoo*o-o»t-oocm : Uc aoax^ooncQt-^useCH j I I ?! 5 M x i c-m a nt&gt;e&gt;MOrtUi«ovn&lt;pn : «:«&gt;u;ct. t^ot-tcot-oooio : X W go N 5) ifl Ol W C. in O: : : pnui«Oiani&gt;nu)r&gt;No : •w to m ec c-i oo 3&gt; t~ o t- u^ t- t- : «CCOr-.r-M00 «O r^Wri ; I I I i i [ 1 1 1 1 1 1 } 1 1 1 1 *£ «2 • « a a Btjtj* „ i -2 * i: b b § 8 8 S S -2 "5 Si O 0&gt; II fa p i Illlllllllll J II J II I J : ® i o § o § S i o ! S i a aB^gO ;•" : B : S ;w t.03 fe 5 :S : J- 2 ■ lilrJffil SeoOo5caa: 0 QOB&gt;.£oocn05&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">a h V Slii J -" i 6«"i -i fsi"i ldJ «I"S &lt;.SS.Ssfc Afloat* o as £2EE£E£§£==E££Ee3££*£fe£ t~©iao)©©©* : o» «© : 10 CO *-&lt; co :io«oh : oc «iant-oeno : t- t- : ct&gt; r-i m t- io*«ia : o&gt; o*o»non»o» |"»oo i oa o&gt; C4 &lt;o VMifq j e» o«nMO&gt;»HH :00V : t-" eo » oo* ! e» oi a&gt; os iio rt II IH " i-l ' CO IH O • IM • f— t &lt;o © &lt;£&gt; t- o o o e&gt; :o«oo«»n : i— ia n o o o Hisnnoovio :uiniono»o :»f*o»t- «t&gt;U3aint&lt;IOC4 :00r1 S«NH irlMMOrt* ; i-T eo eo i-t i-T ci : i-&lt;" ei r-oot-o«o«o :««eHNae :io»r.* iao •HOOeoOricoo :t-TO»»no ioiobion* Hiowioooneiio :NOien«n« :qn_eo«»« n V 10 e« ih rH : V io e* m ih m Ihn'VV rn ■ »h rieuwMNaxneSNuiisnn :«»o-os HL-;np)nc0MncovxM(fixu:^ : w v«N *Si09XNiD3«90XOIAI&gt; : :rH9ON : O »&lt;9»N3t-t-r-»OH3XH&gt;- : laionH : o m n n mh nnnoKH : hni&gt; :m a if I §oosiseNN«eeeigusee : o ■♦ o t- © o MOTH»t-a»aO3»rt«* :mOKM»o f 1 • O) M rt » Nn»»V»U3&gt;O '. n T W«» ooo©iais(eooo©o©&gt;ooao : t- © © o o o ©oooo^-'woioooooeMO© :oc&lt;ooo©o _ « n n » t- r- » e &lt;o r- « » v x » o :r&lt;«o«no i-Tcl r4 H H H IO pi rt H j rt fH Hri" P io to at u&gt; . .to -*-&gt; I I ©^•&lt;-i&lt;e©©©©o&gt;©o©t-'«©©&gt;AC4©©9oo « ■*oo oj «c © © m © t- © eo © oo oo © © -h oo © © © © © M«J ■sin isot- « &lt;e wn t- &lt;e « si &gt;n »«»«« us* * » t. u &gt;-*" i-T V t-J HH«0« W 9&gt; « rH Cl W V iH r^ &gt;.« Illllllllllllllllllllll 3 ** !iI-l|!iIIgilJ!lWllll 111 HNn«uset&gt;«steHein«u)«i&gt;»aOr&lt;N» *^ a t I II v£ m a i s -r I &lt; o C &gt; CD =i I S 3 5 t- « s 1 1 £- - -: o- z pa co a. — 5 s ! | IT B K </seg>
            <seg id="p020">o Q, •- 2 1 S w it c ft ago fl| 111 i r. a ii!i!iiJii!jiiiii,i gg At iSSSS iSSSCS 1SSSS iSSSS r« Inn :&lt;e&lt;eu3co :i-'ri»iou&gt; nt-'ri ;t-»-r«-^«e • 99 ' r+ ' SO #0 ' »H « : o &gt;-&gt; o ■* «o : •- o -r « «e o © t&gt; n © © :ooa« «K : P3 ■» U5 O&gt; i-i :&gt;-IU3r*0&gt;r-lO©i-IU:00 : © 0C -0 i— V :hid«uii&gt; jiouieoiHuee*** : to © tc ■» Icon Vt-Ti-JV»&lt;f-&lt; «•• 1 — :«i&gt;9««uo :oi&gt;«OH«aooieN«HO O ■». © © to — n © :ooi»or-iDr-oo&lt;or-nc«&gt; O :Niausx«t-o : is i&lt; n n « « « a e » is n n « t :ne :atCf « :« r-onn« N ote :©© — ■* ■ • &gt; « I « • I ~*~* - |£J II i i 2 1 — ■ «o © © o&gt; © © © tdooooootoo^^iaoNo • — : © W : o&gt; oc © © :©©©©«•©©©© :©©«©■* &lt; :©» :«n5o iSoeufOnoN :oo»m H ! • t- : &gt;♦ o» ~ ■* :t-_OM«[.»io*« ;qq«i&gt; «j HH iMH*N Vi-frHi-r : i— cm" CO S "is io m , , is = § »e«eoo«oie««ioaeH«N«oeoer- o-s *isHoesooN««a9«o»n*t&lt;ooo«n o -J o n o u; io e t in » n 6 n a q « e t- n c « « « » ""■ r*lilOr*r*r**i*i U)ril0 OHHHMM «-T» «■« 1-1 IJ I I I I I I I M II I I I I | | U I I Sj i n n ■ *s </seg>
            <seg id="p021">e 5 ■ s ? I S £ c 1 s £ I i U Ui i- te S &lt; C ? a q S ui z a fe s 2 S ! E 1 3 d- (0 &gt;&lt; 8 a *- II H 5 j now : la us © to to :*H«««»«xooNe co o to :ot-OHt&gt; :«pi-ifrH«u3coooa&gt;c~o iDOh iwioen | e h q » N t&gt;_ iq » o ia 0 e •O • II " fH f« «H I-I e-j te i-i o e* : t- &lt;o « © e» :nxneoeao :iat-N hhOU ;eamoo&gt;H :au&gt;»noiona : t- oi ■» CnOn iejeOOri I^HrtOlSrllOH !l-O» ouwe loejom :n»»oi-«o«oo«»o OC4NH :Oi-lO©«~ :t-MIOOO»*t-r1i-cO-»« iShiso lonoaio :«nao«ttr-a«iD«r- CM~e4S&gt;u&gt; iisNnn i i-f oo « »" n n" ri i-i" e ri n ■* uiH«H :nn«is6 : » t- us t-eo« fH •♦ e« « t-«e riioKa inviono :«9&gt;t&lt;t-noea vokiu * o o&gt; t- :* co to co : oo co M «ion neun o&gt; i-i •» oeno : o o o o o :oHieoof uoooon «»«e ionidxo :Nn«»»f»»Nooia nnNoi : to i-i « o co : t- oo «iau9tont-« v o co o&gt; o : i-i © oj ■* o : o oo o © cm io © o m o t- to © t- t- o : co oo oo us © : © tp ■♦ © © to © © © © © a&gt; t-iO'VM : &lt;o u&gt; oo ea o :aonuiw«Mf icishn WiHMM 1*4 04f-l !(HN i-T i-l" i-( &lt;-( 1&amp; * 0^ 5 *- ■a • N ■S ON«o»o*ooo»o»»o«ona0900 OOUOt"OHOOlAHO«t"V09IOIOl060g «n«u5t-iao«N«!ioqait-»coo*ict-t-.oe| H H O U H N* H H « H n'V rt*'W I-t «e C4 rJ iH US St! s, i? I ago &gt;. ■w O tif|ii|lilii|ll3l|||lsi r-woiOi-MM^mBr-ooaOi-NW^iowt-oce «««iaiau&gt;ifiiaisioisiaiaip(e«iteewv«e gs s I 1 Ss i sPfll IS!!* tlafMlS^ ionhi- : « oo to s&gt; © :os :»«N«»»99i- nemo : eo o» t- eo o :s« :e»x»««oisx i 1*1 •» rt i * - I •■ Ml-i irt«H«rin icOHNNN i«MWH«rt |2j </seg>
            <seg id="p022">I El 1 s 1 i -i 5 i ? e n a B E I I x O ■ « — S I I | a | c S — 2 a i | 5 - « 1 I Jl!f4WSlt%Pi|li Snt- i&lt;Sn o : © ob oo ©Soo t- eo o&gt; © «©i-c co « 00 ii :UNC. :O i«Or&gt;r&lt;Mia««U!*OiaiN MM - M •" * HH HUH I-I » eS e»oot- :SoMmisSneoiat-oonie««i CO" I © M !»H •» IH rHHH rt • • CO * iamo :gi n n : N e«t-iese9!OMLSOONn i-ooS ■«■ eo ~ «o»ffi^ooto«fccon CO CO O it-f-O :*OTX«1010*Ori«OI0*M «M*&gt;O ! t-" M •* i »N«rJ»MiHN»'M»« »'*N ■•• i-i IOC- iO^E'C'r-lr- »NMrt«0HjlO«H»n« Hh rt t-( iH c» '• t- oo inoonoeNOnienooooooae eo © iisJot- «» M m t- i-c •• • » ■• « ««■ t- » i-J i co •» ~ T. N°HN jtOrtiH »J I-T HHCI Hrt« o 6. C P 9 &lt;o ic P3 ta m^m i !fi«« : ■* iMtoMMasM^coi-i : m m co V " •E Sj - ii !&amp; ►?• 3 C S§P i!!iiiii!itiiiiiHliiii ilfe5l?il5llll!l|illfhl ZZZOCbCOft-B-SSEe-KKKooooeoooaoi °t-t-i-i-f-t-t-t-t-»«ocK»ococ«»ooca&gt;oiffl 2p t- ti SSI e£s^S»H»»i&lt;aNXa)f :«*t~ iSSrt :HrlHHIOMrtM«»M iH *» r-l i j s i Oho leQNOtoO©©©©©© 1 "* o wo "O to * Sen :*Seneo«i«sii)3«oeSHO»o OOOOOnOlOOGQQOOOOOONi-iOOO o*oooSoo&lt;-io5«©ooooo«e»©oo© C i- « O O O " f • O N N « r- » t- U: O O&gt; O 6 » O r- O&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p023">55 •a 2 5 c o UJ ■ M i Q - Ul o a. a. 3 X •I t a E o z. •a N 8 5 u ?^ c 5. 9 " £•§9 585 2 t JL a u&gt; icseoio* : h »-i oo ♦ us t- e» :«otow mne C3 t- : m co eo t- es :u3fianiant- : « oo » us !i-&lt;«« r= • ,-,* o" id t- •»" : •»« V oo »■«»' !hi-'oom iioooo go loVNOOooeonONaonsoveit-otoioeo O :tAC4«e4OMXHt0IAlAQO^t«NnQOOH«HO »-1 f^ i^ 1-? rt 1-* r-1 i-4»0 n :«r&gt;ri00i&gt;ooeo«ioieHeu««eniiiHN uo : « « » e» oo h v h isn o ua a t;« t&gt;ii9 t&gt; v « i «* eb" t-T t-i t- ei « hmniscq (Q«'rtr&lt;tH«HO Si os :«»iso»i«HMnOf*NO»Li:nOKOion to ii-re«ovor-»»Ne»eo»r.nMi-oo» S tH :ONnn«»NH M««nNIOt&gt;OnnN«r-. 0 O Ip4v4 i-T r* rt V 1 •» ■ a — a — o ; io o e&gt; o o o m «c © © © © oo o to © to © © © o o t oo ;u)N«Nio«is*o&gt;eaCNneoeTNNr-Niri © :b-M«et-oet&gt;«at&gt;eMO«u)«oioa»n 5 us i » S e o * oo ■* « « » m o m « * n io » « t - ■» JHN HH tHCO 1-tI-Tl-T «t &lt;D it I "?"? "? *&gt;3 'I i««MMM«ri»NM«*«H»Mn«H««« sS « t- © io ©© w ©©■* o ©©©©©© &lt;c © m © o© us c.— t-wooooooocoooeoo^oiooceooM o*j n»a«i.«Hfo»iAO«9M«r-HX«no»M LJ ma ri T iT T -- *S m* eS ta J M ! I M ! I II ! II I Ml II ! II I • I I I \m\ || I ' IJ ' i^fl i ife i i § t!iii!|gi!|li2iisifiiSiJ s umnimnmnuilit n«io«t-ioaOH«n«is«NooaOnMce«ia« 090»OSO»OSOSOSOOOOOO©0©0^&gt;-li-lt-i£&lt;£&lt;£H &lt; tr m □ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>