<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL MESSAGE OF GOV. JOHN H. MICKEY INAUGURAL ADDRESS OF GOV. GEORGE L. SHELDON, THIRTIETH SESSION LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 1907</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">OF NEBRASKA • lS05 l 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TBE S1W TOM PUBLIC LIBRARY ASTOB. LBTOX AND nuns roLNUATUM K 1949 L • • • • ;;••.: . •••• ..:.. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i CONTENTS VOL. I Uennial V &gt;f Gov. .7. H. I IMS Inaugural Message of Gov. (!. I.. Sheldon Inaugural M f (Jov. (I. I,. Sheldon •.'. Biennial Report of tin- of State •.'. Biennial Report of the of State ;f. Biennial Report of the Auditor of Public a. Insurance Department. X Biennial Report of the Auditor of Public a. Insurance Department. »h. Appropriate on. Biennial Report of the Statt- TrOinrar b. Appropriation 4. Biennial Report of the State Tieitsui •"&gt;. Biennial Report of ( On inissinner of Public I^ands ;nni Build - intfs (including; IW15 'i Biennial Report of Cone mi f Public Land* Mid Build • &gt;. ".I i ry, Lanca I). Hospital for Insane, In r. Hospital for Insane, Liin '/. Hospital for Insane, Norfolk. e. Institution for Feelile-Mind. itriee. i. Industrial School, Kear: ;/. Girls' Industrial Scboo ° ldicrs" and Sailor^" Home. Ciraiiil Island, i. Home for the Friendless. Lincoln. j. Hospital for Crippled Children, Lincoln. k. Industrial Home. Milford. ! /. Soldiers' and Sailors Home. Milford m. Institute for Blind. Nebraska City. ii. Institute for Deaf and Dumb, •Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p004">OF GOV. JOHN H. MICKEY INAUGURAL ADDRESS OF GOV. GEORGE L. SHELDON THIRTIETH SESSION LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">1 MESSAGE c* Governor John H. Mickey TO THE THIRTIETH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA JANUARY l, 1907 rthc Senators and Representatives, Thirtic Legislature of Nebraska: The organic law makes it the duty of the Chief K ill the tion of each recurring legislative body to the general condition of affairs and to make such suggestions and recommendations aa. in s judgment, the needs of the public lis duty I desire primarily to congratulate the members of this as&gt;&gt; 1 n the exceedingly prosperous conditions which prevail in their respec - i it ions of thrift and com which ha •■quailed in the history of ti Without attempting an ana ' the cause it is apparent that a goodly her You are assembled at a time when history is being rapidl&gt; when the public is bo quickened to a sense of justice and when ther»&gt; was niand for the purging of the inequalities which have been to! our civil system. The for improvement alin; lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 Organized society has •&gt; a higher plane and the inquiry of the tlmw is "how can the greatest good i and guaranty greatest number?" Tl -it and I it it the dominating sentiment which will control hrough this entire ses The Revenue Law. assmuii satisfactory phase. The hostility which ihe new revenue I in th» ca bm alrr.o it. It is equal to the necessity of raising sufficient funds to n airs and the gradual floating d .nds which must be nut. A needed an- how - is one which will require I &gt;ort 10 t! of Equalization and Assessments the actual amount of ssislsg road within the state as one of the hast * of assessment. Freight ebraska are considerably higher than in the i the east .mines of the roads doing an interstate business an to the several states in the ra'lo which the total mi mileage within each state. This is a manifest injustice to Nebraska. If the railroads persist in charging our people higher rates than do the people of Iowa and Illinois, then the earninu &lt;&gt; our iould be correspondingly larger and the assi hould be aff t-ordingly. Tl three years and during that time has l:een under the r tiny of all interests. With the exception of two of our railroad lington and the Union Pacific, it has met with unqu;&lt; mention lves seriously air- d the matter of the amount of their assessments and the consequent enlarged taxes. They have gone into the con of the ;&gt; of th' :oard of Equalization and Assessments, so far as ii ad them, and though they lost their suit in the United States Court, when lasts are now pending. Tne aiiount invo: otal taxes due from the I the several cour the exception of those countii the amount in i less than $2,ooo. For the fears 1M4, UN and 1*M the total of thus withheld $1. 000,000. Approxinr.a'.ely $1' this sum belongs to the stale, and 0 rider to -s. school </seg>
            <seg id="p008">GOVERNOR 5 an amount of tax is working great hardship and embarrassment to many county treasuries. Firmly believing that the railroad assess - as made by the State Board are not more than the law makes oblige and are not out of proportion with the assessment of other forms of property, I confidently look to the highest court in the nation for a vindication of the state's ritrht to assess any and all corporations the actual value of their property and the issuance of an order comi&gt; the payment of all deferred taxes. The State Debt. I A. fairly satisfactory progrtss h during i in the reduction of the sta ling general fund warrants aggregated 1 LSI, a total r - the biennium of $ irnount $ ble to tl iition fund act created by th&lt; - filature, providing a one mill levy for the gradual extinction of the ing debt. Ir will thu - penditures for the biennium, aside from the redemption fund. ■ indicating that in tfc&lt; it but li' It is evident that had it not been for the execu i of a m; of large but anna ipproprtetioos the debt would hav - ■d durins th than d&lt; ■&lt; mill redemption fund has really been in operation but one year, so far as having an eftfct upon the receipts of th&gt; measurer's ofli concerned, th- having not 3 paM. When the for tl car begin to come in, however, it is believed there will be niarke:! improvement in the matter of debt reduction, unless legisla - tive expenses and appropriation ian offset the increased re&lt; The tax owed to the state by the Burling on and Union Pacific raili estimated at 1106,000, an 1 payment of which they are resisting in the courts, will also be applied to the debt when collected, making an material reduc'ion. The estimates now in the hands of the State Auditor for the n tenance of all branches of the state government during the next bien - nium, payable from the general fund, total the enormous sum of $ 1, the la r submitted to a NebrasK The estimate i a sum 1489,469.12 too small to pay the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">6 |&gt;wn estimate*. It devolves upon you to do this work, and to do it st thoroughly, both in committee room and upon the floor of pective houses. The treasury must be protected from the threatened la ugh t *It will not do to make appropriations even equal to the [mated receipts, let alone in excess of them. There must be a gradual it reduction, not only through the operation of the redemption fund, also through a wise and economic conservation of the general fund. :h one of you is pledged to an economical administration of affairs 1 the state demands that you make good. The attacks of those who e designs on the treasury will be most aggressive and persistent, you must stand firm for the interests of the taxpayers and the jgrity of the treasury Notaries Public. !In a number of instances during the past four years my attention been called to the fact that many of the notaries public commissioned n the Governor's office are of immature age and lacking in the erience and judgment necessary to the proper discharge of theii lea. In some cases serious criticism and embarrassment have result At the present time the Statutes provide no age limit for notarial ointments. It seems to me that an office so important, having to with the acknowledgment of deeds, mortgages, affidavits and nearly papers pertaining to our legal system, should not be exercised by any 30a of immature years. I recommend that Section 1, Chapter 61, of Compiled Statutes of 1905 be amended so as to include an age lification of at least twenty-one years. Pure Food Law. After many years of effort Congress has finally passed a pure food law, very comprehensive in its scope, affecting all food products and also drugs and chemicals which enter into the compounding of nieiii cines. The federal law applies only to inter-state business. It prevents the traffic in impure food products across state lines but does not prevent the manufacture and sale of such products within state lines. It is erident that if the people of Nebraska are to receive full benefit from the present agitation for pure, wholesome and truthfully branded food the national enactment must be supplemented with a rigorous state law embodying the same features. Otherwise Nebraska will become the home of numerous factories for the production of injurious food plies, all of which can be sold with impunity within the state so long as we have no state law to the contrary. I recommend that the best </seg>
            <seg id="p010">7 • effort of your respective houses be given to the framing and passing of an adequate law which will give to our people ample protection along the lines indicated. The execution of the law should be placed directly undtr the charge of the Food Commission, making provision for such additional chemists and inspectors as are necessary, and an appropria - tion should be made adequate to the work. The dairy interests of the should also receive additional recognition, in connection with the proposed pure food law. These interests are gowing to immense proportions, but the product is handled by a few concerns. There has been quite general complaint of the butter-fat tests made by the cream - and from which they compute the value of the cream shipped to them. I suggest that one or two dairy inspectors be added to the office force of the Food Commission, whose duty it shall be to supervise the butter-fat tests at all creameries and skimming stations and to establish a standard which shall be uniform over the state and just to both producer and manufacturer. Shortage of Permanent School Fund. I On June 20, 1906, the Supreme Court rendered a decision which, i probability, finally disposes of the suit brought by the sta; ver from the bondsmen of former State Treasurer J. S. Bartle state lost, though the decision referred to was based on a mer nicality. This famous case has run the gauntlet of the courts for ber of years and it now appears that there is no possibility of r ring from the bondsmen any portion of the Bartley shortage. Sue g the fact it remains for the state treasury to adjust itself to th equent conditions. Section 9, Article 8, of the Constitution read Dllows: Ul funds belonging to the state for uter - eat and income whereof only are to be used, shall funds held by the state, and the state shall supply all losses thereof, that may in any manner accrue, so that the til remain forever inviolate and undiministaed." It is therefore obligatory upon your body to make provision for the restitution of the depleted funds, either by authorizing the drawing of a warrant upon the general fund for the amount, payable to the Treasurer. or by authorizing a special levy unon the grand assessment roll covering one or more years, sufficient to meet the requirements. The items and amounts of such, shortage are as follows Permanent School Fund . Permanent University Fund </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 Jamestown Exposition. I On May 28, : it of the United States Issued his ■lamation in which he invitel participation by the militia of the &gt;ral states and territories in an international naval, marine and tary celebration to be heU in the vicinity of Jamestown, Virginia, b May 13 to Novemb* 7. in commemoration of "the first nanent settlement of English sp' ople on the western I A copy of this proclamation was transmittel to me through Department of State, under date of May :S1 &lt;ether with ;i ;r from the Secretary in which he expressed "the h your e may find it conveni&lt; •: it ion and to send such mization of its militia as in r will afford appropriate tary representation." With reference to this celebration so many in correspol and inquiry arose that I took it upon myself to appoint a comnii consisting of C. E. Burnham, Rome Mil anley and S. C. Bassett, to look ■ affairs of Nebraska connected there - with and to perform such initial m President and to the Commonwealth of Virginia require riding that the naval and military f»atuies of the celebration are to be upplemented with an ter. I believe it woul '1 at this celebration, which will certain it historic i: md I recommend a small approji r that porpot h us. - and restrictions as, in your judgment, may seem I Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition. The people of the State of Washington in general and of tli - of Seattle in particular are also arranging for an International Exposition of the Art*, Sciences and Indu be held in lune 1 to October 15, 1909. Nebraska ha- la cordial invitation to partici - pate and a special repr&lt; ■.-• of the exposition management has called at the State House to present the matter. Possibly it wouM time enough if the next Legislature passed upon tl .on as to whether or not this state should participate. I simply bring the subject to your attention. icultural College Endowment Fund 43,368.6 mal Endowment Fund 12,600.0: Tot*! $32r, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">9 Legislative Action Requested by the General Government. Accompanying this message is a copy of House Roll 345, passed at the last session of Congress and approved by the President March 20, fc6, together with an explanatory letter from Chancellor Andrews of our te University. Under Uie terms of this law Nebraska "receives valuable additions to the Hatch fund for agricultural experimentation," fe. in return must assume an obligation to keep the funds inviolate, . Here follows an excerpt from the law: "The grants of money authorized by this act are made subject to legislative assent of the several states and territories to the purpose of said grants; Provided, That payment on such installments of the appropriation herein n. 0 any state or territory Eore the adjournment of the regular lature meeting :t after the passage of this act shall upon th&lt; of the rernor thereof, duly certified by th y." L Acting under authority of the abo gubernatorial I to the provisions of the bill under date of March 24, INC, in a communication addressed to the Secretary of the Tresmry, thus making the additional appropriation available for our st o the time of §e adjournment of tin -dslature. It now remains for your »dy to give its formal asst nt to the conditions imposed by the enact - ent, to the end that 1 1 &gt;i&gt;riation ontinuous to our experiment station. kThe Secretary of Argiculture. Hon. Jam&lt; j s \V ie under te of November 14. 1906, u follows: t"I have the honor to advise you that the Department of Agriculture purchased a lot and building situated in block ISO of the original n of North Platte, Nebraska, owned by Mrs. Jennie A. Armstrong, for use as a weather bureau observatory and is now in ] ■ . and in compliance with Section SS6 of the Revised Statutes of the United States it is requested that cession of jurisdiction over the premi - question h ■ grantel by the State of Nebraska to this department." I recommend that you take such action as will relinquish jurisdiction over the property in question to the Department of Agriculture. The original request fr tary Wilson accon Restriction of the Lobby. Extravagant and unnecessary appropriations are very largely due to the persistent efforts of individuals who, through selfish interest or mistaken zeal, make a practice of frequenting the legislative lobby and halls, and even th. porttt- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ity to Influence members in b half of their pet measure. The custom s vicious and works great injury to the State Treasury. Matters affect - ng appropriations ought n cts of m .or in ny degree affected b&gt; ore*. Every piece of legislation ought to stand ui&gt;on its own merits anil tis is especially true of appropriations. The committee n&gt;om is the roper place for advisory discussion, and statements and argui tat cannot be nr.a ought not to be heard at all. 1 suggest that le public interest rt quires that \ on adopt a rule early in the session hich will protect the legislative chambers and halls from the influence ' the lobby, under penalty, and that the rule be rigid! 1. Heads f state institutions, educational and otherwise, should be included in the 'estrictions and should not be i 10 importune for appropriations save in the committee room. In order that all interests shall receive careful consideration the appropriations and claims committees should old public sessions and all parso— having matters to present should be vited to appear at stated li.ues and make argument and submit data •ertinent to the cause -hould be heard at o other time save in Such a &lt; uld. I believe, be the means of protecting the treasury fron -s and extravagant appropriations and would save individual members much annoyance. Railway Commission and Freight Rates. The previous Legislature provided for submission to the voters of an amendn.ent to the cut. 'ing a State Railway Commission of three members. This amendment was adopted by a large majority at the late election, and at the same time the first Board of Commissioners was duly elected. With reference to the powers and duties of the I mission the joint resolution submitting the amendment reads as follows: t'The powers and duties of such commission shall include the r&lt; of rates, service and general conr irriers, as the slature may provide by law," e It will be necessary for your honorable body to define in detail the duties of this Commission and to confer upon it ample authori effectively deal with the subjects which will come before it. You ■ fix salaries of the members and make provision of such clerical as "iay be needed, presumably i to the Board. You should make it certain by legislative n in that the person selected for the important position of secretary shall have had practical expei in connection with railroad management and rate making, able to meet the railroad officials upon their own ground and thus be capable of render - ing •: valuable assistance to The people are looking </seg>
            <seg id="p014">VERXOR to this Commission for relief from railroad oppression. The measn ss achieved by the Board will very largely depend upon the i J of a secretary. He should be an expert. During my term of office many complaints have reached me cated upon alleged unjust freight chargts imposed by the rail; In the matter of shipments within state lines in particular it is as&gt; that the companies operating in this state collect rates which are far in excess of the current rates for similar service in th&lt; i the ea»t and which, when measured by the length of the haul, are dispropo ate. These are matters which most seriously affect the interests of all our citizens. I have made no personal investigation of freight rat. ditions because, whatever my findings might be, 1 have had no ; to act and there has been no board or commission to which such tions could be referred. The railioads of Nebraska are in the owned and controlled by eastern capitalists. These people are more interested in their profits than they are in the general welf;. the citizens of this state, though there should be an equkalj' ;ng between the two. The tendency of the times is tow. eentration of capital and exper:&gt; that where chere is central - izd power there is apt to be oppression. The railroads hai supreme factor in the development of Nebraska and no one will ga their right to reasonable returns upon their actual investmei; also right that the people should be protected against unjust discn: tions and extortionate rates. The remedy of nation. ing vigorously applied and it remains for the several ■ iiially active. I favor such legal restraint as will operate against discrimii, and will guarantee equal privileges to all. Now that tb&lt; esablished a Railroad Commission and have authorized you to i it with ample power, marked improvement along these lin&gt; fldently expected. State Veterinarian. The work of devolving upon the office of the B v increased during the past four years, due to the artopti. effective rules by both federal and state government and t increasing number and value of domestic animals. The last I. appropriated $1,000 for the traveling expenses of the Depui for the biennium, and $400 for an assistant. These amounts ai too small. The demands upon the office are such that the d«fH out over the state a. large part of the time and even then cannot pos do all the work rhat h- 0 do. The amount appropi for an a~ too lin &gt;f keenintr a clerk in the office. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 The stock interests of the state need the protect inn which this office affords and you should see that this Legislature makes appropriate traveling expenses and assistants adequate to present n&lt; Education. The growth of our educational system in all i&lt;s branches has been phenomenal and highly satisfactory. Our people are alive to the i; tance of good schools and have shown a willingness to provide the needs of such institutions whenever the need h;is b en n feat At the present time the state is supp3rting by direct taxation the rsity and two Normal Schools, in addition to five Junta a school for the blind and for the deaf and dumb. I have no doubt but that your honorab'e body will carefully consider the requirements of all these institutions and will make such appropria ions as will further progress and be in line with the growth and development of M Institutional Comments. I am pleased to call your attention to the fac that the penit - is nearly self supporting in the department of maintenance. The current biennial report of the warden shows that for the six months ending Noven-.ber 30, 1906, the per capita cost of maintenance was $66.97. Dur - ing that time the per capita earnings of the convicts were $50.99, making the mt maintenance &lt; but $15. us for each innia little less than nine cents per day. The physical condition of the prison is first class and it stands today as a model institution of its kind. The three insane asylums of Nebraska have each I different statutes and are known by different names That at Lincoln Is known as the '"Nebraska Hospital for the Insane," the one at Ha - ls designated "Asylum for the Incurable Insane," while the one at Nor - folk is styled the "Insane Asylum at Norfolk." Owing &lt;&gt; the variations in the statutes creating them some perplexing questions have a: and are likely to continue to arise in the future, with respect to control, management and legal status. I deem it important that the chapter of our statutes dealing with the insane be revised, that the three asylums be placed on exactly the same footing, that ir - respectively the "Lincoln Hospi al for the Insane," the "Hastings Hn for the Insane," and the "Norfolk Hospital for the Insane," That there be no distinction in the character of the patients received at eithei tution, and that the state be conveniently districted so that each a? okaii ro^oi vc t h f* rmt Ifint fl com i n c fv* T*h ♦ * word ' ' i fi o i i r </seg>
            <seg id="p016">13 I brutal in its suggestion and It should be omitted from the "f any and all of the asylums. I especially enjoin upon you that you see that all appropriations ■id for the various executive departments are ■c and cl Used. Not infrequently appropriations have been juggled with in the past and have been made to apply to expenditures which the legislaure never contemplated. As an instance I have In mind the amusement hall at the Hastings Asylum for the Insane, which waa not sanctioned by the Legislature and for which no appropriation was It was paid for entirely from the maintenance fund of that inati - n. Similar instances could be cited. This is a method of accomplish - ing a purpose which should not be tolerated. Possibly the amusement hall, and the other improvements and additions which have been made from diverted funds, were needed but there is a proper way to meet such needs and that is by direct and specific appropriation. Any other course will eventually lead to serious difficulty, if not scandal. The spirit of this sugestion is embodied in the closing sentence of Section 3, Article E:. Compiled Statutes, which reads: "Provided, that no shall be made to any public buildings without special appropria - the legislature." The Chief Executive should have conferred upon him absii authority and power to remove at will any Institutional head appointed by him, and his action should not be subject to the review of any court or board. Under our system the Executive is responsible for the proper conduct and management of these Institutions and that being the case he should be guaranteed the protection which the absolute r of removal affords My experience teaches me that institutional friction would be redm minimum if it were understood that the s order of removal was final. I recommend that the law rd in conformity wih the idea here set forth. Subordinate officers in all institutions should be appointed by the Superintendent, the approval of the Executive. you are doubtless aware, the Norfolk Asylum for the Insane has been in operation about two years, since its restoration, and has rly reached the maximum of its present capacity. It must divided with more room in the near future. I recommend that the basements of the three cottages and of the Administration building be thus relieving the rooms above and adding to the capacity of the institution to the extent of being able to care for fifty or se\ more inmates. An addition to the storehouse is also needed. This inc should be made large enough to care for the afflicted of that part of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 " ltniD t i j * - J 1111 i 1 1» of this message it is not practicable or necessary tc call your attention to all the varying needs and conditions of the different institutions. For • 'iformation your attention is ci 1 the biennial i rlntendents. To thes - should give careful perusal and thorough consideration. But be w. against acceding 1 r an ippiopilatinii Remember thai •ate is burdened with a heavy debt, contrary to the specific pi tion of ll ness acumen requires that thi. - should be paid before any extrava*:. ■ indulged, either in build ings or equipment for any department. Only the absolute neces - should be provided for. I cannot en.pha.size this idea too forcefully, appropriation in excess of actual ami the executive *■ In M • sea of in &gt;f failure to maintain proper discipline, and of p«-rn a to assault, abuse and maltreat patients were I agains: th&lt;- Superintendent and Assistant Super - intendent of the Norfolk Asylum fpr the Insane. These charges w&lt; I vestigated by me and also by the Bjard of Public Lands and Buildings. I found that the allega' a sustained and on July 10, 1906. I issued formal orders rein- ;ind the Assistant Sui tendent from their n fused to vacate and I then instituted ouster proceedings in the Supreme Court. Later, and be - fore a decision was rendered by the court, both of the officials i altered their action, and vacated their positions to my appoii present incumbents. Since then the Grand Jury of Madison county has indicted four of the ward attendants of the asylum and they arc now awaiting trial in the District Court on tl of assault with ll to do great bodily harm Interest on School Land Contracts and Investment of Funds In his biennial re tnissioner of Public Lands and Build ing» recommends that deferred payments on public land sale coal .iced on a flv&lt; I basis, instead of six per cent, as at pn he reason that an abundance of private money can be obtained at the lower ra'e on farm loans the purchasers of state lands are rapidly ng up back principle, taking a deed and negotiating private loans at less expense. The result is a loss to the interest revenue of the because it is impossiM the funds in permissible bearing nearly so good a ra'e as five p-T cent. fThe Commissioner also suggests that the Constitution be amended permit ot f the permanent school fund in other </seg>
            <seg id="p018">VKKNOK'S M • 15 securities additional to government, state and countv bonds, and state warrants. The opportunity to invest in such securities as the Cot. tion now permits is being rapidly curtailed, for various reasons, while the amount of money which the state has for such in\ is increas - ing and will so continue. I concur with the Conn in both sirr.endations. Anti-Pass Law. During the past two years a very general sentiment has deveh st the issuance of free railroad transportation. Such action on the art of railroad officials is rightly regarded as unjust discrimination and s being subversive of the public weal. Both the great political p ave declared against the practice in their state conventions and edged themselves to definite action. I am one of those who l&gt;. hat a party platform means something and that its tenets should be ithfully carried out by those assuming official responsibility. I n end that at as early a date as is practicable you add to our - gid anti-pass law, applicable to all cat&gt;. 'hose of bona fld&lt; oad employes, the members of their immediate families, and care-!. live stock. With the exceptions noted, a heavy penalty should be mposed both on the party who issues a pass and the party who s&lt;&gt; e same. Direct Primary. In many quarters there Is vigorous opposition to the convei. system of nominating candidates for state, county and district ofl and in lieu thereof it is proposed to substitute a direct primary s\ one that will enable the voters 10 make direct choice of such ean&lt;! at the precinct prlmari that the pro|&gt;osed plan will do away with many current abuses of power and influence, plar - politics of the state upon a higher plane and n.ake possible the seh of better officials. These ai lie wished. I regard it Important that the party pledge in this particular should be fulfills' I urge your honorable body to carefully consider the various ideas that have been suggested along this line and to ultimate! form of a direct primary law. but with such limitations as will make it popular and effective. It should rigidly guani tion of candidates who may have r&gt; plurality of the votes cast but not a majority, and should in all r nard the principle that the majority 1 -ight to rule. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 Labor Bureau EThe results . by the Bureau of Labor and Industrial atistics are not sati and are not commensurate with tl&gt; maint' ii.ii. r as I ha ible to observe the entire 1 the bureau ha.*- tfaappointment. If you think best to continue i department I t the clerk be disi th, as the Dt'pu y Comn institute ample Ice for Silver Service for Battleship "Nebraska." The legislature of It an appropriation of $.'..111111 for the urchase of n ■ ■ for the battleship "Nebraska," the saj &gt;e expended und&lt; r the direction of th • Governor. In the discharge of this trust I invited all ka who d 0 compete o submit desgns which invitation some four or five nrui responded to. After cartful in\ Tract was awarded ugii '., to the • Omaha, that firm, in y judgment. ion. Tl was completed and del me in tl p:irt of I IH05, and voucher for | ta drawn in p la favor of the A. F. Smith lib'd wi:h the uditor N n I&gt;incoln and maha. and is now A. F. Smith Co.. in Omaha. waiting the commissioning which time it will be ormally \ :ich bowl with adle and eiglr anental center piece for Hi loving cup with j&gt;ede&gt; \t the me the would be commissioned before Januaty 1. 19M, but for some reason ther. been delay and the function will not take place for some months yet. The . F. Smih Co. is un 1&lt; r &lt; ihe place presentation without further cost to . and at surh tin ay be fixe 1 for th. Law Enforcement. I have a firm convict on that the Chief Ex&lt;cutive should have more specific power conferred upon him in the matter of law enforce - ment I fi. Art'cle "&gt; of Mitution reads: "The supreme ext-ci. hall be ve&gt;tel in th*&gt; Governor, who shall take care that th^ laws be faithful foundation is well </seg>
            <seg id="p020">17 ;he stai not snfli the power which is often • unber of plain' on the : i ute offei i when the 1. I in their han's On ac of du.y the law - abiding sentiment in t! has bt«"ii done to the ri^l: lK)werlfss to interf befbr inty board. hut such nical. di! more eff&gt; unniend the creation &lt;•&lt; and in civil matters wherein th plain &gt; prosecute, that niand such county ful proeecution. or in lieu tl of the case at th* of the i r to do both, and in of the continued ne&gt;;l .&gt; act the Governor In from office with. Such a law would • of good government and ■ which n&lt; exists. II further recommt n 1 that the statu der penalty, the shipment of liqih iportattao nies into such i and vlllaj , majorii by action of the council, dt-ri lie liquor traffic withii r to whom the shipii; hen a nmunity has r&gt; wishes shoulil uor house, express or traaaportation company. 1 regard such a law as s imperative, to the e id that lo uient m. d not be brought into i The Parole Law. My i that tli iminal is a wise addition to the and thai ioal win ;lt soiiKl) r confinement in thi uiation rather than n impetus to correct hatits of life rather than na ion of condign punishment. The power or ;ide th&gt;&lt; means of a permanent uplift to the penitent one. ;r </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 years of my tenure of offir ave been vtry few violations of the terms of parole, it being i mi km- against imposition. In view &lt;&gt;' individuals have passed U|)on my pardon, commutation and parole record I wish to say thai ration and investigation The warden of th. 11 consul' of parole. •.amined and I have striven to mak&gt; in every possible way tha' was one worthy of clemency nent to the issuance of pardons and commutations I have re&lt; ssions fi rial j.id^ rosecuting attorneys, and the jurors, favorable to the exercise of the pardoning power, and in tew instances have I acted until my own judgment has been reinforced by thoee best knowing to the merits of the particular case. I have felt weighted dcwn with a seme &lt;f th. -ibility resting upon me in ■ xercise of the power of ( and I have endeavored to dis - charge th risibility with exceeding care and with conscientious regard for the safety If the laws governing pardons and paroles are too liberal thei about with such limitations as you think proper, but so lon^ as they exist in their present form, with full power veste 1 in I uirption is that such laws mean something and that tl or will exercise the power conf upon him when the circumstances surrounding the case warrant action. Insurance on Public Buildings. By autho n 6. Article 1, Chapter 83, Compiled Statutes, the Governor tl "authorized and empowered to insure the public build - ings and other pi 'he state, liable to destruction or injury by fire with some good and responsible insurance companv or companies, for the benefit of and in the name of the I numb no appropriation for this puri" of the state to carry its own fire risks. If you think bes for th ■&gt; carry insurance you will make appropriation for the payment of premiums and place the at the disposal of the Governor. The More Important Legislation to be Drafted by Joint Committee I believe the public interests wtO If all bills ing the more imiwrtant niateis of legislation could be forni&gt; an 1 : I by a joint &lt;■• he two houses. This I is especiall&gt; i&gt;ertinent ■ as direct primary, am md railroad lcgiM will be recalled thai the new .tw was | ich a comnii tee and the plan worked so well in that case that I think it woul to follow it in a!! </seg>
            <seg id="p022">(iOVEKXOR'S M 19 where the general public b &gt;ncern. A course is likely to result in a multiplicity of bills upon the same sir a divided support, and either no legislation at all or the final adopti a faulty measure. - State Treasurer's Bond The Attorney General holds that Uder our present law the giving of indemnity bonds each of the individuals or guaranu panies signing such a bond are liable for the whol- amount. The law does not permit of a division of th' f the risk be' individuals or companies, each taking a part and being responsib no more. One bond must cover the whole amount and each \&lt; ing it is liable for all the risk This construction, and it is undoul correct, makes it very difficult for the S ate Treasurer to gi\ factory guaranty bond in so large an amount as is required ($' for the reason that but few of the bonding companus will si - bond. Treasurer Mortensen gave such a bond, signed jointly 1 tnit's. but recently the c mipat, a rule U) nailer companies agreed to sign Treasurer Bl bond jointly but the combined capital of these companies was not suffi - ciently large to justify me in approving such a bond as they couM I have therefore approve:! a bond for Treasurer Brian given b] Title Guaranty and Sur&lt; ty Co., of Scranton, Pa., a company which has a capital and sutp'.us (f $1 It would have been better if companies could have signed with the Title Guaranty and Surety Co.. but the said company would not sign a joint bond. In view of t! iir.mend that the law governing official bends be amended so as to t of the division of large risks between several compan individual bond for such part of the risk as is apportion it and being responsible for no more, and that the amount of risk p. ted to any company be limited r-&gt; twenty-five per cent of its capital and State Suits Involving Heavy Loss. The suggestion of President R&gt; in a recen; n that a law shoul it courts fron aside just decisions for mere technical errors in pleadings, instnu nee, recalls some of the civil cases wherein the Stat was on technical groun the necessity for prnvi ling Th Chipf Pvpcntivt* h </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 of suits to enforce civil obligation! to t! but the fruits of tion, during seasons of both de nocratic and republican rule. been an enormous bill of costs for the state to pay and a Jud| leasing the defendants from all liability. The gravity of iti. will be realized b ( your honorable body, wi law charged with the duty &lt;if providing i the sup, when a f&gt; and th« of the losst* are mentioned. One of t: .aha National Htnk a sin easury J unlawful! mk by I by me&amp;ns of a state warrant, and The suit w.i: In 1897 suit was against former St. 'fficial bond, to recover a shi' people v this immense sum which had been meted Iron i run thi ernni' -nes of tl of embezzlement : unable, in the va- of technicalities known to the criminal law, to find a iini from prison. In tl lit against, his bondsmen it was hel;l that the bond was valid and properly executed. The evidence of the shortage was o : ied many times. Somet I was for the bondsn were finally r&lt; bear the 1 During my first term I bringing of * sui in the Supreme Court against th&lt; &gt;ail&gt;any I by it from tli ibrary fund. For nuu the State .lournal ;iany was d by the sta nt the several volun Supreme Court Rei&gt;oris i the state librarian 1,( of each volume. T Id by the state for |1.54 per co the benefit of the print work for the ■ id the books in bo with the state, his employer, and as stated in made biines and sold them in co state for | li. making a net profit of |2.00 on in all. Thi- court t! instance a decision hi Miparently has no furth&lt; Meanwhile the librarian has on about 20,000 copies ot which otherwise would I sold and the mon&gt; •• library. In view of the ion of the court in tl to the effect that anyone can print and sell the reports and thai the st ion fron </seg>
            <seg id="p024">GOVERNOR'S MESSAOE tion on 1)xe part of its owi s and agents, I reconi: that the law providing for the pi ;ien»e -pealed. Rises involving the taxation of property for state purpose*), cases ng title to state school land, and other cases involving th* roi&gt;erty of the appears to those unskilled in the law to be purelj is. If the people cannot get relief by I e like th.c d by President Roosevelt, provision should be made to u itution to meet pi The Junkin Act. The power of curb tru straint of trade has I forcement of the Junkin Act. This is a la I by the 1. entitled "An act to prot- md conr unlawful restraints and monopolies, and to prohibit the givii iving of [Kirtation of property, and to provide a penalty for the if." Shortly after thi- it into effect I directed th* ■uit a.nai: which has resulted in a su by the Supr - tually enjoining the meml tot from monopolizing the business and controlling i strain. The effect of tin was to give the producers of grain the benefit of one and one f per hundred which had been unlawfully charged for eli and to i impetition in in business throughoir A similar action was he Nebraska Lei \ssociation, the result of which The bill carried with it i ie joint direction of the Governor and the nd of this amount $2, Supreme Court and Commission. During ti limited by tli' :nn to three members, hi cases by a commission of six m&lt; ad the nine so working reduct«l the docket sn tl :uing from th( nd and deu-rmined within a II than a The commission system is a makeshift to add to the without contraveni; in. Thr Bndii ir. ust be appi ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p025">22 and should b&lt; d only un il such time as I h.- Constitution can be amended to provide for a court of sufficient membership. I t&gt; - that a commission of three members will be sufficient to enable the court to take care of its business without unreasonable d&lt;lay during the next two years and I recommend that you make provision for a commission of that number, the appointments to I i the approval of tl :ior before brooming effect 1 II fur' du submit to the an amendnn nt the O n providing for a Supreme Court of five membt increased to sevtn members as the public service may require anl the discretion of the Legislatut&lt; salary in proportion to the ponsibility and dignity of the office. Such an amendment would no ibt be sanctioned by all parties and could i ■ put of the lot and carritd as was the railway udment a* the ion. Th&lt; 1 the relit f which a larger court would »rd and I believe that for the present five members could hea: ermine all the cases. Iowa has a court of six members and find - uber sufficient Child Labor Law. Public sentiment is greatly stirred at the present time by reason of the abuses incident to the employment of child labor. Every child has an inherent right u&gt; an opportunity for self -improvement and ihe best interests of society in general demand that that right should concrete expression. The employment of children of tender factories, stores, theatres, concert halls, saloons, and in even worse plates, is a crime againtt youth and if persisted in will I • rious effect upon the body politic. I lecommend that an adequate la - enacted upon this subject and that there be coupled with it such a pulsory education section as can b Railroad Passenger Rates. With the abolition of f rt e transportation, which I assume this Legislature will accomplish, will naturally come inc the passenger departments of the several railroads. As thi «•- corpora tions are already earning sufficient income upon their stocks and bonds it follows that the people should haw the benefit accruing by reason of the disappearance of the pass. Assuming that the anti-pass Ian be rigidly enforced, it is a safe conclusion tlm a reasonable red ; in present rates can 1 without doing injustice to the rail: I believe the selling of mi: &gt;ks good for 1,000 miles or bo) the rate of two cents per mile, and trip tickets at two and one-hall per mile, would be fair and just, and I suggest these rates foi consideration. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">&lt; ii (VERXOR'S k M 23 Statement No. 4. Estimated receipts for the fiscal period commencing April 1, and ending March 31, 1909. Based on 85 per cent of the amounts levied for all purposes under the grand assessment roll of 1906, and sundry other collections based on actu;i two years: General fund levies for !'.&lt;■ ; 1,911.07 General fund collections on back taxes , Sinking fund collections on back taxes (House Roll 204) Collections of obsolete funds (Senate File 50).. 1," From interest on deposits 16,7 From miscellaneous collections .... From fees Governor From fees Secretary of Sta • From fees Auditor of Public Accounts 192,219.47 From fees Commisioner Public 1 Balidingi M9.16 From fees State Oil Inspector From fees Department of Banki: I From fees State Food Commissioner From fees Board of Irrigation From D. S. Government "aid" S. A: S. Hon From temporary School Fund tax collections. From interest on School and Saline land From lease on School and Salinp land. . From interest on Bonds 271,604.49 From interest on Warrants - .109.47 From Game and Fish licenses From temporary University Fund taxes From Interest on University land . 11,4 From lease on University land 8,0: From interest on Agricultural College lai . . 24, 447. 2-^ From lease on Agricultural College lands rm U. S. Government Aid Agriculture and Mechanic Arts fund rm U. S. Government Aid Agriculture Experiment Station fund From University cash fund 119," From Normal interest fund 1.52 From Normal School Library fund, Peru ... 6,67 From Normal School Library fund, Kearney 5,141.47 From State Library From Hospital for Insane fund From Convict Labor 62&gt; From Penitentiary fund 300.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 From total income of $ General Fun I I The School Fund The ' The Normal School Fund &lt;i The State Library Fund derives . Tne Hospital for Insane Fund derives. ary Fund (landi derive! *r,,lf,1 Statement No. 5. ■rll 1. und ending Marc t Aetna: Improvements rent I Legislate - J1 "" ■ | Treasurer Audit.. Insurant 11/ intendent Public lutructtai Secretary of S Commission. i Public I Board of Public Lands &amp; it Board of Educational Lanis &amp; K.itni- Boanl of Purchase and Sup General Adjutant General Supreme Coun State library Department of Banking :!&lt;.'• State Board of In Game ft Fish Coi: SUte Unh I Soldiers' ft Sailors' Home, Mllford Soldiers' ft Sailors' Home. Grand Island. 117 Hospital for Insane at IJnc 201,: Hospital for II Norfolk Asylum for Incurabl- 4"1 Institute for F&lt; Industrial Si ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p028">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE il School . 115.J Xornial School, K. 111. Normal School, Peru Home for the Frtendlesi &amp; Duml Conimisison aska Libr mission . State Board of Charities &amp; Con ■1 School Ro;ird . l-aws and Journals nue Books and Blanks Junior Normal Sell Board of Equalization &amp; Board of Health $11 FuRitives from Justice &amp; Ol ict Court Support of State Poul 11 . . -upport of State Board of Hort -upport of Stat" Board of Agricultori -upi&gt;ort of S ate Daii »uer (if La ■ ■■ 1 !,"■ ■ rinarian ;iinp; and trail lor Blind iska Industrial Hon.'. ! ! Ill I tal for Crippled and Deformed Child: Legal Advertising 1 deficiency, wolf bounty claim.... deficiem $.",17.i • $-t ite school apportirtnmc 'mrsed during $l.:!4ti the above total of $5.49:5,831.51— iinount i ' a] fund i $::.41t'. niount chargeable to I rslty fund is imount chargeable to the Library fund ia . in. 7 imount chargeable to tl »l funil i- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">(iOVKHNOK'S MKSSAtiK 26 The preceding statements, Nos. 4 and 5, show the estimated r - and expenditures for the coming biennium, as compiled by the Auditor. I transmit herewith a certified copy of a concurrent resolu ion adopted by the Legislature of Xew York. March 1. l»"fi. upon th. Ject of polygamy, which I am requested I on. Accompanying this message is a complete list of all pardoi. eonunutaticns granted by me within the past two years. Umiflltl Efor the action tn each individual cane. If anyon more information pertaining thereto he is respectfully referred to the ntary evidence on fiU* in the Gov&lt; rnor'i office upon which rp has been predicated. In conclusion permi' he pablii largely committed to your hands for the coming two hope that the state may be richly benefited by your deliberations and that you it«v each have Divine guidance in the die luty. JOHN H. MICKEY. Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">" ! I B B I 5 — / •1 a 3 s i 1 i-g-g : i* iig :§~ : S • - SS • 8 • Si Ss-lis*^^ : * | ° a u '■ ;:«.•;- - -= «*s*«««a'': : • n - r - aa a, c=a.^^ a. aa y.- ii £ as il ;!li I! a at o 5_- c - * S *■ iiKiISiiiitii! i </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 PARDONS. Elnn- i — Murder, twenty-five years. Pardon granted for !h&gt; - reason that the complaint was filed in vacation and sentence Nebr., page 37). In 19n4 the warden recommended Cibson for ■ "Fourth of July pardon," bvit such pardon could not be issu te the Chief Justice refused I in the r ■ ■ • &gt;n, considerin. -ion of the ■ ■Mention a pardon was granted February 11, ]:&lt; Edwin T. Croshaw — Burglary, two years. On petit iuri tioiu a physi - cian. trial judge, jurors and county officials stating; that prison - weak-ir.indesi and while rational enough to perform common labor and thereby supporting his family, grave doubts exist as to his mind Bufflciently de\ 0 realize his offense in which view the prose* attorney con&lt; tjohn Clark -Rape, three years. Pardoned on the recommendation of ;e Barnes, Judge Boyd. Prosecuting Attorney Mapes and nine ju all expressed doubt of his guilt. Clark has been a model pri* alth is rapidly failing. August 9, tl . L. Beaumont Obtaining signature by h s, two years. Having fully re-imbursed his victim and Ju m as ;is many of Rock Count&gt; I itizens stating as their oi ♦K^t the law has been fully vindicated, f Charles Ri irder, tv m eVMei doubts as to his guilt. Ten of the jury petitioned for his pardon, m that he was convicted only on circumstantial evidence an : verdict was reached only as a compromise measure. A sworn lishing an alibi has been introduced and a pardon wai William Xieter — Rape, three years, six months. Pardon ion from the parents of the wronged girl. May 26, 1906. t Edward J. Collins — Murder second degree, life. Fourth of Jul l granted according to Criminal Code, Section 569c, all the pro\ same having been complied with. July 4, l'.&lt; Samuel Payne- -Murder, life. Fourth of July pani&lt;&gt; July 4. 1906. Ernest Bush life. A&gt; long and careful Mining to the case of Ernest Bush, his youth, the methods used in his conviction, and having read all the evidence closely and thoroughly. I think there is grave doubt of th&lt; - of this boy. His conduct having been most exemplary since his confine ment, and he having l&gt;een very industrious in his &lt; penitentiary whereby he has worked over time and </seg>
            <seg id="p032">(iOYKHXOK'S MESSAGE 29 hundred dollars. I an. convinced that it is my du eraor to issue to him a full and complete pardon, feeling that society will not in the injured by his release. In granting this pardon I do it with i ho full and firm conviction thai it is a right ex. the pardoning given 10 the executive. December 10, r I Harry Dow — Grand larceny, thn Pardoned after a thorough estigation rod the ir from the prosecuting attorney which he stares that new evidences clearly prove that the sentence uld have been but ninety days in the county jail. December 2!t. l!»o« William F. Bachle — Rape. thre. Pardoned for reason that a dilation and marriage between the complaining witness and prit ig taken place and that a great nuir.ber o ioned for such pardon. Decenil Charles Schneer — Robbery, th Pardoned !&gt;•■ on the rucommendation of Judge Day and Deputy Count; Attorney Fitch, both of whom "believed the law has be?n fully vindicated and he has fully paid for his sin and error." I Lena Margaret Lillie — Murder first degree. Ill appli - ion for pardon as requirtd by statute having been given, and hearing ing been had and many affidavits setting forth new evidence in case having been submitted and argument made in the presence the County Attorney of Butler County, and open hearing and discus 1 of the case having been had, and after many days of deliberation [ study of the testimony as submitted to the court and submitted at time of hearing for pardon, I am clearly led to the conclusion h;&gt;t re is very grave and serious doubt of her guilt and am compiled in own unbiased and sincere judgment to grant her a pardon, rgaret Lillie is this day at 12:20 p. m. granted a full and con don. January 3, It PENITENTIARY COMMUTATIONS. Noel .Martin Larceny, five years. Commuted to three years, livti months, six days, on recommendation of Judge Kelligar and Prosecuting Attorney Quackenbueh, the last named official stating that the conviction was made on circumstantial evid&lt;nce and that the sentence « January 11, !'.&lt;■ William Sirr.pson Shooting to kill, fifte. This prisoner was suffering with an aggravated and loathsome disease not amenable to nent in prison, and on recommendation of the prison physician a commutation from fifteen years to eleven years, ten months, twenty-seven days, was made February S. l'&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p033">30 i KKNOK J" rank Henry — R' » prisoner was afflicted with pulmonarj' tuberculosis and rapidly failing. On petition of his f and the prison pi united from six years to two years, one month, twenty Km Do six months. Affl losis and prisi r his discharge. For this conini George Washit,- "■.. l&gt;.i\i~ Murder, lift-. This cast- was given verv careful eonsid ban two years and diligent lnv&lt; &gt; the convicion that all ends of justice have been fully served and to reasonable don: mmuted to I years, two month- fj. K. ': under an form i unths, tv ■ink E. Li For reason of exi record and or health commuted from seven years to five ECarlton — Murder, life. Commuted from reason that he, during prison lif»\ has shown &lt;■ .lames Wade — Obtaini: ins; a sufferer from tuberr on recommendation of m reputable , tram fivt its, six months. E'harles Broaden — Mui&gt; Commuted from ty-three to fif? if excellent [irison conduc 1 for faithfully serving as librarian and doing much good t r prisonei bjr Warden Beemer. September Hulji From li! he- follow opinion of Judge Kelligar an Richardson County bai ence for slaughter. Many of Richard 1 for Pi Bai.' lie opinii n larcnv 1 from t! mm month, tli non of i rid Supreme Judge </seg>
            <seg id="p034">(JOVERXOH 31 •05. Billiam Brown — Robbery, three years. Coir.muted from three to ar, one month, thirtt oa the following communication from B. F. GockI: "Brown was sentenced to a term of three years on of guilty of highway robbery. The plea should have been for a and th&gt; one instead of three years." November Iiencer Myna -Shoot to wound, one year. Tuberculosis sufferer, physician reports that the only chance to prolong his life is • of environment, his presence in the prison is a menace to the convicts. Commute 1 from one year to three months, December John H. Blair — Rape, three years. Commuted from three to four months, fifteen days on account of the contradictory testimony of the prosecuting witness and the needy c mdition of prisoner's family. He has been a model prisoner and shown earnest repentance. December E Frederick Sargent -.Murder, twenty years. Sargent was in point of ce the oldes' inhabitant in the piison, has for several years and never violated the privilege. In his ir.ore than twelve 3 within the prison walls then has never been a mark against him. these reasons and as an incentive to good conduct to the other pris - s the twenty year sentence was commuttd to fifteen years, eight ven days, January 1. I ■ ating — Robbery, s is. Commuted from seven years years for reason of new evidence being produced which led Hon. i F. Warner to ask that txecutive clemency be extended to the r. January M I fat — Rape and incest, life. This commutation was made _th of the convict's excellent prison record and his evident '1 an upright and honest life. His relatives joined in the for li From life to tw terra months February 22. 1 Eul Kozinsl -ars. On recommendation of Judge one hu which prisoner spent in Antelope County jail, ante! Jan Y. Hite — Burglary, one year. Commuted from one year to - on recommendation of Judge Da&gt; Attorney Slabaugh and Chief of Police Donohue, Trial Judge I), forth that lie was led to believe that Hite had been in trouble before, which suli an error. March 2, : Harry II B. On recommendation of many </seg>
            <seg id="p035">32 tFr&amp;n' a reoomi Paul and I* was ma following pi. v the ion I hi If tn ever abstain from the Hanse thai in e I \i r to k&lt; James Dillon n prison and i rick and citizens commute;) from three years to two years, six months, seventeen days. May 11. 1! b James Neary— model i from three years to . nine months. nln&lt; fou: 8, nine month that his idered ex&gt; let in prison excellen ly was found in destitute condition. July t Charles Fox— Daylight ;ir. three moo h. - it of Judge KelliL ite4. A 1906. Ix&gt;uig Woodruff— I oner's wife and many and for the reason that I doubts as to his pui. prosecuting wi ron: ftJOl n months, i days. September 1, 19 Mark T. Hunter -Obtaining ion of his wife and on account of old age, good pi consideration ik-minded as to be I irresponsible, con \ montl 15, 190«. Ida Terrill — Robl" by the n board declared insane and transferred to the Hospital for Insane. Lin from her nutated to five months, thirteen da] [James F. Wright — Incest, fifi. mnendation of to nine years. e months, eigh &lt;la* - ()&lt; tob«c 27 IMC. Johi. Horse stealing. 1 uted to I </seg>
            <seg id="p036">(JOVERXOR'S MESSAGE 33 Graves, and the prosecuting attorn McAllister. December 3. t Zimmerman — Horse stealing. ;wo years. The prison ph\ tifles that this Indian convict is afflicted with scrofula and tuberculosis 1 strongly advists his from prison. Commuted December kE. J. King -Grand larceny, two and a ha Commuted to nine nths, seventeen days on recommendation of Prison Physician Holyoke, prisoner being consumptive. December 17. 1 Daniel \V. K uiult to kill, thn The senten 1 W. K&lt; ■ that the complaining Malone. who had him arrested, asks for his release le prosecuting authorities of Lane .nty also joining. For still urther reason that his health is |&gt;oor. having been hurt before he was to the penitentiary: his cocdid having been very good; he now laving served about the minimum sentence and upon the recommeoda - on of the warden of the penitentiary, the governor believes it i uty to commute I &lt;-e to take effect at once. From three o two years, four month-, twenty el tier 20. ! t Ernest E. Mann -Burglary, two I'ommuted to eight months, nty-flve days, the amount taken -mall and th&gt; tr.ing Xicholas Gentlemen — Mini: n years, mute 1 to te:i years, the miniirum s&lt; iving the foil' communication from eleven of the twelve jurymen: "The m. jurors who sat in the I. Gentleman, in 1 County in February fully make the following representa' before the homicide Gentlemen had been drinking ex - and the crin* i loubtedly the resul: of his long and ex- T intoxicants. Before removing fronr. the farm to Platte r he ha I a!'.' ir, industrious, law-abiding man and stood lly high n publ We understand his conduct in the penitentiary has been exemplary always and we feel in view of that fact and thp good reputation he bore before he became ad&gt;: to the use of liquor tl stantial reduction of his sentence would be all Also the following: "As I was one of the twelv. round Nick Gentleman guilty in Platt. Nebraska, for which crime he h;is since been serving a nineteen sentence in the penitentiary. I would be pleased now at this time r would reduce his ■ mitnient of time and in ■ tion he has now served a term a&lt;l&gt; i his harsh act." (Signed) Frank M&lt;&gt; 4 the twe-lvi December - </seg>
            <seg id="p037">34 REPRIEVE Frank Barker — V ih. On Jane the Sui&gt;; reversed the decision of the District Court of Lancaster County, holding that said District Court ha;l jurisdiction in the case wherein it was sought to determr laity or insanity of Frank Barker ■ Criminal Code, Compiled Statin. mg impossible to I mine the question at issue prior to the dan- of execution a reprtci said Frank Barker Iwnri ory U|&gt;on the Governor. That the courts may have ample q h a final determination a reprieve until Jun. JAIL COMMUTATIONS. John Monroe — I-anca^' On recommendation of Judge Cosgrave and Rev. Thompson to fifty-thie.' iayi 27, H John De&lt; iglas daylight burglary, four nion hs. On n.eudation of Judge Day and Prosecuting Slabaugh t. months, » days, April I Louis Boughner — Lancaster, daylight bn ilx months and fine. On recommendation of Judge Holmes and Dt puty Count \ ■ William Washington IH&gt;u_ From OM year peniti to one year county jail on request of J&gt; June 16, 1!" Geoi 'ouglas. breaking into a car, six months reoomnendatinn of Jud| months. June 16. *— — ft«&lt;i OB request of pris oner's destitute wife, July 21. II Harry Fink — Douglas. railroad ticktt. On mendation of Jndg&lt; from six months penitentiary to six months county jail. July 2!*. II Willard John^ .iult and battery, ninety &lt;i muted by Acting • ton on request of trial j sheriff, and prosecuting August 21. I Paul Egley — Lancaster, prostitution lays. On ricomn tion of .1 •• an.1 1: five days. A 30, II Elmer Beard— Lai days. p ( from Judge Cornish and Pr&lt; commuted t(j days. Noveml Heber F. Haney— Lancast. days On peti tion of Polici Judge Cosg; </seg>
            <seg id="p038">35 Kirman — Lancaster, drunkenness, thirty days. On n on of Judge O t days, .1 906. Harry Craft — Lancaster, hirty da nineteen days on recommendation of Judge Cosgrave, July 24, 1906. Bjph A. Knox — Lancaster, wif&lt; &gt;&gt;n, three months. Released n days' canfinement on petition of his wife with the consent of [olmes. October t Eliam M. Campion — Seward, .bastardy, indefinite sentenc ti investigation of t ; irony given justify ation issued Octol FJohn and George Vim 1 from Lancaster (' December 21. 190*, for nison of th. 'ondition of their fami - and on advice of Deputy Conn Tyrrell. k William M. Campion — Seward. The pardon issued Ootobti </seg>
            <seg id="p039"/>
            <seg id="p040">OF Governor George Lawson Sheldon TO THE THIRTIETH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA JANUARY ;. To the Senators ami Representatives, Tin lebraskM: J am i' ' you upon this invasion. 1 appreciate beyond jiression ti the people of N placed in me ;it the last tion I appreciate deeply the hijjh howw thereby crmfeiTed upon me I wish t&lt;&gt; thank my friends throughout tli- r the loyal and enthn - s\i]i]Hirt th»'v gave me during the rampaif wiallyjyi for t! id support &lt;&gt;f the loyal republican* and the indejwi to other political partiea than the one to whirl) I the pleaMnre of li»-loiif;inK and liy which I was nominated To the memben of the legislature. 1 ilesire to offer i which I hope and trust will ]»■ taken in the same kindly way and with the same IToihI will You will </seg>
            <seg id="p041">38 booad nut to rain any inn will l»- i ■ ■((iiniiiv. The ■-stimates for current ttxptamm dariag the next biennium Bade l&gt;y the haad&gt; I institnt. iiat it will b -lion Highly th' tferent institutioi - - junket ii .■ pact ha- -n beneficial reaultx It is. then otnmended that u joint conn linteri for the porj^xtf of via • i '-! rations ami injuring into their actual ik ■projiriations are n, The ladaMaiMaa al the nkl !»■ il&lt; imaperous By an act of the hu&lt;t lagialatal* proi ■ - nuide lot meat &lt;&gt;f the outstanding i n&lt;lebt«lne&gt;- &lt;&gt;f the ■ hat act will • nt of the debt within irs if futiuc ■ppnipsiationii within reasonable bounds. The current a*|W W must 1h&gt; kejit within It will pablk d.-tit at thifl 4 this ■tale, ami Dnii The field for invi-&gt;tiii - •ind should !»• enlarjjed. Ti ther forms of inv.stin.Mit equally an tutf e that would increase the i: urn to the fund If it wei vtMtml in &gt;iiuin&lt;'i|ial hoada, achool bonds, or in Nebraska inort| Ntate would W l»enerite«l on account c&gt;f the interest being iKlid at 1 rt of this floal u]i by the state treasurer for the lieneritof tin- pennMi There will lie. therefore, about |»ni (HNl of the pern hool taroatai on this account akN -.1 tod will n idly ■ &gt;f the treasurer when tli ndebtedneaB is ]&gt;aid off. Therefore, it will lie for the lx-r,t ii *tate that this aMjUflai of the constitution 1»- anieinl.-d &gt;., that future q deterniine from time to time what daai o# ;ulditi&lt;&gt; - shall be available for the investment &gt;)f this fund Tli' t'luie law of 1008 has brought about one «rf the most uni - ■uwiauwi ' But there is rtill hich will provide for a more e&lt;[uitable distribution of the Imnlens of taxation aaMMg the ]&gt;ro]»erty holders of t &gt;ler the ]ires«'nt la\ hat is mortgaged is ilsscsmnI for awpoaaa at its full value t' the land without air ■ r the amouir In additioa to ti </seg>
            <seg id="p042">OOVERXOR'S MESSAGE 39 Emnliered wit ■ piece of real ■ that is not mortgaged under the law if the aortg .1 by a mam-tmndmoi at and a great many of them art', no tax is levied against it heranae construed t&lt;&gt; lie personal property. Personal proper! &gt;h1i]nis.-&lt;1 to lie MMMd where tin owiiw of the property n I If do lie tax*il then certainly foreign wmattgpgm should The sensible thing t&lt;&gt; do is n&gt; tax all mortgages. lx&gt;th fi ; nuestic, aa an interest in i Being aaaet ite they vviiuM then 1.. for taxation ]iur]Nisn, wht land is and not where the mortgagee lives. The vulue of the moi • should then 1h i from the value of the mortgaged estate ai .. estate a— coocil ■pea the aqaity he paaaaaei It is contended by many that the result of such a law would incrmnc ite of interest liecause Nebraska is not yet a creditor state. I? libility of an inerea.se in the interest rate may ; rmitting the privilege of contract whereby the owner of the land if he chooso )iav rhe tax on the interest of the mortgagee. He afford to do that and lie none r 1 1 • tf than he is at present. capital that is available for the inv mortgages is driven out of the state non residents may lie expected t' the rate of interest as they no doubt will do when I petition by d&lt; tpital. .ring the ]&gt;ast ten iiitifullv liles.se&lt;l with . and jirices The )ie.i]ile of _' off their in - leMadneai a I * umulatiiiK capital which should ha invested at home. ,t law discrimina" I domestic cajiital and in my o] forcing the residents of this &gt;tate to invest their capital in The i ,\y iniii«&gt;s«*s a tluab Id by a resident of this and to that extent it increases beyond mea.su re the tax upon thai It is not fair to tin- residents of mi public policy to continue the pernici a of the present 1 • rt. aotber amendment that is needed to the revenue law is one that will l&gt;ermit the reduction of Ionia tide ini nder the inesent man who is in debt is taxed for all t' id for all tk btor class of property holders should not be rompeQi . irdinay bunl&gt; ition Notwithstanding the fact tli ■tate permits the deduction of Inma tide debts in Hither, we are still discriminating against the debtor &lt; _'ht nor ji. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">40 lent property holdi much limit' f the city. t&lt;i\vn and vill. online to the than do the h liavi- their terminals within tlit- corporal The railroad bepeflto from the cities, prujKirtioii &lt;&gt;f the city ■ It it curjKi! • lr full share of tin- taxes But the Burlington railroads have refused to pay in full the taxes irly a»««&gt;N.sed and levi. -t them for the ly delinquent aboat three qaar usal to pay this j !&lt;■ million dollar-.. Their artioa m ; i» m&gt;t fair to the other I - of the state and i-. wholly irnujt«i v .-&lt;1 Th' eminent tifullv of it&gt; land, and the ]ieo]ile (if this state in ;&gt; • lli Imild the-*- railn.aiN Beaidei •riction whatever ujxin them in the maf - U]p to the preNcnt time el Pimrt and ma t. Tin-- irporationa, by their r«ndn ■ nolile ijuality fa K that their caodw doubt they would a&gt;k for the protection of the they deny the ri_ wnmn ai r ]iro]&gt;erty its it ■nrnmir Hi all l&gt;ro]&gt;eny Kverytlimj.' that ran lie done will 1»- done to enfor. lion of the«&lt;- delin .1 railroad jirojierty in the fatal far a.« tgnied, will continue to l» at whatevt llection ot a ta.\ i that privilege But rail - relief through the (• I'ntil lijirivinjr them of thi&gt; j,n tberefon s-«d meiiionali/ ini. r congress to paM will .I from enjoining the raUertioo l.-vieil property within 1 1 tThe Burling. hi railroad for tin- i&gt;ur]Ki&gt;«-&gt; of bam i niT. But * companies A; r the different branch lines simply K' x tne whole system within the state I The : roperty with the information furnish aid a»se«i«nient is a difficult jm - tioii mi the part of air ~s»-s&gt; them unreasonably r </seg>
            <seg id="p044">41 but ti worth. Railroads which o] i t&lt;i fnrniah tor each and every branch lii of all t). - .1 that tl law in tin- The question &lt;it eqaital n isa difficult &lt; &gt;i it- A mii! of property according to it - inly to I in any wel i&gt;t proportion of the Imnlen iity shim' It i&gt; neither a crime to I • r tliat it i- the property anil not th&lt; '1 be All amendments \ that will eliminate douhli ion ami loifotin — •-- - •■nt of property will !»■ welcomed l rely at !:• I In the condnct and nun nntitntioi ' iction in it&gt; man. different iiurtitntioi should lie held responstHi ir roncluct and for the r -tlv t&gt;&gt; the The law- of T 1 1 i — ild !»■ an n in which this &gt;tat&gt; vc a delinquent ur incon to it that the 1 ■ plainly thai The .. riallv tl i if the li kind uf pi tii m lobbj ittually mi line of work. men who, by thei' i which id lobby. It ml to riiiK rule n bat that there will also 1m- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">42 111. Hi- Ii.iw.iii • n thiit ill -titutmnal amendment providing for ilftinitflv define the i that will ili-urlv. Fining oiilil he upon it the riminatiooR of ev&lt; to any ■)) prat n hi i.i liMulity . and v or all « tariffs thai are in iiv rairloiul in tlii- -&gt;t;it 'hat thf I l.t-t tlii&gt; law In- w h &lt;!«■! i I MTiit ii ii U- liv r 1 1 - I 'hat you deprive tl urtli It is furt In itiiui law thai will deprive &lt;-i &gt;nuix&lt;ii carrieni i&gt;miuit»iion Im - i|i-ral .-..' I siiK-.-f.-ly lN'li.-vt- that it will be im the heal 1 1 . - *fatf that "iir immediate attenti&lt;« t.. t li«- pnactment of laws that will do with ]in ' I will ulHilish the ' lilroad oiiim i this The iieople dm .il that tliis work hetlottr as qoi&lt;-kl&gt; vvill permit. I ujHiii the tart that tht j v \is We hare railruarfa. !■■ . tiv law t &lt; &gt; cuiitn. date tin </seg>
            <seg id="p046">43 :'-.tl will be a just we, Let u^ work together in harmony. It i - i that sill publican party keep before them tin ii republican state convention Let n i'ultil our promises ami our |&gt;led_ I realise somewhat tl ii|Hin me, and appreciate the importance of the work that lected without ohligatii &gt;t the trust 1 owe the i their paUic servant, 1 shall endeavor in the administi affairs of on tided by whal be for tl and for tl her people. I I* malic- toward ..rations that ha strenuously opposed. and which probably will c tntinne to opixwe. the i liahment of c.nnm &gt;n jartice in this state. Their rij hen they abuse their privileges as they have doiif in th&lt; - !»■ bekl to strict account The weM must not !*• ]&gt;ut out of lmsincs-,. but that tl out of Nebraska politi I realise fully that this reform movement wealth, but rather a movement against graft ami and abuse of p It ha-, for it&gt; object the establishment in this state, from one end I eminent by the people and for the general welfare of the Legitimate interests must he protected. (' inspirators againc goodand violators of the law must be prosecuted. The law ■ land must prevail. I hope and trust that I shall have the loyal sii ninsel of tlie good citizens of t&gt; With the lig their intelligence, and with the wisdom that "God may grant me, I and trust my administration may meet the expectation of the people of this I.AUSON SHELEH &gt;N </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>