<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00031.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00031.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIRST BI-ENNIAL REPORT NEBRASKA FORESTATION COMMISSION APPOINTED BY THE GOVERNOR BY ORDER OF A RESOLUTION ADOPTED BY THE NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE, 1913</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FIRST BI-ENNIAL REPORT NEBRASKA FORESTATION COMMISSION APPOINTED BY THE GOVERNOR K)ER OF A RESOLUTION ADOPTED E NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE. 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">PREFACE The Nebraska Commission on Forestation was created by a resolution introduced by Honorable J. H. Mockett, Jr., upon the request of the German- American Alliance of Nebraska, in Legislature of Nebraska. 1913, known as House Roll No proved April 5th, 1913, viz.: "A Joint Resolution authorizing the Governor to ap imaMon of three to investigate the feasibility of forestati I; in the sand hill region of this state, ami to make a report to the Legislature setting forth a comprehensive plan for the utili/;i - of such lands for forest puqx&gt; "Whereas, there are over one and one-half niilli lands belonging to the State and situated in what i~ is th&lt; sand hill region, these lands being for the most part unfit for cultural purposes and used mostly for the purpose of grazing, i rhcrcas, a continuation of this policy leaves these lands in an eloped condition, with a consequent economic loss to the "Whereas, it is of the highest importance that the state pursue some consistent and comprehensive policy looking to the t. development of these lands, especially as to their adaptabilit forestation purposes, therefore "Be It Enacted by the People of the State of Nebraska "Section 1. That the Governor is hereby authorized on or before August 1, 1913, to appoint a temporary commission of inquir consist of three members from among the citizens of the having special qualifications and knowledge concerning forestation of lands. The commission so appointed shall serve without salary or expenses. "Section 2. It shall be the duty of such commission to fully in- </seg>
            <seg id="p003">forestation of school lands belonging to the state situated in the crn part of the state, and known as the sand hill section, and to determine the policy best calculated to further and encourage the planting and the growth of trees thereon. "Section 3. It shall be the duty of the commission after f investigation to prepare and submit to the next Legislature a fu i report, embodying a comprehensive plan for dealing with the f estation of the school land in the sand hill suction of thi the end that the state may hereafter pursue a complete and c nt policy thereto. The report shall also contain or be accom - panied by a draft of such proposed law or laws as will best enabk the findings of the commission to be acted upon by the Legislature We believe the problem of forestation is an important i all the people of Nebraska, as it relates to the broader quo conservation, as a close study of this report will reveal Respectfully submitted, Carl Rohde. Chairman, Columbus. A. H. Metzger, Rolf. Woodruff Ball, Sec Valentine </seg>
            <seg id="p004">L t i lit Of v i 1 1 I u hese s« i mitiated a state ciallv correct ; t t I lou tion tii n work in we upon the Ne the Bureau of The experic forest reserves I » la^ I I % [orehead, Governor, and Members of the Thirty c joint resolution passed by the thirty-third se Governor to investigate the desirability and feasibility Nebraska, especially as it would apply t ns upon the question of viitir Commission, have vithin our state, we eport ,ir in\ ii, w e do : for the afforesting of the Nebraska. This, not for t lly grown, but for the rea lie state would be prohibits ;eparate state school sec - le reason that trees can - ;on that the cost of ad - e, owing to the isolation the state, through a system of sale or barter of Is, to obtain a compact area upon which can be policy of afforestation economically and commer- pursued along lines similar to those in vogue National Forest Reserves, under the control of restry. ce of the Bureau of Forestry upon our national Juring the past ten years has demonstrated beyond jt the feasibility and the practicability of afforesta - stern Nebraska. f the Nebraska Legislature .lthorizing the appointment of a commi- Is. with recommenda !■■ &gt;t uchcvc that the time cparate sections. s. [owever, we would most earnestly urge upon this session of the islarure tlie desirability of the state retaining title to its pr lings of school lands, especially such as are not adapted to agri- ural pursuits, for in the near future it mav become desirable </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 I this commercialized age. all things are figured in dollars and . This appeal! to us as the surest route by which to reach the est of not only your Legislature but the people of the state at , hence the last statement of the Bureau of Forestry relative suits obtained upon the plantation at Halsey, Nebraska, upon :ismal national forest reserve, is highly interesting and instruc - and we quote you as follows from their forest service bulletin ol "Forestation of the Sand Hills of Nebraska and Kansas": Kck pine, in 20 years, should make one first-class and one sec - t per tree. These may safely be valued at 8 and 4 . respectively, or 12 cents per tree. Suppose, then, that 2,500 are planted i&gt;er acre, at a cost of $8 per thousand. Of these, 80 vtit arc jack pine and 20 per cent yellow pine. Suppose again, that 80 per cent of the jack pines and 60 per cent of the yellow - succeed. The 1,600 jack pines, cut at 20 years, give a gross income of $!92 per acre. This is sufficient to cover the cost of plantation, with 4 per cent interest, and protection at 10 cents per acre per year, and leave a rtet annual income of $4.87. The 300 \ pines per acre are left, and being freed from interest-bearing debt, may be grown to almost any age with reasonable assurance of t. While these are rough calculations and subject to error, it •i difficult to see that the growing of timber on the sand hills, both for minor and major products, may be on a perfectly safe financial basis and may be putting the land to a considerably higher lan for grazing."' We question if today the State of Nebraska is obtaining a greater average than 6 cents per acre per annum through leasing school lands of like character. This foregoing statement proves that under factory conditions our state too could show a profitable invest - ment resulting from the planting and maturing of forests. The need of trees and forests that can be commercially utilized needs must be too self-apparent to every citizen of our state to warrant our discussion of that phase of the forestry question. Indi- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 5 personal reasons. However, owing to the length of time involved between the planting and maturing, it does not appeal to the indi - vidual citizen as a business proposition, and such an enterprise there - fore must devolve upon the state and its lesser political units. Eil such time as the State of Nebraska may see fit to adopt a policy of forestry, we believe every possible inducement and ragement should be offered our citizens and these lesser politi - lits for the planting, cultivation and maintenance of tret forests. For this purpose we would recommend the enactment of legisla - tion that will permit exemption from all taxes lands planted to forest trees; this exemption to apply to these lands and their prod - ucts until the forest trees thereon become merchantable timber, and as marketed the products will be taxed as personal property. Sim - ilar laws are now upon the statute books of many of our states. Profiting by the past experience in foreign lands of municipal owned forests, which are scientifically administered and return large net earnings to the tax payers, aside from the social benefits derived therefrom, as public outing places for their citizens, many of states now permit of their cities and villages owning and operating municipal forests ; Massachusetts at the present time having 56 town forests. Wherefore we recommend that our present state laws covering parks and public grounds should be so amended . permit our cities of all classes and villages to obtain by purchase through special levy or bond issues, gift or device, lands to be de\ to forest purposes, with provision to allow for their proper main - tenance. In fact, we would go further and strongly recommend and urge that similar laws be enacted whereby our counties may own and operate, separately or in conjunction with cities and villages, county forests. These suggested amendments and new laws should be made applicable to lands upon which there is now standing timber, as well as lands for re-forestation and afforestation purposes. At the general election held this fall, the city of Chicago and Cook county, of the state of Illinois, voted favorably upon the proposition of J Mr Mr Mr </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT i i t i i i i i re r I i i bonding themselves for one million dol procee bonds to be devoted to the purchase of lands for r county forests. If the state of Nebraska is to retain her rank with her si states, she must of necessity adopt and pursue a consistent j state forestry. That we say this advisedly is substantiated fact that at the present time 32 states of our Union main forest departments, with annual appropriations ranging from S2 in Vermont to $327,000 in Pennsylvania. Each of the ide a forestry commission under various titles, the commission ha general supervision over all matters pertaining to the quest forestry within their respective state. Workin c of these commissions is a salaried state forester, the active officia Ee of operation and administration. These states all own &lt; ire State Forest Reserves, aggregating many millions of aci state of Maine alone owns 9,500.000 acres, and New Y&lt; ,000 acres. Those states interested in re-forestation w&lt; :ain their state nurseries. It is a well recognized fact that time is a most essential factor the growth of forests and their products. Again, this commissi recognizes that before the necessary funds can he obtained to in ate and further a forestry policy, the public must be further e&lt; cated to the needs of such a course. If Nebraska is to ultimat accomplish results, a start, however small, must be made. Whe fore we feel that it would be public policy for this Legislature continue a commission similar to the present commission, without recompense from the state; this commission to ma further investigations, recommendations and reports, keep in tot with forestry work and conditions at large within and without t state, and doing such publicity work as opportunity and their me; may offer. L T nc]ucstiona.bly Nebraska in line witli modern forest ry ide </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBF ASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 7 1 nation, | c ■etc ill permit of tl iobrara Forest tunity, make provision for the appoint - e Forester under an annual salary, he to forestry commission, co-operating with f Forestry within Nebraska, the State servation and Public Welfare &gt;epartment of Forestry, and to act in Rureau of Forestry had under con of the Niobrara National Forest Reserve, e attention of our commission, and while ch a movement, we, as individuals, i lion would l&gt;e most detrimental to md so believing, felt that we should i hich would demonstrate to the Bureau of For - element of our citizens did not desire any fur - be response, we are pleased to advise you, was 1 \valk&gt; of life, of such character and volume ceded from its position, and the ire from Congress an enlarged appropriation, which tie Bureau of Forestry duplicating in time upon the i rve its present nur.-ery plant at Halsey, in the Iliat the direct interest of the settler and indirect ka might be protected, a soil survey of eoi le at our solicitation bv the Soil Survev \griculture and our State Soil Survey. this reserve by the Government within the bound - , ill inure to the benefit of the coming generations the forestry work within this state goes no further for the present, we, a^ individuals and as a commission, be- of 1 1i p t wo vpir? li 'i vp viTiflir"itPfi on i* p vi^tpn r*f* 3^ ndividuals and public organizations in- egislature &lt;li&lt;l not contemplate that the Further, we were able, as a result of thi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT k mission and the wisdom of the thirty-third session of the Ne i Legislature in creating a State Forestration Commission. Respectfully submitted. State Forestration Commission, Carl Rohde, Chairman, Columbus, Nebraska. A. H. Metzger, Rolf, Nebraska. Woodruff Ball, Secretary, Valentine, Nebraska. Valentine, Nebraska, December 28, 1914. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>