<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>the Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VII. A Comparison of Corn and Kalo in a Ration for Growing Chicks</title>
               <date value="18??">March 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 109 The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VII. A Comparison of Cora and Kalo in a Ration for Growing Chicks C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blistv and F. E. Mussehl LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MARCH, 1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. The effect of replacing 31 per cent of ground corn in a ration by 31 per cent of ground kalo was studied in a growth and body-analysis experiment with two lots of newly hatched chicks. 2. The amounts of feed consumed by all chicks of both lots were kept identical by hand-feeding equal amounts of the pelleted rations daily. i. There were no significant differences in the growth rate or composition of the chicks at the end of a six weeks' feeding trial. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VII. A Comparison of Corn and Kalo in a Ration for Growing Chicks C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. IILISH AND J\ E. MUSSEHL Reasons for the renewed interest in the sorghums are given by Kiessel - bach, Cushing, and Frolik (1), who discuss the agronomic phases of the crop in Nebraska. The value of sorghum as a forage crop has been demonstrated but it is commonly believed that the grain sorghums have a lower feeding value than corn. This belief is based in part on compari - sons of yellow corn and sorghums made before the differences in vitamin content of the two feeds were recognized. ' . Since the nutritive value of feeds varies with the type of animal fed and its vitamin requirements, it is important that conclusions are based on the particular type concerned. The replacement value of the sorghums in livestock feeding has been reinvestigated in recent years but only a limited amount of this work has been concerned with poultry feeding. Thompson (2) concluded that milo is satisfactory in a laying mash, and Hinds (3) believes that milo can be used in poultry rations if vitamin supplements are provided. Heywang and Morgan (4) and Payne (5) con - cluded from growth experiments that grain sorghums can replace corn in the diet of growing chicks when adequately supplemented with other nutrients. The digestibility of grain sorghums for poultry is given by Kaupp and Ivey (6) and Fraps (7), but studies on the utilization of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus from rations where sorghum replaced corn have not been made with growing chicks. : • PREPARATION OF THE RATIONS The purpose of this experiment was to compare the utilization of the nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus of Nebraska ration No. 8 with a ration in which the corn of No. 8 was replaced with kalo. Since the kalo used contained more protein than the • * corn the former.was adusted to the . ) .. .¦ Ration Rarion protein level of the latter by the ad- "X- No. 8 No. 8-kalu dition of starch. As No. 8 formula ¦¦¦¦ y, s u, s contains 31 parts of corn, the modi- Ground yellow corn... 31 0 fied ration was mixed with 31 parts Ground kalo.. 0 ¦/ 25.6 of a mixture of kalo and starch and C 0"1 —— • • ° 5-4 designated as ration No. 8-kalo. Sh°rts .......:.:.... 20 20 ¦»tl ¦¦.¦¦- . -,-.- . . Bran 10 10 Ihe two rations were mixed as fol- Pulvcricd 0at5........ 10 10 lows: &#132;.•¦': : : .:.''. , Alfalfa mea1.......... 10 10 Afluantity of; the rations with- mclT/.Y.'/.'A 5 5 out either the corn or kalo was Dried buttermilk...... 5 5 mixed in sufficient quantity for the Calcium carbonate.... .2 2 two lots. One-half of this quantity Sodium chloride : ,.... 1 I </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 109 was mixed with cither the corn or kalo plus cornstarch to form the com - plete rations. After mixing, the rations were pelleted by means of a 5/32 - -inch die. The experimental variable lies in the substitution of corn for kalo. The corn or kalo contributed 16 per cent of the total protein of the rations. The compositions of the rations are given in Table 1. Tablk 1. — Analyses of the rations. Ration Water Ash Nitrogen Calcium Phosphorus P.ct. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. N'&lt;&gt;. 8 9.1 8.0 3.37 1.66 0.93 N». K-kal" 9.1 8.5 3.47 1.77 0.97 fc.ti.rn Cr f U'lc C™de P^ Nl^ ff~ rat fiber extract Ca:P P.cl. P.ci. P.ci. P.ct. N". 8 4.6 7A 21.1 -19.8 1.77 N". H-kaln ¦).&lt;) 'A 21.7 -18.4 1.83 EXPERIMENTAL FEEDING The chicks used in the feeding trial were White Rocks chosen in a weight range of 35 to 39 grams with an average intial weight of 37 in each lot. The practice of feeding all chicks in both lots the same quantity of food daily was continued. The manner of feeding the pelleted rations was described in earlier work (8) and need not be repeated here. Twenty - one chicks were started in each lot. Three chicks of each lot fell slightly behind the feeding schedule during the final week and were discarded, so 18 chicks completed the trial in each lot. The chicks were housed in two electrically heated brooders in a room maintained at a temerature above 70° F. Cod-liver oil was fed individually by burette at a level of 0.5 per cent of the ration. The experiment progressed without incident until the fourth week at winch time there were three cases of wing picking among the chicks of the 8-kalo lot. These chicks were segregated until the wounds healed and hoth lots were closely watched for further outbreaks. Cannibalism was limited to the 8-kalo lot, with several more cases occurring before the close of the experiment. No cases were permitted to become severe as victims were immediately segregated. No cases occurred in the No. 8 lot. This is of interest in view of the observations of Miller and Bearse (9) on the cannibalism-preventing properties of oats and oat hulls. The rations of both lots contained 10 per cent of pulverized oats and thus should have contained the cannibalism-preventing factor in equal amounts, yet cases were frequent in the 8-kalo lot and absent in No. 8 lot. The difference thus lies in the substitution of 25.6 lbs. of kalo and 5.4 lbs. of starch for 31 lbs. of yellow corn, the amount of protein from each source being kept the same in both instances. In previous work at the Station (10) the </seg>
         <seg id="p005">¦ Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks - f. dilution of a 22 per cent ration with starch resulted in cannibalism and coprophagic tendencies, , : .Records of interval weights of individual chicks were kept, and by comparison with the food-intake records rates of gain of all chicks were calculated. The averages are presented by sex and lot both for the interval gain and the period gain in Table 2. At the outset the chicks of lot No. 8-kalo made greater gains on the same dry-matter intake than those of lot No. 8, but lost this advantage so that over the period of six weeks the average gains on yellow corn exceeded those on kald. . Table 2.— Rates oj gain oj chicks. I Rates ot^ Cms o.v Successive Increments of Dry Matter A«e of chicks (day 5)............... ,: 17 24 29 33 37 41 Dry matter increment {g.) ....V....:. 141 136 137 127 136 143 Lot Ration No. 8 i 12 males, rate of gain (/ur.) 52 56 50 50 27 55 6 females, rate of gain (/&gt;.&lt;:/.) 55 -.; 56,; ,48 43 32 51 Lot Ration No. 8-Kalo 12 males, rate of (jain (p.cl.). .... 59 52 48 46 24 52 6 females, rate of |jain (/?.(¦/.). 60 55 45 44 26 46 Rates of Gain ok Chicks, Calculated at Attained Weight on Gain -'".:¦'" ¦ -•;¦¦!.'• Over Initial Weight . : Total dry matter fed (g.).., &#132;:..... 141 277 414 541 677 820 ' : Lot Ration No. 8 , :. 12 males, rate of K ain (fi'xt.),.:'.¦ 52 54 53 52 47 4'Jl 6 females, rate of Rain (/&gt;^-/.)....... 55 56 53 51 47 4S' • ¦;¦.¦";¦.:¦ . Lot Ration No. 8-Kalo / 12 nialcs, rate of j&gt;ain (^.c-/.)......... .59 56 .'53 51 46 47 1 6 females, rate «f «am (p.r/.)....... 60 57 53 : 51 46 46' &gt;thnc values differ from the &lt;in« in Table 5, jlncc the lallcr arc luscH an I lie nci-uci K lu ami Ilicsc on llicj! livc-wcißht figures. ¦ ' ¦": ': '.'.'- I' The feeding was started October 11 and continued to November 21, at which time the chicks were killed by ether anesthesia after feed had been withheld for 16 hours. Individual live weights were taken, and after the contents of the digestive tract had been removed their net weights were noted. The amount of "fill" under these conditions was slightly under 4 per cent of the average live weight. The mean net weights of the chicks are given in Table. 3. Differences between means are small and the analysis of the net body weights fails to reveal any statistically significant difference as is evident, in Table 4. . </seg>
         <seg id="p006">NI.BRASKA AcHL. H.XP. STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 109 'IM'Li 'i.—Mani net weights ' at slaughter and their standard errors. , ... 1-1 Mules anil females '¦'" '•'""'" (unwiKhtol mean) v- c- s - -1...1 R.,t,,.n N.i X ¦11').50±4.X() -H2.50±fi.79 -116.00i3.92 l.nt Rjiinn No. K-kalu &lt;U0.33±-t.IH) 3'«.50±6.79 -KH.91±3.92 Lmmghinl mean -1H.91 ±3.92 H(lfi.ol)±i.92 -»10^5±2.77 1 Dk- in i nvii:lii i* :lif «'.-i(:hl of ilir chitk -iftrr removal of the cunlcms uf the iligcslivc tract. Tahli; 4.— Primary analysis of the net body weights. . Decrees of Sum of &#132; . Standard Source iv \.inaiion * . Variance . • . frccilom squares deviation Sulxlnss i 1,6-17.22 539.07 I rrnr 32 8,85-1.67 276.71 1fi.63 Tnlal 35 10.5f11.89 . . DISCUSSION The data derived from this experiment are presented in Tables 2, 3, 4, and 5. Table 2 shows that the kalo-fed lot made greater initial gains but lhai the corn-fee) lot made greater gains during the rest of the period. Tables i and 4 show that these differences were not significant. An inspec - tion of Table 5 shows that differences were slight and that the composition of the chicks of each lot was not affected by the ration fed. Likewise the retentions of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus failed to show material differences which could be attributed to the rations. The one difference observed was in the incidence of wing- and toe - picking by the chicks of the lot fed No. 8-kalo. Serious interference with the- progress or the feeding trial was avoided by separating the victims, and the pens were closely watched to detect further outbreaks. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks • Table s.— Summary of growth and analytical data on chiefs. Item Ration No. 8 Ration No. 8-kalo Males Females Males Females Number of chicks 12 5 J2 6 Net weight (g.)... ¦:...'.......... 420 415 410 400 Gain in weight-far.), 382 377 373 363 Dry matter fed (g.) 820 820 820 820 Rate of gain (p.c1.).-. 46.6 46.0 45 5 3 Gam per gram nitrogen iu\ (g.).. ! 12.5 12.4 119 JIV Nitrogen in chick (p.ct.) . . 3.34 332 334 330 Calcium jn chick (p.ct.) 0.9-t 0.92 101 092 Phosphorus in chick (p.ct.) ....... 0.64 0,64 0 69 063 Ratio, Ca:P in chick..........-... 1.46 1.44 1 48 H6 Nitrogen in gain (p.ct.) ,:....... 3.43 3.41 3 42: 338 Calcium in gain (pM.).......... 0.99 0,97 ! 07 o ' 9B Phosphorus in gain (p.ct.) :. 0.68 . 0.67 072 067 Ratio, Ca:P in gain 1.47 1.45 J. 48 146 Ether extract (p.ct.) 4.5 5.2 : 3.7 47 Nitrogen intakd. (g.) .....: 30.48 30.48 31.38 i 3138 Nitrogen in gain (g.)............ 13.09 12.85 12.75 ¦ 12*26 NHfogen retained (p.ct.) 423 42.2 40.6 $~? Calcium intake (g.).. 15.01 15.01 1599 1590 Cacum in gain (g) .:..... 3.80 3.67 3.99 355 Caloam retained (p.c1.)......... 253 24.5 2510 222 Phosphorus intake (g.). ..:......¦ .8.05 8.05 8.74 874 Phosphorus in gain (g.).......... 2.59 2.54 270 2*43 Phosphorus retained (p.c/.)...... 3Q.g iQ2 305 2 7A CONCLUSIONS 1. The substitution of kalo for corn in an otherwise complete ration tor growing chicks had no significant effect on the growth rate of chicks up to six weeks of age. ' . 2. The retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus was not signi - hcantly altered by the use of kalo in the radon. ; : 3. Instances of cannibalism were confined to the kalo-fed lot. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Ni.braska A&lt;;rl. Kxp. Station Research Bulletin 109 LITERATURE CITED 1. KusMI.HAI 11. T. A.. I'I'SHINU, R. 1... AND FKOUK, K. V. 113 N. Ncbr. Apr. Kxp. Sta. Bui. 31 f&gt;. 2. Thompson. R. B. I'MB. New Mix. Apr. Kxp. Sta. Hul. 117. i. HIVDS. 11. )!. l&gt;)!7. Ariz. A«r. Kxp. Sta. Bui. IW. 4. HIiWAVC. M. W.. AND MORC.AN. R. H. I''.J2. I'culln Scirncc II: 307-17. \ P\VNt. 1.. I. I'MH. Kansas Apr. Kxp. Sia. Hul. 268. h. Kaiim&gt;, It. 1"., asii Kiv. J. K. l'&lt; 23. N. C. Aj;r. Kxp. Sta. Tech. Bui. 22. 7. Kraps. &lt;*. S. l l'2X. Texas Apr. Kxp. Sta. Bui. 372. 5. A&lt; KKRSON, C. W., Hl-1111, M. )., AND MusSKIII., !•'. R. I'Ms. Ndir. Apr. Kxp. Sta. Res. Hul. IIW. 'I. MII.I.KR. M. W., AND BhARSK, Cl. E. MX. Piiultry Science- 17: -(66-71. 111. Aikik.son, ('. W., Hush, M. )., and Mi-ssßin., 1\ E. I'M'i Ncbr. Apr. Kxp. Sta. Res. Bui. 108. [2S4MJ 8 </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>