<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER, 30, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER, 30, 1906 BY John T. Hay, M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">\HI) nF 1TBLIC LANDS AND Bl'ILDIN ITon. Henry K, Eaton. Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings _ President Hon. A. Galusha. Secretary of State Secretary Hon. Norris Brown Attorney General Hon. Peter Mortensen State Treasurer RESIDENT OFFICERS John T. Hay. M. D. Superintendent Harrison A. Wigton, M. D Halle Ewing, M. D. First Assistant Physician Second Assistant Physician Pathologist Albert D. Gilmore, Esq Steward Miai Cora L. Damrow Matron XOX-RESIDEXT. L. B. Pilsbury, M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska: — B: I have the honor to submit the eighteenth biennial re - «&gt;1' the Nebraska Hospital for th&lt; Lincoln, cover - he period Iron December 1. 1H04. to November 30, 1! Having held the position of superintendent only about four hs my report must be chiefly of what took place under an - rement I.I. L. (ireiMie, who had managed the institution in a very manner for about five . ed on .July 16, 1906, to &gt;t the position of superintendent of the Eastern Illi ital for the Insane, al Kankakee. I was appointed to fill me date. I&lt;; A. Vountr. path' rtitntion for about four . was promoted to lie superintendent of the Hospital at Nor - bnt did not assume the duties of that office until the 10th •tober and in the meantime acted as First Assistant Physi - in this hospital. Dr. L B. Pilsbury. of Lincoln, was appointed to till the va - 1 by the promotion of Dr. Young. Dr. Mable Dunn, who had b&lt; stant Physi about four j ngned on Aug. 15th, 1906, and .*eed - y Dr. Halle L. Ewing, formerl nt Physician at the iuni. Ken Dr. Young assumed the di Boperintendent at the Ik Hospital. Dr. H. A. Wigton, of Omaha, was appointed position of First Assistant Physician. I mi this it will be seen that almost an entire change in the ■al staff has taken place within the last four months. I am ■d to state that all of the new appointees are working with 1 and interest which promises first Milts as soon as ie mure familiar with their dui MOVEMENT OF POFILATION. of the period December 1. 1904, th. ■ atients in the hospital LM4 men and M4 women i . Daring &gt;&gt;d 111 pat it- • men and !l woi </seg>
            <seg id="p004">126 and drug habitues (738 men and 343 women), making the total number under treatment 1,688, of which 962 were men and 726 women. »Pull details of the number of patients discharged, transferred, :., will be found in Table No. 1. ('he number of patients of all classes remaining in the hospi - at the end of the biennium was 548 (203 men and 345 men). Of these 40 (38 men and 2 women) were patients ad - ted under the Dipsomaniac law. The average number of pa - its actually present in the hospital during the two years was . The number under treatment was 85 more than during the vious biennium, and the average number present was 16 more a during the previous biennium. The number of deaths during this biennium was 134 (19 more than during the previous period). Of these, 2 were inebriates, and the L* deaths referred to in the table as accidental occurred in June of this year, one being an epileptic who fell in a fit while fishing on the banks of Salt Creek and was drowned. The other vas a demented patient who wandered away and was found dead in the field near the hospital. Both of these cases were investi - gated by the county coroner. Another death which was probably suicidal occurred in the fall of 1905. A woman who was out for exercise escaped from the attendants and running up the steps ci the fire escape jumped from a height of 30 feet and struck with such force on the pavement that the spinal column was fractured and the cord injured to such an extent that she died a few months later. CARE OF THE PATIENTS. The standard of care has been raised in many ways and were it not for overcrowding there would be but little ground for plaint on this account by the general public or those who have relatives in the hospital. A training school for nurses was established over a year ago in charge of a trained nurse and the l.ospital idea is being carried out as much as possible. Women nurses for men are being tried on one of the male wards and so tar this arrangement has proved very satisfactory. The necessity of letting aside one of the male wards for in - ebriates has interfered materially with the proper classification and treatment of the male patients and if this condition is not </seg>
            <seg id="p005">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 127 Eieved by the erection of a new building, I shall recommend the Board of Public Lands and Buildings that we discontinue eiving patients under the Inebriate law. GENERAL HEALTH. I An epidemic of typhoid fever occurred in the fall of 1905 — patients and 4 employees were attacked by the disease and 4 employees and 1 patient) died from its effects. The source the infection was never definitely determined, but the water the reservoir was found to be contaminated and after it was lptied and cleaned and the whole water system disinfected the jease was checked. This summer the water was carefully ex - lined once a week by the pathologist and whenever the least fn of contamination was found proper steps were taken to medy it. The result has been satisfactory as we have been actically free from typhoid fever and other infectious diseases [ring the last summer and fall. The general health of all pa - nts in all departments is now exceptionally good. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. Much has been done along this line. Two new boilers were installed in the summer of 1905, two new dynamos were pur - chased, one of the old ones having given out entirely and the other being used as a motor for the laundry machinery. An electric motor and pump has been installed at the pump house, this doing away with the steam plant, and when a duplicate for this pumping machinery is procured the steam boiler can be re - moved. This arrangement is very satisfactory and much more economical than the old method of pumping by steam. Seven power sewing machines were placed in the sewing-room and these are propelled by an electric motor. I Steel ceilings have been placed in two more of the wards of s old building and in the halls and some of the rooms of the Iministration building. A great deal of painting and decorat - l has been done. An addition has been built to the boiler house d laundry. The laundry addition is not completed and a spe - il appropriation is asked for to complete this and to install ne needed machinery. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">128 REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED E duplicate of the pumping machinery at the pump house is ed to provide against accidents which will require an expen - re of about $10* »■ Tv. ago attention was called to the condition of the reservoir and funds asked for to enlarge and repair it. This now for n ith in the report of ,;il appi " l(l is asked for this purpose. connected with the kitchen h is filled with natural ice every winter at considerable trou - iii iec house for tbt thought that this cold i plant can be ii artificial ice and cold plant which will not l&gt;e letter in every way but in the end economical. A spe - cial appropriation of - ■■(! for this purpose. new building for men has been need veral years and iature has 1" 1 repeatedly for funds for this pur - pose. At present th&lt; proper place for acute curable cases and for the chronically sick and feeble. Many of these patients BOW housed in ■ basement ward which is altogether unsuitable. 000 to build a hospital building for men t ilMiut 1 &lt; m ) patiei DIPSOMANIACS. ETC. Th&lt;- la- an act providing for the treatment in this hospital of "" dipsomaniacs, inebriates and p&lt; kbet - e&lt;! to tl: of morphia r other nai -. " This law went into effect July 1. 1906. We beean re - ind up to Xov 77 men and 10 women). Of this num - men and •"&gt; women I to the 31 men and 5 women I wen morphii both. The - that this class of patients shall !»■ treated in v it we have never been able to live up to the l&lt; of the law in&gt;-tli j.art of the patient - i that institution </seg>
            <seg id="p007">129 tin- male patients of this class were placed in a ward by them- selves and since then most of the men have been treated apart the insane patients. As there have never been more than o or 4 women belonging to this class here at one time and as the Is for women have been crowded no attempt has been made to provide a separate ward for them. Patients under this law are committed for an indefinite period •ding th I. We have never with one or two ex- &gt;ns kept patients of this class more than six months and most of them have gone away within three months. The results of treatment have varied greatly, as was to be ■ted. Many of the inebriates have been cured or much bene- by treatment and this is especially true of patients who have come to the hospital willingly with a desire to reform. Those who have been sent here against their will have received little or no benefit. Of the drug habitues I know of only two or three who seem to have been apparently benefited by the treatment. Of 166 earn of dipsomania and - of drug habit, the tits having been away from the hospital 6 months or more, ihr results of treatment are as follows so far as we have been j'ble to ascertain : INEBRIATES. apparently cured much benefited IT Xo. receiving no benefit Unknown Total DRUG HABIT No. apparently cured Xo. receiving no benefit I'nknown &gt; Total U Further experience in the treatment of this class of patients lead to better results. The parole system provided for in the law was adhered to up be summer of 1906, when this section of the law was de- clared to be unconstitutional bv the State Supreme Court. Now 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">130 I treatment of this .hiss ol patients in ;i hospital for the • many They require dir e. different treatment, and different discipline froth the in - arate institution. If the to continue to attempt to &lt;-niv for this claw of defec should Ih- amended in many particulars A suitable place ulil be provided and proper rules for their commitment, &lt;!&lt;• inn-lit iiinl discharge should be made. With loneil I believe much pood eould only to the unfortunates themselves but t&lt;&gt; the whole nity. The law provides that the counties sending |&gt;ati&lt; tin- - - to the hospital shall ; their board and care. The rd of Public Lands and Build ed tliis eharj 5 per th and most of the eountiea have paid for three month's ti each patient sent to the hospital. This m has tumr into the each fund of the hospital and has been used for - In all we I i about $12,000 from this ■id about $10,000 hi ended and accounted for into the hands of the steward of the hos] FINANCIAL STATEMENT AND APPROPRIATIONS NEEDED. (nring the biennial period il led for all pur - 7.19. of which all w;is from appropriations made by I about $lo.(NMt I from the eou the eare of inebi imount $214.61'J current ex] ad the balai number of patients durintr the |» month. Tlr ipropriated for all f wind | t impn &gt;rdinarv running j i - ■Mr. I </seg>
            <seg id="p009">HOSPITAL FOU I 131 iticiits would be so large, p &gt;elonging to tin- Xo district having been kept in this hospital mueh longer than ted. The amount appropriated wan only ai the rate &gt;!_'. "&gt;n per month for each patient, which is not sufficient. Of the appropriation* made by the last legislature thei cpended &lt;ni the ; 5 (| th day of Nov.. 1!)oti. a bait -_' Mosi of the funds are entirely exhausted ropriation of from $15,000 to $20,000 will be the institution to the 1st of April, 1!mi7. Expenditures from December 1. 1!&gt;&lt;&gt;4 to March 31, 1905, tppropriations for periods of two years ending Mar. ■ •&lt;■ of appropriations unexpended ■ mber 1. 1904 IfoHpital for [mane fund i"_'7 ii'in-y appropriation II. \l. Xo. "&gt;4 iency appropriation II R. Xo. 302 nded for employes waji •■ officers' salaries services chaplain T -"» . t m &gt; board and elothing 651.55 fuel and lights 4- general repairs ! paints and oils -&lt;. implements and han new ranL r '' and kitchen furniture returning patients drugs, books and i stationery. : telephone T4.)i4 new boiler and repa am plani building barn L'! new plumbing repairing and improvements ] from Deficiency App. H. R. Xo. " ( 4 179 from Denciency App. H. R. s </seg>
            <seg id="p010">132 Balance of Deficiency App- H. I 4 1.41 Balance of Deficiency App. II . B Balance of funds (lapsed 2317.98 $41010.30 $4101 Appropriations of Apr. 1, 1905 and amount remaining unex- pended Nov. 30. 1906 Appropriated Balances 1905. Nov. 30, '06. Officers' sal;.' $1* 0 $30- ployea v 4WOO.00 719 .-s chaplain 300.00 rand clothing ... 80000.00 145.33 and lights IT Drugs, l&gt;ooks and instruments 2500.00 3.37 ige, telephone, ft.-. 1250.00 Paints and oils 2000.00 itral repairs 00 3.04 v fire hose 1000.00 _inc room repairs 00 11-18 •s, harness, implements, etc Furniture and beddim.' _ &gt;00.00 id burial of patients 1_ r dynamo, electric pump. 3000.00 airs for laundry 1000.00 192 Totals '0 $1417 [MATES OF Al'I'KOPKIATIOXS NEEDED FOR YEARS 1907 AND 1908. CURRENT EXPENSES Officers' salaries 419,700 s' wages Board and clothing 90,000 and lights 17,500 Drugs, books and instruments Postage, stationery, telephone and express _ 2,500 I aints and oils ' </seg>
            <seg id="p011">133 NK, LIN( tin Furniture and bedding 'i ransportation of patients i dry repair! and machinery lea, harness and farming implements 1,00 Library, music anil ami Total EXTRAORDINARY EXPENSES. New building ten trie motor and pump Enlarging a ti&lt; 1 repairing ur 1,000 Artificial iee and eold si nit .1,000 Total The per capita expens i per month is n&lt; live and is &gt;r below the cost of maintaining institutions of similar and character in surroundii For the two j ling March 31, I i are based on the probable a\' ipulation of total amount 200. If a new building ided and ir use before the expiration of that period an additional sum i -■ net CONCLUSION. The report of the steward and the pathologist and the tables are inserted. There are two additional tables. No. 9 and 10, which an I at the request of the National of Charities and Correction. The thanks of the management are due to yourself and the members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings for your uniform interest and assistance rendered in mana&lt;rin&lt;r the institu- •tfully submitted, J. T. HAY, Superintendent. Nov. 30, 1906. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT &lt;»K PATHOLOGIST. I'o the Superintendent: During the time in which the id charge of the laboratory, ■ period ofi r iik in) h&gt;. routim nations of pathologic material have nducted \n endeavor has been mad' of urine from each patient admitted. mi&lt; iniiiat inns nt' the lil I and sputum have been made whei &gt;teriologic examinations of effusions membra ebro-spinal Hiiid. etc. It seems fortu - e tliat the Widol test has been needed in sn few i ust ;i typhoid fever having occurred in the house dur - that probably of alien origin. A preat deal •■!' tli iologic technie employed has bee 'ii with the miination of the pply. I- ninths I water : roir, through whieh most of the water used by ■I examined every week or ten days 'id approximate number of bacteria pm direci water supply, that is the water as it ecimes from the found t. isms of all\ little attention lid to this source. On only two found colon or eolon-like germs in tin r in an &gt; ind on these occasions !■ unals were discovered on allowing the out. After draining the reservoir was thoroughly i to the brim with water, copper sulphate added ; n tl nt 1 to 6000 and allowed to reman ■er whieh the solution was carried away through i.ll tlie main- vice pipes of the water system. After f micro-organisms falls to a minimum. I animals in the storag oir can only by tin- fact that the pi covering of the basin, in tl wooden doi lied with tin. has ifficiently so that considerable crevices exist, ■ the eovei .lie and concrete foundation. repairing the &gt;n. replacing the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">135 liiiii: where badly worn ;m&lt;l earefully screening py orifice, but ;i better way would seem to be to deepen the i-oiici-ete hjisin by riiisniL' its si ( |. entire inner with eemelit and then to liilllil I new dome. This would 111 - pacity of the reservoir and at the same time decs the chances of contamination. Of course an iron stand-pipe wi he preferable to any concrete There have been added to the laboratory in the past few moi • nly such supplies and incidental article* daily conduct of a pathologic laboratory ral valuable u] instruments belonging to the former pathologist, I&gt;: \ Young, were of course removed by him at the tin, departure. Perhaps the greatest need of this department ol ital is a new niorirue which should be supplied with a pi autopsy table, instrument cabinet, an ice-chamber, and he. - sufficient to make autopsy work tolerable in th her. The present detached structure is lacking in all above facilities and its replacement would seem to l&gt;e desiralilc for Itoth sanitary and (jeneral scientific t Among the I'luipmetit needed by the laboratory may lie mentioned a microtome of the rotary type, an electric centrifuge, an .■■ the rapid sterilization of culture media, and a blood-pres linu 1 apparatus. rhe pathologist w thank the superintendent for turagemeni and material aid extended to his departmei hospital w &lt; ■t fully submitted. I.. B. PIL8BURY. Pathologist. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">KOR THE THIRTY- Ending Novkmhe 30, 1906. — ■ «. ■- •£ C &gt; E — = e = - a — =. o *~ a \ - v. 49 Cl lat 17 72 117 114 124 73 m 145 274 -SIT 394 479 KU2 | ( | t /&gt; 1"."&gt;4 1062 917 44 71 74 74 81 72 1 i * 101 lOtt 90 166 113 121 10 6 I 5 11 11 10 47 33 M 19 21 30 lit 14 14 17 47 HO 91 79 47 1 4 1 1 6 a 19 37 19 2 41 16 8 4 9 7 2d 23 20 21 14 1 2 1 .... 4 1 4 2 1 4 4 3 3 3 2 2 I 7 4 7 10 11 12 .... 1 1 1 1 1 I 1 1 4 ■&gt; 2 1 1 2 5 2 3 13 1 1 14 15 17 2«l 36 21 31 19 32 27 31 21 U so 19 :n; 27 52 til .".4 71 12 41 4 14 1 IT n 131 4 ■&gt; 2 1 1 1 •&gt; 2 3 1 4 1 4 I ino 2rt 42 Hi 30 K &gt;7 54 ItS 109 1*1 130 34 IS 19 1!) 2 It. 4 M n i« 77 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">HOSPITAL POK INSANK, LIN' 137 Sub-acute 35 6 41 Chronic 18 20 Recurrent 10 12 Puerperal 9 9 Melancholia — Acute 109 70 179 Sub-acute 5 9 14 Chronic 10 11 21 Recurrent 4 14 18 LK No. 1 Movesie: OF l'OPULA' 190H Total f&lt; Year a a 3 a = t hospital at I)e}jinninff of year luroed from parnli- itients admitted us: and liquor habit admitted. . 214 :i74 190 4 I B 1 T x till 214 10 ruder treatment ' 1177 id ivcovervd d improved d unimproved d not insane artfed^rujr and liquor habit Transferifd to Hastings -ferred to Norfolk Kloped. insane Kloped, drug and liquor habit. . . it on parole. . . 44 10 1 17 41 4 i 1 1 71 121 10 192 21 1 47 14 11 21 71 217 147 ! 21 1 7 47 47 Total removed 536 llemaininyr Noveml*M- 90 (ill ■ ajre number treated 222 TAB ,B NO Type of Disease of p itients admitted. (Insane). ania — Men Women Total </seg>
            <seg id="p016">138 28 4 ndary 4o 12 Ic Acute Delirium 14 •J!l 1 14 ianit&gt;' 44 -.inity .) 14 12 me 1 li 4«il [XEBR1 '• ■ HABITUES liolisin ■_'4t; .it :i 5 TA H I Couni 1 Which Patients Were Admitted Inebriates and Dnig TusiiiH-. Add Total Men. Wonii Men. Women 10 r. 1 1 4 1 -2 1 1 9 1M 41 1 7 1 1 12 - 21 • &gt; ■ ; Buffalo ia b«i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">10 2 11 •_&gt; 4 I Dakota 2 Dawea •J I Niwaon Deuel 1 ■2 I )ixon Id 1 &gt;&lt;&gt;&lt;lir&lt;- Douglas 57 o 12 147 Dandy 1 ■^ Pilbnore i I 11 Franklin 4 7 14 frontier 1 Fnnias 2 10 11 t - 1 27 •j 2 1 1 . &gt; 1 1 1 1 ii I t ;i I I h 4 i • &gt; 19 Hamilton 9 • &gt; 1 15 Marian 6 4 Id I iilVl'S 1 1 Hitchcock 1 1 ."&gt; Howard l' 1 Holt .&gt; 11 •i eft** rs&lt; •! i g 3 Juhnaon 1 5 1 15 1 1 .*&gt; Kearney !t Kcva Paha 1 2 15 Kirnhall 1 1 K'nox 4 1 2 i Lancaster 74 54 153 Liiiciiln 4 4 Madison .". 2 7 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">t) — o J. X Rolls 3 3 14 6 1 16 4 in M 1 1 2 1'helps 11 114 6 4 Willow 3 3 Ridbi 9 S 21 1" 4 .) 1!" 4 4 4 12 18 9 9 - rd 8 2 3 13 Bheridao 13 4 1 1 2 2 3 3 6 ba Blufl 1 2 14 Tha.v. - 7 11 24 Thurstun 2 2 13 3 7 2 8 1 1 Id 4 4 14 er 2 Vorii 1- ii o n I'ork Thomas ] j . . , Totals 461 333 277 10 TABLE NO. 4. Ages of Patients Admitted. Inebriates and Drug Insane. Addicts. Total. Men Women. Men. Women. 80 17 19 3 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">141 32 24 1 40 40 40 57 34 58 151 40 to 45 46 40 44 39 48 131 50 to 55 32 17 9 26 11 70 14 11 4 1 70 to 7.", 17 14 3 BO 1"&gt; 6 2 Id 7 17 90 100 to 10f&gt; 1 1 I'nknown 5 5 5 1"&gt; Totals 461 333 277 10 1081 TABLE NO. 5. Civil Condition of Patients Admitted. Inebriates and Dru^ Insane. Addicts. Men. Women Men. Women. Married 173 185 162 9 Single 218 67 87 wed 43 16 reed 14 19 12 45 I'n known 3 1 17 Totals 461 333 277 10 1081 TABLE NO. 6. Nativity of Patients Admitted. Inebriates and Drug Insane. Addicts. Total. Men. Women Men. Women. i Minor 1 1 Austria 3 3 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">142 4 12 ( hina 1 1 12 12 4 nark M 4 ."&gt; 18 lan.l 1 1 •&gt; 31 24 1 1 1 1 1 4 •_&gt; Norway 1 1 1 ■_&gt; in] . &gt; ,an«l •&gt; 2 4 - 18 14 1 tzerland ■ ) •&gt; 4 1 1 310 215 221 !(• own in l-j 4«il 1*77 in TABLE NO 7 PATIONS OF PATIENTS ADMITTED [nebriatei and DniL r me. Addicts. Total. Mi'ii \A Mfii. Women. ■_&gt; ■&gt; J hildren's H&lt; \ 1 1 7 1 &lt; 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">143 r.utcher* IT &lt; arpenten I' 1 Cattle tiuycrs . 1 1 pel Weaver 1 Can 1 Clerks 1" makers 1 1 I nntraotnr ( ontraetor Collector ! per 1 ( ..uks 1 Court Hniliff 1 I )iinicsiics 1 -enlists 1 &lt;makers '•' ■&gt; Draymen 1 Druprpists 4 hlectncians i stationary 1 ineers, locomotive 1 Fnpineera, civil 1 Farmers 194 64 Farm laboren 21 men. stationary 1 ■men. locomotive 1 lener 1 1 se Trainer* 2 4 1 House-mover 1 •keepers 245 Hotel-keepera 1 Laborer* 4~ Jonrnalisi liathers 1 I.JIWV.Ts - erymen 1 1 S •ns - rshal 1 1 \i • i </seg>
            <seg id="p022">LAND ( '&lt; (MMISSIi 144 Hers 1 2 3 2 16 1 1 10 4 5 1 5 1 3 5 2 4 1 3 ] f) 2 1 1 18 2 2 21 l 333 277 10 1081 .Milliners _ 3 era . 1 N urses Painters 4 Icing-houM foreman _ 1 1 ma - Plumbers u-hers Printer* . . 3 al Clerks .... 1 •r 1 Kailroad laborer Saloon-keeper 1 o 2 i]&gt;hers 1 rappm raveling salesmen I , •&gt;._ Veterinary surgeons liVashwoman SVatch-maker _ 1 •upation 'nknown % k 461 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">145 TABLE NO. 8. CAUSES OF DEATH. Men. Women. Total. .Abscess of liver 1 1 Accident 12 3 Abdominal tumor 1 1 Acute miliary tuberculin - 2 .Acute delirium 1 1 iJrain tumors 1 1 Cerebral apoplexy 4 1! r ■inoma mammary gland 1 1 Carcinoma of stomach 1 1 Chronic bronchitis 2 Chronic nephrite 1 1 Dysentery 1 1 Krysipelas "_' 1 3 Epilepsy 3 Kxhaustion of primary dementia 1 1 of chronic mania 2 2 of acute mania 4 of acute melancholia 3 2 of senile dementia 6 20 of alcoholic dementia 1 1 stinal tuberculoxi- 1 1 obstruction 1 1 Organic brain disease 3 4 heart disease 3 2 1'ernicious anemia 1 1 Pneumonia 7 Pachymeningitis 1 1 Par.-- 6 4 in Peritonitis 1 l Pulmonary tuberculosis 1 6 7 Pulmonary stenosis 1 1 Tuberculous meningitis 1 1 2 j </seg>
            <seg id="p024">146 1 1 TABLE NO. 9. rR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1905 POPULATION. Femal tof inni.i .nt at beginning of fiscal year 214 374 588 Kved during the year 356 discharged or died during the ft. 335 at end of the fiscal \ y average attendance ( i. e. : No. of 203 201 376 inmates actually present) during the 2-1-1 394 616 year t-age No. of officers and employes during the year 47 44 91 EXPENDITURES Current Exp- 1. Salaries and wa I lothing ibsistence 4. Ordinary repairs luniestir- and outdoor exp. 13530.59 Total Extraordinary Expenses. 1. New buildings, land, etc. 2. Permanent improvements to ex- isting buildings Total Grand Total vafM ..$34377.28 5922.18 50402.63 &gt;airs ~&gt;71.53 ... $118334.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">147 TABLE NO. 10. FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906. POPULATION. Male. Female. Total. Nn. of inmates present at beginning of fiscal year till No. received during the year 4&lt;&gt;!&gt; ir&gt;7 No. discharged or died during the year 441 Xo. at end of the fiscal year rily average attendance (i. e. No. of inmates actually ; during year 220 Average No. of officers and employes during the year 4ii '"4 EXPENDITURES Current Exp&lt; 1. Salaries and wages $3492 2. Clothing 597 3. Subsistence 45777.97 4. Ordinary repairs Vi!»6.07 Office, domestic and outdoor exp. 11457.74 Total $103732.60 rtraordinary Expenses. 1. New buildings, land, etc. 2. Permanent improvements to ex isting buildings 1054.33 Total 1054.33 Grand Total JE STEWARD MAKES REPORT PERTAINING TO THE PRO - DUCT OF THE FARM AND GARDEN. FARM PRODUCT. Corn 7000 bushels. Oats .6037 bushels. Spelts 1372 bushels. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">LA N D &lt; '&lt; &gt;M M I { KPORT 148 344 bushels. Millet Seed GARDEN STATEMENT FROM DEC 1, 1904 TO DEC. 1, 1906 Kind. Quantity. Quantity. Bu. Pk. Bunches. Heads. Number 1 14435 2 53 872 1 2 1 2 1 1 2 : Prairie Hay Alfalfa Hay ;ons. tons. Clover Hay Millet Haj Cane Hay Mixed Hay and Feed .00 tons. Straw 00 tons. 1'nsilogo Corn Buifhen-d 73570 lbs. Bntehend -■-!45 lbs. Ifutchered U282 lbs. I gallons Apples .irasrus tring 231 vax ... 14 161 Tops 1 la Cauliflower Ties tli ap] umbers 8 156 Plants - Plums ■ 1 n Peppers lersdkh I "ttuce 3 1 220 2 i old </seg>
            <seg id="p027">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 149 Onions, doz. bunches ...._ _ Parsley 31 Parsnips 212 2 Teas 187 2 /eppers 4 1 Pickles 79 Plums 1 Potatoes U840 Pumpkins Radish, s 173 2 Rhubarb, 38 lb per bu. _ 234 1 Rutabagas 1 Spinach 7 Squash Strawberries, qts. Sweet Potatoes 177 3 Tomatoes, green 28 Tomatoes, ripe 853 Turnips 617 CASH FT' XI). STEWARD'S REPORT — A. D. GILMORE. RECEIPTS. Dec. 1. To balance on hand $1,706.19 Dec. 1. Mrs. John Barret, 2 weeks maintenance John t Barret . 8. Geo. Reed, sale 1 syrup bbl. . 8. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 4 No. 1 G. S. hides, 176 lbs. at 8%e . 8. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 G. S. hides, 114 lbs. at 7%« 6 :S Dec. 8. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 4 No. 1 G. S. hides, 176 lbs. at 8i L c 14.96 Dec. 8. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 G. S. £ 8. John M. Denman, sale 1 boar pig Dec. 10. Kate Wilderding, time lost after pay roll was sent to Secretary of State's office 1 Dec.10. Nona Weart, same as Miss Wilderding Dec. 10. Josephine Kelly, same as Wilderding Dec. 10. Eloise Fitch, same as Wilderding </seg>
            <seg id="p028">150 Dec. 10. P. A. Biesen, same as Wilderding 4.17 Dec. 10. E. Tyrer, sale 1 ham, 7 Ib at 12%« .87 S10. E. Tyrer, 40 Ib lard at ft 10. Mrs. Baret, maintenance of John Baret two weeks 22. Lincoln Hide &amp; Pur Co., saie 4 No. 1 G. S. hides, 208 tb at 8&lt;- 22. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 5 No. 2 G. S. hides, 216 Ib at It 26, Chas. Aldeen, 3 months maintenance of Alb. Lindber&gt;r to Dec. 17. 1904 at $12.50 3.60 6.25 weeks 22. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 4 No. 1 G. S. hides. 208 tb at 8c 16.64 fee. 22. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 5 No. 2 G. 8 hides, 216 Ib at 7c 15.12 26, Chas. Aldeen, 3 months maintenance of Alb. Lindberg to Dec 17. 1904 at $12.50 37.50 26. Mrs. John Baret. bal. due for maintenance of John Baret 3.00 26, Mrs. John Baret. bal. due for maintenance of John Baret 4. Jacob Dixon, maintenance Simon Dixon to Feb. 1, 1905 4. Jacob Dixoii, maintenance Simon Dixon to 33.75 Jan. 4, J. A Harden, sale 1 boar pijr 10.00 r. 6, Lonetta Wanser. time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec y of Slate's office 4.44 Jan. 6, Martha Hedman, same as Mrs. Wanser Jan. 6, J. A. Wiles, same as Mrs. Wanser 2.13 Jan. (&gt;. H. E. Austin, same as Mrs. Wanser .67 Jan. 6. Bertha Heald, same as Mrs. Wanser fi. Marguerite McClung, same as Mrs. Wanser 1.21 Jan. 6. Nona Weart. same as Mrs. Wanser 4 -4 Jan. 6, Josephine Kelly, same as Mrs. Wanser .81 Jan. 6, Fannie Adams, same as Mrs. Wanser 2.13 Jan. 6, Lenora Linsley. same as Mrs. Wanser .71 Jan. 6, E. J. Brown, same as Mrs. Wanser 4.03 Jan. 6. E. Tyrer. sale 2210 Ib stover at $4.00 4.42 Jan a L. Damrow. sale 1 blank book .15 Jan. 12. J L (Jreene, sale 12 tb sausat" L20 il2. Frank McCartney maintenance of W. S Mc - rtney from Mar. 1 .1903 to Nov. 23. 1903, 8 months and 23 days, and from June 13, 1904 t&lt;» Nov. 7, 1904, 4 months and 24 days at $12.50 per month 169.58 Jan. 16, John D. Shea, sale 1 boar pig 10.00 Jan. 21. P. A. Seidell. sale 1255 Ib lime and 25865 Ib sand </seg>
            <seg id="p029">151 Jan. 21, W. G. Seidell, sale 1-2 load sand .50 Jan. 22, &lt;!eo. Luce, sale medicine 1.00 r\V. (;. Seidell. sal.- 1000 tb lime $5.00 and slacked lime. $7 and 8 yds. sand $8 Jan. 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 4 Ho. 1 salt cured hides 234 tb ; , - 18.72 Jan. 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale S No. 2 salt cured hides branded, 621 lb at 7c 43.47 Jan. 27. Sale 250 tb old rags 2.50 Jan. 27, J. D. Ondekirk. on account sale 1 boar pig 2."&gt;0 ■ 2, Jacob Dixon, for 1 month's maintenance of Simon Dixon 12.50 Feb. 11, J. B. Harris, sale 1 hog. 246 lb at 4c 9.80 Feb. 11, Jas. Ooen, sale 10 Tb bacon at He 1.20 Feb. 11. T. H. Williams, sale 7 lb beef at 5c M Feb. 11, W. A. Campbell, sale 26 loaves bread at 5c 1.30 r. 11. \V. A. Campbell, sale 1 pip head. 25c and 1 liver 10c .35 r. 11. \V. A. Campbell, sale 1 gal. syrup 35c. 12 lb pork chops at lie— $1 1.67 Feb. 11. W. A. Campbell, sale 7 tb ham 77c. 31 If. be at 5c- - 2.32 §b. 11. W. A Campbell, sale 18% lb bacon at lie, $2.03 and 1 pk. apples, 25c Feb. 11, W A. Campbell, sale 1 gal. hulled hominy .10 Feb. 11. K Tyrer. sale 1 gal. sauer kraut Feb. 11. Jas. Coen. sale 8 tt&gt; beef Feb. 11, Max Storkan. sale 10 loav. i! 1.00 11, If. A. Dutton, time lost after pay roll W sent to SccV of State's office .SI Feb. 11. Ellen Bowery, same as Mr. Dutton .40 Feb. 11. Bei Mr. Dutton Feb. 11, Olive Eakew, same as Mr. Dutton Feb. 22. .1. H Ondekirk. bal. due on sale of boar pig 7.50 rM. V. Owens, sale 1 overcoat worn home by him 8.00 Feb. 18, Jas. Coen. sale 12 lb bacon at 9c 1.08 Feb. 18, Jas. Coen, sale 6 lb meat at 5c .30 Feb. 23. Mary Thompson, sale old rags Feb. 24. J. L. Greene, sale 17 lb ham, 9 6-ln </seg>
            <seg id="p030">152 25, Jas. Reed, sale 4 syrup bbls 2.00 26, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 G. S. hides 2 120 ft at T 8.40 Feb. 28, R. K. Johnson, weiehing 1 load of corn .05 1, Jas. Coen. sale 6 tb meat, 30c and 3 tb lard 25c Mar. 3, Jacob Dixon, 1 month's maintenance of Si - mon Dixon 12.50 Mar. 7, L. Stein, sale 370 tb old rags at lc 3.70 Mar. 8. Paul Carlisle, sale of medicine 1.00 Mar. 11, Geo. Blakely. sale 17 Ib live turkey at 17c 2.89 Mar. 11. W. C. Gray, time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office Mar. 11, Bessie Reed, same as Mr. Gray .89 r. 14, S. Aldeen, for maintenance of Alb. Lindberg from Dec. 17, 1904 to March 14. 1905 36.25 M«r. 15, J. A. Wiles, sale 2% ft sash cord at 35c .87 t21. J. R. Purbaugh, sale of 67 hogs and 1 cripple stag 13810 Ib at $4.50 621.45 Mar. 29, Geo. Bartlett, sale cane feed 3.00 liar. 29, Mary A. Thompson, sale of rags 2.00 Mar e of old iron 5180 Ib at 25c 12.95 Apr. 8, J. E. Williams, time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office 6.77 Apr. 8, Ellen Bowery, same as Williams .40 Apr. 8, Josephine Kelly, same as Williams .40 Apr. 8, Bessie Reed, same as Williams 1.61 Apr. 8, Florence Hough, same as Williams 1.06 Apr. 8. E. Tyrer. purchase of 3 loads of cobs 1.50 Apr. 8. E. Tyrer. purchase of 7 ft bacon .70 Apr. 8, J. Smith, purchase 1 calf 12.00 Apr. 8, Jacob Dixon, for 1 month's maintenance of Simon Dixon 12.50 / pr. 10, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 1 S. cured hide 45 ft at 8V4,- 3.82 Apr. 15. Otto Anderson, sale 2 loads cobs $1.00, 29 ft chickens $2.90 3.90 Apr. 19, Mary A. Thompson, sale of old rags 181 ft at lc 1.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">ITAL FOU I 153 Apr. 19, D. K. Campbell, feeding and care of cow 4.00 Apr. 24, Mr. Bennett, sale of old horst _ 50.00 Apr. 28, J. N. Gillan, 1 mo. pasture of cow, May, 191 Apr. 29, J. K. Honeywell, for ice cut 4.00 May 1. Mrs. Darrow, 1 month pasture of cow May 3, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 No. 2 hides branded, 101 tb at 7%c 7.57 May 3, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 2 lamb skins at 35c .70 May 8. Hattie MeKehie, time lost after pay roll was sent to See'y of State's office 1.13 May 8. Ethel Hoffman, same as MeKelvic J'ay 8, Elenora Kahl. same as McKelvie 73 May 8, Lillian Trichka. same as McKelvie 1.53 May S. Max Storkan. sale 40 Tb soap crrecs. 2.00 bB, Max Storkan. salf 12 loaves bread, 60c and 3 lb ham, 36c .96 May 8, Geo. Blakely, sale 1 gal. coal oil .15 May 8, W. A. Campbell, sale 39 tb meat at 10c, $3.90 and 17% soup bones at 5c — $.87 . 4 77 ry 8, W. A. Campbell, sale 10 It) bacon, $1.00 and 9 lb pork chops 90c and 6 tb ham 60c 2.50 May 8, W. A. Campbell, sale 7% tb salt pork, 40c, 3 lb spare ribs, 30c, and 2 Tb mutton stew, 8c .78 r8, W. A. C.impbell, 1 pig li 45 loaves bread $2.25. 4 tb prunes 25e 2.75 t8, W. A. Campbell, 13% gal. skim milk, $1.20, and 2% gal. cream, $1.00 2.20 r8, Jacob Dixon for maintenance of Simon Dixon 1 month 12.50 May 8, C. B. &amp; Q. Ry., rent 80 acres for sheep sheds 250.00 May 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 1 salt cured hide, 51 tb at 8%c 4.33 May 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 2 salt cured hide 55 lb at 7%c 4.12 May 15, J. A. Weart, sale 3 tb pork, 30c and 2 loaves bread 10c .40 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">154 May 15, Jas. Reed, sale slop from general kitchen 25.00 ty 16, Nye &amp; Buchanan, sale 1 car hogs. w. 15620 lb 160 lb dockage. 15460 lb net at $5.17y 2 $800.05 Less freight _ $19.55 Lew corn, $2.00. yardage, $6.48 8.48 Lew inspection 15c Commission $6.00 6.15 $34.18 34.18 $765.87 7t May 23, J. A. Weart. sale 2 lb meat May 23, Dave Moreland. sale 1 yd. sand 1.00 May 24, T. H. Williams, sale 2 pigs 5.00 May 24. J. L. Greene, money left by Eliza Hall .40 May 31. J. A. V ,le 2 tb meat .18 re 3, Jacob Dixon, for 1 month maintenance of ion Dixun 12.50 June 3, Ellen Bowery, sale 6 2-3 lb coffee at 15fl 1.00 June 3, J. A. Weart, sale 2 lb butter at 16c re 6. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 1 No. 1 S C. hide IS It) at le 1.17 re 6. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 2 F. H. S. 40 IT) at Be 3.20 re b if, error double charge, see Vchs. 13613 and the two being the same vouc 2.14 June 8, J. A. \ ,Ae 2 IT) meat at 10c r Edgar Ramey. time lost after pay roll was sent to if State's office 7.74 June 10. \V A Campbell, same as Ramey L29 June 10. Roy Marsh, same as Ramey 3.83 June 10. Fannie Adams, same as Ramey .35 June 10, Florence Hough, same as Ramey 2.13 June 10. Lillian Trichka, same as Ram&lt;\ I s June 10. Susie &lt; ime as Ram. 1.77 June 10. T. H. Williams, sale of 450 IT) coal at $4.00 .90 June 10, Ja^ sale of 480 lb coal at $4.00 96 June 10, Ja- month's pasture of cnw 1.50 June 10 Eva ■ bath brush 1.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">155 I 1 . \ I j r * ' I w i IjJ pi ■ ' 1 j *.&gt; June 11, Mrs. Darrow, for pasture 1 cow month of June 1-50 June 11 J. A. Weart, sale 3 1T&gt; butter at 16c -*8 June 14, Eugene Burnham, for pasture 1 cow for May 1.50 June 14, J. A. Weart, sale 2 tt&gt; meat - 15 June 14, Geo. Shaw, sale of old rubber June 15, L. Stine, sale 1480 tt&gt; rags at lc _ 14-80 »e 16, Louise Borcher. money refunded traveling expenses hum. 2.50 June 17. Mrs. E. C. Johnson. Supt. Home for Friend - less, sale 6 pigs at $2.50 15.00 te 19, B. R. Hearson. 5 weeks board, at $12.50 per month 15.67 June 20, W. L. Roscoe. for pasture 2 cows for May and June 6.00 June 20, Win. Hawes, services cutting grass 1.00 te 21, Dr. Jas 1,. Kreene for 7tf days board of Milo MfCord. at $12.50 per month 3US te H, Dr. .las. 1.. Greene for •_'!•'-- days board of (has. Sterberg te 21, Dr. Jas L. (.reene for 11 days board of Paul Olson 4.44 te 21, Dr. Jas L. Greene, for 4 days board of Snyder 1.67 te 21. Dr. Jas. L. Qrwne for 4 days board of McKinney 1.67 re 21. Dr. .(as. L. QtMBC f« 15 days board of Wal - ter Anderson te 22. F. Gillan. 2 months pasture May and .June 1 cow at $1.50 3.00 June 22. 11. Kaurup, sale pair iboea 1.50 June 24. Jas. Lanjdey. sale 1 sow and 7 pigi June 24. Jas. Langley. sale 14 bu. rye at 50e 7.00 re 27, Dr. J. L. days board J. Snyder at $12.50 June 27, Dr. J. L. Greene, for 5 gal raw oil at 46c June 27, Dr. J. L. Greene, sale 1 pt. turpentine .08 te 27, Dr. J. L. Greene, sale 25 tb Venetian Red 50c and 3 tanks of water $1.2n 1.70 July 1, W. II. I time lost after pay roll was </seg>
            <seg id="p034">156 sent to Sec s office ..._ 1.00 July 1, P. A. Henry, same as Rogers 3.67 July 1, J. O. Brower, same as Rogers ..._ 4.05 July 1. Nona Weart, same as Rogers .83 July 1, Fannie Adams, same as Rogers .24 July 1. H. Hammond, same as Rogers 1.10 July 1, Mildred Haufgarn. same as Rogers .73 July 1, Mjnnie Schilling, same as Rogers ~&gt; July 1, John J. Fussier, same as Roger&gt; 4.17 July 1. Max Storman. sale 40 loaves bread 2.00 July 1. Jaeob Dixon 1 month maintenance of Simon Dix 1250 July 7, C. Wettlauger. sale of medicine 2.00 r8, John J. Sullivan (Platte Co.) maintenance Jos. Wells, dipsomaniac, three months from 45.00 July 8. July 10, Lenora Linsley. sale 1 box red raspberries .15 July 10, Ja- Hire cow 1 month June 1905 1.50 July 14, C. Morris, sale 4 boxes red raspberries .40 ry 14, Saunders Co. maintenance of John Morgan, dipsomaniac three months from July 14, 1905 45.00 ry 17, B. Hawkins, three months pasture 1 colt, use of team and cultivator — 15.00 July 20, Creiphton Morris, sale 1 doz. handkerchiefs .50 r20, Creighton Morris, sale 3 boxes red rasp - berries ry 21, Gage Co.. maintenance Wm. Helman, dipso, three months from July 21, 1905 . 45.00 July 25, Robt. Emerson, sale 1 piece ice .10 ry 27. Valley Co., maintenance of A. Rowan, dipso - maniac, three months from July 27, 1905 45.00 July 27, C. Morris, sale 1 qt. raspberries _ .15 July 29, Dave Mooreland. sale 2 shoats 6.00 July 29. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 11 empty bbls. 5.50 July 29, Geo. Shaw, sale of old iron - -27 July 29, Mrs. Darrow, pasture of cow, July 1-25 July 29, Chas. Frederick, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 100 Aug. 1, C. H. Frederick, sale 2 bu. tomatoes _ 2.00 Aug. 2, C. H. Frederick, sale 2 bu. tomatoes 2.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">157 ■ 2, Platte Co. maintenance Morris Kern from Aug. 1 to Nov. 1. 1905 45.00 2, Geo. Hoffman, sale Vi bu. tomatoes ... 2, Geo. Hoffman, sale 3 doz. sweet corn 3, Wni. Vogfct, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 3, Hargreaves Bros., sale 70% b". tomatoes 70.50 -'. 3, Jacob Dixon. maintenance of Simon 3. Wm. Vogfct, sale 1 bu. tomatoi- Dixon 1.00 3. Wni. Voght, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 t. 4. Lonetta Wanser, time lost after pay roll was sent to &gt;f State's office .40 :. 4. Lonetta Wanser, time lost after pay roll was sent to &gt;f State's office .40 4, Eleanor Kahl. tame as Wanser 4, Eleanor Kahl. ume as V\ Auir. 4. \ona Weart, - Wanser Aug. 4. Nona Weart, - Wanser 4. Josephine Kelly, same as Wl 4. .Mildred Hauf^arn. same as WaBMT 4. Josephine Kelly, same as Wa 4. .Mildred Haufgarn, same as Wanaer Aug. 4. Max Storkan, sale of 53 loaves bread Aug. 4. Max Storkan, sale of 53 loaves bread 4. 1!. Tyrer. sale 1 pr. ladiei &gt; (l and 1 pr men's shoes $2.00 r. 4. K. Tyrer. sale 1 pr. ladies sh 10 hihI 1 pr men's sli Aug. 4. F. B. &lt; le picture molding Aug. 4. F. B. &lt; le picture molding g 4. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 2 No. 1 r. 4. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 1 hides. 37 tt&gt; at 9e hides. 37 tt&gt; at 9c Aug. 4. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 No. 2 hides 91 cut 40 tr&gt; at 8c An-.'. 4. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co.. sale 3 Xo. 2 hides 91 cut 40 TT) at 8c 3.20 Aug. ■"), K. R. Rucker. sale peck tomatoes Au&lt;s. ."), K. R. Rucker. sale peck tomatoes Aug. •"). Wm. Vosrht. sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 II. Fredrick, sale 2 bu tomatoes 2.00 5. Buffalo Co., maintenance of K. J. NfcDer - mott from 45.00 7. \V. A. Campbell, sale 38 !t&gt; beef steak at 10c 3.80 Aug. •"&gt;. Win. Vosrht. sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 II. Fredrick, sale 2 bu tomatoes 2.00 5, Buffalo Co., maintenance of E. J. MVDer - mott from 45.00 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 38 !t&gt; beef steak at 10c 3.80 7. \Y A. Campbell, sale 31% ft&gt; beef, boiling at 6c ■ 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 31% Ib beef, boiling at 6c 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 14^ tb pork loin at 10c 14") 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 14^ ft) pork loin at 10c 1.45 ■ 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 3 lt&gt; ham at 12&lt;- .36 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 17% ft) bacon at 12c 7. W. A. Campbell, sale 17% lb bacon at 12c Aug. 7. W. A. Campbell, sale »&gt;."&gt; loaves bread at 5c 7. Win. White, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 Aug. 7. Wm. Voght. sale 1 bu tomatoes 1.00 r. 12, Saunders Co., maintenance of A. P. Camp from July 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">158 r. 12. Dr. John Smith, personal, for his mainten - ance from Aug. 10, 1908 45.00 maha Co., for maintenance of Alb. A Adaaa, k*g. 10 45.00 r. 12. Adams Co.. maintenance Chas. W. Ktaley from Aug. 7 12. J. K. Megahan. sale 3 bu. tomatoes 3.00 r, 12. S K. Ralston, for maintenan. Ralston 1 month lL'.'.n Morris, sale 1 watermelon r. 12. Hitchcock Co.. for maintenance of Henry Bauer from Aug. 12. 1905 4r&gt;.&lt;)&lt;&gt; r. 12. Lincoln Hide &amp; Pm tie 1 hull hide KM i tt&gt; at Be 8.00 r. 12. Richard- maintenance of Michael iicy from Aof. 13 45.00 r. 13, Buffalo Co., for maintenance of Frank Duffy from Aug. 13. 1 ?♦&lt; »~&gt; Aug. 14, J. R. Megahan, sale 4 bu tomatoes 2.00 r. 14. Wayne Co .. maintenance of Fred Schrader from Aug. 14 45.00 15, Mrs A. P. Ferguson, sale 1 bu. tomatoes r. 17. Northwestern Junk Co., sale 1440 1b old rags at $1.10 15.84 Aug. 17, Fannie Adams, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 Aug. 17. A S. Williams, sale 1 bu. tomatoes r. 17, Valley Co.. maintenance of Christian Cappel from Aug. 17 45.00 Aug. 19, Frank Gillan. pasturage 1 cow for July 1.50 Aug. 19, J. M. Gillam, pasturage 1 cow for June 1.50 Aug. 19, Wm. Voght, sale U bu. tomatoes .50 Aug. 21. J. R. Megahan, sale 4 bu. tomatoes 1.20 Aug. 21. Cora L. Damrow, sale 2 bu. tomatoes 1.00 Aug. 21, Jos. C. Wells, sale 1 % bu. tomatoes Aug. 22, Buffalo Co.. for maintenance of Paul L. Lund from Aug. 22 45.00 Aug. 22, Susie Castle, sale 1 bu. tomatoes Aug. 22, S. W. Burnham. sale 3 bu. rye 1.50 Aug. 22. Mrs. Munson, sale of hay 2.00 Aug. 23. H. Lateovit, sale of 8935 Ib old iron at 2H C 22.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">159 23, Fannie Adams, sale 3% It) coffee at 15c 24. Win. Voght, sale f&gt; lm. tomatoes t. 24. Lincoln Co., for maintenance of John Leibee from Aug. 24, 1906 »Dougla or maintenance of Geo. Houl - iston from Aug. 14. 1906 tDoogil tor inaintenance of Harry Smith from Aug. 25, 1905 25, W. A. Campbell, repairing tL'.'i. Fillmore Co., for maintenance of John Bren - an from Aug. 36, 1905 27. \V. U Weekly, sale 1 piec »27 for maintenance of Sadie Miller from Anir 96 F. B. I ile 1 bn. cucumbers t Coming Co., for maintenance of Jas. Mc- Keeiran from Aug. 28, I!*' 1 "' 45.00 2ft. Frank (iillam. paatura w for Aug. t. 29, Lancaster Co., for maintenance of Win. Hoadley from July 21, 1906 .vug. 29, Mrs. G. A. Younger 1 bu. toaMtOM .50 Aug. 30, Standard Oil Co.. sale 2 empty barrels at 80c 1.60 -'. B. Hawkins, sale of sand, etc .95 2, Dr. J. L. Greene, sale 1 boar pit: 10.00 for maintenance of John Fenton to Dec. 2, '05 45.00 it. 2, Dawes Co., for maintenance of Wm. R. Sim - mons to Nov. 28 45.00 2, Holt Co., for maintenance of Gus. Uecker to Xov. 30 45.00 t. 2, John Gillan, 2 months pasture of 1 cow July and Aug. 3.00 Sept. 4, W. L. Ruscoe, pasture of 2 cows July and Aug. ..._ 6 00 Sept. 4. Hargreaves Bros., sale 27 bus. tomatoes 24.25 Sept. 5. Cedar Co., for maintenance of Fred Frerichs to Dec. 4 45.00 Sept. 5. Franklin Co., for maintenance of Edw. Ful- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">160 7. Gene Burnhau. ■• of 1 cow June and July 3.00 tt. 8. Jacob Dixon. aintenance of Simon Dixon 1 m«' 8. G. F. Swihart. sale of old bath tub 2.00 ward Co.. for maintenance of Louis Thom 45.00 Hospital, sale 1 mien le 1 boar pii; bal. due on pasture Hoffman, sale ',« bu. tomatoes 14."&gt;U 15.00 .50 le 1 boar pig 15.00 bal. due on pasture man. sale \-_&gt; bu. tomatoes .50 -haw, sale old paper and tin 1.11 e old paper and tin 1.11 Sept. 11. R. En lie 2240 ft coal at $4.00 4.48 Sept. 11. R. b ']&lt;■ 2240 tt&gt; coal at $4.00 ■t. 11. B. Tyrer. sale 6 It' meat, $ .60; 2 tb bacon, $ .24; and 250 tb iee, $1.2r. 2.09 t. 11. Jas. Harlan. time lost after pay roll was sent to Secretary ol - office .89 tt. 11. E. Tyrer. sale 6 lt&gt; meat, $ .60; 2 ft bacon, $ .24; and 250 ft ice, $1.25 2.09 rll. Jas. Harlan. time lost after pay roll was sent to Secretary ol - office .89 t. 11. Bessie Reed, sain.- as Harlau .81 t. 11. Bessie Reed, same as Harlau .81 • 11. Fannie Adams, same as Harlan t. 11. Fannie Adams, same as Harlan r. 11. Saunder- •■ maintenance of C. Quinby to Nov. 8 45.00 1. 11 Saunden Co., for maintenance of C. Quinby to Nov. 8 45.00 t. 11. York Co., for maintenance of Ora A. Tucker to Dec. 11 45.00 r. 11. York Co., for maintenance of Ora A. Tucker to Dec. 11 tt. 12. W. A. Campbell, sale 22 loaves bread. $1.10; 12U »&gt; nieat. - t. 12. W. A. Campbell, sale 22 loaves bread. $1.1' 12U It, meat. - tt. 12 W. A Cwpbell, sale 12% ft boil beef, $ .77: 3 ft S; and 61) &lt;rals. milk, t. 12. W A Campbell, sale 12% lb boil beef, $ .77; 3 lb bacon, $ .36; and 69 pals, milk, ■ $5.t.L' 6.75 ■ $5.»i2 6.75 • 12 W. A Campbell, sale 4'^ M ts. cream Campbell, sale cream 4-"&gt; nderwocxl. sale 3 bu. tomato's • 13. J.-i pMtore eow 2 no. 3.00 • 13. Jas. Coen, pasture cow 2 mo. 3.00 rl3. Jas. Coen. sale 1 bo. tomatoes. $ .25; exeg. of chickens, $ l'h 1. 13. Jas. Coen. sale 1 hu. tomatoes. $ .25; exeg. of chickens, $ l'h 1. 14. John Greene I ,,l e 3 ft coffee. $ .7 2 ft supar, $ .12; ice. $ .13 1.00 i. 14. John Greene I ,,le 3 1T&gt; coffee. $ .7 2 It) supar, $ .12; ice. $ .13 5. Wayn. ;,4\ to r 15. Dr. A. P. ,,. water rent to Sept. 16, 1905 Sept L M.-sJnrr m 1.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">161 Sept. 18. R. Emerson, sale 2 loaves bread 10 Sept 19. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 6 No. 1 hides. 31.20 312 Ib at 10c Sept 19. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 No. 2 hide, 61 ft g^ Qq 5.49 Sept 19. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 bull hide, 84 tt» at 8c Sept. 19. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 deacon _ .40 10 Sept. 19. Sale of tomatoes rt. 20. Colfax Co., for maintenance of John Wood - worth to Dec. 20, 190:. 45.00 Sept. 20. Colfax Co., for maintenance of John Wood - worth to Dec. 20, 190 45.00 rt. 20. B. Hawkins, sale 4 yds. sand, $4.00 ; hauling same, $1.0() 5.00 Sept. 20. B. Hawkins, sale 4 yds. sand, $4.00; hauling same, $1.0() 5.00 rt. 20. J. R. Burroughs, sale U^U tt&gt; bacon at If $2.61; and 3 ft coffee, $ .75 3.36 Sept. 20. J. R. Burroughs, sale 14% tt&gt; bacon at If $2.61; and 3 ft coffee, $ .75 3.36 Sept. 21. Floy Millett, for maintenance to Sept. 21, '05 12.50 Sept. 21. Floy Millett, for maintenance to Sept. 21, '05 12.50 rt. 21. Northwestern Iron &amp; Junk Co., sale 1410 Ib old rags at I 1 -* 21.15 Sept. 21. Northwestern Iron &amp; Junk Co., sale 1410 lb old rags at I 1 -* 21.15 Sept. 21. Gteo. Shaw, sale empty cans Sept. 21. Gteo. Shaw, sale empty cans Sept. 21. R. Emerson, sale 1 doz. fruit jar rubbers .10 Sept. 21. R. Emerson, sale 1 doz. fruit jar rubbers .10 rt. 21. Webster Co., maintenance of John Galbreath to Dec. 21 45.00 Sept. 21. Webster Co., maintenance of John Galbreath to Dec. 21 45.00 Sept. 21. H. L. Smith, maintenance 17 days 8.50 Sept. 21. H. L. Smith, maintenance 17 days 8.50 rt. 24. Sheridan Co., maintenance of Pat O'Rourke to Dec. 24 .._ 45.00 Sept. 24. Sheridan Co., maintenance of Pat O'Rourke to Dec. 24 45.00 Sept. 25. John Zimmerman, water rent to Sept. 15, '05 2.00 Sept. 25. John Zimmerman, water rent to Sept. 15, '05 2.00 Sept. 26. Cass Co.,. maintenance of Wesley J. Bower to Dec. 26 rt. 26. Cass Co.,. maintenance of Wesley J. Bower to Dec. 26 45.00 rt. 27. Lincoln Co., maintenance of Frank Jones to Dec. 27 1 __ 45.00 Sept. 27. Lincoln Co., maintenance of Prank Jones to Dec. 27 1 __ 45.00 rt. 27. Lincoln Co., for maintenance of Jas. Bab - bett to Dec. 27 45.00 Sept. 27. Lincoln Co., for maintenance of Jas. Bab - bett to Dec. 27 Sept. 28. B. Hawkins, sale 2 yards sand 2.00 rt. 29. Nemaha Co., for maintenance of Jas. D. Car - men to Dec. 29 ... 4s m Sept. 29. Nemaha Co., for maintenance of Jas. D. Car - men to Dec. 29 r. 3. Madison Co., for maintenance of J. R. Car - ter to Jan. 3, '06 45 00 Oct. 3. Madison Co., for maintenance of J. R. Car - ter to Jan. 3, '06 45 00 Oct. 4. B. Hawkins, sale 2 yards sand 2.50 Oct. 4. B. Hawkins, sale 2 yards sand 2.50 Oct. 5. Frank Lazo, sale 1 pig g 00 Oct. 5. A. A. Bushee. for maintenance of attd. 1 mo. 15 00 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">: Wayne Co., for uance of J. C. Har- 5. 45.00 mer to Jan. Susie Castle, tin,, ifter pay roll was sent to Secretary of office 7. Ellen Bowery, same u Castle _ Mabel McGaw. same as Castle I 7. 7. Henrietta Hamnion.i. -ame as Castle Ella Nelson. MU ' astle 7. 7. Bobt. Emerson, sale '2 bu. tomatoes G. D. Moultou. weighing 1 load of hay K. K. Frantz, sale 11 head hogs, 16501b, at 7. 10. • AO 7. J. L. Gliddeii &lt; astle 7. Max Storkan, salt- of 76 loaves bread, $3.80; sale of 14 buns. * .20 7. E. Tyrer, sale old pile wood 7. Robt. Enters." I bu. tomatoes I $6.30 per ewt. 11. Bartley .Mdlugh, sale 10 head hogs, 1660 tt&gt;, at $6.30 per ewl 11. John Doctor, sale 1 boar pig 1 11. Louis Thorn, sale 1 boar pig 103.95 104.58 Oct. 11. Geo. Shaw, sale old zinc .68 11. August Borcher's maintenance 13. Dodge Co., for maintenance of Louis F. Dahl to Jan. U — 12.50 45.00 111. Knox Co., for maintenance of Amos Holt to Nov. 11, « 14. Floyd Willett, for maintenance 14. Mrs. Louisa Harrison, maintenance to Nov. 45.00 Mi 15, '05 _ !__ 15.00 B16. August Borcher, for maintenance 17. L. B. Stuff, sale 5 ft sugar 17. Buffalo Co., for maintenance of L. W. Frayer 50.00 25 to Jan. 17 45.00 Oct. 18. Ca8s Co., for maintenance of Alex Black to Jan. 18 45.00 Oct. 18. Cas8 Co., for maintenance of Alex Hunter to Jan. 18 45.00 Oct. 18. Adams Co., for maintenance of Jas. Rumer to Jan. 18 45.00 Oct. 18. V. Stark, sale of 1 boar pig Oct. 18. V. Stark, sale of 1 boar pig 15.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 163 rl9. Wayne Co., for maintenance of Bert Johnson to Jan. 19 45.00 rl9. Buffalo Co., for maintenance of Chas. M. Trott to Jan. 19 45.00 tl9. Nye &amp; Buchanan Co., sale 48 hogs, to wit : 28 hogs, 12300 ft at $5.00 $615.00 20 hogs, 4170 lb at $5.30 ... -'21.01 $836.01 Freight charges $19.55 Yardage 3.84 Corn 3.00 Inspection 15 Commission 6.00 $32.54 $803.47 80 t20. Lancaster Co., for maintenance of S. Polsky to Jan. 20 45.00 t. 23. J. J. Sullivan, maintenance J. 8. Wells to Jan. 8 45.00 r. 27. Buffalo Co., maintenance of H. Wilhelmy to Jan. 27 45.00 r. 24. Buffalo Co., maintenance of Jesse Andrews to Jan. 24 45.00 r. 28. Adams Co., maintenance of J. H. Sleuman to Jan. 28 45.00 r30. Adams Co., maintenance of E. D. Veitch to Jan. 30 45.00 r30. Lancaster Co., maintenance of W. V. Bain to Jan. 30 45.00 Oct. 31. Duncan Campbell, sale of glass 1.00 Oct. 23. John Neal, sale 1 Berkshire boar pig 25.00 Nov. 1. E. B. Rucker, sale 2 shoats, $6.00 each 12.00 r. 1. Cass Co., for maintenance of R. R. Living - stone to Dec. 8 45.00 Nov. 1. A. A. Bushee. for maintenance of attd. Dora Poole to Nov. 1, 1905 ..._ _ 13.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">164 LA, liee, for maintenance of attd. Lil - lian Richardt to Nov. 1. 1905 — _ 6.29 r2. Colfax Co., maintenance of Andrew Gless from Nov. 2, 1905, to Feb. 2, 1906 45.00 Villiams. sale 1 boar pig 15.00 Merman, for maintenance of Aug. Borcher 12.50 lie sole leather _ .45 6. Geo. Sehall, sale of iron, etc. .21 hall, sale of iron, etc. .21 r. 7. 1 .. maintenance of Mary Ann 45.00 maintenance of Mary Ann r. 8. 1 -, maintenance of Fred Miller tn 8, 1905, to Feb. 8, 1906 45.00 .. 8. Lam-aster Co., maintenance of Fred Miller fro J, 1905, to Feb. 8, 1906 45.00 lorkan. sale of bread, to wit: Oct. U $ .80 Of 1.30 .60 $2.70 . 8. T. H. Williams, sale 28 bu. ear corn at 40c 11.20 8. T. H. Williams, sale 28 bu. ear com at 40c 11.20 8. Wayne &lt;'".. maintenance of Oliver M. Eicher 8. Wayne Co., maintenance of Oliver M. Eicher from Nov. 8, 1905, to Feb. 3, 1906 45.00 from Nov. 8, 1905, to Feb. 3, 1906 45.00 r. 8. Cash received from Oct. pay roll error in com - puting wages of II. Hammond, 29c ; and Lillie Richardt. .86 8. Cash received from Oct. pay roll error in com - puting wages of II. Hammond, 29c ; and Lillie Richardt. .86 r. 8. Cash received from Oct. pay roll error in making up time of Frances Edgar — she was paid from a special attds. fund 10.64 ;sh received from Oct. pay roll error in making up time of Frances Edgar — she was paid from a special attds. fund 10.64 10. Box Butte Co., maintenance of Win. Rains . 10. Box Butte Co., maintenance of Win. Rains 10. Buffalo maintenance of J. A. Lee to 46.00 to Feb. 9 10. Buffalo Co.. maintenance of J. A. Lee to 45.00 10. Peter Lundgren, sale y 2 sole leather r. 11. Cedar Co.. for maintenance of W. P. South - well to Feb. 11 tv. 11 maintenance of Edward G. Boynton to Feb. 11 r. 11. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale of 2 bbls. of tal - low, 746 lb at 33.57 11 W. A Campbell, sale for the month of Oct. to wit • — </seg>
            <seg id="p043">165 Cake, 15c; 16 loaves bread, 80c $ 95 7 It&gt; ham 88c, 10 lb beef steak $1.00 _ 1.88 6* ft boiled beef 35c, 2 ft pork 20c 55 4 ft bacon 50c, 7% gals, milk 75c 1.25 For the month of Nov. to- wit: 20 loaves bread $1.00, cake 10c 1.10 8 lb bacon $1.00, 4 lb ham 50c 1.50 9 tb pork 90c, 9 lb beef steak 90c- 1.80 21 bu. corn at 35c 7.35 8 gal. milk .80 13, C. L. Meshair, sale of medicine 2.00 £ 13, Colfax Co. maintenance of Frank Ellis to Feb. 13, Oti 45.00 Not 13, Adams Co. maintenance of Horace C. Dean to Feb. 13 45.00 14. Amos Watson, sale old iron and zinc .50 E 14, Cass Co. for maintenance of Wm. Sage and Marion Armstrong to Feb. 14, 1906 90.00 Nov. 15, W. H. Harrison for maintenance of Louise Harrison to Dec. 15, 1905 15.00 Nov. 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co. sale of 2 No. 1 salt cured hides 32 lb at 10c— $3.20 and 4 No. 2 salt cured hides 285 lb at 9c— $25.65 28.85 Nov. 15, Boyd Co. maintenance of Marcellus Johnson to Feb. 16 45.00 16, Knox Co. maintenance of Nels Nelson to Feb. 16 45.00 Nov. Nov. 16, Thayer Co. maintenance of Chas. Blanchard to Feb. 16 45.00 16, Nance Co. maintenance of Chas. Osterson to Feb. 16 _ 45.00 Nov. 17, Northwestern Junk &amp; Iron Co. sale of old Nov. rags 1350 ft at $1.50 Nov. 17, Douglas Co. maintenance of P. K. Callahan and Geo. Gibson to Feb. 17, 1906 90.00 18, Hall Co. maintenance of Pearl Bryan to Feb. 18, 1906 18, Mr. Sullivan, sale 1 boar pig 15.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">166 Nov. 21, Thayer Co.. maintenance of E. R. Frederick to Feb. 21 45.00 Nov. 21. Boyd Co., maintenance of Oscar Lenoir to Feb. 21 45.00 Not. 22, Wayne Co., maintenance of A. F. Kincaid to Feb. 21 45.00 Nov. 24, Franklin Co., maintenance of Ernest Carpen- ter to Feb. 24 Nov. 23. Nye &amp; Buchanan Co. sale 79 hogs —15820 Ib at $4.70 3 hogs— 1230 tb at $4.40 Loss Freight charge* Yardage Corn Inspection Commission Nov. 24, Lancaster Co.. maintenance of Samantha Loar to Feb. 24 45.00 Nov. 24, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. for 303 3-4 yds. 9-4 Pepperell sheeting at .20 •iO.75 516 3-4 yds. bleached Fruit at 6 3-4c 34.89 95.64 r. 27, Wayne Co., maintenance of Everett Sherman to Feb. 26 45.00 Nov. 27. Sheridan Co. maintenance of Geo. Stratton to Feb. 26, '06 and Chas. B. Kendell __ 90.00 27. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 empty syrup bbls. 1.50 Nov. 27, Standard Oil Co., sale 1 ref. oil bbl. $1.10 and 5 sub. oil bbls. $4.00 r. 28, W. A. Campbell, sale following items: 16 loaves bread at 5c— 80c and 9 Ib bacon at 10c —90c $1.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">167 9 ft boiled beef at 5c — 45c and 3 ft bacon at 12c — 36c .81 2 ft ham at 12%c— 25c and 3% ft pork at 10c — 35c .60 20 bu. corn at 35c— $7.00 and 5 gal. milk 50e 7.50 $10.61 10.61 Nov. 29, Nebr. State Penitentiary, sale of 293 ft turkeys at 20c r. 30, The Crete Mills, sale 675 bu. wheat at 70c $472.50 Less freight charges on 9500 tb at 6c 5.70 $466.80 466.80 Dec. 2. E. Walworth, for 20 loads cinders at 20c 4.00 r. 1. Buffalo Co., maintenance of Prank Duffy and P. P. Lund to Feb. 21, 1906 90.00 Dec. 5. J. A. Hayden, sale 1 male pig 15.00 Dec. 5. Lancaser Co., maintenance of Wm. Headley from Aug. 29, 1905, to Sept. 29, 1905 15.00 r5. Richardson Co., maintenance of John Cassi - dy from Dec. 5, 1905, to Mar. 5, 1906 45.00 f. 5. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 No. 1 salt cured hides, 185 ft at lie -20.35 8 No. 2 hides, 521 ft at 10c ")2.10 $72.45 72.45 t. 6. Buffalo Co., maintenance of Harry Swindler to Mar. 6 _ 45.00 t. 6. Chas. Nierman, for maintenance of August Borcher from Nov. 1 to Dec. 1, '05 12.50 t. 7. Max Storkan, sale 10 loaves bread $ .50 26 loaves bread 1.30 1 sack rutabagas 1.00 12 loaves bread .60 $3.40 •2 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">168 7. Jas. Coen, time lost after pay roll was sent Dec. 10.67 Dec. 7. W. A. Campbell, same as Coen 4.00 Dec. 7. Lillian Join ;»s Coen Minnie Schilling, same as Coen Deo. 7 Dec. 8. Walter Miller, sale 1 chamber .40 1 fb butter Dec. 8. Floyd Willett. maintenance to Dec. 15, '05 Dec. 8. \ Bushee. for board of 2 attds. — Dora Poole and Lillian Richardt for Nov. Adai maintenance of Ray Turner to Dec. B. to Mar. 10 10 Butte Co.. maintenance of Jas. Dono- van to Mar. 1 12 Otoe Co., maintenance of Chas. S. Russell to Mar. 12 13 Lanr ... maintenance of Thos. A. Bee- rup to Mar. 13 45.00 £ 14 J. A. Weart, sale 2 bu. corn at 35c Cuming Co., for maintenance of Carl Ca- 14. narsky to Mar. 14 Dec. ec. ec. )ec. ec. 15. W. II. Harrison, for maintenance of Louisa Harrison to Jan. 15. 1906 16. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 6 No. 2 hides. 327 lb at 10, 32.70 Red Willow Co., maintenance of Ben Olcott and Ray Lackey to Mar. 19, 1906 Thayer Co.. maintenance of Frank E. Trum - bull to Mar. 19 19. 19. Hall Co., maintenance of Arthur M. Drew Mar. 19 19. Dec. £ 21. T. H. Williams, sale 6 Yb lard at 10c 22. Garfield Co., maintenance of Jas. Alderman and Ervin Darling to Mar. 22, 1906 23. Lancaster Co., maintenance of H. F. Haney to Mar. 23 C. 9. Adai maintenance of Ray Turner to Mar. 9 . 10. Don- maintenance of Fred J. Merrill 21. Sarpy Co., maintenance of Jas. Curley to Mar. 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">169 of lard for popcorn B. F. Knijrht Co., treasurer, refund overpaid Dec. 215 £ on school land rental s: 26 Walter Miller, sale 3 syrup bbls. at 50c each Custer Co., for maintenance of Thos. R. Van- 27 green to Mar. 27, 1906 27 Buffalo Co., for maintenance of Harry Hill to Mar. 27 fuming Co., maintenance of Henry Mock Dec. 27 to Feb. 4 ._ 45.00 Dec. 28 Northwestern Iron &amp; Junk Co., sale 905 lb old rags at $1.50 13.57 Thayer Co., maintenance of Frank Wheeler 28 to Mar. 28 45.00 Dec. 28 Lancaster Co., maintenance of Wm. Headley to Dec. 29, '05 45.00 z. 29 Max Storkan, sale 52 loaves bread at 5c 2.60 30 Gage Co., maintenance of Ben Williams to Mar. 3(1 45.00 1 1 J. L. Williams, sale 1 hog, 290 ft at 5c Nemaha Co., for maintenance of A. L. Adams from Nov. 12, 1905, to Dec. 12, 1905 14.50 15.00 Buffalo Co., maintenance of Geo. Wright to Jan. 2 Apr. 2 ■I Cora Damrow, sale 4 1000-yard spools thread E. M. Ramey, board of 1 colt 1 mo Buffalo Co., maintenance of Chas. R. Lutes to Apr. 5 '£ 5. 5. 5. $48.82 48.82 t. 6. A. A. Bushee, board of two attds. to Jan. 1 21.50 . 6 Chas. Nierman, maintenance of August Bor- cher to Feb. 1 ■E 23. John Greene, R. Hay and R. Gilmore, sale an. 6. Burt Co., maintenance of L. E. Brown to ■- Apr. 6 4. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 9 hides: . 2 No. 1, 32 Ife at lie $ 3.52 7 No. 2, 453 ft at 10c . 45.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">170 Jan. 8. Madison Co., maintenance of J. R. Carter to Apr. 4 45.00 Jan. 8. Johnson Co., maintenance of C. A. Howorth to Mar. 14 45.00 Jan. 8. Sarpy Co., maintenance of David Wilber to Apr. 8 45.00 Jan. 8. Walter Miller, sale 1 syrup bbl. Jan. 9. John Wonder, sale 3 head hogs, 880 lb at $6.00 cwt. 52.80 Jan. 11. Buffalo Co., maintenance of Frank Roberts to Apr. 11 45.00 Jan. 9. Saunders Co.. for maintenance of Richard Prittie from Oct. 28. '05, to Jan. 28, '06 45.00 Jan. 11. Grant Co.. maintenance of John W. Mc- 45.00 Jan. 12. Gape Co., maintenance of Benj. F. Gardner to Apr. 12 45.00 Jan. 13. Sale of 16 nurse books to nurses 25.60 Jan. 14. Richardson Co.. maintenance of Jos. Wilson 45.00 Jan. 15. B. Hawkins, ace. pasture for cow and colt at season, 1906 4.S0 Jan. 15. Dixon Co., maintenance of Bert McClary 45.00 Jan. 20. W. A. Campbell, sale 5407 lb coal at $4.00 per ton 10.81 Jan. 20. Buffalo Co., maintenance of Arthur Wood- ward to Apr. 20 45.00 Jan. 20. Adams Co., maintenance of Geo. F. Kelly to Apr. 20 45.00 Jan. 22. J. W. Tewksberry, for road labor 3.00 Jan. 22. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale — ..._ 2.00 t24. Fillmore Co.. maintenance of John Brennan from Nov. 26, 1905, to Feb. 26, 1906 45.00 Jan. 24. Thayer Co., maintenance of Daniel Harp Michael to Apr. 11 to Apr. 14 to Apr. 15 . 3 oil bbls.. 80e $2.40 4 gyrup bbls., 50c 2.00 $4.40 4.40 to Apr. 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">171 £ 24 Dr. J. L. Greene, sale 1 sow, 300 ft at 6c 18.00 24 Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale — 5 No. 1 cured hides, 314 ft at lie 34.54 4 No. 2 salt cured hides, 298 ft at 10c __ 29.80 Laverty Bros., sale 80 hogs, 16,400 25 lb at $5.25 .$861.00 Less freight charges $18.15 Yardage 6.40 Corn 2.00 Commission 8.00 Inspection .15 $34.70 34.70 $826.30 826.30 27 Hamilton Co., maintenance of John A. Marks to Apr. 27 45.00 127 Hall Co., maintenance of Andrew Conner to Apr. 27 45.00 27 Sale 17 nurse books at $1.60 Sale 4 nurse books at $1.35 ... $27.20 5.40 $32.60 32.60 £ 27 Aaron Sullivan, sale second hand telephone 2.00 27. A. S. Williams, sale 1 turkey 1.60 27. Wayne Co., maintenance of John Murphy to Apr. 27 _ 45.00 29, Thayer Co., maintenance of Martin J. Hawkins to Apr. 29 45.00 £ 30, Isaac Cohn, sale 561 tb old copper at 12y 2 e ...._ 70.12 30 Douglas Co., maintenance of C. A. Perkins to Apr. 30 45.00 30 Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 bbls. tallow 747 lb at 4%c 33.61 31 Dodge Co., maintenance of Anton Faiman to Apr. 30 46.00 :n Sale and deposit of 4 nurses books at $1.60 — $6.40 and 1 at $1.35 7.75 Keith Co., maintenance of Benj. Cramer to 2 May 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">172 3, Arthur Nichols by M. 0. No. 46528 for board and clothing ... 40.83 : 3, Hamilton Co., maintenance of Jacob K. Pen- ner to May S 3, Hamilton Co., maintenance of John V. Marks 45.00 * to May 5 5, Boyd Co., maintenance of John Mentzer to 45.00 May 45.00 m. 5, Chas. Xierman, maintenance of Aug. Borcher to Feb. 1 : 12.50 ™. 6, Franklin Co.. maintenance of L. E. Bowers : to May 6 6, Hall Co., mainenance of Samuel Yost to May 6 — — 7. Max Storkan, sale 72 loaves bread 45.00 1 hog head .25 $3.85 3.85 » 7, T. H. Williams, sale 15 lb pork loin at 10c $1.50 15 lb beef at 6c .90 2640 lb coal at $4.00 ._ 4.78 $7.18 «■ 5 7, Geo. Blakely, sale 2680 lb coal at $4.50 7, J. 0. Brower. time lost after pay roll was 6 .03 sent to Sec'y of State's office _ _ 6.77 ! 7, W. J. Barr, same as Brower 7, Emma Hultberg, same as Brower 7, L. D. Hamilton, same as Brower 7, Sale nurse books, 2 at $1.35 _ $2.70 3 2 at $1.60 3.20 $5.90 ,90 9, Colfax Co., maintenance of Louis Harzke to May 9 45.00 &gt;„. 9, Adams Co., maintenance of Jas. Donlon to </seg>
            <seg id="p051">173 Feb 10, Buffalo Co., maintenance of Chas. Bostock to May 10 to May 10 45.00 Feb. 10, Dora Poole, sale 1 nurse book _ 1-35 10, Dora Poole, sale 1 nurse book _ Feb 14, Douglas Co., maintenance of Ruby Slattery to May 14 Feb 15, Red Willow Co., maintenance of Wm. Math - ers to May 15 ers to May 15 45.00 16, I. J. Nichols, for maintenance of John Wood - worth from Jan. 4, 1906, to Apr. 4 Feb worth from Jan. 4, 1906, to Apr. 4 _ 45.00 Feb. 16, Dr. Ferguson, labor on road with teams 3.00 16, Dr. Ferguson, labor on road with teams 16, Buffalo Co.. maintenance of Arthur V. Moffitt to May 16 Feb Feb 17, H. E. Burnam for pasture 1 cow for Aug. and Sept. $3.00 H. E. Burnam for pasture 1 cow for Aug. and Sept. $3.00 37 LSale of medicine -40 Sale of medicine -40 $3.40 Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale Feb 21 2 No. 1 salt cured hides 171 ft at 10c $17.10 8 No. 2 salt hides 514 ft at 9c 46.26 1 No. 1 green hide 89 ft at 9c 8.01 2 No. 2 preen hides 140 ft at 8e 11.20 $82,' 82.57 Feb. 24, W. G. Seidell, 2 loads of cinders 1.00 tb. 26, Boyd Co., maintenance of Jacob Becker to May 26 45.00 Feb. 26, Miss Linsley, sale 2 spools thread .10 Feb. 26, I. Cohn, sale 46 ft liprht copper at lie 5.06 Feb. 19, W. A. Campbell, sale 2710 ft coal at $4.00 5.42 Feb. 27, Clara Poole. et al. sale 3 doz. oranges at 21 &lt;• .63 28, Geo. Underwood, sale 4 sows 970 ft at $6.00 58 20 tb. 28, Valley Co., maintenance of John H. Luke to May 28 45.00 rb. 28, Holt Co.. maintenance of Gus Uecker and Jas. F. Hughes to May 28, 1906 _ 90.00 rr. 6, Chas. Nierman, maintenance of Aug. Borcher for month of Mbrch Mar. 8, Damon Co.. maintenance of John H. Liggitt to June 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">174 t. 9, Kearney Co., maintenance of Gust Beisel to June 9 45.00 Mar. 8, E. Tyrer, time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of office .24 Mar. 8, Alma Hill, same as Tyrer .62 Mar. 8, Alice McGaw, same as Tyrer 5.35 Mar. 8, M. Haufgarn. same as Tyrer 1.78 Mar. 8, F. J. Fittl- -' brood sows _ 26.65 Mar. 8, Max Storkan, sale of 56 loaves bread 2.80 Mat. 8, Geo. Blakely. sale 2730 ib coal at $4.50 6.14 Mar. 8, T. II. Williams, sale 920 tb coal at $4.00 1.84 Mar. 10, Cedar Co., maintenance of Jay L. Pierce to June 10 45.00 Mar. 14, Sale 1 nurse's book ... 1.60 Mar. 14. Stanton Co., maintenance of Chas. W. A. Staube to June 14 45.00 r. 15, Hall Co.. maintenance of Claus Grotzky to June 15 45.00 r. 15, Douglas Co., maintenance of Jennie L. Rutherford to Jun. 1 • 45.00 Mar. 17, Amos Watson, sale 1 condemned table 3.00 Mar. 17, W. A. Campbell, sale 2330 lb coal at $4.00 _ 4.66 r. 19, Franklin Co., maintenance of Henry McGin - ley to June 19 45.00 Mar. 19, Conscience by cash 1.50 Jlgr** 19, Stanton Co., maintenance of W. C. Glaser 45.00 to June 19 .. Mar. 20, Earl A. McCreery for 6 mo.'s board 1 horse 48.00 r. 21. A. A. Bushee for board of 2 attds. for mo. of Feb. and 12 das. in Mar., 1906 41.62 r. 22, J. A. Smith &amp; Co.. sale 6 No. 2 hides branded, 470 lb at 10*c _ $48.18 1 deacon (calf hide) .40 $48.58 48.58 Apr. 2, Hall Co., maintenance of Silas Woodworth to July 2 45.00 Apr. 3, P. F. Zimmer, sale 1 horse 100.00 Apr. 3, A. C. Williams, sale 1 brood bow 18.50 Apr. 4. Douglas Co., maintenance of Barney Kimmer- </seg>
            <seg id="p053">175 Apr from Jan. 29, to Apr. 29, 1906 Apr. Borcher for the month of April, 1906 5, H. B. Troxell, sale of one team 5, Lincoln Upholstering Co.. sale one high £2 Z: ■K 1800 tt&gt; old iron pipe Apr. is ti. Walter Miller, sale 10 grain sacks £ 6, Geo. L.Williams, sale 660 lb hogs at 6c 6, Antelope Co., maintenance of John Schwart- :: Apr. Apr. 7, Gage Co., maintenance of Clum Boop to July 7 45.00 9, A. B. Colles, time lost after pay roll was Apr. sent to Sec'y of State's office _ Apr. Apr. 1 9, F. H. Williams, sale of coal 900 lb at $4.00 9, Max Storkan, sale 70 loaves bread at 5c 9, Sadie Bich. same as Colles _ 8, Dawson Co., maintenance of Thos. Weaver 9, Northwestern Junk &amp; Iron Co., sale 1450 lb Apr. £S Apr. 10, E. L. Snyder, sale 2 hogs, 400 ft at $6.00 Apr. 10, Dixon Co., maintenance of Carl Snyder to ". Apr. 10, Geo. Sloan, sale of medicine 10, Geo. Nelson, weighing 7 loads of hay . 17, Franklin Co., maintenance of Marly Clark 45.00 Apr. 18, Keith Co., maintenance of Chas. F. Mahaffey ts Apr. 19, Sale 2 nurse books 1 — $1.35 and 1 — $1.60 5, Cass Co., maintenance of B. B. Livingstone 5, Chas. Nierman for maintenance of Aug. speed condemned engine .... Shafting 5, A. R. Honold, sale 1 second hand mimeo- graph ing to July 6 6, Lincoln Co., maintenance of Jas. A. Erskine to July 6 9, J. B. Harlan, same as Colles 9, F. E. Noble, same as Colles _ 9, A. L. Harris, same as Colles _ to July 8 rags at $1.10 per ewt. ._ _ July 10 to July 17 to July 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">176 19, Hall Co., maintenance of Chas. Plummer to : July 19 19, J. S. Smith &amp; Co.. sale 1 hide 30 ft at 11 3-4 $3.52 6 No. 2 hides 425 ltiat 10 3-4 45.68 1 bull hide 108 lb at 8c _ 8.64 $57.84 57.84 Apr ac Kohn, sale 1170 Ib old iron at 25c 2.92 Apr. 21, Goo. 0. Loos, sale 3 pcs. pipe .50 21. Holt Co.. maintenance of Frank Mann to Apr. July 21 Apr. 23. Dr. J. T. Hay. sale 3 condemned chandeliers 3.00 r. 24. M. o., maintenance of Arthur Conrad July 24 45.00 r. 26, Scotts Bluff Co., maintenance of Leroy Craig from Apr. 14. to July 14, 1906 _ 45.00 Apr. 26. Northwestern Junk &amp; Iron Co., sale 1150 tb old rags at $1.10 per cwt. 12.65 Apr. 26, F. D. Crane, cash difference sale one boar pig 100.00 May 2, Keith Co.. maintenance of Andrew L. Charles 45.00 ,ug. 2 May 3, Dr. A. P. Ferguson, sale of medicine .50 May 3, David Moreland, sale 3 runt pigs 6.00 May 4, Louie Stine. sale 400 tt&gt; old rags at 1 l-4c 5.00 May 4, E. B. Stephenson. 3 months board for one horse at $8.00 24.00 May 4, O. J. Hammond, sale 4 duck coats at $1.25 5.00 May 5, Adams Co., maintenance of Geo. Cole to Aug. 5 45.00 May 5, Dawson Co.. maintenance of Gottlieb Engiler 45.00 N'ierman. maintenance of Aug. Borcher for month Maj 12.50 May 9. Nemaha Co.. maintenance of Wm. Van De- Berg to Aug. 8 45.00 May 9, Sarpy Co.. maintenance of Walter S. Ruble to Aug. 9 45.00 ry 10, Augusta Leding. time lost after pay roll was sent to .ite's ofti. .92 M Ay 10, r.. ni i 1 v AT fl \* h u tr h sfl m 6 s s Tjod i 1 1 * * </seg>
            <seg id="p055">177 May 10, Amos Watson, sale 2760 \h coal at $5.00 May 10, J. A. Weart, sale 34(X&gt; tb coal at - 10.20 May 10, Max Stdrkan, sale 40 loaves bread at 5c 2.00 May 10, j. A. Weart, sale LOO tb ground feed .90 May 10, Male attds. 49 duck coats for uniform at $1.25 each May 11, J. 0. Smith &amp; Co., sale— .. 1 hides 32 It, at 12c $3.84 1 No. 2 hide 51 lt&gt; at lie 5.61 2 deacons IS tt. at 6c .90 $10.35 May 12, E. Finney, hauling cement 100 Caster Co., maintenance of Frank Klousek May 13 to Aug. 13 45.00 .May 14 hn, sale 78 tt. old lead at 137% lb old brass heavy at 12e 16.50 125 lb old brass light at 7c $27.98 May 14, B. Hawkins, balance due on pasturage 1905 Platte Co.. maintenance of Chas. Finney to 17 Au- 17 May 17 Thayer Co., maintenance of Carl Harder to Aug. 17 45.00 Way 17 Thayer Co.. maintenance of Merton McDon- aid to An?. 17 May 15, Ira Gillam, pasture 1 cow for 2 months 3.00 19 Stanton Co., maintenance of Herman Prawitz to Aug. 19 45.00 May 19 Nance Co., maintenance of Paul W. Theel to Aug. 19 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. lease land rental due May May 19 1, 1906 on land used for sheep barns 250.00 May 22 Adams Co.. maintenance of Clyde Olmstead to Aug. 22 45.00 Received of Dr. H. J. Lenhoff maintenance May 22 of J. M. Malone to Aug. 23. 1906 45.00 May 28, Sale two spools thread .10 May 30. Adams Co., maintenance of W. N. Thompson to Aug. 30 45.00 it </seg>
            <seg id="p056">May 31, F. E. Noble, sale 3 duck coats at $1.25 each Jane 1, Antelope Co., maintenance of Wm. E. Launt to Sept. 1 re 4, Adams Co., maintenance of Gerd Harms to Sept. 4 June 6, Douglas Co., maintenance of John E. Long to Sept. 6 45 re 7, Chas. Nierman, maintenance of August Borcher for June June 7, Chas. Xierman, maintenance of August Borcher for June in June 6, L. A. Whitten. sale of medicine June 6, L. A. Whitten, sale of medicine 1.00 June 6. Sale 2 spools of thread June 6, Sale 2 spools of thread June 7, Adams Co.. maintenance of Frank Lepinski June 7, Adams Co.. maintenance of Frank Lepinski to Sept 7 45 to Sept. 7 45.00 June 7, Max Storkan, sale 2 duck coats at $1.25 each June 7, Max Storkan, sale 2 duck coats at $1.25 each S M 7, Max Storkan. sale 50 loaves bread at 5c 2 2.50 Jane 7, Max Storkan. sale 50 loaves bread at 5c 2.50 r7, D. W. Jones, time lost after pay roll was sent to f State's office 5 66 June 7, D. W. -Tones, time lost after pay roll was sent to f State's office 5 June 7, F. B. Cross, same as Jones June 7, P. B. Cross, same as Jones 3 3.22 8, Sale 15 white duck coats to at $1.25 each tie 15 white duck coats to attds. at $1.25 each lg 18.75 June 8. J. S. Smith &amp; Co.. sale 7 No. 2 hides 348 lb at lie June 8. J. 8. Smith I 2 hides, 348 ft at lie 00 38.26 June 10, Pierce Co.. maintenance of Frank Otto to Sept. 10 45 June 10, Pierre Co.. maintenance of Frank Otto to Sept. 10 45.00 June 13. Dixon Co.. maintenance of Henry Balbrick to Sept. 13 4c * 15, Louis Stein, sale 1600 ft old rags at ! 1-4* $19.50 June 13. Dixon Co.. maintenance of Henry Balbrick to Sept. 13 45.00 »15, Louis Stein, sale 1600 lb old rags at 1 ......$19.50 Less 50c dockape Less 50c dockape Old brass, light 21 lb at 10c Old brass, light 21 ft at 10c 2.10 2.10 $21.60 21.6 $21.60 21.60 June 20, Thayer Co.. maintenance of Edw. Walrath to Sept. 20 45 qq June 20, Thayer Co.. maintenance of Edw. Walrath to Sept. 20 June 20. J. S. Smith &amp; Co., sale 9 No. 2 hides (branded) 553 ft at lie 60.8 June 21. Xuckolls Co., maintenance of L. F. McCor - mick to July 19 ak m\ June 21, Northwestern Junk &amp; Iron Co. for </seg>
            <seg id="p057">179 1800 ft old iron at 3c .... 5.40 179 ft old insulated wire at 6c 10.74 2.61 87 ft old lead at 3c ... $29.75 29.75 June 21, Sale 2 spools thread 1.70 June 21, Standard Oil Co., sale 2 empty bbls. 26, Boyd Co., maintenance of Wm. Taylor to Sept. 26 45.00 27, Douprlas Co., maintenance of Geo. Houliston June 45.00 to Sept. 27 28, Douglas Co., maintenance of Henry G. Weise to Sept. 28 45.00 2 Dixon Co., maintenance of Geo. H. Neff to Oct. 2 45.00 Gage Co., maintenance of Frank Moose to 3 45.00 Oct. 3 July 3. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 5 empty syrup bbls. at 50c 2.50 July 3 G. R. DeFord. time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office 83 July 3, O. J. Hammond, same rd .46 July 3 W. T. Perigrrin, same as DeFord July 3, M. Storkan, sale 52 loaves bread at 5e 2.60 July 5 Mrs. Jane Smith, for maintenance of F. J. Smith for the month of July Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale of No. 1 hide. 15.00 July 5, 67 ft at 12c 8.04 July 5 Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 4 No. 2 branded hides, 240 ft at lie 26.40 5 D. C. Berry. Co.Treas., amt. overpaid on lease rental Nov. 4 s F. C. Abbott, sale two duck coats at $1.25 C. Rubendoll, sale two duck coats at $1.25 C. Niermann, maintenance of Aug. Borcher for July 3 6. 6. 9 12.50 Hamilton Co., maintenance of Christe Gul- July 10, ickson to Oct. 10, '06 4500 July 11 Box Butte Co.. maintenance of Jas. Dono- </seg>
            <seg id="p058">180 July 11, A. D. ' 1 c*M strawberries 2.50 July 13, N. W. Junk &amp; Iron Co., sale 730 ft old rags at IV 9.12 17. Pien nee of Albert F. Mag- danz to Oct. 17 45.00 tl7. Lincoln Hide A: Fur ('&lt;».. sale 2 No. 1 salt cure.l hides. 70 ft at 12c 8.40 6 N 7 It* at lie Juh n.n Sullivan, sale 1 second hand telephone 2.00 July 24. John Due. Bowing alfalfa 1.00 July 21. Lena Carveth. maintenance of Stephen Car - 45.00 Kirkpatriek Bros., for board one stray horse 1.50 28, Fn uiff. for service of nurse _ 20.00 31, Bo maintenance of H. 0. Young to 45.00 July 31. Frank Klousek. 1 male hog and 1 sow 35.00 1, J. R. Megahan. in bu. tomatoes at 50c 5.00 ». 1. Win. Vogfat, 1 bu. tomatoes. $1-00; 1 bu. om _ 1.75 ». 1, Buffalo I mtenance of W. R. Rusco to 45.00 ». 1. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 7 No. 2 hides, br i( 3 ft it 11 43.47 1, J. M Gillman. pasture for e L28 J. R. Megahan, sale 10 bu. tomatoes 3, Wm. Voght, sale 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 4. Boyd ('".. maintenance of L. J. Theil \ov. 4 45.00 Wm. \ e 1 bu. tomatoes 1.00 ♦i. J. R. Mlegahan. sale 10 bu. tomatoes 5.00 to., maintenance of vin and A. II. Garrison from Feb. 20 to May 20, '06 t Maintenance of ('. A Widrick from June 12 to Sept. 12. "06 46.00 fi. Wm. Boorland, sale 400 !b sand Williams, sale of slop 25% It. meat It 1 of attd. for mo. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p059">181 Aug 7, Robert Guthrie, for board of attd. for mo. of July 7. Myrtle Pickering, ace. of board of private patient from Aug. 4, '06, at $15 per mo. 20.00 Aug. 7. Kearney Co.. maintenance of Lars Johnson to Nov. 7 45.00 Aug. 8. Mrs. Anton Hansen, maintenance of John Schachter to Nov. 8, 1906 45.00 8, Douglas Co., maintenance of A. S. LaFevre to Nov. 8 45.00 Aug. Aug 8, Mrs. C. H. Brainard, maintenance of C. H. Aug 9. Thos. J. Carmody, maintenance of Alexander White to Nov. 9, 1906 45.00 Aug. 9, W. R. Hackney, time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office - 5.32 Aug. 9, Ellen Bowery, same as Hackney Aug. 9, Marie Sannielson. same as Hackney .87 9, O. C. Amos, same as Hackne&gt; 9, Clara Decker, same as Hackney ... i ■z Aug. 9, Sadie Rich, same as Hackney 9, Cora Edgar, same as Hackney 9, Maude Williams, difference in wages in laun- dry and dining room .2 z 9, Max Storkan, sale 64 loaves bread at 5&gt; 9, Dixon Co., maintenance of Jas. Brown to Nov. 9 10, Dodge Co., maintenance of Wm. O. Dodge Aug. to Nov. 19 z 10, Alys Ingalsbe, sale ltt yds. sand 12, Dawson Co., maintenance of D. I. Wilkins to Nov. 12 Aug. 12, Pierce Co., maintenance of Benj. Winger to Nov. 12 _ Aug. 13, Cedar Co., maintenance of Jesse E. Miller to Nov. 13 13, Lancaster Co., maintenance of Willard Coop - er to Nov. 13, Aug. 14, C. Niermann, maintenance of August Bor- cher for Aug. Brainard to Nov. 8, 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">14, Myrtle Pickering, bal. due on board of pri - vate patient to Nov. 4, 1906 14, R. A. Coyle, for maintenance of Peter Coyle :: to Nov. 14, 1906 14, Adams Co., maintenance of Conrad Gabler to Nov. 14 45.00 16, Jefferson Co., maintenance of E. B. Flans- berg from July 20 to Oct. 20, 1906 45.00 16, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale of 3 No. 1 salt cured hides, 132 ft at 12 %c 5 No. 2 salt cured hides, branded, 270 ft 16.50 :: 25, Webster Co., maintenance of M. C. Sherman and F. B. Hadley to Nov. 25 90.00 26, Dawson Co., maintenance of Clinton H. Kreitz to Nov. 26 K 2 20, J. Ager, sale 1 brood sow 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 No. 1 salt cured hide. 50 ft at 12 He - 6.25 6 No. 2 salt cured hides, 5 branded and 1 at 11* Aug. 17, Colfax Co., maintenance of Jos. Kastanek. " Fjr., to Nov. 17 . 17, Alys Ingalsbe. sale 1 yd. sand, 80c ; and 3* sk. cement at 60c. $1.95 :: Aug. 18, Pierce Co., maintenance of Jos. Boulting to Nov. 18 45.00 Aug. 18, Douglas Co., maintenance of Radnor Worth- ing to Nov. 18 Aug. 18, Y. H. Williams, sale of 5 loaves bread at 5c Aug. 19, Adams Co., maintenance of Alexander Ray , to Nov. 19 _ _ 45.00 t. 20, Nebr. Epworth Assembly, sale five loads of cinders ,50 Aug. 22, Platte Co., maintenance of Geo. Bradshaw to Nov. 22 45.00 f. 23, Johnson Co., maintenance of Taylor Hol- brook to Nov. 21 - Aug. 23, Johnson Co., maintenance of Lillie M. Peter- son to Nov. 23 45.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">183 Aug. 31, J. R. Purbaugh, sale 18 hogs, 6560 tt&gt; at $5.00 328.00 Aug. 31, W. A. Campbell, sale 40 loaves bread 2.00 1 bu. onions .75 Sept. 3, F. C. Swihart, 4 empty syrup bbls. 2.00 Sept. 4, C. Nierman, board of Aug. Borcher for Sept., 1906 rt. 4, Robt. Guthrie, board of attd. for Mrs. Guthrie for Aug. 15.00 tt. 4, Lancaster Co., maintenance of Aug. W. Johnson from Sept. 1st to Dec. 1st, '06 45.00 Sept. 4, J. J. Ripa, one boar pig 15.00 Sept. 5, Gus Storm, one male pig 15.00 Sept. 5, Wm. Breed, two male pigs $15 each _ 30.00 Sept. 5, Anton Jelinck, one male pig 15.00 Sept. 5, Vine Kastanek. one male pig 15.00 tt. 6, Webster Co., maintenance of Chas. Moran - ville from Sept. 5th to Dec. 5th 45.00 rt. 6, Josephine Kelley, time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office 2.84 Sept. 6, Ellen Bowery, same as Kelley 3-4 da. .72 Sept. 6, J. R. DeFord, same as Kelley 6.45 Sept. 6, Cora Edgar, same as Kelley 3 1-4 da. 1.84 Sept. 6, Mrs. Ella Cannon, same as Kelley 3 1-4 da. _ 2.63 Sept. 6, J. M. McNeill, same as Kelley 9 da 7.26 Sept. 6, Geo. Blakely, 1 1b butter _ .25 tt. 6, Buffalo Co., maintenance of Lavern Merri - man to Dec. 6 __ 45.00 Sept. 6, Max Storkan, 74 loaves bread at 5c _ 3.70 Sept. 6, Hans F. Bole, 1 male pig _ 15.00 Sept. 6, Adolph Kastanek, 2 male pigs 30.00 Sept. 6, H. L. Sawyer, 1 male pig _ 15.00 Sept. 7, T. H. Williams, 2 loaves bread .10 Sept. 8, Jas. Mjckey &amp; Co., ice, coffee and popcorn 1.00 Sept. 8, A. A. Nelson, one male pig 15.00 tt. 10, Lancaster Co., maintenance of Edw. J. Dougherty from Sept. 10 to Dec. 10 45.00 Sept. 13, Pat Smith, one male pig 15.00 Sept. 14, M. W. Erickson, one male pig ..._ 15.00 Sept. 14, Chas. A. Challquist, one male pig 15.00 Sept. 13, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 8 No. 2 hides </seg>
            <seg id="p062">184 LAND OOMM UKPORT tt. 17. Ti . maintenance of Charley Melton 1 7 45.00 ti, O. J. King for maintenance of Clinton D. Of from May 1 &gt;, 1906 12.50 t' Hall ('".. maintenance of Andrew Conner fro 45.00 tt. 19, Douglas Ool, maintenance of Wm. Thomas from Sept 19, 1906 45.00 Sept. 21. W. J. Mil. one vinegar bbl. 1.00 r21. Dr. J. T. Hay. maintenance of Robt. Howe fro 21. 1906 45.00 • Douglas Co., mail of Reuben Flow - 45.00 t&gt;. Dr. A I' a, water rent to Sept. 15, Maintenance of B. S. Ramsey from ■ t. 1 to Dec. 1 45.00 r24, Dixon Co., maintenance of Ernest Hinz from I. 1906 45.00 Sept. 25, Colfax Co., maintenance of Chas. E. Brown to D. 45.00 Sept. 26. Dawson Co.. maintenance of Frank Kelly 45.00 to D. Sept. 26, Johnson Co., maintenance of Frank L. Dins - more to Dec. 2' 45.00 B. &amp; Q. R. R. for killing one cow Aug 29 30.00 ■ 28. J. H. Ager, sal.- one pig 125 Ib at 7c 8.75 11. Lancaster Co., maintenance of Wm. Hill to 45.00 Sept. 28, Lancaster Co.. maintenance of Louis Boner to 1 45.00 tl, Hall Co., maintenance of Hazel Jennings to Jan. 1, 1907 45.00 tl. Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale hides to-wit: — 4 No. 1. 230 tb at 13c 29.90 6 No. 2, 295 It) at 12c 35.40 3, Douglas Co.. maintenance of Arthur E. Mot- ta« to Jan. 3. tW 45.00 r maintenance of Dr. E </seg>
            <seg id="p063">HOSPITAL FOU INSANE, LINCOLN 185 D. Beem ami L. T. McCormick and burial ex- penses for latter 4, Max Storkan. sale 28 loaves bread 1.40 t4, EL E. Austin time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office 2 da ' 1.83 4. Henrietta Hammond 1 da. lost same as Austin .83 Oct. 4, Joe Storkan. 1-2 da. same as Austin _ .50 4, Augusta Leding,error in making up pay roll 11.67 4, Ellen Bowery, error in making up pay roll 7.87 4, T. H. Williams, sale 1038 ft coal at $7.00 3.63 4. John McDill. sale one coat uniform 4, Margaret Neely, sale one spool thread .05 t. 4, Ella Torrence. error in time making up pay roll 9.00 4. Minnie Schilling, same as Torrence .75 t5, Dr. Hay, maintenance of Dr. John Smith from Oct. 5th to Jan. 5, '07, part paymen 40.00 6, Robt. Guthrie for board attd. for Mrs. Guthrie 15.00 f6, Lancaster Co., maintenance of Thos. E. Ste - vens from Oct. 6th to Jan. 6, 1907 45.00 9, Pat Smith, sale 1 calf 15.00 Oct. 10. Chas. Xierman for board of Aug. Borcher... 12.50 flX Scotts Bluff Co., maintenance of Leroy Craig and Mae Craig from Oct. 11th to Jan. 11th, '07 90.00 r. 11, Jefferson Co.. maintenance of Jas. Cadey to Jan. 11, '07 45.00 Oct. 11. J. I. Sittler, sale 1 Berkshire pig 15.00 11. Frank Swab, sale 1 Poland China boar 15.00 11, Albert Beck, 1 Berkshire boar 15.00 Oct. 12, E. B. Stephenson, 1 month board for horse _ 8.00 16, O. Loose, sale 2 gal. machine oil 1.00 16. Dora Poole, 2 books $1.00 and 50c 1.50 Oct. 16. Mrs. Xoble, 2 books $1.00 and 50r 1.50 Oct. 16, Ella Torrence, 3 books $1.00, $1.35 and 50.- 2.85 Oct. 16, Ida Jester, 4 books, $1.00. $1.35, $1.60 and 50c 4.45 Oct. 16. Margaret Camerer. 2 books, $1.60 and 50c 2.10 Oct. 17, Minnie Schilling, 2 books. $1.00 and $1.60 2.60 Oct. 17, Buffalo Co.. maintenance of Edw. W. Black to Jan. 17. '07 45.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">186 Oct. 17, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale No. 1 hides 68 1b at 13c i No. 2 hides branded 440 lb at 12c 18, Alice McGaw. 1 book $1.00 Oct. 18, Albert Beck, sale 1 male hog Oct. 19, Thayer Co., maintenance of Chas. Blanchard to Jan. 19, '07 I Oct. 19, Marie Samuelson, 2 books $1.00 and $1.35 _ Oct. 19, Ellen Bowery. 1 book $1.00 Oct. 20, B. Hawkins, sale 1 ton cane ha} Oct. 22, Gertrude Hills, 1 book Oct. 22, Mrs. Bowling, 2 books $1.60 each . rl2, Sale of 5 boars at Kansas City, Oct. 10. '06, to- wit:— Cat. No. 31, reg. No. 90351 $24.00 Cat. No. 32, reg. No. 90349 25.00 Cat. No. 33, reg. No. 91264 21.00 Cat. No. 34, reg. No. 90354 39.00 Cat. No. 35. r 90355 115.00 Total sales $224.00 . 40.00 Leas $8 per head com. Net cash received ...$184.00 1*4.00 Oct. 23, Madison Co.. maintenance of Chas. F. Wobig I from Oct. 23, 1906 to Jan. 23, 190" 25, Elizabeth Malone, 1 book $1.60 25, Mr. Swihart, service of boar 1 Oct. 25, W. J. Miller, sale 8 tt&gt; meat r25. Nance Co.. maintenance of Uryal Highbee from Oct. 25, 1906 to Jan. 25, 1907 s Oct. 29, Mr. Blank, sale one Berkshire boar Oct. 30, Daisy Reynolds. 2 books $1.60 each Oct. 30, Madison Co.. maintenance of LaFayette Chit- tic from Oct. 30. 1906 to Jan. 30, 1907 1, Joseph Soobodie, sale 1 boar pig ss Obed Loos, sale 1 gal. machine oil Ella Nelson. 1 book $1.00 1.00 W. R. Goolsby. sale 2 duck coats at $125 2.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">187 Nov. 2, T. H. Williams, sale 1 loaf bread .05 r. 3, Boyd Co., maintenance of Thos. Holland from Nov. 3, '06 to Feb. 3, '07 ... 45.00 Nov. 3, Miss Jones, sale of uniform goods — 2.50 Nov. 5, C. Nierman for board of Aug. Borcher for Nov. '06 tv. 5, Douglas Co., maintenance of Henry Wiese from Nov. 5, '06 to Feb. 5, '07 45.00 tv. 6, Gage Co., maintenance of Harm Huls from Nov. 5, 06 to Feb. 5, '07 _ 45.00 Nov. 7, G. F. Swihart, sale 1 bbl .50 Nov. 7, Board of attd. for Mrs. Guthrie _ 15.00 r. 8, Sarpy Co., maintenance of Jas. Curley from Nov. 8, '06 to Feb. 8. '07 45.00 Nov. 9, Mabel Adams, 2 books $1.00 and 50c 1.50 Nov. 9, F. C. Miller, sale one lantern globe .15 tv. 9, Louie Stein, sale 613 1b old rags at $1.25 per cwt. 7.66 r. 9, Marie McNeil, 1 1-3 da. time lost after pay roll was sent to Sec'y of State's office .75 Nov. 8, Mabel Moore, 4 da., same as McNeil 2.84 Nov. 8, Alice McGaw, 6 da., same as McNeil _ 4.84 Nov. 8, Ella Nelson. 1-2 da. same as McNeil .40 Nov. 8, C. C. Davis, 3 da., same as McNeil __ 2.42 Nov. 8, L. M. Grasley. 4 3-4 da., same as McNeil 3.84 Nov. 8, C. C. Davis, sale 3 duck coats at $1.25 3.75 Nov. 8, Ella Nelson, sale one nurse book 1.60 Nov. 12, J. R. Megahan, sale 3 hogs 800 lb at $5.50 44.00 r. 12, F. D. Pickering for board of Mrs. Pickering to Dec. 3, 1906 15.00 Nov. 12, Wilber Mills, sale sacks. 2890 at 4c $115.60 25 at 2c .50 300 at 3c .... 9.00 $125.10 125.10 Nov. 12, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 4 No. 1 hides 189 lb at 12c 22.68 9 No. 2 hides 565 lb at lie 62.15 Now 12, W. A. Campbell, sale 49 loaves bread at 5c 2.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">188 12, C. G. Br e 1 Berkshire boar 16, Johnson Co., maintenance of Robt. T. Smiley from Nov. 16, '06 to Feb. 16, '07 16, Antelope Ool, maintenance of John P. 45 00 Penne to Feb. 16 45.00 16, Madison Co., maintenance of Thos. C. May - hew and Wm. T. Ferguson from Nov. 16, 1906 to Feb 16, 1907 90.00 17, J. R. Meprahan. sale 3 hogs 720 ft at 5%c 39.60 17. Ronald Hay, Raymond Gilmore 6 lb popcorn .30 1!). Don maintenance of Alfred Laughlin to Feb. 19. W 45.00 19. Kearney ('«.. maintenance of Neils Larson to Feb. 19, -07 45.00 SO, Lancaster Co., maintenance of J. C. Miller 45.00 Feb. 20. '07 20. Harpreaves Mercantile Co., sale 3060 ft cab- bape 21. Pasturapre two cows 1 month 30, Johnson Co., maintenance of Reuben Brott from Nov. 30, '06 to Feb. 28, '07 45.00 EXPENDITURES. Voucher ]!»m4 Number. Dec. 17, Wm. Haase, purchase cornstalks _$17.00 13207 21. A. S. Williams, repairing bupgy 2.85 13208 Dec. 21. Otto Anderson, services laying cement 48.00 13209 Dec. 21. 0. S. Gray, services as attd. 5.40 13210 'ov. 22, Josephine Kelly, sale 1 nurse book Joy. 22, J. R. Purbaugh. sale 83 head hogs 17170 ft " at $5.70 ov. 22. IT. 0. Kleine. sale one male hog ov. 22. Dawes Co . maintenance of John G. Farrell to Feb. 23, '07 ov. 27, Alb. Bocek, sale one boar pig ov. 28. Jeflfcrson Co., maintenance of C. H. Dodson to Feb. 28. '07 fv. 30. J. S. Weart, sale 8 lb dressed turkey at I8V2C ~~ ,„ [ov. 30, Johnson Co., maintenance of Reuben Brott </seg>
            <seg id="p067">189 t. 21, A. P. Taylor, dental work for John Barton, patient 1.00 Dec. 21, Jas. Reed, purchase of seed oats and straw 88.44 13212 21. James Little, purchase of emery stone 2.00 13213 Dec. 21, Western Union Tel. Co., service- 19.71 1 Dec. 21, G. F. Culpepper. services as attd. -83 13215 Dec. 21, Albert D. Gilmore. rent of school land .__168.00 13216 21, J. C. Kahl. breeding Berkshire sow 15.00 13217 1905 Jan. 7. X. C. Abbott, stereopticon viewi 10.00 1 Jan. 31, Austin Bridges, rent lots :?. 4. 5, ti. 7. X. E. 33, town 10. range ti East 15 acres 45.00 13241 Jan. 31. B. Hawkins, laying brick 1.80 1 t. 31, State Journal Co., supply record and pay roll book 35.00 13243 Jan. 31, J. A. Wean a in addition to pay roll 2.18 1 Jan. 31, (i. B. Clark, purchase 40 acres corn stalks 6.00 1 Jan. 31. Woodruff-Collins l'tir. Co., delivery blanks 7.50 1 John Cram, labor on wall at west farm 2.75 13430 S. Iva McCann. services as chg. 4th ward 5.36 1 10. ("has. Herman, purchase of corn 19.48 1 13, C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., rent of land 10.00 1 14. Alice IngaU ices as attd _ 5.94 1 14. Bertha Ludwiir. services as attd. 4.84 1 14. H. O. Foltz. toning 2 pian&lt;- 6.00 1 Feb. 14. Elenora Kahl. services 1 day as attd. 74 1 14. C. E. Shirey.. services u barn man 4.52 13438 Feb. 14, Western Union Tel. Co.. serrieM 5.63 13439 Feb. 22. J. H. Ondekirk, hauling ic. 5.00 13440 t. 25, W. G. Seidell. furnishing music for pa - tients' dance 22.50 13441 25, Albert D. Gilmore, paid for hauling ice 6.70 1 Feb. E. Shirey, stabling state team in city .95 1 Mar. 1. Jas. Reed, difference on trade of team 150.00 1 Mar. 7. Martha Park, service as nurse 8.93 1 Mar. 14. Susie Castle, services as stenographer 2.14 1 r. 20, Hoye Directory Co., purchase of city directory 5.00 13 Apr. 1. Susie Castle. ■erri«« 2.14 13613 Apr. 1. R. S. Calvin, services 3.38 13614 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">190 a 8, J. B. Harris, services 6.45 Li 10, Nonetta Wasner. services ....... 5.65 £ 10, Esther Brown, services 7.50 10, J. R. Burroughs, street car fare when on state business 1.10 13619 Apr. 10, G. N. Follmar. blacksmithing 42.30 13620 Apr. 10, G. N. Follmar. blacksmithinp 16.30 13621 Apr. 10, G. N. Follmar, blacksmithing 11.95 13622 42.30 13620 Apr. 10, G. N. Follmar. blacksmithing 23.50 13623 10, W. W. Towle. breeding 2 mares 20.00 13624 Apr. 10. Phillip Goldman, tin work 10.10 ] Apr. 10, Otto Anderson, services 16.87 13626 Apr. 10, D. K. Campbell, rent of house for farmer 2 months 20.00 13627 II T. Helms, music fur Easter Sunday service 10.0(1 13628 25, Rudge &amp; Guenzel. furniture in physician's office 368.78 13629 Apr. 25, J. M. Roper, purchase of weeder 5.00 13630 29, Walter G. Seidell, music patients' dance 12.00 13631 May 27. New York Bakery, purchase 5 lb almond paste 2.80 13733 I. 29, J. E. Miller, ice to fill ice house 15.00 . 29, Woodruff-Collins Ptg. Co., printing 5.00 . 29, J. Shamp Imp. Co., farm implements _. 26.20 . 29, E. L. Snyder, services 5.00 . 29. Howard Kelso, services 2.02 . 29, Harry Porter, stationery 5.55 . 29, Harry Porter, stationery _ 3.50 . 29, Geo. P. Tucker. V. S. services 19.00 . 29, C. E. Shirey. cash advanced 1.25 4. J. E. Cunningham, services 6.03 1OCOO A.O\JiJiJ 1OCO4. Iy 8, Ernest Tyrer, purchase of buggy and harness ... 25.00 y 8, H. Parrell. services 3.60 v 9, Hanah A. Tyler, hire of derrick 8.00 y 9, Earl Longacre. services 5.00 y 15. Western Union Tel. Co., services _ 21.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">191 31, T. H. Williams, purchase 2 hogs 460 ft at $5.17 1-2 .81 Less shipping chgs. 1.00 $22.81 22.81 13734 May 31, Lincoln Drug Co., drugs 49.26 13735 r31, W. L. Tetter Wall Paper Co., purchase of paper _ 21.88 13736 May 31, Sol A. Ksensky, purchase 2 gal. whiskey 6.00 13737 ty 31, G. A. Crancer, purchase picture frame moulding 5.04 13738 r31, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., difference in G. O. sections 3.50 13739 May 31, Esther Brown, services 11.00 13740 ty 31, J. R. Burroughs, street car fare while on state business .90 13741 May 31, C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., demurrage 6.00 13742 May 31. ( '. E. Shirey. freight and express paid 17.96 1 June 4, Eva Harnish, services 2.20 13820 June 5, Lillie Riehardt, services 1.06 1 June 14, D. K. Campbell, rent of residence for s June -June June June June June June June June June June June June 27. Chas. Slattery, blacksmithing 33.90 13838 farmer _ 20.00 14, W. C. Sheets, purchase of hay ... 12.75 *» 14, Fay Woodruff, services .... 1.00 14, J. H. Wilson Co., purchase of recording - clock 112.50 13825 14. P. H. Wohlenberg, purchase tobacco stems 2.00 14. Palisade Mfg. Co., drup- . 15.40 \rlington Chemical Co _ 11.80 14, E. L. Snyder, services __ 5.00 14, W. R. Hackney, services ... 6.11 IQQOfi -tOOOQ "IQS9Q 14, R. Iwanski, services . 5.00 13831 27, C. E. Shirey, freight and exp. chgs. ad 27.96 27. H. P. Lau &amp; Co., purchase molasses 19.78 27, Lincoln Coffee &amp; Spice Mills ... _ 56.35 27, J. B. Trickey, purchase spectacles 2.25 27. G. N. Follmar. blacksmithing _ 15.65 •iqaqo 1 'IV?'} looob 27, Standard Stock Food Co., purchase stock food 75.00 13837 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">192 June 27. Lincoln Hardware Co.. purchase hard- 19.63 13840 ware June 87, Kostka GiaM .V 1'aint Co., purchase 4:3.36 13841 paint, ei June 27, J. H. Arends i Co., i)iirchase butter _._130.74 13842 June 27. H. Herpolsheimer. purchase dry gooda 126.07 13843 June 27. H. Herpolahdiner, purchase dry gooda 126.07 13843 June 27. Beatrice Creamery pardttM but - ter, eggs .116.05 13844 June 27. Burt W. Richards, boiler insurance 33.00 13845 June 27. Miller &amp; Paine, purchase carpet etc 92.57 1 June 27. Miller i Paine, purchase carpet :*8.17 13847 June 27, Western Union Telegraph Co.. wr for May 7.27 13848 June 27, Mil 9-92 1 July 6, Wm. Wilson, moving farm cottage 20.00 13938 July 7. C Wettlaufer. as attd 5.81 1 her Brown. as stenographer ... 7.00 1 July 7, Ernest Tyt as chief cook 8.75 July 7, R. Iwanski. services in addition to pay 13942 roll 5.00 July 7. E. L. Snyder. services in addition to pay roll 5.00 7. Maud Williams, services in addition to pay roll 4.0(1 Ky 7. Robt. Bear, services in addition to pay roll 5.00 II K Austin, services in addition to pay roll 92 Aug. 1, O. F. Lambertson. dental work for patients 15.00 1. B. Hawkins, service laying brick 30.90 3. J. R. Burroughs, street car fare while on s ate business .80 3, C. K. Sliirey. expense on state business .60 3, B. Hawkins, services layinp brick "&gt;70 3, R. Iwanski. services in addition to pay S roll 5.00 14023 ta. 3. E. L. Snyder. services in addition to pay roll 5.00 14024 3. C. B. &amp; Q. R are service aokbouse &amp; Tyrell. purchase of carna- 1.00 ~ tion plants 4.00 14026 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">193 :{, Diamond Compound Co., purchase boiler compound 37 ..vj 1 : - ». ( i . A . ( ]*il 11 (*i 'I' t ' ' . | Mil 1 .oh •'!. Iliill Bros. d&gt;.. purchase castii :&gt;. Will II. Green, wall paper and labor 57.94 Aug. :;. Western Union Tel.. Co.. services 2.86 1 3, II. E. Sidles, purchase six tennis balls :{. Miller &amp; Paine, purchase merchandise A Young, expense transferring pa tieiits 2.05 1 Vnir. :!. Howard Kelso. ser 4.84 i :i. Milu McCord, services as carpenter -42-~»' • 1-1 10, American Berkshire Ass'n r Aug. etc. 2.(mi 111. I). K. Campbell, rent of house for fanner 20.00 1!&gt;. A. I). Oihnore, expense whil llllSi: 37.13 i ]'.K A. 1). Oilmore. expense shipping 11.5.1 1 1!', A. 1) (ti! nnii'e. spending money adv. Aug. 14041 patients l!t. A. D. Oilmore, spending money adv.-: pat i 44&lt;) Aug. 25, John Ilanjrpi, pnrchi r July 4th 12.25 25, C E. Hedges, purchase castings 11.50 1 Aug. -'&gt;. (i. P. Tucker, veterinary 13.5(1 I-l _'."•. Carl Funke, purehaw dishes l'."). SipI A Ksenskv. purchase wlii - i'."&gt;. Alma Hill, services as \ &gt; 1.45 Aug. 25, -I 0. Brower, ser\ ittd. 1. Annis Wilterding, servi&lt; 1.31 35.00 L'. Karl Lonpacre. ser\ ."). Emma Ilultln 4.s4 5, Margarei Carr, ser&gt; 14110 .'&gt;. Lillian B. Stnff, 2741' 14111 •"&gt;. Alice McGafi 2.00 5, Ellen Bov 'vices 16.93 1411? Sept. 5, Marie McNeil, Sept. 5. Florence P L29 1 4 11 r&gt; S.'pt. ;». K. I.. Snyder, services 5.00 14116 5, R. lwanski. services </seg>
            <seg id="p072">194 5, L. L. Pyle, services 22.58 141 ]•&gt; Sept. 5, Cora Brodt, services _... 5.68 141 1!) fcept. 5, Mabel Dunn, expense transferring pa tients 1.00 1412" t. 8. H. C. Dawsmi. purchase Poland China boar 100.00 14121 rt. 11, Beatrix purchase cream arator 300.00 1412:2 rt. 6, A. D. Gili pense of patients to state fair 39.65 1412.? Sept. 13, Lillian Ferris enoprapher 3.00 14124 rt. 25, Jacob Dixoa, overpaid mi maintenance of S. Dixon L4125 4. Walter Am or butchering, etc. 12.00 1 5. Marparet (amerer, services as attd. 7 !»o 1 6. Nora Breitv rvices as attd. 3.71 1 York PhannacMl Aaaoe. drutrs 18.40 I 7. P. E. Noble, services as attd. 6 67 I 7. Mrs Sadie Noble services as attd. 3.67 1 1&lt;|. W. R. Hackne; sea as attd 2.50 I i Harlan, aerviees a* attd 2.33 14240 7. .1 M. McNeil, services as attd. 7.50 14241 10. Lincoln D) 39.42 14242 10, Kl«»pp &amp; Barth- I 14243 I attd. .81 14244 one hay mare 250.00 1424") R. Iwanski. 1.33 1424H I). Gilin h paid for express 63.93 14247 E. L. Snyder. 5.00 142"&gt;1 29. I) K Campbea rent 14.00 14248 Quinby «i Leibee. painting eorniee, etc. 57.20 1 T. H. Bailsback, carpenter tools 8.00 14250 tlO. Lillian B. Stuff, money for meals transfer - ring patients $1. lawn for 3.50 1 10, Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 7.63 14253 \ Weart. ier a attd. .97 1 10. Woodruff-Collins Printing Co.. receipts 12.75 1 B. QaiT orate 15.00 14256 tF. H. Rohrs. dep. sheriff. Xemaha Co., ret. I&gt;atient 20.35 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">195 Oct. 14, Robt. Emerson, service .80 1 r. 14, Cora Damrow, cork sole on shoe for pa - tient 2.25 1 Oct. 10, Quinby &amp; Leibee, services 8.40 14260 Oct. 10, Wm. Hellman, services ..... 4.40 1 Nov. 2, W. A. Doggett, shuttle carrier 1.00 14362 Nov. 2, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co.. twine, etc 1.50 1 Nov. 2, C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. car service 7.00 14364 Nov. 4, Abbie McKnipht. services 2.93 14365 Xov. 4. Ethel Hoffman, services 2.00 1 Nov. 2. Kate Gallagher, services 2.93 1 Nov. 2, Louetta Wanser, services 3.33 1 Nov. 2, Dess Hoffman, services 3.33 1 Nov. 2, Clara Walling, services 12.04 1 Nov. 8, Nicholas Ress, refund 43.00 1 f. 9, Catherine O 'Conner, services as steno - grapher 1.00 ! fv. 9. Western Union Tel. Co.. for July ser - vices 1 1378 r. 9, Western Union Tel. Co.. for August ser - vices 3.75 1 9, Western Union Tel. Co., for September ser - vices 5.86 14373 Nov. 2, Harry Porter, mimeograph, etc 33.00 1 Xov. 9, E. B. Rucker. i 9.33 1 11, E. L. Snyder, services 5.00 I 11, R. L. Smith, supplies 94.40 1 Nov. 13. Dierks Lbr. &amp; Coal Co., lumber 122.37 1 13, Medico Legal Journal 12.00 1 Keefe, services 1.42 1 f. 13, Lillian B. Stuff, cash expended for patient 2.65 I 13. Milo McCord, Bervieea 106.25 1 20, II. J. Smith, grass mower 44.90 1 21, Betta Bennett, 2.94 1 C. E. Shirey, cash expended 3.10 1 28, Harry Porter, supplies 19.79 1 28 Harry Porter, supplies 16.25 1 &lt;; A. Young, cash expended 3.50 1 7 I an Dirt. Tel .65 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">196 •&gt;f '. A IV 1 1 ! 1 1 1 1 ■ ml Union 1 tea 21.00 144V, 10.00 1 11. Lincoln Tr. •■.. moving dynamo 6.00 ! 13. .1 II. Ouderkirk, pork and cum stalks 16.83 144** rn stalk- 3.00 1 i{. Burr .90 14490 Fred -Mill.-r. service* 10.00 144M1 Clifford Qninby, cash expended for took 40 144M-J kc. tuning chapel piano 1.00 \4VXI Win. S. 25.50 144M4 Walter II. furnishing music at patient 30.00 144!t."» rK. Tyrer, Furnishing music for employ dance | 6.00 144!tti 30.65 144!i7 - Mo Felts, tuning piano 3.00 1 A. I). Gilmore. exchange paid 2.55 14499 Jan. ■_'. ii W. ! attd. 9.76 I k 10.65 14582 id. :5.7:5 14583 ra Wall attd. AV&gt; 1 cutter for 6 12.50 14.W. 10. Ma; 30.75 I 1"). B. Hawkins, building chimney 4.80 14.&gt;. io.no i- pat!' 8.75 Mill. IfeCord, service* 12 ■ u. popeom at 65e 8.45 fi. T. H. Willi 'i expended for ■ ,, tie whip 1.50 i«:» 3.33 ii Tyrri 1.2") !i. .1 T. I ill expended in transferring patients to II 3.60 I i .1. Loverii 5.64 ,44-, i Harlan. eash expended for repairs watch l.(H&gt; 144.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">197 20, Nellie Amos, services 2.50 Jan. 20. Marie McNeil, services i'"-" I Jan. 20, Alma Hill. a 2.50 I Jan. 20, W. J. Barr. services 11. til 1 Jan. l'o. The .John Van Elan kitchen uten Jan. L'ti. \V. W. Towle, services 15.00 1 Jan. 27. S. V. Burnham, 1 hog 15.00 ' f. 2!t. A. I). Gibnore, cash advanced for patients 1 spending money 7.00 i 1, T. II. Williams. 1 hog 19.45 ! 1. .1. (i. Carmen, a 50.00 1 ti. Pueha &amp; Fuctis. decorating wards 300.00 1 Feb. ti. L II. Watson, service* 5.81 I Peb. '■&gt;. -las. Harlan. services 1.13 1 Ludwig Becker, furnishing music 8.00 I it. .1. L. Greene, cash expended 1.53 1 10. T. II. Williams, cash expended -J.tiii 1 10. P. M. Bost. services 1.61 I K). Yankee Hill Brick Co., hrick 3.7.") 1 ll\ Marjraret Carr, refund on 1 ip 10k 1.60 1 12. Margaret ('an-, services 9.35 I 16, Lincoln Mfg. &amp; Development Co.. supplies 10.70 1 lit. W. B. Saunders Co., hooks for nurses 114.75 ! Peb. 17. Pacha &amp; Fuchs, decorating wards 255.17 ! 17. Win. II rn stalks 4.00 1 l!t. J. M. Camp, carriage repairs H.4."&gt; 1 1!&gt;. Lincoln Sash &amp; Door Co., sawdust 9.25 14700 21, Theodore Kaar. cider 5.00 147oi Feh. '2'2. A. 1&gt; Gilmore, v ¥ h piw j 1T1 ir 11 t I h t ) i * \ ' sils 154.50 Jan. I'd, M. Scott. Al'1. H. &gt;.V M. R. K I ght c-li 24.:il ,4,,, Jan. 22. Lincoln Coffee «.v Spice Mills, coffee and Is|ii.-. 64 . 24. A B. Colics, half paymeni for ferreta 4.00 IS Jan. 24. R. I. Mans, hogg 24. Win. Spjihn, 1 hog 1 Jan. 24. J. A. Warren. 2 hogi (5.77 26, Walter Scidell. furnishing music foi ly dance* 24.im» 14601 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">198 Feb. 23, Lincoln Bottling Works, liquid gas 9.00 1 Mar. 1, J. G. Carmen, services 50.00 14765 Mar. 1, John Leibee, services 50.00 14766 Mar. 1, J. R. Burroughs, servic •&gt; 5.00 1 Mar. 1, C. E. Shirey. cash expended 1.75 1 Mar. 1, E. B. Slawson, farming mill 5.00 1 Mar. 1. Harry Porter, supplies 16.85 14770 Mar. 1, Ottenheimer &amp; Co.. 1 coat 1.00 14771 Mar. 1, Ernest Tyrer. music 8.00 14772 Mar. 1, W. G. Seidell, music 30.00 14773 Mar. 1. Lincoln Harness &amp; Imp. Co., repairs 5.00 14 &lt; 74 Mar. 1, Rudge &amp; Guenzel. 1 table top 16.00 14775 Mar. 1, The John Van Range Co., tin baskets, etc. 24.25 14776 Mar. 1, Minneapolis Threshing Mfg. Co., repairs 7.00 147 1 7 Mar. 1, T. J. Thorp &amp; Co.. rubber stamp, etc 3.65 1477K Mar. 1, Dierks Lumber Co., lumber 190.65 1477!) Mar. 1. J. R. Burroughs, cash expended .80 14780 Mar. 1, Carl Canarsky, services 2.00 1 Mar. 1, Geo. Williams, services 25.00 1 Mar. 1, Chester Swinson, honey 10.80 14783 Mar. 1, Alex Weininger. service .3.22 1 Mar. 1, Polk, McAvoy Dry Goods Co.. 1 directory 5.00 1 Mar. 1, Clara Geddis. services !)4 147&gt;tJ Mar. 1, J. G. Carmen, services 5 22 1 Mar. 1, C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. Co., car servic. 2.00 1 .Mar. 1, Nona Weart. services 2.68 1 Mar. 1, Josephine Kelley. services 1.18 14790 Mar. 1, Isaac Ferishette, repairing mower 2.50 147fU Mar. 1, State Journal Co., supplies 12.85 14792 Mar. 1. Otto Anderson, cash expended 2.05 1 Mar. 1, Frank S. Springer, registration fees 16.00 1 Mar. 1, Marie Samuelson, services 5.50 147Mr&gt; r. 1, J. L. Greene, cash advanced for return of patients 93.17 14796 Mar. 1, George Underwood, plumbing 203.75 147H7 Mar. 1, Lena Dishong, services 17.82 1 Mar. 1, A. D. Gilmore, cash expended 30.25 1471)9 Mar. 1, W. L. Seidell. hauling ice 1.25 14800 Apr. 2, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, furniture voucher 442.50 1 Apr. 2, AUis Chalmers Co., freight chgs. voucher 1.83 14880 Apr. 2, Walter Seidell music voucher 24.00 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">199 Apr. 2, Woodruff-Collins, supplies voucher 15.50 14882 Apr. 2, Lincoln Imp. &amp; Transfer Co., repairs 2.90 14883 Apr. 2, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., steel ceiling 18.18 14884 Apr. 2, M. O. Reilly, to meter testing, repair- 68.00 14885 ing and adjusting dynamo, etc. H8.00 14885 C. E. Shire v. cash exDended 4.48 14886 Apr. 2, C. E. Shirey, cash expended Apr. 2, John Hopkins Press. American Journal of Apr. Apr. .Apr. . v pr. Apr. Apr. Apr. Apr. 9, G. N. Follmar, horseshoeing 9.30 14912 Apr. 9, G. N. Follmar, horseshoeing, etc. 19.85 14913 &gt;pr. 9, E. Fleming, 6 alarm clocks 5.40 14914 Apr. 9, Mary E. Reid, 3 doz. books on bacteriology 18.00 14915 Insanity, 190ti 5.00 2, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., paper 9.75 2, Korsmeyer Co., electrical fixture 132.23 I 2, E. Fleming, repairing clock 100 2, Reddig, Mossholder &amp; Co., grates 30.06 2, H. J. Heinz Co.. pickles, catsup, etc 67.75 2, International Harvester Co., 1 manure spreader 105.00 2, O. G. Amos, services 1.17 2, Mrs. E. Walroth -'.16 2, Jas. L. Greene, P. M., postage stamps 30.00 9, Geo. Williams, services 25.00 9, Walter Anderson, services 15.75 9, Dr. J. L. Greene, cash advanced for re- s turn of patients .135.58 9, Alex Weininger, services 12.26 9. Geo. Underwood, plumbing dining rm, etc. 30.00 9, Chas. A. Wenino, tuning chapel piano L50 ,4,0, 9. Josephine Balsleym, services 1.47 14901 9. Wm, Krause. cor. galv. iron and repairing tin roof, etc 302.30 - 9, Ella Torrence, services 2.66 14905 9, Western Union Tel. Co., telegraph service 13.68 9. Xebr. Telephone Co., telephone tolls 46.15 IS 9, Xebr. Telephone Co., telephone rental 42.00 9, J. B. Trickey Co., smoke spectacles 1.00 \Z 9, J. M. Camp, repairing carriage etc 8.75 9 Will H. Green, painting main center and - stairway 527.44 14911 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">200 1 Moline ~_'..&gt;o 1 I l!». Alice &lt;r;n\ 2.13 14!»17 tl&gt;r. .! L. G •'! tor j :,| 10.00 1 4!»1M hspended for dent - i patieni 2.05 14918 r 5.25 1 nn-nt work 69.31 1 1. Louii- H;ir/kf. unloading eo«l 3.50 \V&gt;~ i 1. .1. (I (jinn carpenter 44.61 14978 1. K. L. Snyd« 5.00 14979 1. K &lt; Wippr. hay 1. Joh lawn 1.75 1 1. Wall 11. furnishiiitr imisi,- for pa nta' dances '24. (M) . 1' M.. ]&gt;■ 30.00 - LtUBfa lumber 79.60 u;- t &gt;rni»ldr- h&gt; 144.00 8, Dr .1 I,, i h Advanced for turniin.' patienta 69 E Sb • : vaiict'd for fn i^lit and &lt;'X|iri 29 8. Harry Porter, office supplies 1' B, Hall Bros. Co., milk cans. r. I id&lt;i pan&gt; S9.40 Itnbr. 7o.l-~&gt; 8. Ru and chairs repj "p^ 25 8. Ru ■■! wainscottinp hall and - 84.20 .4«e ftddKMMe i Tyr.-ll. plants 9.75 ncoiii Han repairing harnean •'! 4&lt;&gt; .1 Flowers, tiatehet chisel and drills l 95 R. Bnrroof ifa expended .70 ,4996 Idith Tipton. refund on nurses book 1.60 8, Henn Farrell. tei'vieei 6.10 I tolls 36.65 s and ho </seg>
            <seg id="p079">201 l-i. I* rank Mow mi of hi 17. \V. T. Betz, seed corn 6.00 I May 22 J. M. Camp, repairing vehicles :4l'"&gt; 1 I'll. Western Supply Co., engine room supplies 2s.2t&gt; 1 22. (has. Slattery, horseshoeing 48.70 1 22. J. II. Wilson, time slips for recorder 4.ii4 1 ■22. Cal. Hirsch ,V Sons I i K. Co.. 1 iron bed 1&lt;m&gt; 1 ty 22, Miller &amp; Paine, carpets, cork carpet, cur - tains, shades jinil picture frames 14 15006 22. -I Shanip Impt. Co.. 1 potato plant.' I 22. Lincoln Imp. ft Transf. Co., 1 disc blade 1.75 1 ty 22. Woodruff-Collins Ptg. Co., report Manks and 10.50 1 -"•&lt; • 1 1 ty 22. Walter Anderson, unloading coal and ting fence posts son i:,ii1l&gt; May 22, Augusta Leding. services 6.25 1 May "J2. Ella Torrenee. services r.46 1 _'•_'. ( ;.-!,. Williams, services 25.00 15015 fy 22, The John Van Ran* 1 100-gal. polished copper coffee urn $342.00 gal. polished copper tea urn Slti.oo 15016 .May 1'L*. Lincoln Hardware Co.. hardware 125.44 1 May I'L*. Geo. P. Tucker, vet. service- 15.00 1 ty !'"_'. Dr. -I. L. Greene, cash advanced to return patients lt;!».()'J 15019 May I"-'. -I. L. Greene, P. M.. postage stami&gt;s 30.00 ' ty 22, -F. L. Greene, cash advanced for picti for Ward t; 6.00 15021 ty 22. .F L. Greene, cash advanced for clothing for Kllen Fry. a patient 8.20 l-")n-_&gt;-_&gt; Ifay 22 J. E. Williams. Bervieea 2.02 1 June 1. Otto Anderson, cement work 69.37 June 1. W. R. Goolsby. services 3.23 1 June 1. Fred Beehtle, building fence 17.00 1 June 1. y\. C. Henry, services 7.10 1 June 1. Oeo. Blakely. cash expended in the mat - ter of purchasing a pomp 3.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">202 June 1 Clara Poole, services 1.50 1 June 1, Scotts Bluff Co.. refund 25.00 1 June 1, Acme Broom Co., brooms 75.00 15084 June 1, Dierks Lbr. Co., lumber 58.33 15085 June 1, H. J. Heinz, preserves 13.00 15086 June 1. The Farm Home, advertising 8.40 I June 1. Win. Krause, zinc and labor 65.00 15088 June 1, Miller &amp; Paine, carpets and window shades ~&gt;14.63 15089 June 1, G. N. Follmar, blacksmithing 10.00 15090 June 1, C. E. Shirey. cash advanced for freight and express chgs 16.05 15091 June 1, Walter Seidell. furnishing music 12.00 June 1, Nebr. Hardware Co.. hardware 52.60 Ee 1, Korsmeyer Co., electrical supplies 30.13 e 1, Western Furniture Co., 1 pr. wagon shafts 3.00 e 8, Geo. Willi;. 25.00 25.00 June 8, Katie Knie, services 11.71 June 8. Henrietta Hammond, services 1.48 June 8. Viola Daw 1.42 June 8 Minnie Jor 1.42 June 1, Mrs. Bowling, services 1.42 June 8, Walter Anderson, meat cutter for May 12. "&gt;n June 8, J. A. Weart. services 5.00 re 21. Walter Anderson, meat cutter 16 days in June . 8.00 15104 June 21. A. D. Gilmore. spending money advanced to patient 8.00 15105 June 21. A. D. Gilmore. cash expended for exp chgs. and patients attending circus 11.48 15106 June 21. A. D. Gilmore, cash advanced to pur chase one horse 100.00 15107 June 21. A. D. Gilmore. cash advanced to patients for labor 7.00 15108 June 21. A. B. Colles. 1 ferret 5.00 1.-.1D9 June 21. Hay &amp; Gilmore. labor in garden 3.00 15110 June 21. C. I. Roop, painting 43.23 15111 June 21. Otto Anderson, laying brick, gutters &amp; cement work 76.87 15112 Tnlv *&gt; Pnatlp l?nTM»r &amp;■ Mntthau-s "X hnvnitfll casket* 45.00 15169 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">203 July 2, Dr. J. L. Greene, ret. patients 82.35 15170 July 2. Frank Wheeler, painting "&gt;4 .95 1 July 2, O. W. Iverson, painting 1.50 15172 July 2 J. L. Greene, P. M. stamps I July 2, Postal Tel. Co,, message .40 1 July 2, Wm. Krause, tubs, pans, repairing ry 2, Western Supply Co., 1 Jenkins Bros, globe yoked 20.1(0 1 July 2, Spier &amp; Simon, duck coats 115.58 15177 r2, W. G. Seidell. furnishing man and team for cultivating corn and potatoes II 60 15178 July 2, A. S. Crew, pair combined glasses 7.00 15179 r2, C. E. Shirey, cash advanced for express and freight charges 34.14 15180 ty 2, C. E. Shirey, cash expended in the matter of purchasing a team for hospital 9.14 151M July 2, J. H. Penfold Co.. surgical instruments 196.79 1 ry 2, Yankee HH11 Brick Mfg. Co., brick for gutters 100.80 15183 July 2, Singer Sewing Machine Co., 1 shuttle 57 15184 July 2, F. E. Noble, services as night nurse 27.50 1 July 2, J. S. Decker, services 26.58 15186 July 2, J. A. Weart services 5.00 1 July 2, J. M. McNeill, services 25.00 15188 July 2, Cora L. Damrow. services as matron 51 July 2, Geo. Williams, services as farm hand 25.00 l July 2, A. B. Colles, services __ 4.35 1 July 2, Farm Home Co., advertising B.40 ry 2, A. J. Morris, window shades and adjusters . July 2, Katie Knie, services as attendent 6.74 1 July 2, Francis Edgar, services as attd. 9.53 July 2, Nona Weart, services as attd. 14.17 1 July 2, J. S Weart, services as supervisor 28.33 1 ry 2, Nebr. Tel. Co., rental of instruments and use of lines from July to Sept. 30th 42.00 15198 July 2, Geo. P. Tucker, veterinary services 23.00 15199 July 2, G. N. Follmar. blacksmithing 23.95 1 July 2. Western Union Tel. Co.. messages 28 77 I July 2. Xebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 43.70 1 t i o /~fc+* \ *-i ik A on 07 i conQ </seg>
            <seg id="p082">204 ]; \| Ti'lliall. bwildinir material for c 1096.78 15204 IDr .1 I. Greene, ret. i and expen- &gt;dy &lt;&gt;t' Mi's. i'. 1'. SI., stamps for month of July 2. o E. Rector, drugs 188.33 15207 lsv:',:{ 15207 July 2. Fred Bechtle. labor 23.00 1 _' Fr.-.l B.-.-htl.'. 1« I- &lt;.r 23.00 1 July 2. Ella \ 2.00 1 _'. Ella Nelson, - 2.00 1 ti.:{!i 15210 Juh al TeL Co.. ii .:{!» 15211 c&lt;&lt; . .:{!) 15211 Milo M arpenter 39.76 \'&lt;2]2 July 2. .1 - y. rep. pump 4.&lt;Ml 15213 tShaap Inipl Co.. 1 dain rak.' ami ker -I'.ii 15214 July 2. Lineoli Mills, coflfee 48.00 15215 rle two brass beda ami hair I niattn's&gt; 113.83 15216 ty 2. A 1) Qilm U-.l tor patients i to 4-1'av I spfiid - 31 85 15217 m r.V I), (iiln in and orangM for ly 4th ti.72 15218 July 2. Dan Harp, t cutter 2.").ini 15219 July Harlaii. Mrvieei 8.00 I y. mulberries 90 r\V II Green, painting and decorating mp - atendent'a oftVe IT- i'n 15285 r-l A. Weart, •ervie» rdener in addi - to pay roll 5.00 Florence Peck, services 2.84 ! J. II Heinz Co.. vinegar 15.98 I pap polish 9.00 I A L. I'lideland. hones and mugs 4.2") 1 Lincoln Tent ft Awning Co.. twningi 23.50 I r Walter Sei lell, labor of man and team and furnishintr music for patients" dance. July 4th 21..-.0 15292 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">205 ■ * i i 1 1 i i i j j ' '^s . * * * . » 1 1 * i_j ■ y el 1 1^ f rans. galv. pipe, ete. I ■ • it. Harry Porter, office supplies li'.:{") 1 it. Harry Porter, office supplies 1l'.:{"&gt; 1 it. Lincoln Leather Co., shoemakers wax. patches and soles L8.90 it. Lincoln Leather Co., shoemakers wax patches and miIis it. Oillen &amp; Honey, crystal Hake 3.50 I it. Ooncordia Casein Snap Co.. 1 bbl. soap B.6(J Aug. it. Sarpy Co., for refund on a&lt;-&lt;- 'i of Walter it. Sarpy Co., for refund t of Walter An, s. Ruble •_'!).:.() 1 Aug. 9, Yankee Bill Brick .Mt gutters it. Win. II. Thomas, rubber blanket 1.46 1 ii, Yankee Hill Brick Mfg. Co., hi Am.' &lt;ruti • •'■iii'i I it. Win. II. Thomas, rubber blanket 1.46 1 Dr. -I. T. Hay. pet. patients Hi4.i&gt;i) l Dr. .1. T. Hay. ret. patients 1&lt;&gt;4 20 1 Aug. it. ( '. H. siiircN'. money expended for freight and express cIil.'^ 7.71 15303 it. c E. Shirey, money expended i" the mat - ter of purchasing a team for the hospital 12.:i7 I l&lt;t. Alice MeGaw. services 14. ~&gt;'2 1 it. ( '. E. Shirey. money expended for fn Aug and express ehtrs 7.71 it. C. E. Shirey. money expended in the in.it - ter of purchasing a team for the hospital 12.:i7 Williams. ser\ Ki. .1 s. Decker, services 27.22 1 1&lt;». F. E. Noble, services J7:.n in. .1. M. McXeill. services ■_•:. "ii i 111. T. II. Williams, services .-)(!.( Ml It), -las. Uarlan. services 30.00 1 lit. W. .M. Kelso. services 5.85 1"' 10, .1. H. Rnrroiii-'hs. services 1". Maggie Bowling, lilt lit. Lucy Johnson, sen in. L. II. Watson, sen 4.."&gt;'i 1 in. Eva W Is. 111. Mabel Moore, services 4ii7 In. Alex Wining ices Kt.lMI 1 lit. .1. B. Harris, upholstering chairs 15.00 1 lit. Alice Crawford, services 13.71 1 Aug. 10, Sarah -I. Ferguson, sen ti.L'l 1 ■ 10, Mabel Wilson, stenographer ii 7i \ iil'. in. 0 ( ■ Am. 13.55- 1 10. C. F. Hedges, truck wheels and rep. chair in. Remington Typewriter Co., repairs 2.00 I 10. i. \ Follmar. blaeksmithing 7.85 1 "1 l\ I I \\" </seg>
            <seg id="p084">206 r. 10, Nebr. Hardwar wire fence, hose, staples and bolts 164.72 1 .Aug. 10, Cooper &amp; Cole Br room repairs 51.31 1 Aug. 10, Harley Drug Co.. drofli l.")4.72 15331 Aug. 10, Rudge &amp; Guenzel, furniture l'77.30 1 Aug. 10, Lincoln Hardware Co.. hardware 63.17 1 r. 10, Rudge &amp; Guenzel ' 1 eeilingi cream freezers, cups, forks and spoons 71.95 I Aug. 10, Lincoln Hardware Co., hardware 5 *"&gt; | r. 10, Lincoln Traction Co.. 1 trip with trailer from Lincoln Park to show grounds and return 9.60 I r. 10, Woodruff-Coll it blanks for dairy and reports 15.00 1 r. 10, W. H. Green, papering four rooms of farm cottage 2 • : Aug. 10, Lincoln Tint i Awning Co.. awnings 7.00 1 r. 10. Marshall Dental Supply Co., 1-2 yd. rubber dam .85 1 r. 10. The Dr. G«o. LeSninger Chem. I formaldehyde ' 48.00 15341 Aug. 10. Fr. 48.00 I 10, Hall B Is 27.05 ! Aug. 10,o E Rector, drug! 169.05 1 *up. 10. Warner &amp; Beekmui, si 4 &lt;»&lt;&gt; 1 Aug. 10. W. L. Seidell, 1-2 bu. plums .75 1 in. J. M. McN .9.68 1 10, J. T. Hay. P. M . 1.VH) 2e stamps 30.00 1 10. Ot 1 labor at cement work 6.00 1 10. W. A. Simmons, refund 35.00 1 'herry. - 25.1M* 15361 H E. Austin, services 1.77 1 25.00 1 10. Roman Twanski. services 50.00 1 Mina Kurhke. 1.77 1 ' 10. If 1.12 1 10. T H. Williams, services 50.00 1 Alma Hill ■ 5.65 1 '•a L. Pamr - 50.00 1 10. Lillian Ward, sev 1.77 1 10. Minnie Schilling. » 6.21 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">207 10, J. T. Warren, services 8.87 1 Sept 10, F. E. Noble, services 27.50 1 Sept. 10, J. S. Decker, services 27.50 1 Sept. 10, Lillian B. Stuff, services .51.66 1 Sept 10, Frank Howard, diff. in trade of team 100.00 1 Sept 12. Ernest Johnson, servic* - 3.00 1 Sept. 12, J. A. Weart, services 5.00 1 Sept. 12, N. B. Baldwin, service! 7 _'i; 1 Sept 12. Gertrude Hills, services 8.13 15368 Sept. 12, Lillian Johnson, services 5.24 15366 Sept. 12. Jas. Harlan, services 29.03 15365 Sept. 12, C. C. Clark, services 7.92 1 Sept. 12. Dr. J. T. Hay, ret. patients 7.71 15374 K. Shirey, freight and exp. ch 38.36 1 13, Crane Co.. boiler feed pumps 130.65 1 13, O. E. Rector, drngi 67.21 1 13. E. Fleming, repairs, spectacles, clocks . 13.35 1 tt. 13. .1. If. Camp, new side paul and corner irons buggy neekyoke center Sept. 1:5 Korsmeyer Co., d;iss panel and electrical IS. J. H. Conrad &amp; Co.. coffee 26.00 1 13. The Garlnck Pk&lt;_r Co., rinsr. spiral, sheet supplies 13, Singer Sewing Meh. Co., knivt-s .:',(&gt; i H. Heinz Co.. vinegar, pickles 4 13. J. M. Tamp, wagon repairs !&gt;.5O 13. Clarke. Da\ instruments 13. Isnac FViaehette, sharpening lawn mower and repairs 2.00 13. Lincoln [mp. ami Tr. Co. Plunger. 83 pn 1.70 13. Lineoln Harness and Imp. Co., repar 13. C. A Schaflf. carpenter labor and sand pa | 33.60 13. Reddijr. M"n— hnlrlnr &amp; nt drain ]&gt;lates and one chair casting 4.75 Bariey Drug Co.. &lt;l 13.19 13. Frank E. Lahf. poultry nettintr ltf.00 13. Lincoln Hdw. Co., rivets, screens, nails. etc. 30.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">208 ial case 15.00 ] Miller &amp; Pain&lt; t.\ D Gilmore . traveling expenaea kford. 111., and return :!i'.(H 15449 t.\ . 1 ) I i 1 1 I fare for patient-* L5450 tA. D GilB for pa - 14ti(» 15451 lui Plynn, straw 2.00 1."&gt;4:&gt;l' J. L. I L'titi 15453 - J. L. I 2.66 15453 ]'-lM-'&gt; ] i ; Damro 50.00 l i L Danrow, :&gt;&lt;t.oo 15455 "J7..")i) i r»4."»*; ■J7..")i) 4. John Farrell, services 4.17 15457 4. John PaireH, ■ervieeg 4.17 ! 4. M. C. Henry, service* 9.00 1 4. II. C. I 9.00 1 • &gt;.(MI 1 •~&gt;.&lt;KI 1 4. Roman [waaaki, wrrieea 50.00 1 4. Roman [wa ;&gt;(i.&lt;mi i 4. Roman [wanaki, expenses to L#ouurvilli 4. Roman Iwanski. ex] i Louisville trading i'.4!t ' Milan,: lL'.on I ■k l'.4!t I Melander. Il'.ok 1 4. P. K \obl&lt; 27.50 1 4. P. K SobU i'T 50 15463 4. Flora Peck, services 4. (Mi 1 4. Flom Peek 4.00 1 WilNai 12.50 1 4. Maude Will 1.17 1."&gt;4m&gt; 4. Maude Williiiins. serri&lt; 1.17 15466 4. T. H. Will 50.00 I 4. T. H. Willi 50.00 1-Vliw Qilnore. •_' lamba 180 tt. at 4 AA&lt;- v.v&gt; I fJilmore. 2 lambs 180 tt. at 4 :5-4r 8.55 I 19.67 15469 19.67 15469 P. (. l);i\is, mason work on boilen 10.00 15470 P. Q i uon work on boilers 10.00 15470 Dora I' 5.13 L"&gt;4i 1 Dora 1' 5.13 1"&gt;471 l T. Il;i\. 150 mps O.00 15472 i T. Hay. I npa W l."»47i' J. T. I ~h advanced on returning • f. T. II i\;uice&lt;| on returniiiir pati^ L5473 .ish advanced for freigfal and express ehi. r s. 41.66 1")474 A. -I ' Herl 120.00 i:&gt;47."» Lincoln Traction Co., motor cars 4 trips from Lincoln park I Il'.(M) l.&gt;4iti r Paper &amp; Bag 19.20 1"&gt;477 in </seg>
            <seg id="p087">209 r. 13, -I. Sharp (mpt. Co., twine ami poll spri for iiii.\ &lt;" I rl-5. International Harvester Co., of Abbot repairs for farm machinery 17. Florence Meddoms lL'.oti I rls. Robt. Powell, refund on t&gt;i&gt; da the number of days )&gt;iiiil for in adv of the hi. charged at 50e per daj 31.00 t. 27. A. 1&gt; Gilmore, cash expended in attend - ing the sale of •"&gt; boars at the Amer Royal Live Stock Sale held at K C, Oel lo. 1906 74 o- 15483 :'.. &lt; '&lt;&gt;r;i Brodt, Ml 8 i Nov. !. Cora li. Dmmrow, 50.00 1 .1 s Decker, services 27.-J- .1 H Ilarlaii. :?. Roman Iwanski. services 50.00 I :i. F E. Noble, s.-i-\ -i.-cs 27.50 1 Nov. 3, Zilla Payson, 2.06 1 Florence Peck, Bervices 4.00 1 Nov. :i. Minnie SebiUii 1 *4 1 T II Williams, service* "-""i 1 I Nov. 3, \V. \V. Towle, stallion 45.00 I Nov. 6, J. A. Middleton, services 12.50 1 ■ K B. Backer, services 19.50 1 r Woodruff-Collins 1'ti: Co.. blanks and ■tionei-y 5 50 15556 r Woodruff-Collins P blanks and 23.00 : fr. 10. C E Shire\. cash advanced for freight and express charges : '. 7 . 14 15558 10. The .1. A. Parks Co.. quartette books 4.38 1 Nov. 10, Western Union Tel. Co.. telegrams 11.74 1 r. 10. W. &lt;;. Seidell. music furnished for pa - tients' danees 30.00 I 10, The Farm Hom&lt; idvertisemei Nov. 10. Geo. II Both, harness repn 12.20 10. David Higgina .81 1 10. Marguerite Wallix 7.81 i lit. J. T. Hay, 30.00 1 n </seg>
            <seg id="p088">210 J. T. Hay. cash advanced for ret. of pa tients 70.80 10, Armour &amp; Co.. drug! 32.50 1 12. Lincoln Plow &amp;. Imp. Co.. mower supplies 4.55 1 12. Marie Samuelson. services 12.60 1 J. T. Warren, services 15.00 1 15. Dora Walling. 8.40 1 decker, services 21.08 1 tv. 13. W. R. Holt, one thoroughbred Berkshire sow :&gt;1.00 1 ■ A. Crawfonl. as painter 25.20 1 turned 4 4") 1 SUMMARY OF CASH KIND. ToUl amount on hand, December 1. 1W4 $1,706.19 rl amount received from December 1. 1904 to May 31. 1905 2,44 rl amount received from June 1. IS member 30. 1905 7.269.16 rl amount received from December 1. 1905 rl amount received from .Tune 1. I'' 1 7,42 Total n $26,742.90 rount disbursed from December 1. 1904 to May 31, 1905 $1,629.46 runt disbursed from June 1. 1905 to mber 30, 1905 3.350.19 runt disbursed from December 1 190.") to May 31. 1906 9,013.11 runt disbursed from June 1, 1906 to mber 30. 1906 9,095.40 Total disbursed $23,088.16 Balance Nov. 30. 1906 $3,654 .74 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>