<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home To the Governor and Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Thirteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER SO 1*14 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">448 KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION Lena E. Ward Sude B. Ward Wm. Sandusky Superintendent Matron Physician EMPLOYEES M. Evelyn Meyer Vivian Antram Ida H. Mclntee Emma Beard Secretary and Teacher Head Nurse Sewing Teacher Cooking Teacher Eugene Robinson F. J. McGhee Farmer Engineer Louis Lamprecht Fireman </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 449 To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Hotranl Kenneihj and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I herewith submit, for your consideration, the thir - teenth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Industrial Home. During the past biennium, two hundred forty-five have received care in the Home. The work of the Home is divided into details of eight weeks each. This gives every girl a chance to learn some - thing in all branches of the domestic work. However, if a girl is not able at the end of the eight weeks to do the work on the detail in which she is placed, she is kept there an - other eight weeks or until she is able to do it well. We feel that it is better to get one thing well, than a little of all. We have been fortunate in having a splendid woman, who thoroughly understands cooking, to supervise this part of the work this biennium ; heretofore, the matron, who al - ready had her hands more than full, had to look after this and it was impossible for her to give as much time and at - tention to it as was needed. So many girls, who come to us, have never done any cooking, but are anxious to learn and it has meant so much to them to have someone with them all of the time to teach them. It has also been m saving to the State, as many of the girls have never been taught to be saving and when left alone have wasted a great deal. Our new laundry has been such a satisfaction to us the past six months. In October, 1913, our old laundry was destroyed by fire. While it was a poor excuse of a laundry, yet we found it much better than none. For nearly a year, the washing had to be done by hand and it was no small task to wash for so many in this way. So the girls as well as everyone else greatly appreciate the new laundry with its electric washer, extractor, mangle, irons, etc. Tw&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">450 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF girls now do the washing that was done by six or eight be - fore. We have more girls in the ironing-room, but the work is completed in much less time. We hope next year to have a woman to supervise this part of the work for it is very necessary that, wherever there is a detail of girls working together, there should be someone with them. The house work is divided into the different floors and a girl is detailed to care for a floor for the eight weeks, making beds, sweeping, dusting and looking after the work in general. This is under the supervision of the matron. We also have a sewing department in which all the sewing of the Home is done. Many girls come to us who cannot run a machine or who have never worn a thimble. At first they think that they never can learn to sew and do not want to try, but, as all must go to the sewing-room and do their own mending and help with the other sewing, they soon become interested and, by the time they are ready to leave the Home, they do very nice work. We do not have any regular time for fancy work, but try to teach the girls what we can in this line, knowing that it will be a pleasure and benefit to them after leaving the Home. All detail work closes at 2:15 P. M. and all go to school until 4:45. While it is impossible to classify our school work, as we should like to do, yet we try to follow the reg - ular course, the best we can, to give each girl the work she needs most. The girls, with but few exceptions, enjoy the school work and often speak about it and do not under - stand why they never liked school before. This, we think, is easily explained, as they do not have so much to distract their minds, as they had before, and there is no staying away from school ; all must go, if able. Some, after leaving the Home, go right on with their school work, that is, if it is a girl who has a home and someone to help her. One girl, who recently left the Home, worked and saved her money and is now in one of our universities. This girl came from a home where the father and mother had separated and she had had to work in a lundry to support herself and help support a little sister. If the public could only know just what some of these </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 451 poor unfortunate girls have gone through before coming here and could look into some of the homes ; or, it may be a girl, who has never known a home and the love and care of a father and mother; or, as the case may be, a little school girl, who on account of her ignorance and inexperi - ence was led wrong, then, after all this, she must often give up home and friends or the dearest thing on earth to her, I am sure there would be a great deal more sympathy shown for this class of unfortunates. The day's work is closed each evening with a short chapel exercises, led by one of the ladies of the Home, ex - cept on Wednesday evening, when we have our Christian Endeavor meetings under the supervision of one of the la - dies, but led by one of the girls. They all take a great in - terest in chapel exercises and never want to miss. On Sunday we have our Sunday school at 9 :30 in the morning. We have a nice little library, the books having all been carefully selected by the State Institution Librarian and, at the close of Sunday School, all go to the library and get new books to read. The afternoon is spent in reading and resting. We are often asked whether the girls appreciate all the State is doing for them and, in answer to this question, I am going to give a few extracts taken from the letters written by the girls in the Home to their people, or by those who have gone out of the Home and are writing back to girls who are here. "Mama, you need not feel badly because I think so much of this Home, for you would too, if I could only tell you how much it has done for me and how good they have been to me." — Irene. "Tomorrow I will have served eight months of my time. But, Etta, you don't know how I hate to see my time come to leave the Home. Sometimes it does seem that it is the only home that I have ever known and I hate to think of leaving." — Helen. "Well, mama, I have only eight weeks at most until 1 can come home. I can hardly realize it myself. You told me. when 1 came here, that this would be a year in my life that was lost, but 1 can't see it that way now. Of course, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">452 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF as far as outside happenings are concerned, it is lost, but ' the lessons that I have learned will never be forgotten. I have learned a great many things here that I would never have learned at home. I don't intend to settle down at home and never turn my hand over to help support myself like I used to d:&gt;." — Louise. (This girl, after leaving the Home, took a course in nursing and is doing well.) Received April 8. 1913, by one of the girls in the Home from one who had left several months before: "Words can never tell the good the Home has done me. I shall never, never regret the year I spent there, as long as I live, although it was awful to think that I had to go there and to become a mother. But 1 believe God only sent this punishment to me. as a warning, because, if this had not happened to me, 1 would only have yielded to these temptations and gone on deeper in blac!'. sin, until I would have been past saving; as it is I have had my awakening and shall never commit this sin again. And ' had always been brought up in the church and my dear mother tried to bring me up a true Christian. But never had I learned the real worth of our Saviour and what a great thing it means to us to live a true Christian life, until I went under the teaching of this Home. I cannot say what I owe to the State nnd the Home for what they have done for me. I can say that last year was the best year I have ever spent in my lifetime. I know that I can now live a good life and be a woman and, whenever I think or speak of the Nebraska Industrial Home, I assure you it will al - ways be with the highest honor and respect." — Genevieve. REPAIRS We have been able to do but very little repairing on the main buildings this year, but have built our new laundry and repaired the roofs and down spouts on main buildings. An entirely new steam line, laid in conduit, has been put in from the power house to the main buildings; this will effect a great saving in coal as practically all of the heat will now come into the buildings instead of warming all the ground around. A number of much-needed repairs were made at the power house, among which wa r . a new smoke stack. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THK HOAR!) OK COMMISSIONERS 453 NEEDED REPAIRS AND PERMANTNT IMPROVEMENTS One of the first things that we want in the way of permanent impro\ements is two sun nurseries. The two rooms now used as nurseries are both on" the north and all the sunlight that the babies can get must come in at one lone window in the east. This not only deprives the babies of the sunlight that they should have, but makes it impos - sible to ventilate the rooms in the winter as they should be, as all the other windows are on the north. These are cold, dark rooms and are not fit places for the babies, as sunlight and fresh air are two things they must have to do well. Another m.ich-needed permanent improvement is a dairy barn. So much of the milk is fed to the babies that too much care and attention cannot be given the cows and the milk. They are now milked and cared for in the barn with the horses and it is in no way sanitary. The outside and inside walls of the two main build - ings must all be gone over. The mortar on the outside walls has so deteriorated that it has fallen out in many places and the bricks are also dropping out in places. The moist - ure goes right through *o the inside walls and they are at times covered with mildew and are often so damp we can - not use the rooms. The outside wood work has not been painted for years, if ever, since the buildings were first put up, and this should all be done, as well as the porches. A great many of the rooms will have to be plastered painted, papered and have new ceilings. Some of the floors are so badly worn that they will have to be replaced. The plumbing will have to have a general overhauling and some new bath tubs and fixtures installed. The only place that we have to care for our vegetables and fruit that we put up for winter use is in the basement through "which all the steam used in warming the buildings must pass. The result is that each year a great deal is lost for want of a proper place to care for these things. This we hope to remedy with an outside cellar and root house. It will also be necessary to have a new engine and boiler before two years pass. The engine now in use is a </seg>
            <seg id="p009">454 I'IRST BIENNIAL REPORT &lt;»K small high speed engine and now, that the laundry is run by electricity, it will be too much for this engine. There is only one high pressure boiler, so that every two weeks when the boiler is washed, the lights must be off and this necessitates the use of coal oil lamps. This is a very dan- gerous thing where there are so many to handle them. FARM There are only thirty-seven acres of land in connec- tion with the Home and so much of this is taken up by yards, orchard and some waste land, that we do not have what is needed to keep the number of cows that should be kept. Therefore, we are asking that a forty acre tract, adjoining the Home on the east, be purchased and a number of cows be added to the herd. A number of fruit trees have died the past two years and these should be replaced or a young orchard started. There is also a great deal of repairing and improve- ments that should be made about the barn and yards. Value of farm produce for biennium $2,757.55. The following table shows the work done in the domes- tic departments : Laundry Average number of pieces laundried per week 2,581 Sewing Department Pieces mended 8,200 New garments made 3,986 Culinary Department Fruit and vegetables canned (quarts) 5,377 Kraut (gallons) 184 Pickles in brine (gallons) 46 Dried corn (pounds) , 225 Loaves of bread baked 21,912 Buns 11,232 Cakes 328 Cookies 15,648 Doughnuts 5,000 Puddings 594 Pies 3,504 Biscuits 12,162 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 455 1 also wish to express my appreciation for the hearty co-operation and many kindnesses shown us during the past biennium. Respectfully, Lena E. Ward, Superintendent. Mil ford, Nebraska, November SO, 191 A. REPORT OF THE PHYSICIAN Mins Lena E. Ward, Superintendent, Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford, Nebraska. Dear Madam: It is my pleasure, at the end of this biennium, to sub - mit my report as physician to this Institution. The general health of the inmates has been good. Our babies suffered an epidemic of whooping cough during the winter of 1913-14. During this epidemic there were thirty - five babies, varying in age from three weeks to two and one-half years, who contracted the disease, many of the cases being severe. Among these there was one death caused by complicating gastro-enterities. During this biennium there were eighty births: fifty - five normal; twenty -five abnormal deliveries; seven still born ; and three premature. Two hundred eighteen pa tients have received hospital care. I want to specially call your attention to the urgent need of a sun nursery. We believe it will materially re - duce our infant mortality by giving the babies the benefit of sunlight during the whole of the day and making it pos - sible to install proper ventilating system. At present the nurseries are situated in the northeast corner of the build - ings, making it practically inaccessible to the sunlight and the problem of proper ventilation during the winter months a difficult one. It is also a pleasure to call your attention to the hearty co-operation and invaluable assistance afforded us by the Superintendent and Matron in the performance of our du - ties as physician to this Institution. Respectfully submitted, Wm. Sandusky, M. D. Milford, Nebraska, November 30, 191 U. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">456 URST BIENNIAL REPORT OK TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION 'Includes those who have been previously in this or a similar insti - tution. For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 Dee. 1. 12 July I, 13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30.13 For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1914 Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T Present at begin- ning of period Admitted, Adults: For first time Readmitted* Transferred from other institutions Infants: Born at in- stitution Returned from trial homes in which placed before commencement of period Admitted 11 54 65 16 67 83 ■iO .'50 20 20 1 1 3 3 10 15 25 9 17 26 1 1 1 1 '/ 17 71 88 11 54 ■ 41 41 91 91 1 1 1 1 4 1 20 9 29 39 41 80 : i i 1 12 13 Total under care 22 101 12:: 26 107 133 38 122 160 52 193 245 Discharged: In due course. Transferred to oth- er institutions Died Departed without leave Married Infants placed in permanent homes Infants placed in trial homes and not returned dur- ing period Still born 3 2« 29 2 25 27 2 2 2 13 13 4 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 1 16 3 2 5 3 3 2 2 5 57 62 10 108 118 ... 5 5 ... 7 7 5 7 12 8 11 19 1 2 3 2 2 3 3 12 3 13 4 7 2 9 11 8 19 2 2 4 3 7 Total removals 6 34 40 9 36 45 20 75 95 35 145 180 Absent in trial homes at com- mencement of 01 during period and later dis- charged without returning to in- stitution 5 4 9 3 3 6 7 5 12 15 12 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 457 TABLE II. AGES AND COLOR OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, It ending Total AGE to Nov. 30, for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium W C T W CT WCT WCT 14 and under 15 1 1 1 1 15 and under 16 1 1 2 2 4 4 7 16 and under 17 2 2 4 4 6 6 12 12 17 and under 18 3 14 2 18 and under 20 9 1 10 6 2 6 6 11 1 12 6 16 16 31 1 32 20 and under 25 11 11 10 10 28 28 25 and over 8 3 1 1 4 4 Totals 29 2 31 23 23 42 42 94 2 96 TABLE III. SEX AND COLOR OF INFANTS BORN AND ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT 10 15 25 9 15 24 20 9 29 39 39 78 2 2 2 2 1 12 13 11 16 27 9 17 26 21 9 30 41 42 83 TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year EDUCATION Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium F F F F 3rd {rrade &amp; below 5 1 18 4th grade 2 4 5 11 5th grade 2 12 6 6th grade 2 2 4 8 7th graded 8 3 9 20 8th grade" 8 8 10 26 High achooL 4 3 5 12 Unknown 1 t 1 Totals.... 81 23 42 96 For Yet Nov. S Dec. 1. 12 to June 30, 13 M F T White Colored Admitted: White... 10 15 25 i i 2 Totals .... 11 16 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">458 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE V. NATIVITY OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year NATIVITY D«.l.ll July 1,13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium F F F F Nebraska _ 18 17 26 60 U. S. other than Nebraska 8 3 12 28 Total native born .... 26 20 37 83 Germany 12 3 Total foreign born 1 2 S Unknown 5 2 S 10 Totals _ 31 23 42 96 TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 NATIVITY OF For Year PARENTS Dec. 1.12 July 1, '13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium F F F F U. S., both parents 17 17 Foreign, both par- ents 1 2 13 16 Mixed 15 6 Unknown 30 20 7 57 Totals 31 23 42 96 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 459 TABLE VII. PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year PARENTAL Der. 1. '12 July 1,13 ending Total CONDITION to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium F Both parents dead.. 3 4 Father dead 1 3 Mother dead 7 1 Parents living to- gether 19 12 Parents separated.. 1 2 Has stepfather Has stepmother 2 _ Unknown 1 2 Unknown Totals 22 U TABLE VIII. AGES, AT DEATH OF PARENTS, OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total Nov. 30. for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium F F F F Age at death of father: 2 3 fi 3 8 7 Under 10 years 1 1 1 10 and under 15 yrs 15 years and over. Unknown 2 3 3 4 4 Age at death of mother: Under 10 years 3 2 3 2 12 3 5 10 and under 15 yrs 15 years and over. 2 5 Unknown 1 1 4 6 27 52 Totals 12 13 44 100 n AGE Ju </seg>
            <seg id="p016">460 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK Totals U 2:! 42 96 &gt;.A iSSIONS OF ADULTS FRC O DELINQUENT HOMES For Year Ending: Nov. 30. 1913 For Year CLASS D?s VIS July 1,1.! ending Total to to Nov. 30, for lune30, i:» Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium F F F F Feeble-minded: Father 1 1 Both parents 1 1 Insane: Father 1 1 Mother 1 1 Intemperate: Father 5 2 7 Mother 1 1 Delinquent: Father 4 2 17 Mother 1 2 3 Both parents 4 2 4 10 Brother 1 2 3 Sister 1 3 4 Unknown 9 6 14 29 Totals 26 11 31 68 TABLE X. PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 OCCUPATION Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium F F F F Cash Girl Clerk Cook Domestics Factory Hotel work House-keeper In school Laundry Office work Tracher Telegraph Telephone Unknown Worked at home l 2 i 13 ""&amp; 5 5 " ■ 3 .......... ■' = t z I ! '.'. 2 4 1 2 3 13 1 6 1 7 2 1 ........ 2 2 1 5 3 31 1 M 1 15 2 2 1 1 6 3 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 461 .E XI. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMI AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For Year Ending Nov. 30. 191:? COUNTY O -: I. 12 ' July 1/18 ti to Jon* 30. '13 Nov:{0,'13 For Year endinir Total Nov. 30. for 1914 Biennium F F F F Adams Antelope Blaine Box Butte Buffalo Butler Cass Cliiv Colfax Custer Dawson Dodjre Dnufdas Fillmore Franklin Fumas G. K e Gosper Greefcy Hall Hamilton Harlan Hitchcock Johnson Kearney Lancaster Madison Merrick Nance Otoe Pawnee Platte Polk Saline Saunders Scotts Bluff Sheridan Sherman Sioux Valley Wheeler York 1 1 1 2 2 1 2 1 i ;'.'.;; zzzzzzzzz 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 2 1 1 .......... 2 s 1 "1" ZZ.ZZZZZZZ 2 1 2 1 1 1 .......... 1 1 1 1 1 -t 1 1 1 "i &lt; 3 3 1 2 2 4 1 1 2 4 1 1 2 4 6 7 1 4 1 2 1 4 1 3 3 3 1 1 1 2 2 1 3 8 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 3 1 2 3 ....... .......... 1 3 4 Total* 31 23 42 96 42 N s </seg>
            <seg id="p018">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 462 TABLE XII. ADULTS— HOW ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 Voluntary applies tion Decree of Court: Delinquency Dependency Totals Dec. 1. '12 July 1, 13 endine Total CAUSES Nov. 30. for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Acute intestinal ob - struction 1 1 1 1 Acute indigestion Aspiration pneu- 1 1 1 1 monia 1 1 1 1 Congenital atelec - tasis 1 1 1 1 Gastro-enteric Hydro-sephalus Hematogenous 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 jaundice lleocolitis 11 11 1 1 1 1 Malnutrition Pneumonia Premature 123 1,12 23s 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 2 2 2 Still born 3 3 2 2 2 2 4 3 Syphilis cirrhosis liver 1 1 1 1 Whooping cough 1 1 1 1 246 336 77 14 12 14 26 Totals — — — For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, It ending to to Nov. 30, June 30, 13 Nov.30, Vi . 1914 Total for Biennium F F F F »- n 20 38 ■S9 2 4 1 I 1 31 23 42 96 TABLE XIII. CAUSES OF DEATHS For Year Endinp Nov. 30, 1913 For Year </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 463 TABLE XV. DISTRIBUTION OF LABOR OF ALL ADULT MEMBERS OF HOME AT END OF BIENNIUM, NOV. 30, 1914 Kitchen Dining room Laundry : Washing Ironing Mangling Hanging clothes Nurseries House- work Hospital ward Totals 36 For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 AGE AGE Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30, 13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T r m f t M F T Under one month.. 1 and under 3 mos 3 and under 6 mos 6 and under 12 mos 1 and under 2 yrs 16 and under 18 yrs 1 1 1 2 "T7.Z i ZZ.ZZZZZZ ZZZZZZZ'Z. ZZ. i i i 3 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 5 4 5 9 2 112 2 2 13 2 112 1 2 2 1 1 Totals Totals 2 13 13 4 5 7 : 12 8 11 19 4 3 2 5 4 2 6 9 es... ..♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>