<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00095.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0095.0003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">1941-1942</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1941-1942 </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003"/>
         <seg id="p004"/>
         <seg id="p005"/>
         <seg id="p006"/>
         <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 31, 194 2 From: The Adjutant General. To: His Excellency, Dwight Griswold, Governor, Lincoln, Ne - braska. Subject: Biennial Report for 1941 and 1942. 1- In compliance with requirements of Sections Ito 55, Chapter 55, Article 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1929, and th' c supple - ments thereto, the following Biennial Report for the calendar years 1941 and 1942 is respectfully submitted. 2. The Nebraska National Guard as a military organization continued in active federal service. From all reports received in this office the officers and men of the Nebraska National Guard are acquitting themselves in a manner which reflects credit upon the State of Nebraska and its people. Th e commendable manner in which the officers and men of the organization have carried out their assignments clearly vindicates the confidence which the Gover - nors and the Legislatures of past years have placed in them by appropriating funds for the maintenance of the organization. 3. During th e period of the current bienniura, and under the provisions of L. B. 368, 55th Nebraska Legislature, approved April 18, 1941, nine units of the Nebraska State Guard have been organized, all of which are presently located in the City of Omaha. The officers and personnel of these units ar e outstanding citizens. With - out doubt they will successfully carry on a state of training which will develop a proficiency capable of meeting any emergency which might arise within the boundaries of the State. As of this date the Nebraska State Guard consists of 57 officers and 343 enlisted men. 4. Like the National Guard in former years, the armory hous - ing situation for the State Guard units in Omaha is very unsatis - factory and efforts will be made, through th e cooperation of the Nebraska Armory Board appointed by the Governor, to improve this situation. 5. In conclusion, the writer wishes to express appreciation to our Commander-in-Chief, to the members of the Nebraska Legislature, </seg>
         <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the officers and enlisted men of the Nebraska State Guard, the Omaha Chamber of Commerce and other public service organizations, and to the hundreds of loyal aud patriotic citizens who have so loyally cooperated with the Military Department with their en - couragement, assistance, energy and moral support, thereby materially aiding this Department to function with the degree of efficiency it has. GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. FINANCIAL STATEMENT—MILITARY DEPARTMENT Appropriation 1941-1942 Biennlum ? 35,000.00 Iteappropi-iation 1939-194(1 Balance 10,133.06 Cancelled Warrants 1939-1940 «-40 545,141.46 Expenditure* July 1, 1941 -December 31. 1942 Salary &amp; Wages * 8.591.24 Supplies 5870-07 Expense "•795-26 Parts &amp; Repairs 2,111.28 Equipment 3,115.15 Lands &amp; Buildings 5,217.75 1 181.52 30,882.27 Fixed Charges ''"' $14,259.19 Balance Note: Ot the obave expenditures, the following amount was from funds appropriated for the Nebraska State Guard $7,989.28 and in addition an allotment of funds from Account 15 B 2,107.57 „, , $10,096.85 Total </seg>
         <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 13, 1941 General Order No. 1 1. Pursuant to authority contained in paragraph 23, NGR 3, dated August 9, 1933, the following change of station is announced, effective September 13, 1940: Headquarters, 3rd Battalion, 134 th Inf., Seward to Beatrice 2. The current season for outdoor range practice will be from January 1 to December 31, 1941, inclusive. 3. Only authorized and properly supervised firing on the regularly established ranges will be permitted. The firing of all other arms is prohibited on the reservation. 4. Permission for firing by units and details will be secured from this headquarters prior to such range practice. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: (1 copy ea&gt; Chief, N. G. B. C. G. 7th C. A. C. G. 35 th Div. C. G. 69th Brig. C. O. 134 th Inf. C. 0. 3rd Bn., 134 th Inf. File </seg>
         <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 1. 1941 General Order No. 2 ORGANIZATION OK THE NEBRASKA STATE GUARD 1 Pursuant to the provisions of L. B. 368, 55th Nebraska Legislature, approved April 18. 1941. the Nebraska State Guard is organized this date with the following designated units: State Staff Corps Ist Infantry Regiment station Designation T O XS(» 10 1 '41 Omaha Hit. &amp; Serv. Det 11-0 22-EM Omaha Med. Det. 5-0 14-EM Omaha Hu_. Ist Bn. 6-0 0-EM Omaha Co. A. — Ist Bn. 3-0 63-EM Omaha Co. B—lst Bn. 3-0 63-EM Omaha Hq. 2nd Bn. 6-0 0-EM Omaha Co. E —2nd Bn. 3-0 63-EM Omaha Co. F—2nd Bn. 3-o 63-EM 2. The Commanding Officer. Ist Infantry Regiment, will im - mediately secure the necessary enlistments to bring units within the strength prescribed by Tables of Organization, have physical examinations made, and assemble the command for Inspection for State Recognition on November 14. 1941. ¦;. The Monthly Report of State Guard Duty Performed. NSG Form No. 9. will be rendered as of November 30, 1941. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major I Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General </seg>
         <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL DISTRIBUTION: (1 copy ea.) Chief, NGB (2) CG 7th CA State Staff Corps (11) Hq. &amp; Serv. Det. Med. Det. Hq. Ist Bn. Co. A, Ist Bn. Co. B, Ist Bn. Hq. 2nd Bn. Co. E, 2nd Bn. Co. F, 2nd Bn. File (General Order No. 2 is th e last of the series of 1941) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 18, 1942 General Order No. 1 1. Pursuant to the provisions of L. B. 372, 55th Nebraska Legislature, approved May 9, 1942, the following appointments as members of the Nebraska Armory Board are announced: Yale C Holland, Chairman Harry Trustin R. Ware Hall Max Miller A. D. Majors By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: (1 copy ea.) File </seg>
         <seg id="p012"/>
         <seg id="p013"/>
         <seg id="p014">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 1, 194 2 General Order- No 2 1. The current season for outdoor Range Practice is hereby extended from May 1, 1942, to October 15, 1942. 2 Only authorized and properly supervised firing on the regularly established ranges will be permitted. The firing of all other arms is prohibited on the reservation. 3. Permission for firing by units or details will be secured from this headquarters, prior to such range practice. 4. The current season for Indoor range practice will be from January 1 to December 31. 1942. inclusive. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major I Inf. I IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: 1 ea. Hqs 1 ea. 0 1 File STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 10. 194 2 General Order No. :', 1 Upon renewal of an initial enlistment In the Nebraska State </seg>
         <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Guard, the enlistee will not be required to undergo a physical ex - amination, provided he certifies in writing that he has not sustained an injury or suffered an illness that has in any manner incapacitated him from performing active duty as a member of the Nebraska State Guard, or the duties of his normal civil activities. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: 1 ea. Hq. File STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 1, 194 2 General Order No. 4 1. Pursuant to authority contained in LB No. 368, 55th Ne - braska Legislature, approved April 18, 1941, the following unit of the Nebraska State Guard will be organized at the station indicated, effective this date: Unit: Band Designation: Headquarters, Ist Inf., Nebraska State Guard (T/O 7-11 NSG) Station: Omaha 2. Pursuant to authority contained in LB No. 368, 55th Ne - braska Legislature, approved April 18, 1941, the following units of the Nebraska State Guard will be reorganized and redesignated as follows: New Designation: Headquarters Company, Ist Inf., Nebraska State Guard </seg>
         <seg id="p016">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Old Designation: Headquarters Detachment, Ist Inf., Nebraska State Guard Service Detachment, Ist Inf., Nebraska State Guard (TO 7-12 NSGI Station: Omaha 2. The Band, organized in accordance with paragraph 1, will conform to Tables of Organization 7-11, Nebraska State Guard, ap - proved November 1. 1942. 4. The Headquarters Detachment, Ist Infantry, Nebraska State Guard, and the Service Detachment, Ist Infantry. Nebraska State Guard, reorganized in accordance with paragraph 2, will consolidate to form the newly designated Headquarters Company, Ist Infantry, Nebraska State Guard, and conform to Tables of Organization 7-12. Nebraska State Guard, approved November 1, 1942. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major I Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: C. 0. Ist Inf. (31 C. O. Hq. Det. ( 1 i C O. Service Det. ( 1 i File (1 ) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 2, 1941 National Guard Circular No. 1 AUDIT OF COMPANY COUNCIL BOOKS, 1940 1 Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1940. in accordance with the following instructions: </seg>
         <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL a. The account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under "Other Funds" and on ac - cordance with paragraphs 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 of the in - structions. (See also the model.) b. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, regardless of receipts or expenditures. c. Certificates for receipts and itemized invoices for ex - penditures are required for all transactions during the current year. d. In case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transactions, cut off bottom of page above "Total receipts and expenditures" and the top of the next page "In Account with Fund", etc., under the word "year" and above "month", and paste these pages together. c. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of December 31, 1940. 2. In cases where the Council Book has been filled and the last certificate has not been signed, it will be necessary to send in the old and the new book. However, these books should be used until they are completely filled and they are good for a period of from five to ten years. 3. For further instructions in Council Book procedure refer to "Rules and Regulations, Company Funds, Nebraska National Guard" (Blue Cover) published and distributed In January, 1940. 4. These Council Books with vouchers will be sent to the Adjutant General's office for audit, after which they will be re - turned to the custodian at Camp Robinson, Arkansas. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General DISTRIBUTION: (1 ea 0) State Staff 8 Det. Hq. Staff 35th Dlv 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. 69th Brig 4 134 th Inf. i Regtl Staff; Bn. Co. &amp; Det. Comdrs 27 110 th Med. Regt. (Regtl Staff; Co. Comdrs.) 13 110 th QM. Regt. (Regtl Staff; Bn. Co. &amp; Det. Comdrs.) 16 Instructions Nebr. NG 4 Comdg. Gen. Hq. 7th CA 1 77 File (xi STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 15, 1942 Circular No 1 COMMUNICATIONS AND REPORTS I Effective immediately all official communications and re - quired reports from and to Company and Detachment Commanders of the First Infantry, Nebraska State Guard, and the Adjutant General's Office will be forwarded through the Regimental Com - mander for his indorsement. 2. The only exception to the forgoing instructions is requisition for office supplies (NSG Form 1) which will be forwarded direct to the Adjutant Generals Office, State Capitol, Lincoln. Communications will be in accordance with military regula - tions as to style and spacing. One original and three carbon copies will be made; one carbon to be retained for organization file while the original and two carbons go forward to Regimental Commander for first indorsement. The Regimental Commander, after entering his indorsement, retains a carbon copy for his file and forwards the original and last carbon to the Adjutant General's Office. 4. Communications and reports from and to the State Staff Corps will be transmitted through the Executive Officer, State Staff Corps. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: Regimental Commander (50) State Staff Officers d e a) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 20, 1942 Circular No. 2 STATE GUARD MORALE The following is an extract from a letter published by the War Department, Services of Supply, under date of April 14, 1942, and is here published for the information and guidance of all concerned: 1. Numerous inquiries and criticisms have been called to my attention concerning the present and future status of the State Guards. 2. The limited federal assistance in available equipment re - cently announced by the Services of Supply, especially as to the temporary withdrawal of certain arms and ammunition, probably occasioned this apparent casual dissension. Clothing and equipment will be loaned or made available by purchase to State Guards when it Is reasonably certain these items are not required for the rapidly increasing field forces. The decision to temporarily withdraw certain items of equipment was made necessary after a careful study by the Requirements Division of the Services of Supply. 3. It must be definitely understood that State Guards are primarily a State Force activated, equipped and controlled by State executive orders. However, the Federal government is vitally con - cerned with the continued existence of these authorized State forces. ft 4. It is my belief that the true picture of supply to field armies is not fully understood by all. Therefore, it is urgently requested that no attempts be made to encourage criticism, especially by foster - ing political pressure, in any way to Impede the war effort or minimize the field service requirements of the fighting forces. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5. Substitute items of equipment will be made available as soon as sufficient quantities are assured. More definite instructions will be issued in the near future. 6. It is desired that the substance of this matter be presented informally to organization leaders within your state and that these leaders be urged to keep a flexible state of mind and a determination to carry on even though somewhat handicapped, and continue their former creditable performances. j*j JOHN F. WILLIAMS John F. Williams, Major General, Chief. National Guard Bureau By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: Regimental Commander (50) State Staff Officers (1 ea) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 30, 1942 Circular No. 3 MISSIONS FOR STATE GUARDS The following extract from a communication under date of April 2:;. 1942, War Department. Services of Supply, is published for the Information, action and guidance of all concerned: "As a result of conferences held this week it is apparent to all that the War Department Intends to establish more definite missions for the employment of the several State Guards, and will furnish all the assistance in training and in the supply and pro- </seg>
         <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL curement of equipment that is legally possible. These con - ferences also disclosed that in some instances officers and en - listed men of State Guard organizations held assignments in 0. C. D. activities in their communities. It Is considered Im - practical, and, in fact, detrimental to both organizations to accept such dual assignments. In the event of an actual em - ergency requiring the employment of 0. C. D. units the local state guard units will be actively employed on vital assign - ments, and, as the duty of all state guard officers and enlisted men are primarily with their state guard units they will not be available for 0. C. D. duties. All such dual assignments should be immediately terminated." By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: Regimental Commander (50) State Staff Officers (1 ea) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 29, 1942 Circular No. 4 WAR DEPARTMENT OUTLINES MISSION OF STATE GUARDS New tasks hav e been defined for the State Guards in instructions recently issued, the War Department announced today. These State forces, created under Congressional legislation of October 21, 1940, to replace in the States the National Guard units then In the pro - cess of being inducted into Federal service, took on new Importance with the outbreak of war. Under the new directive State Guards still remain State forces for use within the boundaries of their own States, but their functions have been fitted into a broad pattern for the home defenses of the Nation. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The National Guard Bureau is the War Department administra - tive agency for the State Guard and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau Is charged with promulgating the necessary instruc - tions and suggestions for training the State Guards In accordance with War Department policies. The new directive provides that the Commanding Generals of the nine Corps Areas assist State au - thorities in the training and development of the State Guards and make available to them various training aids. Suitable part time instructors will be provided whenever they can be spared. The mission of the State Guards as defined by the War Depart - ment Is to provide an adequate, trained force for employment within the boundaries and Jurisdiction of their respective States as directed by the State executive and legislature. The State Guards are expected, under normal circumstances, to be used for the benefit ot the State to meet domestic emergencies such as civil disturbances and disasters resulting from war or other cause and to guard and protect vital Industries, Installations, communications, and facilities when local police and civil guards are deemed inadequate. In ad - dition, the State Guards may be expected to assist Military Police and other units of the Army, to suppress the efforts of enemy agents such as organized fifth column groups and parachute troops and to cooperate with Federal military authorities in extreme emergencies especially in the evacuation of civilians and in Information and observation duty at or near frontiers. The War Department, through the National Guard Bureau and Corps Area Commanders, has circulated to th e various State Guard authorities suggested training programs to standardize progressive and balanced training. The War Department emphasized the fact that It desires every effort be made to make the training of State Guards interesting and practical and indicated that proficiency should be developed by the use of realistic methods of training. Instructions on this point are: "Conditions and situations which might confront the State Guards should be simulated as closely as possible In problems and exercise. Imagination and Ingenuity should be used to think up and conduct practical and realistic problems and alerts." By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R, TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff </seg>
         <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL DISTRIBUTION: Regimental Commander (50) State Staff Officers (1 ea) RESTRICTED STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 2, 1942 Circular No. 5 TIRES AND TUBES FOR STATE GUARD f The following letter from the War Department, Services of Supply, Washington, D. C, under date of June 25, 1942, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "¦The Office of Price Administration has stated that no blan - ket ruling can be made granting eligibility to all State Guards' automobiles since tires depend upon the use to which each vehicle is devoted. Only those vehicles used principally, or in some cases exclusively, for the purposes set forth in the Tir e Rationing Regula - tions may be equipped with tires. Those not In war use are in - eligible for tires. "Adequate provision is made in the revised Tire Rationing Reg - ulations to equip vehicles used to perform work of the nature indica - ted under Paragraph 4, a. to c. inclusive, restricted letter April 30, 1942, AG 324.51 (4-30-42) MC-SP-M Subject: 'Missions, Training and Employment of the State Guards,' provided such missions con - stitute the principal or In some cases the exclusive use, to which the vehicle is devoted. The nature indicated above is repeated for your information: '4. a. Maintain the laws; suppress disorders; and protect the life and property of individuals within the State. b. Meet such domestic emergencies as may arise within the State including civil disturbances and disasters resulting from both war or other cause. (War Disaster Relief). c. Guard and protect vital industries, installations, com - munications and facilities essential to the war effort when other means such as local police or protection by civil guards are deemed inadequate by authorized State or Federal agencies. </seg>
         <seg id="p024">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL J. Prevent or suppress the activities of enemy agents such as fifth columnists and parachute troops either in the absence of, or in support or conjunction with, Federal troops. f. Cooperate with Federal military authorities In extreme emergencies, especially In information and observation duties at or near frontiers and in the evacuation of civilians.' "Tires may not be used for purposes only remotely or Indirectly related to the public health, safety, or the war effort. Thus the use of vehicles to tTansport State Guards to places for drills or parades or such activities would be ineligible use under the Tire Rationing Regulations. "In regard to the hire of motor transportation. State Guards are deemed to be 'workers' within the meaning of section 405 (el ( '6) of the Regulations, and when engaged in guarding and patrolling bridges, factories and other establishments essential to the war ef - fort, they may hire buses for their transportation as a type of 'charter services' permitted to them under the Tire Rationing Regulations. "The Office of Price Administration feels that ample provision is being made under the Revised Tire Rationing Regulations to take care of state Guards and that further concessions would only Imperil and jeopardize the program for the conservation of our lim - ited rubber supply. /s/ JOHN F. WILLIAMS John F. Williams, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R TIRNER -Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: Regimental Commander (50) State Staff Officers (1 ea) </seg>
         <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA STATE GUARD LINCOLN August 4, 1942 Amended Circular No. 6 MONTHLY REPORT OF STATE GUARD DUTY PERFORMED 1. Pursuant to Letter CNGB, dated 13 July 42, subject "Monthly Report of State Guard Duty Performed," report will be made monthly, commencing with July 1942, by the Commanding Officer of each Company, Detachment, or corresponding unit, covering detailed re - cords of the training and duty performed by each recognized State Guard or authorized auxiliary reserve unit. 2. The "Monthly Report of State Guard Duty Performed" will be executed in quadruplicate on NGB Form 1670, the origlnial and two copies to be mailed to this office immediately following the end of each month, the remaining copy to be retained by the unit. 3. Sufficient copies of NGB Form 1670 are inclosed herewith to provide each unit with blanks required for reports for July. Additional supply of blanks have been requisitioned and will be issued to cover the remainder of the quarterly period ending Septem - ber 30, 1942, upon receipt. Thereafter issue will be on regular requisition for office supplies (NSG Form 1). By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: C. 0. Ist Inf. (50) Staff Corps (1 ea) </seg>
         <seg id="p026">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA STATE GUARD LINCOLN August 12. 194 2 Circular No. 7 MONTH I, V REPORT The following is extracted from State Guard Bulletin No. 4 — Hq Seventh Service Command, dated 10 August 1942. "I. Reference mltueo letter The Chief. National Guard Bureau, duted 22 June 194 2. subject: "Monthly Report." (State Guard 319.1—Gen); It Is desired that the report be forwarded so as to reach this headquarters not later than the following date of each month: Monthly Report tenth" 2. Information necessary to compile the Monthly report is taken from NSG Form 9. "Monthly Report—Duty Performed" as submitted by each headquarters and unit. In order to meet the dead-line for submitting the monthly report, all NSG Forms 9 must be received by this headquarters on or before the eighth of each month. 3. NGB Form 1670. "Monthly Report of State Guard Duty Performed" should be completed and forwarded so as to reach (his headquarters on or before the eighth of each month. by order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: /'. H. R. TURNER '" &gt; Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant Ge.ieril Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: Hq. (1 ea i Unit (1 ea) </seg>
         <seg id="p027">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA STATE GUARD LINCOLN September 12, 1942 Circular No. 8 AMMUNITION FOR STATE GUARDS 1. The following extract of letter Chief, National Guard Bureau, SPNGB State Guard 471-Nebr-l, dated 3 September 42, is quoted for information of all concerned: "1. Studleß are now being made with a view of setting up a training allowance of ammunition for State Guards. An announcement may be expected upon completion of these studies. "2. AH ammunition, except .22, heretofore Issued by the War Department, and not expended under previous au - thority, will be retained for emergency use. Previous in - structions in conflict with the above ar e rescinded. /s/ JOHN F. WILLIAMS John F. Williams, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." 2. Immediate steps will be taken by all unit commanders to comply with the above. By order of the Governor: GUY N. HENNINGER, Brigadier General, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: H. R. TURNER Major (Inf.) IGD Assistant Adjutant General Chief of Staff DISTRIBUTION: C. 0. Ist Inf. (50) Staff Corps (1 ea) </seg>
         <seg id="p028">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c&gt; Nebraska State Guard When the Nebraska National Guard was ordered into service on 2:; Dec. 1940, under provisions of Presidential Executive Order No. 8605, 30 Nov. 1940, the State of Nebraska was left with our Military force for use in emergencies within the State. The 55th Nebraska Legislature, meeting in regular session early in 1941, recognized the necessity for a State Military Force, and L. B. 368 was accordingly introduced, providing for the organiza - tion and administration of the Nebraska State Guard. This legisla - tive bill was passed with the emergency clause, was approved and became effective 18 April 1941. General Order No. 4, AGO-N"ebraska was issued 1 October 1941, organizing the following units of the Nebraska State Guard. State Staff Corps Headquarters &amp; Service Detachment, First Infantry, NSG Medical Detachment, First Infantry, NSG Headquarters, First Battalion, First Infantry, NSG Company A. First Battalion, First Infantry, NSG Company B. First Battalion, First Infantry, NSG Headquarters Second Battalion, First Infantry, NSG Company E. Second Battalion, First Infantry, NSG Company F, Second Battalion, First Infantry, NSG All units organized pursuant to General Order No. 2 were mustered on 14 November 1941. Units of the Nebraska State Guard mustered into the service of the State on 14 November 1941 were as follows: toil Authorized Strength Mustered Strength Officers Enlisted Officers Enlisted Men Men State Staff Corps 12 0 12 fi Hq. &amp; Serv. Det 11 22 11 15 Med. Dept. Det 5 14 5 4 Hq.. Ist Bn 6 0 fi o Company A :: 63 3 55 Company B 3 63 3 43 Hq.. 2nd Bn 6 0 6 o Company E 1 63 1 50 Company F 3 63 3 44 50 28.S 50 211 </seg>
         <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The War Department made available, limited supplies of certain items of clothing and equipment for issue of State Guard Units Requisitions were submitted and the following items received: Belts, web, waist 334 Caps, garrison, wool, O. D 400 ( Coats, wool, O. D 2 g j Coats, work, denim, blue 33i \ Hats, work, denim, blue 334 Leggings, canvas 32g Mackinaws, O. D 218 Overcoats, wool, 0. D 409 Raincoats 300 Shirts, cotton, O. D 334 Shirts, wool, O. D ggo 1 Pacs, artic, shoe 328 ji Shoes, service 160 I Trousers, cotton, 0. D .....668 Trousers, wool, O. D. 741 Trousers, work, denim, blue 334 j Blankets, wool, O. D 600 i Cups 300 j Rifles Cal .30 Ml 7 300 Bayonets, Ml 7 300 Scabbards, bayonet Ml 7 300 Shotguns, 12 gauge 120 During June and July 1942, all rifles, bayonets and bayonet f scabbards vrere ordered returned to the War Department, and ad - . ditional single and double barrel shotguns were provided to replace i the rifles recalled. Monthly Strength Report I Nebraska State Guard _ , Str at end Gain Losses of month En- En - ., . Of- listed Of- listed Of- Month fleers Hen fleers Men fleers EM November 1941 50 211 50 211 December 1941 3 64 1 2 52 273 I January 1942 0 19 0 22 52 270 , February 1942 4 19 3 27 53 262 1 I </seg>
         <seg id="p030">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Str. at enil liiiin Losses of month Kn- Kn - i if- listed Of- listed (&gt;r- Monlli fiiers Men firers Mci, ficers EM March Ift 4 2 2 IS 2 23 53 257 April 1942 2 21 1 19 54 259 May 1942 1 33 1 27 54 265 June 1942 1 32 1 20 54 277 July 1942 ;; 29 3 25 51 281 August 1942 "i 41 4 29 52 293 September 1942 ." 59 1 19 54 333 October 1942 2 47 1 32 55 348 November 1942 3 3X 2 29 56 357 December 1942 1 B 0 20 57 34P An analysis of separations of enlisted personnel Indicates such discharges were due to the following reasons: To accept commission in Nebraska State Guard 18 Due to physical disability 4 For business reasons 5S For non -residence 6 2 To enter armed forces of United States 81 Expiration of term of Service 71 The turnover in personnel during the 1941-42 Biennial period. based on the average monthly enlisted strength of the Nebraska State (iuard. was 102.1 c;. Of the seventy-one enlisted men discharged at expiration of term of service, fifty-three reenlisted In the Nebraska State Guard, the percentage of reenlistments being 74.6%. Losses due to entry into the Armed forces of the United States accounted for 21.3% of the turnover of enlisted personnel. The enormous rate of turnover in enlisted personnel presented a major problem in maintaining the strength of the several units, but through intensive recruiting efforts, was increased from the initial mustered strength of two hundred eleven on 14 November 1941 to three hundred forty-three on 31 December 1942, and in - crease of 62.6^, . Legislative Bill So. 3«« INTRODUCED BY JOHN MEKOTA OF SALINE; AMOS THOMAS, GEO. T. SULLIVAN OF DOUGLAS; RICHARD N. JOHNSON OF </seg>
         <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL DODGE, JOHN S. CALLAN OF GAGE, WALTER R. RAECKE OF MERRICK AN ACT to provide for a "state guard" for th e state of Nebraska; to designate a short title; to repeal Article 2, Chapter 55, Com - piled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, relating to home guards; and to declare an emergency/ Be it Enacted by the People of the State of Nebraska: Section 1. Whenever any part of the national guard of the state of Nebraska is in active federal service, the governor Is here - by authorized to organize and maintain within this state during such period, under such regulations as the secretary of war of the United States may prescribe for discipline in training, such military forces as the governor may deem necessary to defend this state. Such forces shall be composed of officers commissioned or assigned by the governor, and such able-bodied male citizens of the state as shall volunteer for service therein, supplemented, if necessary, by men of the reserve militia enrolled by draft or otherwise as provided by law. No one may be commissioned as an officer who has been convicted of a felony. Fingerprints of all officers and enlisted men shall be taken and forwarded to the federal bureau of Investigation in Washington, D. C, for examination. Such forces shall be ad - ditional to and distinct from the national guard and shall be known as the "Nebraska state guard". Such forces shall be uniformed. Sec. 2. The governor is hereby authorized to prescribe rules and regulations not inconsistent with the provisions of this act governing th e enlistment, organization, administration, equipment, maintenance, training and discipline of such forces: Provided, such rules and regulations, in so far as he deems practicable and desirable, shall conform to existing law governing and pertaining to the na - tional guard and the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder and shall prohibit the acceptance of gifts, donations, gratuities or anything of value by such forces or by any member of such forces from any individual, firm, association or corporation by reason of such membership. Sec. 3. When called into the active service of th e state, such forces shall receive pay and allowances at the sam e rates prescribed by law for officers and enlisted men of similar rank and length of service in the United States army. While in training at home station or engaged in other inactive service, such forces shall re - ceive no compensation. Sec. 4. For the use of such forces, the governor is hereby authorized to requisition or purchase from the secretary of war </seg>
         <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL of the United States such arms and equipment as may be in pos - session of and can be spared by the war department; and to make available to such forces the facilities of state armories and their equipment and such other state premises and property as may be available. Where state facilities are not available, grounds, armories and other buildings may be leased and maintained In the manner provided by law for the Nebraska national guard. Sec. 5. Such forces are not required to serve outside the boundaries of this state except: (a) Upon the request of the gover - nor of another state, the governor of this state, may, in his discretion, order any portion or all of such forces to assist the military or police forces of such other state who are actually engaged in de - fending such other state. Such forces may be recalled by the gover - nor at his discretion, (bi Any organization, unit or detachment of such forces, upon order of the officer in immediate command thereof, may continue in fresh pursuit of insurrectionists, saboteurs, enemies or enemy forces beyond the borders of this state into an - other state until they are apprehended or captured by such or - ganization, unit or detachment or until the military or police forces of the other state or the forces of the United States have had a reasonable opportunity to take up the pursuit or to apprehend or capture such persons: Provided, such other state shall have given authority by law for such pursuit by such forces of this state. Any such person who shall be apprehended or captured in such other state by an organization, unit or detachment of the forces of this state shall, without unnecessary delay, be surrendered to the military or police forces of the state In which he Is taken or to the United States, but such surrender shall not constitute a waiver by this state of its right to extradite or prosecute such person for any crime committed in this state. Sec. fi. Any military forces or organization, unit or detach - ment thereof, of another state who are in fresh pursuit of Insur - rectionists, saboteurs, enemies or enemy forces may continue such pursuit into this state until the military or police forces of this state or the forces of the United States have had a reasonable op - portunity to take up the pursuit or to apprehend or capture such persons and are hereby authorized to arrest or capture such persons within this state while in fresh pursuit. Any such person who shall be captured or arrested by the military forces of such other state while In this state shall without unnecessary delay be surren - dered to the military or police forces of this state to he dealt with according to law. This section shall not be construed so as to make unlawful any arrest In this state which would otherwise be lawful; and nothing contained In this section shall be deemed to </seg>
         <seg id="p033">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL repeal, modify or conflict with any of the provisions of present or future laws of this state with relation to the fresh pursuit of crim - inals. Sec. 7. Nothing In this act shall be construed as authorizing such forces, or any part thereof to be called, ordered or In any manner drafted, as such Into' th e military service of the United States, but no person shall by reason of his enlistment or commis - sion in any such forces be exempted from military service under any law of the United States. Sec. 8. No civil organization, society, club, post, order, frater - nity, association, brotherhood, body, union, league or other com - bination of persons or civil group shall be enlisted in such forces as an organization or unit. Sec. 9. No person shall be commissioned or enlisted in such forces who is not a citizen of the United States or who has been expelled or dishonorably discharged from any military or naval organization of this state or of another state or of the United States. Sec. 10. The oath to be taken by officers commissioned in such forces shall be substantially in the form prescribed for officers of the national guard substituting the words "Nebraska state guard" where necessary. Sec. 11. No person shall be enlisted for more than one year, but such enlistment may be renewed. The oath to be taken upon enlistment in such forces shall be substantially In the form pre - scribed for enlisted men of the national guard, substituting the words "Nebraska state guard" where necessary. Sec. 12. (a) Whenever such forces or any part thereof shall be ordered out for active service the "articles of war" of the United States applicable to members of the national guard of this state in relation to courts-martial, their jurisdiction and the limits of punishment and the rules and regulations prescribed thereunder shall be in full force and effect with respect to the Nebraska state guard, (b) No officer or enlisted man of such forces shall be arrested on any warrant, except for treason or felony, while going to, remairiing at, or returning from a place where he is ordered to attend for military duty. Every officer and enlisted man of such forces shall, during his service therein, be exempt from service upon and posse comltatus and from jury duty, (c) Members of the Nebraska state guard ordered into the actual service of the state by any proper authority shall not be liable, civilly or criminally, for any act or acts done by them while in the performance of their duties. </seg>
         <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Sec. 13. All acts and parts of acts inconsistent with the Pro - visions of this act are hereby repealed. Sec 14 This act may be cited as the "state guard act". Sec. 15. That Article 2, Chapter 55, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, relating to home guards, is hereby repealed. Sec. 16. Whereas, an emergency exists, this act shall be in full force and take effect, from and after its passage and approval, according to law. Approved April 18, 1941 ROSTER—NEBRASKA STATE GUARD 31 December 194 2 Governor Dwlght Griswold Commander-in-Chief Brigadier Gen. Guy N. Henninger The Adjutant General Lieutenant Colonel H. R. Turner Assistant Adjutant General Lieutenant Colonel W. J. Atkinson Executive Officer and State Guard Property Officer Major Wilmer G. Johnson Engineer List of State Staff Corps—3l Dec. 42 Lt. Col. Leo B. Bozell i Lt. Col. Ira D. Beynon Lt. Col. Vincent C. Hascall Lt. Col. John H. Hopkins Lt. Col. Theodore W. Metcalfe Lt. Col. J. Clyde Travis Major Wm. F. Patterson Major Allen T. Hupp Major Hird Stryker Captain Herbert L. Karrer HEADQUARTERS, Ist INFANTRY, N. S. G. Colonel Leo J. Crosby Lt. Colonel Frank S. Selby Major Maurice P. Brogan Major Harry Trustin Captain Frederick W. Clayton Captain William H. McNichols Captain Robert P. Samardick </seg>
         <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL NEBRASKA STATE GUARD BAND W. O. Edward P. Pfeifer Technical Sergeant (Grade II) Douglass, Gerald J. Privates (Grade VII) Braun, George H. Chaloupka, Michael M. Cummings, William H. Douglas, Harold L. Edwards, Roy W. Pratt, Eldon M. Pryar, Earl Gash, Harold H. Hager, Elmer L. Johnson, John F. Kaster, Forrest W. Mills, Frank M. Neely, Howard E. Nebsit, Robert L. Polley, Bert Spencer, James E. Turnquist, Roy C. HEADQUARTERS COMPANY, Ist INFANTRY, N. S. G. Captain Raymond Talbot Captain Fred Hamilton Captain W. Matthews Captain Hubert Owen * First Lieutenant James Barrett First Lieutenant Arthur Martin First Lieutenant Varro Rhodes Second Lieutenant Edwin Bumpus Second Lieutenant Samuel Black First Sergeants (Grade I) , Lintzman, Daniel Master Sergeants (Grade I) Farris, Thomas J. Sherman, Paul G. Simpson, Roy R. Technical Sergeants (Grade II) Baker, Charles 0. Fenner, Bernard A. Meier, Harold L. Thornton, Aden C. </seg>
         <seg id="p036">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Tretlak, Isadore M. Staff Sergeants (Grade III) Basonek, Charles S. Benecke, Walter A. Henderson, Lee H. Pazlat, Frank Fried el, Sam M. HEADQUARTERS COMPANY, Ist INFANTRY, N. S. G. Sergeants (Grade IV) Gallup. Charles A. Higgins, Marcus E. Jenks, Chester K. Kennedy, Francis P. McGee, Carl W. Madgett, Donald M. Summers, Tilford W. Welch. Lawrence W. Corporals (Grade V) Dahl, Ralph A. Leßaugh, Edwin W. Leonard, Joseph M. Mungall, Ross G. Sip, Richard J. Toulborg, Paul G. Wegner, Verlyn D. Privates First Class (Grade VI) Cox, James E. Ledyard, Edmund J. Metzsch, Howard F. Petersen, Donald E. Privates (Grade VII) Anzalone, Joseph Collier, Robert K. Deane, Norman P. Duffy, Matthew C. Dworak, Henry J. Privates (Grade VII) Ervin, Paul H. Gillette, Earl L. Graham, Delos A. Hemmingway, Edwin W. Hohaus, Charles C. Hultman, Roy T. 34 </seg>
         <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Kious, Lee Klever, Charles F. Mooney, Joseph T. Sherman, Sol Shipley, Harold L. Smith, Sidney J. Tesar, Frank Werner, Thomas J. Whltesldes, Dwlght E. MEDICAL DETACHMENT, Ist INFANTRY, N. S. G. Lt. Colonel Tenney Harris Major Rolland Ensor Captain William Hamsa Captain George Hageman Second Lieutenant Luther Thompson First Sergeant (Grade I) Olson, Le Roy V. Staff Sergeants (Grade III) Bernard, Harold F. Koch, Frank H. Sergeant (Grade IV) Foral, Martin F. Corporals (Grade V) Hallgren, Ralph H. Nash, Walter J. Rase, Roger Y. Tedesco, Merle Privates First Class (VI) Lane, Lawrence V. Kologenski, Henry L. Sudyka, Lawrence A. Privates (Grade VII) Barry, Frank A. Benis, Joe S. Binder, Thomas W. Bowers, Edward E. Cowan, Charles G. Privates (Grade VII) Dagosta, James V. DeWitt, George E. Mair, Clayton A. Peterson, Lester R. Quinlan, Joseph J. Quinlan, William J. 35 </seg>
         <seg id="p038">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Ramsey, Claude J. Singer, Louis Soukup, George W. Stoysich, Rudy F. Upah, John E. HEADQUARTERS, Ist BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Lt. Colonel Clarence T. Spier Major Ben F. Knuth Captain Irving W. Benolken Captain Richard E. Baliman \ Captain Lawrence I. Shaw COMPANY "A", Ist BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Captain William D. McHugh, Jr. First Lieutenant Adlai J. Rhoades Second Lieutenant Stanley F. Kuncl First Sergeant Montgomery, Clifford C. Technical Sergeant Goetz, Harry Sergeants Linke, Richard J. Musgrave, Roy 1. Woosley, Floyd Corporals Boyd, Wlllard C. Coffin, Charles B. Harrington, Howard W. Munson, Allan V, Searle, Ben L. Tanga, James J. First Class Privates Marer, Jack W. Raddle, Ernest W. Soukup, Frank J. Privates AUgood, Adrian A. Allgood, Donald E. Barras, Charles F. Boand, Clifford E. Privates Cannaday, Edward L. Cameron, Horace A, 36 </seg>
         <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Coniglio, Paul P. Dahlstrom, Bert T. Edward, John T. Fellman, Louis Ferguson, Carl H. Finiff, John Freed, Schoal Giller, Hyman Goode, Morrison Herbaugh, Harold E. Hornsteln, Julius Johnson, Melvln G. Lewis, Delbert J. Livingston, Richard M. Mallett, Beryl W. McCabe, Roy M. McCullough, Hugh H. McMullen, Kenneth D. Mlddleton, George E. Mlddleton, Virgil S. Michael, Floyd M. Moore, Harry E. Roberts, James Robinson, John P. Privates Rosenthal, J. L. Schiefelbeln, Leonard L. Sheridan, Philip J. Splegal, Richard H. Stautfacher, Benjamin W. Thomas, David N. Townsend, Richard 0. Travnicek, James J. Umatum, Fred A. Vmble, Howard L. Underwood, Orvllle A. Vorel, Charles A. Wainwright, Gordon R. Wine, Ben Wharton, Joseph Wheeler, George H. Wright, Lloyd L. Sahn, Otto H. Zorlnsky, Hymle Fitch, Glenn C. 37 </seg>
         <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY "B", Ist BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Captain Alfred G. Ellick, Jr. First Lieutenant Robert J. Blttner Second Lieutenant William B. Loring Sergeants (Grade I) Byrne, John J. Sergeants (Grade II) Scheer. Carl E. Sergeants (Grade IV) Bradford, Dana C. Fradenburg, William J. Hugglns, Warren E. Jones. Samuel E. Malashock, Lloyd G. Sales, Blrchel M. Corporals (Grade V) Berman, Leo Comlne, Lawrence Cooke, John L. Llndley, Thomas I. Moran, John A. Rathsack, Victor H. Webster, Wendell E. Privates (Grade VI) Abts, Lawrence J. Allgaler, Jack C. Braymen, Lawrence W. Hepler, Clifford W. Iske, Robert D. Lyman, Edward W, McManus, Leo G. Madison, Richard L. Nowlnskl, Max Owen, Edward F. Trebllcock, Robert W. Wellman, Walter R. Privates (Grade VII) Adams, Robert K. Balrd, William 3. Barata, Anthony J. Baughman, Charles R. Byrne, Charles F. Carden, Hubort C. Chrlstlanson, Fredrick W. Conlgllo, Joe 9, 38 </seg>
         <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Culllson, William A. Draney, Cecil C. Dutton, Charles M. /-Fenstermacher, David S Fischer, Anker E. Privates (Grade VII) Goltl, Martin F. Gross, Lawrence G. Hall, Robert J. Hansen, Clayton L. Hutcheson, William 3. Hydock, Leonard E. Ireland, George C. Jensen, Roy H. Mclntyre, Robert D. Mitchell, Stuart R. Nathan, Julian Newton, Clarence L. Nigro, Alfred J. Novak, Edward J. O'Brien, William T. Palmesano, Anthony J. Parllman, Morris Pavelka, Joe W. Rhoden, Carl M. "-., Saup, Marshall W. Seka, Sam R, Sterba, Joseph J, Tvrdy, Joseph F. Walander, William J. Westln, Clifton Jr. Wolfson, Harold Y. Zerbe, Donald F. HEADQUARTERS, 2nd BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Lt. Colonel Marion F. Mulvnney Major Alexander McKle, Jr. Captain John M. Douglas Captain Albert E. May Captain Walter S. PeterHon Captain Harvey A. Smith COMPANY "E", 2nd BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Captain Tlmon H. Dawson First Lloutonant Eugone P. Melady Jr. 39 </seg>
         <seg id="p042">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Second Lieutenant Stuart P. Benson Sergeants (Grade I) Welch, Paul G. Sergeants (Grade II) Pierce, Albert E. Sergeants (Grade IV) Bassett, Loren G. Flynn, William E. Fredericksen, Ralph Friedman, Philip Lair, Harry H. Strell, Philip A. Corporals (Grade V) Cameron, Winfred K. Gazlnskl, Robert J. Gaube, Erneßt H. Mlejnek, Victor R. Retynski, John R. Round, Dudley J. Scharp, Arnold Privates First Class f Grade VI) Allen, Marion F. Bone, Donald J. Collins, James E. Dokulil, Lawrence E. Donnelly, Leo F. Fuxa, Anton GranlewBki, Frank H. Little, Ivan K. Mlejnek, Frank J. Peterson, Leon B. Quintaro, Salvadore Schlotzhauer, Ellis R. Stilen, Frank Svendsen, Carl F. Usher, Howard G. Yanovich, William B. Privates (Grade VII) Badami, Henry A. Banark, Adam Bozman, Dan W. Calver, Robert W. Cole, Harry E. Cox, Earl T. Craney, John L. Davis, Frank J. 40 </seg>
         <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Davis, John P. Ekborg, Donald R. Ellas, Ellas J. Fellman, Joe Garrett, George W. Gendelman, Hymie Guilfoyle, Michael F. Lofflin, William'H. Kelly, Kerwood M. Maher, Donald H. Moshler, Frederick D. Peterson, Irving L. Sund, Roland L. Svoles, Gregory H. Swanson, John I. Trautman, Herman A. Vincent, Thomas P. Swanson, Russell J. COMPANY "F", 2nd BATTALION, Ist INFANTRY Captain Irving M. Sorensen First Lieutenant Chris J. Jensen Second Lieutenant Robert M. Young First Sergeant (Grade I) Peters, Hugh C. Sergeants (Grade IV) Conlan, James P. Olson, Clarence S. Orlando, Tony Seipel, Carl W. Warner, Charles W. Young, Kenneth O. Corporals (Grade V) Davis, Robert A. Hagerman, George M. Holmes, James C. Miller, Orrin W. Shafer, Ward G. Swigert, Warren R. Privates First Class (Grade VI) Bandiera, Joseph B. Fetters, Rea L. Fields, Lloyd R. George, Alfred L. George, Everett H. 41 </seg>
         <seg id="p044">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Gillaspey, Elmer G. Hough, Jack K. Privates First Class (Grade VI) Kaspar, Richard J. Lewon, John W. Moscrey, Salvatore P. Paddock, Miner D. Phelan, James F. Whitney. Elmer L. Privates (Grade VII) Ballinger, Wesley R. Brande), Frank Browne, James A. Browne, James E. Cady, Eugene W. Cain, George Jr. Capellupo, Peter Carlson, Anthony B. Coburn. LaVerne C. Coffman, Jack V. Eklund, Clarence S. Friedman, Wiliard I. Gillogly, Wade L. Hnetkovsky, Frank Johnson, Louis W. Kaspar, Donald C. Privates (Grade VII) Kocourek, Josef Kostkan, Jerry Larsen, Maynard Lawrence, Dale Ludwig, Floyd E. McKaln, James R. Milder, Myron R. Miller, Asa Mueller, Edward 0. Neal, Marvin C. Nowaczyk, John C. Olsen, Peter A. Sawatski, James J. Shields, Robert E. Smogye, John Thatcher, Howard H. Wolf, Joseph P. 42 </seg>
         <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL CIVILIAN DEFENSE Under date of 27 June 1942, Governor Griswold appointed the Adjutant General Commander of the Nebraska Citizens Defense Corps, composed of the following Civilian Defense Units: Wardens Division Auxiliary Police Auxiliary Firemen Public Works Public Utilities Emergency Medical Division Emergency Mortuary Division At the request of th e Commanding General, Seventh Service Command, Governor Griswold appointed the Adjutant General as Controller of the Nebraska Warning Sub Area for the Nebraska Air Raid Warning System on 7 July 42. Instructions were received from the Central Defense Command to perfect the organization of an Air Raid Warning System for Nebraska immediately. Provisions were made for the establishments of an Air Raid Warning Service by General Order No. 3, Headquarters Central Defense Command. 23 June 1942. The Area Warning Center at Omaha was activated pursuant to General Order No. 42, Headquarters Seventh Corps Area 11 July 1942. Accordingly, preliminary plans for the Nebraska Air Raid Warning Service were prepared and submitted to the Director of the Internal Security Division, Seventh Service Command, and were approved under date of 14 August 1942. The plans for the Air Raid Warning Service provided for establishing a Sub-Area Warning Center at Lincoln, thirteen dis - trict warning centers, based on the District set-up of the Nebraska Advisory Defense Committee, fifty-four sub-district warning centers, and approximately five hundred fifty local warning centers. The tentative communications plan was presented to the North - western Bell Telephone Company of Omaha, and the Lincoln Tele - phone and Telegraph Company for the purpose of checking with their toll circuits to secure the most efficient service possible. The Sub-Area Warning Center was organized and established in Lincoln, early In August of 1942, and the thirteen district warning </seg>
         <seg id="p046">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL centers were established at the same time, all operating on a twenty-four hour basis. Organization of the fifty-four sub-district warning centers began August 15 and was completed by September 15. All Warning Centers were operating with twenty-four hour service. The Nebraska Air Raid Warning Service received its first White Test" warning message on 11 September 1942, which va transmitted to all district warning centers in seventeen minutes after eceipT Thereafter. "White Test" warning messages were received ,TZ 'rate of one or two per week, both day and night messages being received. Average transmittal time to District Warning Centers has been approximately ten minutes on each test. Details relative to the Nebraska Air Raid Warning Service are elassme as "Restricted", which precludes the publication of ad - it ona information, other than the fact that the organization of he sy tern made provision for the rapid and efficient transmission of Air Raid Warning messages to every incorporated city, town, and village in Nebraska. SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who participated in th e service of the Spanish-American War in the First. Second and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop X, Third Volunteer Cavalry: COMPANY A—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name A„.t IDue Pvt Bye. Joseph G *3.2u Pvt. Gelvin, Robert N $3 20 Pvt Allen. Roller C 3.2-1 Pvt. Kremer, Cochran A 400 &#132;v t. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 Pvt. Sommers Nels J^. 3.20 Pvt. Morgenstern. Henry A. 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W^ 3.20 Pvt. Shivelv. Bion 3.20 Pvt. Wompler, Elmer B 3.20 Pvt. Freeman, Charlie 0 3.20 COMPANY IV— FIRST REGIMENT ,unk Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Gannger. Albert 80 Pvt. Ki.lhom Perry A. ... 4.00 , p vl . Black. John 400 Pvt. Ressekuie, Herbert L... 4.00 Pvt. Grainger. Louis I 1-60 </seg>
         <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY C—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rani Name Amt, Due Pvt. Johnson, Hans 3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 320 COMPANY D—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt, Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Alley, John S 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John *4 00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J. 400 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 COMPANY E—FIRST REGLMEXT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B 1.60 Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 320 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W 3.20 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Bays, Wm 80 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Moffett. Jesse C....... 320 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 COMPANY F—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt Due Sgt. Callagher, Joseph P 3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvln W 320 Cpl. Sims. Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E. 3 2 0 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua ' 320 Cpl. Fell. Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D.. "3 20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E.. ' 320 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F. 320 Pvt. Davidson. Houston 3.20 Pvt. Webb. Frank 320 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 COMPANY G—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 320 Pvt. Dowis Jonathan E 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 320 Pvt. Underwood, Henry C... 3.20 COMPANY H—FIRST REGLMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt. Due j Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H 3.20 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C... 400 Pvt. Dawson. Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 400 Pvt. Downing, Edward 5... 4.00 Pvt. Smith, George J 400 Pvt. Mansker. James F 3.20 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 160 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Seeley. F. Homer... 240 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 Pvt. Wlnagel. Anthony J. 240 </seg>
         <seg id="p048">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY I—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Hotel, Leon V 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J 4.00 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 COMPANY X—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. DeLong, Herbert B lib Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N 3.20 COMPANY I-—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due. Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Downs, James W 3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt Green. Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey. Mort. B 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H... 3.20 COMPANY M—FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W 3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin A 3.20 Cpl. Rucker. Winifred L 3.20 Pvt. Jack, Cecil B 3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 KIELD AND STAFF—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due P.M. Brown, Robert 3 4.00 Mus. Murnhouse, F. Edd 4.00 COMPANY A—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupernell. Ernest H 3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Pain, Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned X 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T... 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles 3.20 </seg>
         <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY R—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Whitmer, James X 3.20 Pvt. Briggs Ernest G Wag. Crow, Wallance H 3.20 (Died 'in service)'. 320 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank... 320 Pvt. Smith, Frank A 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Eli A 320 Art. Grossett, Chas. E 3.20 COMPANY C—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Miles, George 3.20 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 320 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 160 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larch A 3.20 Pvt. Kime, David 160 Pvt. Lee, Ira E 3.20 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E 160 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, John H 320 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R 3.20 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester 160 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 COMPANY D—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A 4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 400 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E."" i.QO Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M. 400 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 COMPANY F—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick 3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 320 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 320 Pvt. Alexander, Chas., W 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 320 Pvt. Dahiem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COMPANY F—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Auit. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton, George 3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 320 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchel, Harry D 480 </seg>
         <seg id="p050">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY G—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2nd Lt Hodgins, Eli 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T 80 Cpl. Hays, Robert A 3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S 80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F 80 Pvt. Blenkiron. Harry V 80 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H &amp;n pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L 80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 3.20 Pvt Fisher, Leo &gt;&gt;0 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E 80 Pvt. Gainey, John H 80 Pvt. Ritter, David 80 Pvt. Horn, George L.. Jr.. .i%O Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D 80 COMPANY H—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Borland, John A 4.00 Pvt. Johnston, George H... 4.00 Art. Nlell, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Ahvah 4.00 Pvt. Bowers. Henry H 4.00 Pvt. Meltner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 4.00 Pvt. Davis. Harry E 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Serensen, Ole C 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry 0 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 4.00 COMPANY I—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Nam e Amt. Due QM Sgt. Rainey Jacob A.. 4.00 Pvt. Schuelke, Herman A... 4.00 Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore.... 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. Walker, Joseph H 4.00 Pvt. Penland, John W 80 Pvt. Way, Rueben D 4.00 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 COMPANY X—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T 3.20 Pvt. West, Charles 3.20 Cpl. Hill, John T 3.20 COMPANY L—SECOND REGIMENT Ra-.ik Name Amt. Due Hank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Jack. Charles H 2.40 Pvt. Cottrell, Eugene W... 3.20 Pvt. Clarenden, Alvin T 4.00 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Leonard, Wm. C 80 Cpl. Sage, John M 3.20 Pvt. Powell, Joseph A 3.20 Wag. Bauman. John P 4.00 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Abel. Louis 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 </seg>
         <seg id="p051">I REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY M—SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Alfreds, Frank H 5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm 5.60 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W... 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncan C 5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 FIELD STAFF AND BAND—THIRD REIGMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, R0y.... 9.60 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L. 12.00 COMPANY A—THIRD REGIMENT ** V. Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Anlt Due QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W...32.55 pyt Gray Burton E .... 2 .40 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 pyt Hinckley&gt; J(mn 3 1.60 Cpl. Steinbach. George 12.72 pyt Hurstt Arthur J 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Mathew 1.60 pyt KoontZi Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. Marksbury. Thos. N 1.60 pyt Lee Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 pvt Q'Leary, John J 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt Pace perle R 2.40 Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 pvt Reynolds, j o hn A 1.60 Art. Ball. Wm. A 18.39 Pvt Schneider. Wm 2.40 Pvt. Allen, Thomas 4.80 Pvt Smith, John J 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 Pvt Taylor, James J 2.40 Pvt. Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt Trombley, Ward., A.F. 18.39 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr... 2.40 COMPANY R—THIRD REGIMENT i 1 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. Keanes, James N 80 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. Whales, Edwin F 3.20 Pvt. Bradford, George H 80 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas 80 Pvt. McGrew, Frank 80 Pvt. Custer, Ellsha 80 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W...33.64 Pvt. Francisco, John H 80 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt. Roop, Scott 0 80 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N 80 Pvt. Habbick, George W 1.60 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 Pvt. Jarvis, Chas T 80 </seg>
         <seg id="p052">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY C —THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Cpl. Dillion, Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip 2.40 Cpl. Miller. Wm. E 27.4 6 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P 8.58 Cpl. Burket, Harry B 2.40 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Pvt. Henske, Fred 80 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W...27.45 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Hlleman, Robert E 27.46 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F 2.40 Pvt. Howell, Harry H 22.74 Pvt.' Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Keliher. John F 4.80 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.30 l'vt. Long. Wilbur W 5.75 Pvt. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Mitchell. Edward F 2.40 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albin F 2.40 Pvt. Zurubsky, James 7.64 COMPANY D—THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt Reynolds. Walter D 4.80 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry 1.60 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 4.80 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B 26.74 Pvt. Allwein, John C 1.60 Cpl. Christensen. Pvt. Anderson, Edward 4.00 Christian A 36.18 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew 3.20 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Mus. Howell, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M 8.00 Pvt. Jansen. Nels P 23.91 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G 8.00 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C 80 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Roble, Ernest 4.80 COMPANY E—THIRD REGIMENT Itunk Name Amt, Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Slddell, Bert E 13.01 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L 80 Pvt. Lewln. Samuel C 80 COMPANY F—THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Baughman, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Olson, Chris 80 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 </seg>
         <seg id="p053">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Kment. Joe 1.60 Pvt. Karges, John 36 69 Pvt. Knott, Fred 80 Pvt. Sarre, Alfred H. 80 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 160 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Underbill, Charles.. 36 69 Pvt. Nicholson, James 1.60 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 COMFANY G—THIRD REGIMENT Rank Same Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Larson. Felix G 29.72 Pvt. Foreman, Oscar 29 72 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S 29.72 Pvt. Fuller, Guy W 160 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Howard, Edward.... 29 72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt. Larson, Axel W.... 29 72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac 80 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29 72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William 4'ou Pvt. Conner, Clement T 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A.... 29,2 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 COMPANY H—THIRD REGIMENT Hank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Headwell, Axel 31.09 Pvt. Robinson, Edward. '3 20 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N 6.55 Pvt. Thomas, James T... 3*20 Pvt. Lelchty, John 6.55 Pvt. Matson, Albert 5 6 0 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T 31.09 COMPANY I—THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name An.t Due Sgt. Derienger. George 36.61 Pvt. Brown. Frank H '4 00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry D.S. 37.56 Pvt. Carrol, John W. 4 ' o o Cpl. Dickenson, John W 12.07 Pvt. Center. Albert. 480 Cpl. Felts, William B 6.40 Pvt. Dlnsmore, Claude "rZ 924 Cp . Jensen. Chris M 4.00 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander 320 Cpl. Meyer. Otto 4.00 Pvt. Falrchlld, Homer 160 Wag. Brett, Zinc H 22.45 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A..: Pvt. Jones, Lloyd 0 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 160 Pvt. Miller. Fred S 9.24 Pvt. Hanks, Harry E 0 Pvt: Padol. Adam 8 0 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A..'.'."" 924 aw S rry'„ ChaB E U-12 PVL Palmer ' Arc^^d G.'....5'.60 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W...23.40 Pvt. Roberts, James W 924 Pvt. Aitken. George F 37.56 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus "Vbb Pvt. Baird, Francis H 4.80 Pvt. Stonef John GZ" 400 Pvt. Bersley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Swan, Richard B JJ Pvt. Vandyke, John T. 6.40 Pvt. Warrington, Albert J...2.40 </seg>
         <seg id="p054">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY X—THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Ist Sgt. Jacobsen, Carl L...34.29 Pvt. Mines, James S 1.60 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N...34.29 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H 80 Pvt. Porterfleld, James A...34.29 Pvt. Cofield. Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Roardon, Patrick J 2.40 Pvt. Hlghtower, Harry A 2.40 Pvt. Roff, John L 29.57 Pvt. Kennedy. George H 7.20 Pvt. Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kankright. Clinton D. 27.68 Pvt. Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Pvt. Kruger, Wm 80 Pvt. Van Sickle, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. Mathews, Stanley 30.52 Pvt. Williams, Wm. M 1.60 Pvt. McCaulley, Wm. G 1.60 COMPANY L—THIRD REGIMENT RankNNav e Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Nicholson. Chas. J 4.00 Pvt. Kelley, Robert S 6.40 Cpl. Taft. Charles C 21.01 Pvt. McColl, John 14.00 Wag. Stockton, Andrew 32.34 Pvt. McCormick, Benj. D... 8.00 Pvt. Krltsch, Herman 6.40 Pvt. Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H... 5.60 Pvt. Lee, Justivin E 1.60 Pvt. Bradshaw, Thomas H. 5.60 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A 21.01 Pvt. Burns. James E 3.20 Pvt. Mardock, John E 1.60 Pvt. Chisolm, Ralph 0 5.60 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Redfield. Cyrus R 4.80 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. Rundus, Frank 32.34 Pvt. Athos. Andrew G 27.62 Pvt. Sherry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Black. Wm 2.40 Pvt. Swanson, Nels 32.34 Pvt. Fox, Ernest S 24.79 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Pvt. Walker, Chas 27.62 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E... 6.40 COMPANY M —THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt. Hensel Wm. A 2.40 Pvt Foster, John E 4.00 Pvt. Klelnsmith, Morris 35.38 Pvt. Bennett, Ntles 21.22 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H 17.44 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Maddan Chas 35.38 Pvt. Brewick. Andrew T 3.20 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E 11.78 Pvt. Cantello John 10.84 Pvt. Ratekin Janson L 80 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Pvt. Timmons Alfred D 34.44 Pvt. Heisler, Robert D 80 Pvt. Wiesman Jacob 2.40 Pvt. Foster Frederick W 17.44 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A...13.60 Pvt Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Alley, Franc 2.40 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 Pvt. Beardsley Wm. S 80 Pvt. Johnson John D 13.60 </seg>
         <seg id="p055">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL TROOP X— THIRD CAVALRY Rank Name Anit. Due Hank Name Amt. Duu Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter.... 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger, Claude G...2.40 It !s recommended that thin list be given a circulation In the newspapers of the State with a vle«- to locating such of these men as possible. . * </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>