<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Forage Crops</title>
               <date value="1918-12">1918-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">UulkiM 169 Otsmhti, I9IN Forage Crops r A, hll'.xwl.l.iiw il AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. U. S. A. » I ruifM MahfMtM'a iir-ntm 1ur»*» rrup </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA Honorable E. P. Brown, President, Davey. Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln. Honorable Frank L. Haller, Omaha. Honorable Victor U. I.vi ohu, Fall* City. Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Honorable Harry I). Lamms, Seward TIIK NTATION "I I l&lt; Ml- Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. Burnett, D. Sc., Director. CHAB. E. Gunnels, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service. J. 8. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. C. A. LEWIS, B. SC., Bulletin Editor. THK WOKKIMi HTAKI- F. W. UP8ON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. 'L. W. CHASE, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineer inn. W. W. BURR, B. Sc., Agronomy, T. A. KIE88ELBACH, A M., Agronomy. H. J. GRAML1CH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. L. VAN Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene. H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Animal Pathology. J. H. FRAND8EN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. SWENK, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. HOWARD, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead WlLCOX, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Subnotion, North Platte. JAMES Cowan, M.E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. *L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. 'G. K. K. Link, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart - ment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Granted leave of absence. • lit- UOVBBMIMtl iiiiakii Till: REOKHTM »Y TIIK 1 NIVKKKITY) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTKNTH P»M Classification of forage cropn ii Importance of forage crop* in Nebraska ■ r i 8eedinjf and care of pasture* in Nebraska 6 Permanent paiturei a Perennial pasture plant* in Nebraika ... 6 (ir:iKhi-N 6 I&gt;etrumcN ♦; Chief characteristics of perennial pasture plant* 6 Brome grass ,. g Orchard grass 7 Meadow fescue 7 Kentucky blup Kraii 7 Red top Timothy 7 Canada blue itra»* , . % Tall meadow oat gran h Western wheat grraii 8 Alfalfa 8 Red clover 8 AUike clover 9 White clover 10 Sweet clover 10 Pasture mixtures 12 Eastern Nebraska 13 PaRture mixture for normal soil 13 Pasture mixture for low and very wet or overflowed ground 13 Pasture mixture for thin clay soils 1!? Pasture mixture for sandy soils 14 Pasture mixture for shady places 15 Temporary pasture mixtures 15 Central and western Nebraska IS Pasture mixture for normal soils in central Nebraska and for irrigated or subirrigated soils in western Nebraska 15 Time of seeding pastures 16 Seed bed preparation 17 Manner of seeding 17 Seeding with or without a nurse crop 18 Pasture management 18 Renewing worn-out pastures 18 Annual pasture crops 18 19 Rape 20 Rye Oats 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Seeding and care of hay crops in Nebraska 21 Permanent meadows 21 Alfalfa 21 Seed bed for alfalfa 22 Time of seeding alfalfa 22 Use of nurie crop with alfalfa 22 Rate and manner of seeding 22 Harvesting of alfalfa hay 23 Timothy and clover. _ *. 24 Redtop and alsike clover 26 Brome grass 25 Annual hay crops _ 26 Sorghum 26 Millet - 27 Sudan grass ....28 Oats and field peas 29 Oats and field peas * 2f Soybeans and cowpeas ...30 Hairy vetch 30 Silage _ 81 Silage crops and varieties 31 Culture of Corn for Silage 31 Harvesting 31 Soiling crops * 82 Root crops for stock feed 82 Mangels 32 Sugar beets 32 Forage crop yields at the Experiment Station during three years, 1915 to 1917 33 Comparative yields of perennial and annual forage crops, 1915 and 1916 33 Comparison of three methods of planting annual forage crops, 1915, 1916 and 1917 34 Rate of seeding test with Black Amber sorghum and Sudan grass for forage, 1915, 1916 and 1917 81 Forage test of different kinds of millet, 1916 and 1917 35 Effect of the number of cuttings on the yield of alfalfa hay, 1915 to 1918 3« </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FORAGE CROPS BY T. A. hlt"MIUUI The purpose of this bulletin is to give information which will assist the farmer in solving his forage problems. Forage crops adapted to Nebraska conditions are briefly described and the cultural practices best suited to their production are given. The comparative yields of various forage crops at the Experi - ment Station during the three years, 1915 to 1917, are com - piled in tables at the end of the bulletin. CLASSIFICATION OF FORAGE CROPS Forage crops consist of those plants which are grown pri - marily for their vegetative parts, to supply roughage for animals. These plants may be grouped according to the special purpose for which they are grown as follows: 1, pas - ture; 2, hay; 3, silage; 4, soiling; and 5, root crops. Accord - ing to their length of life these are known as: 1, annuals; 2, biennials and 3, perennials. The perennials, which under proper treatment may live for many years, should be planted largely for permanent pastures and meadows. Biennials, with a life period of only two years, are rather temporary crops except where so handled as to permit natural reseeding and thereby maintain a continuous stand of plants. Annuals are one season crops and are grown altogether for temporary use. These may be either fall or spring annuals, according to whether they require seeding in the fall or spring. Nearly all forage crops also fall into the three groups — legumes, grasses, and roots. Legumes and grasses include most forage plants. IMPORTANCE OF FORAGE CROPS IN NEBRASKA The following data in table No. 1 indicate approximately the acrea«e prown in Nebraska in 1915 of the three principal grain crops and of the principal forage crops. The 191 5 acre - age represents normal conditions as existed prior to the time when the war and the severe winterkillinsr of certain crops had produced an abnormal apportionment of the different crops. The yield per acre and value are given for onlv part of the forace crops in the 1916 Annual Renort of the Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 State Board of Agriculture, from which the data were com - piled. Forage crops are seen to occupy an important, place in Nebraska agriculture. Table 1. Showing Acreage of Principal Nebraska Grain and Forage Crops in 1915* Grasses — The principal perennial grasses suitable for Ne - braska are: 1, brome grass; 2, orchard grass; 3, meadow fes - cue ; 4, Kentucky blue grass ; 5, redtop ; and 6, timothy. Grasses of minor importance are : 1, Canada blue grass ; 2, tall meadow oat grass ; 3, western wheat grass ; 4, wood meadow grass ; and 5, slender wheat grass. Legumes — The important perennial pasture legumes are: 1, alfalfa; 2, red clover; 3, alsike clover; 4, white clover; and 5, sweet clover. Altho red clover and sweet clover are bi - ennial crops living for but two years, they are, in this bulletin, included with the perennials for convenience. CII1KF &lt; IIAKACTKBIHTU'M OF I'KKKN N l.\ I. IMKTIKK PI.ASTH Brome Grass (Bromun inermix) — Brome grass starts grow - ing very early in the spring and grows thruout the season ex - cept when extremely dry and hot. It is deen-rooted and forms a compact «od. It stands drouth well and often produces some pasturage when other presses are dried tin or cease growing. In palatability, brome grass ranks very high. Yield ToUl Crop Avcram ptraer* production I'rie ■ VbIiw Am. H.-nh.l, /(«./,,/« Ih.llu,. 1 1, liar. Corn 6,990,0:u :i2.fl 228,094,7:16 .50 114,047,368 Wintrr wheat 3,416/130 19.7 67,320,448 .HO 5:S,8f&gt;6,358 OnU 2,125,179 154.7 73.704,462 .28 20,654,049 Tons Torn Alfulfa 1,191,310 iM 4,088,598 6.00 24,5:11,588 Wild hay 2,635,46:1 1.18 3,132,219 6.00 18,793,314 Sonrhum 120,576 Millet 101,263 Timothy 168,686 Blue KraKH 5X5.194 Clover 95,246 Other tame jrra«i.... 386,000 1 &lt; 'umpi ril fnim lh» 1*16 Annual Report of th« Ncbruks 8UU Board of Avrieul- tun. SEEDING AND CARE OF PASTURES IX NEBRASKA PERMANENT PASTURES </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Forage Crops 7 Orchard Grass — Orchard grass starts early in the spring and grows rapidly. It is rather deep-rooted, drouth-resistant, and endures shade better than the other common grasne*. Where great heat frequently complicates drouth as is especi - ally the case in south central and southwestern Nebraska, orchard grass i« at least as hardy as brome grass tho less pala - table. It is a bunch grass rather than sod-forming, but this quality is not very objectionable when it is sown with a mix - ture of sod-forming grasses. Meadow Fencue — Meadow fescue commences spring growth about the same time as the Kentucky blue grass and continues till late in the fall. It is somewhat bunchy in habit but not so much so as orchard grass and forms better sod. It is a rival of timothy in speed of getting started from the seed. Like orchard grass, meadow fescue is rather heat-resistant. This grass is palatable and nutritious, but apparently not as pala - table as brome grass and blue grass. Kentucky Blue Grants — Kentucky blue grass is a long-lived shallow-rooted grass which forms a dense but shallow sod. It is one of the most palatable and nutritious of grasses. Blue graps may be pastured very early in the spring as well as late in the fall, but it ordinarily provides the least amount of pas - ture in July and August of any of the standard grasses. It is the running mate of white clover. Once it has established itself this grass is very aggressive and in time crowds out other grasses almost completely. For this reason and because of the high price and poor germination of seed, and slow develop - ment of the plant, blue grass should always be sown with other grasses and in very small quantities. Redtop Redtop is especially well adapted to low, wet, acid soil and thrives even where water stands occasionally. No other commonly cultivated grass will compare with it in this regard. It also does relatively well on sandy, gravelly, clayey, or other soils of low fertility where rainfall is fairly liberal or srround water is close to the surface. This grass starts rapidly from the seed and forms a very dense sod. Because of a rather low palatability, it should be grown only where its special adaptation is of importance, and where better pasture plants do not thrive. Redtop is the running mate of alaike clover. Timothy — Timothy is a rapid arrowing semi-bunch srrass. Because of the cheapness of seed and its rapid jrrowth in starting from the seed, it is usually desirable to include this grass liberally in pasture mixtures. The more permanent but </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 slower growing and more expensively seeded grasses will crowd out and largely replace the timothy in a few years, but in the meatime the timothy provides a large yield of pasturage. Timothy thrives on stubborn clayey soil and endures consider - able swampiness. It is the running mate of red clover. Canada Blue Grass — Canada blue grass is a sod-forming grass especially adapted for sandy and clayey soils of low fer - tility. Like redtop, it is somewhat lacking in palatability and should be used mainly where more palatable grasses do not thrive. In the meantime it acts as a soil up builder, till better grasses are able to start on the enrichened soil. Tall Meadow Oat Grass — Tall meadow oat grass is a bunch grass of value in this State only on sandy and gravelly soils. It is not very palatable but seems to be fairly drouth and heat resistant It makes a prolific growth but does not endure grazing as well as being used for meadow. Western Wheat Grass — Western wheat grass, sometimes erroneously called blue-stem and in some sections often called blue grama grass, is a native grass not yet brought under culti - vation but which gives promise of being well worthy of trial. It is a free-seeding, sod-forming, and fairly drouth resistant grass. According to Kearney, it is the most alkali resistant grass practicable to sow. Seed must ordinarily be secured locally from the plants growing wild. Unfortunately the seed usually germinates very poorly. The plant is also peculiarly subject to a fungous disease called "ergot," which forms black "ergot spurs" where the seed should be. Cattle eating liberal amounts of badly ergotized hay suffer from abortion and the loss of such body parts as ears, tails, and hoofs. Alfalfa — Alfalfa is a perennial legume not especially well adapted as pasture for cattle and sheep, altho it is recognized as admirably suited for hog pasture. It is injured by excess - ive tramping and close grazing and gradually kills out under such treatment. The grazing of horses and sheep (especially the latter) is particularly severe. It also frequently causes bloat in cattle and sheep, which danger can, however, be over - come by seeding only small quantities with grasses. Alfalfa may safely be pastured by horses, and is considered by many farmers as a satisfactory night pasture for them. Heavy tramping is apt to be injurious to alfalfa, especially on sandy ground when dry. Alfflfa is also injured by tramping on heavy unhumlfled clay when wet. Red Clover— Red clover when seeded alone is not very suit - able as a pasture plant except for hogs. Cattle and sheep </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Forage Crops 9 grazing on it are subject to bloat as with alfalfa. However, it should have a place in most pasture mixtures wherever it thrives. Altho a biennial plant with a life time of only two years, it commonly reseeds sufficiently to maintain a fairly continuous supply of clover plants where not pastured too closely. As is true with all legumes included in hay or pasture mixtures, red clover not only enriches the feeding value of the crop, but helps build up the soil as well. Red clover starts rapidly from the seed and is relatively drouth resistant. Tim - othy usually makes a good companion grass for red clover. Flu. 1 Medium rod clorer In full bloom. l"fl ; yllow itwl Hover In full lilm.iu, right. Photographed Jun« 21, 101ft; planted Annum 10. 1014 AUike Clover — Alsike clover is intermediate in growth habits between red and white clover. Its primary use in Ne - braska is an a pasture plant grown in a mixture of grasses, es - pecially on low, wet soil. Its soil adaptations are quite similar to those of redtop and the two should commonly be seeded to - gether. It also grows comparatively well on rather infertile ■oil. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nt'lmiHka Experiment Station Iliillctin 109 White Clover — Whit* clover in the most common of all pas - ture legumes. Like blue grass it gradually make* iu appear - ance in pastures even if not intentionally Heeded there. ThU clover spread* by itn prostrate stem* at well ait by need, and iU spread In rapid after It once ha* a start. For thin reason only imall quantities need be included in a pasture mixture. White clover in shallow rooted and usually dries up temporarily in mid-summer. It in the running mate of blue urn**. A pre - dominance of white clover in pastures in undesirable because It causes clobber* In horses, and bloating in cattle and nheep. Simt Clover — Hweet clover in the one legume which may be pastured rather satisfactorily with cattle and sheep when Headed alone. It ha* |u*t Htarted to come into prominence M a forage plant in Nebraska and the extent of Itn value in not fully known, altho it gives promise of \v&gt;**i&gt;**U\v consider - •ble value n* a paiiture crop, Uh advantage over alfalfa lief in Itn being far U&lt;** conducive to bloat in cattle and sheep. It cannot, however, be pastured with absolute safety, Mince occas - lonal caHM of bloat are reported, It \* commonly believed that blonl may be largely avoided by keeping the stock oft when the sweet clover Is wet with rain or dew. The natural life time of sweet clover In not reduced by nrn/,\uu i\* I* thnt of nirnlfn. To make good pasture the plant should be graced nufflclently close to prevent roars? growth, especially the second year, At the sam# time, If permanent pasture Is desired, care must be taken nut to grnxe the plant so closely after the first yeitr that an Insufficient &lt;|ii«ntHv of seed will be formed to reseed fur the following yenr, The ttermnnence of a sweet clover pnnture depend* entirely upon Its ability to reseed, bemuse the plnnts die at the end of the second year when they have produced seed. I 'nder judicious handling, this natural reseedlng ap* (renrs In be finite dependable Mnd a number of sweet clover pastures In tno state are known to have been pastured fur ft period n( sin years, Heeding during two consecutive years ftt the start has been recommended to provide Cor annual re seeding, and also fur continuous late and early pasture, If •own In the fall, sweet plover bears seed the following summer and then dies, Hweet clover has an unusually wide adaptation It thrlvwt tm doth relatively wet and drv soils, fertile and Infertile soil, ■ami? arid clayey soil, and both when seeded alone and when »e#d*d In a mixture with other pasture Hani* It may Ire </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Foruye Cropt 11 expected to grow wherever alfalfa grown and in addition upon land that in too infertile or too wet for alfalfa. It m aUo better ■uited to »oll* which are rather alkaline than in alfalfa. Since Mweet clover grown tall and muken a rather coarM growth unlfMK grazed c lonely it in commonly undesirable to include nmall quantltle* of Hweet clover Heed in paMture mix* turn. Our rather limited experience with thin crop at tht prenent time lead* um to recommend, an a general practice, ■weet clover for panture either alone or not at all. Unlenn pro - perly managed, cattle are apt to dinlike nweet clover and may treat it as a weed where other palatable legume* and grannen may be had. However, if one'* cattle are Known to have ac - quired a tante for xweet clover, it may be inrluded in panture mixture*. Whll*- the MUer t»«t« &lt;tf nw««t Hovtr Im ulUin &lt;,U)»'U&lt;m»h\» to i'nMI* which Mrf not iwv\tnUimt&gt;i\ to It, thin nwil l/y tut mean* \m Nfi iin»tirm&lt;nintMlil»' «lim« ■ultv If cmHI«* »•&gt;&lt;■ ininwil Into M •w»&gt;«&gt;l clover |m«liirp enr\y In (hn »|»»lnx whi«n IhD plafttH Mf« •till young *n&lt;l ♦♦'tiller ««il IHMo o«n»r grepn vxg«««»M&lt;)M ♦* t« »&gt;• li««l, they will readily Ml It and UMtmlly &lt;t*»v*«(&lt;»»» » •«r&lt;»»»ir Ilk Ing f»f It, Howiwrwl with alfalfa, *wM clover, whon noi (/»/. ••!»*»■•, iH-obahly &gt;im, |»omh&lt;I lor pound, m high feeiiinK value fir * »#•»&lt; Hn««&gt; (&lt;m(«f» ih K»'i(««M "»&gt;i«tr, mu </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Srlinitlrit Mtiiinhtinil Mlnlhm llnllilhi UlU 12 tm live »\m-k nihI In mm* rutriri In IiiiUiUm* up Mm- h^mmIc MIim IIi»&lt; I/NiiiImI *ltlt»&lt; i^ (lt« MkiuiIhI y*|jow iwH «'li»V*r UIN* Iff M««i f"f ffH*l IM *■ *l|!l hIkiuI M|UM| fMlli|« I lie HIIIHIhI fullo* *wcH wuviir muni, itowt«vi'P, !w Mvojimii Iiwnmm uiumr "IU NUUllll'in* II M|I|IHMM 1(1 Iff MftKMMMJlj^ ♦♦/(fllli^M jl I* (HI \iiitlhlU lit UttWl »'!l»Vf»' ■Kfll |»H( Ml'ff ftff'llfM i/K »i»WM, iMfMCfl- MM I" III* rHViiMMlWWMi «f |ilHfil Him (^»|(l!ll)/ll« Tim jl*im*l ■iiTdfi'l «f •wxd lifil |^»&lt;|m&gt;«ll»iii I* «ll«'f»MwJ mi \m\t» 17 I'fMIMIt NllimM 1(1 MHlf*' !(( •WUM l(Ml fMffll* rM»»M tWMttO'M II III VimutiU\t &gt;Im]mI«I*&lt; lu mkw m mlMuM »»r *m&gt;I l/i» IihHmm mw*\ ***••*• HM(| I^IOdM MMlflM |f|VM(M »i«»l»»»M)»l Vlnlll*, j(('»lw» »-d)i M(t«llMli« |((uv|i|« moM » ; M(i!llMK/if» MMAMttr&lt; M l»l(fl)i«f r»«»l vmImw, «(i»I unit* fMiiwWti miU vHM*, Tim •licit |/Imii(# *Im(mM Iw I»m-Ix»M If) (((UMO'M wlil^li MM Mi llixm«x|vx» »ikM |/(» (((»/• |»ll&lt;l Ml IfMl fMlH/ WkII »»(l«|/lx(l Iu III* HtHflllluti* IIM'(«F ; ll lIl^V »M' ■'/*♦!( TllMK •&gt;I((M|(| U «#(4«&lt;M (» »M» ; ll MIMfl M«*r Mi*f Him*' •kji|»Ii«mi*«&gt;i» ///i* mi\h*v Vn¥ nummn, m |&gt;m do* HiiftiHr* »h(i(M i»dil«iii lc»llt (|*»'|( mii«I MlmllMW »»»»»• nd | f |Mlll« *«»'l^ IHI* l«l* |fr»(**i»M If |&gt;««, «&gt;«•«*• Mll'l UuHIHt*, *Ul\ mi* »r mum m fnvmmu nr***** A&gt;i*\ti*unu Ui i)m tmnn *imI \nm\\v *i» \n Mi* »|iwl«l M'll »'*»(Mllli/»n nimi \m m\v*u i*mh\ viih»)t\mn\inh Tti* &gt;wl/»llv« «/&gt;»!■ &lt;&gt;&lt; •»«««&lt; In mIm&gt; m nwi&lt;»» - i» Mm \wwifl\nn "I Mm vmHohm MimU V«rK m» p*tmlv« »um\ »m(-Ii m Mim iff*** »&gt;mI whiU f|(»vi«r Nhoidiil Im m««&lt;|«iI In only v«ry »nmll (/owntitiM, »iim« Mm«f iilwxt* »t»rl from Mm tmi&gt;4 mo »\h*\v Miwt «( Imm&gt;i Mmy »'»»»m»i fm (l«i»»'»«l«&lt;i M|«ni lo urntiwm i\h\vU Mum* In im»ii«r«, »n&lt;l wuw Mmy »r« w»- Ui/lmli»&lt;/1, Mr« v«r| »tftfrwM»lv« *n&lt;i im»&lt;lw»llv hut Moruly r«|/l»w « i&gt;lh*r jirntuum, rlm«*n utrniU U\&gt;u Ifni&lt;/Miy cwn w*\l im utmimi vurv ft**\y. l''*w rt«l&lt;l» (♦»■«&lt; w»ijr«ly uniform m U&gt; »oil, »r«l wbur* * mlxturo of ly\m i» »own, flm vort \m*i m\n\tUn\ U&gt; th# vui iouM Mm!* of will IkikI Ui \irmnmUm\it Iburn, Th« folhwlnv iitmUtru m\*Utr*» *r* i*mIImI(I«« V&gt;r plHiilfnv u/i'i'i itic i»ttHi&lt;ii)«r i'/»n/||t !on» for which Mmv «r» i»ii&lt;^'«h»*4 Mrt'i rttf^Mfnt h minimum itmount of &lt;uut&lt;\ \wr m&gt;r* on * fnvor* m!/U&gt; »«««&lt;l l»wl Tlmiw combinMtionH n\ny im modlrt&lt;«1 uni&gt;ni\nii Ui h fHrrrmr'H «Kp*rmnti« with th« &lt; to|» un&lt;i«r hi« \mrtku\nr iiiin\\iUnt* Th« f&gt;rU»M rlmrirwl for th« n««4n vury from year Ui yunr And urn m«r«ly »uiryw»tfv&lt;i of ih« cotit of th« vnriowi* iw«tur« mixture, Th« t»wU Hr« rtgurwl on prt-wiir prifi««, </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Pttmi/0 I 'in /it 13 NA/ttMN *&lt;mmik I friHhui' Mlflutf fur Hntmut Hull in Muni tin Nfltmtltu jl *Sr 3fL Sffa. ' ■•fw M &lt;•#• /'«««* •( •f H »» » tf/ FhmIhi'* Ml* I m i fni 1,1111' inn! S'hiu W*l m th»iflnn'nl i ii urn iii i iii fthiohni NhluitMlm f ».,»„» WC Itff^ff^ tWP wttff0 wWft0f wWFW rf*^ 1 W WM Wf ' * wtfrtfHf ttf fwff fff wW^w WfWr I, I'iimIhii kin I ii it: Im Tli hi ('In it Hull* hi Minimi N»hiii*l-u m l&gt;,m.t, P,,*»4t HM'ii, IhMii, H4I, AUlk« »'|i«v«r K m, |/lm x«.« 41/ «W um, 4* «-/ Itlw vr»M I M 2M .17* l» Whiu *l'/v«i I 9flf *9*f £ftf '*™™F 'ff*f Ji*m\ *n»i nl minium p*r ui», %*l'l&gt; n ill ' %' /'"««» HUH* §HtM&gt; I'tiHKti p*)HHti I'jflM' r'tf/fl' 1'Mttt *H»t H( WitUtHl ffHf m*i WA* M A WhuAa. k-ii...Mi~J kgitim k*Mt iliimk ui MAI. iX-X^i F l.i.Uj tC.li.J »Mi. ..fc- -*/. I »&lt;&gt;. n«« t n \m m m/7 &lt;'•»«(• Mum uhum 't \\ tM U -» Al(*ifuur •wwrtvlww 'i </seg>
            <seg id="p014">4. Pasture Mixture for Thin Sandy Soils in Eastern Nebraska Mm4 Wright K.tcm«Ud Prte* p*r Coat of Crop* |.rr per prtu p« pound st M«d tor M» bu»h»l l.u.h.1 bMM rate on* wra Redtop fanuila blue gnu •A 14 2.00 .148 .43 Tall meadow oat grow 3 14 4.00 .286 M Brome gnu 5 14 2.50 .179 .89 Alfalfa or mveet clover 8 60 12.00 .200 .60 Total eoit of mixture per acre, $4.06. F»«m4 Pounds DotUr, PolUr. DalUrt 6 14 3.00 .214 1.28 r brOM ka bx penmen Station ",u, etin 109 'I I 1 w/4 i •5 « 1.11 c. 12 3 4 1 Klir. 3. — I*H»tur« gr»»«-ii of Ni-lirmiki &gt; Mi-mliiw fi-»riii-. (4) Timotbr. (6) t KrrniD. (7) lti-iltu|&gt;. i»i Wi-«ti-rn iiii'lu liliu- tfriimi anil wuoil nii-iiilnw u li-li luiti- ini&gt; liii|iurtiiii&gt;'i- for M-i-ilInu |i I « ii. II) K.lilu » In-lit ■«•« ii r it- nu u in I 7 SI Hruim- iiriiM. 121 Orilnii-il i •■ky lilui' i(r&lt;». 16) Tall in* Knu (ft) Kli'inli-r win-lit | m Hi-- inil&gt; "illn-r |M-ri-iiiil.il ur i-nt lumturm Id NVtirimkii. 0 KriiH. 1-illliiW KriiM. mxMwa </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forage Cropn 15 6. Pasture Mixture for Shady Placet in Eastern Nebraska lead W»l«ht K-tlmaUd Prtaeper Cost of Crop. price per poundat aaad tmr mi baehel bwaai buahet M&gt; on* Mr* hound* I mndt l),,IUir, Dollar, Doiiart Orrhunl jfra»x •J 14 3.00 .214 1.93 Wood meadow irra» Blue gran* 7.26 ..".I* 1.66 :&lt; 14 6 White clover 2 Total co»t of mixture per acre, $6.66. 6. Temporary Pasture Mixture for Eastern Nebraska' Hard WrlKht Ketlmat«l I'rlce prr Coat of price prr p'njfid st ■— d for |.&lt;-r acre liu-twl InKhVl buahel rat» on« u» Total coat of mixture per acre, $2.06. 'Thia »lmpU mixture U uwd v»ry »«u-n»lvrl&gt; fur Umpwrsry inuiurx of Z or &gt; r«*n duration In iut»rn Nrtir»ka. r'or pvrnuiiMmt p»tur«* • imtor vnridy of Inn* llvod pianu atHMiM b* nwd. CENTRAL AND WEHTKBN NKBRAKKA All of the crops previously diftcututed are adapted to the east - ern half and more especially to the eastern third of the state. As we go westward they become less and less adapted because of a shortage of moisture and the native grasses must be re - lied upon to furnish pasture, except on the irrigated and sub - irrigated valley lands. The following mixture is suitable for seeding on the normal soils of central Nebraska, and the irri - gated and subirrigated lands of western Nebraska. 7. Pasture Mixture for Normal Soils in Central Nebraska and for Irrigated or Subirrigated Soils in Western Nebraska' Total cost of mixture per acre, |3.63. TiwIit thr mora UvorabW condltiona in evntrsl Ncbraakm, mu timothy mar ba ad - drd ami thr amount of bromr «n» rrducrd. If aaad of the native weaUrn wheat craae, or of •lender wheat Kraaa ean ba obtained. ( pound* of either of these may be aubatituted for I poanda of the other craaaaa. TbaM two rnwi an, however, aucKrated only for the recion north of the I'lattr and In th« l'anhand:e. 'In the laaa favorable parta of the above mentioned region, the red clover ahould ba omitted and tweet elover may be aubatituted or the alfalfa inereaaed to 4 pounda. 14 2..-.0 .170 1.07 60 30.00 .600 1.00 Hound* /'.,«»,/. IhUlar, HoiUn DtlUn Timothy 12 4ft 4.00 OSh 1.06 R«l clover 6 60 12.00 .200 1.00 Crop* Brome gram Meadow fescue Orchard gram Alfalfa Red clover* p«r mtn found. 8 4 4 2 2 W,iKht V bwlMl Pmii 14 24 14 m K.dm.U.1 DiAian 2.W 3.26 3.00 12.00 12.00 PliMHT pound ■&lt; biMtMlraU DdUri .179 .136 .214 .200 .200 c-t ..f M«lfor OB€ M» Ddlan 1.43 .54 J| .40 .40 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 16 T1MK OF HKK1MNO PAMTl'KKS We are not limited in Nebraska to any one time of the year for seeding clover, alfalfa and the grasses. Both fall and spring seeding have their advantages. However, extended trials indicate that the latter part of August is the most suit - able time for seeding grasses in eastern Nebraska if the seed bed and moisture conditions are favorable then. Alfalfa and the clovers will bear seeding in hotter weather and can be sown under favorable moisture conditions as early as August 10. If seeded later than September 1 there is considerable danger of winterkilling because of the small growth which the plants are able to make after that time. Particularly is this true of legumes. While some doubt has always been expressed as to the success from fall seeding of red clover, the Experiment Station obtained perfect stands during the three years 1914, 1915 and 1916, by seeding in August. Cooperative tests with fanners in eastern Nebraska during two years have also given satisfactory results from seeding red clover in August. It is recommended that, as a general practice, none of these perennial seeds be sown in the fall unless conditions are favor - able during August. If August is unfavorable, seeding may be delayed until spring, with March and early April as the most suitable dates. Alfalfa may be an exception to this rule of early spring seeding since the young plants are usually not re - garded as being able to withstand as severe frosts as are grasses and the clovers. In central and western Nebraska spring seeding should pro - bably be the rule because there is somewhat more danger of winterkilling there, and because moisture conditions are likely to be much more favorable then. Fall seeding where possible is likely to result in a profitable growth relatively free from weeds the following year. In the case of spring seeding without a nurse crop it commonly is necessary to practice clipping with a mower at least once or twice during the first season in order to control the weeds. Spring seeded perennial forage crops seldom produce much the first year. Early preparation of the seed bed is desirable whether seeded in the fall or in the spring. /The seed should then be planted only when growing conditions are favorable. In addition to the planting seasons mentioned as suitable for grasses and clovers generally, sweet clover may be sown in the early winter so that germination and growth will not take place before spring. It is believed that after being subjected to such winter exposure the many hard seeds ordinarily con- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forage Crops 17 tained in sweet clover germinate more readily. This is es - pecially true of unhulled seed. The slow germination of hard seeds also tends to be overcome by the planting of scarified seed. ■BED BKII I-Kt I-MI VI ll.N The most essential requirements of a seed bed for small seed is that it shall be compact, fine and moist. This condition can in some instances be best attained by shallow plowing, disking, and harrowing. In other instances a mere double disking and harrowing may produce the desired condition. It is commonly desirable to either plow or disk the ground as soon as possible after the previous crop has been removed. This helps improve the physical condition and moisture content of the soil. In case the seed bed is not sufficiently compact at seeding time it should be artificially compacted as with a cor - rogated roller, for example. In the absence of a roller, a disk when properly handled is a fairly good packing implement. On light sandy soils which blow easily, the seed may be drilled directly into stubble ground without special prepara - tion. If such stubble is very weedy, disking may be necessary. MANNER OF iBKDINO The seeding may be done either with a wheelbarrow seeder, a drill with grass seed attachment, an endgate wagon seeder, a hand broadcast seeder, or by hand. Few men these days can seed dependably by hand. Experience would indicate that sowing broadcast with a wheelbarrow seeder and covering with one harrowing is one of the most dependable methods. A complete pasture mixture can be seeded satisfactorily with this implement at one seeding, whereas varieties differing much in seed weight must be planted separately in order to insure uniform distribution if a centrifugal machine such as an endgate seeder is used. Drills especially made to seed small expensive seeds very shallow also give satis - faction. These drills, tho rather expensive, are likely to prove a jrood investment where much seedintr is dine. Ordinary grain drills may be used by mixing corn meal with the seed to prevent too rapid seeding. There is some danger of the seed or young plants being washed under by heavy rains in case a prain drill is used. The amount of seed to sow per acre is indicated in this bulletin with each mixture or single crop to be sown. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 HHDIXfl WITH OK « Illllll I A M KSK ( Kill' Under Nebraska conditions where a shortage of moisture frequently interferes with crop growth, there is serious danger of losing these expensive seeds by sowing with wheat or oats. The small grain nurse crop often uses so much water at the expense of the grass that the latter fails as a result. If a nurse crop of wheat or oats is used, it may often to advantage be cut for hay in order to prevent the complete drying up of the young grass. When grown to maturity the small grain is best cut rather high above the ground. The tall stubble thus left tends to shade and protect the suddenly exposed small plants. In those years when rainfall is plentiful, successful stands are usually obtained by seeding with oats, barley or winter wheat. If a small grain nurse crop is used, the grain is advantageously seeded somewhat thinner than normal, preferably about one-half the usual rate. Unfortunately, seedinpr of winter wheat or rye thinly seems to do rather little good, since the plants occupy the ground after all, thru their power of stooling. When seeded in the fall in this state, perennial forage crops are almost always seeded alone. The principal exception is in case sandy or otherwise free-blowing soil is seeded. In such cases, oats or other small grain which will die when severely frozen, is seeded to hold down the soil. FASTI RE MWd.MIKM Pasturing may sometimes commence as early as June of the first year on a fall seeded pasture. Newly seeded pastures should be grazed lightly except where sweet clover or pasture mixtures are seeded with oats and pastured. All stock should be kept off during and immediately after heavy rains except on sandy soil. Pasturing should ordinarily be delayed until late summer or fall, in order to avoid damage from tramping and the pulling out of small plants. After the pasture is once established it requires judicious management in order to secure the maximum and most pro - fitable grazing. It is a well known principle in plant growth that up to a certain limit the rate of growth is rather depend - ent upon the leaf area. If the pasture is always eaten off closely the yield will be reduced. Pastures may often be ad - vantageously divided into two parts so that one portion may grow undisturbed while the other is being grazed. Dividing a pasture also reduces the amount of tramping a grazing ani - mal must do to p"t its fill. When too close pasturing is practiced, weeds are liable to be - come troublesome. Weedy pastures should be mowed once or </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Forage Crops 19 twice during the season so as to prevent the weeds going to seed. This should, if possible be done at such a time that some of the grasses may go to seed and help thicken up the pasture. MNBWINfl WOKN-OIT FASTI RK* Pastures which have become thin and weedy may often be greatly improved by a year's rest. The weeds should be clip - ped, and the grass allowed to go to seed. Only light pasturing should be practiced for a year or two. An application of 6 to 10 loads of manure per acre helps to thicken the stand as well as to increase the yield. It may also be desirable to scatter suitable seed over the pasture to aid in thickening the stand. The amount and kind of seed to sow will depend upon the amount and kind of grasses and clover present in the old pasture, and the character of the land. In eastern Nebraska and on subirrigated land west of this, timothy, blue grass and white clover are nearly always in order on normal soil, while on low wet ground, timothy, alsike clover and redtop. For clayey ground in eastern Nebraska, Canada blue grass, white clover, red clover, and redtop are well suited. Canada blue grass and redtop are also adapted to sandy soil in the eastern third of the State. If the land is so located that it can be cultivated and cropped, it is often desirable to break up the old pasture and grow grain crops upon the land for a number of years. The pasture should in this case be established on other land. However, this is a satisfactory practice onlv in the eastern third of the State. In the central third of Nebraska, pastures should be retained as loner as possible, and in the western third, no sub - stitute for native pastures has thus far been found except where irrigation is practiced or the soil is naturally subirri - gated. ANNUAL PASTURE CROPS Rape — Rape provides an excellent temporary pasture for hogs, sheep, and cattle, except that it is not suitable for milch cows because of tainting the milk. It may be seeded any time between March 20 and August 1, altho the best results are se - cured by seeding alone in the early part of April. Dwarf Essex rape is the best variety for Nebraska condi - tions. From 5 to 7 pounds per acre should be seeded broad - cast and lightly harrowed in on well prepared soil. If drilled, 3 to 4 pounds of seed will be sufficient. Rape should not be pastured until it is well rooted and has </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 20 grown a rugged stem. The plant will then be 10 to 12 inches high. Stock should eat only the leaves which will renew themselves from the stem and thus provide a continuous pas - ture for the remainder of the season. Ordinarily rape is ready to pasture in about eight weeks. Rape may also be sown into cornfields at the last cultivation for late pasturing; or after small grain in early July, where corn is to follow the next year. But this practice is not advisable unless the season is abund - antly moist. Catch crops of this nature frequently reduce the yield of the following crop by virtue of using moisture which might otherwise be accumulating in the soil. Rye — Rye may be sown in August for temporary pasture for hogs or cattle. It provides good pasture during the fall and sprin?. Six pecks should be drilled per acre on a well pre - pared seed bed. Rye and winter wheat planted for a grain crop may both be pastured to advantage upon land where a rank growth is produced. The danger of lodging will thereby be somewhat reduced. Care must be taken not to pasture when the ground is wet or in the spring after jointing has commenced. Winter erain on sandy soil should be pastured very lightly indeed, and then only when the ground is moist. On normal soil, pasturing, unless done very lightly, is liable to somewhat reduce the yield of grain. Fig. 4. — Kape paRture </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forage Crops 21 Oats — Oats may be sown for spring and early summer pas - ture for cattle, sheep and horses in the same manner as when seeded for grain. Pasturing may usually commence about three weeks after seeding. Oats are sometimes successfully seeded with a permanent pasture mixture or sweet clover, when kept pastured down. SEEDING AND CARE OF HAY CROPS IN NEBRASKA The following list includes the more important hay plants suitable for Nebraska : 1. Perennial plants : alfalfa, timothy and brome grass. For very low wet land, redtop and alsike clover are suitable. 2 Biennial plants : red clover 3. Annual plants: Sorghum, Sudan grass, millet, oats. In addition, soybeans, cowpeas, Canada field peas, and vetch are frequently mentioned as annual hay crops but have come into very little use, and are not of great importance. PERMANENT MEADOWS ALFALFA Adaptation of Alfalfa — Alfalfa is by far the most important hay crop grown in Nebraska. It is well adapted to all normal soils of the eastern half of the state. In the western portion it thrives on the subirrigated, and irrigated land. As a broad - casted crop it is not well adapted to the uplands of western Nebraska where a shortage of moisture is the limiting factor. Some farmers, however, are finding that alfalfa sown in rows and cultivated is a successful crop both for hay and seed on these same uplands. It may also be grown there fairly suc - cessfully on ground which receives run off water from higher land. It thrives nowhere in the State on badly water-logged, acid, or very alkaline soils. Fortunately, relatively little Ne - braska soil has any of these afflictions. Alfalfa may success - fully be grown on bottom land where the water does not stand closer to the surface than about three feet. In the eastern third of Nebraska, with its more humid climate and finer tex - tured soil, ground water three feet from the surface is prob - ably too close. The "common" alfalfa grown almost universally in this State is surpassed by no other variety. Altho Turkestan and Grimm alfalfa have been widely advertised, they have nowhere come into common use in Nebraska and have shown no super- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 iority. Grimm alfalfa has not been tried very widely in Ne - braska, and may prove to be worthy of extended trial, espec - ially in the extreme western and northwestern portions, in case the freezing of the past few winters is repeated. Seed Bed for Alfalfa — Wherever possible, the ground should be plowed thoroly for the crop preceding alfalfa. The seed bed lor the alfalfa may then be prepared either by plowing shallow and working down or else by double disking. What - ever the method, it is very important that the seed bed be fine, firm, and moist. The subsoil should also contain considerable water to insure success. If necessary, artificial packing should be resorted to in order to secure firmness, because the seedling plants dry up more readily in a loose seed bed. On a loose seed bed, fall sown alfalfa is much more liable to freeze out. Time for Seeding Alfalfa — Thruout the eastern third of Ne - braska, August seeding should be practiced if soil conditions are favorable. Otherwise it is best to withhold the seed and sow the following spring. Where fall seeding is practiced, profitable crop yields should be expected the following year. Alfalfa seeded later than September 1 is often subject to winterkilling, altho in favorable years somewhat later seeding may be practiced. Use of Nurse Crop with Alfalfa — Alfalfa seeded alone in the spring usually yields lightly the first year and requires one or more clippings. However, a sucessful stand is more certain than if seeded with a small grain nurse crop such as wheat, barley, or oats, seeded at the normal rate, because the grain deprives the young alfalfa of much moisture. If a nurse crop is to be used, it should be planted at from one-half to two - thirds the normal rate as a "modified" nurse crop. If the season turns out very dry the small grain should be cut for hay before ripening. Some farmers use this practice with uni - form success at least as far west as Custer county, their idea being that spring-sown alfalfa will be obliged to compete with something, and it had better be with thinly sown grain than with weeds. For this use a thin seeding of early oats or beardless barley is most suitable because these crops will make excellent hay. Rate and Manner of Seeding — On a well-prepared moist seed bed, 12 to 15 pounds of clean, viable seed per acre is the proper amount to sow. On a poorer seed bed, slightly more seed should be used. Either broadcasting or drilling </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forage Crops 23 may be practiced. In either case the seed should not be cov - ered to exceed 1 inch, except that on light open soil it may be sown 1 ' o to 2 inches deep if necessary to reach moist soil. On soils which blow badly, alfalfa may be seeded directly into stubble if the ground is moist and free from growing weeds. The stubble helps hold the soil. In the fall a small quantity of oats or barley may also be sown with alfalfa on sandy soil in order to keep it from blowing. The grain will be killed by frost and will hold snow as well as soil. In communities where alfalfa has not been grown extensive - ly inoculation with either artificial culture or soil from an old alfalfa field may be necessary. The latter method appears to be the most practical. In most localities of the State, the necessary bacteria appear to be present without special in - oculation. The soil most likely to need inoculation is either thin sandy soil or clayey soils light in color. Harvesting Alfalfa Hay — In this State from three to four cuttings of alfalfa may be secured according to the season and locality. There are two indexes as to the proper time for cut - ting alfalfa hay. These are (1) the appearance of the first bloom and (2) the starting of new growth at the crown and lower part of the old stems. The hay should be cut according to which ever index appears first. Waiting for new shoots may mean hay too mature, while waiting for blooms may re - tard the next crop. For horse feed it should be cut somewhat more mature. Since the loss of leaves from overdrying, and the discolor - ation, mustiness, and decomposition resulting from rain after cutting greatly reduce the value of the hay, the haymaking should be so managed as to avoid all unnecessary delay between cutting and stacking. In good drying weather half a day or less in the swath and a day in the windrow will ordinarily suffice before stacking. It must be borne in mind that external moisture from rain or dew is more likely to cause mould in the stack than is moisture within the plant. The leaves form about 50 per cent of prime alfalfa hay and their loss natur - ally is serious. A side delivery rake is a great aid in turn - ing the windrow for drying out when rained upon. In poor drying weather, and especially with the first crop, it is often better to get the hay into the stack a little too green and let it brown cure rather than to have it rained upon or lose too many of the leaves. Brown cured hay is of high feed - ing value. Alfalfa hay should not be placed in a barn until it is thoroly dry, as there is otherwise considerable danger of fire thru spontaneous combustion. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 TIMOTHY AND CLOVER Timothy and clover are primarily adapted to the eastern third of Nebraska. However they seem to do distinctly better in the river counties and in the dozen counties in the northeastern part of the State, than they do elsewhere. Tim - othy is seldom planted alone in this State but rather is mixed with medium red clover for hay. It has been customary to sow 10 pounds of timothy with wheat in September and to add 6 pounds of clover early in the spring. When a successful stand is obtained in this manner and the year is favorable, the clover makes a large growth after the wheat is cut. The following year a cutting of mixed hay is harvested, folowed by a cutting of mostly clover. In succeeding years timothy pre - dominates, the amount of clover depending upon natural re - seeding. The timothy may also be seeded in the spring with the clover. Experiments with the fall seeding of red clover during recent years have led to the conclusion that this crop may be seeded quite safely during the second and third weeks in Aug - ust in those years when moisture conditions are favorable, and a good seed bed is to be had. If timothy and clover, or clover alone are seeded in the fall without a nurse crop, a stand is more certain than when the clover is seeded in the spring and obliged to compete with a grain crop. Four years out of the past eight years in the greater part of the clover portion of the State, red clover, when seeded on winter wheat in the spring, has generally failed because of drouth. If sown with a nurse crop it may be sown with a grass seed attachment at the same time that the grain is drilled. It may also be broadcasted ahead of the drill, depending upon the drill to cover it. If sown in the spring on winter wheat it may be drilled crosswise to the wheat rows with a disc drill set shal - low. It may also be broadcasted without covering on a light snow in March, or else broadcasted and rolled or harrowed later as early as the soil will permit working. When seeded in the spring without a nurse crop either tim - othy and clover or clover alone usually make but one cutting of hay while two cuttings or one cuttting and a clover seed crop may be had following fall seeding. When clover is seeded alone 10 to 15 pounds of seed per acre should be used. A mixture of timothy and clover produces better horse feed than does clover alone. For cattle and sheep, however, straight clover hay is superior. It is also probable that clover alone has a more beneficial effect upon the soil than has the mixture. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forage Crops 25 The hay should be cut when the clover is in full bloom with a few blossoms turning brown. Where the crop is mostly timothy and is to be used for horse feed, it should be cut after the timothy has come into full bloom and most of the blossoms have fallen. For cattle, timothy makes a more palatable hay if cut when first starting to bloom. The same precautions should be taken in making timothy and clover or clover hay as for alfalfa. Clover is injured even more seriously than alfalfa by being rained upon after it is cut. RKUTOP AND AI.SIKK CLOVKK On soil too wet to grow other hay crops advantageously, a mixture of redtop and alsike clover may be sown at the rate of 12 pounds of redtop to 5 of alsike clover. The same cultural methods apply to this mixture as to timothy and clover. IlK-MIK »iRA8H Brome grass has been used to a small extent for hay. Twenty-five pounds of seed should be sown per acre either in the spring or early fall on a well-prepared seed bed. Good yields of hay are produced for perhaps the first three years and then the yield greatly diminishes as a result of the grass becoming sod-bound. If it is to be used longer as a meadow it will be necessary to break the sod shallow in the fall or early spring from which treatment it quickly recovers and renews its vigor. Care should be taken to plow thus only when the ground is thoroly moist, and the soil should be re - packed at once, preferably by going over it once or twice with a corrugated roller. Brome grass should be cut for horse hay shortly after bloom - ing, when the head turns purplish in color. For cattle and young stock it is best cut somewhat earlier. One of the great - est objections to the growing of brome grass is that it is seldom possible to secure seed free from the extremely dangerous quack grass. ANNUAL HAY CROPS Sorghum — "Black Amber" is the bent variety of sorghum or cane for forage. It grown finer, cures more readily, and mn - turen earlier than the Orange or Sumac. It in alno more de - sirable than any of the grain sorghums of which Kafir has the greatest value an forage. The adaptation of norghum in very wide, thin crop being the mont extennlvely grown annual forage crop in all parts of the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 v.'-.»w*H ftii-fwOMMif MhHini liHllphtt inn fttMtti. If Id Mf MHwlHl VMllIM Mil III** ll|il«Mt!« tit W^lhHI Nf - ll)H«h H hyt-H HlfHlfH lliiM Hill tilHVt* llpfHHMP ilf H|t|l«lllH« nllMllHtM I iiHN KHfttlllUH |lHiVltlh« Illh (lltwl ilH|lhlHltllilt- Ih» oritiiiii'ii ii' i i imii i mm M|« Ifftf hi Nil imiin nf ihii NUIh wlincn NlfjiirM Iliflvn Immi'm l« iim mimmI nitDil nil' diiinliiiiii mIiii'h Him hITmIIm i» h iimii'm IKitllUlilK null III MImw I'liilliMiiiniiM, mITmUm mmIk Mr Hi MiMmii ImikmIv fciiiii (Jim mIi hiiiI Imhvmr Him mihiiiiiI iiiiicm ■Ihmim v |iriulii»'IIVM lliMii linnii'M II hi&lt;i&gt;ii|iIki| IIik mill, mi&lt;»|i) Cm 1 Inn jiiil HI V IiimIbIhIm mIhiI'Iiihk III Him •nil A Him tfl'iiWII |n Iimmi I jf M H I'HIIIm MMll M||H«t|l iWll, Mlll'tfllllKI IIINV lid ll«»*ll mi|i|'M«nil V fill lllll'NMi Tim hi»Ihiiihi t iiiiiiiiimi Chi hmmiIIiki In In Ii|'mmiI*&lt;mmJ hi ill'lll mi m wkII |i»'i«|m»'Nil ikmiI IimiI iliiiiiiM Him Im*i ImlC nf Mhv nr </seg>
            <seg id="p027">hit-Hit* riM^ 27 NM»U IH dllll*, HIVUHH* the «m| | III |U llpltM '|WM HHtj HIlMlW* IH KWUMfH NnWHsftH HfH HlH hH«f J-hIm, Hllll HfHHRHS iflHJi -IhhhihI |hihi»»; mIiMi In ihhHIi-hII* hII hhIhH Hfr hhHIk VVIiIIh lilt- 4 It-ltl Illllll ll^lllHl aHHtllMM IHH* llH Hi iHf^H, fl|H Hf M • In. I la i KtilBhl HIIM Hill IIHHflV mi Hhll HHIHI . NHltli mi sIih i ti I • BMIf hIihii Ihu *HHt| |a In Hih ilmiyli hjmj»». II -imijli i, h Inf In iIm "ill iii IIih 8H«Hi #■»##-■ l»n Hf [iHk* Hill llHH (HltNll MIDI ihiI.m) Al Im»«I fWH MNHM "I illllHM "l.t|llll-( Hit- |Hljl|l(Ml| llHllllt- II III || llH slH^ltMH pjlll IRW HlllN tlM|IHHtllllM iHIWt-U II|IH|I lilt. illNtlMM III |||H IH* Miiuii.iiiU imiii in Him nil), iii.ti la. Diiit.il illtHH wllliiiil MMHl III HIM (HUM )» || llHlltfNf III Mllllltf III IWll I M HM|ltJ| "iMtfM Ml IHMllUlU, II |n IMIIllU llMfl III [Ml II MCHlt • Illllf H« |II(«H|I(|X, llMlllM |l»M|IHCMll, ||imMVM», II NHl it Hit *|J|| II MM ihiM hIIm IIih f|M«l I 1 IHIII 4 l»l 'l Im||k JIMI MM H HIM*' H ).»|imiImi| iiihImi hvm(mwm mm»Ih|ii Nwlint-lut fiijin i:niit|illMii» An Mil HVMI'HIfM |m| MIIA Hllfl HI Mi. Minn Hm|i|mi| f\ H lull* Hf wmM • IIIHll rtir»t»M |ll't' HHM Hi l|lH |li»|IMI'llll»/||( H|ltl|i||| H» pilllli.ll •-•! »illi M Inn* iif mIIhIIh I hum link I* iinliiiiH \\\i Him I) inruiiiii In hIChII'h m|' i Imvmc Iihv ii|i|ihii nllv Ittivxlv Iihmmm»n II |« vn»&gt; nun h IhuMhk III imiiIi in .I/1//1/ MjIIhIm mih hiIm|iIhi| Im IIih mhiiih hii||i||I|m|IM M Ii •iiimIhiiii I Iih&gt; iIm mil rui|iil|'H h« Iiiiiv h yi'Mttiiiif •mmmmii hi • ImiW flimlllllh Iml Hint III"!! V'IhIiI |ti«« '\\m HI'H IIKHll I llll'lU it .&lt; iiilili i|h|ih wlmii IIih IIiiih Im Iuu -.hull I'm iilllHI' i&gt;CM|W HI IMHllllM TIlHV HIM MH|ihHhIIV' huIImIiIh fill' HHMllllltf «llH|'H (Kirjl fnllt'il Iii iiuiltM 11 mIhihI mi 1 hmk iIhhIimVhiI Ik hull ill' IIiimiI, MhhiI Illll IIIHV llM llMIIM ll«J * HMD MHV I h Hill) -Illlv \t\ Till IIIMRl I'liiiiiiiiiiiU ni'MHH him! inuliiililv Iihm| hiiIImiI miiImIImh Hf ihIIImI MI'm Him i'iiiiiiiimii, lli'iiiiMii, IImiihmiIhii, hiiiI HIIimiImii Mlllt'l IlltV I* Nil IIHHNlinrHI'llll'V It't'll hll 1 llMl'HMH lll'lltllliM llf |l« Illllll lllllM I'ltMI'l ll|lll|| lllMll MllllMVH Till' ll if Hi|.&lt; IiiImi Ihikiii.i. rmmmiii In lit* NMintmliiil Iiih|miI|ii|ihI Im Hit' iImkimm til 1 iniiiiiiih Nn liiliii')iiii« I'ltMil* Inline, IuiwmvmI'i kIihi rml III i'hIIIm mill «Iimh|i ll ■liiilllil Iim imiI IimCiiIm JIim ■mmiI Im CmimihiI WllUM lllll'llili'il till' llllI'MMN, Illll MUM Iim lull Illll II I Iim •mmiU •iim in llin milk ■Ihmm rm mnl «Iimm|i MmIII^ «&gt;MM»'MM»', HllllH I'MI|I|||'I¥ •MlllM^llHl IIIIIIK lltllM fllf HIllllH lllMll illll'* llMllilll* Minimi ihn*» NihIhii ifi'MM In n I'mmmhIU ihIihiIiiimiI hiiiuihI fnlMMM 1 ■in|i * till ■nil HUM I'lllllHlll' H)Ih|iIhI illllll VHl'V Mlllllllll III </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Hvbnuhi K\i&lt;iwiint$ut Shillmi llulhtlii urn ihiiMi of Attilmr imiik in growth imiiii, It »IHT»r« Himtawhftl from i'miim In tlml II hIimiIh fur mnr» fm»ly Mint In flnar nl»m»il. A* fin* iMNiiiK la ihimIiii'miI iiiiin Mt 1 1 lit ii ui'mm whmi • I »- 1 1 1**«1 un pniiiiiU |mc Mi'i'n mm frnm t'Hiiti iIiIIIimI iMmikIihU |t»r H^r*. It Mlmi iiimIu&gt;« it mm h mm., i nphl nl KfiiVVth hMm Iwltlir ml, idHi*? 1 1 fill* t in ii l i ii, ii him! twti ml linn* nf Imv mttv luii|npnl!v Iim litti vwlml uiiiimmIIv in ftat^rit Nelii'MNkN wht*n iiniUiiirn (mniliiiitiiN wr» fwvucMliln- Thu Iwm miliiin*, ImwMVur, Met* nut iikuly it* yittlii «• iniiMh fnrHtiP m ilin tut** eulliinf iif i'miiw. Ah «ii HVorHirit fur thrwt yKMI'M Hllllttll t(|MHH llHH Vlnlllml Illllv (iH |IMC (Hill «» llUti'll M MM MmUml funding U\nU iiwllualu thMt Mu4hh irrMH In not ■up«rior to i'Mim rnr ontlln »m1 Mh»«p find U Mt»n with Itma </seg>
            <seg id="p029">I '"I •till I I "II* 29 mlluli liy thmn, HihImii imH la imIImIimi) hy Imram miwI II nuty |ii'i Iiiiiik pi us i' Hii|iri lui til nun' fur Ihum liny, MihIhii hchm nmy Iim hmwii IimihiIi'MhI, iIi'IIImiI, nr Itt ••ulll VMtt**l row*, Nil h it liriiHili'HHlliiM nr ilrllllnn In ihi'I'himIiIm, Mi'«|it iimli'i u&gt;i v 1 1 1 v I'liiiilllliiiiH, 1 hiimk m Iliii'i 1 liny In iii'iiiliii'Bil Mini llll&lt; Illliiil ill 1 illlllVHllll|f I* MVIllllxil ||| I'llVVM, t\ III (I |IHl|||lU Of M*ii| \wr mi 1 )** in mmli'lmil. WIinii iifimili'Mtmi ni' iIiIIImiI. Ifl In III) iMHimU nf mihI uliniilil Iim ii»mi| \wf accm 1 1 «lni|iM W nmmiImiI III Him Inline |ihiI nl Mnv |f "iiih In Inn.. In (hi* HUlu n|Miii h whII |iim|ihi«*iI Mwii liwl. Thf mhiI ahnulil Iih i»iivi"m»iI Mil 1 1 .. Iiii'Iim ii*»|i Him MNm* m i'mhk. WhiIhii HIHM In Imfti nil fnf Iihv wIii-ii III lull IiIummi, mIIIim II MIMV "IhihI 1'iiiKi'i « Illiniil h|i|HI'iIhIi|h IiiIhiv \t nun |iIhm« to Hill Him MihImii minah Iwlcn, Iihi vmhIIhh mI Hit* WlfllKt 1 nU|t» In i^MrMMhlM 'hiiMM In rnM» (iiiih nf liny !»••»• MHfit mny lm pk |»«'ImiI IlllllliC fHVMMlllM HlhlllllllKH. lltllll ItliilM (ImIIIiIIm liifMfliiMllMii |n In Iim Iihi! In Him c HilM^» thM «hI(im |iH&gt;t'Hlilliifi nIimiiIiI Iim IhKmii imIhIIvm |ii li'Hlniliitf flllilwH jffMNN NN Wftit fHH*&gt; NlHl'M NlUlMH tfCNNN. I* i-h'*»\)t Hf IhImiI Im ■HiyliiiHl (tic MHIM llNlltfMC ffnlii iimImmhIIIK tliHV HlMi »»nh llnl« mmmiImi! Im Him iimIIiimu iiihiiiimi m I'm)' hmIH milkw Mil MMIctlf »|MMlliftr (if ilMV, Nll'|iMlliil- Im Ilinnlk, M llWI fill III Him milk mi MflV HHIItfH nImmh III Ml MhujiI. Him Hiif-Hi SMNlMHI, M*UmIHM IIMflllMtll HMll "PMHhMlllH*" NMIiHullN llf HlN m*b&lt; mh Mfly vmhu^i nhhIi mn KfiNFNMii, TPtM HpHi Hf Hurt, pin Mill Iim tijinil nIiihh II In Imnn ■iiIi|ni-| Im nuvmmi i iin| WHIfft CHI lll'fN lllH fNMllllDJ VHlHM, NMll MIHI'N IIHHllV HVHllMN HllM NHIHIIIM dri 11M1 Miitl i^f MHWuypf, nil hhIhmiU m( fHl»Hvnlv iMW.fir HI »V NIIV III l)|t&gt; NUfn, h IiIkIihi vIhIi) nf fam* WlU Hi lilt HlllMll ft Mill .» Ilimlilllll l.tl.- &gt;.iiImIv NIII'll HN H^BllUll *»Wl (hit* uwl tuitl I'm* il«»» Hi's mmmmImiihILv *m\w\ (m \m W[[\\ • HIIMllw rtp|t| (IMHH, Wllii:|l UllftlHTH UFMIIMMMH fMHl| llf «« - umIImiiI inmlllv TIiIn mimliiimHMii »f»B \» iiimM |ii'imil«lii|F ill thu wwwiii hihI iiuiilmni iwrU m/ Him HMh wnnw Min liftrtNi nnl mi Mi'fMt Oiip miuI imtHmlf IimnIimIn if «m'h nIhimW Hg nlrtlllPlI |IM»' MMI'H- TlIM |»M«* NlillMlli lit* lIl'illMll Ul H Im|)H| llf U ,,r I iiimIhm hn uhi'Iv in Hin »|irini* »* Him hi'mmihI imii Ii« Wjpkwl, Within tht* itMkl Iwu in' thru* iIhv» Him imtN -Ii.hiM lit* ilnllmi Hi N mn Mini it • |H I. ill' lii mult .tniii.l .tml Imrniwwi- The ornji «*huiilil Im hHi'venteii when the imU mn In the ilmiifh Nt»u». Trirw »r fnur rtwyN of yum) lirvmn wenther »m f#- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 V./.ionfrM Niviinlntriil Mil Htm Ihilhltn Hit) IhIimiI h»'fniM AlHtklnu On» nr Him MffMtMl iilijMi'llnini U Ml* |h'm Iimv In Him IiImIi (Mini iif nm\ Ptiillhntn* HHlt ('lllMH'ti* NllVllMMhft Mllll l&lt;ilW|l»Hfl Mlf HIIIIIIhI l..tfiiniM« which ihmv Iim MhiM-n fni' Iimv. NiiviiMMim Iimvm In mmii - imI HhiiWIt Kt'MMfMl- miIm|iIiiIIhh |ii NmIm mmUm I'liinlllliin* limn INVP IMlWilMNN, NiivIimhIi Mil ImIIm* mi-m MVMIImMm " 1(1**1 Will IllH UP* Iimv ill Nil iimi'Ih hI' Him WImIm wliPfPHft i'hw|imm« mi'm lun l.il» Ml' «»'«ii'in Mini iiMiiiiiin Ni'lini-kii TIimmm i'hi|i« mi 1 ** mil imvlh'Nlili* wIimi'kvmi' iilfiillii IhHVM, TIik j^ImM i» imImIIvmIv iiimII, Hip ihmiI In nuiimihIvn, ihmh&lt; ImIiiii 1 In i'miiiiiimiI Himii with mHiki 1 Ikiv i&gt;I'ii|i«, Mini Him Iniv In illlllHill In hicm IImImIIvmIv hiiIImIiIm vmiImIIm- rut' Iimv III Him m»«Imiii HumI hI Him NmIm mtm Wlnpi ihHI mill Nmw I«*ih i'mwiimmm. Mini I'lninl, AinliMi'Ml, lliiliMiliuiill Mini MMiliuni VmIIhw hiivIimmiim, In imiiHkI itinl wmmImi'ii NmIii'mnhm milv mmi'Iv vmiImIImh mi'm m) mII hMiiniiiiililti, niii&lt;h m« Nmw I'Ii'm i&lt;iiw|imm&lt;*i mihI I'iiulv \ mIImw nr I ••• Wmiii IIiiIiiihi, WIiIiikIii, Mini CIii'DiIm ■iivIimhii" NmvIikmmm Mini i'iiH|inii» ■liiuilil Iim |iIhiiImi! mi it wm|| |h»i|imimi| •ihhI IimiI Ml Him Mini nf Him iurn iiliiiilliiu ■mmmiiii In Hila HImIm I Iimv him mil ■tillnMi&lt; rue hmmiIIiim mIImc miiimII wimim tun v Mil M« U l'l'MI|IIMllllV ■IIUMimlMll Illll' Kl'llWllltf HMMMHII U Illll • in. i i mill inn mliil'iill iimiimIIv Iimi llnillml W|imii|«| IihiiiiIhI Iiiii hi Cur mIImIIh U 1 1 • • * | m • • 1 1 1 { &gt; i|m«IimIiIm h.Hili f ■ r IIim»m |i|'ii|i* inm IIm iiwii iim iilliu miiliiln I in iiiIiim Inn Ihi'Im «lili'li Ii mil inii'ii imii|M&lt;iii.|i' wllli iillit'C mIiiiIn, NmIHihi lii'iiiiiii'HMlliiM mil iIiihh ill Illlnu hi !• III hmiimihI ihiii'I IhiIiIh III I III* MIhIh WIimii niiwii mi lluil nillh nllnii U Im |ihm|Ii|m. Him hIiiw mmcIv i»im«||i hIIiiwn Him wmmiIm In Imm'iiiii* iMlMlilliiiiMil TIimum hmmiIm iiCImii t &lt;i it i i | i ImI mIv lulu' Him null, I'lmilliitf In I'iimh lilt inilii'M muni mill i hIiIvhIIiiii 1 1 U »« Biiffl I* Him him! Inn! Hum Im I'minil imial iiiiirlliiililM Twu ImimIimIh nf •mmiI |IMI' Mi'I'M ulinillil )im iimmiI H Iimii IiI'mmiIi'iimImiI, n |ii.il«» wIlMH iIi'IIImiI, miii) iiiip IimIt IiiimIihI In ciimd II ChmI ii|uhi I'iiwiimm* mIiiuiIiI mil Iim hi! U\\- ln«y mil II Him iii-i iimiIh him iI|im RiivliHiiim ■Intnlil Iim imi! HtlMi I Iim |iiii!« MI'M wm|| rmniMi Mini IimI'mim Him Immvmh Uyin In fMll, TIim »lMin« mim mmmj'om Mini •M|i|lV Mllll I'MI|II I'M dill) III M&gt;M llMVM fllllll I'llHlIM WMIlll"! I"' fnl'M IimIiim tilMi'HMil. 'Him CmmiIIhh vmIiim nf Him Iimv Im IiHi YImIiIm • »r TU In Ii ImiH i«Mi hi ii. iiimv Iim mhiimi'ImiI in mhhImcii Nm llfMMHN. Utiliu Vpfttt IImU-v VmIi'Ii Ik m fnll |iImii|m|| |m&lt;miiiim Him m«mhI huHi'IiIIiH'mI vmIiim nf wIiImIi Iiiu mil Iimmii nillv iImIimiiiIiimiI fur </seg>
            <seg id="p031">hii'iiu* Vntp* 31 thin MmI*. Tht«N» MijiiMN In l««. hHWMrer. link cMmin fur It* 1'lllllllM III HlfllMI'tl NmIi|M«I&lt;H hni'HIHM II I'HHMllI I'H|H|IM|» With ..IImIIm II |.|m( iM Ii|&gt; WllUllI JlMVl' I'I'ImIIVmI.V M ('I'M I Ml' VIlllIM III Him m|i|iiihU nl hmMmhi NmIiim*I«m « Iii'Im iniilMlllM l« iimmiimIIv iImIIcImiiI riii Mir«lr«. NmmiI iniiHllHllim (mmv |H'hvm Milvhiilifn WllMl'M VMll'll llM« Hill llMI'H |l|MV|llll«ly tfl'lltt'll IImhiiiik Ml II* I lulling Imlill, vmIiIi •IhhiIiI ihhiiiihhU Iim miwn wllh m mi mil i'Hi|i in ■iiii|M&lt;ii ii A KiUliui' at ivm lie h loli'i' ttlit'Ml mill VMli'h mIihiiIiI Iim hmmiImiI in mmciv Wm|iImiiiIimi, iioiiiw Mil iihiiihIh hC vmIi'Ii mihI III iiiiiiihIh hC mmu'h A iiihMil ll'M I ln|l HUM lit' Illtl VMftlMll lIlM I'MllimldH hlHM tllM M)/ Mllllllll MM Kl III I||M iHMlll fill 1 M lUft Mill! lllMII lllllll'llMll lit' t'MI'ttMt , A U'W MllliillllllMl illl^i Ih| mIIIhh Will Iim IIMI'MMDMI'V I IM fl ll'M »ll»l IllHM •IM..I Mihnii I 'hum mill Vttih'IlM 1'ni'ii |m uihhii mIiiiimI imiIvmi* iillv mm Him dIimum cimii In iIiIm HIkIm, mimI Iih» Iiumii diii'iimmiI Iiv mi iiilmr iii'n|i fill' IIiIm iim, Khi'Iv Kiilli' hihI AimIimi' mii'tfliuiM huh In Him IhIiiih ih'iivh m t'luMf rlvnl nr kvmii m ■iiiimi'Iiic In Him •lili'i in I Im hI 1 Him HIiiIu wIimcm llmv ihhIiiih iIumiIIi IimIIhi' Hum imi'll l'|i In Him ihmmmiiI Illlin Himv Iiiivm linl Iimmii m«I*i||m( v»*lv Kinwn I'm 1 IIiIm |iiii'|iiihm, Any ui Him miiimII ihmIii i'Ihiim iihiv Iim iihhiI fiic HlliiifM, Iml I hull 1 iimm U mil vmi'v |M'mi'I ImhIiIm. lllllll'lllllHIH HIM Illlll ill IfKllMI'lll I'lll'll WHIhIImx IIIHMl hIIIImIiIm fiic im Mhi In iiny Imiiliiv *rv mImh IimhI rue hIIhum II I* inm ollili', IniWMuic, lii (i in w It *• 1 1 if 1 1 1 1 v ImImc i'mI'H fm 1 xllimi' Hum flit 1 ki hIii I iiiMM full niMliil'lly nf Him wihIii Id mil umiuIhhI Ciilhui' nf I'niti fur Siluui II I- rullinr i'iimIuiihiiv In liliuil llmill mil' ililnl iimii' I'Hi'ii |imi miM fiif rIIhiim IIiiiii fill' imhIii IMI'MIIUM H MIIIIIMWllHl InI'MHI' hlHIIMItK I* |ll ■mllli I'll Illlll (ImiiImiI mI Him hiiIIiiiiiv imIm, IihwmvmI 1 , iiimI*m» m«h'mIIm(iI h|Imi«m M'llllnn Him cuin III i'IiIIIvmImi) Ciiwh fiillii'i Hum |i|niillni&lt; In dim Im lil'i'ivi iilili' mm II Imh«m|i» Him ulculii mm Him ••»••••» liM|'VM«lMf Cm ii ilillli'il mHIi h IImIhi 1 in (iiiiCH Miiillv I«m|iI fcMM nf wnwln Hum II'iiiiImh'iIiIIImiI, Ih'i nniimi linn pihnulil Iim IimcvmmIhiI fill' MIhvm wIimii Him I»mI' m|r him In Him IimiiI iIhiimIi Mmkm A I Hi|« Hhih Him ihmIh i - wmI iIi'IiImiI hihI I'lHrtltitt, Him Ihwmc Imhvn Iihvm I mi In ilcy h|i mhI ill". Mini miiiiN iif )|im (nml«M mi Him mhn «♦ •• hfOindtn* In will mii Mini ullii'i* I»m IihIIimIi' kikIiiMIv Tn&gt;* iiiihIJIv m« whII Wl iii HmIiI HiidlmiM in Iiii'I'mhum mi In Hil« «I«»m iif niMlniiu cidiiiKf nf HUH fut xiImmk I* nnilmlMilili' </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 NvImukH NwHtmmtl HhtH»n Ihtlhlm luu ■hiiimi M* ■iillltiu la HiHMiil Him IihivmmI liiif nf hiwwii fiii'MUM Mini fiwil Him iIUhHIv In Him Iihiii hi ImmiI )mI, Tlila (iihi'IIi'm him? lia rnlliiM nil hIIIihi |m »n|i|ilv nil Him mimmii t •-•-• I iIiuImm Him Mrnwliw MMMMitn, ill 1 iiimimI* In *I||i|iImmimiiI Him |ihnIihm iIiii Him I li»« Imi &gt;!i v ■NMRiill hIikii nimhim In iinnr UmlniililMilly iiiiiim |&gt;ml la (lit* iliii'Mil mi mii Hi'»M lip Mnninn limn lip |im«IimIiim tIijj i*nai nf fuMillntf In, Ikiwuvhc, Ulan mI'hnIIv IuhmnhiI. wlilili hINmI» th« hiIvmii(«hh iif Mt'NNiHt* vImIiI iniilt*i Him Mioihiiila nf »•« miiujvh fHI KllMftf Mlllllial MIllVHMHllv |l!hl'lll'fll It) NNtl|'HM|«N tl Nf lm«l*M UMHHNllik 1 . lilt* |H'«»'lli'H nf mililiiK la IhHiIhiIhI h ill Him nrnlia H»t« iml atiWH iiMiiihHIv /mi Hila |tn»|iimH it m iffllillN avlHin nf Mnlllfitf, If la HmInM*i In auml t'in|m wlilch w II hMi VlHI* N hiilialHIll. ■l|i'i'MM|nii nf fumi lliHl Him tfHlWllllf HKNMHM, tVn(i« inllMMtt fnf anillHtf Nfn nlfalN, HHfd, w!in«I, •/**, HUM, mnl nitfa ami hpm him i i i inn 1 * him ■mi m rMmi Thu HfHWlHM Mf |»MHf HHlH« U MtHHk MjMfi #*MHMalVH fflHH ff»H MfMlhlHllMll HfHlHI a (NMH milHM UlMlC, /wrflMII VNlllH la MM IP »W M»HM Hmf fif allNiK, If la ilniililfnl If (liny ilMaMtVf Hinfn Si m\n hmH MfH fliMii Kin HfniwH^ vncp Imiffitfl HfHMHHfiiiM in W|Mi«Ji» If innl Hfntia nf hm*&gt; Mini hih In Iim iffimii l»i Mk M&gt; nUi MMNJMilH HfK (flMll* »flN IH»mr »UHl(flltllli WMH' *M tfUN alini) il fin an*M( Hliniil MmV IA III hhIHvhIkiI hm N fWKf NHNt-l Hf^ HIM fHfK Hf II (m I* miHIHla tlf »MM)I NNf NMfH ■ Tllf V i«l»V Mi ItmiJ N JJMHlWJ tlflll Hilt) HMVWHJl 'a IH IHHJI MKKrt WWn Mm Hl#f|H»/if1 »MH ••♦•Hi • Ml^ »H»«hW &gt;/h Hi hiimiI In n»&gt; pwi HVHfy« in fli Muhw- T jla la Hi»i ? fiv ttfaf It n^liiM Ml In III f In Ihmi^.im w Mi h linn, fnllimM liv Imrtil MilijiiliiK Wnm HilllVHflnii wIMi h Imffiiw »if WKnHPf 1 i» unMnaaM^ In i niilinl Him HHjr ia la »|miH dv li(»&gt; m nnMliM mil imMtl l«y IihiiiI Mllllll UH WHrtV JSfMP Ml* fMMfM NfV llUfVMf^ MutC »MM^&gt; Hf^^^/'^'ff In n r»»rt hkIImi 1 mf In hIi^ wmm "W w^ *^\* •»{'•' WH^y n in'MVMfif fFMtyiiiw. |u WvmMhhi Mm ftm him ftiM InnaMimfl HV Hl"W'»^ » HMffiw rio'rnw «Imii»* nun aliln nf Mm mw. Mm mihiimmU Nrn Mmii iiullwl nikI IiimiwiI Iim hniirt; TiMWir Wm«/« 'l^n hmHmt* nf aiiVHf IwvU i&gt; itlm'«l HImjiMmhJ -III, lliMl il»mi:rlliwl flir IMHII^It, WKMjtjll HlHf I ft IIWIMlU &gt;lt *»m\ KM anwn In mwa 1)4 IiimIimh mmi i TIikv him •••iiiimwIimI IimhIm» Ut hnrvnaf Hmn mniiMttla hum** Mm rnnU wim nIiiihmI wiMrwv undir thu vmuim. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">t'lumn 1'nifin 33 rilHAHDl l Mill' t IM.I'N * I IIIK: frlM'HIIMMI MM IIHN lu|&gt;. IUH A MrlM Mf l'illll|IHIf IIVM J'Ml'HVi' HNli (Mill »HI ■Ullt'il ||i Hit - fHll nf IIII4 Mini Hirllitf mC Illlft mikI i'iiiiIIiiiihI ilntlliy Illlft. HUM him! I|»I7 'iIihuh wmi'h cnIIimi' CmvuinIi n •hmkIii nhiI miliifwIlMl lll«ll"l Ht'lllw UlNII IMMIIImI WMl'M III III III Hl| ' I r|ft f* hhIIn MID |f IVMtl III ThIiImm U In II HN h (UmIIiiiImhI V ImimhI I In , mIihw Him imIhIIvm |i|'iii|iii&gt;I|iiii iiiiiImi 1 rNViifMlilM I'liiiifilliiiia, All i'in|m wmih |iIhh|hiI mi m (iImwhiI hiiiI « mI| |h&gt; inn i il «t«t.i| lixil TIih |iImN VHrlfli rinlll miihImiiIIi In mif Ililillflli hi if In a|«« miii| wttfn iIiiihIhnImiI In |mH All ylnliU wmcm rmliii'tnl In h mninini'N i-niilMiil nf II |i**r «*«rtl In nrilMC Him) limy ahmiM Im inmilMfMHln, f nhlh i I'nmfMt'HHi'f yinhl* nf l^iputM it ml Atttttml hnmn&gt; t'l-Htti, Ml* mill Win H«ic ill «l»M«MIIMt«IHl H HInmhIhI loid hmh IHHH Kl/ttT/i 1 (.'IIIMIIIMII HlfHlfH (jfliinii mINim.. Jinl'HtHII llfMlfN Hkll fJHVNt 'ni-IMI*. IHUllllKfil 1 ■'mliiii. wuliii* ini 4imiiimI KHfMMH ■ liilul, ulMli Piw'lMlllrt.. Mm .win .mil,! ftl UllHIll MlUlHfH *»m ■ MM! S AlUIUtfi II Ilil ' till hll'HW &gt;hj k»t «INM Mmfi WH UN "|(|im»»miiIM( fwr PM jppff^Aiti icpniNiiru .^ M HNH&gt;» ill )IM|H| M« •Mll|HI I urn «*•► I Mltlll 1 "' 'la MM IHM I Hfll II ( n»« m i Hi i MINI IMUl f MH» HlHI INN I 1 MINI Ml IMMIMM (HI N« ! III'MII . khi Kim &gt;mi kmi ttV. li I M XN i-Ni li MHMH- £ hi hmI II kk.ImI AfltfHI HI ■ ( ' 'I I) ;: W HHllnil ffHflU Id, IHII! M 1 M j li HI II V I" m M HI M HHtl l&lt; « K »t is ►"Ill ■hi. »i *r f ))» i f f&gt;yi 1 1 w »l*i» Ml»H» m ttJmj </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Xrhraaka Ksprrimrnt Station Iliillrtiii JttO Table H. Compariaon of Three Method* of Planting Annual Forage Cropa, 1015, 1910 utul 1017 Kind uf Crop IUU o( YUld .if h«y per aor« with and M*dln( 12' &lt; muialurii content manner ut atwdinv pur mm 1916 UUtt 1U1T Avar. i» Paund* T«M« Turn Tnnd Ton* BUik Amber norghum 1. Cultivated row. 5 2.6 5.3 4.3 4.1 2. Broadcasted HO 4.7 4.9 4.0 4.8 3. Drilled Sudan grass 80 5.9 6.2 5.7 5.9 1. Cultivated rows 5 2.9 4.8 3.5 3.7 2. Broadcasted 40 2.8 4.4 3.6 3.6 3. Drilled 40 4.1 4.2 3.8 4.0 Kafir com 1. Cultivated rows 5 2.3 4.9 3.7 3.6 2. Broadcasted 80 3.6 4.5 4.1 4.1 3. Drilled 80 4.2 5.2 4.8 4.7 Dent corn 1. Cultivated rows 20 3.9 2.6 2.H 2.9 2. Broadcasted 110 4.4 2.6 3.7 3.5 3. Drilled 110 4.B 4.4 4.8 4.5 Table U. Rate of Seeding Test With Black Amber Sorghum and Sudan Grass for Forage, 1915, 1916 and 1917 Yield of hay per acre with 12% moisture content Crop and rmtc of (ceding per acr 1916 1916 1917 Aver. T&lt;mt Tout Tom Tom Black Amber sorghum 2 pecks ! 3.6 5.0 5.3 4.6 3 pecks 4.7 4.8 5.7 5.1 4 pecks 4.8 5.2 5.7 5.2 6 pecks 5.0 5.4 5.6 5.3 8 pecks 4.9 6.2 5.7 5.6 12 pecks i 5.2 6.3 5.9 5.8 Average 4.7 5.5 5.6 5.3 Sudan grass 2 pecks 2.7 4.4 3.2 3.4 3 pecks _ 2.7 3.8 3.5 3.3 4 pecks 2.9 4.2 3.8 3.6 6 pecks 3.4 4.0 3.7 3.7 8 pecks 3.4 4.1 3.8 3.8 12 pecks I 3.5 4.0 3.8 3.8 Average I 3.1 4.1 3.6 3.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forage Crop$ 35 Table 5. Forage Tent of Different Kindt of Millet 1916 and 1917 f&lt;«t. . t Yield p«r uri with Vtrloty •.ilium VI", muUtur* MinUnl l»rur. 1*11 KIT Avar. /*•«*• Tim* Totu Tan* 2 4.0 4.1 4.0 2 3.7 8.7 3.7 2 3.6 3.7 3.8 2 3.0 3.1 3.0 2 3.1 2.4 17 Common Millet German millet Hungarian millet . Siberian millet Broom com millet Flff. 7. — Manner of testing forage crops at tbe Experiment Station. Timothy and clover, left; permanent pasture mixture, right. Seeded August 11&gt;, 1014 ; photographed June 21, 1915 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169 E i &gt; II s . l l c u t-: 5 a: 1 -■a hill! B iie« -■-£ -^* s r 65 I IB ■ ja i BpsSr-, Zt. a - |l? III 1 1 1 S5! Ill co S"&gt; i I I "*h : : : ill ; i i ■3 t-goi oen r&lt;co&gt; &lt;ho&lt;o 3 S «*US «NO ■&lt;»»■« rH^S o 5 co M cc tc ■&gt;» co 1/3 co eo eo e&gt;i XC a I ig : io&gt; lit- i : I *J5 1 : :» i iS • i5 ill CM 5 c ,3 : : t» i 10 1&gt; i &lt;© ■ ■ • 3 ij a •' &lt;O : co &lt;N : 00 : ; • *P B •§ ioOA : OJ t- : «O O OO© .„ °_3 K |^*O :OU5 llOCO CO J3 *j J ■ 00 CO I £"• .' CC 00 tc lC C«J ■a " c c &gt;S loxt- •^"■^«cc oon 000 S-s - Mt-ec ona ocom t»oS 5C S t*'* °&gt;1*i OOtr-t- I- — !M 5^ 3 &lt;S Me*»H efnei eJ«i-T n ■yc » ei &amp; co tocoo ust^o 000 £« 1 — tc&lt;o fun ann -5 § ■ -£ 5 CC^tC MNU5 OMrH SS« fci g ig mine* Via" eg Wei eicc« .■Jjjtf C0O3CO CCCCCO COCCCC CC CO CC * I p ■S eiccio M^m nkio eceoej ■ - - a 1 1 I 1 N 1 I ! Ml li .1 Ii.ShJ ri* E ° S| ESi i|S« [is ! ! I :i Hii^iiPJijiii! » ij-s «|i li-g in | JS5« s; 22 "WM "Hejec Hcnn ihojcc I i 5 = o r S-S -5- ~* 2 - = *= ■5 % i a x S 15 F =-. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>