<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00038">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0038</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiemtnal Station-Lincoln</title>
               <date value="18??">1940???</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001"/>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">UNKNOWN </seg>
         <seg id="p004">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Personal Qualifications for Judging Dairy Products 3 Score Cards tor l)air\ Products . 3 Judging Milk 4 Milk score cards 4 Flavor and odor 5 Sediment 7 Bottle and cap 9 Terms used in scoring milk 9 Judging Cream JQ Cream score cards . . \\ Flavor and odor . _ ]2 Sediment 13 Acidity 13 Smoothness and body ]3 Terms used in judging cream 14 Judging Butter 14 Flavor and odor 16 Body t * 17 Color, salt, package ]8 Terms used in judging butter 18 Judging American Cheddar Cheese 21 Flavor 24 Body and texture 25 Finish, appearance, and color 26' Terms used in judging cheese 26 Judging Ice Cream . . 28 Flavor . „ 30 Body and texture, melting quality, color, package 31 Terms used in judging ice cream 3J Conducting a Judging Contest 33 Preparation of contest samples 3$ Use of Score Cards and Guides 37 Contests 40 Rules governing contests 41 Grading the cards 42 Methods of tabulating 43 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Judging Quality in Dairy Products ; ; p. a. downs ( IN THE DAIRY industry increasing attention is being paid to the question of quality o£ products. The well established system of.buying and selling butter and cheese on the basis of quality by score or grade j is practiced in the principal markets of the world. The other dairy pro - ducts, while not marketed by score, are receiving more and more attention • j in this respect. As more information becomes available and the judging better standardized, other dairy products will doubtless be sold by grade. PERSONAL QUALIFICATIONS FOR JUDGING DAIRY '! I ¦¦&gt;''¦ ¦'•';. '¦ PRODUCTS ' . ; j .; Tasting really includes both taste and smell. Strictly speaking, Uste in - cludes sweetness, bitterness, sourness, and saltiness, or a combination of these. No other tastes arc known and they are sensed only by the minute organs called "taste buds" on the base of the tongue. All material in order to have a taste, must be soluble. . . Most of what is ordinarily considered as taste is really derived from the sense of smell. Odors are detected by the olfactory nerve located in the nose. When food is chewed it is not only broken up but is also warmed j in the mouth so that the volatile odors or aromas are liberated. With the J mouth dosed these odors find their way through the nose, where they arc detected by this nerve. If it is desired to distinguish the fine odors of la product it should not be examined in a cold room, and cold material should be warmed to a temperature approaching 98" F. Ice cream should be held on the tongue until it is warmed.to body temperature. The presence of perfume, strong-smelling soap, tobacco, or any other material j of like nature will interfere with the detection of flavor and odors of dairy products/ That people differ in ability to taste—that is, to detect the presence of sour, sweet, bitter, and salt—has been demonstrated by Blakes.ee and Fox. 1 By the use of a test paper they have shown that the inability to j taste is. apparently transmitted as a Mendelian character. On the average, three out of ten persons failed to get a definitely bitter taste from the paper. While the inability to taste this material may not indicate inabil - ity to taste other materials that are bitter, it does show that not all per - sons have the same tasting ability. Some people may have a keener sense of smell than others and can detect odors more easily. Proper education and training in the art of tasting and classifying flavors and odors may, however, improve this ability. SCORE CARDS FOR DAIRY PRODUCTS In the judging of dairy products it has been necessary to develop score cards suitable for both commercial and school use. While these score *A. F. Bbkalce and A. L. Fox, Tasters and non-tasteri, lour, of Heredity, Vol. 28, No. 3. March, 1932. j </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 cards are basically alike, more detailed descriptions are found on the stu - dent cards. On the other hand, as in the case of the student cards for milk, cream, and ice cream, certain factors such as bacteria count and street temperature are not used in the actual process of judging, because these qualities can be determined accurately only by laboratory methods. In the development of judging work, especially in connection with edu - cational phases, the American Dairy Science Association through its com - mittee on judging of dairy products recommends certain changes in score cards from time to time. Usually the changes are confined to details of special interest to the educator rather than the commercial judge. Basic changes in the securing of these products usually originate in such organ - izations as the federal Bureau of Agricultural Economics and the Bureau of Dairy Industry, or in some other organization interested in commercial grading of these products. The methods of scoring milk and grading butter and cheese, while well established, are not considered perfect. In the case of butter a radical departure from the present system ol judging has been proposed but not yet adopted. The material set forth in this publication is in general that utilized by the dairy industry and approved by the American Dairy Science Association. Certain modifications have been recommended for instruc - tional purposes. JUDGING MILK The judging of milk is carried on under various conditions and often made use of by producers in an effort to improve the quality of the milk delivered. Educational scoring contests are used to advantage in milk - improvement programs and as a part of the regular inspection system of a city health department. In commercial milk organizations the practice of judging samples of their own product in comparison with their com - petitors' encourages the marketing of higher-quality milk. The judging of milk in colleges, high schools, and in connection with 4-H club work throughout the United States has been very successful. The information obtained in this way should awaken an interest in better milk, with the producer as well as the consumer. MILK SCORE CARDS AMD THEIR USE The card developed by the federal Bureau of Dairy Industry is used where laboratory facilities permit and includes the factors of bacteria count and street temperature or acidity. Directions for scoring are given on the back of the card, and details can be found in Circular 384, "How to Con - duct Milk and Cream Contests," by C. /. Babcock and C. S. Leete, U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1929. Score cards may be obtained in separate form. The bacteria count is determined by the plate method and acidity by titration. A score card used for instructional purposes and for judging milk where laboratory facilities are not available is given below. It agrees in all essentials with the card of the U. S. Department of Agrciulture. Certain </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 5 factors (bacteria count and temperature or acidity) are not scored and are considered as perfect on the card. Definitions of terms describing faults are furnished with other materials to the student, MILK SCORE CARD . Contestant's No.. ¦.....'......: Sample No ..... Grades Factor Sludent Official ; . Critldsmi s:ore ,-.' score Score Criticism &#132; Bacteria (-15) 45.00 FUVoll : Malty '.. ¦¦•."'•¦ - ¦ '. - : ¦•¦• _^^_ Bitler ' Metallic : ' ' ""~ Cardboard ' Musty &gt;'- ¦» -7 sr : s id &gt; — • —— 'Disinfectant Unclean '"-¦j." .... 'J Peed Weedy Sediment (10) . Plat ¦ '"¦'•- -'•' ' - • Garlic or onion Temperature or -' •'' acidity (15) 15.00 ; ... - . . . ¦- ¦¦¦¦•¦•-."¦" ¦ •.--•'• Sedlmentt See page 6 ot this Bottle and cap (5) . circular. TOTAL (100) . Bottle tad capt " ¦ -.- j ' ''..-¦¦-¦¦ Absorbent cap " . ¦ -: ! ! ¦ *'.. 'protector-. PLACING -¦¦¦"'- Chipped mouth . Diny bottle _ r -— —i" Leaky ap ¦''.'..; » ?¦'¦-.¦-.-. Up not protected' GRADE ON CRITICISMS (T0TAL).............i___i Uot 11 * ProteCted ! Unsealed cap protector TOTAL GRADE.. ............ I - Appros-cd try ihe American Dairy Science Association. JUDGING PROCEDURE The order of judging will depend upon the situation. In all cases samples should be kept at a temperature below. 50" F. until examined for flavor. The scoring for-bottle and capimust be carried out before the bottle is opened. If only one sample is available and bacteria count, acidity, or street temperatures are desired they^ should be determined as soon as possible in the order named. These should be followed by the determina - tion o£ flavor and sediment. . Flavor and odor.—Before milk is scored for flavor and odor, the bottles of milk should be placed in warm water until the milk attains a tempera - ture of 70° to 90° F. Faint odors are more easily detected at these tem - peratures than when'milk is cold. Scoring should be done in a room free from odors. The sample should be well mixed before being opened and part of the contents should be poured into a clean cup or glass. Smell at once the open container of milk and note any odor that may be present. Flavors are determined by tasting the milk. It is well to sip the milk . slowly and allow it to remain in contact with the tongue for a short time. During this time the mouth should be closed and the breath slowly passed out through the nose. Odors that may have been overlooked by the first </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 6 Fie, I.—Standard disks for scoring sediment in milk. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 7 smelling arc usually detected by this method. The cups or glasses should be rinsed with water before new samples are poured in. and the judge may rinse his mouth with water or chew a piece of apple. While no definite ratings can be given that will cover all varieties and intensities of flavors and odors, the following general guide may be used: Description of flavor Hating Pleasant, full flavor, free from defects (no criticism required) ... 23.0 to 25.0 Lacking full flavor, flat, very slight feed, slightly cooked. ;... 21.0 ta'22s Co£ked flavor, feed, salty, slightly cowy, slightly metallic, slightly bitter, slightly weedy or malty .....i.... .....:...... 18.0 to 20.5 Strong feed, weedy, garlic, bitter, unclean, musty, cowy, slighdy high acid, slightly rancid, or cardboard (cappy).. 12.0 to 17.5 Rancid, strong cowy, high add. 0.0 to 11.5 Fio. 2,—Types of sediment testers, with cotton disks. Samples that are sour or have disinfectant or other off flavors so bad as to make the milk unsalable must score 0 in flavor and odor. Cuts of less than half points are not used except in case of a tie, when quarter points are used. -.-'.. Sediment—Sediment may be scored either by direct observation of the bottom of the bottle or by the use of the sediment tester disk (Fig. 1). The latter method is preferable where the equipment (Fig, 2) is available When sediment is scored in the bottle the samples should stand undisturbed for at least an hour before being scored. Each bottle is then examined in a good light by lifting carefully without tipping until the bottom can be seen. To score "perfect," not so much as a single movable speck is allowable in the bottom of the botde. When sediment is present, points must be deducted according to the quality. The following scores are sug - gested where a pint of milk is scored.; </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 8 Number of tiny particles _,_, g Numb „ of No perceptible trace 10.0 Four to six tiny particles 9 7 One » n ro nny p^ „ p.p Sj . , o cj •• • ¦ Two to four tiny pamcles 9.8 Eight to ten tiny particles 9.6 Further reductions arc based on quality and character of sediment. For instance, a hair would cause a 0.5 point cut. When a sediment tester is available the sediment may be scored by grading the sediment disk from one pint of milk. The milk should be B___§_l B____l B' ¦¦^| E£jßW£^fl ____________|_____c I ¦ -.¦¦' 3__ ¦A' __| BS B tmmti' ''¦I - -¦ '--I ' ej^v'.' ;j vm -¦'¦¦ ¦ n-'-. : :; a^e7k' ;j:*7^*^^B m ________SHiSi^^J ; .B ____________?_i ___*^^^^^^^^^^_1 I RE ¦ tIIJB \aaaass^*^saaaaaa\ ________* *--*s*^^^^_3-**&gt;w*^^B r . BM^._j^Ml-&gt;---l MBtSyi?'s"^--B mm?t:"^PP?P--&amp;:rfims\ _______r^avW* k________r&lt;" • -"*¦»'" __¦ ____¦¦-*.'s'.'"';V*'.-:'r/';,'*vJ^_M - r-&lt;--. '-_- - - ¦.'. I *-'&lt;j f- - 7 &gt;lc-_________i .........^ V&gt;-"'f ¦' -""¦'^" _. ¦7 &#132;.- .-73____ V - *¦ _p|^-#wl -.-t %;_l^4 i: -*-/4^H ______»-¦"'. -'-¦''^r':"';___B ____B^^^*-^^.-^*^_fst^_______B Fig. 3.—Bottle and cap camples prepared to show certain faults. Criticism 1. Lip partially protected (0.25) _°I' 2. Lip partially protected (0.50). Not full (0.50) sm 3 Unsealed up pro , ra&lt;&gt; , «)._5) "JW 4. Lip not protected (1.0). Chipped lip (0.50) ,£ 5. Up partialis- proiccicd (0.25). Not full (0.25)... vX ':£_*££. r,:, (pipto (0; 2S)- UnK-w °»"™-n"''as)..:.:::.::.: «S «. Lip not protccced 9. Abwrbem cap cover .eh«... cloth) (0.50)! Unsealed «'p protector (6.25)'.'.'.'.'.] 415 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 9 warmed slightly before it is run through the tester, as it will pass through the cotton disk much more quickly. A perfectly clean disk will score 10 with cuts for increasing amounts o£ sediment. Figure 1 will give an idea of the numerical ratings given to the disks. While only half-point cuts are shown, finer gradings are often made. Usually whole points are used between 0 and 7, and half points. between 7 and 8, one - quarter points between 8 and 9.5, and one-tenth points between 9.5 and 10. (See suggested scores in paragraph above for this last group.) Bottle and cap.-—All samples should be in milk bottles. Deductions in score are made for dirty or chipped botdes, bottles not full, and for caps which;do not cover the lips of the bottles or which do not fit properly in the cap seats (Fig. 3). The top of the botde may be covered with parch - ment paper, metal foil, or some other covering impervious to water and dust. To obtain a perfect score, the covering must be securely sealed so that i^cannot be removed without breaking the seal. If the botde is closed with the usual cardboard milk cap, the pouring lip is unprotected and cut accordingly. It is also cut if covered with absorbent material such as cloth or common paper. Types of defect Suggested cuts Bottle not fu11...... 0.25 to 1.0 Between 'A to "_ inch........... 0.25 cut Between 14 to 54 inch. &#132;..0.50 cut Between }ft to I inch........... 0.75 cut •.-.'•'¦' Over 1 inch.. ....... 1.00 cut. ."'¦''- Dirty bottle (dirt inside of bottle): . .... ... ..... 0.5 to 2.0 Cap poorly seated or leaky (if uncovered). 7 0.1 to L 0 Chipped lip ......... 0.1 to 0.5 Pouring Up unprotected...;. .-.-.*.................... P..... ¦ 1.0 .- Pouring lip partially pr0tected................ •'...'. 0.25 to 0.75 Cap covering non-water proof.. 0.25 to 0.75 Unsealed cap protector.....! ...!................... &#132;..; 0.25 ' '.-¦ TERMS USED IN SCORING MILK Flavor criticisms: - BITTER—-A bitter taste may be caused by stripper cows, bacterial action, or certain feeds. CARDBOARD— A flavor which resembles the odor and taste of wet cardboard, sometimes called "cappy". It is caused by action of metallic salts, especially copper salts. :- - . COOKED- 1-/, custard or caramel flavor caused by pasteurization or heating of milk to too. higb-a temperature. , COVVV—A flavor or odor which resembles the smell of cows. This flavor usually indicates a lack of cleanliness in the barn, where the milk absorbs the cowy odor while being handled. DISINFECTANT—Any flavor which might be due to the use of chemical disin - fectants around the cows. Very objectionable and easily avoided. FEED or FEEDY—Usually more common in the winter and early yspring and caused by strong-flavored feeds such as certain roots or silage. All strong-flavored feeds should be fed after milking. FLAT—When milk lacks a full, pleasing flavor it is spoken of as being flat or tasteless. This flavor is due cither to the condition of the cow or lack of high-flavored feed. '¦¦¦¦' </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 10 GARLIC or ONION—A flavor found in milk from cows which have been eating wild garlic or onion. Very objectionable and can seldom be removed from the milk. Cows should be removed from infested pastures three or four hours before milking. HIGH ACID—As bacteria grow in milk they ferment the lactose into lactic acid. The first appearance of such acidity is referred to as "high acid." A pronounced "high acid" flavor is called "sour". "Sour" milk is not salable. MALTY—A flavor resembling that of malt. Often due to the development of cer - tain bacteria and usually indicates unclean conditions. METALLIC—This flavor gives the impression of holding a piece of metal in the mouth between the teeth. It is often caused by the presence of metallic salts in the milk due to handling milk in rusty cans or pails. MUSTY—A flavor suggesting a musty or moldy condition. It may be due to feed - ing musty feed or the storage of milk in a musty cellar or milk house. RANCID—A flavor characteristic of spoiled butter or resembling the • flavor of butyric acid. It is due to the decomposition of the butterfat. In milk it may be due to the condition of the cow or the feeding of rancid feeds. SALTY—SaIty flavor is often due to a high sodium chlorine content and is often found in milk from cows affected with mastitis or garget. UNCLEAN—FIavor and odor which one would find in unclean utensils especially ibose improperly washed. Very objectionable and can easily be prevented. WEEDY—A feed flavor characteristic of certain weeds eaten by the cow. Often found in milk during the dry season when good feed is short in pastures. Often resembles a svood flavor, due to the dry condition of weeds. Bottle and cap criticisms: ABSORBENT CAP PROTECTOR—A term used to indicate that the cap protector or hood is absorbent and not waterproof. CHIPPED MOUTH —The moutb of the bottle cither at the cap seat or on the pouring lip should be free from chipped places. Such places are difficult to clean and are considered a defect. DIRTY BOTTLE—Refers to the condition of the inside of the bottle. Any con - dition which indicates an unclean bottle where it comes in contact with the milk is objectionable. LEAKY CAP —One that leaks or drips milk when the bottle is inverted. The ex - pansion of milk in bottles often forces milk out around the cap, bur if the cap is properly seated it will not leak or drip svhen inverted. LIP PARTIALLY PROTECTED—Certain kinds of milk caps partly cover the pouring iip but not completely. Such conditions are designated by the above term. UNSEALED CAP COVERING—AII hood cap covers or protectors should be securely fastened so that tbey cannot be removed svithout detection. When this is not the case this term is used as an unfavorable criticism. NOT FULL—A bottle of milk should be full to within one-fourth inch of the cap. JUDGING CREAM The judging of cream can be carried on wherever samples are avail - able. No equipment is necessary except something to be used as a tasting rod. a place to wash the rod after each sample is tasted, paper towels for wiping the tasting rod, and a waste jar. Cream may be classified as bottled cream for household use and com - mercial cream in cans. It is used in both the sweet and the sour condition. Sweet cream, having a greater variety of uses, demands a higher price, but the fact that cream is sour does not make it unsalable, provided it is of suitable quality. The quality of butter to a large extent depends upon the flavors present in the cream rather than the acidity, provided the cream </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 11 is not too sour. Smoothness and body are important factors in good cream. For butter making a thin cream is expensive to handle, and when it sours often develops curd lumps which are objectionable. Cream which contains sediment or extraneous matter is not acceptable for food purposes by the Food and Drug Administration of the United States Department of Agri - culture. __¦__*%--' ___E*!: __•*¦*- -^55^ I S^F&gt; WfciiiH IP%' ¦nSTH ammjlsP "--'-' [il mmm. ___Ci':^_____itS_s aamMWfiißS^aa W.S_*-. Jt7Pr:^aaat ---¦--.¦-..:-¦:- PP2J*2m _-_-t.f-. mmati^-'^r. p*^7sV B£_*7m j_l_r _________________________[ lß__a.' ¦ ta_______L_____s___l _____^_______F:^_____________D.^___________H __¦&lt;-*-S_^fc_: I V!IB_..^I ¦¦ B*--' 7___N _¦____¦_&amp;- '-A &lt;w \J ____1 ____r*'- -s7"6_*_'-.*^'- __^________L. "¦****«_?. S______________ *^^^ _l!P!**^^_r7 •'.•.-'¦ Fio. 4.—Cream is used in households in large quantities and should be of the •-:•'¦ fiighcst quality. CREAM SCORE CARDS AND THEIR USE The card' developed by the U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Dairy Industry, is used for scoring sweet cream in bottles intended for household use. This type of cream approaches the requirement for fluid milk and is judged on the same basis. The card used 1 for the scoring of commercial cream and presented be - low takes into consideration the requirements for this type of product. Where laboratory facilities are available the complete score card may be used, including bacteria and yeast and mold count of the cream. Samples showing a total colony count of less than 500 per cubic centimeter, as determined by the use of skimmilk, acidified malt, or other suitable agars </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 used in the determination of proteolytic bacteria and yeast and mold, should be considered perfect. A deduction of 0.1 point for each additional 1,000 colonies should be made. Where laboratory faciltics are not avail - able and when judging cream quality is done for instructional purposes, bacteria and yeast and mold count can be considered perfect. JUDGING PROCEDURE Where the yeast and mold count is to be determined, this should be done first, before the sample is subjected to any contamination. The sample can then be warmed and scored for the other points in any order desired. cream score card C_n.oi.m-. No Sample No. Factor ' Student I official 2__! ¦- i »»'- ' score Score j Criticism Criticisms Bacteria count («) j 15.00 j j FUvon r —! Flat Cooked Hum (251 I ' B,"'r Disinfectant Cosvy Garlic or onion ¦ "— - ' Feed Yeasiy i i j Musty Metallic Scdimen. (10) | I | _,*„ Unc * u „ .... '_._ _! | Weedy Watery ""- . j Rancid Greasy ¦"&lt;"'-'&gt; (15) j . I ) _ I I Acidity! Smoothness and ;" " j ' ~ Slightly sour "** &lt;5&gt; Medium sour ! 1 Very sour I I Rank sour TOTAL (100) | . | I 1 I | l l SmoolhnciS and body: "AC,SG Thin Boiling _ I 1 I __ Dirty Too thick I Moldy Curd lumps TOTAL GRADE ) ) 1 Flavor and odor.—The determination of flavor and odor in cream is carried out in the same manner as with milk. The samples should be at a temperature of 70° to 90° F. when examined. A glass or composition rod about the size of a lead pencil is dipped into the cream and a small amount is transferred to the mouth. The cream is tasted and the flavor and odor determined. The following material is given as a guide in determining the score for certain flavor defects. Description of flavor Rating Full flavor, free from defects 23.0 to 25.0 Lacking flavor (flat), very slight feed, slightly cooked or watery 21.0 to 22.5 Cooked flavor, feed, salty, or slightly cowy 18.0 to 20.5 Strong feed, weedy, bitter, musty, cowy, yeasty, or unclean 12.0 to 17.5 Rancid, greasy, metallic, onion, or garlic 0.0 to 11.5 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Judging Quautv in Dairy Products Samples showing disinfectant or coal oil, or defects pronounced enough to produce butter scoring 87 or below, &lt;score 0. Sediment—Sediment should be scored by the examination of a sedi - ment disk prepared by filtering four ounces of cream through the regula - tion cotton sediment disk used for milk. A perfecdy clean disk will score 10, with deductions for increasing amounts of sediment. The same system of grading should be used as in the case of milk. (See page 6.) Method of Determining Sediment- in Commercial Cream 1. Use four ounces of cream. 2. Pour the cream into die filtering bottle (if such a filter is used) or into a mix - ing vessel. .:.'.,: I 3. Add 'A teaspoon of baking soda, or commercial soda ash or sesquicarbonate of soda and stir or shake Until the neutralizcr has been mixed with the cream. • .. Rinse out the sample jar which held the cream with at.least 180° F. water (distilled or cleaned), pour this rinse into the cream, and thoroughly mix again. 5. Add enough water to 180° F. or above to dilute this mixture to about one pint. 6. Then filter through a Rapid-Flo filter disk (Johnson and Johnson). The mix - ture should at least be 160° F. before filtering; higher temperatures arc desir - able on some cream. (Do not heat the mixture.) All water and containers must be clean. Water can be cleaned by filter - ing it through disks similar to those used to filter cream. Acidity.—Acidity can be detected by taste and measured by titration. In judging, usually the taste has to be .depended upon/but the opinion of the judge may be checked against the jitratable acidity present. This acidity is determined by titrating nine cubic centimeters of cream with one-tenth normal sodium hydroxide solution, using phenophthalein as an indicator. The number of cubic centimeters required divided by 10 gives the per - centage of titratabk acidity expressed as lactic acid." Suggested range of ratings Rating Criticism Score Acidity test Sweet cream.......... 13.0 to 15.0 0.12 to 0.24 Slightly sour.... .......... 10.0,t0 12.5 0.25 to 0.35 Medium sour. 7.0; to 9.9 -"-. ¦ 0.36 to 0.60 Very sour.. 5.0 to 6.9 0.60 to 0.80 Rank 50ur.................. 0.0(to 15 over 0.80 Smoothness and body.—Smoothness and body should be scored by observing the condition of the cream as it clings to the sampling rod as well as by the feel on the tongue. A perfect score would be allowed for a sample of cream, free from curd lumps, dirt, mold, and having a smooth i even hody of medium thickness. '¦';:¦'" '¦ -. -j- i Suggested range of ratings . ;..-.'..¦.¦-¦...-. Rating Free from curd lumps, dirt, and mold with even, smooth body of reasonable thickness ...............:}... , 4,5 ro 5.0 Small amount of curd lumps, slightly too thick or slighUy too thin in body ....;............ 4.0 to ... Large amount of curd lumps,. too thick or too thin; slight boiling; dirty. 3.5 to 3.9 Cream thar is moldy, boiling, or dirty.. ..'j........ '.......; 2.0 t0.3.4 'Sediment is sometimes called exti-iteou. matter. ¦Philip A. Wright, Testing Milk and Cream, U. S. D. A. Misc. Pub. No. 161, 1933. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricu.ti.ra_. Experiment Station Circular 54 TERMS USED IN JUDGING CREAM Flavor criticisms! BITTER—A bitter taste which may be caused by feed or the separation of milk from stripper cows. COOKED—This flavor, also referred to as "heated", resembles that of cream which has been overheated. May be caused by overpasteurizing or allowing the can of cream to stand in the hot sun until the cream has become heated. COWY—A flavor or odor which resembles the smell of a cow. Caused by the absorppon of the cosvy odor in the barn while the milk or cream is being handled DISINFECTANT—Any flavor svhich might be due to the use of chemical disin - fectants around the cream. Very objectionable and easily prevented. FEED—lndicates the flavor resembling that of feed. Usually found in the spring and fall svhen the feeding of roots and silage is in progress or tbe cows are on wheat or rye pasture. Al! such feed should be fed after milking. GARLIC—A common flavor due to wild garlic in pastures. This can be corrected by removing cows from the pasture three or four hours before milking. METALLIC—This flavor resembles that which is noticed when metal is held in the m°..V;_-!V S ?"*'. by ha"Ay 'aB die milk or cream in rusted pails, cans, or separators. MI/SIT—An odor or flavor often associated with a moldy or damp cellar. Cream which has mold growing in it will often show a musty flavor. ONION—A flavor like that of onion caused by cows having eaten wild onion. It on be eliminated in the same manner as garlic flavor. SALTY—A salty flavor may be due to salt being added or may be found in cream from cows svhich have mastitis. UNCLEAN UTENSILS—A flavor due to an unclean condition, especially of the utensils. It borders somesvhat on a musty flavor. WATERY—Used to describe a condition caused by the addition of water to the cream or by excessive rinsing of the separator or cans. T EEJ_ V—A flaV°r rcs,:mbl'nB *••* °£ drying weeds. Caused by the cows eating .seeds. This defect can be reduced by removing the cosvs from the source of feed three to four hours before they arc milked. YEASTY— A flavor or odor resembling those resulting from alcoholic fermentation produced by yeast. It develops rapidly when cream is held at temperatures of 80' to 10(1° F. and results in much foaming or boiling and sometimes a bitter flavor. It can ' be retarded by holding at losver temperatures. Smoothness and body criticisms: BOILING—If yeast is actively growing in aan of cream to the extent that carbon dioxide is formed fast enough to cause foaming, it is referred to as boiling. ( C^RD LUMPS—When •*¦'•¦ "™m becomes sour it has a tendency to produce lumps nt curd. If the cream becomes quite warm these lumps contract and become hard. DIRT— Panicles of dirt or other foreign matter arc sometimes found on the surface of cream or are visible to the eye during examination. , mol-D—When cream is held for some time a mold growth (Oorpora fart... often develops on the surface. TOO THICK—Used when cream is so high in fat that it will not flow. THlN—Cream that is watery and low in fat does not keep well and is expensive to handle and transport. This may be due to rinse water being added to the cream. JUDGING BUTTER The judging ot butter is a well-established practice and has been used as a means of grading that product in the major markets of the United States for many years. By this means the federal and private judges grade large amounts of butter which is sold on the market on a graded basis. In the industry the practice of scoring butter by individuals interested in </seg>
         <seg id="p017">¦•'¦•¦ I.' - ¦ &gt; Judging Quality in Dairy Products 15 -the purchase or sale of butter is common. Factory shipments are often scored and sold on the basis of grade. National contests among the'manu - facturers of butter are held from time to time. The place of butter judg - ing in the dairy industry makes such judging of great interest and import - ance. ''¦'.' BUTTER SCORE CARDS AND THEIR USE While the types of butter range from high-quality creamery butter, both salted and unsalted, to dairy butter, the same score card is used for all. The highest-quality product scores 93 to 94 and the lowest scores as low as 867 Butter scoring 92 or over is I often referred to commercially as 9______ _-ll^l^-'^ii____j _B m^A?___jj_\ W^Ta^. . m Eg_»«S ¦ __l'^__l B^^Sl BMam ma\P -_______[ ______k",'A* _______________________________________________________________ _________' ___________________________________*_--i __¦ '°':-^H H ¦&lt;____ Kv!Tf^*P^&amp;s". 7'"7-3_HB ¦ i£P&gt;*| mmM ____|_;;-':-:&gt;^3__i___l'____.|s__a rt^___fl l___r ______ _____L, _____3__________________*j____i E^ »'^i i^i kj n i I^l niKai _s_i I PV^' 1 ''719K' ¦_r_i SiMi I j 'jMfc' jUi 'I^BrM|___i_________Bn ¦ __r,__^ l_r__ __ Fio. 5.—A fine, dean flavor is essential in high-quality butter. "extras", while butter scoring 90 is designated as "Chicago standards". The score card used for grading purposes consists of a card of suitable size with space for information describing the lot of butter. The score is based upon the factors of flavor, which'is allowed 45 points; body, 25 points; color, 15 points; salt, 10 points; and package, 5 points: making a total of 100 points. For instructional work the following score card is used, based upon the same number of points, but with additional details and terms. In the judg - ing of butter many different types of butter packages are encountered as shown in Figure 6. It is important regardless of type of package that a representative sample be obtained by the use of a trier. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 butter score card Contatant'i No. Sample No » j ~,r- ¦ . Grade* Factor Slud&lt;:nt officlal __=_— score score e enr . ~*M ' ""' cism Criticisms Flavor (45) Flavor: _ Acidy Woody Storage Briny Muity Cheesy Body (25) Cowy Bitter Neutralize Feed Garlic Gasoline Fiiby Cooked' Metallic Color (15) fat 0«"V pU cream / Coanc Heated Unclean Oily Yeatty Burnt Weedy Rancid Tallowy Sail (10) - . — Body: Gummy Mealy Sticky l'acta ß e (5) Graiy s _| v&gt; . Cloudy brine ! I Ipiliv Weak Crumbly TOTAL (100) eh,. i i ! Colorjpccks Mottled '¦ I ] White specks Wavy PLACING | Uneven ; J J I I : Salt: GRADE ON CRITICISMS (TOTAL) | Gritty ' i Packa 1 ge: \ 1 Dirty tub Poor finish TOTAL GRADE | . ] I Appro\cd by Ihc American Dairy Science Association. JUDGING PROCEDURE Butter can best be judged by the use of a long butter trier which will reach well into the butter, thus getting away from the exposed surface of the package. The trier should be inserted as flir as desired, turned one revolution, and pulled out of the butter. It should be passed immediately under the nose so that the aroma can be observfcd. It should then be ex - amined by good light for color defects. The bqdy should be determined by the presence of free water on the plug as well as the resistance of the plug to the finger when pressed against it. A small amount of butter should then be placed in the mouth for the judging of flavor. The con - dition of the package should be observed before the work with the par - ticular sample is finished. Flavor and odor.—The small amount of butter that is placed in the mouth should be allowed to melt on the tongue. The mouth should .be kept closed so that the volatile products will pass out through the nose where they can be better detected. The odor should be determined by smelling the freshly drawn plug of butter as soon as possible after it is removed from the package. The temperature of the room where the iudeintj is carried on should be such that the butter will remain firm but not too cold, as this prevents the detection of flavors to the best advantage. The atmosphere must be free from odors of all kinds which might interfere with the sense of smell </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 17 of the judge. The trier should be free from exposed steel and must be wiped clean after each sample. While definite ratings will vary with the intensity of the flavor and odor defects, the following guide may be used. I IJ IJ P '"'^Si'^l Paßßst'sßßsl iSa^^9 iSBBMH Ssf'iVaSSSSBSBsI PsBSSSSSSSBSSSBSBsJ SaSsS SSSSSsTjia Fio. 6.—Types of butter packages (left to right): 3-pound paper uih, 5-pound tin . can, 1 -pound prim, 2-pound roll, 'A -pound prims, and 64-pound wooden tub. Description of flavor Rating Fresh, fine, sweet, and clean, if fresh make; or fine, sweet, and clean if storage butter (no criueism required) 38 0 to 39 0 Fresh, sweet, and clean if fresh make; or sweet and clean if storage; also very slight feed, coarse, or flat 37 0 to 375 Burnt, oily, heated, neutralizcr, yeasty, feedy, briny, storage, cowy, actdy, cheesy, weedy, cooked, or tallowy to a slight degree...... 35.5 to 36 5 I renounced burnt, oily, heated, storage, neutralizcr, cowy, yeasty, cheesy, weedy, or feedy. Slightly metallic, woody, bitter, or un - clean. Very slight old cream ;.... _ 33 5 t0 35 q Old cream, unclean, or musty. Slight gasoline, lime, fishy, or metallic 32.0 to 33!u Garlic, gasoline, rancid, pronounced or stale old cream, pronounced oily, metallic, or cheesy.: :.:.'. 300 to 31 5 Body.—The body should be determined by the examination of the trier and plug of butter for excessive amounts of free moisture (drops of water). The clearness of such moisture should also be observed. The thumb should be pressed into the plug of butter to determine the firmness and its ability to hold the incorporated moisture. Inability to hold this moisture is spoken of as leakiness. The ideal body should have a firm waxy texture, and perfect grain, as indicated by a jagged or irregular toothed edge, when butter is broken apart. It should be free from salviness or excess free moisture and should not show a milky brine. Description of body jj^ Firm, waxy and good grain. \ 250 Crumbly, greasy, leaky, mealy, salvy, sticky, weak, gummy, or cloudy brine to a pronounced degree...,.;.... .......... 240 to 255 Any of the above to a very pronounced degree .........'..'..;.'...'." 23!0 to 23 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 Color.—The plug of butter should be observed in an abundance of day - light and any unevenness of color noted. The presence of specks or extreme orange or yellow color is objectionable. Description of color Sating Uniform color throughout—may be light, medium, or full golden yellow 15.0 Color specks (reddish orange), mottled, uneven wavy, or white specks 13.0 to H. 5 Salt—The amount of salt in butter may vary from none to a rather high salt content. This variation is not objectionable provided the salt present is completely dissolved. Description of salt Rating Uniform and all dissolved—may be light, medium, or heavy 10.0 Undissolved or gritty 9.0 to 9.5 Package.—The butter must be neatly and properly packed in a sound package which is clean and free from mold. Description oi package Rating Neatly packed in clean, sound packages .5.0 Dirty tubs or container or poor finish 4.0 to 4.5 TERMS USED IN JUDGING BUTTER Flavor criticisms: ACIDY —Applied to butter which has an acid flavor. It is due to the churning of high-acid cream and is common during hot weather and in highly flavored butter. BITTER —A bitter taste which may be caused by cream from stripper cows or cream which has developed a bitter taste from bacterial action. BRINY—A condition due to unincorporated brine due to improper working. Such butter will have a much more salty taste than the butter with the moisture properly incorporated and having the same amount of salt BURNT or SCORCHED —Very similar to a cooked flavor, but more pronounced and more disagreeable. More commonly found in butter made from neutralized sour cream, pasteurized at a high temperature. CHEESY or CURDY—These terms are used whenever butter has a flavor which resembles that found in fresh cheese or curd. Usually caused by churning thin, sour cream in which the curd has coagulated; by using a starter which is too sour; or by leaving too much buttermilk in the butter. COARSE —This refers only to the flavor and indicates that the butter is lacking in fine, swcct-cream flavor, which is required for fine butter which will score 93 or better. The term is used in describing 92-score butter and is usually the result of not grading the cream closely enough. A can or two of cream of questionable flavor or quality added to a vat of fine cream may be the cause of a "coarse" flavor in sweet - cream butter. COOKED—A custard or caramel flavor caused by improper pasteurization or heat - ing the cream to too high a temperature. Usually appears in butter made from cream of high quality. COWY or BARNY—A flavor or odor which resembles the smell of a cow. Usually indicates lack of clean methods of milking and the milk and cream absorbing cowy or barny odors which later show up in the finished butter. FEED or FEEDY—Usually more common in the winter and early spring and caused by strong-flavored feeds such as certain roots or silage. All strong-flavored feeds should be fed only after milking. FlSHY—Suggests an odor or taste resembling that of dried fish. It is characteristic of butter of poor keeping quality and is a very serious defect. It may be caused by </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 19 absorption from being stored near fish, from feed condition, or bacterial action. The development of the defect is intensified by the presence of metallic salts in the butter. FLAT—Used when butter lacks the pronounced delicate flavor and aroma character - istic of superior-quality butter. Due to churning sweet cream without starter, cream from stripper cows, excessive washing of butter, and excessive dilution of cream with water.' GARLlC—Caused by the cows' eating wild garlic. Objectionable and can seldom be removed from milk or cram. Butter made from cream produced on pastures con - taining this plant often has the characteristic flavor. GASOLINE—Caused by exposing the milk, cream, or butter to the fumes of gas - oline. This happens by permitting gasoline engines to operate too close to the milk or &gt; cream or by contaminating the cream cans with gasoline. Cans should never be used ' for cream after they have had this product in them. Cream or butter having this flavor • is practically useless as a food. ¦'"_.' " HEATED—This term does not have reference to overheating of the cream in the process of pasteurization, but is a flavor characteristic of butter made during extremely hot weather where cither the cream has been subjected to the hot sun while in the cream cans, or the butter has been exposed at some time to the direct heat of the sun and becomes very soft. Either condition will result in a flat, greasy-tasting butter which is commonly described as "heated". METALLlC—Suggests the taste of metal or the odor, which may be noticed when the cover is removed from.a rusty cream.can.. MUSTY—Suggests a moldy vegetable cellar. NEUTRALIZER—An alkaline flavor, resulting from the improper use of alkali as a neutralizcr or overneutralized cream. OlLY—Butter-oil taste in butter which may be due to various causes, such as exposing cream to the hot sun, causing the butterfat to form a film of butter-oil around the Inside walls of the can. OLD CREAM—Suggests the use of stale cream in the manufacture of the butter. May be caused by unclean separator, mixing sweet and sour cream, or not cooling the cream on the farm. RANCID—-A rancid or strong flavor characteristic of old butter of poor keeping quality. It is due to the decomposition of the butterfat and is common as a decomposi - tion product of practically all animal fats and oils. It may be caused by molds and bacteria as well as enzyme and chemical action. When present to a pronounced extent butter is no longer salable for table use. .'¦ STORAGE—This flavor develops in butter held for any considerable time in cold : storage. The butter gradually loses some of its delicate flavor and aroma and develops this peculiar flavor. It develops more quickly in inferior butter than in the better types. The exact cause has not been demonstrated but it is believed to be due to chem - ical changes. TALLOWY—Refers to butter which shows a distinct taste and odor of tallow. Very often bleaching of the color can be noticed in tallowy butter. The defect is caused by exposure to air, light, and heat, by metallic salts in the cream or an excess of neutralizcr. This defect, like ''rancidity", makes the butter unfit for market use. UNCLEAN—This term is; used whenever the. butter has a flavor or odor which is objectionable and foreign to butter and suggests unclean conditions. Flavors of this kind usually originate in dirty conditions somewhere in the handling of milk and cream on the farm. Improperly cleaned cream separators or milking machines, or careless methods used in milking are the most common causes of flavors which we describe as "unclean." WEEDY—The taste.of certain weeds that cows have eaten. WOODY—A flavor not very common but occurring at times. Resembles the odor of new wood and is usually due to new churns, paddles or other wooden equipment which had not been properly treated before being used. Some bacteria and mold, as well as wash water and wooden packages, may be responsible for the flavor in butter. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 YEASTY a flavor and odor resembling those resulting from alcoholic fermenta - tions produced by yeasts. In the advanced stages of fermentation a bitter taste often develops in the rrenm » ivcll ,1&lt; much foaming. Butter made of low-quality cream usually shows indications of this flavor. Body and texture criticisms: CLOUDY URINE—The incorporated water in salted butter is referred to as brine When drawing a plug of butter with the trier, droplets of brine will appear on the surface If this b dourly (not clear) to a marked degree, it is spoken of as cloudy hnne It "caused by improper washing and working of the butter and is often asso - ciated with leaky butter. CRUMBLY—This characteristic, sometimes described by the term "brittle", refers to buner wh.rh does not siirfc together. It fails to draw a satisfactory plug and does not cut or spread readily. Usually found in fall, winter, and early spring due to the hard condition of the fat globules. ' GREASY—With this type of body the butter is not waxy in appearance but has the J™ of 'oft Rrcas&lt;:- U"»lly «»&gt;c to overworking, especially when the butter is '-FAKY-The moisture has not been properly incorporated and the butter shows considerable tree moisture, which drips off of the trier. MEALY—Huttcr showing a granular or mealy condition. May be due to pasteurizing "i ii mas br caused by an "oiling off" of the butter-oil when butter is added to the a. am lor n pasteurization, or by improper neutralization of sour cream. s.U.VY-This tern, is used to describe butter in which the grain has been destroyed 1.. the extent that the texture resembles that of lard. It may be due to overworking i cry firm butter, especially when lacking in moisture. WEAK—A condition used to describe butter which lacks the desired firmness and standing up properties. Usually caused by churning cream too soon after pasteuriza - tion or without cooling to a low enough temperature to secure proper firmness of the butlcrtat before churning. Color Criticisms: COLOR SPECKS—Reddish yellow specks throughout the buttct due to sediment in the butter color used. Mtn-n.ES—An uncvenntss of color in the body of butter is shown in the form of spots (mottles) of lighter an.l deeper shades of yellow. This is caused by the uneven distribution of the salt and is a very serious defect on the market. UNEVEN'—When different lots of butter of different shatlcs of yellow arc packed together, the package will show an uneven color. WAVY—When the uncvenness of color in the butter is shown in the form of streaks or waves it is referred to as "wavy". Caused by uneven working and work - ing remnants ot olhrr churning! into the butter. WHITE SPECKS—Larue numbers of small white specks (curd specks) through - out the butter is due to the incorporation of small particles of coagulated casein \lso caused by starter or cream being allowed to enter the churn without proper straining. Salt Criticisms: GRITTY-When butter is gritty between the teeth it usually contains some undis - solved .salt due to insufficient working of the butter. Gritty butter is very often wavy or mottled in color. 3 DIRTY TUB-The butter tub should be clean in order to be pleasing to the eye of the purchaser, Tubs ot butter which are ob.ectionably soiled or dim- arc crhiciz d unless the judge is otherwise directed. Package Criticisms: POOR FINISH—The surface of the butter in the package as well as the nancr used to cover the hotter should be smooth and have a pleasing appearance. When h" S h | not the case it is spoken of as "poor finish". ' </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Judging Quality in Dairy Products JUDGING AMERICAN CHEDDAR CHEESE The judging of American cheddar cheese in the United States markets is well established. Standards and grades are accepted and are used to guide the producer, dealer, and consumer in the buying and selling of cheese. The United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Agri - cultural Economics, carries on cheese scoring and grading work in the principal markets of this country. A fundamental knowledge of the practice of judging cheese is of importance to those interested in the pro - duction as well as the consumption of cheese. iisl P^! I I *± A w%m U ssssssssT^wJ ssMT? .riVa.) I 1 Ml BfEIJ sssss^sssV'.l IWKSPI P^ffi SBSBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBBn&amp; ¦¦¦ * isaßsEeSlM&amp; . tii2rTtfKTC^7^i^BaaKs&gt;t?^WaSHB MM Wkl: ':' '%sb^ sasMl Fig. 7.—High-quality cheddar cheese in a convenient-sized package. American cheddar cheese is made and marketed in several styles or shapes known commercially as cheddars, flats (single or twin), daisies (single, double, or triple), young Americas, squares (5 and 10 pounds), and Long Horns. The shape of the cheese does not affect the scoring of cheese made from whole milk. Skimmed, part skimmed, and process cheeses are not included in this class and should be scored by different standards. CHEESE SCORE CARDS AND THEIR USE On the question of the best score card for American cheddar cheese some difference of opinion seems to exist. For that reason there are two score cards in use. The one used by the inspection service of the United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Agricultural Economics, and j set forth in U. S. D. A. Circular 157, is as follows: </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 _, Score Havor ,„ Body and texture 40 Finish and appearance ' on 0)101 !!"""""!!'.!""'.!!"; io Total 100 It will be noted that the number of points allowed for body and texture is greater than that for flavor. No doubt this is due to the fact that commercially the body of the cheese determines its value more than the flavor. »\lsr^^H Bsaa^V Fio. B.—Steps in examining cheese. The score card used throughout this country in educational work and approved by the American Dairy Science Association is shown below. Inis card allots 45 points for flavor and 30 points for body and only 15 points for finish. In addition there is certain descriptive matter useful for instructional purposes. JUDGING PROCEDURE The samples of cheese properly labeled should be allowed to stand at room temperatures for a few hours before they are scored. This allows the cheese to become warm after being removed from storage and gives </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Judging Qus\lity in Dairy Products : cheese score card Contcttant't No .... ' ¦¦-'¦. Sample No .v..... - . «.-¦ t . Grade* Factor, ¦&lt;£? &lt;%? ;SOTe Grid. Critic,™ ¦¦¦ acore cum ¦¦ • Fl"°&lt; (45). fe fcmaxKi UMT -I 1 : 1 — Bitter Flat Randd Body end Cowy Proity Weedy tenure (30) Feed Unclean Yeasty Body end teatnra Finish (15) Corky Gassy Spowy Crumbly Mealy . Weak "—~ : —: Curdy ¦ Open '¦ . . Yeast *"- ; &lt;-°&gt; I j j;¦¦¦:; ..¦:' Fhk? £Sc mi m c ,h °k' w - - Flnliht TOTAL (100) Cricked rind Unciet lurfacei I I Huffed "Moldy Lightipou Rotspou PLACING Wrinkled bandage Paraffin Soiled —— -^—: : ; — -Scaly ¦ GRADE ON CRITICISMS (TOTAL) .... T~. ..¦-...¦ i colon ——— . Acid cut Seamy Mottled Wavy TOTAL GRADE.... ¦ Approved by the American Dairy Science Association. ¦ a more characteristic appearance and body. Cheddar cheese should be judged by the use of a trier. The sample should be drawn with a clean trier so that a representative sample will be obtained. The trier is inserted well into the top of the cheese in a slanting position, if possible, turned around once, and then withdrawn. In this way, a long, round, cylindrical sample, commonly called a plug, is obtained. After the plug has been drawn it is passed under; the nose and the flavor determined. This can best be observed by smelling the plug and by crushing and warming some of the cheese between the thumb and the fingers and then .smelling. As litde actual tasting as possible is advisable in judging cheese. The con - tinued tasting of strong cheese soon deadens the sense of taste. Much depends upon smell. The plug is removed from the trier and rolled be - tween the fingers to test its texture, which is judged by its pliability and compactness. An ideal texture is one that shows a solid, compact, con - tinuous curd free from breaks and holes. When the plug is rolled it should bend readily and show a flinty appearance resembling the surface of broken flint when broken. After the plug is broken a small portion is pressed and nibbed between the thumb and Angers for the determination of body. An ideal body feels soft, firm, and smooth in consistency. The plug when drawn from a cheese of ideal body should be smooth and waxy in appearance. After trie examination, the remainder of the plug should be replaced in the trier hole and the surface sealed with a small amount of cheese. The make-up or appearance of the cheese as a whole should be noted and the color determined by observation during the examination of the plug. </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 aßß&amp;jssr^iallßßßtl' '^^nmr^^^^^^^jk^'^' )'':^^^'^'^^^tmmy^i^^^^ /¦"i&lt;;. I.—A marked case of sivcet-curd holes in a sample of canned cheddar cheese. CHARACTERISTICS AND RATINGS USED IN SCORING AMERICAN CHEDDAR CHEESE ¦' Flavor.—ln the scoring of cheese, flavor must be considered from the standpoint of degree and quality. A newly made cheese does not have a well developed flavor and aroma. Usually it has a raw-curd taste and is; classed as a "fresh" cheese. A cheese that has been held in the curing room for some time and has a moderately developed "nutty" flavor is classed as "mild", and cheese which has considerable age and has ripened more fully and developed a rather sharp taste is classed as "aged" cheese. The demand of consumers of cheese varies greatly, some desiring a fresh, very mild-flavored cheese, while others desire an aged cheese with a distinctly sharp taste. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Judging Quality in Dairy Products 25 Cheese which has developed a characteristic cheese flavor and does not possess a raw-curd taste, receives the same rating for flavor whether it is "fresh", "mild", or "aged", provided it is clean and pleasing. The quality of the flavor may be classified from the standpoint of palatability under five general groups as "highly pleasing", "desirable", "slightly objectionable", "objectionable", and "poor". The total score of cheese and its relation to flavor characteristics are as follows:; , A highly pleasing flavor is an especially fine, clean flavor and aroma very fully developed and especially pleasing to the taste and smell. It is characteristic of highest-quality cheese, scoring 95 points or more in total score and 40 points or above on flavor, and it requires no flavor criticism on the score card. '¦.',- Slighdy objectionable flavors' are flavors such as "cowy", "feed", "weedy", or "heated", and when only slightly developed are permitted in cheese scoring 89 to 91. Slight defects may appear in body and texture as well as in color in a cheese of this score. Objectionable flavors are those'flavors objectionable to the taste but not developed to the extent that they/are distinctly disagreeable. Such flavors as "cowy", "weedy",-and "feed", 1 when distinctly developed, are common in cheese of this quality and also such flavors as "fruity", "acidy", and "bitter" when only slighdy developed. These flavors are permitted in cheese scoring 86 to 88 points, which may also show defects in body, texture, and color. I Poor or "off" flavors include all objectionable flavors which;have developed to the extent that they are distinctly disagreeable to the taste. They arc common to cheese of [low quality and include such flavors as "unclean", "yeasty", "fermented", "pronounced acid", "strong bitter", "strong fruity", "moldy", and "ijancid". They, are permitted in cheese scoring 85 or Jess, which may also be accompanied with marked defects in body texture and color. Cheese scoring below 83, usually spoken of as "culls'', is not suitable for general consumption. j Description of flavor 'A Rating Characteristic cheese flavor, well developed, clean, and highly pleasing 41.0 to 43.0 Clean and desirable, but lacking characteristic cheese flavor. 40.0 to 40.5 . Flavors (cowy, feedy, weedy, bitter) present to slight or moderate '. degree ... -. j. : 37.0 to 39.5 Flavors above present to pronounced degree or flavors such as acidy, j bitter, fruity, unclean, fermented, moldy, rancid, yeasty, present j to slight degree .'1........... ,'. 35.0 to 36.5 Flavors such as acidy, bitter, fruity, unclean, fermented, moldy, rancid j and yeasty present to pronounced degree '.. ......... 30.0 to 34.5 Body and texture.—The term "body" as applied to cheese refers to the degree of firmness of the cheese as a who/c and its general consistency; the term "texture" refers to the character of its structure. The general appearance of the plug will show the nature of the texture; that is, 1 whether it is "close" or "open".and also, the presence or absence of "gas holes", or "pin holes", "sweet curd holes'! or "yeast holes". A portion of the cheese </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 rubbed between the thumb and fingers will show the nature of the body of the cheese and indicate readily such characteristics as *'corky", "mealy", "crumbly", "weak", "pasty", or "spongy". Cheese to receive the maximum rating of 30 points for body and texture must be smooth and silky, slightly translucent, meaty and waxy, free from gas holes or any tendency to mealiness or pastiness, and must not be sticky, rubbery, or corky. Such cheese is not criticized on the score card for body and texture, because it is seldom found. Description of body and texture Rating Firm, waxy, smooth and not more than, three small mechanical openings on a trier plug 29.0 to 30.0 Four to six mechanical openings and sweet curd holes on a trier plug, slighdy weak 27.5 to 28.5 Slightly corky, crumbly, curdy, mealy, pasty, lumpy, weak; a! few pin holes; seven to twelve mechanical openings or sweet curd holes on a trier plug 25.5 to 27.0 Many pin holes or ragged mechanical openings; distinctly corky, crumbly, mealy, pasty, weak 235 to 25.0 Spongy structure, yeast holes, very weak 20.0 to 23.0 Finish and appearance.—A neat, uniform, smooth finish gives a cheese an attractive appearance and increase its market value. Cheese to be given the full rating of 15 points for finish and appearance must be uniform in size and shape, covered with a clean, closed, smooth fitting bandage, free from "mold", and have square edges, sound rind, and dry, clean, and even surfaces. Cuts are used when "wrinkled bandage", "cracked rind", "un - even surface", "scaly paraffin", "rot spots", "mold", and "huffed" condi - tions are found on a cheese. Description of finish Rating Clean, neat and smooth, rind sound and uniform in color 15.0 Huffed, light spots, moldy, scaly paraffin, soiled, uneven surfaces, wrinkled bandage 14.0 to _a_s Cracked rind, rot spots 13.0 to 13.5 Color.—The color of cheese varies greatly, depending upon the market, from uncolored (white) to a dark yellow color. The degree of color does not affect the score except in extremely high or reddish-colored cheese which is limited to a score of 91 points. Cuts in color score are made when "white specks", "wavy", "mottles", "acid cut", or "seamy" conditions exist. Description of color Rating Even and slighdy translucent 10.0 Acid cut, seamy, wavy, molded, faded 9.0 to 9.5 TERMS USED IN JUDGING CHEESE Flavor criticisms*. ACIDY—A sharp acid taste or a sour odor in cheese is denoted by this term. It is caused by over ripened milk and insufficient cooking of the curd. BITTER—A term used to indicate a bitter taste which is due to feed conditions, condition of the cow, or bacterial action. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Judging Quality in Dairy Products ,'! COWY—A flavor and odor that resembles the smell of a cow. It indicates that unclean milk or milk which has been allowed to stand in the barn and absorb the odor was used in the manufacture of the cheese. FEED—A term to describe flavors that resemble feeds. especially those that are strong such as silage and roots. Such feeds should always be fed after milking. FERMENTED—A term used to describe a flavor which resembles fermented whey or milk and has a somewhat sickening taste. It is caused by unclean conditions in milk or in the factory. jl FLAT—Cheese that lacks flavor and aroma due to too sweet milk, improper cook - ing of curd or too much washing of the curd. ]| FRUITY—This flavor is sometimes referred to as "sweet" and is suggestive of artificial pineapple odor. j . , ;! GREEN—A flavor characteristic of a fresh (green) cheese in which there has been no development of the true cheese flavor. j ¦ HEATED—A term used to describe a flavor that resembles that of heated fat and is due to using milk which has been exposed to too much heat. j MOLDY—A flavor or odor that resembles that of mold. It is often spoken of as musty and is caused by mold growth in the cheese. 1 RANCID—A flavor due to the decomposition of butterfat and'is common in old dairy products of poor keeping quality. When it is present to a pronounced degree the product is unsuitable for table use. j UNCLEAN—This term is used to describe a flavor or odor which suggests unclean conditions. It is often due to the condition of the milk which is carried through into the' cheese. ' '¦.-;'. '¦¦'. .'I. ' WEEDY—A flavor due to the use of milk which has a weedy flavor., jit is often accompanied by a bitter flavor. . j ¦ YEASTY—A flavor and odor resembling those resulting from the fermentations produced by yeasts. Very often large gas holes are found in cheese that show a yeasty flavor. j Body and texture criticisms: ! CORKY—A term used to describe a cheese that is hard, tough, and overjnrm which docs not crush down readily when pressed.between the thumb and finger, CRUMBLY—A crumbly body is one that breaks down in a crumbly condition when pressed, and rubbed between the fingers. It is closely associated with mealiness and is commonly found in "acidy" cheese. ('•. FLAKY—This term is used to.denote a condition that seems to indicate that the curd has not properly knitted together. It is characterized by the plug breaking with an even and glistening surface. r f. GASSY—When cheese ferments it often shows many small gas holes often spoken of as pin holes. A cheese in this condition is called "gassy". Sometimes the gas holes arc caused by yeast in which case they are usually much larger in size than the pin holes. :'• J . ¦•;' |! ¦:.;¦-, MEALY—A cheese that breaks down into fine crumbs when pressed between the fingers is called mealy. TheJ feeling between the fingers resembles that of corn meal. The condition isoften associated with a sour flavor and an "addy" cheese'and may be bleached or "acid out" in color.. OPEN—This term indicates that,the cheese is not compact but rather has openings throughout the cheese. These are usually due to the mechanical failure in pressing the curd and tend to produce a somewhat imperfect union of the curd pieces, PASTY—A condition that is sometimes called "salvy". Such a cheese when pressed and rubbed between the fingers appears to be very soft usually from excessive moisture. It also smears on the fingers and is sticky. SPONGY—The ideal body feels solid, firm and smooth in consistency. A spongy body is one that lacks firmness and springs excessively when pressed. Very often such a condition is associated with "gassy" holes. I </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 SWEET CURD HOLES—In certain types of cheese made with low acidity, small round gas holes somenmes appear. They are often found in very good cheese and arc usually very glossy in appearance. Such holes arc spoken of as "sweet curd holes" or •sweet gas holes". When they develop to a larger size they arc sometimes referred ro as Siviss eyes. ' WEAK—A weak bodied cheese is one that is soft and lacks firmness and is often caused by excessive moisture but is not necessarily sticky like a pasty cheese. YEAST HOLES—During the fermentation process by yeast, gas is formed rather rapidly. Such holes spoken of as "yeast holes" are often elliptical in shape and vary greatly in size. They are often spoken of as "fish eyes". Finish and appearance criticisms: CRACKED RIND-Thc rind of .1 cheese should be smooth and free from cracks. Any cheese that shows cracks should be criticized. . HUFFED—Cheeses in which considerable gas has been produced often show a bulg - ing of the sides and top. . MOLDY-This term is used to describe the presence of mold on the cheese, especially when it is under the paraffin. ROT SPOTS-When cheese KSs excessive moisture, spots of decomposed cheese o.icn appear on the surface. They are often dirty in color and soft to the touch SCALY PARAFFIX-Thc paraffin on a cheese should adhere tightly to the cheese. It it is loose and scales off this criticism should be used. UNEVEN SURFACE—The surface of a cheese should be smooth and even. The presence nf ;, hurh rim or ridge around the outside of the cheese or an unevenncss of the surface can be criticized by this term WRINKLED BANDACE-The bandage that covers the side of the cheese should term ' ™ "" ['mff"'- U'" d°cs not- " Cln be crilicizctl b &gt;': this Color criticisms: nn^Wh^rl^ C°'"n ,f ! hT C s, h°uJ d be uniform and even throughout the whole „„ ¦ A ¦ "I"' " "f v and shmvs lißht areas throughout it is spoken of as cJ"«\"\v°l^t°T m" *? k™, °f '1S "'hi,C SPCC(CS am' ""&gt;' WW ¦'" 'heese t^pcialls that which has been aged at low temperature. MOTTLED-This term is used to describe a variation in the color of cheese. It con - ,s so. irregular lighter color spots of rather large size so that it gives a mottled appea" ance. I is caused by an uneven distribution of the color in the different paruX of cheese during the making process. parades 01 ,„HS, F hAM- Y_A *"*!&gt;' aT L ra"CC rcfc" '° n pale Hn * s«rrounding each piece of curd c^rf \" °U"'nC °f "he P'KCS ns they were before bei "B P™«l. soiled in mTsLacT '" '""^ ' "'^ " Und""' *"* «b" b«" wa,«ls VTe7we„ &lt;:!;r Cl! h:,t S. h°*S ",raks ,° f lighttr co,or *» »««" &gt;" ** «ona of biases is spoken ot as being wavy in color. JUDGING ICE CREAM witbWh,!n 7"T " °"c °J °Ur leading dairy Products&gt; il has °»'y l*cn within the last few years that any great effort has been made to stand - •Z? w Pr" y meanS °£ 'udginB- Durin S the development and WtT .'f; " 'Ce"Cream 'udging many score cards have been proposed. While all do not agree as to which is the best score card for the purpose, rtie larger group of those interested have settled upon the card presented </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Judging Quality in Dairy Products ICE CREAM SCORE CARD AND HOW TO USE IT The score card used where laboratory facilities are available includes bacteria count. The maximum ratings for the separate divisions are: Bacteria .-.;.' .20 Flavor ...v.............................................. 50 Body and texture ,'..; 25 Package and color ..' ............... 5 '-'¦'-.'¦ •¦ ¦ 10° ' " The: bacteria count is considered perfect when by the standard plate method it is found to be less than 50,000 per gram. A. deduction of one point is made, for each 25,000 over 50,000. When it is desired to judge ice cream where laboratory facilities are not available and for instructional' purposes the factor of bacteria is considered perfect on the score card and other descriptive material is added which aids in its use. ICE CREAM SCORE CARD Contestant's N0... ".. ________ . - . ¦ Sample N0....... ' - """ ' ¦' * _ «__ . . Grades ~ ¦ . ' _ Student Official rrr: — ""or _„ Jcor _ &#132;„„ . Cnn- Criticisms ¦' score c ;, m ¦ . . • Flavor! Flavot (50): . Cooked Dryorcon - ' ¦ '' ' ¦ ¦: Egg powder denied milk Body and Garlic Metallic . texture (25) . ' High acid ! ¦-•-.' Neutralizcr - - ¦ ' ¦ ' : __' ¦ Lack! fine flavor Old ingredient j ~~~" I ; ~^—. : — Lacks flavoring Salty Bacteria (20) 20.00 j Unnaitinl ' Toosweet 1 flavoring : Too high flavor -— - : ' — —— Lacks sweetness Unclean Package and j : Storage color- (5) .--.¦! : : 1 = : - ¦ ______ '" B°*f and texture.. j ' . ' "~— ~~~ ~~ : Buttery -Sandy "- TOTAL(IOO) :..'•'' Crumbly Fluffy Coarse and icy Soggy —: — : : : ——— • . Weak PLACING Package and color: - . . : - .No parchment - • Uneven color • Rusty cans Unclean package GRADE ON CRITICISMS (TOTAL)... . Unnatural color ' • Melting quality: ¦¦"•-¦':.: Curdy Does not melt TOTAL GRADE Wheys og . Approved by the American Dairy Science Association. JUDGING PROCEDURE In the judging of ice cream care should be taken that proper refrigera - tion is provided to keep .'the samples in good condition. The ice cream should be so tempered that it can be dipped readily but-is not soft. Ice cream that is too hard or too soft is difficult to score, especially for body and texture. To show melting quality, a scoopful of each sample should be placed on a plate as the judging starts and allowed to stand throughout the judging so that the progressive melting may be observed. The body and texture should be determined first, while the ice cream is firm. By the use of the spoon and the eye such conditions as "fluffy", "crumbly", </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 5-) and "soggy" can be determined. A small amount placed in the mouth will reveal such defects as "buttery", "gelatin lumps", and "weak". If it is chewed slowly, "sandiness" or the presence of an "icy" condition will be noticed. The small amount of ice cream that has been placed in the mouth should then be held on the tongue for a minute or two until it is warm and the volatile flavors can rise into the nose. The mouth should remain closed during this time and the flavors gradually forced out through the nose. Practice is usually needed because of the coldness and the sugar, which are not found in other dairy products. _-_-_-_-_-_-_-_-_-_-^^^_-_-_-_-_-_-_-_-_-H _V^^_l _a_e^^_!__l \\\m\ *£ '^^B Wv m M |l i '!:'^4| ¦ _w2l IJr ' __!__! s_i B_Pi mma _B^_l Fio. 10.—High-quality ice cream is a refreshing dessert. Flavor—As in all other dairy products the flavor should indicate that it has been made from materials of high quality. The flavor should be clean, fine, and sweet. The extract or flavoring should be present in such amounts that it will impart a characteristic flavor. Variable judgment should be used when one is scoring on the question of intensity of flavor, as some localities demand higher flavors than others. The character of the flavoring material should be considered. It should be pleasing and well blended. Description o( flavor Rating Highly pleasing and desirable. Fresh, creamy, clean flavor, flavor - ing well blended 4 5 . 0 M 50 n Desirable but not too well blended. Too sweet, lacks sweetness, too high flavor, lacks flavoring, lacks fine flavor, slight egg, cooked, condensed, or dry milk ( 42.5 to 44 5 Objectionable flavor. High acid, egg, cooked, condensed or dry milk, unnatural flavoring, old ingredients, storage, feed, oxidized, salty. 39.5 to 42.0 J-oretgn (off) flavor. Salty, feed, high acid, neutralizcr, old ingre - dients, oxidized, storage, and unclean 36.0 to 390 Unsalable product is scored zero. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Judging Quality in Dairy Products Body and texture.—The ideal body and texture for ice cream is one that is smooth to the tongue, free from large ice crystals, fine grained, and compact. It melts down'freely on the plate and resembles the body of high-quality sweet cream. -.;:... Description of body and texture • - . . ' Rating Very desirable. Firm, smooth, ve1vety...........'— 24.5 to 25.0 Fairly desirable. Fluffy, crumbly, coarse or icy, weak or 50ggy...... 22.0 to 24.0 Undesirable. Sandy, or any of the following to a pronounced degree: crumbly, coarse or icy, buttery, weak 20,0 to 22.0 Melting quality.—A small amount o£ ice cream should be allowed to melt at room temperature and the following conditions observed: Desirable. —Melts freely, free from curd, and does not whey off. No additional cut on body and texture. Undesirable.—Curdy, does not melt, spongy or wheys off. Make addi- i tional deduction in score for body and texture, but not to exceed one point. Color.—Desirable color should be uniform and natural, in which case there should be no deduction. Undesirable, unnatural, or uneven color should have a maximum deduction of one point. Package.—Desirable package should be clean, bright, and with parch- ! ment if in a can in which case the^e should be no deduction. Undesirable ', I package may be an unclean, can, rusty can, a can without parchment in I which case the maximum deduction is one point. TERMS USED IN JUDGING ICE CREAM . Flavor criticisms: - CONDENSED MILK or DRY MlLK—This term is used to describe a flavor result- , ing from the excessive use of condensed or dried milk products.: While they are used in ice cream their flavor should not be noticeable. ' COOKED—A flavor resembling boiled or over-heated milk or milk products. Some - times called scorched. May be due to the flavor in the materials used or to a too high pasteurization temperature on the ice cream mix. EGG POWDER—The use of egg yolk powder sometimes causes a noticeable flavor in ice cream. The most objectionable flavor is where poor flavored or stale egg powder i is used. ¦ GARLIC—A flavor resembling the odor of garlic is found in ice cream made from ¦ milk drawn from cows that have eaten wild garlic. ' HIGH AClD—When milk or milk products have a slightly sotir flavor and odor ' it is called "high acid".; A pronounced'condition of this kind is. called "sour". J LACKS FINE FLAVOR—Sometimes' an ice cream does not have the fine, full flavor ! that one desires. In such cases this.term is used to describe the defect. It also may be caused by poor quality flavoring, i.; LACKS FLAVORING—An ice cream should be pleasingly flavored, but sufficiently strong to show its characteristics. If this is not the case the above term is used to designate the defect. Often caused by not using enough flavoring extract. . LACKS SWEETNESS—When a product is not sweet as when not enough sugar is used, the above term is used. I METALLIC—This flavor gives one; the impression of holding a piece of metal in the mouth between the teeth. It is often caused by the presence of metallic salts in the milk products from which the ice cream was made or from handling in rusty cans. </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 NEUTRALIZER—When dairy products of high acid content are used in the ice cream mix and alkalies are added 10 reduce the acidity a "neutralizcr" or "soda" flavor is produced. OLD INGREDIENTS—At times there are flavors that cannot be defined exacdy but which resemble old, ofl-flavored products. Such flavors are referred to as "old in - gredient" flavors. RANCID—A flavor characteristic of spoiled butterfat and resembles the flavor of butyric acid. It is due to the decomposition of the butterfat and may be found in any product that contains rancid /at. SALTY—A salty flavor in the product usually results from contamination by salt. Although some makers add a small amount of salt to the mix, a noticeable salty flavor should be criticized. STORAGE—This flavor develops in ice cream when held for considerable time in storage. It gradually loses some of its delicate flavor and develops a "storage" flavor. TOO SWEET—When a sample seems to be sweeter than the taste desired, this term is used. It is caused by too much sugar being used TOO HIGH A FLAVOR—Too much flavoring extract of good quality may result in a flavor that would be referred tn as "100 high a flavor " UNNATURAL FLAVORING-This term refers to the type of flavor and usually refers to synthcuc flavor resembling vanilla. It may also result in the use o( flavoring extracts other than vanilla in small amounts such as lemon or maple. UNCLEAN—A term used to designate a flavor and odor which one would asso - ciate with unclean utensils or cans. Milk products made from milk which has this flavor will often impart it to the ice cream and is very undesirable. Body and texture criticisms: BUTTERY—When the ice cream contains butter granules large enough so that they can be delected on the tongue or roof of the mouth, it is called "buttery" It is often present in improperly homogenized ice cream. COARSE—The texture of an ice cream should be smooth and fine; when this is not the case, it is criticized as being "coarse". It may be caused by incorrect com - position or improper freezing. CRUMBLY-Whcn ice cream does not hold together but instead breaks or crumbles this term is used. It is due to incorrect composition and sometimes to too high an overrun. b „l La V~J^ _n«' rP°«'»&lt;&gt;" o( excessive amounts of air in ice cream produces a Huffy or light body. r m „^ LAT"^ E fi Lti MPS;r I, ,UIisSO! V"1 Bcla,inc is s°mc«&lt;"« f°"nd in ice cream. Such a condinon is defined as "gelatine lumps". GUMMY The use of too large an amount of stabilizer often gives a body and tcx- ZltS ,T mC,&lt; radi,y' " haS a firmn"S "ot 'haracterbtic of -cream of good body and texture. ,rJ CJn ThiS 'Crm I USCi'° dcnDtr, ,hc Pr"c"« of i« crystals in the ice cream when they are large enough to be noticeable between the teeth. Large crystals may be due ,„„ h, r _? .. ° denote ,he Dresence of lactos&lt;: crystals which ate large SOGGY-Heavy, compact ice cream is often referred to as "soggy". It may be due rnTyfsfn at,u7o7a,r '"&gt;' "™U" ™'* '" "~ WEAK-Whe„ ice cream is held on the tongue, one expects it to melt down and -£_-!• me,K d™ -&amp; ** SET- Melting quality criticisms: </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Judcing Quality in Dairy Products ;.'".¦ DOES NOT MELT—When ice cream fails to melt down into a creamy mass this term is used as a criticism. i ' WHEYS OFF—If the curdy condition has progressed to the point where the curd ; separates from the scrum or whey, this term is used. fj Package and color criticisms: NO PARCHMENT—Every can of ice cream should be covered with parchment '-/ under the lid. When this is not the case the package should be criticized. ; RUSTY —When the interior-of the container shows rust spots die package should !'¦ be criticized by using this term. ?; UNCLEAN PACKAGE—AII packages containing food products should be clean. ¦V. When they are not they are criticized by this term. UNNATURAL COLOR—The natural color of cream is the color desired. The f.- degree of intensity should not be criticized. The occurrence of shades of red, green, and orange should be considered as unnatural in vanilla ice cream. !; UNEVEN COLOR—When two or more lots of ice cram are. mixed together after t freezing an uneven color may result COIWUCITNG A JUDGING CONTEST r ¦; Judging of dairy products can be carried on wherever suitable samples I and equipment are available. The nature of the work makes it possible | to carry on such work in the classroom if desired. High-school contests in ;:•'. the judging of milk, cream, and butter have been conducted for several years in Nebraska. Collegiate contests in judging of milk, butter, cheese, {:'¦ and vanilla ice cream have been conducted each year in connection with • the dairy-industries exposition under the direction of the American Dairy Science Association. Observation indicates that there has been great variation in the training X of the individuals that have taken part in these contests. A coach can [¦ impart to the pupil only knowledge that he has obtained from experience f. or from available literature. In an eSort to standardize the.information :&gt; much research has been carried on throughout the United States on methods of judging and factors affecting;the quality of dairy products. j Through the cooperation of the United States Department of Agriculture ;.:?- . and committees of the American Dairy Science Association much progress '%. has been made in standardizing procedures. This information with other material as presented here it is hoped may be of value to the teacher or |;. coach in presenting judging work to the student,;¦';•'¦', | MILK SAMPLES §: One quart of milk to represent each of the seven samples to be scored, |. as well as the three key samples, should be on hand for each 12 to 15 | persons in the contest. It is preferable that it be divided into portions so I that each group will have a freshly warmed sample when they examine if' it for flavor. Such samples not used for flavor determination should be fe kept, cold until warmed for use. | Materials for preparing the bottle and cap exhibit should be available, I . such as parchment paper, tin foil, cloth, and string. A sediment tester |I and disks are necessary for preparation, of sediment disks. Petri dishes for I" holding the disks are preferred but not absolutely necessary. Paper cups f» ¦ '"•. ¦ ¦'¦..''' ' '¦'-¦'¦•¦¦•.. fv ¦ •t: '. ¦¦¦•¦• i: "..-.¦¦.-.. ¦¦ ¦¦¦;¦¦ ¦'¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 for use in tasting the milk are usually used, although individual glass containers will answer if provision is made for rinsing them between samples. The milk to be scored should show as wide a variation of flavors as possible but should represent marketable milk. The botdes to be scored for bottle and cap should be prepared to show typical variations. Sediment disks should show a considerable range. Each sample for scoring should be well marked by number on the judging table. Usually three key samples are prepared for the contestants to examine, with the: judge's scores and criticisms attached. These should represent high, low, and medium quality in flavor, sediment, and bottle and cap. The contest ordinarily consists in judging seven samples, which should cover a wide range of scores for each factor. Flavor samples.—Usually a sufficient variety of flavor samples can be obtained by examining the milk of several producers. Samples of milk from individual cows will often furnish excellent variety. If specific flavors are needed the following procedures may assist in producing the desired flavors: B'TT^~ The addition of a very small amount of quinine or powdered gall will give this flavor. The amount used will depend upon the intensity desired. CARDBOARD—A botde of fresh, warm milk is placed in cold water (ice water is best) and surrcd with a piece of clean copper until cooled to 45° F Leave the copper snrrcr in the milk and hold for several days at about 45" F. The flavor develops m°™ Pronounced af,CT b «ns "eld. The milk must be kept cool and sweet. COOKED—PIace bottle of milk in hot water bath, heat to 150° F., and hold for ¦JO minutes and cool. COWY—Take a container of fresh, warm milk and allow it to cool while exposed to a cloth which has been treated as follows: The cowy odor is the most pronounced at points on the cow's body where there is the greatest amount of oily secretion. If a cloth is rubbed back of the ear or back of the front legs it will absorb this oily secrenon and odor. By exposing the cloth to the cooling milk by hanging it over the container, the desired results can be obtained. DISINFECTANT-The addition of a minute quantity of the disinfectant material or exposing the milk to a cloth upon which some of the disinfectant has been placed should give the desired results. Hypochlorite disinfectants do not affect the flavor of mdk but most other disinfectants do. FEED-This flavor can be obtained from the particular feed or group of feeds by exposing the warm milk if the feeds have considerable odor, or submerging them in ** ™i k T ,"l, da" u C,&lt;,*'.' f ** hare a ™" ""or, "Me the milk is celling fW w7h?M °f/"dividual cows should be examined when looking for this flavor. Withholding afl feed from a cow for four to five hours before milking will oe slig°htiyZ! te °" '" *' m"k 3nd tt"d W m3ke " "»" IKS S fnd _ ffIrHCA?!rS ON_I? rOP I a fT Pr? of cut V'ik °r Mion ™° '«&lt;= milk, develop rtisrW °' ""* *** " 7°° R £°f 10 to 12 hou" •» ™»% METALLIC—This flavor is difficult to produce satisfactorily. If warm fresh milk Ltl'Yvo—'dX^ ras,y and a,Wcd to cL -"*^M* or 'flair™' 11 " mUS'y » *«* «»** </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Judging Quality in Dairy Products fe RANCID—This flavor can be produced by adding a very minute quantity of • butyric acid or exposing the milk while cooling to a cloth on which has been placed ¦ a few drops of butryic acid or a small amount of rancid butter. SALTY—A salty sample of milk can very often be found by sampling the milk of jV individual cows. It can be produced by adding a small amount of common salt r UNCLEAN—The flavor is difficult to produce artificially and can best be obtained S by sampling the milk-of the producers as it is delivered to a milk plant It is not f&gt; usually hard to find in warm weather. U WEEDY—The flavor is usually obtained without much _ difficulty in the fall, !;¦'; especially during a dry season. The exposure of milk, while cooling to some half-dried 5 rag weed should give a characteristic flavor. |i- It is generally better to develop a stronger flavor than desired, as it can be adjusted by diluting with unflavoted milk. With a little very I- good sets Of samples can be prepared. |; Sediment disks.—Sediment disks for judging can best be obtained by |f. filtering pint samples of warm milk through the sediment tester. Usually f; the sample of milk as produced is much more satisfactory than prepared | samples. .If several quarts of rather dirty milk can be obtained, disks showing different amounts of sediment can be prepared by filtering dif- I ferent amounts of milk. For a clean disk a sample can be run through I the second time. .-. t Bottle and cap.—A set of botde and cap samples for judging can be {: prepared at "the time of the, contest. In instructional work it is often desir - able to prepare a set that can be used more than once. In this case approximately a teaspooniul of formalin should be added to each quart of }: milk used. Skimmilk may be used in place of whole milk. While pint r; bottles are preferable, other sizes may be used if desired. |,! The following suggestions will be helpful in the preparation of these g samples. The bottles are filled with milk in the usual" manner and capped fi- with regular caps. (Fig. 3.) &gt;; ''¦' ABSORBENT CAP PROTECTOR—A piece of non-waterproof paper or cloth is | placed over the top of botde and fastened in place with wire, string, or rubber band. S CHIPPED MOUTH—A botde with a chipped mouth or pouring lip will have to fc be selected to show this defect |; : DIRTY BOTTLE—Select a bottle before filling that has a small amount of dirt jp . dried on the inside walls. ;' &#132; ,„ |i LEAKY CAP—Notch or dent the edge of cap before capping the botde. This wilt y i ¦ ' cause it to leak, when inverted. - |j. . LIP NOT PROTECTED—A bottle capped with an ordinary cap will be satisfactory. | LIP PARTIALLY PROTECTED—This will have to be shown by the use of special |; caps which only pardy cover the pouring lip. !¦ NOT FULL^-Adjust the amount of milk in bottle before it is capped. I A perfect bottle and cap can be prepared by securely fastening some I) waterproof material over the top of a full bottle of milk with a sealed I fastener. Such material as parchment paper, tin foil, or.i regular hood caps fc can be used for this purpose. ¦¦¦ •¦ ; </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 CREAM SAMPLES Very little difficulty should be experienced in finding suitable samples. Cream as delivered to the cream station or creamery will usually furnish enough variety. The samples may be held in any container that is handy, although it should be so constructed that the tasting rod can be dipped into the cream with ease. If sufficient variety of flavors are not available similar procedures as suggested in the case of milk may be followed. The incubation of cream samples at a temperature of about 100" F. for twolor three days will usually develop a yeast flavor. Often the holding of cream at a temperature of 70° F. for three to four days will cause a moldy cream flavor. BinTER SAMPLES While it is desirable to have butter in tubs or other large containers so that a full trier of butter can be drawn, it is not practical under ordinary conditions. In contests of national character this type of package ts used but for smaller contests smaller packages can be used with much less expense. Butter in any type of package that is available can be used for judging work. The one-pound print is a very satisfactory package or even the quarter-pound print may be used. Where such packages are used the factor of body is usually considered perfect because of the inability of the judge to draw a plug. A spoon can be used in place of a trier in this case. CHEESE SAMPLES As the style or shape of the package of cheddar cheese does not affect the score, a variety of shapes or styles of packages may be used in the same class. Often it is difficult to obtain the desired quantity of cheese all in the same style of package. For that reason one should pay no attention to the style of the package. A section or slice of a larger pack - age, provided the judge can draw a trier full of cheese, will be satisfactory. Either white or yellow cheese may be used together in the same group of samples. All cheese samples should be tempered at room temperature for several hours before they are judged, as cold cheese is difficult to judge. ICE CREAM SAMPLES Vamlla ice cream is usually used in a judging contest. Suitable samples can be obtained in most towns. The type of ice-cream container is of little importance, provided a sufficient supply is available. In the classroom or small contest, pint samples are sufficient but enough pints of each sample should be available so that a fresh sample can be had for each group of students or, if the sample is depleted, before the students are through judging. In large contests usually two-and-one-half-gallon containers are kept in a ten-hole mechanically refrigerated cabinet adjusted to the proper temperature for dipping ice cream. In this case each student dips his own sample as he uses it. In a smaller contest samples can be kept under </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Judginc Quality in Dairy Products proper refrigeration and brought to the place of judging as needed. In this case the properly tempered samples are numbered and submitted .for judging. The sample should have a spoon in it with which the judge places a small amount of ice cream upon his own spoon,.which is placed in his mouth. This procedure eliminates the dipping of the spoon that has been in the judge's mouth back into the ice cream sample. USE OF SCORE CARDS AND GUIDES Probably one of the greatest difficulties that the inexperienced judge encounters is the proper use of the scoie card. Figures placed in the wrong place, mistakes in adding, and general carelessness are common troubles. The student should score each item and place a check mark to the right of the term or criticism that describes the defect. If the defect is not listed, write it in the blank space. The smallest cut should be one-half point, except where one-fourth point is used to break a tie. In sediment scores the smallest cut is one-tenth point. Detailed scoring guides for the dif - ferent products designated for instructional use are very valuable, as copies can be made and furnished each student for study. MILK ••:.: - Flavor—Perfect score, 25—Normal range, 12-24 Highly pleasing and desirable, 23-25. Fine, clean, pleasing—no criticism required on the card. ¦ : Desirable but lacking in quality, 21-22.5. Flat (lacking in full flavor), very slight feed, slightly cooked. . Slightly objectionable, 18-20.5. Cooked, slight feed, slightly salty, slightly cowy, slightly metallic, slightly malty. Objectionable, 12 to 17.5. Strong feed, weedy, bitter, unclean, cowy, slighdy high acid, slightly rancid, cappy or cardboard, garlic or onion, malty.; Very objectionable, 0 to 11.5. • Rancid, strong cowy, high acid, slightly disinfectant '- Note: Samples that are lour or strong disinfectant or unsalable, score 0. Sediment —Perfect score, 10—Normal range, 5-10 A perfectly clean disk scores 10 with deductions for increasing amounts of sedi - ment. (Sec photo of standard disks.) Score whole points between 0 and 7, one-half points from 7 to 8, quarter points between 8 and 9.5, and one-tenth points between 9.5 and 10. Bottle and Cap—Perfect score, s—Normal range, 3-5 Perfect bottle and cap, 5 (no criticisms). : Clean bottle full of milk covered with waterproof hood cap and securely fastened. Imperfect bottle and cap, 3-4.75. Cuts made in score dependent upon defect. Based upon suggested cuts (see list, page 9),- Note: The factors of bacteria (45 points) and .temperature or acidity (15 point,) arc not used in ttvulcrit judging contests and are considered perfect on the card. ¦¦; CREAM Flavor—Perfect score, 25—Normal range, 12-25 Very desirable, 23-25 (no criticism). Clean, full, free from defects. .'.'.' </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 Desirable, 21-22.5. Flat, very slight feed, slight cooked, watery. Slightly undesirable, 18 to 20.5. Cooked, feed, salty, slightly cowy. Undesirable, 12-17.5. Strong feed, unclean, yeasty, weedy, bitter, musty, cowy. Very undesirable, 0 to 11.5. Rancid, greasy, metallic, onion or garlic, very unclean, disinfectant. Aridity—Perfect score, 15—Normal range, 0-15 Desirable, 13-15. Sweet cream, 0.12 to 0.2-1 per cent acidity. Desirable, 10-12.5. Slightly sour, 0.25 to 0.35 acidity. Undesirable, 7-9.9. Medium sour, 0.36 to 0.60 acidity. Undesirable, 5-6.9. Very sour, 0.6 to 0.8 acidity. Undesirable, 0-4.5. Rank sour, over 0.8 acidit&gt;'. Smoothness and Body—Perfect score, s—Normal range, 2-5 Satisfactory, 4.5-5. No curd lumps, dirt, or mold. Satisfactory, 4-4.4. Small amount curd lumps, slightly too thick or too thin. Unsatisfactory, 3.5-3.9. Large amount curd lumps, very thick or too thin, slight boiling or dirty. Unsatisfactory, 2-3.4. Moldy, boiling, or dirty. Sediment—Perfect score, 10—Normal range, 0-10 A perfectly clean disk scores 10 with deductions for increasing amounts of sedi - ment. (See standard disks, page 6.) Note: The factor of bacteria (45 points) is not used in student judging contests and is considered perfect on the score card. BUTTER Flavor—Perfect score, 45—Normal range, 31-39 Desirable, 38-39. Fresh, fine, sweet, and clean (no criticism used on card). Desirable, 37-37.5. Fresh, sweet, and clean. Also very slight feed, coarse, or flat. Slightly objectionable, 35.5-36.5. Slightly burned, oily, heated, neutralizcr, yeasty, feedy, briny, storage, cowy, acidy, cheesy, weedy, cooked, tallowy. Objectionable, 33.5-35. Pronouncedly burned, oily, heated, storage, neutralizcr, cowy, yeasty, cheesy, weedy, feedy, slightly metallic, woody, bitter, unclean, very slight old cream. ' Objectionable, 32-33. Old cream, unclean, musty, slight gasoline, lime or alkaline, fishy, metallic. i Very objectionable, 30-31.5. Garlic, gasoline, rancid, pronounced or stale old cream; pronounced oily, j metallic, cheesy. ' Body—Perfect score, 25—Normal range, 23-25 Desirable, 25 (no criticism). ? Firm, waxy, good grain. </seg>
         <seg id="p041">I Judging Quality in Dairy Products Undesirable, 24-24.5.'¦ ... . , : :' Cloudy brine, crumbly, greasy, leaky, mealy, salvy, sticky, weak, gummy. t Undesirable,. 23-23.5. . . _ -&#132; Pronounced cloudy brine, crumbly, greasy, gummy, mealy, salvy, sticky, weak, f. leaky. ?&gt;¦ I Color—Perfect score, 15—Normal range, 13-15 Desirable, 15 (no criticism). i I Uniform color throughout May be light, medium, or full golden yellow. I , Undesirable, 13-14.5. Color specks (reddish orange), mottles, uneven, wavy, white specks. Salt—Perfect score, 16*—Normal range, 9-10 Desirable, 10 (no criticism). » ¦ Uniform, all dissolved; may be unsalted, light salted, medium' salted, heavy salted. j Undesirable, 9-9.5. '.'. Undissolved or gritty. Very heavy salt (very briny). Package—Perfect score, s—Normal range, 4-5 , Desirable, 5 (no criticism). i '¦' Neatly packed in clean, sound packages. Undesirable, 4-4.5. j'j Dirty tub, poor finish. ¦:¦¦¦¦¦ Nott: As the package can be easily soiled by the students, all samples should be given a perfect score on pacjraee in a student contest. . CHEESE. ' Flavor—Perfect score, 45—Normal range, 36-41 . ! ¦: j Highly pleasing, 40-43 (no criticism). ; Characteristic cheese flavor, well, developed, "clean, or desirable but lacking : character"!.tic cheese flavor. . . "¦' . Desirable, 37-39.5. Slightly bitter, slightly cowy, slightly feedy, slightly weedy. Slightly objectionable, 35-36.5, Pronouncedly cowy, pronouncedly feedy, pronouncedly weedy, moderately bitter, slightly acid,: slightly fruity, slighdy unclean, slightly fermented, slightly ';'. moldy, slightly rancid, slightly yeasty. Objectionable, 30-34.5. : i Pronouncedly acid, bitter, fruity, unclean, fermented, moldy, rancid, yeast &gt;.'., Body and Texture—Perfect score, 30—Normal range, 26-295 vVj Very desirable, 29-30 (no criticism). ''' Firm, waxy, smooth, and not more than three small mechanical openings on a X ¦ ' ; trier plug. ¦'¦'..'¦ ¦: Desirable, 27.5-28.5. % Firm, waxy, smooth but slightly open. (Four to six mechanical or sweet curd £' holes on trier plug.) May also be flaky. Slightly objectionable, 25.5-27. , , V Slightly corky, crumbly, curdy, mealy, pasty, lumpy, weak, gassy; open (a few |. pin holes, 7 to 12 mechanical openings or sweet curd holes on a trier plug), y sweet curd holes, yeast holes. % Objectionable, 23.5-25. : fc Distinctly corky, crumbly, mealy, pasty, gassy, weak, open; (many pin holes or v. ragged mechanical openings). | Very objectionable, 20-23. i; ' . Spongy structure, yeast holes, or weak. . </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 Finish—Perfect score, 15— Normal range, 14-15 Desirable, 15. Clean, neat, smooth rind. Sound and uniform in color. Undesirable, 14-14.5. Huffed, light spots, scaly paraffin, uneven surfaces, wrinkled bandage, moldy, soiled. Very undesirable, 13-13.5. Cracked rind, rot spots. Color—Perfect score, 10—Normal range, 9-10 Desirable, 10. Even and slightly translucent. Undesirable, 9-9.5. Acid cut, seamy, wavy, mottled, faded. N'orr: Color ihnulil not be scored off unless defect i. quite apparent. ICE CREAM Flavor—Perfect score, sf)—Normal range, 36-46 Desirable, 45-50 (no criticism). Fresh, clean, creamy, well blended. Poor blending, slight off flavors, 42.5-44.5. Lacks fine flavor, lacks flavoring, lacks sweetness, too high flavoring, too sweet; slight cooked, egg, condensed or dry milk. Obicciionablt, 39.5-42. Cooked, egg, condensed or dry milk, feed, high acid, old ingredient, oxidized, salty, storage, unnatural flavoring. Foreign and off flavors, 36-39. Feed, high acid, neutralizcr, old ingredient, oxidized, salty, storage, unclean. Body and Texture —Perfect score, 25—Normal range, 20-25 Very desirable, 24.5-25 (no criticism). Definite defects, 22-24. Coarse or icy, crumbly, fluffy, weak, soggy. Objectionable defects, 20-22. Pronounced coarse or icy, fluffy, weak, buttery, sandy. Noti: Fnr undesirable melting quality (curdy, docs not melt, wheys oft) the maximum cut is one point. No cat is made if the ice cream melts frcciy to smooth and creamy consistency. Color and Package—Perfect score, s—Normal range, 4-5 Desirable, 5 (no criticism). Defects, 3-4.5. Unnatural or uneven color, unclean or rusty can, no parchment Note: The 20 points needed to make 100 are given to the bacteria count and are used when desired or when facilities permit, Out not in student judging contest*. When the flavor is so bad as to make the sample unsalable, the flavor score is zero. In judging contests only salable samples are used, and the minimum flavor score is 36. Since the can may become soiled and parchment disarranged by contestants, "package" is given a perfect score in student judging contests. The contestant should score each item and place a check mark to the right of the defect If the defect is not listed, write it in a blank space. The smallest cut on any item is one-half point except that one-fourth point may be used to break tics. A combination of two or more defects often justifies giving a lower score value than that indicated for cither defect alone. CONTESTS Only those persons that have had training and some experience in the process of judging should be entered in a contest. They should be in good health, dressed in clean clothes, and free from body odors. This is especially true of hands. The use of strong-smelling soap, tobacco, or </seg>
         <seg id="p043">; Judging Quality in Dairy Products other materials will often hinder the work of not only that person but also others within smelling distance. As the contest lasts for several hours a good night's rest, followed by a normal or slightly lighter than normal meal, should be taken previous to the contest. No strong-flavored foods or those likely to upset the stomach should be eaten. During the contest some coaches prefer to furnish fruit such as apples to enable the individual to clear his mouth. Water, no doubt, is as satisfactory as anything and eliminates the possibility of fruit flavors and odors. The mental attitude of the contestants is very important. They should enter the contest with the purpose of learning rather than with that of winning. Too often the latter idea has made the contestant nervous and he has failed to use good judgment during the contest. A feeling of self - confidence and the resolve to score the products accurately regardless of the outcome of the contest is the proper attitude.. It is an educational contest and not all can win, but all will profit from the experience. The material needed by the judge is a good pencil and a gutter trier. A six-inch-size butter trier will be handy to use. In general the room should be light, of normal temperature, free from odors, and Urge enough to accommodate the students. A large table should be available for holding samples of each product. A supply of fresh warm and cold water is neces - sary, as well as containers for waste materials. A sink is very desirable. A score card for each sample of the different products f.6 be scored should be available and packaged ready for distribution' as the contestant is ready for them. ¦; , , ' RULES GOVERNING JUDGING CONTESTS .'¦"-' 1. A team shall consist of three persons; 2. No mark of identification of the contestant or school shall be in evidence during the contest. \ 3 No notebooks or paper shall be taken into the contest. Score cards will be furnished. 4. While the contest is in progress there shall be no communication between contestants. 5. All persons except the contestants and those in charge shall be excluded from the place of scoring during the contest. 6. Each contestant on entering the place of contest will be assigned a number and will be given score cards on which to record his scores anct criticisms. The contestant shall place the number assigned him on each card. . , ¦;¦'.., J. The constants will be divided into groups containing one indi - vidual from each team. Each group will score samples of products as directed. r 8. The person in charge shall set out three key samples of each product, showing good, medium, and poor quality, with the Judge's score and criticisms; attached. The contestants shall have access to these samples during the 10 minutes previous to their, scoring of that product in the contest, and then only. . ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 9. Each contestant shall score seven samples of each product, 45 minutes being allowed for each product. 10. Each contestant should look his cards over carefully for mistakes in order to see that they are marked with proper placing of samples and then arranged in order with No. 1 card on top and turned in to the person in charge of the group. GRADING OF CARDS The work of the contestants shall be graded in the following manner: The scores, criticisms, and placing shall be graded separately, but the grades shall be added to form the total for the product. The lowest score wins. (See Fig. 11.) (A) Student should mark his card with his number and number of sample. (B) Place scores and placing of sample in first column and check crticismi describing - defects observed. (C) The contestant's tirade on score on each item is the difference between bis score and the official score. (D) The criticism checked by the student should be the same as the official criticism. (E) The eradc and cri.icism shall nor exceed one ooint for any one item. If the student has one cnucism right out of two, O.S is given as a grade. (F) The grade on placing is the difference between the student placing and the official placing. ic.) The student's eradc for the samole is the sum of the score grade, the placing grade, and the criticism grade. UILI SCORE CARD CouUiUui.'i tu. .j»a/_&gt; ' a_pwntg; H-»Q SOaijmtt. JSIIuIU' Ulliigo— ——: —== —"» — -• Faotor *W- Scora Scora I Crltlolc CBITICISIB _r C t*rt» (&lt;c&gt; «5.00 ~* **** ~* _!»r!«_r_ SEIIJ -titer &gt;_fo) Jjfcjfc _fc2_j__J ).S IZLl^lZ* P_&gt;» &gt;» - i —— " * _rrt£ OulMB / . . __£-" _y a~ J ?—&amp;tr Wnir at g-"--* do) _£___ J__e_ .&amp; / Flat ' _? Garlic, or J - Tanparmtttra or - csnttm X ¦ iiumu (») ' -trm -M=r^ — — ~la_-_f7 — -f s#» pa~» X c « ' Bottla and - _&#132; ««»___/ __c _i,_i___? i___L_________"_«i_3_s_i — goo) g____Q j/g J ~~~~ ~ G__»&lt;~ r -~—l —— 1/ __ »-«_ipi_tuiijr o__s OS CMTICiac-=- J r* _^**"^ protaetacs / —;— * Hot full lOiil rj__s 1 .l_ta_,«a _ p prouo. sjN* J 1 1 . tor . . ippro—d fey t_&gt; iaarloaa Dairy Selanoa laioeiatlon. Fro. 11.—Explanation of use and grading of score card. </seg>
         <seg id="p045">.!¦.'¦: Judging Quality in Dairy Products .) I Score.—The contestant's score on each item on the score card will be given a grade expressed by the difference between his score and the official |score. For example, if a student scores flavor 2250 and the judge's score is 22.0, the student receives a grade of 0.5 point. I. Criticisms.—When the score of any item, such as flavor, sediment, etc., A j ' 'is cut, a critical descriptive term must be checked (except as specified on the score card). In grading a student's criticisms the maximum cut for i" each item shall be one point. J.'....[" Placing..—The grade for placing is determined by the difference be-; 3 tween the position of the contestant's samples and the official placing. If. the contestant, for example, placed the highest-scoring sample fourth, he loses three points; if he placed the second highest sample seventh, he loses five points; and so on for all seven samples. ' j Determining the grades and platings.—The contestant's grade is found by adding the differences on scoring, placing, and criticism. The con- - testant having the lowest grade is placed first. A team's grade is the sum of the grades of its members. The team is placed according to its grade,' the team having tiWowest grade winning first place. [ When two or mepe contestants tie, or teams have the same grade, the -warding of the prize is decided by determining which has the lowest score on flavor, and then on other items in the order in which they appear on the various score cards.. If no prize is involved, the placing shall be given as a tie. METHODS OF TABULATING ¦¦' After the cards for each product have been graded and checked they can be tabulated either by the use of the large record sheet or the card. system. The large score sheet provides a place for the contestant's name and number as well as the team identification. For each product judged urine columns are provided, one for each Of the seven samples, and one for the total score for the individual and another for the total score ot the ;j. • team. In addition a column should be provided for individual placing and ii one for the team placing, making a total of. eleven columns for each :,'.': product. For the tabulation of all products, four columns are necessary, J! one for the total score for the individual, one for team score, one for mdi! - '.- yidual placing, and one for team placing. Care should be taken that errors Ikare. not made iri tabulating and addition: Additions can be checked by }|| adding the totals for individual scores in each product and comparing jj| them with the sums of the team scores for, all products. After additions i]l have been checked the placings can be made. - n{ Another method of tabulation is the; card system, which is used by the .(?; American Dairy Science Association and members of the Dairy Bureau of ;{| tne United States Department of Agriculture, at the National Collegiate i;j Contest each year. This consists of transferring the scores of each student ;ji for the particular product to a card. The total score is determined by ' : i | adding and the cards placed iri order with the lowest score first. In this </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 54 way the individual ranking for the product is obtained. This is carried out for each product. On another card the scores of all products are tab - ulated for the contestants. These are added and the cards are placed in order to determine the ranking of the contestant. In the same manner, a card is made out for each team, using the totals from the cards on each product. In this way the team totals for each product and all products are determined and ranked by sorting the cards. Either method of tabula - tion can be used with satisfactory results. I A new development in an effort to simplify tabulation is the intro - duction of the multiple score card. This score card holds the record of seven samples of the product to be scored. In addition a place is furnished for the tabulation of the grades on the seven samples. The method of grading consists of a cut-out card upon which the official.scores are written. This card fits over the score card, thus saving the writing o£ the official scores on each contestant's card. This saves considerable time in grading. This new method of grading has not as yet been used in the national contest, but it is believed that such a system will soon: be used. After it has been perfected it may be desirable to use such a system in smaller contests. f°Mi </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>