<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923-09">1923-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 194 August, 1 Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska JAMES A. HOLDEN. SUPERINTENDENT SCOTTSBLUFF EXPERIMENT SUBSTATION LAMB FEEDING YARDS AT THE SCOTTSBLUFF EXPERIMENT FARM THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY I. The results obtained show that lambs cannot be finished for market on roughage alone. A grain or its substitute must be in - cluded in the ration. II. Corn was the best feed of any tested for fattening lambs. In a ration of corn and alfalfa it required 307 pounds of corn and 652 pounds of alfalfa per 100 pounds gain. III. Dry pulp proved to be a good substitute for corn, having from 80 to 85 per cent the feeding value of corn. The average of 6 tests shows that 113 pounds of dry pulp and 30 pounds of alfalfa were equal in feeding value to 100 pounds of corn. IV. Sugar beet tops when properly handled have a higher feeding value than is generally known. The average of 6 tests shows that the tops from 16 tons of sugar beets have the same feeding value as one ton of alfalfa and 491 pounds of corn. KM'KHIMKVI- NO. 1 (AVRRAGR OF 3 TKSTS I»l7-l»lt»&gt; I. In a test comparing corn and alfalfa, corn and dry pulp in equal amounts and alfalfa, and dry pulp and alfalfa, dry pulp was better than corn in one test but the 3-year average was in favor of corn except where the pulp and corn were fed together. The net profit per lamb was 51 cents where corn was fed, 54 cents where both corn and dry pulp were fed, and 40 cents where dry pulp was fed. II. Adding either beet tops or wet pulp to a ration of corn and alfalfa increased the gains per lamb 5 pounds and 2.5 pounds re - spectively, and also increased the selling price per 100 pounds. The net profit per lamb was $1.02 where beet tops were added and 89 cents where wet pulp was added, as against 51 cents where only corn and alfalfa were fed. The amount of feed per 100 pounds gain was as follows: 313 pounds of corn and 720 pounds of alfalfa where just corn and hay were fed; 261 pounds of corn, 518 pounds of alfalfa, and the tops from 1.38 tons of sugar beets where beet tops were added to the corn-alfalfa ration; and 255 pounds of corn, 627 pounds of alfalfa, and 1,462 pounds of wet pulp where wet pulp was fed with corn and alfalfa. (Lota 1, 4, and 5. Table 2.) III. Molasses cannot profitably be substituted for corn when fed with wet pulp and alfalfa. The corn lot made 30 pounds gain per lamb as against 19.6 when molasses was fed. The corn-fed lambs sold for $10 and the molasses-fed lambs at $9.75. The corn lot produced a KXPKK1MKNT* XOS. 1 AND 2 (AVKRAGR OK • TESTS 1»17-1KS) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">profit of 89 cents per lamb and the molasses lot 30 cents per lamb. (Lots 5 and 6, Table 3.) IV. A ration without grain or its substitute is unprofitable. Ra - tions of alfalfa, sugar beets and alfalfa, and sugar beet tops and alfalfa proved to be little more than maintenance rations. The gains made were low and the cost was high. Each of these rations produced a loss, amounting to $1.77 per lamb where only alfalfa was fed, 70 cents where sugar beets and alfalfa were fed. and 4 cents where sugar beet tops and alfalfa were fed. (Lots 7, 8, and 9, Table 4.) V. One pound of corn per lamb daily proved more profitable than 1^4 pounds. (Lots 1 and 10, Table 5.) K1PKHIMKNT NO. 2 lUKIMl.K Of TIIHKK TKJtTX 1WSO-1922) I. A test comparing corn and dry pulp when fed with alfalfa showed that corn produced a little faster gain, lambs of higher selling value, and more profit per lamb. Where corn and alfalfa were fed, it required 302 pounds of corn and 583 pounds of alfalfa per 100 pounds gain; where dry pulp was fed during the first period and corn the last period with alfalfa, it required 129 pounds of corn, 204 pounds of dry pulp, and 631 pounds of alfalfa; and where dry pulp and alfalfa were fed, it required 357 pounds of dry pulp and 652 pounds of alfalfa. (Lots 1, 3, and 5, Table 6.) II. In another test, comparing corn and dry pulp when fed with both cottonseed cake and alfalfa, the corn still had the advantage, except where corn replaced dry pulp during the last part of the feeding period. Here the corn had no advantage over the straight dry pulp lot. In fact, it showed less profit. (Lots 2, 4, and 6, Table 7.) III. Cottonseed cake increased the gains 25 per cent; the selling price per 100 pounds, 20 cents; net profit per lamb, IS cents; and cost per 100 pounds gain, 10 per cent. (Lots 1 and 2, 3 and 4, and 6, Tables 6 and 7. See discussion under Table 7.) IV. One-third pound of cottonseed cake per lamb daily was more profitable than one-half pound when fed in rations of dry pulp and alfalfa. V. When sugar beet tops were added to a corn and alfalfa ration the gains were increased 4.6 pounds per lamb and the selling price 5 cents per 100 pounds. The net profit per lamb was $1.11 where beet tops were fed and 70 cents where only corn and alfalfa were fed. (Lots 1 and 10. Table 9.) VI. Where beet tops were added to a dry pulp, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa ration the gains were increased 4.2 pounds, the selling price </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 remained the same, and the profit per lamb was 97 cents compared with 70 cents where the beet tops were omitted. (Lots t; and 11, Table 10.) VII. In a test comparing beet tops and corn silage when fed with dry pulp, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa, 1 ton of silage was equal to the tops from 6 tons of beets and 280 pounds of alfalfa. The gains made were about equal but the selling price was 15 cents per 100 pounds in favor of the silage. The profit per lamb was also in favor of this lot, being $1.07 where silage was fed and 97 cents where beet tops were fed. (Lots 8 and 11. Table 11.) VIII. Where beet tops and corn silage were compared in rations of cottonseed cake and alfalfa, the lambs getting beet tops made a little more gain, sold for 20 cents more per 100 pounds, and made a profit of 17 cents, while the lambs fed silage lost 27 cents each. One ton of silage and 41 pounds of cake had the same feeding value as the tops from 5 tons of beets and 75 pounds of alfalfa. I Lots 9 and 12, Table 12.) IX. When dry pulp was added to a ration of corn silage, cotton - seed cake, and alfalfa, the gains per lamb were increased IK. 4 pounds, the selling price was increased 80 cents per 100 pounds, and the profit per lamb was $1.07 where dry pulp was fed and th-e loss was 2 7 cents n per lamb where the dry pulp was omitted. These lots were the extremes, the lot getting dry pulp being the best and the one wh&lt; the dry pulp was omitted being the poorest of all lots. iLots 8 and Table 13.) X. In another test where dry pulp was added to a ration of beet tops, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa, the lambs getting dry pulp made 13.3 pounds more gain, sold for 45 cents more per 100 pounds, and showed a net profit of 97 cents as compared with 17 cents per Iamb where dry pulp was not included in the ration. (Lots 11 and 12, Table 14.) XI. Lambs fed beet tops or silage seem to shrink most. There appears to be no difference in the shrink, dressing percentage, and quality of meat between corn fed lambs and dry pulp led lambs having the same degree of finish. Corn fed lambs seem to have a higher per cent of fat than those fed pulp. (Tables 15 and lfi.) </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebratka |:V JAMES A. HOLI&gt;EN The data presented in this bulletin have to do with the study of lamb feeding on irrigated farms in western Nebraska. These tests were begun in the fall of 1916 and continued for 6 consecutive winters. The results represent 2 different ex - periments, each covering a period of 3 winters. In the first experiment there were 10 lots which were fed 10 different rations and in the second experiment there were 12 lots, each receiving a different ration. In conducting these experiments, it has been the aim to gather information on the feeding value of home-grown feeds, especially the by-products of sugar beets, and to find out how these feeds can be combined with feeds shipped in so as to yield the highest return from the feeding operations. It is true perhaps that market conditions go further than any other one factor toward controlling the profits from feed - ing operations, yet the kind of ration used is a factor that is of great importance and one that can be controlled by the feeder himself. Important differences in the efficiency of various rations have been found, as will be noted in the fol - lowing pages. The best ration is the one that produces the largest gains with the highest finish and at the lowest cost. Lamb feeding fits in well with a type of farming followed by many irrigation farmers in the North Platte Valley. This is a type of farming in which the principal object sought is the production of large yields of potatoes and sugar beets. Alfalfa is also usually grown in such a cropping system, not so much for the crop itself as for the beneficial effect that it lifts on the following crops after it is plowed up. This type of farming requires a maximum amount of labor during the summer months with little or nothing to do during the winter months. Lambs are usually put into the feed lot after all of the fall work is completed and are shipped to market before spring work begins. This being true, those who are finan - cially able to stand the losses of the bad years find that lamb feeding is profitable, that it furnishes a good market for roughage, such as alfalfa and beet tops, and that it also pro - duces manure on the farm, which aids materially in keeping up the yields of the other crops. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 Most of the lambs used in these experiments were bought on the Denver market, coming there from the ranges of Colo - rado or Wyoming. They were bought during November or December. The lambs varied in weight from year to year. The lightest lambs used were those bought in the fall of 1919, which weighed 42 pounds into the feed lot, while the heaviest ones were those fed during the winter of 1921-1922, which weighed 63 pounds at the beginning of the experiment. The average initial weight of the 3 cars of lambs used in the first experiment was 56 pounds and in the second experiment 50 pounds. Each year all lots were made as nearly alike as pos - sible with respect to weight, breeding, and quality, and all lots were given the same treatment except for the difference in the ration. The initial and final weights were determined by taking the average of at least 3 weights taken on successive I The daily ration was fed in 2 equal portions, morning and ning. The concentrated feeds, such as corn, dried pulp, cottonseed cake, were weighed separately and then mixed ording to the rations of the respective lots, and were then tributed in the feed troughs, which were in a different pen m where the alfalfa was fed. One pound of corn or dried p, or a mixture of the two, per lamb per day, unless other - le stated, was considered a full grain ration. Cottonseed :e was fed at the rate of one-third pound per lamb per day «pt in one lot where it was fed at the rate of one-half md. It usually required about 25 days to get the lambs to a full srrain or cake ration. As much wet pulp, sugar sts, sugar beet tops, and alfalfa hay were fed as the lambs uld consume without unnecessary waste. No uneaten feed, :h as stems of alfalfa, was weighed back to be credited to i different lots. The lambs were fed in open lots without even a windbreak. Alfalfa hay was fed thru hurdles. Sugar beets and sugar beet tops were thrown into the feed lot and were there eaten by the lambs. Corn, dry pulp, and cake were fed in troughs which were in separate yards from the feed lots. Wet pulp and silage were fed in troughs in the feed lots. Molasses was fed on the wet pulp. The lambs always had access to salt. Fresh water was kept in each pen continuously so that the lambs had water at all times. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 7 The prices of feeds' herein used are: Alfalfa hay _ $10.00 per $10.00 per ton Corn silage Sugar beets Wet pulp _ 4.00 per ton 6.00 per ton 1.00 per ton Molasses Beet tops Corn _.. 15.00 per ton .50 per ton yield of beets 1.20 per hundredweight 1.00 per hundredweight 2.50 per hundredweight Molasses dry pulp Cottonseed cake 43% INITIAL COST OF LAMBS The initial cost of the lambs is herein figured at $8 per hundred pounds, weighed into the feed lots with freight paid to Omaha. This means that the lambs cost about $7.50 per hundredweight at Denver, freight paid. The shrink and other small items of expense amounted to about 50 cents per hun - dred pounds. The lambs were fed hay for a few days after arriving at the Experiment Farm before they were weighed into the different lots. By comparing the Denver weights with the initial feed lot weights, one finds an average shrink of 2.6 pounds per lamb. EXPERIMENT NO 1 This feeding test was conducted during the winters of 1916-1917, 1917-1918, and 1918-1919. Each winter there were 10 lots of 30 lambs each. The first winter the lambs were on feed 76 days and the second and third winters they were on feed 100 days. The average initial weight of these lambs was 55 pounds the first year, 60 pounds the second year, and 54 pounds the third year, or an average of 56 pounds per lamb. The lambs fed during the winter of 1918-1919 were ap - praised by lots at the close of the experiment. This was not done the 2 previous years when the lambs were all shipped together and sold as one lot. The appraisal was made by 2 •The following data were furnished by the Great Western Sugar Com - pany and represent the averages for a 5-year period: Ninety-five pounds of plain dry pulp are produced from a ton of susar beets. The molasses dry pulp has from 25 in 30 per cent of molasses. A ton of sugar beets produces 38 pounds of discard molasses having; from 80 to 85 per cent dry matter. After a silo loss of some 37 per cent, about (00 pounds of wet pulp carrying: lfl per cent dry matter are realised from a ton of «ug»r beets. There are about 300 pounds of dry matter in the tops from a ton of autar beets. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 8 expert sheep commission men. The values placed on the lambs of the different lots were based on the Omaha market with the tops selling at $19.50 per hundred pounds. The selling prices used in computing the results of Experiment No. 1 are based on this one appraisal with the tops of $19.50 figured down to a $10 basis, or 51.282 per cent of the 1919 KATIOV* III) Lot 1 — Corn and alfalfa hay Lot 2 — Half corn and half dry pulp and alfalfa hay Lot 3 — Dry pulp and alfalfa hay. Lot 4 — Corn, beet tops, and alfalfa hay. Lot 5 — Corn, wet pulp, and alfalfa hay. Lot 6 — Wet pulp, molasses, and alfalfa hay Lot 7— Alfalfa hay. Lot 8 — Sugar beets and alfalfa hay. Lot 9 — Beet tops and alfalfa hay. Lot 10 — Heavy feed of corn and alfalfa hay. As sugar beets are one of the principal crops grown in fi North Platte Valley, and as dry pulp is a by-product of s industry, it was thought advisable to gather information to the comparative feeding values of dry pulp and corn, was with this in mind that Lots 1. 2, and 3 were fed their respective rations. The corn, dry pulp, or corn and dry pulp together, were fed at the rate of one pound per lamb per day after requiring 25 days to get the lambs up to full feed, or a daily average of 0.875 pound per lamb. The lambs receiving both corn and dry pulp showed a slightly greater average gain than either the straight corn or the straight dry pulp lot. The lambs fed during the winter of 1917-18 produced greater gains from dry pulp than they did from corn, but the average of the 3 tests is in favor of corn. In the hay-corn lot it required 720 pounds of hay and K pounds of corn to produce 100 pounds gain. Where the in ration consisted of half corn and half dry pulp, it re - quired 655 pounds of hay and 161 pounds each of corn and dry pulp. When dry pulp replaced all the com, it required 837 pounds of hay and 338 pounds of dry pulp for the same gain. The dry pulp appears to have a greater feeding value when fed with an equal quantity of corn than it does when used alone. By comparing these 3 lots it appears that in the half and half ration 106 pounds of dry pulp was equivalent »l II". II I I I I M. DIM I'l I.I 1 rilll ( llll\ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 9 to 100 pounds of corn and 43 pounds of hay, while in the dry pulp ration it required 108 pounds of dry pulp and 37 pounds of hay to replace 100 pounds of corn. It might be that a greater variety of feeds is advantageous. The initial cost of the 56-pound lambs was $4.48 each, or $8 per hundredweight. A charge of 15 cents to cover interest and a charge of 40 cents to cover shipping cost are allowed per lamb. These charges together with the feed cost made each lamb cost $7.05, $6.92, and $6.97 respectively for Lots 1, 2, and 3, at Omaha, labor not considered. A shrink of 6 pounds per lamb was allowed from feed lots to Omaha. This shrink is based on the shrink made by the lambs shipped in March, 1922. The corn-fed lambs and the pulp-fed lambs were both valued at $9.75 per hundred pounds, while the lambs fed half corn and half dry pulp were valued at $9.60 Table 1. — Can dry pulp be substituted for corn, wholly or ni part, when fed with alfalfa hay? Experiment No. 1 — 1918, 1919. Lots 1, 2, and S Lot number Number of lambs 1 HII 1 HII 2 90 2 M 3 90 3 ", 1 RATION Corn Alfalfa Com Dry pulp Alfalfa Dry pulp Alfalfa Average gain per lamb Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. Kain: Corn Dry pulp Alfalfa 27.5 313 720 27.7 161 161 655 25.6 338 837 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb Additional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10 r /r for 120 days Marketing _ Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb $7.36 $4.48 $2.02 $ .15 » .40 $7.05 83.5 6 77.5 $9.75 $7.56 $0.51 $6.82 $4.48 $1.8» $ 16 $ 40 $6.92 83.7 6 77.7 $9.60 $7.4« $0.54 $7.57 $4.48 $1.94 $ 15 $ 40 $6.97 81.6 6 75.6 $9.75 $7.37 $0.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 per hundred pounds, or 15 cents less. The appraised value is based on the appraisal made on but one set of lambs, those fed during the winter of 1918-19. The receipts per lamb varied from $7.56 where corn was fed to $7.37 where dry pulp was fed. The net return per lamb was 51 cents where corn was fed, 54 cents where half corn and half pulp was fed, and 40 cents where dry pulp was fed. BKKT TOPS AND WKT PCLP Beet tops and wet pulp are other by-products of the sugar beet industry which have a feeding value for livestock. To obtain data as to their feeding value when fed with alfalfa and corn, Lot 4 and Lot 5 were fed, Lot 4 receiving beet tops and Lot 5 wet pulp. The lambs in Lots 4 and 5 were fed TABLE 2 — Can sugar beet tops or wet pulp from sugar beets be profitably fed vrith an alfalfa and corn ration ? Experi - ment No. 1—1917, 1918, 1919. Lots 1, U, and 5 lOt number ot number lumber of lambs. 1 4 5 lumber of lambs _ I 90 90 90 RATION RATION Corn Alfalfa Corn Top. Alfalfa Corn W&lt;* pulp Alfalfa verage gain per lamb ■ounds feed required for 100 lbs. gain: Corn Tops (from ton of beets) Wet pulp _ Alfalfa 27.5 313 720 32.6 261 1.38 518 30.0 M 14fi2 627 Cost of feed per 100 lb«. gain Initial cost per lamb , Additional costs per lamb: Feed _ Interest at 10% for 120 days _ Marketing _ Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight _ Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb 17.36 $4.48 $2.02 $0.15 $0.40 $7.05 83.5 6 77.5 $9.75 $7.56 $0.51 $6.41 $4.48 $2.09 $0.15 $0.40 $7.12 88.6 6 82.6 $9.85 $8.14 $1.02 $ 6.93 $ 4.48 $ 2.08 $ 0.15 $ 0.40 $ 7.11 86.0 6 80.0 $10.00 $ 8.00 $ 0.8» </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 11 the same daily ration of corn as those in Lot 1. All 3 lots were given all the hay the lambs would clean up. The lambs getting tops or wet pulp were fed all they would consume of these feeds. The results of these 3 lots are tabulated in Table 2. By adding beet tops to the hay and corn ration the average gain per lamb was increased more than 5 pounds while wet pulp increased the gains 2.5 pounds. In the amount of feed required to produce 100 pounds gain, the tops from 1.38 tons of beets were equivalent to 202 pounds of hay and 52 pounds of corn, or 1,462 pounds of wet pulp were equal to 93 pounds of hay and 58 pounds of corn. With the prices of hay and corn as herein used this replacement value would give beet tops a value of $1.18 per ton yield of beets and wet pulp a value of $1.59 per ton. The wet pulp used was weighed at the feed lot after being hauled 8 miles and no doubt con - tained considerably less water than it did at the factory. The appraised values were also in favor of the lambs getting tops or wet pulp, with the wet pulp lambs leading with a value of $10 per hundred pounds, which were market tops. The net profit per lamb was $1.02 where beet tops were fed and 89 cents where wet pulp was fed as compared with 51 cents where only hay and corn were fed. SUBSTITUTING MOLASSKS FOR CORN Molasses is still another by-product of the sugar beet in - dustry which is used as a stock feed. To find out if molasses could be profitably substituted for corn in a wet pulp and alfalfa ration, Lot 6 was fed, the molasses being fed with the wet pulp. As will be seen from Table 3, the lambs fed corn and wet pulp made 30 pounds gain, while the lambs fed wet pulp and molasses made only 19.6 pounds. By comparing the amounts of feed consumed by the lambs in each lot for each 100 pounds of gain made, it can be shown that 255 pounds of corn replaced 283 pounds of hay, 1,543 pounds of wet pulp, and 188 pounds of molasses. On this basis, corn had a feed - ing value of $1.41 per hundred pounds, saying nothing of its value in producing faster gains and lambs of higher selling value. These advantages are reflected in the profit per lamb, which was 89 cents where corn and wet pulp were fed and 30 cents where the lambs were fed molasses and wet pulp. There was 3 times as much profit per lamb where corn was fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">TABLE 3. — Does it pay to feed corn or can sugar factory (feeder's) molasses be substituted for corn in a wet pulp and alfalfa ration? Experiment No. 1—1917, 1918, 1919. Lots 5 and 6 USIfftt 1(1)1 i. II M.I AliONR On most of the irrigated farms of the North Platte Valley there is abundant roughage but little or no grain except that needed for the work horses. This roughage consists mostly of alfalfa hay and beet tops. The problem that confronts the fanner is how to feed this roughage so as to realize the great - est profit with as little extra expenditure for additional feed as possible. If lambs would make sufficient gains on roughage so as to show a profit even tho somewhat less than when fed an additional cash feed, the roughage ration might, in some cases, be advisable. For the farmer to borrow money with which to buy feed increases his feeding risk. Lots 7, 8, and 9 were fed for the purpose of getting information on the ad - visability of feeding lambs for market on roughage alone. Lot number Nutaber of lambs _ ot number utaber of lambs. ... 5 90 6 »0 RATION RATION Corn Wet pulp Alfalfa M. •!».■&lt;»&lt;■&gt; Wei inii|&gt; Alfalfa Average gain per lamb Pounds feed requirefl per 100 lbs. gain: Corn Feeder's molasses Wet pulp Alfalfa 30.0 255 1462 627 19.6 188 ■m 910 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lanfb Additional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10 r /r for 120 days Marketing Total cost per lamb _ Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb $6.93 $4.48 UM $0.15 $0.40 $7.11 86.0 6 so.e $10.(10 $8.00 $0.89 $7.46 $4.48 $1.46 $0.10 $0.40 $6.49 75.6 6 69.6 $9.75 $6./ 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 13 Lot 7 was fed a straight alfalfa hay ration, Lot 8 was fed alfalfa hay and sugar beets, and Lot 9 was fed alfalfa hay and sugar beet tops. The lambs were fed all they would clean up of their respective feeds. The alfalfa hay ration proved to be little more than a maintenance ration and an expensive one at that. Adding sugar beets or beet tops to the alfalfa improved the ration but even then the gains were low. The average gain per lamb was 8.9 pounds in Lot 7, 19.2 pounds in Lot 8, and 19 pounds in Lot 9. The feed require - ment for the gain made was very high. Where hay was fed alone, it required more than 2 tons for each 100 pounds of gain, at a cost of $20.95 or practically 3 times as great as in most of the other lots. The cost of the gains was also very Table 4. — Can lambs be finished for market on roughage alone? Experiment No. 1—1917, 1918, 1919. Lots 7. 8, and 9 Note: All three lots in Table 4 show a kw Lot nu m I i«r Number of lambs 7 HII 8 90 9 90 -! RATION Alfalfa S. beets Alfalfa Topi Alfalfa Average sain per lamb _... Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Sugar beets Tops (from ton of beets) Alfalfa S.H 41»0 19.2 1890 1020 19.0 4.6 1000 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb Additional costs per lamb: Feed _ Interest at 10 r / r for 120 days Marketing Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight Selling value per cwt - Receipts per lamb 1^88 per lamb $20.95 $4.48 $1.86 $0.15 $0.40 $6.89 64.9 6 58.9 $8.70 $5.12 $1.77 $10.76 $4.48 $2.07 $0.15 $0.40 $7.10 75.2 6 69.2 $9.25 $6.40 $0.70 $7.30 $4.48 $1.39 $0.15 $0.40 $6.42 75.0 « 69.0 $9.25 $6.3S $0.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">kh where sugar beets were fed, being $10.76 per 100 pounds. j cost of a 100-pound gain where beet tops were fed was $7.30. By comparing the amount of feed consumed by the lambs in these 3 lots for a 100-pound gain, it may appear that sugar beets and beet tops have a very high feeding value when com - pared with alfalfa. For instance, comparing Lots 7 and 8, it will be seen that 0.95 ton of sugar beets had the same feed - ing value as 1.50 tons of alfalfa hay and, comparing Lots 8 and 9, the tops from 4.6 tons of beets seem to be equal in feeding value to 1.6 tons of alfalfa hay. It is not intended here to convey the idea that it is believed from these results that one-half ton of sugar beets or the tops from 3 tons of sugar beets have the same feeding value as a ton of alfalfa when each is fed alone, but rather, that one-half ton of sugar beets or the tops from 3 tons of beets when fed with 1 ton of alfalfa is equal to 2 tons of alfalfa when fed alone. If Lots 7 and 9 are compared with Lots 1 and 4 respectively the value of corn in these rations becomes apparent. Where E'alfa was fed alone it required 4,190 pounds of hay for a 0-pound gain, but when corn was added to the alfalfa ration required 720 pounds of alfalfa hay and 313 pounds of corn r the same gain. Here 100 pounds of corn replaced 1,110 pounds of alfalfa. When the alfalfa and beet tops ration is compared with the alfalfa, beet tops, and corn ration, 100 pounds of corn had a replacement value of 185 pounds of alfalfa and the tops from 1.23 tons of beets. It seems that when a variety of feeds are fed, the lambs are able to utilize each feed to a better advantage. At the close of the experiments the lambs in each of these 3 lots were classed as feeders. The appraised value of the alfalfa-lambs was $8.70 and of the others each $9.25 per 100 pounds. With this low selling price, together with the small gains made, the lambs in each of these lots show a financial loss. The losses amounted to $1.77 where only alfalfa was fed, 70 cents where sugar beets were fed, and 4 cents where tops were fed. Where corn was added to the alfalfa ration, or to the alfalfa-beet top ration, the net profits per lamb were 51 cents and $1.02, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">LIMITING TIIK COHN RATION Where alfalfa is rather plentiful, as is the case in the North Platte Valley, and where corn must be shipped in, it is important to know whether the daily ration of corn can profitably be limited. It was with this in mind that Lot 10 was fed and is here compared with Lot 1. One pound daily per lamb constituted a full corn ration for Lot 1, while those in Lot 10 were to have received IV2 pounds. It required about 25 days to get the lambs up to 1 pound daily and be - tween 30 and 35 days for them to reach lVa pounds. The lambs in Lot 10 that were fed during the winter of 1918-1919 would not eat IV2 pounds of corn daily. They reached lVfe pounds for about 2 days, when they seemed to go off feed, and from then on until the close of the experiment an average of IVi pounds was all they would eat. Several attempts were made to increase the daily ration up to l'/o pounds but when the amount reached about l'-j pounds the lambs would not clean it up. Had the alfalfa ration been cut down, no doubt the lambs would have consumed IV2 pounds of corn, but the lambs in both lots were fed all the alfalfa hay they would consume. Or, had the lambs been larger, they might have eaten the IV2 pounds without any trouble. These lambs weighed 54 pounds. The average gain per lamb for the 3 years was the same in each lot, being 27.5 pounds. The average for the first 2 years shows 1.3 pounds per lamb in favor of the heavy corn ration, while the last year the gains were 2.6 pounds in favor of the light corn ration. The lambs in Lot 10 being slightly off feed several times during the last year had a damaging effect on both gains and selling price, as shown in Table 5. The amount of feed consumed for 100 pounds of gain was 720 pounds of alfalfa and 313 pounds of corn when the light corn ration was fed and 678 pounds of alfalfa and 374 pounds of corn where a heavy corn ration was fed. The lambs get - ting the heavy corn ration ate 42 pounds less of alfalfa and 61 pounds more of corn per hundred pounds gain. By using the results of only the first 2 years the heavy corn fed lambs consumed 77 pounds less of alfalfa and 52 pounds more of corn than did the lambs getting the light ration of corn. Perhaps if the lambs had been appraised at the close of the first 2 years' experiments, the lambs getting the heavy corn ration would have been appraised as high as, or perhaps higher than, the lambs getting the light corn ration; but, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">as shown in the table, the one appraisal made in the spring of 1919 on the lambs which had been a little off feed several times, valued these lambs at $9.50, or 25 cents per hundred pounds less than the light corn lambs. On the basis of this appraisal and the average of the 3 years' results, the heavy corn fed lambs gave a net profit of 17 cents compared with 51 cents where the corn ration was limited. If the same selling price is used for both lots, the net return per lamb is still in favor of the light corn ration. There are times when a heavy corn ration might be profitable. If the lambs are large and the price of corn relatively cheap compared with alfalfa hay, it might be advisable to limit the hay ration so that the lambs will consume more corn. TABLE 5. — Does it pay to limit the corn in a corn and alfalfa ration? Experiment No. 1 — 1917, 1918, 1919. Lots 1 and 10 Lot number Number of lambs ot number lumber of lambs 1 lit M RATION mmS H. corn Alfalfa RATION Average gain per lamb Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Light corn ration Heavy corn ration Alfalfa 27.5 313 7 I'd 27.5 374 678 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb Additional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10*7r for 120 days Marketing Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot _.. Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight _.._ Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit or loss per lamh $7.3« $4.48 H.M $0.15 $0.40 $7.05 83.5 &lt; 77.5 $8.75 $7.56 $0.51 $7.87 $4.48 $2.18 $0.15 $0.40 »7.1» 83.5 6 77.5 $9.50 $7.3t&gt; $0.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 17 KXI'KRIMEXT XO. 2 This experiment covered 3 winters, 1919-20 to 1921-22 in - clusive. The lambs were bought on the Denver market and were of Colorado or Wyoming origin. The initial feed-lot weights per lamb were 42 pounds for those fed during the winter of 1919-20, 43 pounds for those fed the next winter, and 63 pounds for those fed the third winter, — or an average of 50 pounds. These lambs were on feed 100, 120, and 80 days respectively, with an average feeding period of 100 days. The lambs used the first year were medium large framed, with pood length and height but very thin ; those fed the second winter were fine boned with but little stretch ; and those used the third winter were large type, inclined to be a little coarse and carrying some flesh. The prices here used for feeds and the initial cost of the lambs are the same as in Experiment No. 1. The selling prices are also based on the same top of $10 for 100 pounds. All lots of these lambs were appraised at the end of each feed - ing test. The tops were $18.10 in the spring of 1920, $10 in 1921, and $14.75 in 1922. These tops represented the Omaha tops on the day the lambs were appraised. The average of these three years' tops is $14.30. The selling prices here used are 70 per cent of this 3-year average appraised value and are in most cases the exact values placed on the lambs in 1921, and in no case do they vary more than 10 cents per 100 ix&gt;unds. The principal object of Experiment No. 2 was to gather information on (1) the comparative feeding values of corn and dry pulp, (2) the advisability of adding cottonseed cake to a ration of corn or dry pulp with alfalfa hay, (3) the rela - tive values of a light and a heavy ration of cottonseed cake wh^n fed with alfalfa and dry oulp. (4) the replacement value of beet tops, (5) the comparative feeding values of beet tops and corn silage, and (6) the value of dry pulp in a ration with beet tops or corn silage when fed together with hay and cottonseed cake. HATIONS KKI&gt; IN KM'K.KIMIONT NO. There were 12 lots of lambs in this experiment. The first winter there were 31 lambs per lot and during the next 2 winters there were 25 in each lot. The rations fed to each of these 12 lots were as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 194 Lot 1 — Corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2 — Corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 3 — Corn 40 days, dry pulp 60 days, and alfalfa hay. Lot 4 — Corn 40 days, dry pulp 60 days, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 5 — Dry pulp and alfalfa hay. Lot 6 — Dry pulp, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay Lot 7 — Dry pulp, V4 pound cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay Lot 8 — Dry pulp, cottonseed cake, silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot 9— Cottonseed cake, silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot 10 — Corn, beet tops, and alfalfa hay. Lot 11 — Dry pulp, cottonseed cake, beet tops, and alfalfa hay Lot 12 — Cottonseed cake, beet tops, and alfalfa hay. Corn and dry pulp, or combinations of the two, were fed at the rate of 1 pound per lamb daily, after requiring 25 days to get the lambs up to this amount. Cottonseed cake was fed at the rate of one-third pound per day per lamb except in Lot 7 where it was fed at the rate of one-half pound. Silage was fed at the rate of about 2 pounds. The beet-top lambs were given all the tops they would eat. All lots were fed all the alfalfa hay the lambs would clean up. v| BMill TIM. DRY PILP FOR COHX In this experiment, Lots 1 and 5 received the same rations as did Lots 1 and 3 respectively, in Experiment No. 1. Lot 3 in this test differed from Lot 2 in the preceding experiment in that here the lambs were fed dry pulp alone during the first part of the experiment and then gradually changed to corn so that corn was fed alone during the last part of the experi - ment instead of the corn and dry pulp being fed together in equal amounts during the entire period. Twenty-five days were required to make the change from dry pulp to corn, the amount always being 1 pound of the mixture per lamb daily. As will be seen from Table 6. the gains made per lamb were in favor of corn. The lambs receiving corn made a fraction over 3 pounds per lamb more gain than those getting dry pulp, with the dry pulp-corn lambs about half way between these two. In the way of feed that was required for a hundred pounds gain, the advantage was also in favor of corn. Where alfalfa and corn were fed, the lambs consumed 583 pounds of alfalfa and 302 pounds of corn for a hundred pounds gain ; where dry pulp was fed the first period and corn the last period, it required 631 pounds of alfalfa, 129 pounds of corn, and 204 pounds of dry pulp ; and where alfalfa and dry pulp were fed, it required 652 pounds of alfalfa and 357 pounds of dry pulp </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 19 per hundred pounds gain. By comparing these 3 lots, it can be shown that 100 pounds of corn in the alfalfa-corn lot had the same feeding value as 118 pounds of dry pulp and 23 pounds of hay in the alfalfa-dry pulp lot, and the same as 118 pounds of dry pulp and 28 pounds of hay where alfalfa, dry pulp, and corn were fed. It will be recalled that in the discussion under Table 1 it was shown by comparing Lots 1 and 3 that 100 pounds of corn was required to replace 108 pounds of dry pulp and 37 pounds of alfalfa in Experiment No. 1. By striking the average of the 2 experiments, which will represent an average of 6 tests, it appears that 100 pounds of corn is equivalent in feeding value to 113 pounds of dry pulp and 30 pounds of alfalfa hay. In this experiment the same interest charge, marketing cost, and shrinkage allowance are used as in Experiment No. 1. Table 6. — Can dry pulp be substituted during the first part of the feeding period or thruout the whole period for corn when fed with alfalfa? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 1, S, and 5 Average gain per lamb _... 30.2 28.6 27.1 Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Corn 302 129 Dry pulp _ 204 357 Alfalfa 583 631 652 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain _ $6.54 $6.74 $6.83 Initial cost per lamb $4.00 $4.00 $4.00 Additional costs per lamb: Feed $198 $1.93 $1.S5 Interest at lO'/r for 120 days. | J0.15 $0.15 $0.15 Marketing _ $0 40 $0.40 $0.40 Total cost per lamb *6.53 $6.48 $6.40 Final weight at feed lot | 80.2 78.6 77.1 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha 6 6 6 Selling weight i 74.2 72.6 71.1 Selling value per cwt $9.75 $9.70 $9.65 Receipts per lamb »7.23 $7.04 $6.86 Profit por lamb I $0.70 |LM »0.4« Lot number Number of lambs 1 81 3 81 I 81 RATION Corn Alfalfa Corn Dry pulp Alfalfa w </seg>
            <seg id="p020">(The appraised value of the lambs in the 3 different lots was htly in favor of corn. The net profit per lamb was also f avor of the corn, being 70 cents per lamb where all corn i fed, 56 cents where both dry pulp and corn were fed 46 cents where only dry pulp was fed. Had the dry pulp corn lot been fed 5 days and the dry pulp lot 10 days jer, the lambs in each of these lots would have shown the le gains as did the lambs in the corn lot. And even if the selling values had remained the same, the net profit per lamb in the 2 lots would have been higher. Had the appraised value increased with the gains made, which is possible, the net profit per lamb would have been correspondingly higher but still less than from those in the corn lot, since the feed cost per hundred pounds gain was less in the corn lot. The rate of gains and the selling value of the lambs are factors to be considered along with the cost of feed ; one is equally as important as the other. tl)l)IM. &lt; OTTONSKKD CAKE To gather information on the advisability of adding cotton - seed cake to a ration which included alfalfa hay, Lots 2, 4, and 6 were fed, and the data obtained are given in Table 7. These 3 lots received the same rations as were fed to Lots 1, 3, and 5 respectively, plus one-third pound of cottonseed cake per lamb daily. By comparing Tables 6 and 7, it will be seen that the lambs receiving cake made the greatest gains. This increase amounted to an average of 7.2 pounds per lamb. The addi - tion of cottonseed cake to the ration reduced the amount of other feeds required to produce 100 pounds gain. For in - stance, by comparing Lots 1 and 2 it can be shown that 81 pounds of cottonseed cake replaced 126 pounds of alfalfa and 60 pounds of corn ; in Lots 3 and 4 the replacement value of 87 pounds of cottonseed cake was 145 pounds of alfalfa, 24 pounds of corn, and 38 pounds of dry pulp ; and in Lots 5 and 6, 87 pounds of cottonseed cake were equivalent in feeding value to 174 pounds of alfalfa and 90 pounds of dry pulp. Ir each case the cost of the cottonseed cake fed amounted to more than the feeds saved. This does not mean, however, that the cake-fed lambs made less profit than did the other lambs. As a matter of fact, they made 15 cents per lamb more profit. The cake-fed lambs made 25 per cent more gains </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 21 and sold at 20 cents higher for a hundred pounds which more than balanced the 10 per cent greater feed cost. A 57.5 pound lamb costing 8 cents per pound in the feed lot with freight paid must sell for 10 cents on the market to cover shipping cost, interest, and shrinkage. The profit, therefore, will be the difference between the feed cost and sell - ing value per hundred pounds multiplied by the gains made. If this margin is wide and the gains are high the profit will be greater than when either of the other conditions exists. Where the margin is 2 cents and the gains are 40 pounds per lamb the profit will be the same as with a margin of 4 cents and a gain of 20 pounds. As a guide, it might be stated that the smaller the margin the larger must be the gains and the greater the margin the smaller the gains can be to show a Table 7. — Can dry pulp be substituted in part or whole for corn when fed with alfalfa and cottonseed cake? Experi - ment No. 2—1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 2, U, and 6 Lot number Number of lambs | 2 81 4 81 4 XI 6 81 6 XI RATION Cora Cake Alfalfa Corn Dry pulp Cake Alfalfa Dry pulp Cake Alfalfa h Average gain per lamb Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Corn Dry pulp Cottonseed cake .... . Alfalfa 37.3 242 81 457 35.3 105 166 87 486 34.9 267 87 478 - h Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb Additional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10&lt;7 r for 120 days Marketing _ Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight - Selling value per cwt _ Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb 17.21 $4.00 $2.69 30.15 $0.40 $7.24 87.3 6 81.3 $9.95 $8.09 $0.85 | $7.52 $4.00 $2.65 $0.15 $0.40 $7.20 85.3 6 79.3 $9.85 $7.81 $061 I $7.23 $4.00 $2.52 $0.15 $0.40 $7.07 84.9 6 78.9 $9.85 $7.77 $0.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 profit, the selling value being the same. The lambs that make 40 pounds gain will usually sell at a higher value than those making only 20 pounds. There are 2 kinds of gains, growth and fat. The fat gains are the most profitable because it is the amount of fat over the carcass that determines the margin in the buying and selling values. Fat lambs sell higher than growthy lambs. The greater the difference between the feed cost and the price of fat lambs per hundred pounds, the nearer the price of feeder lambs can approach fat lambs and still show a profit. Again, as the feed cost approaches the price of fat lambs per hundred pounds, the greater the dif - ference must be between the feeder lambs and fat lambs to give a profit. Lots 2, 4, and 6 also afford another comparison between corn and dry pulp. By comparing Lots 2 and 6, 100 pounds of corn were equivalent to 111 pounds of dry pulp, 2.5 pounds of cake, and 9 pounds of alfalfa, and in Lots 4 and 6, 100 pounds of dry pulp replaced 105 pounds of corn. The corn fed during the last period of the feeding test in Lot 4 appears to have had but little more value than dry pulp. Cottonseed cake appears to be equally beneficial when added to either a corn or a dry pulp ration with alfalfa. It did not prove as valuable when fed with a ration where corn replaced dry pulp during the latter part of the experiment. Cottonseed cake at the rate of one-third pound per lamb daily has proved to be a profitable feed to use even tho the gains have been more expensive. LIGHT AMD HF.AVY i IKI HATIONM Both Lots 6 and 7 were fed a ration of alfalfa hay, dry pulp, and cottonseed cake. They differed one from the other in the amount of cottonseed cake fed. The lambs in Lot 6 re - ceived one-third pound daily while the amount was increased to one-half pound per lamb in Lot 7. On the basis of the amount fed, the cake consumed in the heavy cake ration seemed to be almost equally as efficient, pound for pound, as that fed in the light ration. What was said with reference to the beneficial effect of cottonseed cake in the discussion under Table 7 might well be said here. By comparing Lots 6 and 7 it will be seen that the extra amount of cottonseed cake in - creased (1) gains made, (2) cost per hundred pounds gain, and (3) selling value of the lambs. The net profit per lamb was slightly in favor of the lighter ration. With the prices </seg>
            <seg id="p023">here used it may not be advisable to feed more than one-third pound of cottonseed cake per lamb daily ; but should the price of cottonseed cake become relatively cheaper compared with other feeds, then the one-half pound ration should be more profitable. It appears from the results secured from the feeding of different types of lambs that the heavy ration of cottonseed cake was especially beneficial when fed to light-boned, short- coupled lambs as those fed during the winter of 1920-21. Table 8. — Is a third or a half pound daily ration of cottonseed cake per lamb the more profitable when fed with alfalfa and dry pulp? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 6 and 7 Lot number 6 7 Number of lambs 81 81 Dry pulp Dry pulp 1-3 Ib. Cake 1-2 Ib. Cafce RATION Alfalfa Alfalfa Average gain per lamb _.._ J4.9 37.9 Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Dry pulp _ 267 245 Cottonseed cake 87 118 Alfalfa 478 453 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain $7.23 17.66 Initial cost per lamb $4.00 $4.00 Additional costs per lamb: Feed _ _ $2.52 $2.90 Interest at 10% for 120 days 10.15 $0.15 Marketing _ $0.40 $0.40 Total cost per lamb $7.07 $7.45 Final weight at feed lot _ _ 84.9 87.9 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha. _ « 6 Selling weight — I 78.9 81.9 Selling value per cwt. ! $9.85 $9.90 Receipts per lamb - _ ! $7.77 $8.11 Profit per lamb I $0.70 $0.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">ADDING BKKT TOPK TO (l.lll.n AND \ To gather more data on the value of beet tops, a ration of alfalfa, corn, and beet tops was fed to Lot 10 and is com - pared in Table 9 with Lot 1 which received the same ration minus the tops. Lots 1 and 10 in Experiment No. 2 are the same respectively as Lots 1 and 4 in Experiment No. 1. In both experiments the lambs fed beet tops made consid - erably faster gains than did those not getting beet tops. This increase was 5.1 pounds in the first experiment and 4.6 pounds per lamb in the second experiment, with a 6 lot average of 4.85 pounds. Where alfalfa and corn were fed in Experiment No. 2, it required 583 pounds of alfalfa and 302 pounds of corn; and in Lot 10 where beet tops were fed with alfalfa and corn, and it required 391 pounds of alfalfa, 260 pounds of corn, and the tops from 1.68 tons of sugar beets for each TABLE 9. — Can beet tops be profitably fed with a ration of alfalfa and corn? Experiment No. 2—1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 1 and 10 t number ber of lambs t number ber of lambs . 1 81 Hi RATION RATION Corn Alfalfa Corn Tn|&gt;s Alfalfa • Average gain per lamb Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Corn Tops (from ton of beets) Alfalfa M -' Ml 583 34.8 260 1.6K 391 tof feed per 100 lbs. gain al cost per lamb Itional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10&lt;£ for 120 days Marketing il cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb $6.54 14.00 $1.S8 $0.15 $0.40 $6.53 ■M I 74.2 $9.75 $7.23 $0.70 $5.92 $4 IX) $2.0« $0.15 $0.40 $6.61 84.8 6 78.8 $9.80 $7.72 $1.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 25 100 pounds of gains made. On this basis the tops from 1.68 tons of beets were equal in feeding value to 192 pounds of alfalfa and 42 pounds of corn. In Experiment No. 1, as recorded in Table 2, the replacement value of the tops from 1.38 tons of beets was equal to 202 pounds of alfalfa and 52 pounds of corn. The average of these 2 experiments shows that the tops from 16 tons of sugar beets when fed with a ra - tion of alfalfa and corn are equivalent in feeding value to 1 ton of alfalfa hay and 491 pounds of corn. By charging the beet tops at 50 cents per ton yield of beets the gains made in Lot 10 where tops were fed cost less by 10 per cent than did the gains in Lot 1 where tops were not fed. The selling value of the top-fed lambs was $9.80 as compared with $9.75 for those without tops. With the gains made, cost of feed, and selling value of the lambs, all 3 in favor of the lambs getting beet tops, the net profit per lamb must also be in favor of the top-fed lambs. The net profit was 70 cents where alfalfa and corn wero fed and $1.11 where beet tops were fed with alfalfa and corn, or practically 60 per cent increase. To get the most feeding value from beet tops, they should be put into small piles soon after the beets are harvested and later hauled to the yards and fed. Pasturing beet tops is not the best practice either from the standpoint of feeding value or from that of the effect on the land. The season also has much to do with the feeding value of beet tops. If the fall and early winter are wet and cold, the beet tops will not cure properly and therefore their feeding value will be less than when properly cured. A heavy freeze before the beets aro harvested also damages the leaves and lessens the feeding value of the tops. COTTONttKRIt CAKK To get the feeding value of beet tops when fed in a ration of alfalfa, dry pulp, and cottonseed cake, Lot 11 was fed. Lot 11 received the same ration as that fed to Lot 6 with the addition of beet tops. It appears from these results that beet tops have similar value when fed in either a corn or a dry pulp and cake ration. In each case the lambs receiving beet tops made more gains at a lower cost and with a higher profit. The appraised \l&gt;l&gt;l\«. BKKT TOPH TO A KATION OK A I.K AI.K A. PVL.P, AND </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Iies of the 2 corn lots were in favor of beet tops, while the y pulp and cake lots were the same in each case. In terms eed requirement for 100 pounds gain, Lot 6 consumed 478 nds of alfalfa, 267 pounds of dry pulp, and 87 pounds of onseed cake, while Lot 11 consumed 355 pounds of alfalfa pounds of dry pulp, 77 pounds of cottonseed cake, and tops from 1.49 tons of beets. Here the tops from 1.49 i of beets were equal to 123 pounds of alfalfa, 29 pounds try pulp, and 10 pounds of cottonseed cake. On this basis tops from 16 tons of beets have the same feeding value as -thirds of a ton of alfalfa, 310 pounds of dry pulp, and pounds of cottonseed cake. By comparing the replace - it value of tops in this test with the replacement value of tops fed with the alfalfa and corn ration as discussed rJLE 10. — Can beet tops be profitably fed with a ration of alfalfa, dry pulp, and cottonseed cake? Experiment No. 2—1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 6 and 11 t number ber of lambs 6 81 11 II Alfalfa Dry PalP Cake Top. Alfalfa RATION -&gt; r *- r'age gain per lamb ids feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Dry pulp Cottonseed cake Tops (from ton of beets) Alfalfa 2«7 87 478 39.1 238 77 1.49 355 — Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb Additional costs per lamb: Feed _ Interest at 10&lt;* for 120 days. Marketing Total cost per lamb Final weight at feed lot _.._ Shrink from feed lot to Omaha Selling weight Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per Iamb _ _ $7.23 $4.00 $2.52 $0.15 $0.40 $7.07 84.9 6 78.8 *m M $7.77 $0.70 $8.83 $4.00 $2.67 $0.15 $0.40 $7.21' 891 6 83.1 $9.85 $8.19 $0.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 27 under Table 9, it will be seen that the replacement value of beet tops is less when fed with dry pulp and cake than when fed with corn. The lambs in Lot 6 gave a net profit of 70 cents while those in Lot 11, getting beet tops, gave a net profit of 97 cents, an increase of 40 per cent. The beet top-lambs in the corn lots showed an increase in profit of 60 per cent. Beet tops, properly handled, have a higher feeding value than is generally believed. " «&gt;!&lt;&gt; SILAGE AND BEET TOPS COMPARED The building of silos in the North Platte Valley is being encouraged, especially on the high and well-drained lands where the pit silo is possible. In most cases these silos are built primarily as an adjunct to dairying but there is no reason why the silo should not be used more extensively by sheep feeders, especially by those whose farms are too great a distance from the railroad for sugar beet growing to be practicable. Silage when fed in a proper ration is a valuable feed for finishing lambs. It cannot be substituted for grain, however. Lot 8 was fed a ration of alfalfa, dry pulp, cotton - seed cake, and silage. Lot 9 was fed the same ration minus the dry pulp. To get the comparative feeding values of silage and beet tops, Lots 8 and 11 are compared in Table 11 and Lots 9 and 12 are compared in Table 12. The silage corn used in this experiment was of the variety known in eastern Nebraska as Hogue's Yellow Dent, which is a large corn, yielding under good conditions from 15 to 16 tons per acre. It is of the late maturing variety and under western Nebraska's climatic conditions seldom gets beyond the early dent stage. Perhaps the corn yield would amount to about 50 bushels per acre. The common field corn used in western Nebraska, if grown under similar conditions, would produce about 12 tons of silage or around 65 bushels of corn per acre. The silage here used, therefore, is not especially rich in corn. By comparing Lots 8 and 11, it will be seen that the gains made were almost the same in each case, being 0.6 pound in favor of the lambs getting beet tops. For each hundred pounds gain the amounts of dry pulp and cottonseed cake were also about the same, while the lambs getting beet tops con - sumed 70 pounds more alfalfa. The lambs in Lot 8 were fed </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 499 pounds of silage and those in Lot 11 were fed tops from 1.49 tons of beets for the same gains. In round numbers, therefore, this experiment shows that 1 ton of silage is equal in feeding value to the tops from 6 tons of beets and 280 pounds of alfalfa. The cost of a hundred pounds gain was the same in both lots but the selling value was considerably higher for the lambs fed silage. These lambs were in all 3 tests appraised higher than any of the other lambs. They were classed each time as tops of the market. Had the selling value been the same, the net return per lamb would have been practically the same for both lots, but the higher selling value of the silage - fed lambs placed them in the lead by 10 cents of the lambs fed rtLE 11. — How do corn silage and beet tops compare in feed - ing value when fed in a rattan of alfalfa, dry pulp, and cottonseed cake? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. 77 Lot number Number of lambs t number ber of lambs 8 81 11 81 RATION Dry pulp Cake Silwm Alfalfa Dry PU'I Cakr T..|- Alfalfa RATION Average gain per lamb Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Dry pulp Cottonseed cake Silage Tops (from ton of beets) Alfalfa _ 38.5 L'4-' 79 499 285 39.1 238 77 1.49 355 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb ritional costs per lamb: Feed Interest at 10&lt;£ for 120 days Marketing Total cost per lamb '. Final weight at feed lot Shrink from feed lot to Omaha. Selling weight Selling value per cwt Receipts per lamb Profit per lamb $6.83 $4.00 »2.63 10.15 $0.40 $7.18 88.5 6 82.5 $10.0&lt;l $8.25 $1.07 $6.83 $4.0« $2.6/ $0.15 $0.40 $7.2-' 89.1 6 83.1 $9.85 $8.19 $0.»7 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 29 *II.A&lt;;K ANU Illl I TOP* AUAIN COMPAHKI) Lots 9 and 12 afford another comparison between silage and beet tops. Lot 9 was fed alfalfa, silage, and cottonseed cake and Lot 12 was fed alfalfa, beet tops, and cottonseed cake, differing from Lots 8 and 11 respectively, in that dry pulp was omitted. The lambs fed beet tops made faster gains than the lambs fed silage. This increase amounted to 3.7 pounds per lamb. From the amount of the different feeds that was required to make 100 pounds gain, it appears that in this test 1 ton of silage and 41 pounds of cottonseed cake have the same feeding value as the tops from 5 tons of beets and 75 pounds TABLE 12. — What are the comparative feeding values of silage and beet tops when fed in a ration of cottonseed cake and alfalfa? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 9 and 12 ] Lot number 9 12 Number of lambs 81 81 Cake Cake RATION Silam Topi Alfalfa Alfalfa Average Rain per lamb _ 22.1 25.8 Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: Cottonseed cake 137 117 Silage »72 Beet tops (from ton of beets) 2.47 Alfalfa 561 597 H Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain $«.1« $7.15 Initial cost per lamb 1400 $4.00 Additional costs per lamb: Feed - $180 $1.84 Interest at 10% for 120 days $0.15 $0.15 Marketing $0.40 $0.40 Total cost per lamb $«.SS $6.39 Final weight at feed lot 72.1 75.8 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha « « Selling weight I M.l , 69.8 Selling value per cwt $9.20 $9.40 Receipts per lamb $6.08 $6.56 Lou Profit Profit or loss per lamb $0.27 $0.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">of alfalfa. The cost of a hundred pounds gain was $1.01 higher where silage was fed. The lambs in both of these lots were classed as feeders, with those in the lot getting silage appraised at $9.20 and those getting beet tops at $9.40 per hundred pounds. These were both poor lots financially, the lambs in Lot 9 showing a loss of 27 cents each, while those in Lot 12 gave the slight profit of 17 cents. It will be remembered that the 3 lots of lambs in Ex - periment No. 1 that were fed only roughage each showed a financial loss. In this experiment, even when cottonseed cake was fed with the roughage, the returns showed either a loss or but a slight profit. It is very evident from these 2 experiments that lambs cannot be finished for market on roughage alone. A finishing ration must include a grain or a grain substitute. The importance of a grain substitute is clearly brought out in the next 2 tables. ADDING DRY I»l I.I' TO A RATION OP »ll. tl.K. I irrri&gt;\ »l .1 .11 &lt; \KI AND ALFALFA One would naturally think that lambs getting all the alfalfa and corn silage they would eat, together with a third pound daily ration of cottonseed cake, could make rather satisfactory gains and perhaps show a profit, other things being favorable, but, as shown in the table, the lambs getting this ration made the poorest gains of all lots and were the only lot that showed a financial loss. On the other hand, where dry pulp was added to this same ration, it proved to be one of the most profitable lots in the experiment. This wide difference is due to the fact that the ration fed in Lot 9 was lacking in a real concentrated fat-producing feed such as grain. To show the real im - portance of even a grain substitute as a supplement in a ration for finishing lambs for market, Lots 8 and 9 are compared in Table 13. The increase in the weight of the lambs getting dry pulp was much greater. The gains made per lamb were 38.5 pounds where dry pulp was fed and 22.1 pounds where dry pulp was omitted, an increase of 16.4 pounds or 74 per cent in favor of the lambs getting dry pulp. In terms of feed requirement for a hundred pounds gain, it can be shown from these results, by a little simple arithmetic, that 242 pounds of dry pulp in a ration of alfalfa, dry pulp, silage, and cottonseed cake had the same feeding value as 276 pounds of alfalfa, 58 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 473 pounds of silage in the same ration without the dry pulp. In other words, with the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 31 prices of alfalfa, cottonseed cake, and silage as here used, dry pulp would have a feeding value of $31.15 per ton. The feed cost of a hundred pounds gain was $1.33 cheaper where dry pulp was included in the ration. One of the out- standing differences in the lambs of these 2 lots was the degree of finish as indicated by their appraised value at the close of the experiment. The pulp-fed lambs were valued at $10 per hundred pounds, which was the top for the market, while the lambs getting the same ration except the dry pulp were appraised at $9.20, which was the lowest of all the lots. Dry pulp in a ration of alfalfa, silage, and cottonseed cake is here the determining factor between profit and loss. Where dry pulp was fed, the profit was $1.07 per lamb and where dry pulp was omitted from the ration the loss was 27 cents per lamb. Table 13. — Does it pay to add dry pulp to a ration of silage, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 8 and 9 Average gain per lamb _ J8.5 22.1 Pounds feed required per 100 lb«. gain: Dry pulp I 242 Cottonseed cake _ 79 137 Cottonseed cake Silage 499 972 Alfalfa 285 561 Coat of feed per 100 lbs. gain $6.83 $8.16 Initial cost per lamb $4.00 $4.00 Additional costs per lamb: Feed _ $2.63 $1.80 Interest at 10% for 120 days. j $0.15 $0.16 Marketing $0.40 $0.40 Total cost per lamb $7.18 $6.35 Final weight at feed lot _ 88.5 72.1 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha, 6 6 Selling weight - I M-5 66.1 Selling value per cwt $10.00 $9.20 Receipts per lamb _ _ $8.25 $6.08 Profit Low Profit or loss per lamb I $1.07 $0.27 jot number S'umber of lambs... 8 81 I SI Dry pulp Cake Sila*.- Alfalfa Cake Silage Alfalfa RATION </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 194 ADDING DRY PULP TO A RATION Of' COTTOXHKKD (AKK, ■KKT TOPS, AND ALFALFA I Another check on the importance of grain, or its substi - i, in a ration for finishing lambs for market is afforded by lparing Lots 11 and 12, where alfalfa, dry pulp, beet tops, I cottonseed cake were fed to the first-named lot and the ne ration minus dry pulp to the other lot. As shown in jle 12, a ration of alfalfa, beet tops, and cottonseed cake ived to be a better combination than the same ration where t tops were replaced by silage, and will not, therefore w as marked difference in favor of the grain substitute was shown in the discussion following Table 13, but even ■e it had a great influence. Here, too, the gains made were very much in favor of I lambs getting dry pulp, this increase amounting to 13.3 inds or 52 per cent for each lamb. The feed cost was less 32 cents per hundred pounds gain in the ration where dry p was fed. By comparison, the results of this test show t 238 pounds of dry pulp was equal in feeding value to 242 inds of alfalfa, 40 pounds of cottonseed cake, and the tops m 1 ton of beets. With prices here used, this gives dry p a feeding value of $22.75 per ton. The dry pulp had 1 a greater value in its power to produce lambs of higher ing value per hundred pounds. Where dry pulp was fed. lambs were valued at $9.85. Those not getting dry pulp re valued at $9.40 per hundred pounds. The real value of dry pulp in this ration is clearly shown in the net profit • lamb, being 97 cents for the lambs fed dry pulp and 17 cents for the lambs not getting dry pulp. One hundred lambs fed the dry pulp ration would yield the same returns as 570 lambs fed the same ration without the dry pulp. The feed replacement value of the dry pulp in this com - parison does not represent its entire value in the ration. Bere dry pulp was fed. the gains were much greater and the ing value higher. With other prices remaining the same as here used, dry pulp could cost up to $37 per ton and still show the same profit as that produced by the lot where dry pulp was not fed. ( Again, in Lot 8, where alfalfa, dry pulp, silage, and cottonseed cake were fed, if the dry pulp consumed had cost $48 per ton the loss pe** lamb would not have been any greater than was the loss in Lot 9. where the same ration except the dry pulp was fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 33 It is not the purpose here to show so much the feeding value of dry pulp as it is to discourage any attempt to finish lambs for market without feeding some kind of grain or its substitute. It is probable, had corn been fed instead of dry pulp in Lots 8 and 11, that its greater feeding value, as shown all thru these experiments, would here also have been mani - fest. In these experiments where corn and dry pulp have been compared, the results show that dry pulp has from 80 to 85 per cent the feeding value of corn. This does not mean, however, that a feeder is justified in paying up to this same per cent of the price of corn for dry pulp, since corn has an additional value in its power to produce faster gains and lambs of slightly higher selling value, which are important factors to be considered in planning a ration. Table 14. — Does it pay to add dry pulp to a ration of cotton - seed cake, beet tops, and alfalfa? Experiment No. 2 — 1920, 1921, 1922. Lots 11 and 12 Lot number 11 12 Number of lambs 81 81 Dry pulp Cake Cake Top« Top» RATION Alfalfa Alfalfa Average gain per lamb S9.1 25.8 Pounds feed required per 100 lbs. gain: 238 Dry pulp Cottonseed cake 77 117 1.49 2.47 Tops (from ton of beets) Alfalfa 355 597 Cost of feed per 100 lbs. gain Initial cost per lamb $6.83 ' $7.15 $4.00 $4.00 Additional costs per lamb: Feed $2.67 $1.84 Interest at 10&lt;7r for 120 days $0.15 $0.15 Marketing $0.40 $0.40 Total cost per lamb $7.22 $6.39 Final weight at feed lot 89.1 75.8 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha 6 6 83.1 69.8 Selling weight Selling value per cwt. Receipts per lamb Profit or loss per lamb $9.85 $9.40 $8.19 *6.56 $0.97 $0.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">PACKING HOI SK DATA fin the spring of 1921 and 1922 when the lambs were sent market, some of the lots were weighed just before leaving the feed yard so as to compare their feed lot weights with Omaha weights to ascertain the shrink per lamb. The lambs of the different lots were also marked and the packing house that bought the lambs was asked to kill each lot separately and get the dressing percentage and the quality of meat of the lambs fed different rations. Swift &amp; Company bought the lambs both years, and the data furnished by them together with the average shrink per lamb are given in Table 15 for ti lambs shipped in 1921 and in Table 16 for those shipped 1922. TABLE 15. — Shotving gains made, shrink from feed lot to Omaha, and yield of the lambs fed different rations at the Scottsbluff Substation, 1921. The lambs were on feed 120 day 8 Average per lam As will be seen from Table 15 the shrink was rather high for the lambs shipped in 1921, considerably higher than for the following year. The lambs fed silage or beet tops shrank more than the lambs in the other lots. There appears to be no difference in the amount of shrink or yield between corn - fed and dry pulp-fed lambs. Just why the yield should be so low for Lot 3, which was fed dry pulp during the first period and then finished on corn, is difficult to explain. The quality of meat of the lambs in all lots was classed as being No. RATION No. Uu. Shrink Yield 1 Alfalfa, corn 2 Alfalfa, corn, cottonseed cake.. • Alfalfa, dry pulp, corn • Alfalfa, dry pulp, cake S Alfalfa, dry pulp, silage, cake 10 Alfalfa, corn, top* 11 Alfalfa, dry pulp, tops, cake... ■ 30 3« ■ 35 40 36 42 6.8 7.4 7.2 7.6 86 M 9.6 463(1 47.7» 44.64 47.35 48 16 48.56 47.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western Nebraska 35 The shrink per lamb was less in 1922 than in 1921. While the average shrink of the lots getting either silage or beet tops was a little higher than the average of the other lots, there was not as great a difference as was the case in 1921. In this test the corn lots showed a little less shrink than the dry pulp lots. The shrink per lamb of the lots getting the same ration each year was not consistent. For instance, Lot 10 showed a high shrink in 1921 but a relatively low shrink in 1922. The yield seems to be about the same for corn or dry pulp when cottonseed cake is added to the ration. The percentage of fat, however, is in favor of corn. The yield and percentage of fat is very low for Lot 5 where alfalfa and dry pulp were fed. The gains were also low. It appears from this and from the results from the feeding tests that cottonseed cake is advisable in a ration where dry pulp is fed. TABLE 16. — Showing gains made, shrink from feed lot to Omaha, and yield of the lambs fed different rations at the Scottsbluff Substation, 1922. The lambs were on feed 80 days Average per lamb Gain* Shriak Yield Fat «... Lbt. Percent Percent N RATION 11 Alfalfa, dry pulp, beet tops, cake 31 8.0 49.60 2.2 [I-U-5M] 1 0 Alfalfa, corn Alfalfa, corn, cottonseed cake Alfalfa, dry pulp, corn, cotton- seed cake _ Alfalfa, dry pulp Alfalfa, dry pulp, cottonseed cake Alfalfa, dry pulp, Vt lb. cotton- seed cake Alfalfa, dry pulp, silage, cake Alfalfa, corn, beet tops L'4 3d 28 20 28 3d 31 30 u M 4 4 M 7.6 7.9 6.2 i 47.93 49.57 49.56 46.12 49.37 49.56 48.95 49.38 2.0 2.7 2.3 1.4 2.2 2.0 2.1 2.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE Scottsbluff Experiment Substation is located on the North Platte Reclamation Project, 6 miles east of Mitchell and 8 miles northwest of Scottsbluff, Nebraska. The tract consists of 160 acres of land irrigated from the Government canal. A wide variety of experiments are being conducted with irrigated crops. The work of the Station is maintained co - operatively by the University of Nebraska and the United States Department of Agriculture, and is under the direction of a superintendent detailed by the Office of Western Irrigation Agriculture, United States De - partment of Agriculture. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>