<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF THE GAME, FORESTATION and PARKS COMMISSION STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Years of 1929, 1930 and 1931</title>
               <date value="1931-12-31">1931-12-31</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF THE Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Commission STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Years of 1929, 1930 and 1931 GAME, FORESTATION &amp; PARKS COMMISSION Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page No. Letter of Transmittal 3 Organization 4 Financial Report 6 Administration 1 0 Secretary's Office 12 Permits Issued - 12 Law Enforcement - — : 1 6 Arrests, Confiscations, Etc. _ . _. 18 State Parks . &#132;.. 20 Recreation Grounds 25 Forestation — ■- 3 1 Game Reserves . I~ 34 Game Birds -. 35 Fish Propagation 39 Fish Distribution - 44 Fish Stocked 58 Conservation &amp; Salvage of Fish . 61 Educational Work 65 Scientific Research 67 Exhibitions ... 69 Hunters' Shooting Script 70 Game, Fur &amp; Fish Farming 7 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL State of Nebraska Office of Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Commission, Lincoln, Nebraska To His Excellency, Chas. W. Bryan, Governor. My Dear Sir: I herewith submit to you a report of the business transacted by the Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Commission, State of Nebraska, for the three years since the Commission has been m existence, i. c., 1929, 1930 and 1931, as required by law. In the interests of economy it has been deemed advisable to publish the report biennially rather than annually. No separate report was published m 1 929 as the Commission did not come into existence until April 22 of that year, therefore we are including the eight months of 1929 along with the re - ports of 1930 and 1931. Respectfully, FRANK B. O/CONNELL, December 31, 1931 Secretary and Warden </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION * ORGANIZATION THE Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Commission came into exist - ence on April 22, 1929, at which time the revised Game Code, contained in House Roll No. 466 of the 1929 Session of the State Legislature, being an emergency measure, was ap - proved by. the Governor. At that time Governor A. J. Weaver appointed the fol - lowing five members to become Game Commissioners and to hold office as designated: - Hon. E. R. Purcell, Broken Bow, for a term of five years, ending on January 15, 1934. i Hon. F. A. Baldwin, Ainsworth, for a term of four years ending on January 15, 1933. Hon. Webb Rice, Norfolk, for a term of three years end - ing on January 15, 1932. Hon. Guy R. Spencer, Omaha, for a term of two years end - ing January 15, 1931. Hon. George Dayton, Lincoln, for a term of one year end - ing on January 1 5, 1 930. At a meeting held in the Governor's office on May 9, 10, 1929, with Governor A. J. Weaver acting as ex-officio chair - man, as provided by law, the Commission was duly organized and selected Frank B. O'Connell, Lincoln, formerly Chief of the Bureau of Game &amp; Fish, Department of Agriculture, as Secretary and Warden, for a term of five years, ending Jan - uary 15, 1934. Other personnel of the old Bureau of Game &amp; Fish, De - partment of Agriculture, were taken over, as well as the several institutions and property pertaining to game and fish administra - tion. The four State Parks, formerly under the State Park Board, were also taken over, together with the superintendents of same. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">STATE OF NEBRASKA 5 On January 15, 1930, the term of office of Hon. George Dayton expired and at that time Governor Weaver re-appointed Mr. Dayton for a term of five years, ending January 15, 1935. On December 31. 1930 Governor Weaver announced that he had received the resignation of Hon. George Dayton be - cause of illness, and further announced that he had appointed Hon. George Hastings, Grant, to fill the vacancy. On January 8. 1931, Hon. Chas. W. Bryan became ex - officio chairman of the Commission, having been elected Governor to succeed Hon. A. J. Weaver. On January 15, 1931 Governor Bryan re-appointed Hon. Guy R. Spencer for a term of five years, ending January 15, All commissioners appointed by the several Governors were confirmed by joint sessions of the Legislature, as provided by law, and all furnished the necessary bonds. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GAME, PORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION FINANCIAL STATEMENT A LL moneys expended by the Game, Forestation &amp; Parks XVCommission are derived from the sale of hunting, fishing, trapping and other permits and from the sale of fish, concessions at state parks, sale of confiscated articles, liquidated damages and sundry other sources. The State Legislature appropriated the permit fees only and no part of funds expended are derived from general taxation. The state law provides that not to exceed ten per cent (10%) of all game fund receipts are to be used for the mainte - nance and improvements of the state parks. YEAR OF 102D On hand, Dec. 31, 1928 $197,580.27 RECEIPTS: Sale of Permits 197,204.00 Sale of Fish 6,321.29 Sale of Confiscated Articles ■. 443.82 Sale of Real Estate (By Direction of the State Legislature) : 150. 00 Concession Receipts from Parks : 1,452.46 Liquidated Damages 1,881.00 Collections from 1928 Accounts , ' 569.50 Overpaid 1929 Accounts 277.00 Miscellaneous Receipts ■. 362.08 Total Receipts '. $208,061.15 EXPENDITURES: The following expenditures were made by the Commission for the eight months of 1929 during which they were in charge. The first four months of 1929 are covered in reports of the Department of Agriculture. Administration $ 10,030.20 Law Enforcement ■. 29.110.64 Fish Distribution 13,906.04 Conservation and Field Activities 15,534.27 Purchase Game Birds 3.193.00 Purchase Game Fish , 2,659.40 Eggs, Feed, etc 544.75 Purchase and Care of Trees 52.80 Educational Work : 1,985.82 Scientific Work 167.97 Purchase and Improvement Recreation Grounds 3,340.79 Purchase and Improvement Distribution Plant 20,091.52 Fish Hatcheries: </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE OF NEBRASKA 7 Gretna 7 514 „, . &lt; Valentine : 1fifi77K9 Dundy County ~ZZZ\Z\\ZZZZZ.Z l.iri'.lt State Parks: Arbor Lodge q 49c rc Chadron 23874a Victoria Springs ', ' st °»*y : :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::; Jllli ANALYSIS OF ■EXPENDITURES:' ' $149,006.32 Land Purchased % » jgg r^g Permanent Improvements 31 704*19 Equipment Purchased .- .^ZZZZIZZZIZZ-ZZ 16*999'l0 General Operation Expense "™""""" 100*146*35 Total $149,006.32 year of 1oso receipts: ?^ e °J *f™ ita $217,407.00 Sale of Fish 5 837 87 Sale of Confiscated Articles ZZ! 1017 63 Concession Receipts from Parks 955 17 Liquidated Damages 2 35500 Collections from 1929 Accounts 32100 Miscellaneous Receipts "".".."""I 419.21 Total Receipts I228.312.8S EXPENDITURES: Administration g jg 8 jq 7 q Law Enforcement ■ 4s'qri «•&gt; Fish Distribution ..//.!ZZ"Z'.Z"/.Z'r. : 23 17477 ■ Conservation and Field Activities .Z.Z.Z. 22270 17 Purchase Game Birds ZZZ! 19*034 25 Purchase Game Fi3h '."'."."".'.[ "'. 13649 00 Purchase Eggs, Feed, etc 2766 SO - Forestation Work \ 9*824 67 Educational Work i'qiq'99 Scientific Work .; ZZZ^ZZZZZZZ! 85492 Purchase and Improvement Recreation Grounds 77 031 23 Fish Hatcheries: .--.-,. G /f na , ••■ - 12,601.47 Valentine V 17,364.49 Dundy County 16.974.Q4 ■ State Parks: Arbor Lodge 5 049 93 Chadron 6,544.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION Volley ; 3,405.60 Victoria Springs -. 3,463.70 Niobrara Island 394 02 Total ■ $307,097.72 ANALYSIS OP EXPENDITURES: Land Purchased $ 49,243.00 Permanent Improvements 44,807 27 Equipment Purchased '...'.'.'.".".'.'.":'. 20434 21 Game Birds and Fish Purchased' 32 6S3 25 General Operation ; 159, 929*99 Total ■ $307,097.72 YEAR OP 1931 RECEIPTS: Sale of Permits $212,693 36 Sale of Pish ; 2,743.85 Sale of Confiscated Articles 686 80 Concessions "'""'"'""""''*' 1,008.79 Liquidated Damages 975.00 Collections 1930 Accounts 283*58 ' Miscellaneous Receipts 37.07 Total Receipts *$2 18,428.4 5 * — These receipts are estimated, as some accounts are still unsettled and the State Auditor has not examined them at time of publication of report. EXPENDITURES: Administration .. $ 16,495.56 •Law Enforcement 41,163.92 Pish Distribution ; """.".""".", 2o!,82o'l8 Conservation and Field Activities ..."... 18'l65 - 43 Purchase Game Birds 2,440.93 Purchase Game Fish 16,997'61 Purchase Game Animals 769 14 Purchase Fish Eggs ......":."*"""".""" 1,59500 Forestation Work , 4.S35.04 Educational Work 2'888*67 Scientific Work .....„.........."!..." 177.81 Purchase and Improvement Recreation Grounds 92 472 4 5 Fish Hatcheries: Gretna J 9,755.10 Valentine ; 29,892.47 Dundy County 17,905.47 State Parks: Arbor Lodge , 5.S18.42 Chadron 7,693.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE OF NEBRASKA 9 Stolley - 3.652.53 Victoria Springs 3,590.15 Niobrara Island 553.60 Total Expenditures ; $297,683.24 ANALYSIS OF EXPENDITURES: Land Purchased ; $ 68,023.72 Permanent Improvement 48.102.63 Equipment Purchased 3,892 76 Game Birds and Fish Purchased ......Z.'.Z l!o95.00 Maintenance and Improvement State Parks 21,30s!46 Maintenance and Improvement Fish Hatcheries 57,553.04 General Operation 97,207.63 Total -■ $29 7,683.24 On Hand December 31st, 1931 $ 38,274.89 Book Accounts Due (estimated) 30,000.00 Total - - $ 68,274.89 Real Estate now owned (estimated value) .. 518,000.00 Equipment: Fish Car ...$ 20,000.00 Fish Trucks 10,000.00 Automobiles 6,000.00 Office 2,000.00 • State Park Fixtures and Supplies .... 10,000.00 Hatchery Equipment and Supplies .... 5,000.00 Engines, Pumps, etc. '. 2,500.00 Seines 1,000.00 Total $ 56,500.00 Total Real Estate and Equipment $574,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION ADMINISTRATION Commissioners : Chas. W. Bryan, Chairman Guy R. Spencer, Omaha George B. Hastings, Grant E. R. P.urcell, Broken Bow F. A. Baldwin, Ainsworth Webb Rice, Norfolk. Secretary and Warden: Frank B. O'Connell, Lincoln. : Office Employees: June Jackson, Neligh, Chief Clerk Delia Konkel, Broken Bow, Bookkeeper Enola Hassler, Ogallala, Stenographer. Commission Meetings. The Commissioners meet four times each year for regular ' quarterly meetings and as often for special meetings as business warrants. During 1929 there were nine meetings held, during 1930 eleven meetings and during 1931 there were five. Be - sides these meetings the commissioners did considerable field work, visiting the various institutions under their control, in - specting real estate with a view to its purchase for recreation grounds and other inspections which were necessary. Committees In order to expedite the work .of the Commission and to divide the various duties, a number of standing committees were named during the past several years. Chief among these were the following: Hatcheries, Distribution and Nurse Ponds Committee: Spencer, Chairman; Baldwin, O'Connell. State Parks Committee: Purcell, Chairman; Hastings, O'Connell. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE OF NEBRASKA 11 Lakes and Recreation Grounds Committee: Baldwin, Chair - man; Spencer, O'Connell. Game Reserves, Game Production, Forestation Committee: Rice, Chairman; Purcell, O'Connell. Conservation and Scientific Surveys Committee: Hastings, Chairman; Rice, O'Connell. Vice-Chairman: Webb Rice. Per Diem and Expenses. Under the law each Commissioner receives $ 1 0 per day for such time as devoted to the work of the Commission but in no case to exceed thirty days in any one year. Each Commissioner also receives his necessary travel expense for attending meetings and inspection work, etc. During the three years the per diem and expenses of the several Commissioners were as follows: YEAR OP 1920 Commissioners Expenses Per Diem A. J. Weaver $ 37.84 $ F. A. Baldwin 589.29 300.00 Webb Rice 163.60 150.00 E. R. Purcell 242.41 210.00 Guy R. Spencer 262.66 130.00 George Dayton 123.98 300.00 ♦Frank B. O'Connell 478.64 YEAR OP 1030 Commissioners Expenses Per Diem A. J. Weaver : ; $ 19.61 $ F. A. Baldwin 696.95 300.00 Webb Rice 322.38 215.00 E. R. Purcell 828.17 300.00 Guy R. Spencer 585.41 300.00 George Dayton ; 7.50 90.00 •Frank B. O'Connell 1,055.95 YEAR OP 1031 Commissioners Expenses Per Diem F. A. Baldwin $ 675.23 $300.00 Webb Rice 153.58 115.00 E. R. Purcell 1 329.02 240.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">GAME. FORESTATICN AND PARKS COMMISSION Guy R. Spencer ; .' 2 26.69 150.00 Geo. B. Hastings 14 3 . 48 110 00 •Frank B. O'Connell 802.16 * — Tn e Secretary devotes his entire time to the work of the Com - mission and in lieu of per diem receives an annual salary of $3,000.00. Under the law Commissioners are not permitted to receive per diem for more than thirty days in any calendar year. Several of the above Commissioners have given considerable more time to the work than the stipulated thirty days, for which, of course, they received no al - lowances. SecreUuy's Office. Three rooms in the State Capitol are occupied by the Secre - tary of the Commission and his office assistants. Here all the permits, records, correspondence, educational activities and gen - eral administration work is centered. Permits. Each year it is necessary to issue some 200,000 permits, as follows : Resident Hunting and Fishing. Non-Resident Hunting and Fishing. Non-Resident Fishing. Resident Trapping. Non-Resident Trapping. Alien Fishing. Game Bird Breeding. Fur-Bearing Animal Breeding. Game Fancier. Fur-Buying Permit. Missouri River Commercial Fishing. Fish Vendor's Permit. Private Fish Hatchery. : Training Dogs. Beaver Damage Permit. Pheasant Damage Permit. Scientific Permit. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1923 EUailZio^^ GROWTH OF DEPARTMENT ]^24 Hums—— SALE OF PERMITS,ETC JU/.D I $167,469.69 MMBMMBI iQ7fi bl73.61Q.16 — — |^J i | i M^— jj^| 1929 I M— B— 1MB 1930 Ull^lIoOIH^HHiHBIHH PERMITS ISSUED . • J»20 1030 1031 Resident Hunt and Fish ....'. 170 244 1S7 02? .,-,„„ Non-Resident Hunt and Fish ZZZ " Ml 448 • «? Non-Resident Fish 3 1G4 , , = , ,, ill Resident Trapping \\\\ *•*** l*'°»* Nonresident Trapping ' , Alien Fishing """ 22 „•" "" Breed Game Birds 453 532 J° K^ 1 " 8 Anlmals E:: L B J " Non-Resident BuyFurs 1G tl Scientific Permits 2q J7 " Game Fanciers ... "' f. Private Fish Hatcheries .... 9, ,: Pheasant Damage "'".'. " 400 iin . Beaver Damage \Z ZZ ll 164 *Note— The above figures are estimated, inasmuch as the State Au - ditor s report is incomplete at time of publication of this report. Permits are sold by over a thousand accounts including county clerks, hardware stores, banks, sporting goods stores, etc. Each year it is necessary to print the permits and send them out to the accounts and" make collections for the same, account - ing to the State Auditor for all sums collected. The books are audited at the end of each year and reports of same are filed. 1 The amount of money derived from permits each year can be ascertained by referring to the financial section of this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION Maps. In order to carry out a state-wide program of conservation, the Commission authorized the Secretary to begin a five-year program of mapping the various natural resources in the State. This work has been carried on for two years and maps covering some thirty counties are now available in the Secretary's office, which show water, forests and recreational resources. These maps are cased and made in such form that blue prints can easily be made from them at anytime work is to be carried on in any particular county. At the time the Commission took charge there were no records available in the Secretary's office showing these resources, and it was deemed advisable to get this work started at an early date in order to better administer laws gov - erning such matters. Contracts. ■ During the past three years numerous contracts have been made for the purchase of land, building of lakes, nurseries, buildings, etc. Most of this work has been done by contracts, copies of contracts being on file in the Secretary's office, al - though in some cases the work has been carried on by the Com - mission's own personnel, thus utilizing employees during off seasons on other work and equipment already owned. All the legal papers pertaining to transfer of land have been approved by the Attorney General of the State, properly recorded in the counties where such parcels of land were bought, and the papers pertaining thereto filed in the Secretary's office.' Educational Work. The Commission has felt that education is an important part of law enforcement and has authorized steps to be taken which would bring to the people of Nebraska a realization of the need of conservation and the strict, observance of all game laws. In order to carry this to the majority of the citizens of the Com - monwealth, the State Press has been used, and at this time the Commission desires to acknowledge the ifine co-operation which </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE OP NEBRASKA has been given them by the staff of reporters on duty at the State Capitol, as well as the Press Association representatives and editors of the various state papers. A quarterly publication, known as "Outdoor Nebraska," has been published. Some seven thousand copies of this bulletin are distributed each quarter of the year to sbhools, organizations and individuals interested in conservation work. • Motion pictures have been taken of the Commission's activ - ities and these have been furnished free with a game warden in charge to lecture to the schools and organizations desiring same. During the past two years one hundred showings have been made to approximately twenty-five thousand citizens of the State. Correspondence and Records. The Secretary's office handles a large volume of correspond - ence each year, the same growing as time goes on. Thousands of inquiries are received in the course of each year, all of which are g.ven prompt attention. Hundreds of complaints regarding game violations, etc., are received, which are immediately placed m the hands of district game wardens for personal investigation. Records are kept of all correspondence and transactions and are available when needed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION LAW ENFORCEMENT Chief Warden: Frank B. O'Connell. Special Investigator: Wm, H. Lytle, Benedict. District Wardens: C. C. Herling, I 1 09 Chase St., Falls City. C. C. Rankin, Kearney. Frank DeVry, Route No. 1 , Ames. Dewey Grace, Valentine. W. J. Weller, Atkinson. . ,C. A. Gray, 805 South 2nd St., Norfolk. L. J. Cunningham, Hay Springs. E. Sinner, Culbertson. W. O. Monnette, So. Sioux City. C. A. Parkhurst, Creighton. Loron Bunney, Columbus. B. H. Lashmett, Ord. Everett Ling, Harvard. Chas. Butler, Tecumseh. *M. E. Ramsey, Bridgeport. *This warden was employed until Dec. 1, 1931. i I ' iiiii — i — I — </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE OF NEBRASKA Special Wardens. In addition to the District Wardens, there are a number of Special Deputy Wardens in the several districts. It has been found more satisfactory to use Special Wardens primarily for watching Game Reserves, . Recreation Grounds and reporting information regarding violation of law, rather than making ar - rests. Where possible, the District Warden makes the arrest and prosecutes upon the evidence secured by special men. Bonds. All Wardens are required to give surety bonds. District Wardens give bonds in the sum of $2500.00 each and Special Wardens in the sum of $500.00 each. Uniforms. . The later part of 1929, the Commission furnished each Dis - tnct Warden with a suitable uniform and since that time, wardens have been required to wear the same while checking permits and where coming in contact with the public generally. Of course it is not always possible for the warden to be in uniform, as at times he must withhold his identity. The uniform has had a wholesome effect in law enforce - ment work. Sportsmen and citizens generally feel they are better protected by the uniformed officer and more respect is secured. Transportation. All District Wardens are furnished automobiles purchased by the Commission jand in no case are Wardens paid mileage. Experience has |shown that it is better for the state to own the vehicles than to pay mileage, owing to the fact that it is dif - ficult to check the latter. Small automobiles are used and traded in at the end of each year, thus making the depreciation cost per man very smallJ Cars are operated on the average for, from 2 to 4c per mile, including depreciation. i Field Diaries. All District Wardens are now required to carry field diaries which are filled out daily and sent to the office at the end of </seg>
            <seg id="p018">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION each month. This diary calls for a complete report on expenses, personal and transportation expenses, miles travelled, (daily), complaints investigated, licenses inspected, arrests made, devices confiscated and such other .work as the warden is called upon to do. Complaints. Hundreds of complaints are handled each year from all parts of the state. These reports which come into the office are re - ferred immediately to the district warden of the respective dis - trict who makes a personal investigation, reporting back to the office what action was taken, if any. All special permits such as those issued for scientific pur - poses, damage caused by pheasants' and beaver, are likewise investigated by the wardens. 1925 EH— ARREST FOR. VIOLATION OF 1Q26IID—HH^H^ame laws 1927 cm— ■— ■— i 1928 HZ——— 1929 CIOHHHH— ■— 1930 EZZZHH— — I^—H 1931 eia— ■— — ■ YEAR OF 1021* Arreats ; 528 Complaints investigated 600 Articles confiscated 411 Liquidated damages collected $1,881.00 Fines collected Tor school funds S. 329. 50 Fish salvaged by wardens 304.989 Permits checked .' 9,300 Special investigations 4 33 YEAR l»30 Arrests .• 635 Complaints investigated : 1,094 Articles confiscated 933 Liquidated damages collected : $2,355.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE OP NEBRASKA Fines collected for school funds : : 10,800.00 Pish salvaged by wardens 400,000 Permits checked 10,400 Special investigations 619 YEAR 1OS1 Arrests 531 Complaints investigated 800 Articles confiscated 390 Liquidated damages collected $ 965.33 Fines collected for school funds 6.533.25 Fish salvaged by wardens 423,800 Permits checked 7,600 Special investigations 289 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION STATE PARKS Arbor Lodge State Park . . Frank Williams, Superintendent Chadron State Park ... James W. Good, Superintendent Victoria Springs State Park . C. O. Williams, Superintendent Stolley State Park . . . . F. W. Blaise, Superintendent Under the present state laws, the five state parks are under the administration of the Game, Forestation and Parks Commis - sion. Until 1929, parks were administered by a State Park Board and the necessary funds were drawn from the general state fund through an appropriation each biennium by the state legislature. When the state parks were placed under the Game, Foresta- - tion and Parks Commission in I 929, the law was amended to allow 1 0 % of all receipts from the hunting and fishing licenses, etc., to be used in the maintenance of state parks and since that time these parks have been cared for from such a source and no property tax has been used. 0 STATE PARKS \ ■-- * ,-'■ J,~.\^L^A^,-^4$f\ •RECREATION =» 11- V t m ] -v^Ar-^J- J¥\r " 7r^3\ GROUNDS • r W ..-».•. M ,~\ KXI'KXniTURKS DCRINC) 1»2» Arbor Lodge State Park ■.. «3 495 55 Chadron State Park 2^S7 4n Victoria Springs State Park nfiSlT Stolley State Park 'Z'ZZ'ZZ'.'Z':.'.'.'.". 1,118!44 EXPENDITURES DURIXO 11)30 Arbor Lodge State Park 1 $5 049 93 Chadron State Park ZZZZ 6455 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE OF NEBRASKA Victoria Springs State Park •&gt; 4fi , 7fl Stolloy State Park ZZZZ^ZZZZ^ZZZ IaII.60 EXPENDITURES DURING 1031 Arbor Lodge State Park &gt; R S1ii ... Chadron Stat-? Park illi-i Victoria Springs' State Park I'SqniK Stolley State Park ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ i.illH It will be noted that the Commission did not take over the parks until May of 1929, therefore the expenditures during that year were partially borne by the old State Park Board. Arbor Lodge State Park. Considerable improvement has been carried on at Arbor Lodge State Park, in addition to the regular maintenance thereof. In 1929 the tin work on the mansion and stables was re - paired as well as part of the floors in the mansion being given attention. The drives through the grounds were repaired and new gravel placed where needed. About thirty trees and one hundred shrubs and roses were planted and about eighty indi - vidual specimens were added to the museum, the most of which were placed in the Nebraska City Room. During thp year '929 there were 31,000 visitors. In 1930 the metal roof on the porches of the mansion were repaired, all buildings painted and shutters and screens repaired. The drive through the grounds were repaired and additional gravel spread, as well as a hundred rods of new drives gravelled. A large fish pond was repaired and stocked and a rock garden was built, also having a small fish pond therein. Some forty trees and one hundred and fifty (150) shrubs and roses were planted. Ten picnic tables were added to the grounds, four of which were donated by the Rotary Club of Nebraska City. Some hundred and fifty (150) individual specimens were added to the museum, one hundred and thirty-seven (137) of which were placed in the Title Room. There were 32,000 visitors during the summer of 1930. In the year 1931 all of the uncarpeted floors were varnished, drives through the grounds were repaired and the two main entrances to the park paved. The . brick paving around the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION monument was replaced by cement and a walk was built across the monument square. The Honorable Joy Morton paid the expenses of the im - proving of the monument. New labels were made for all trees in the grounds. The Daughters of the Union Veterans furnished a room in the museum, placing sixty-seven (67) individual specimens of the Civil War therein. Twenty additional specimens were added to the D. A. R. Room nnd about forty specimens to various other rooms. One of the interesting specimens added this year is the original patent to the Arbor Lodge site, issued ' to J. Sterling Morton and signed by President James Buchanan. There were 33,000 visitors at the park during 1931.' Charfron State Park. During the latter part of 1929, five new cabins were con - structed at the Chadron State Park and five other cabins re - paired. All of these cabins were of rustic design, in keeping with the scenic effect of the country and were fitted with cots, stoves and other accommodations for tourists and visitors. This park is very popular for picnics and a large number of these were held in 1929. Other attractions provided for the visitors were horse-back riding and walks through the rugged country thereabouts. A cafe is operated at this park as well as a store where supplies can be purchased. Playground equip - ment for children is maintained. During the summer, some eighty picnics were held as well as twelve concerts, thirty-two church services, six band concerts, eleven Boy Scout meetings, twelve Girl Scout meetings, twenty - four baseball games, with a total estimated attendance of 125.000. During 1930 a swimming pool was provided, part of the cost being donated by citizens of western Nebraska. Dressing rooms were constructed and equipped with accommodations for a large number of visitors who desired to swim. In addition to the swimming pool a trout nursery was built in the park and some 1 5,000 fish were raised therein. During the summer of </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE OF NEBRASKA this year there were some sixty-eight picnics, twelve band con - certs, twenty-two ball games, thirty-seven church services held Some 14,000 visitors used the swimming pool and the attend - ance was estimated to be around 123,000. During 1931, five new cabins were constructed in the park, as well as a number of minor improvements made. A contract was made for electric light at the park and electric lights fur - nished visitors without charge. During this year some seventy-six picnics were held, eight band concerts, eighteen ball games, forty-two church services and other events, with some 12,000 persons using the swimming pool. The attendance during 1931 is the largest at the park in its history, there being approximately 128,000 visitors. Victoria Springs State Park. In the summer of 1929, Victoria Springs Park experienced a very disastrous flood and much of the grounds were damaged. Practically the entire latter part of the year was given over to cleaning up and repairing of the park. A foot bridge leading from the picnic grounds across the creek was constructed and other minor repairs were made. During 1930, the grounds at this park were greatly im - proved. A lake was built of some fifteen acres, the creek was straightened, two dams were built and considerable dirt filling was put in. In the summer of 1930 the highway past the park was gravelled and the Commission gravelled the road connecting with the highway running into the park. Additional camp equip - ment was installed as well as other minor repairs having been made. . During 1931, a thousand yards of dirt was used for filling in the south end of the picnic grounds; the two springs were repaired and raised and put in better shape; a bath-house was constructed on the bank of the lake and equipped with suits, etc., for the accommodation of the public. A small electric light plant was installed as well as a water pump for taking care of shrubbery and trees and minor repairs were made. Five hun - dred pines were added to the pine grove, several thousand bass </seg>
            <seg id="p024">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION were raised in the lake which were distributed in nearby lakes and ponds. AH buildings were painted and improvement gen - erally carried out. This park is now in much better shape than ever before. Stolley State Park. Considerable improvement has been made at this park dur - ing the three years that the Commission has had charge. The gardens were enlarged until they now cover some two acres. Buildings have been painted and repaired, as well as roads and drives being gravelled and covered with cinders. Picnic grounds have been enlarged through clearing of under-growth in the east end of the park and a nice assortment of playground equip - ment has been installed. Two large chemical toilets were built. The superintendent was furnished a light truck in order to service the park. A small tractor for cultivating and mowing lawns was furnished, as well as other minor equipment. This park is used extensively for picnics and the flower gardens are attracting considerable attention. Playground equipment has proven especially attractive. Present Status of Parks. The Commission instituted a "Pay-As-You-Go" program for each of the state parks, placing them on separate budgets and requiring superintendents to adhere strictly thereto. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE OF NEBRASKA RECREATION GROUNDS IN order to provide the citizens of Nebraska with suitable places where fishing, hunting and camping can be had free of charge, the Commission during the past three years has con - tinued a policy began in 1926 of establishing a state-wide sys - tem of recreation grounds. These recreation grounds are not state parks, but are meant to supplement the four state parks, as well as to provide fishing and hunting for the thousands of Nebraska citizens who desire such outdoor recreation. a STATE OWNED !=i F 3 I"™" |—"|--- "F^" "*" 1"" ~" " " " ™. U .. | \ PROPERTIES UNDER " r 1 s~ sto: I, S CONTROL OF COMMISSION =• 1 -»- - « p™ J ' """ "" B P" pB \ Practically all of the recreation grounds purchased and im - proved have contained some water, the Commission desiring to get at least 50% water where possible. In locating these recre - ation grounds, the Commission has tried to get them placed over the state so one or more of them would be within a short drive of any citizen, regardless of where he lived. In order to carry out this state-wide plan of establishing these grounds, it has been necessary in some cases to purchase natural lakes, while in other cases it has been necessary to secure aban - doned sand pits or to construct artificial lakes. During the past three years, the Commission has added the following recreation grounds to the four projects purchased </seg>
            <seg id="p026">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION previous to that time and the twelve meandered lakes which were placed under the Commission's jurisdiction by the Legislature. 1925 imizO— PURCHACE AND IMPROVEMENT 1926— h'^4-57 RECREATION 1927 ■■■1*13,762.76 1929 ■ * 3.34OJ9 1930 IIIIiOIiHHHHBHHBH Louisville Sand Pit Recreation Grounds. Some hundred and ninety acres of sand pit lakes were pur - chased in Cass County, adjacent, to Louisville for $9,398.50. There are some eight lakes located at this place, all of which contain deep water and are suitable for fishing. Since the pur - chase of these grounds, roads have been built through them, camping equipment provided and most all of the pits have been heavily stocked with fish. Long Lake Recreation Grounds. A tract containing 80 acres, bordering on Long Lake in Brown County was purchased by the Commission for $2,000.00. This purchase was later fenced, trees planted and other minor improvements made. Merriman Lake Recreation Grounds. A lake containing over 1 00 acres was purchased near Merri - man in Cherry County for $2,800.00, there being a total of 1 60 acres in the tract. This project has been fenced, a road built into it, spillway improved, trees planted and other minor im - provements made. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE OF NEBRASKA Cotton Mill Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased a lake known as Cotton Mill Lake, located near Kearney in Buffalo County, there being ap - proximately 100 acres, for the sum of $4,000.00. Since the pur - chase, this tract has been fenced, auto gates constructed, a dam and spillway installed, trees planted, etc. Rowell Lake Recreation Grounds. A quarter section of land containing a small lake of about 1 0 acres was purchased in Antelope County for the sum of $1,200.00. A large planting of trees was made here, a windmill erected and other minor improvements made. Blue River Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased I 5 acres located on one of the larger dams on the' Blue River for the sum of $2,025.00. The purchase of this project was to make use of the dam and to give fishermen a means of getting to the Blue River. This tract has been fenced, cleared and opened up for public use. Oxford Lake Recreation Grounds. A tract containing 30 acres, of which approximately one - half is ■water, was purchased near Oxford in Furnas County for the sum of $1,236.00. This has been fenced and a dam con - structed in the way of improvements. Memphis Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 1 4 7 acres, of which approxi - mately 100 acres is water, located adjacent to Memphis in Saunders County, for the sum of $15,000.00. This project was originally used for harvesting ice. Large substantial dikes and dams, together with water rights were secured with the land by the Commission. This project has been cleared, seeded, trees planted and heavily stocked with fish. Pressey Recreation Grounds. The Commission accepted a gift of 80 acres from the Hon. H. E. Pressey of Oconto, Nebraska, located in Custer County. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION The South Loup River flows through this tract and it is well timbered. A small nursery has been constructed here, together with other minor improvements. Pibel Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased the. Pibel Lake Resort located in Wheeler County near Spalding for the sum of $6,500.00. This tract contains 65 acres, most of which is water. An arti - ficial lake, dam, spillway and hotel building came with the prop - erty. The building has been improved, the dam widened, the spillway enlarged and other minor improvements made. Willow Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased a tract of 480 acres in Cherry County for the sum of $4,000.00. This tract is partially under water and Willow Lake is considered an excellent sand-hill fish - ing lake. Litchneld Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 20 acres located near Litch field in Sherman County for the sum of $1,500.00. Minor improve - ments have been made, but owing to the shortage of water, it has not been possible as yet to develop it to its full extent. Champion Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased a small tract containing 1 2 acres for the sum of $1,200.00 located on Champion Lake near Champion in Chase County, Nebraska. This is an excellent fishing lake and its purchase was made in order to permit the public to have access to the lake. Loup City Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 50 acres adjacent to the Middle Loup River, located near Loup City in Sherman County, Ne - braska for the sum of $5,000.00. All of this tract was well timbered and rights for taking water from the Loup River, to - gether with the necessary channel for leading the water through the tract, were secured. Since the purchase a lake has been con - structed and stocked with fish. Other minor . repairs and im - provements have been made. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE OF NEBRASKA Wellfleet Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 45 acres for the sum of $594.00 and accepted a gift of a school lease on an additional 1 60 acres, located adjacent to Wellfleet in Lincoln Cotunty, Nebraska. Since the purchase a dam costing $6,000.00 has been con - structed and Medicine Creek, which flows through the hold - ings has been dammed, now giving the public an 80 acre lake. Alexandria Lake Recreation Grounds. A tract of 40 acres, located near Alexandria in Jefferson County, Nebraska, was purchased by the Commission for the sum of $3,000.00. Since the purchase of this tract, three ter - raced lakes have been built and stocked with fish. The project has been fenced and other minor improvements made. Arnold Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased a tract of 40 acres, located near Arnold in Custer County, for the sum of $4,000.00. It is ex - pected to construct a lake of about 20 acres, on this site, but such construction has not as yet been completed. Frye Lake Recreation Grounds. Frye Lake, located near Hyannis in Grant County and containing 345 acres was purchased by the Commission for the sum of $7,245.00. This is an excellent fishing lake and at the time of purchase was well stocked with fish. Union Pacific Lake Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 1461/2 acres of abandoned sand pits located near Fremont in Dodge County for the sum of $7,325.00. There is over 100 acres of water on this tract, one of the pits being over one-half mile long and the largest in the state. No development work as yet has been undertaken at this place. Ravenna Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 80 acres located near Ravenna in Buffalo County for the sum of $5,000.00. This tract is </seg>
            <seg id="p030">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION adjacent to the Loup River and will contain a lake of about 50 acres when completed. No development as yet has been under - taken on this project. Ballard's Marsh Hunting Grounds. The Commission purchased 1583 acres known as Ballard's Marsh in Cherry County for the sum of $15,830. This Marsh is one of the best feeding grounds for migratory waterfowl in northern Nebraska-. The same has been opened by the Commis - sion for public hunting. Richardson County Recreation Grounds. The Commission purchased 55 acres located near Verdon in Richardson County, Nebraska, for the sum of $5,500.00. A lake containing approximately 30 acres is now under con - struction. . </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATE OF NEBRASKA FORESTATION Forester, Chas. Boyd, Ainsworth. '-pHE state law makes it the duty of the Game Commission to -L study forestation conditions and methods of development throughout the state; collect information and data pertaining thereto; co-operate with and assist all citizens, organizations and communities within the state in forestation work; disseminate forestation information through reports, recommendations and such publicity methods as the commission may deem expedient. With this in view, the Commission has co-operated with the Federal Forestry officials and other organizations and com - mittees in the state that are interested in forestation. Each spring the federal forests in Nebraska distribute thous - ands of trees and the Commission has aided in this work where - ever possible. Information, is carried from time to time in the Commission's publication "Outdoor Nebraska" which will be of value to those citizens who desire to make plantings and en - gage in forestation work on their property. Trees Planted Around Lakes. In addition to educational work, the Commission has planted a number of trees around the northern Nebraska lakes and on property owned by the state. A forester has been engaged to look after such plantings as it has been found that initial plant - ing of trees is the small part of the work and that the proper care of same is very important. Merriman Recreation Grounds. At the Merriman Lake Recreation Grounds (Cherry County) about 500 trees were planted in 1930. Here it was necessary to haul in black dirt as the soil was extremely sandy and although the two seasons have been somewhat unfavorable, the trees have done well. Long Lake Recreation Grounds. At Long Lake Recreation Grounds (Brown County), a small planting of trees was made in 1930 and the same have made a </seg>
            <seg id="p032">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION good growth. Quite a number of willow were planted along the lake shore of this lake in order to attract food for fish as well as to provide shade. Also cottonwood, Chinese elm and honey - locust have been planted, as well as some pine. Rat and Beaver Lakes Recreation Grounds. In 1929 at Rat and Beaver Lakes (Cherry County) a large number of pine were planted and some of them have done ex - ceedingly well standing from three to five feet in height. Willows were planted along the lake shore for a half mile and other good forest trees placed along the foot-hills. These lakes are very popular for fishing and the Commission is anxious to get suitable shade for the many visitors there.. Goose Lake Recreation Grounds. At Goose Lake (Holt County) a large number of willow and cottonwood have been planted. In the spring of 1931 a large number of transplants "cottonwoods" which were found growing along the lake front were planted up on higher ground along the foothills and it is hoped to enlarge a nice tree clearing which is all ready thriving at this place. Rowell Lake Recreation Grounds. At Rowell Lake (Antelope County) through the co-oper - ation of local citizens, a large planting of trees was made in the spring of 1930, there being about ten acres planted at this time. Other trees were planted around the lake in 1931. Both plantings have been damaged more or less by dry weather con - ditions, but it is hoped a considerable number of these plantings can be saved. Memphis Lake Recreation Grounds. At Memphis Lake Recreation Grounds (Saunders County) a tract of about 40 acres is being planted. The work was begun in the spring of 1930 and arrangements have been made for another large planting in the spring of 1932. There are a few trees now and it is the hope of the Commission to have a fine picnic ground available for the thousands of citizens who un - doubtedly will make use of these grounds for recreational purposes. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE OF NEBRASKA Other Plantings. Other plantings of trees have been made at the Gretna, Valentine and Dundy County Fish Hatcheries, at the Fremont Recreation Grounds (Dodge County) and work has been begun at the Alexandria Lake Recreation Grounds (Jefferson County), and the Wellfleet Recreation Grounds (Lincoln County). At the state parka, plantings have been made at Arbor Lodge and Victoria Springs. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION GAME RESERVES Big Game Reserve. IN 1 929 the Commission purchased holdings in the Wild Cat Hills in Scotts Bluff County as well as taking over a lease on state school land, which has been made into a big game reserve. The following year part of this was fenced and the same has since been stocked with buffalo, elk, antelope, deer and game birds. It is the intention of the Commission to make this reserve a show place for Nebraska citizens so that the children of to - morrow may be able to see large animals native to Nebraska. The reserve is located in a very picturesque section of' the State and already thousands of people are visiting same each year. "■ "' " • ° ■ T 5851 ?!! •*• 1 ** l^&amp;i GAME PRESERVES _. L "J* I |^ [ J. M 7^°L. |"^^~L_XlJgk • STATE OWNED &gt;TV .. +==^ — ■■ \— - ~".JW 1 f^TaS Other Reserves. The Commission has leased a large number of reserves and stocked the same with game birds in a state-wide program to conserve some of our native game birds as well as to establish new species brought into the State. Reserves leased and stocked during the past three years are as follows: Number County Whore located ■ Acreage 22 Sherman 1,040 23 Saunders 1,400 24 Holt 3,920 25 Sheridan and Dawes 20,360 26 Rock 1,500 27 Brown .: 1,800 28 Douglas 3,813 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE OF NEBRASKA 29 Hamilton and Merrick 1,000 30 Dodge ; 640 31 Sheridan and Cherry 10,000 32 Lincoln ■ 2,800 With twenty-one reserves previously established this makes a total -of thirty-two now being used for the propagation of game birds. Federal Reserves. The Commission has cooperated with the Federal Govern - ment in the' establishing of a migratory game, bird reserve in Garden County, Nebraska. This reserve ultimately contains forty thousand acres of which much of it will be splendid feed - ing and resting grounds for migratory waterfowl in their migra - tions. The Commission feels that this reserve will be a great asset to the State in helping to conserve the migratory waterfowl as well as being an attraction to the citizens of the State who are interested in bird life. The reserve also contains a number of lakes suitable for fishing, which the Commission is stocking which ultimately will be available to Nebraska citizens. GAME BIRD PROPAGATION AND DISTRIBUTION As more and more of the state of Nebraska has been de - veloped, less and! less nesting grounds for the native game birds of Nebraska have been available and for this reason very im - portant changes in conditions have prevailed. • D •• I raa EQUAIL L — . _ I i I ) *°--WU~ s= =r- ° ["" j\ • H PARTRIDGE '"" * n J "" t" '• "V V WILD TURKEY __J — — pfj^- U-- 1 -' =^ r 33 ! 53^^ </seg>
            <seg id="p036">GAME. FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION Bob White Quail, at one time very numerous in Nebraska, have become so few that it has been necessary to protect them by closed seasons for a number of years. The Prairie Chicken and Grouse, once abundant in northern and western Nebraska, likewise became so few that it "was neces - sary to close the season in 1 929. Protection and feeding grounds for the migratory waterfowl have also become necessary, owing to the shortage of suitable areas where they can breed and rest in their annual flight. Realizing that it will be impossible to retain the Bob White, Prairie Chicken and Grouse in sufficient numbers to furnish hunting to any appreciable number of citizens, game authorities have found it necessary to bring in other birds to replace the native stock. The Chinese Ring-Neck Pheasant. Some fifteen years ago, the Chinese Ring-Neck Pheasant was brought into Nebraska and since that time has thrived until 1929 when it was possible to have an open season in some counties. Since then an annual open season has been held in more and more counties. The Commission has given considerable study to the pheas - ant and is using every possible means to protect them and propagate them in all of the counties in the state where it is deemed advisable. The Commission has likewise given con - siderable study to those areas in the central part of the state ■where these birds breed rapidly. It is realized that it is possible to have too many ol these birds in a concentrated area where they cause some inconven - ience and damage to farmers living therein. With that in mind, open seasons have been fixed and permits granted with the view in mind of not only protecting the birds where they are few, but also to protect the interests of the farmer who owns fields that are used by these birds for breeding grounds. It is estimated that there are several million pheasants in Nebraska today and the food value alone of the annual kill </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE OF NEBRASKA amounts to thousands of dollars. Where the pheasant is properly regulated, it has been found to be a valuable acquisition to an agricultural state, a3 well as an excellent game bird for the sportsman. Hungarian Partridge. In order to secure a bird to replace the Bob White Quail, which probably will never be found in Nebraska in large num - bers again, owii^g to the lack of suitable cover, the Commission has introduced the Hungarian Partridge which has been imported from central Europe. These birds are hardy and excellent game birds and they consume a large number of insects. They are very popular with sportsmen where it has been possible to have an open season. The Commission made a very large purchase of these birds in 1930, stocking them on game reserves throughout the state in the hope that coverage will be started and that the proper en - vironment for such birds will be found. WUd Turkey. Some experimental work with the wild turkey, which at one time was found in Nebraska in considerable numbers, has been carried on by the Commission during the past several years. Owing to the fact that it is extremely difficult to obtain wild birds for stocking, the work has been rather slow and it is still Bit ■ -too GAME BIRDS STOCKED 1927 HBn m 1923 I^^HoOO 1930 EmUHHi^BMHI 1931184- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">GAME, PORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION too early to tell for certain whether or not this bird could be re - habilitated in certain favorable areas of eastern Nebraska. Game Birds Stocked By Commission. (1929, 1930 and 1931) County Hungarian Partridges Quail Turkey Pair Pair Pair Box Butte .... 15 Brown 69 Buffalo 54 15 Butler 10 Cherry : 79 30 20 Custer 54 Colfax ; 10 Dawes 142 : . "" 15 Dundy 54 15 Frontier .'. 79 15 Furnas 79 15 Garfield 20 Greeley 6 .... Harlan 1G .... Howard 21 15 Holt 108 30 .... Johnson 9 Knox 89 "" Lancaster 22 20 Madison ; 54 Morrill 10 Merrick : 25 . 15 33 Nuckolls 9 Otoe 25 15 Pierce 54 Rock ,. 80 Sarpy 8 Saunders 103 18* Sheridan Ill . 30 "i'o Sherman 24 15 Scottsbluff 54 15 70 Thayer 68 Thomas 78 Washington 25 15 50 Wheeler 3 Total 1,649 293 253 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">STATE OF NEBRASKA FISH PROPAGATION AND DISTRIBUTION Hatcheries : Gretna Hatchery Judd Weaver. Sup't. Valentine Hatchery . . . Garland Gray, Sup't. Dundy County Hatcheries . . Harry Runion, Sup't. Nursery Department: Nursery Superintendent . . . J. M. Merritt, Valentine Private Fish Culture: . G. H. Nichols, Norfolk. Fish Car Operator: Robert Fosberg, Louisville. ' Hatcheries. The Game Commission operates four state fish hatcheries. The oldest is located in Cass County on the Platte River, eight miles south of Gretna; another is located one and one-half miles from Valentine in Cherry County; another at Benkelman in Dundy County and another near Parks in Dundy County. A sub-station operating under the Valentine State Fisheries located some ten miles south of Valentine in Cherry County is also, operated. ■ The four larger fish hatcheries are now used as propagation and hatching stations. Some ponds at the several hatcheries are used for rearing fish, but the hatch houses and other ponds are used primarily for hatching and the holding of small fish prior to being placed in nursery ponds. Gretna Fish Hatchery. The Gretna Fish Hatchery is the oldest in the state and part of its value is for recreational purposes, there being excellent </seg>
            <seg id="p040">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION picnic grounds located there where thousands of visitors come each year. During the year of 1929, considerable improvement was made at this hatchery. Old concrete walls around some of the brood ponds were placed, all buildings were repaired and paint - ed, new flower beds were made and minor improvements under - taken on the picnic grounds such as furnishing additional tables, etc. During the year 1930 a new brood pond was constructed about three quarters of an acre in size. It was necessary to do some excavating work and new concrete walls were constructed around this pond. A 1 0 horse-power engine was installed, pumping the water supply from the Platte River, the supply from the springs being inadequate for taking care of any addi - tional ponds. During this year some repairs were made on the concrete walls around the brood ponds and 50 feet of paving replacing a part of the main road through the grounds was laid. Concrete steps leading up to the picnic grounds from the hatch house were also constructed. A water hydrant and 60 feet of new pipe were laid. The pump house was remodeled and all buildings painted and repaired. A number of young trees and some shrubbery were planted on the grounds. During the year of 1931, several new concrete walls were installed around brood ponds and several old walls repaired. A new strip of paving was laid on the main road to the grounds and some re-surfacing with gravel undertaken on the road. The residence buildings and minor buildings were painted and re - paired. New tables were constructed for use in the picnic grounds and several outdoor stoves installed. New batteries were pur - chased this year to replace the old ones for the light plant. The personnel at the Gretna Fish Hatchery handles some 100.000 cat fish each year which the conservation crew traps from the Platte and Missouri Rivers. The Superintendent of this institution is also charged with the responsibility of caring for the Memphis Recreation Grounds. During the past several years some experimental work has been carried on at this hatchery, </seg>
            <seg id="p041">STATE OF NEBRASKA such as fertilizing brood ponds and an experiment was made with the Hessen Fish Trap which is used for trapping young bass. The Valentine Hatchery During 1929, five brood ponds were rebuilt, same having been destroyed previously by a flood. Six new ponds were also constructed as well as. five small holding ponds. A new garage was constructed and the main reservoir dam raised three feet. The front part of the hatchery grounds was fenced and all build - ings painted inside and outside. During the year 1930, three more ponds were built and a number of the old ponds cleared of stumps, debris etc. During this year four small ponds for holding trout were constructed on the state experimental farm, located nearby. Development on a sub-station was begun twelve miles south of Valentine where twelve new ponds were built. During the course of the year, the personnel of this hatchery built concrete spillways on Moon Lake, Willow Lake, Dewey Lake and Trout Lake. During 1931 two brood ponds were remodeled, a new barn was constructed and the sub-station completely finished. Three old buildings at the sub-station were torn down. During the summer it was necessary to lower 300 feet of the main spring line. Other work taken care of this year by the personnel of this hatchery included the building of a small trout pond on Schlegel Creek, the remodeling of a trout pond at Johnstown. The building of wings on the spillways of Willow, Dewey and Trout Lakes. Some conservation work was also done in removing fish from several nearby lakes. Dundy County Hatcheries In 1 929, four new ponds were built at the Rock Creek plant. A bridge was constructed across the creek leading to the hatch - ing ponds and several retaining walls built on the ponds. Three concrete spillways were constructed and some sewer pipe laid. A total of over 4t000 square yards of riprapping was laid on three of the ponds. The residence at this hatchery was repair- </seg>
            <seg id="p042">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION ed, a bath-room being built and installed with bath fixtures and other minor repairs being made. During the year of 1930, a modern fish hatchery was con - structed at this hatchery at the cost of $6,000.00. This is one of the most modern hatching houses in the country and has a capacity for hatching one and one-half million eggs. A hot water system was installed in this building and all other buildings painted. Three retaining walls were built on ponds and the old hatch house made into a residence for one of the workmen. During 1931, 400 feet of tile was laid at the hatching house, several retaining walls were constructed, paving placed in front of the hatching house, a well was dug and a wind-mill erected and other minor improvements made. At the Benkelman Hatchery located in Dundy County, one of the dams was refaced in 1929. All buildings painted, well sunk and a windmill erected. Some hundred trees were plant - ed and some pens for wild turkeys with the proper inclosures were also constructed. During 1930 two of the dams were refaced and a retaining wall built on the east side of the residence lawn. Some 50 trees were planted during this year. During 1931 the hatching house at this hatchery was re - modeled and five aquariums were placed therein for permanent exhibition. Holding and Distributing Plants In 1929, the Commission authorized the construction of what is known as a holding and distributing plant. This was built at the State Fair Grounds on the state property which was donated for such use by the State Board of Agriculture. A modern fish plant was constructed for some $20,000.00. This plant con - tains tanks for the holding of several carloads of fish, together with trackage and unloading platforms for the fish car, store - rooms for seines and other equipment, an office and rooms for employee's quarters. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">STATE OF NEBRASKA Hundreds of thousands of fish are handled each year through this plant and its use greatly expedites the work of the Commis - sion, i Holding Pond . Each year the Commission moves hundreds of thousands of bullheads from over-stocked sand hill lakes, to southeastern Ne - braska and in order to carry on this work efficiently and at the the least possible expense, a series of holding ponds were con - structed in 1931, four miles east of Havelock in Lancaster County, Nebraska. Here the bullheads brought down from the sand-hill lakes are now held and fed, same being trucked out to ponds, lakes, rivers, etc., as needed. Fish Car and Fish Trucks In order to cut down the expense of transporting fish, the Commission authorized the building of five trucks, especially designed for the handling of fish. This fleet was put into opera - tion, relieving the railway fish car from making individual de - liveries. By using the fish trucks, the Commission was able to handle a much larger number of fish at much less expense, prac - tically all deliveries of fish to lakes, ponds, etc., now being made by these trucks whereas the railway car is used for express work or other long distance hauls. ' Nurseries Modern fish culture requires the use of nurseries located near lakes and ponds to be stocked. Baby fish hatched in hatcheries are placed in these nurseries and when partially grown released into natural water. - By the use of these nurseries, a much larger percentage of fish reach maturity and the cost of transporting them is greatly reduced. During the past three years the Commission has added the following nurseries to some four or five all ready in existence: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">■ GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION County Whore Located Near Town of Kind of Pish Blown County Johnstown Trout Brown County Long Pine Trout ' Cherry County Trout Lake Bass Cnerry County Pelican Lake Bass Cherry County Schlegel Creek •. Trout Clierry County Snake River Trout Cherry County Dewey Lake Bass Cherry County Boardman Lake Trout Cherry County Niobrara River Trout Sheridan County Rushville Trout Sheridan County Rushville Trout Sheridan County Rushville Trout Sheridan County Gordon Trout Dawes County Chadron Trout Dawes County State Park Trout Dawes County Marsland Trout Saunders County Memphis Crappie and Sunfish Custer County Victoria Springs Bass Antelope County Royal Bass Antelope County Royal Trout Holt County Steel Creek Trout Holt County Steel Creek Trout Holt County Verdigre Creek :. Trout Contract Nurseries During the year of 1930, the Commission undertook an experiment with fish culture. A contract man was engaged whose duty it was to promote the building of private ponds, such fish raised therein to be sold to the state. During 1930 and 1931 some twenty contract ponds were built by individuals who were interested and during the fall of each of these years, some 50,000 bass were-secured by the state. In addition to the bass purchased from the contract ponds, the Commission made extensive purchases of bass from private fish hatcheries now operating in Nebraska. Prices paid for such . fiingerling bass raised were $30.00 and $50.00 per thousand. Such purchases were used to augment the supply raised at the hatcheries and nurseries owned by the state. Fish Distribution The following report covers the distribution of all fish during the past three years: . </seg>
            <seg id="p045">STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ I 102!) UJ30 l»;jl Ailiuns County — Bullheads i onn ? eax 01 «™ gSSi 8 "" :::::::::::::::: 2000 "« suS I:::::::::::::;::::: 2 -ggg 6 °« wiii ie^ 0111 !::: :::::::::::: «■«« == pike ;z;z;z 2 4i Crapple ...; ;.. \ ZZZ". 64 ZZZ 5.500 12,343 32,000 Antelope County — ?S^:eeeeeee; ?: E -- --s |^ a^EEE:EE:E 2 i; 2 4 5 °s ■ 1 Blo , sss &gt;8o ° Blue Gills orn ••• Catfish : - : :::■""::■- !!! :::::::::::: -gsb - 41,990 48,713 100,890 Artliur County — Bul^eads ! 14 ' 00 ° crappie ;;;;;; y^jjjj l72 : 00 &lt;&gt; 24,000 182,000 Hex ii ie County — £ r&lt; * D P ie 12,000 500 5 000 £S» h r\ -^jiji *:?SS per": 11 ....::::::::::::::::::;;;:;;;;;;; 1 - 500 2 i° 0 ° 0 '"™™ Black Bass 1,000 !6.200 4.500 12,500 Box liutte County — c« as l.::::: : «•;•• sunnsh ::::;::::::::;:::::::; ;;;;::;;;;;; 2:000 ::::::::;;;; 5,150 7,500 Boyd County — Black Bass _ 7i550 160 30 Rock Bass 300 catnsh ;;;;;;;; l- 0 - 0 - Trout :::::::::::: To 7,850 160 780 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION _ 1»29 1030 103J Brown County — ass u . 28,100 44,600 40,000 * erc J}. : 50 . 1,000 ° u 5 fls . h 500 3,408 22,000 Tadpoles 5 000 Crappie . TiT-Tn j5 uni j eads - ::::::::::: -"Tbo llillo if 0 " 1 , ■ 20,000 46,000 34,560 Pickerel 132 48,782 100,258 154,530 Buffulo County — g a " ish . 37,000 1,735 4,000 Bullheads , U6 32,350 23,500 Crappie »49 3,000 1,000 £ ass 4,068 4,490 Pike 16,345 . Perch 18,050 Sunfish 7,000 1,205 Blue Gill 770 Bullfrogs ; :;;;;:;:;;;; sbo 85,198 42,840 29,000 Uurt County — Bullheads , 3&gt;000 1S0Q ? ass -r 10,900 * ercl \ : - 300 Crappie . 2 ,000 16,200 1,800 Butler County Bas s 2,200 . 2,756 Bullheads 2 204 T.'zTo Perch 804 Catfish 37900 701 ra P pl , e " 210 1,500 Sunfish .... ■ a: pike I:::::::::::::::::;:;:;::; ;;:;;;;;;;;; U ;;:;;;■■;■;; . 6,100 6,788 3,750 Cjiss County — C/aPP'e 50,255 3,500 6,000 Bullheads 16,325 51,800 17,850 u ?" s . h 18.650 14,000 Catfish 8,554 3, 800 Blue Gill , 2,450 23,000 • 29,000 f as f ■■ 10,531 20,688 40,775 I Rock Bass 200 2,250 Perch 2,500 Bull Frogs „ ■... ;.; 8,000 3,000 Z...ZZ \ P} k , e , ; 200,000 50,000 Pickerel 48 \ 117,513 308,038 157,625 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1»21) 1930 1»;$1 Chase County — I™"} , ' 4,200 850 3.600 Sunfish 8 g50 ? ass , ■ ■■--•- 14,300 i'i'Xcii 4^00 Perch 1,100 650 Grapple 650 cattish - "T'doo 19, GOO 16,250 17,450 Cherry County — Bass "-- 66,850 93,914 189,901 GraPPfe 9,104 13,370 50,350 £ erc , h , 9,250 13.G25 14,350 | Un " Sh . 3.2S0 11,475 43,675 Bullheads 24,020 9,700 362,525 Blue Gill ;... 2,995 I/ 01 ' 1 _ "ieTooo "bV"66p Rock Bass 1,000 5 700 Bull Frogs 32,500 71,300 'lO.'oOO Pickerel go Catfish 400 "4S34 Minnows £;„„„ .14.9,459 238,084 738,185 Cheyenne County — £ rout 2,650 7,800 5,200 uass 1,200 1,500 2,650 9,000 6,700 Clay County — Bullheads 55f700 277, noo Catf ' 8h ■ 1,000 1,060 700 Sunfish ; 6 300 Perch 1500 Bass 3,300 2,069 761 Cra PPie 2,000 700 6,300 67,329 278,461 Colfnx County — Bullheads 11,925 400 Sunfish 1 1,000 400 Blue Gills ]„.„■ 2,985 Catfish ; ' 8 90 700 Crappie i : 950 400 P erch ■••■ ■ I.: "li"o6'6 Bass 1,000 2,400 18,750 4,300 13,000 CmniiiK County — Bullheads l, 1O o 3,200 11,500 Cat » sh : 1,000 5,500 Sunfish 120 369 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION I»2!) 1030 1031 Perch ; 4,000 Pickerel 160 Bass 1,559 962 '""..".'". Bullfrogs 1,000 5,000 3,779 9,691 22,200 Custer Count y — Bullheads 4,000 15,055 Sunfish 369 2,600 B as« - 113 ' 770 Catfish li700 Crappie 100 4,600 Trout 2,280 Frogs 150 500 150 5,082 ' 27.005 Dakota County — Bullheads : 12,350 25,000 100,000 Crappie 2,230 " Bass ... 6,015 6,200 Blue Gill 900 Pike 33 '.'".".".'.'.'.'. Sunfish 1,000 ".'.'.'.'.'.'".'.'. 22,528 31,200 100,000 Duwrs County — Perch , : 1,100 25,000 27,200 Bass 2,700 17,000 16,972 Trout 14,000 91,400 24,000 Crappie 1,700 3,000 Bullheads 500 1,000 28,000 Catfish 1,500 Gold Fish 12 . Blue Gills 125 Bull Frogs 10,000 20,000 145,912 99,297 DnWHon County — Blue Gill ;.... 1500 Bass 3,000 4,300 4,250 Crappie 1,300 100 Sunfish 1,017 2,350 Bullheads 3,100 Catfish 157 Perch , „"„.".". 100 "...".I". 4,017 11,307 5,850 . j Deuel County — Bass ; 2,000 Crappie ; 3,000 Bullheads 5 O oo Sunfish 2,000 12,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1929 1030 1031 Dodge County — £ ass , -■■ 29,500 46 455 49 673 £™ P k P BasH ; - 20 ° »^»0 MOO itOCK UaSS 4Q r, nnn S&amp;. :::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: ..£".» 8!! j : . S « iKp,,,-:::::-:::::-::::::::::::: ii ...»!! ,&gt;«{ rlKe - 200,000 39,385 450,705 74,173 Douglas County — S™ 6 •- 45,760 7.000 4,000 Catfish L 7&gt;00 ° 55 ' 115 41 - 800 jj£ J QQQ Blue GiU ::::::::::::::::_T4^ ilooo ••s.ooo 87,159 104,615 69,3To Dundy County — : 1 ;, eads 2,000 100 600 Sunfish soo Trout 62,180 """9,030 "."!ZZ 67,480 9,130 47,550 Pillinore County — Bullheads l.ooo 2,500 Perch 2,600 s untis , h •■- ■ "Xsoo Oappie , ' 200 Catfish 1 300 "TBOO 3.600 5,500 1,500 Franklin County—' Catfish j 600 400 Crappie , 200 Trout - - 23,000 10,300 ".'.'.".".ZZ 23,000 10,900 Frontier County — Tro«t 5&gt;8O o Bass - 12,000 17,000 Perch I 1,500 Bullheads 800 * " 14,300 22,800 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">GAME, PORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION 1020 1O3O 1031 Fiirnas County — Bullheads 2,000 3,000 Sunfish 7,000 Bass 8,000 2,200 Perch 12,000 100 Catfish 300 1,000 7,301 Crappie 400 8,300 15,400 19,601 (iafic County — Bullheads 4,160 6,100 7.450 Catfish . 3,600 1,000 8,000 Perch 6,200 5,000 25,000 Blue Gills ; 1,200 Crappie ■. 500 1,100 Bass 2,000 Goldfish 12 17.160 . 12,612 41,550 Garden County — Perch • 40,050 Blue Gill 186 Trout 22,400 20,000 ''.".'.'.".".'.". Bass ; 12,000 46,180 Bullheads ; 4,000 Pike 1,000 22,586 32,000 91,230 Gurfield County — Crappie '. 500 Bass 800 4,700 20 Perch 5,000 Frogs . 100 '."".'".".'.'. Sunfish 150 1,500 !.!!!!!!!!!! Rock Bass 2,000 Bullheads 1,500 "".".'.'..'.".". 6,550 9,700 520 Grunt County — . Bass 000 . 20,000 86,511 Perch 500 92,951 Sunfish 500 38,100 Bullheads 31,700 Catfish ; 5,000 1,600 25,000 249,262 Greelcy County — Bass 1,200 19,600 9,020 Bullheads k . ■ 18,000 Crappie 200 5,000 Perch 1,200 Catfish 500 2,400 20,300 32,020 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">STATE OF NEBRASKA IO2O ■ 1030 1031 Hail County — Crappie 1,860 800 200 Bullheads 3,160 36,000 46,500 Bass 1,458 1,750 Catfish 1,561 800 1,500 Perch 15,600 X. 2,800 Blue Gill 4,260 1,000 Sunfish 4,000 I*..".."." Tadpole 1,500 27,999 44,750 52,500 Hamilton County — Bullheads 1,000 600 8,500 Perch 2,000 Sunfish 1,000 1,000 600 12,500 Hnrlnn County- Bass 15,000 Catfish 200 500 Trout 100 300 15,500 Hitolicook County — . Catfish 7,280 6,250 Bullheads 1,200 17,450 2,050 Perch 2,000 ...-. 200 Sunfish 750 870 1,190 Bass 1,275 2,165 Crappie 920 Blue Gill 800 Trout : ' 800 4,750 28,595 11,855 Holt County — Bullheads ;... 1,300 27,300 61.650 Sunfish 5,250 21,800 14,000 Catfish 3,000 1,800 Bass 10,125 20,990 24,498 Trout 40,000 41,020 173,080 Pickerel : 400 1,842 Perch 6,000 Crappie 3,140 850 7,700 Frogs 13,000 66,215 127,960 284,570 Hooker County — Bass 3,680 Bullheads ; 2,000 Crappie : 3,300 8,980 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION 1O2O 1030 1031 Howard County— -r Bullheads 5,000 3,000 Bass 150 ; Perch 150 Gold Fish 30 Catfish 1,000 "£,666 300 6,030 6,000 J off orson County — Catfish 2,000 560 1,500 Bullheads 1,100 2,500 Perch 7,800 Crappie 200 500 Trout 6,000 20,000 Gold Fish ' 220 . Bass " jo 3,160 6,980 . 32,310 Johnson County — Catfish 500 Bullheads 3,000 3,500 6,800 Perch 500 Bass 6,000 3,000 10;500 6,800 Kearney County — Bullheads 1,000 2,000 Bass 900 900 , 1,000 2,000 Keith County — Perch 1,000 11,000 Bass 1,000 2,000 Crappie 2,000 Sunfish 800 Trout 20,000 ■ ""■]"!"!! 22,800 15,000 Key a Palm County — Perch ...; 300 Bass • 100 245 Sunfish : 100 33 Bullheads 3,000 2,000 5,000 3,000 2,500 5,278 Kimball County — Trout 20,000 3,400 4,250 Crappie ;. 6,000 Bullheads 4,000 Bass 1,000 4^500 Perch 76,000 20,000 80,400 18,750 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1020 10:10 Uiai Knox County — g a «» ■■■ 2.000 4,000 4,000 Bullheads , 7,750 li20 o ....... 9.750 5,200 4,000 I/iincastor County — Bj'llheads 12,430 2S 80() 2G ,800 Blue Gill 75 x 000 2 000 Crappie 300 750 1.200 " ass . 500 75 36 Ca" 1 .^ 2,200 275 Sunfish • 250 14,805 33,375 36,311 Lincoln County — Bullheads 2 400 ,, n Blue Gill &gt;40 ° , "SO Ppie '■■■■■ "Uli I 3 ;il8 p a k 8^ ■ .-•■ 25,244 30,015 cat«sh"::::::::::" : 40 - 0^ 500 - 000 sh ■ 5.094 - T" 4 "86 i ro \ u 6,000 2,400 Rock Bass i; 9 25 79,926 552,863 Ijoup County — Perch 3,000 Bass soo Sunfish 150 Bullheads ; "siooo ~.Z'.'.Z'.~. 3,950 5,000 MimIIkoii County — BulIheads 2O.?5O 51,886 33.300 ? asi ;. , ■ 30,124 30.801 4,016 Sunfish SOO 4,700 a f p , p ' e ■ 4.130 9.000 " "BTd'od Catfish 100 1 non Pickerel lc 1&gt;uo ° Blue Gili ;;;; '2,000 Frogs 650 Goldfish : 10 56,580 98,387 43,316 McIMierson County — Bass 12,566 211 500 Bullheads 3G4,fiO0 450,114 126!oOO Crappio 2,850 23,875 9,000 P en =&gt; 1,500 4,950 Sunfish 550 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">GAME; PORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION 1O2O 1030 1031 Blue Gill 480 382,546 488,939 346,500 Merrick County — • 11,647 20,000 Catfish 5,595 2,234 Pike 207 Gold Fish 30 Crappie 1,950 553 Blue Gill 280 Perch 1,500 ""'"59" """ Bullheads 5,760 10,000 16,000 Sunfish 1,080 105 1,000 Trout -6,000 Pike 360 18 Drum Head ; 3 28,409 38,972 17,000 Merrill County- Trout 49,000 35,950 28,670 Bass 300 16,600 20,981 Perch 3,900 78,312 Bullheads 11,000 53,200 52,550 138,963 Xance County — Perch ;.- 1,000 Bass 2,000 • ... Crappie 1,000. 200 "~Z...... Catfish , 1,000 ; 4,000 1,200 Xeiuuha County — Bass ; 400 Crappie 38,600 Bullheads 31,900 70,900 Xuckolls County — Bullheads . 1,000 Catfish , 200 ..".."..'.'."..'. 200 ' 1,000 Otoe County — Bullheads 1,000 . 1,000 Catfish • 300 Perch 3,000 '.'".'.".'."". Bass ■ 100 '.'."..'....".".. 4,400 1,000 Pawnee County — Bullheads 2,500 400 2,500 400 . </seg>
            <seg id="p055">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1029 1930 1031 Pierce County — BunaX* 1 ■ 3^o° 4l00 ° M0 ° Trout ■.■.■.".";;.;. ""iji'i 3,760 4,000 13,075 Platto County — Bass 1,000 .. . 2 100 catnsi, : 1&gt;120 ._;;;; J -*°° Perch l &gt;UO o Trout ""225 Bullheads T.800 ""i'.000 ;;;;;;;;;;;; ;;;;;;;;;;;; IZ° 7320 225 11,600 -Polk County — Bullheads 100 Crappie ; '.'.'.'.".".'. son ca «i«» - :::::::::::; ij™ 100 1,300 Itcd Willow County — Trout 4U0 400 Ricliurtlson County — Bullheads 4,300 40,000 83,000 Sunflsh 1,500 4,000 37 375 Grapple 2 00 . 306 Catfish 300 Z"Z" Bass 200 100 6,800 44,200 120,775 Itock County — S^s ■ 2,050 1,000 10,042 Tr °ut '- ' 9,500 Su nfish 5,600 1,000 P^h ' 2,000 1,000 Bullheads 100 200 Crappie 600 ."".'"""" 10.350 12,700 10,042 Salino County — Ca«Jsli 6,875 3,550 5,900 Bullheads 13,350 10,500 6 500 Bass 6,000 1,500 P erch , 6,200 12,200 "800 Cra PP le 4,945 4,500 200 37,870 32,250 13,400 Harpy County — ierch •::::::::::::::::::::::;;;:;-:;::::::::: 20 ill .± 8 . 9 . 5 . .!°;!°° </seg>
            <seg id="p056">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION 1020 1030 1031 Bullheads 8,810 9,900 3,050 Crappie 12,577 4,000 1,000 Catfish 33 1,400 15,000 Blue Gill 4,438 5,000 Gold Fish ;-... 750 "'_'; Pickerel 420 '.'.'.".".'.'.'". 47,303 14,035 39,750 Saunders County — Catfish 29 2,600 5,184 Pike 18,000 Bullheads 24,500 4G.300 7 300 Sunfish 58,100 2,500 Crappie 5,800 5,525 4,500 Blue Gill 300 Bass 700 '"Too Perch 1,000 32,329 131,225 19,484 Scotlsbhiff County — Trout 92,900 74,305 59,160 Bass 7.SC5 19,145 12,875 Perch 232,900 238,200 216,500 Bullheads 4 120 Gold Fish - 72 .'".'.". ! 333,237 331,050 292,655 Seward County — Perch 10,200 10,000 22,700 Crappie 500 18,000 Catfish 4,400 500 6 400 Bullheads 3,860 800 15,700 Frogs 500 Sunfish 500 1,000 18,460 12,800 . 63;800 Sheridan County — Bass 17,100 34,500 82,563 Catfish 5 00 . Crappie 2,200 1,500 17,500 Bullheads 13,480 1,150 28,000 Perch 14,120 15,000 Sunfish 1,000 Trout 12,000 siTo'ob *60|000 Fross ! 4,000 32,000 Blue Gill 3S0 50,160 137,270 193,563 Sherman County — Bullheads 500 5,000 11,700 Ba»s 500 Perch 500 "... TeToOO Catfish 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1O2O 1030 1031 Crappie 200 4,000 1.500 5,700 31,700 Sioux County — Sunfish 2,340 Bullheads 480 Bass 6,200 5,753 Trout 2,400 4,435 Crappie ; 500 Frogs 2,000 Gold Fish "i'i Perch '. 225 . !"""!"" 14,145 5,765 4,435 Stanton County- Bullheads , 2,noo 55.000 Bass 395 2,000 2,600 Catfish 2,000 Crappie J 2,!)20 2,500 Sunfish 2,500 5,815 4,000 62,100 Thayer County- Bass G73 20 6,000 Bullheads J 6,000 3,800 1,575 Catfish • J 1,000 500 2,225 Crappie J 3,000 200 500 Perch i 1,200 Sunfish ' ............ l"500 Goldfish 12 11,873 4,532 11,800 Thomas County— Catfish 1,000 Sunfish 40 .....!.!"" Bullheads 2,000 1,040 2,000 Valley County — Bar.s 100 Perch 1,000 Catfish : 800 Bullheads 1,500 1,100 2,300 Washington County- — Pe-Rh 1,800 Bullheads 8,900 27,300 30,000 CraiJDie 500 200 15,000 Sunfish . 15,000 Blue Gill 800 10,200 27,500 61,800 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION 1020 1030 1031 Wayne County— Catfish '. 1,000 1,000 Webster County — Trout 15,000 12,000 3,690 Crappie 1,000 200 510 Bullheads . . 1,000 Catfish l,50t) 400 ".....!"...'. 17,500 13,600 4,200 Wheeler County — Bass 5,000 2,600 Perch 3,000 10,000 Bullheads ....; 7,500 8,000 20,100 York County — Catfish ;.. 1,060 1,500 4 200 Sunfish 100 237 Bullheads 19,500 13,072 "lOOO Trout 125 ........ Perch 1,200 100 Gold Fish , 24 ..". 21,860 15,058 5,200 RECAPITULATION OP PISH STOCKED bounty 1020 1030 1031 Adams 5,500 12,343 32,200 Antelope 41,990 48,763 99 390 Arthur 24,000 182,000 Boone .^. 16,200 4,500 12,500 Box Butte^. 5jl50 7(5O o Boyd 7,850 160 780 Brown 48,782 100,058 154,530 Buff alo 85,198 42,165 29,000 ?,"" 16,200 1,800 Butler 6,100 6,788 3,750 Cass 117,521 308,038 157,625 Chase 19,600 16,250 17,450 Cherry 149,509 234,765 738,185 Cheyenne 2,650 9,000 6,700 C'ay 6,300 67,290 278,700 C°lfax : 18,750 4.300 . 13,000 Cumlng 3,779 9,691- 22,200 CUfter , 150 5,082 27,005 Dakota 22,558 31.200 100 000 Dawes 20,000 145.912 99,297 Dawson 4,017 11,308 5,850 Deuel 12000 P°&lt;iEf 39,385 450,705 74,175 Douglas 87,159 104,815 68,100 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">STATE OF NEBRASKA County . - 1029 1930 1931 Dundy ...J 67,480 9,130 47,550 Fillmore J 3,600 5,500 1 500 Franklin J 23,&lt;5OO 10,900 Frontier j 14,300 22,800 Furnas 8,300 15,400 19,601 Gage I. 17,160 12,112 41,150 Garden 22,786 32,000 91,230 Garfield 6,050 9,700 520 Grant ; 1,600 25,000 249,261 Greeley , 2,400 20,300 32,020 Hall 29,899 45,250 52,500 Hamilton 1,000 . 600 12,500 Harlan KOO 15,500 Hitchcock 4,750 28,140 11,855 Holt 66,015 127,830 284,695 Hooker 8i980 Howard 300 6,030 6,000 Jefferson 3,100 6,420 32,310 Johnson 3,000 10,500 6 800 Kearney 900 1,000 2,000 Keith 22,800 15,000 Keya Paha 3,000 2,500 5 278 Klmball .... 20,000 80,400 18,750 Knox 9,750 5,200 4,000 Lancaster ;.. 14,805 33,375 36,311 Lincoln 79,926 552,863 Loup 3,950 5,000 Madison 56,580 98,387 43,316 McPherson 382,546 488,989 346,500 Merrick j 28,409 38,972 17,000 Morrill I 53,200 52,660 138,963 Nance J 4,000 1,200 Nemaha L ; 70,900 ......'.'." Nuckolls J 200 1,000 ...".". Otoe J 4,400 T.000 Pawnee , 2,500 400 Pierce j 3,760 4,000 13,075 Platte 7,420 225 11,600 Polk — - - 100 1,300 Red Willow 400 Richardson 6,800 44,200 12o"775 Rock 10,350 12,700 10,042 Saline 37,870 32,250 13,400 Sarpy 47,303 14,035 39,750 Saunders j 32,329 124,835 19,484 Scottsbluff 333,237 331,650 292,655 Seward 18,460 12,800 63,800 Sheridan 50,160 137,270 193,563 Sherman 1,500 5,700 31,700 Sioux 14,145 5,765 4,435 Stanton 5,815 4,000 62,100 Thayer 11,873 4,532 11,800 Thomas 1,040 2,000 Valley 1,100 2,300 Washington . _ 10,200 27,500 61,800 Wayne 1,000 Webster 17,500 13,600 4,200 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION &lt; """ lv l»itl» 1»;jo io»l Wheeler , , 8&gt;000 20,100 ork • : 21.S60 15,058 ""i"ioo lf&gt;-) T To a til 2.278.960 4,037,244 5,189.169 1 330 Total •"•'J'om'iSS 1'1'il Total 4,0.}/, 24 4 1-MX 1Olal " - ■ 5.189,169 Grand Total : : 11.505.373 SPKC'IKH OP FISH DISTRIBUTED .. 1»2') IH30 H); n " a i f; S ; nip - ■ 368.320 G06.S0S 1.016.479 p™??' 6 173,190 179.792 312.459 s",, l s1l •,-• 348.275 449.014 650.513 „„,", 62.20? 152, 1S5 228958 1 IKe 16,945 658,278 556,000 ■ ■ ■ - * </seg>
            <seg id="p061">STATE OF NEBRASKA CONSERVATION AND SALVAGE OF FISH Foreman — Lee Hudleson, Blair ; Nature of Activities T^ACH year a considerable amount of conservation and salv- J-^age of fish is carried on in Nebraska. While a large num - ber of fish are hatched and propagated at state fish hatcheries and nurseries, nature likewise hatches thousands of fish in ponds, sloughs, bayous, etc., many of which would never reach ma - turity because of such water drying up in the summer or freez - ing out in the winter. The Commission, therefore, has found it advisable to carry on salvage work as it is cheaper to save the fish which nature hatches than it is to propagate them at the state hatcheries. This work has been greatly enlarged during the past three years and proper equipment furnished in order to carry on the work. Beside the salvage of game fish which are planted in deeper water, the same crew is used for the removal of coarse fish from such water where they are a menace to game fish. These fish consist of mostly Buffalo, Carp and Shad and are marketed where possible and the revenue therefrom placed in the state game fund. 1929 Activities . During 1929, some 270,000 game fish were salvaged and I 70.000 pounds of coarse fish removed from lakes and ponds. Seining activities were carried on at the following lakes and ponds throughout the state: Champion Mill Ponds, Champion Crystal Lake, South Sioux City Columbus Country Club Ponds, Columbus Bartley Lake, Bartley Curtis Lake, Curtis No. 8 Sand Pit, Fremont Veterans Lake, Fremont Schneiders Pond, Cedar Creek Harse Lake, Miller Izaak ; Walton Pond, Meadow Lake Quinnebaugh, Tekamah . Bunn's Lake, Blair </seg>
            <seg id="p062">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION Whitney Lake, Crawford Whitman Lakes, Whitman Crete Mill Pond, Crete Country Club. Lake Ponds, Genoa . Pawnee Park Pond, Columbus Linoma Sand Pits, Ashland Sand Pits, Central City Rice Lake, Mitchell Smith Lake, Broadwater Sullivan's Lake, Meadow Grove Johnson Lake, Stanton MajMajes Lake, Norfolk. Cottonmill Lake, Kearney Lake Kearney, Kearney Wendts Lake, Battle Creek Louisville Pits, Louisville Blue Hole, Kearney Platte River Slough, Grand Island Jackson Eddy, Jackson U. S. Rifle Range, Ashland Wilkins Lake, Blair Wighorn Slough, Ashland Clarks Lake, Bellevue David City Ponds, David City Mansfield Lake, St. Edwards Hoffmans Lake, Melbeta Fair Grounds Lake, Bridgeport Lake Ostenberg, Scottsbluff University Lake, Mitchell Lewis Lake, Mitchell Three Mile Lake, Flats . . Whitewater Lake, Flats Dailey's Lake, McPherson County Ponds on Ed. Dailey's Lake, McPherson County Small Lake 1 mile E. Whitewater L., Flats E. Coyote Lake, Flats Small pond south end of Diamond Bar L., Flats Small pond V4 mi. south of Reed's Lake, Flats Small pond east end Whitewater Lake, Flats Holes east end of Reed's lake. Flats Sand Rock Lake, Falls City Old Bed Nemaha River, Falls City Mulhalls' Pond, Norfolk Rescue Work, Platte River, Columbus to North Platte 1930 Activities During 1930 some 300,000 game fish were rescued and transplanted and 246,574 pounds of coarse fish were removed. The following lakes and ponds were seined: Crystal Lake, South Sioux City Carter Lake,. Omaha Country Club Lake, Columbus Crete Ice Pond, Crete Curtis Lake, Curtis Harse Lake, Miller </seg>
            <seg id="p063">STATE OF NEBRASKA Linoma Beach, Ashland Louisville Sand Pits, Louisville Champion Lake, Champion Kane Lake, Winner Quinnebaugh Lake, Tekamah Lamberts Lake, Neligh Millers Lake, Clearwater Lorenzon Lake, Neligh Kane Lake, Wisner Wendt's Lake, Battle Creek Clark's Lake, Ewing Ice Pond, Clearwater Neise Lake, Neligh Oxford Lake, Oxford Baker's Lake, Tekamah Minatare Lake, Minatare Yellow Banks Lake, Battle Creek Swinbank Lake, Crawford Dr. Emerson's Lake, Seneca Branting's Pit, North Platte George's Lake, Hyannis Platte River — Holes Harse Lake, Miller Horseshoe Lake, Calhoun Bunn's Lake, Blair McKenzie's Lake, Wisner Nemaha Lake, Nemaha American Legion Lake, Primrose Camp Shelton Lake, Columbus . . Scheeger's Lake, Tilden Abbott's Lake, Hyannis Wright's Lake, Hyannis Sear's Lake, Hyannis' George's Lake, Hyannis Hoffman Lake, Melbeta Prye's Lake, Hyannis Box Lake, Flats West Diamond Bar Lake, Plats Stone Lake, Ashland Rapp Lake, Waterloo Gresh Lake, Palls City Gardner Lake, Merriman Bowering Lake, Merriman 1931 Activities During 1931, over a half million game fish were salvaged and transplanted to other water and approximately 300,000 pounds of coarse fish removed. Rivers, ponds and lakes seined during this year were as follows : Moon Lake, Johnstown Linoma Beach, Ashland Rice and University Lakes, Scottsbluff Middaugh Lake, Ames </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION U. P. Sand Pits, Fremont Murphy Lake, Fremont Blue River, Beatrice Heckendorf Lake, Pilger Louisville Sand Pits, Louisville Lake Quinnebaugh, Tekumah Missouri River, Herman Benkelman Club Lake, Benkelman Lake Minatare, Minatare Ostenberg Lake, Scottsbluff Cotton Wood Lake, Kearney Snyder Lake, Ewing Cotton Wood Lake, Atkinson St. Michael Lake, St. Michael Wendt's Lake, Battle Creek Crystal Lake, Tilden Crystal Lake, South Sioux City Rat Lake, Ainsworth Goose Lake, O'Neill Weblemore Sana Pits, Fairbury East Reservoir. Kimball Cheyenne Fur Farm, Sunol Bayard Lake, Bayard McCartey's Lake, Bingham Moran's Lake, Hyannis Ross Hager's Lake, Hyannis John Reverc's Lake, Hyannis George's Lake, Hyannis Soda Lake, Hyannis • Frye's Lake, Hyannis Club House Lake, Hyannis Eagen's Lake, Hyannis Moser's Lake, Lakeside Crescent Lake, Oshkosh Island Lake, Oshkosh Sprague Sand Pits, Sprague Swift Lake, Ashland Republican River — Rescue Work Platte River — Hoop netting West Lake, Pilger Willet Lake, Albion Snyder Lake, Cedar Creek Small Lake near Ravenna Small Lake near St. Michael Dr. Emerson's Lake, Seneca John Slaymaker's Lake, Atkinson Hytrek's Lake, Stuart Kane Lake, Wisner Paul Brockman's Lake, West Point Alexandria Nursery Ponds, Alexandria Meyer Lake, Falls City Sand Rock Lake, Falls City Hoffman Lake, Melbeta Fair Grounds Lake, Bridgeport Blyberg Lake, Homer Arlington Fair Grounds Lake, Arlington Bartley Pit, Loup City State Lake, Litchfleld. Horseshoe Cut-off, Falls City </seg>
            <seg id="p065">STATE OP NEBRASKA EDUCATIONAL WORK T&gt; ELIEVING that education is one of the best means for pro - -L» moting conservation of natural resources as well as instilling respect for conservation laws, the Commission has authorized and devoted some of its funds to this kind of work. During the past three years, considerable information has been given regarding the work the Commission has been doing and the need of conservation has been brought to the public through the work of motion pictures. Suitable reels have been made up showing the various phases of the work, and the wild life of the state and these have been available for schools, organizations and other groups desiring to see them. Some! hundred showings have been made, reaching approximately 251,000 people. Another phase of the Commission's educational work has been the publication of a quarterly magazine known as "Outdoor Nebraska." Each quarter the last three years, this publication has reached a large number of citizens who are interested in the conservation work some seven thousand (7000) copies being published each quarter and distributed without cost to libraries, schools, organizations, and individuals interested. This publication has met with very hearty response on the part of the public and has been widely quoted in other publications and newspapers. During the past two years the Commission has published a folder known as "Outdoors In Nebraska" which has been avail - able to tourists and those persons in this state desiring informa - tion regarding state parks, recreation grounds, lakes and other places of interest. Some 25,000 of these folders have been published each year and distributed generally throughout the state. A goodly number have also been put in the hands of distributing organiza - tions in the view of interesting people of other states in the state of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">GAME, FOREST ATION AND PARKS COMMISSION A small booklet regarding state parks has been published each year and is sold at the Arbor Lodge State Park at 25 cents each, such revenue going to help in the support of that institution. This booklet gives considerable information regarding the state's parks and a large number of copies are sold each year. The game laws are compiled and published in a small book - let each year, some hundred thousand copies being required to meet the annual demand for same. A small folder abstracting the game laws is also published and is available for the public. Other small folders such as "Open Season on Muskrats", "Hunting Hours" etc., are published from time to time in order to familiarize the public generally with the laws and regulations of the Commission. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">STATE OF NEBRASKA SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH I SCIENCE plays a great part in the propagation and conserva - tion of game and fish life today. In the past, entirely too much expensive stocking of both birds and fish has been carried on in a more or less haphazard way, without due consideration to the food supply available or the environment for such birds and animals to be stocked. This resulted in considerable loss. In order to have more scientific data at hand, the Commis - sion in 1930 began some studies along this line. The findings of such investigations as have been carried on have been pub - lished from time to time in order to provide a permanent record, available for use at all times. Investigations of Food Habits of the Pheasant In cooperation with the Agricultural College of the Univer - sity of Nebraska, the Game Commission carried on a study of the food habits of the Ring-Neck Pheasant in certain central counties of Nebraska during 1929 and 1930. Specimens of the pheasant in its native state were captured and the digestive tracts of such birds carefully analyzed and the contents thereof classi - fied by authorities at the Agricultural College. These later were compiled and published under the title of "Food Habits of the Ring-Neck Pheasant in Central Nebraska." The Commission wishes to acknowledge its indebtedness to . Professor M. H. Swenk, Department of Entomology, University of Nebraska and to Mr. Jess Kovanda, Smith-Hughes instructor in Agriculture at the Ord City Schools, who assisted in carrying out this work. Necessary . collections under authority of the Commission were carried on by Mr. Kovanda and the balance of the work was under the direction of Professor Swenk. Report On Investigations in Cherry County Lakes During the year of 1930 and 1931 a water analysis and zoological investigation as well as a study of the distribution of vegetation - 'was made in the more important lakes of Cherry County. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">GAME, FORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION This work was carried on under the direction of the Com - mission by Mr. George W. Bennett and Mr. Harold Pedley, Mr. Bennett conducted the chemical and zoological aspects of the problem, while Mr. Pedley made botanical investigations and ob - servations. This study was subsequently published by the Com - mission under the title "Report On Investigations in the Cherry County Lakes" and was distributed to interested citizens, em - ployees of the department, as well as made a permanent record in the commission's office. Investigation of Hatchery Ponds and Fish Nurseries During the summer of 1931 the Commission carried on a study of the water analysis and botanical conditions in certain spawning ponds at the Dundy County, Gretna and the Valentine Hatcheries, as well as some nursery ponds which are being used by the Commission. This report has been compiled and will be published in the near future. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">STATE OP NEBRASKA EXHIBITIONS -pvURING 1929. 1930 and 1931. the Commission made an -L/exhibition of Nebraska fish at the Nebraska State Fair. Here some forty (40) different species of fish are shown and thou - sands of visitors view the aquariums. This exhibition is one of the largest in the middle west and is always a popular attraction of the State Fair. In addition to the annual state fair exhibit, some permanent fish exhibitions are maintained at the Valentine Hatchery, lo - cated near Valentine in Cherry County and another at the Gretna Fisheries, located on the Platte River in Sarpy County. In 1931 another permanent fish exhibit was added to the above two. this one being at the state fishery near Benkelman in Dundy County. The Commission also, maintained a park exhibit at the Ne - braska State Fair during 1930 and 1931. This exhibit is lo - cated in the Agricultural Hall which likewise has proven very popular with thousands of visitors. A cooperative exhibit is planned for the 1932 State Fair. The Commission has joined hands with, the Nebraska Nursery - men's Association to provide an exhibit of shrubbery and trees. The work is all ready well along and it is believed that this ex - hibit will prove very attractive. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">GAME, PORESTATION AND PARKS COMMISSION HUNTERS SHOOTING SCRIP THE 1931 Session of the legislature passed a law known as "Hunters Shooting Scrip" Act. The purpose of this Act was .to permit farmers to receive a feeding and trespassing charge for hunting upland game birds. Books containing five (5) coupons, good for 50 cents each were printed by the Commission and sold to hunters desiring to hunt on scrip farms. The hunter purchasing such a book placed the same in the possession of the farmer, who desired to accept such scrip and upon leaving the farm, gave the farmer one coupon for each pheasant killed. The Commission placed this Act in operation in the fall of 1931. A total of 13,065 coupons were sold. Of these, farmers accepted approximately 2,245, whereas refund was made on the balance. The Act has not been in operation long enough to ascertain its full value, but it is believed that this is a step forward in bringing farmers and sportsmen of the state in closer harmony and making it possible for thousands of acres of land, now closed, to be opened to regulated hunting. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">STATE. OP NEBRASKA GAME, FUR AND FISH FARMING THE Game laws permit the state to license private game, fur and fish farms. The Commission has felt that such private industry was a good thing for the state of Nebraska and has encouraged game, fur and fish farming.' During the past three years the following private farms have been operated: Game Farms 1929 453 1930 478 1931 461 Pur Farms 1929 ; 379 1930 352 1931 302 Fish Farms 192 9 1 8 1930 23 1 9 31 3 7 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>