<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  MILKING MACHINES.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">■e i T T A Cc University of Nebraska. Agricultural Experiment Station NEBRASKA. XXI, A II MILKING MACHINES. }n of the Milking Machine, and Its Cost. ect of the Milking Machine upon Yearly Records of Production. ort Period Trials and Detailed Experiments. Be Required to Milk with Machinery as Compared with Hand Milking. e Influence of the Milking Machine upon the Bacteriological Con - dition of Milk. lswers Submitted by Dairymen nclusions. A. I.. Haeckeb ami E. M. I.i i D» ehki 7. Khin I.INt i »LX, MM! \&gt;K A BULLETIN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">IGRICULTMAL EXPERIMENT STATION VKBKASKA fHE GOVERN'NG BOARD THE STATION OFFICERS r \ hi km ii J. s. DALES, Ml \YM W MARSH THE WORKIN3 S II u&gt; U i \ t . \\ V A I. II 1 KK .1 l'llll I N II Bw&lt;i Lonun, B.S Ai.m\ Keysbr. A.M.. Vbni ■ W I'.h.l. A.M.. A HBDLL A.M.. .1 M. H. S« eni, A.M., .1 i r 11 \&gt; S. ALLEN tG. WHITIIOR] DERICK II \HliiflT (•I! (I. I. 'i FOR1 (ii \&gt;. B. \mh:i:&gt;i :&lt;iK (tH'PLAX BChatbubn, A.M.. / ECmeimon, B.H I' Stout. ( .1 KSn&gt; DEI \I S II Kl. US, &lt;i\ix. M. I ■ Sll K!&gt;K\ I\T. A M I I. M I.irn.K. U.S. . i s. M 8. 1 1' H Makkkh. AH W. W. Hi iiu. US, 8 \\ I'khin, / </seg>
            <seg id="p003">MILKING MACHINES. HAECKER \XD K. M. LITTLE. is installed at the Nebraska Agricultural ie purpose of investigation in October, eral kinds of mechanical milkers had been &gt; and the demand' for information in v great. To meet this demand it tudy of milking machines, and accord - n the market were inspected. Power dered to U&gt; the most practical for the dairy, and Kennedy machine was selected. ipidly along dairy lines during the been hampered markedly by disinclination of hired help to milk achine offers a possible solution of lilems while the possibility of its sni revolutionize dairying as a hniiimi ore profitable basis. We have, there - on the various phases of the milking c bulletins have Ix^'ii published in An xpcrimcTital triuU with milking ma. title of "Milking Machine*." (liven in the s publishing these report* an as foil. tural Experiment Station, Bulletin 1-10, October Vgriculture, B. A. 1.. NO. !C. January, l'.H)7 \iricul tural Experiment Station, Bulletin 47, May. l'.MtT Department i&gt;t Agriculture, Bulletin l"&gt;(t. .Inly. 1907. b'anui Agncultura) Experiment Station. Bulletin s."&gt;. January htc the results of the experim t wo vears. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 DESCRIPTION OF THE Mil. KIMi MACHINE AM The Burrell- Lawrence Kennedy cow from the udder by means of suction. In sucking of a calf. The calf takes hold of the ing the muscles of the mouth draws the mill result is caused by the removal ,( other words, the creation ( ti ire the m When the milk Hows i; relief to the teat. Th on practically this sam \ the ail- f by rul&gt;lx'i rig milk is for and ■ piston connection b relieving th&lt; appliance milkers. The va&lt; ejector and ai ment Station pi; steam ejector is attache! is very simple anil dura and regular and the eject in operation the boiler must in constantly to maintain the is much more convenient ai form of power is very practical sary for the washing and prom penally is this true of the machine milk* can he operated by any kind of farm motive power. \\ building, from whirl iiMiMaiiuy in maintain the req entirely upon the vacuum rei in. to control t he vacut The air pump a perfectly efficien iled a three- horae power &lt;■! </seg>
            <seg id="p005">\ 1 I I II [■' i ; K'umj; the Where electricity is not &gt;n the farm. We ban iniiiff of the milking an in connection with this 1)11)11 which is eon .Hid mis in front two cow attached mrce of power untile air. Ikei i w.iter in tl Ml 'egulator or safety valve. It rorrei tcMi irrp.at. ii ler and cornier al P Iker metal mis of A half-inch :■ milker with the r.mi'hion 'ctor drawl the air oir is opened exhausting the nilk cocks the vacuir imount of vacuum ere of powc placed a Flip ri o the ealvai vacuum and teats of the I in the milking machine irmounted by a tightly •al Darts of the milker. ntaining :i vet mi wln'ii the i nilk cocks lead n cone-shape* nected to the )f t lie COWS. "he amount of vacuum shniilil Ix 1 alxmt ltj incl </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I fe tto niilkiiii minute can U KfH, drawn t he ii Tl of tin an.l the fcxible ; will occi flow .-mil rate the \ cupa and the cups must of the van-ing get her with hi? Edi is equivalent amount may !«■ vari« inals in uiv n.iTt i &lt; ■ i ■ I ■ • &gt;- nieiit iif the teat cups am pieteneaa of milking. In Met and combinations i the equipment u </seg>
            <seg id="p007">up*. Slouthi \. N 1 Ni 1 So. ( \, 1 N. I &gt; I No, ( t No. I No. *"• I. 1 \ ■&gt; i \,, . N 1 \,, i t No. : i \, &gt;^- N N« I I No. 1 1 No I No. 1 I No I No :t No. 2, 1 No. 1 t i \,, .-, I No. ii i No ii t No » No I No 1 No ii I No t No. 3 I No 4 « No liffereni sizes of parts necessary to milk vc can appreciate, partly at least, the responsibility He must remember what combination fits end •mutually keep changing parts to meet the e animals, and he must always have the different s,.f&lt; me is lost while milking. :irts to the milking machine that wear out ulsator springs must DC replaced every thi. I this is a very small item. The rubber curt.ii.w ir and stretch out of shape quite easily from time to time. The manufacturers .te curtain with which to replace the , K-s not fit in the normal position of the s deeper in the cup. This is a weak feature, K' made to fit against the udder as snuely as ore new mouthpieces should always l*&gt; usod in - ig to use these substitute curtains 1 some idea of the cost of installing and keeping plant in running order, the complete </seg>
            <seg id="p008">to Fit;. 1 . The milkii equipment in the University di and supples for two veins, is given here. This does not inelttd the cost of power for operating tin power gasoline engine were used i SI HUM </seg>
            <seg id="p009">I .l\c. MACHINE EQDIPMKM Sim i¥ c 1 nm TWO nil :t ("hi VI I I 71 ciiiiiii gauges IMI &lt;KM ■■ I IioHiimi casting « J7 ill vj t 1 IKI tv I .VI I 1 .'M~kl-|: III iaphrani.H ■-, 7S ; rings I 30 :&lt; hi M '" '. ; a : xi a i nun M cui m&lt; I" .. « j«r. 13, I HUB H&gt; intln I. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">I ) I 1907 June is. H«&gt;7 Viik- -'. I!«I7 i - A up. 2, l'.MtT K.-l,. _M 1908 Apr. 14, WON \pr. 24, 1*»*»S I T»'at cups sup mouthpiffm I I OK THK Mll.KINt; M VCHIXK ll'oN 'i H tFifty-thrw diff&lt; nee the installation "f t Kperimeni Station. &lt;&gt; it tinuallv with the iiu-cliai tried, while others have ordi have been obtained, toget shorter pcriodl of time. While tof definite conclusions. the\ hi nes and form an ideal lias ias milking can lx&gt; done l&gt;v niachinei at least, this method appeared qtl record is not sufricient to prove i if experimental work arc of machine milking upon the cow I of milk. In view of this fact thi those cows in the dairy herd u Is hy machine. In 1908 I was liegun which will cover a liave never l&gt;een milked by li far as milking is concerned » milkers. So far. two lactation Teat cup mouthp 30, IMM To 13 pirn _&gt;7. 1907 2 -.-I- Apr lti. l'.X)7 tried, while others have Imm'ii short time. As a result, t wen </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 impair favorably with University dairv. ilc n i down their milk quit* IN and are less inclined to hold up mied to hand milking ecu uilkinji is Ih-zui i men t a with the cow« in line e\i&gt;e i -pedal selection of individuals for any t all cows were tried out without otnliilitv. If the machine milked a cov lined to the end of tin nerallv cont i any difficulty, a cow would not respond ■omit of the interference of other exiieri- id the general practice inflammation has none out of If the inflammation due to tin der will Ik- in a normal condition in he congestion will remain tor :i \t its normal condition vii here are given in peril ■ animal can thus !*• foil. Ik- made from time to time. ich space and w and date of freshen- •eil during the lactation |&gt;eriod, ned by hand stripping afte imount and per cent of hutter - v was milked bv hand for i w istinction between the met llowa the lactation record to l&gt;e possible, tlic inachiiH' tni- u&gt;r rcsciitcil to. Manipulation will Ik- nece* 111 period and ;i compa Kxperimeni Station. Ixit the j »n t »li- I require too much s|»:ic»- nfusinjr. The tallies df yearly nade in the column marked </seg>
            <seg id="p012">N Table I. Milking muekint V cross, bit imthth i1.it r, 1894. 1 ri-hcni-il January ■ |l|tl ~ |) :1 t, il milk Stripping I'n.. l/(. Jan. ll&gt; 12 Jan. 13 -38 Jan. 27 Feb 23 24 M:ir 23 liar. 24 April 21) April 21 M:iv Is May 10 — June 1"&gt; Jum- Hi July 13 July 14 Aug. HI Aujr 11 Sept. 7 8 21 1 1 28 28 28 14 116 6 M2 1 ft*2 I I!i7 I i:il 7 N I 1M&gt; 'J 82 6 By I | l&lt; 1: hand :&gt; I I ii in l 7 •&gt; ii 1 1 Total nv~&gt; i I, 1 rLE II. Mtlk i mi mad Horn May 1. f a j i «i ///// Dat.- D»yi tal mil tM Imip l.'i i 16— July 13 1 1 Aup. Id 11 S.-pt. 7 . 8— Oct. :&gt; 8 Nov. 2 . :i A) 1 Jl 28 28 js js 28 28 28 'MKI S 1)77 J 25K 7 160 i) 113.1 \ Total </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 M motion. . \h* I'JKI. Kresheneil May -17. l!«l tayi Total milk Stripping Bultt&gt;r-fal 4 i l&gt;7 :. 12 2.0 » H ID -10 Mi (I UN) t 580. 1 I 43 Mm a . Hold* in, bu mo 1 A talmilk Strippiiun Butter-fat i.:. I 5 Hv hand 'A) I !."» Mi S *Mi I J H 3.21 '• 4s ii 3.41 M 161 ii .! 06 s«i: g IX. 4 1 M 819 N I Mi I »(&gt;".» :,7I t l.'ti :i t J'.i ici ii Tit (i » 7(i 331 B I". 8 I 17 _&gt;7ti (i ti I I !»1 13 60 I) 1 17 3.80 It 1 1 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">H Table V. — Milking maehint record of Ban . ./&lt; i VI. Milk Bor I Dal / July II Ann. I" II Sept. 7 _'s 23 Mar. .'(I M 21 April lx April Id May 16 Mav 17 .Inii.- 6 21 177 B Nov. J \ 3 Nov. :«i I IV-. 28 29 .l;in. .'.") 26 Feb. 22 Born lorn Octol bar IT r 1898. . Freshened July 3, \&gt;M Total milk Stripping Julv 7 Any. :i i Auk. :il i Hept.JM Sept. 29 Oct. 26 : Nov. •-&gt;:&lt; N .t I).--. 21 52 Jan. is Jan. Ill Feb. 15 Fed. 16 Mar I I Mar. 15 April I 1 April 1_&gt; May 9 May 10 June 6 : June 13 ■ 's JS 28 ■Jx 28 28 28 28 28 28 Pound* Pound* ii."&gt;l ."&gt; By hand "15 8 710 * ; 1 • ■ 138 '.i tsT J 191 Hi.' J 17 s ll-v I 111 i&lt; 1 171 I J I H I I) 19 7 ii Total </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 iIxt 12, 1908. Freshened May 19, 1907. Pounds Pounds Per cent Pound* 24 til 1.4 - ITS \ 28 522.5 4 :t t 58 N M Day itul milk Stripping! Butter-fat Pmmdt I'ouml* Percent Pounds 682 1 4.2 J :« Nov. 1( \ I). Jan. 1 1 achine record oj Lincoln H.. Jersey, by months. Day- Total milk Strippfa Butter-fat _'s 8M.fi 31.8 t !*) 28 (&gt;:« :» 113.1 ».-•» 28 .'&gt;■&gt;! 1 38 ti I iiT 2\ n 28 :{."&gt;&lt;) &gt;i lo.i) 4.70 28 .'&lt;I7 3 ».J ■_&gt;7!t -i 18. &gt; 5.16 U i.i ■J4&gt;i s i s.") 13 M |«8 8 1.7 5 18 21 EM 3 .0 :? 71 _&gt;'.»7 4:W4.l 361 ■"&gt; 1.72 -'"7 73 I. Milkiny machine n-cord oj PatMy, Jmtg, by months. Born December 14. 1902. Freshened May 2, l'.K)7. jx 883 1 4.2 4 :« 28 tHXi.ti 0 4 4.' 28 &lt;i!!2 :i (I -4 17 H W.S •• -4-1 24.81 28 4!t:&lt; B 17ti :i 4.-K) .'1 7»i 28 - : 4 211.7 5.M 2i U 28 :«vs ; ui ;&gt; .-&gt; iio jx _&gt;77 4 22.3 ."&gt;4tj IS IS .■x MB S 15.3 4 4&lt;&gt; 11 7H 180.8 .8 4.1^) 7 x7 47l&gt; 1 1 .V&gt;4 .3 4 .VJ 1 1 :i 4'J </seg>
            <seg id="p016">/.. ir In ■ii in Table X. M Idim \. I I.T, II M:ir III \l , Mar. 24 April Jl April 21 May 18 May lit Jum- 1.1 Inly I] July 1 t Anjs- 1" Aui. II Sept. 7 Tata 363 sum | : I'ahi.k IX. Milk-, I '.I. ]'l .'(I Nnv. ID i : i &gt;.•&lt;• 1 1 I". Jan. II 1 2 — Fi 8 Vpril I ■ II June 8 til Sept. 7 M 610 . ■•I. I 28 510 ! 6— Xi.v. I js \nv. 30 H :il •• I I ■&gt;■ H :il'.i i 29 — Jan. 2"&gt; Js _&gt;.",_&gt; i as fa. n a im N l:ir. 7 1 1 H I </seg>
            <seg id="p017">&gt;/ 17 'urn record of Estella, Hoist* in. by months. 1904 KiWienetl Ami 17. 1!M)7. at Days Total milk Stripping! Butter-fat 8 919 i :il :«i 4S 28 870.4 H 28 M6 i » 7.-.N M M 21 iK( ■0 17 :«) » 296.9 tin id U 3« 8216.1 None 3 28 J70 13 Feb. 21 Mar. 2:! 28 i&gt;22 0 " 28.3 4.99 M 95 Mar. 2 4 April 20 2s 603.9 127.0 4.58 27 69 April 21 May Is 28 K2.7 19.8 4.68 28 is.'. 7 It s 4.68 Pmmds Pounds I'rr ant Pound* 8 976.1 None 3 ».» 8 li&gt;4t; .7 ■ :i :«) 28 717 3. 17 3.16 21 49 J.21 28 893.5 28 642.4 28 480 . 2 May 19 June 1"&gt; Jv _".I4.6 (I 4 00 11 tv Jane lt&gt; July .'tl U 196.7 II I 10.32 280 S3 l.s") 4 i s."&gt; //(;/ much i hi it cord o[ Hilda, tirade Jersey, by nttinths. { First lactation . ) I reshemd September 17. 1906. I &gt;:iy~ Total milk Stripping Butter-fat I'ouruls Pifuiul.-i I', r cnl Pounds 21 MS. 8 By hand 17:. M II 28 ii."&gt;;i.3 • 5.04 28 SOt ■■ i '.»_' 28 - I 10 :&lt; 5.09 29.64 28 Ml. 4 Partly :&gt;A2 30.31 by hand </seg>
            <seg id="p018">0 r« /, . lorn l-.i &gt; N 2 Jan. 18 Jan. 19 Fab. !•"&gt; I Mar. 14 Mar 15 April II Anril 12 Mnv &lt;t Ei i- m:\\ :i 10 .Inn.- 11 7 Inn.. 13 T,,l«l Table XIV. If Hi in Hot, i &gt;v April .. May May :f May :i M«v Ml Jmio Tut ' s:&lt; fAHIK XIII. Ml, »Dct. ■&gt;- \.., May "&gt; June I Jiiiw ' .1 1 iiii« -&gt;&lt; HUM' _ .14111 _.' Jump HO Inly 11 July 38 A iir. •_»-» Aup 25 Sept. .'1 Oct. 19 Oct. _&gt;&lt;&gt; Nor. 16 17 Dee. H IS Jan. 11 Jan. 13 Fed M:.r. 7 Mar s April A Anril :. Mmv 28 28 28 28 28 28 '_' &gt; _' &gt; &gt;S 77"i ti'.i! r,:\ )s7 I7n !.-..-&gt; 122 127 4.'.' J 1 C </seg>
            <seg id="p019">M IS'. I 1 li. ; I'.NN H: / .)/ Mattii . llolsttin. by months / o/ Marguerite, HoUU mill iumI Decetnl ijra Total milk Stripping Batter hi \m ii Bv I 3«0 in HIS s I V i.-.l 1 N IK 17 28 smi ■s sss 1 M SI I' I aa 3.15 .; 28 1 1 08 m; 1 1 :&lt; » 163.1 :&lt; lit I, Freshened December 2H, I, 1906. V- Total milk Stripping! Butter-fat \ s s § g V s s s I PfMMMJl I'i'urt'ls i .'"Mi M By baad 1 !."&gt;:; g I 8 1441 II 0 1287 t n 1330 7 ii 1336 9 ii Ii7i»:{ ii I ( l.vs .-&gt; II 912.1 ii tti; 8 ii 821 . 9 ii 3 .."■ t 1 1 122 8 ii Per cent Pound* 4 (X) II J S7 U 7ti \i ()7 H W&gt; 3.21 11 31 3.03 m :«i _&gt; 7 1 _• !X&gt; 3.03 3.07 :(_&gt;:{ 20 II :&gt; .-&gt;l 12 '.'I 4 :r&gt; ti 12206 1 1.9 :t in :!7l 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">rHi.h XVII. Milking m Horn July 20. \'M)l. Freshened December I. Date H:i\- Total milk Stripping* Il'oillltls I .hin. 19 M I Iini ii By hand _*() Feb. 16 7vi ii None 17 Har. 16 B23 N 17 April 13 28 B 2 I t May II Imi i 1J Jin 2§ 11_' t _'. •( 28 1 AKLK XVIII. Mill Ik i mi tIKII I 111(11 1, idhs. Born June _'l Date I 18 Jan. 19 jo I.I, 16 17 M:ir. 16 17 April 13 U May II 28 28 28 28 28 28 28 .'I'SO It Ml I s.")7 1 1 m:» i 7-&gt;ii ii 563 :, :il(i '.i 159 I </seg>
            <seg id="p021">-'1 IS ■s :s Js :s &gt;H \ _'s :s f.VI S II is 13 jsii !l 's 193 1 .'I S.~) li i,s s Sane t 62 _' t&gt; 68 \\ .1/ / o/ Hit hi/. Jersey, by m&lt; «(■/; y .'7. 1905. Fmbened July 7. I1HI7 / s ."&gt;!!» ii None 4 '.Mi 25 7s ;iis i 17 17 \ Hi ii 87 II M ( I s l.V) 7 18.9 ii M\ 8 I 1 .9 1 6 sit v M s 1 1 0 7 08 ! \1 v i/ mackiru record of L\dd\a, Jenejf, b§ months 24, l«05. Freshened January 10, l'«&gt;7. Days Total milk Stripping! Butter-fat Pound* Patmd* Permit I' .")&gt;H( ti Null.- \ !Hi .•&gt;71 A ■■ » .".7 .'..■&gt;! 2 ■ I •'&gt;.-&gt; S21 1 5.10 193 7 ■ "&gt; .t) 198 7 " I 7-i 171 1 1 "»1 21 40 1J."&gt; _» ■ I 66 •a 8 2(1 II M 8 .-.-' Days Total milk Stripping* Butter-fal 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">.1 Table XXI. Yearly total. Days in mil ■ « ( nnunolii 1 M:,r H:i I.I:. S|.. II&gt;;u-.\ I Hilila i K: Mil. Ik iv r. I i. i.i.i Kul.; W proaurtioii. t tbi. upturned. The uinoi luiii" ;i atisfartory Duly half of tin- li- i ivlicn the milking machinei (trippings from the entire n Phis ir \eee t han .73 poun&lt; lificnni only when we consi mil when we learn that in ;i ITIi. ailed Ekcil nut perfectly &lt; r others stripped </seg>
            <seg id="p023">/ »/ &gt; •; ntli or two during the entire k of the mechanical milkers w ictorv during some Bit I isa In.-, method of milking it t li ■nt ot teat cups to teats was butter-fat produced by certain in erv small. For instance, a review of the e twentv cows shows four records that fall Ix'low er-fat while ten. or exactly one-half, ot () pounds of fat per year. It has Ikmmi the aim )epartinent during the last few years to keep the p to 300 pounds and very rarely has an\ &gt;&lt;&gt; pounds of butter-fat. In fact, a careful it and mature animals which n carried ndard have Ikmmi removed from the rint their second lactation Mable, Table I. page 12, the production of milk lining 1 7:i.liti pounds of butter-fat. This &gt;ly low. Taking up her record by "_' v her production was not consistent, diminishing nth to month. During April ami May. the Mable milked fairly regularlv. hut the dairy n milk flow during this time, so her that she was not doing satisfactory worl e a record quite similar to that of Mable. She iter than Mable, so the season of the I as an influence upon persistency in milk ion of the record of these two cows will Ik; \ ivell as was expected of her while the Marie nor Lincoln M. Have. Ida. ;iml ltho at times the per cent of strip rd. for example, shows 790.2 nd the other two records show per cents al 1 to produce at least 2(H) poondl ol lactation and must give promise oi f subsequent yearly record </seg>
            <seg id="p024">lie was U'in&lt;r milkei s one month's prod iv machine milking I,..,,-,, I.,- .1... ....,..,,, , i ,.;_,, m.,U \ ., Tl,,. iw» ,liff i any animal in the herd. Her and if it had not Ixmmi fur the fact th; b « •" * eloaed. Tlie per cent of fat in her milk was bo hi&lt; -hows a possibility of meeting the standard ' ■ o During the first three months Rul&gt;\ was i ■ obtained, lnit during the next three nmn Wll l.-irl :l I h ill ll&gt;c t machine *&gt; t,,l,l. Tl milk at one \t:;tin she w i purposes and niilkiii; well tlininui the yea Mat tic. Marguerite a lv satisfactory when well a&lt; expected. Hubv. a heifer ' have Ix'cn removed from tin- her </seg>
            <seg id="p025">s, The influen msiden .\lien the record nilking mac hi in ild thus indirec Is of Ruth, Mabl. ■ on certain cows, y affect the herd Marie, and Ruby. iction of [uiva- ,v nt Station pleted records by mnarison of COT hail !&gt;een removed. This r&lt; teal cups small enough to fit this t that time and in coaaeqttMMC the k. The teat eupa must tit the will attract a surplus flow of 1 m will \te impaired. -fat production given in Table XXI uds for the 20 cows. The aw Nebraska Experiment Station, as WM 284 82 pounds. This average in- The twenty machine recur -Is fall Ix'low the ids l&gt;v exactly 22 13 puundsnf fat. This \vs the records of the twenty cows milked at below the herd production of former because it .shows how several pi xir records veral poor record &gt;f tin- poor in- ter-fat, tin- avera pounds butter-fat, duction of the \.\ which have e ieveral years </seg>
            <seg id="p026">»/ Induction during the ten years she \* unds of butter-fat while the produi machine. The exceptionally low recoi tributed tn cause- other than the met ho rnlitinn.etc.. Imt her health appeared ex&lt; in record made by hand promia s not interfered with her work an yet. I her 1908 lactation period Mable ha.- pnnl d 215.84 pounds of butter-fat. She irk at the present writing and if past per future ability we can safely estimate 1 ice H large as the one made during 1907 rrettable 1007 record is attributed to th whine to draw the milk from a peculiai iv gives nearly all of her milk thru the 1 ng very deficient in development. Furtl The most complete record of this nature is tin it uf M Shorthorn cross. Her life performance, witl 1 the ( premature first lactation record, is given here Table XXII.— Record ,,j Mablr. a Skarikon //(a mil. milk milk IMI7 Hand .-,7:;i 7 IX9K " 7.-,:;.-, .' IH99 _nii ii!i.-, | s MMHI " 777., 7 I!N»1 !H|&lt;| 1 i«k 7.-.I. 1 n 1903 ■ 301 7tiil •• 1904 61 |s 11 &lt;l I90o :yis I l!HMi 701 1907 Machine 252 4185.1 1 :;i 1 u; 1 ip'i 1 i'i 1 ."is 4 L'l 1 14 4 .00 ' The sliortest number of ila\&gt;. the and butter-fat, and the lowesi pi this cow was milked l&gt;v machine. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">1/ • obtained with dif- (■in thai the machine method &lt;&gt;f milking is in t! mple i&gt;{ a COW thai ilitl Hot rMpOBd ti) tlie milking, the life record of Ruth III, a J&lt; d of liutli III. milked stern y oc.v hi, It nth III ■ y &lt;n* hi, i I '. y- ill I'c uinU lVr I'. IB milk milk Imttrr-fat l&gt;ult. l.".4li I ;.'t 7481 J » IHI i ;."&gt;_'."&gt; :i :«M 1913 1 I Mi _m&gt; 1927 li t 78 P. i l.".4li I ;.'t 71M 1 » IHI ti.").'.". :i :; II :U 4913 1 I Mi 7«»l H I 58 7JK11 s I .VI 7315 9 ■*&gt; 7(1 tls M Machine 217 4050.9 4.20 170.02 217 4050.9 4.20 170.02 321 5957 II t itaiinii production up t • &gt; the time the machine |poim&lt;l&gt; ill' milk ami 305 27 pounds of lmttpr- during the year she was milked by machine milked bv machine i.")i) S) |iciumls df milk and 170.02 pound machine milker caused this cow to dry up hciwn by the short lactation period in I'.iur. _&gt;■ number of days in milk had bed only '217 days in length. Ruth is Ix-ing ii. ilker paused tlii.~ cow to dry up lactation period in I'.'UT. avs in milk had Ikhmi 338 k inly '217 days in length. Ruth is Ix'ing c again during l!Mts. hut she has not Ix-on fresh long lin during HM)S. hut she lias not Ix-on fresh long comparison. This cow was in perfect health ui on. This cow was in perfect health •ord wan made and her udder is a very j her udder if a ven idc am Marie have each completed a five year- bv hand and the la- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">by machine. These two records are somewhat similar to Ruth Ill's and Mables. Tahlk XXIV. — Records oj "Comrnotmn and Ma hand and machine lactation rxriod* .ml Met hud of bni-il inilkinp Year Km Average Hand 1!MI4 Hi 1st (in HK).-&gt; 6 l'Hlti l(«)7 H Machine 1908 9 Average These cowe made ver\- small lacta t machine milkers were used. The con ked, however, as is the case with Mable a A numlier of the other cows havii have also made previous records by hand. The* here to show how the performances when the \i hand compare with those made bv machine milt 1 udinq KHand I9O:S 2 365 MV.M) .» 4 (\7 1!M&gt;4 324 4ti7!l 1 1.80 224 4s HM).-&gt; » 365 7829 1 4 U) l'.MMi ."&gt; 2»1 TITli 1 4 3S -'7ii 42 Machine 1907 6 283 5100.4 4.43 225.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">w ng hath hand and ma - chine lactatio D:iy- III milk Milk Butter- liutter- fat fat I'tmiulx /'• "»741 J » \tl 9426 3 * 4."&gt; 6367 9 4 91 IS lit I.". :ii:i 343 1906 8 9 1907 \ :(.V i 717s 1 4 71 ■in I90o 329 S7S2 i&gt; I 00 10220 9 32 1907 8844 .7 3 .97 \v. *«» 9182 7 lli:&lt; \ :w:&gt; 4 91 \ :«7 lilj't li I is \ (Jr. Holstein !!»()."&gt; - ; 79 I'.HMi .itir&gt; 1081.1 3 3 78 1907 5 316 10376 .6 3 .21 :i4l KMMi ."■ l!HMi 1907 363 10426 ii :{ 17 8104.1 3.61 S2 3 \ 364 :i -i .Vt II HHMi 1907 :iti.-&gt; sill (i 3.30 8216.1 3.28 ss 3 308 \ :«« 831 I i) -i .'» M HHM) I :di.') 7.').'i(&gt; it 5.20 1907 5 399 8344 .2 3 .92 Year Air&lt;' ry 190.5 2 365 "&gt;K)7 () 1 M 1906 H4H 5688 N 5. 1:5 1907 4 297 4394.1 4.72 207 .72 190a 1 365 KSK7 (I I :C. :«;.'&gt; 87T9 0 t 58 310 s«i 1907 4 280 4721.1 4.52 213.49 I "1 ■ &gt; 4 • &gt;•&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Among these rec( ive performance for ea ■stance, Bave, [da. Kp 17 pounds of butt i ii i - lit their ivn iii lei I i showing nit . and Mi iTtiinii; trhine was in use \ Ii case, and avera lion is lower than ,• ,.,.„•&lt; It i. till v nil 5.60 A in siune instanc llll.llt ■■ I .If -It ■&gt;!• when the milkinj I.. tUmmm „•■. ,.,.,, ■ ilwlill-ii ri. it table in lithe inn! to machine n tin- mil Lii herd cannot Ik • i i i i ! 1 1 w- Bavim lit t whole must lie avoided. V SHORT l'KHKH) TRI \I.S \M&gt; I) E number of shorter experti n time since the installatii nearly every phase of the n the many different factoi ■se data can well lie &lt;l Mice ir t he be ricrii 1 hiVKi i&gt;in i ■ rill i lei wi» t 1 inilkiii" in.icliiii f 1*1 ilil t 111' VI Ee doI satisfad tpplication rannoi known to lw adapt) </seg>
            <seg id="p031">n h i n i 1 &lt; g time thruout, and some very inter* pecially is this true of the figures that per- ilking and the yield of l&gt;utter-f:it. to - control these points. We wish to . of the minor details to l&gt;e considered ichine and its operation. SATING HAM) AM) MACHINE MII.KINC rated that one man should milk the count of the disastrous effects of a con - kers. The constant alternation of machine ring would apparently have the same or a he cows. To show the effect of alternating ilking a very good example may l&gt;e had from cows in the University dairy herd which reatment l table shows the effect of alternating hand ipon the yield of butter-fat. Thee ur cows and cover a period of six ecu alternating hand and machine mill iod was detrimental. The total amount of lot 11/ four cows for rii conm Milk produced let hod oi Butter-fat milking By machine Stripping Total Pound* PmnJi I'd:. Machine :&gt;!*&gt; i&gt; f,7 :( 083 7 I ."» Hand TOT 7 4 1 :!1 14 aw 7 i 7 Machine 555.3 l-'s ."&gt; 683 8 H !• 527 8 158 8 886.5 -I 8 J9 99 Hand M t 1 I; ■lac H:iimI Hand 2030.2 1.5 Machine HiT') 2 :r&gt;4 I 2033 6 t (I leriment the two methods oi milking were so radi- in operation that when the milker was substituted the cows did not milk out completely. The amount meased as the experiment progressed, plainly in- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">the milk and in consequence more stripping evident that we cannot make a comparison betweei of milking by alternating these methods. milk was practically the Bame in each case but tl butter-fat was materially lowered. It would be ( esting to know whai became of this fat but ire have, ; ; 1 1 i ii i 1 1 «i this. The record of Bessie McKinlex i • given here to t of alternating methods of milking. Me unsatisfactory after tw&lt;&gt; weekly substitutioi tliat the attempt wa: considered a total lailii amount of Btrippings increased but the udder l&gt;e&lt; and the milk wtw drawn with difficulty even bv perhaps, an extreme care but ilic re ull i no worse expect it constant changing from one method to the mittetl with an entire herd. Milking l.\ hand in t .......,,,, .,,,.,. .qimui^ in i i.i 1 11 i 1 11 i instance, and with machinery in the evenine. a nrai ' ' ' ■ "■•" i ii in i * 111 i in ririilll^. ,1 |l[;n Ear advantageous where labor i- poncerne&lt;l. \\&lt;&gt;\ factory w hen t he effect on | I kBLK X \ \ II. /,'. , I/, A i'&lt; Week (.1 Me ill, nl of (if milking B} -' . I ,■! ,. '1 I i:ill,l :&gt; &lt;• ], Feb. Hi 16 Machine I9ti 7 W ■ _■&gt; Feb. 17 23 Ham! 3 Feb. -M M:ir. J Machine I7ll 7 Ills Mar. :\ &lt;) Hand Ml 16 1 lie significant point brought ou1 by this ree by the performance of a number of other cowa n ■&lt;■(•(' neat, is that when machine milking and hand i on irregularly and interchangeably the machine c w </seg>
            <seg id="p033">, extensive enough to fullv tummkt of regularity in millrina \vi.«. ommand .it pvwv niilLiinr t.i.. - shown li roeedure is accompanied bv nrnmnim Again, after the change back to thi will not give u|&gt; all their milk or rcaDowi -fci'inl time on accouni ol thk uiicxiM-ctcl The Experiment Station plant has an emermnrv nwrva iiwi..lL,.l ntal trials with Bessie MrKinlov U p end of each teat was tre.-ite.l «itl, ■ ,lil..t..^ ■ n quite easily bv hand. The milker &gt;r occasion, which is worthv ol note Aft... llilk the milker ni ri«i«.fc.il ninutes azain adinsted to tl... '11 epeated several times to no milker was removed, over eichi Doumfa of milk some reason the machine would not r - this particular case. OKI) BY MACHINE. erest is shown in the aceonmanviiiir 1 ated after ten weeks of machine use „ ■rd. These COWS showed rammrkmhla r»,»,. ice l&gt;ut they show whnt m» l, mid procure power that will 1» - milking will have to lw&gt; mihatitni 'i kU'd tit tL.. I ■ , • ermora the routine work of tin il)lp is caused l&gt;\ the une\i». I Tlll'V will h»VP tn lu&gt; tf.in.»l ing an emergency reserve installed. Im- U8ed ;l!lll slllilllil oik- . ipacitated the other can !«■ :mi.li..,i N VM&gt; DELAYED STRIP PI Nil B1 \i.&lt; iiivw ind the thought occurred that this Deration. Arrnnlinvtv tlw. ti^l.f vere the same as had )mm tl,, &gt;taill :ill the milk hv mAJm </seg>
            <seg id="p034">OB t heir performance and for the sakt containing the production figures band during the same )&gt;eriod of time is givci Week ( Maolni milk I'l ,I:in. 20 26 I7(W .I:in. L'7 Kcli Feb. :&lt;-!» I.Vsii Feb. Id Hi I .VCJ Feb. 17 17 Feb. Jl Mar i:.n Aver, 1 .V.l_» Table XXIX.— Weekly Week of Milk 1907-8 PetuM 1 Jan. 5 1 mm Jar, 8 12. l.-,i; Jan. I3-1U . 1521 Jan. J\) _'ti [55 Jan. L'7 Feb. 2. ] |."&gt;7 i M. I ■ |3« Feb. 10-16 1281 8 Feb. 17 23 1351 FpI&gt;. J4 Mar. 2 1382 Mar. 3 9 1361 1 Average 1427 A glance at the last column in ei parative production of the two lots in pound: The lot milked by machine produced, on an a of butter per week and the record is a veritabk ity thruout. The hand-milked lot shows a l:i , n larity in milk and butter production. I tBLE XXVIII.- Weekly product, mack l&gt;.t&lt;)7-v PtmmtU Pound* I:,,, 1 '• ~M Jan. ."&gt; 1548. I M 7 \M Jan. 6 12 t * "»* » — &lt;i.'&gt; 7 Hi7 J:m. 13 IH 1820.7 2fi :; ItiJ Mar. :&lt; &lt;t </seg>
            <seg id="p035">.1 msidered. Tin ilesired under an\ en here makes the evennei iiiii. The amount of milk procure) l&gt;e rioted in passing. Dur- le conditions were quite constant and the V , &gt; I \C I II Roxanna Parthenea, a Hoktein row I'ter calving and extended thru a i» iilk flow, denoting persistency in n ini done as thoroly as could possibly &lt;l nj Roxanna Parthenea beaux !i r nil Milk produced Butter- fat pings lot Pmadi l'.,unil* I'mimls /'.. VI M I I HI r_» s i it '.a I I 1 . s •' I I sj l :* 79 1 &gt; III I « III a. » &gt;i a tn :! t ll 77 II' »:( 1 1 M) 3 :? 1 1 H.i ..', i H7 (I :i I II "- 12 05 I » &lt;Hi 117 kinsr machine ». Rounni fa! did nut vary in I there were prae- (■•■ks. A certain manipu- \ever. l&gt;efore all the t wci-t liirds nf the ift iler. herinninc at the </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 very top, and. working continually ilownw all hard places, thus freeing the alveoli and milk cist By this method it has been possible to obtaii from this cow during a large pai are only one or two cows in the I'niversutv herd thai machine milking unless pare m Aa the spring season advanced and the cows were put tine, quite a little difficulty « \perieiiced m ke( Metho&lt;l nl !i. klii Ei properly fitted to the cows. 'I •h elastic curtains or mouthpiece ect inward and when the cup is rubber mouthpiece presses dowi in place. With the spring flusl rh. tl PON THJ THK COWl </seg>
            <seg id="p037">IIII At this time the amount of BtrioDinn was jr. i I'i'i \ tave been interested in the itiilkinu: ma Ivisability of strinnint after the milkon eli' iirwr titiiI finft^P Tl,« ♦ ,... .til. I 1H- n-;i mill fast became delicate and tendc eee became too small, pressing tight 'itcrt'il with the milk flow TK»w «• &gt;!&lt;■ to meet the needs of the differeir and necessitated a considerable outlay f&lt; ■inonstrated that careful work WM lai'lime n.iits mil itt&gt;.n,l t.&gt; »!,„ :— . ,i;..:.i </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Us eater than the rotnpar would indicate. Furthern have a retarding influence i hat th&lt; -milk and i\ 1V11 \i lie and anio pm in wet p II III ss 7 4 0 1 I ' 7 7 1 ."&gt; 4 8 I K -2-1 4 3 .'.'. :{1 71 ii 4 6 4 up earlier than new duction, even th&lt;&gt; a t rated !&gt;&lt;■&lt;• nine quit! dairy qualitu tot;tl amoui Table XXXI. 77 xlti Test I Test Van 1 In tH 6 Vuf 11 IT Ms \utr- is -I !M» 7 W- 25 31 83 7 Perti. /.'.- /./,&gt;. 5 0 1 .73 I 1.1 4 8 7 .". 4 4 3.98 i ! 3 1 3 7 3 (Ml I 10.5 9 4 10 0 9 5 Pn-ru. i :C(i .s 8 .0 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">1/ KIN Toi Milk Test t 9 3 II 7s His 13 8 10 0 -' IHI l'&gt;7 1 4 2 9 6 :f 17 171 9 5 0 s ,,1 9 0 1 .".7 !l ».'&gt; 14 0 3.5 19.49 s.l.n 9.5 7 .'.'I tir_'..'&gt; 4.3 I ir-i milk Stripping* Test I ,i Milk Test Fat I Milk Test 199 » IK7 N _'i Hi :; IBH 1 3 1 I. j 113 1 4 36 3 7 ii '.P.". :iil S 9 6.' mi Jl^ fi 4 5 3 2 ii nil :{_&gt; i io 2 :« :iu .':&lt;&gt;. 7 4 1 4 2 7 M I-' 7 9 ii 1.21 180.7 4 6 3.5 2«.79 11J.:( 10.0 II -4.4 LINCOLN BE \\ T\ milk &gt;inga Total . Test I ■:.! : Milk Test k Test 3 8 5.19 i:&lt; s 9 6 I :s:i l'&gt;n "&gt; 4 33 4 4 ii .'7 I 12 &lt;i 4 4 3 I IH :i 8 4 1 lij i:W II 3 9 •"&gt; 19 &lt; 3.6 4.68 17 8 5 Ml li:W ii 3 8 - i 3.8 19.71 17 &gt; 8.8 7 4 .1 QU1 milk Stripping* Total : Test l:.t I Milk Test Kat I Milk Test II Urn. .".HI &gt;sn 272 I.I,,. Perct. I.I- ■ Lh* /' &lt;l 2 1 till I 92 .s 7 0' 733 12 til 7 20 •'&gt; i;i !ir&gt; ii 5i :. ;&gt;"&gt; 7 30 ii i(t .-&gt; 18 1.91 r.'ti 7 5 6 ii *»7 !; :{.«• 2 3.0 II « I 2 5 7 SS U 72.7 7 1 •"&gt; Hi i :i^^ 1 3 4 117". .:. 2.0 6.0 _'t ..'.1 I ".",7 7 3 .0 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Kirsl milk I'wk Milk Test Fat Milk Test I -,i Milk Test /A*. Per it. Urn. Um. I'. , H I b» I b* I', i 1 Id -M.-f H 2 8 fi x:&lt; (14 (I 6 8 (1 :i!l I :«7 s 3 9 Milk Test I :,t I Mitt Test *Mg- II 17 261.0 2 l ."&gt; 4s T:i s 6 7, n 3 l Aug. IS 24 _'.")7 II 2 2 5.67 64 .7 5 2 3 r. 2 8 25 31 277 6 2 4 li 11 1 _ I) SI 1 IUt(l.:i 2.4 6.7 17.:*) 1306.2 3.5 3 - \\ Ten Kind milk fat k Test . &gt;|,|k Tes Milk Test I /./,- P, Aug. I Id 1 222 12 3.'. 7.4 J ', 3 Oi \Ug. I Id 1 222 1 2 3 Aiij;. H 17 1223 I 2 0 1 17 fc&gt; H 8 9 :; 7!) I 2«6 II 3 1 Auk. 11 17 1223 1 2011 Aug. IH--24 1222 H 2 fi l!t ;, 6 &gt; '7.' I 3 3 Any. Is _M L&gt;22 ti 2 6 ."i 7~ 24.4 2 2 1 I 2 2 1 &lt;U 29 i 9 8 .'vx _•;,:: s 3 1 'Ion, 2 3 7 8 IJ .31 HB2 H 2 3 I ir-i milk Xaub I Milk Test 1 Milk Test I ,■ M ,lk Test Milk T 1 i /A-. Pi r H. Um Lb*. i; r rt. Um / J*' 11 '- I 4 4 13 17 II .-, 8 0 1 ii 4 6 286 I 4.4 13.1 Brownie : H.Vl s 44 l."&gt;.(w .'.' .&gt; 8 0 J ; 5 0 Brown* .11 s 44 lo.ga 8 0 ('ommotioti , -V50 ."&gt; 3 5 19 !!• s:i 11 9 5 7 91 ,;|_&gt; -, 4 3 Commotion J ,V50 ."&gt; 35 19 w vi 11 95 \ [r 'y 761 (i 3 5 26 7d 112 3 10 0 II (Ml H7?i s 4 4 Lincoln B 1 522.9 3.8 19.71 :(7 s 8 8 :&lt;:;:, .-,11117 4 1 1179.5 2 0 _&gt;l .,1 397 1 6 0 .'1 :,] 15.57 7 3 0 1040.3 2 4 _■( ill 25.5 9 6 7 17 Hil Udtl ' 35 2 3 20 61 I.V.I K 7 8 12 7(1 |1053 I 3 1 Total ."i.Vsi; .I 3 0 Mil ,17 los:i s 7 7 v; o fi It is interesting to note that in the c ■t tat in t be strippingijwa* regularly i milk. Taking the case of Queen. :i~ tli </seg>
            <seg id="p041">y u 11 the strippinga was n actual amount there was only I'll inted for bv the difference The machine milk contained 2.0 |kt ned 6.0 per cent. When the lether and a test made of the whole fat. The percentage per cent nutter at as in the first milk iree times • total product. The figures shown The figure* shown in ist ant ially corroborated in each of light variations. The highest iree in the first week of Grey's record, i was obtained from M\ 4 pou rated in each of the The highest weekly s;ht variations. led in the first week of Grev'a record, the I'his test was obtained from 36.4 pound |UentIy contained 4 11 pounds fat. Thi ly contained 4 11 pounds fat. 'I lore than is contained in KM) pound ire than is contained in KM) pound! ii shows the abnormal rkhne the table, or summary, is probably it shows the condensed totals ,\hich shows the abnormal richne i par! of the table, or summary, is probably the hows the condensed total triuuinirs for the das-- contained - )|iii]&lt;;:: for the das-; contained s -&gt; ipm ximatelv half a: much a- was contained in itely half a: much a- was containei •r five times as much milk was obtained liv c times as imich milk was obtained ppinjr at the loss that would occur should Where the stripping! arc such a hi t would occur should the ■c\ Where the strippin ich a large oduct we can expect to find a fa n expect to find a fairly total butter-fat. The marked richness of the utter-fat. The marked richnef Ider is a matter of extreme import a t extreme import i matti thought by the machine operator w icliine operator when flit I)V the l [ clean. lean nance have been kept during the pi experiments but space will not |&gt;er ve been kept during the pi xpenments hut pace will not |K&gt;rmit 11 detailed form. To show the relal To show the relative tiled . however, it may l*&gt; well to stipplein be well to supplement &gt;vev ne or two representative tables show representative tables showing %\s by milkings. While any one i ings. While anv one of a ds could Ik- given, those of (irev i Is could Ik- given, those of (irey and thev -how verv clearlv the fluctuations they -how very clearly the Buetuati when the machine is in usi it </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Table XXXIII. Weekly record oj Gr&lt; of milfc ami jut production from milhim Kirs) | Milk Test l.ii I Milk Test I .,. l&gt; Milk Test Urn. P, 4 3 o I 1-' I 3 5 ».2 2 6 111 26 II 7 0 s II 16 in i 6 8 ; -' 19 13 .' 6 Table XXXIV. II 'Ik- ,i in Date ' Milk Test IM. I', '.) II 4 0 H 2 1 7 III 1 4 1 II) III 14 3 13 Kim. -'. 7.U 3.0 21 2 7 7 II 3 3 Aim 31 s l 5 7 Total ! l 1 15 n 3 8 9 -'•"&gt; ! is .' 3 8 §1111 4 0 It . -'li 13 6 2 9 in i 43 a 12.5 8 a _&gt; 2 tB.O 3 6 _'_' -'(I 7 II 4 0 10 :i 4 4 C) 2.9 10 B.3 4 7 44 9.2 5 5 :,l 10.5 S 8 .61 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">M 1/ le, taken from the records of (!re\ IWI1 ine was Is _' pounds, while OB k August 31, it was only i 2 pounds. The he difference was not recovered liv ck irregularly during the week, making production very uneven. Tin 8. 1 per cent in the machine milk. nt in the strippin mother Jersey cow. is more uniform than lie total amount of milk produced, the rcentage of butter-fal are fairly regular. a hen the machine failed to draw all the I in the strippings. The fact that Lottie ilid ci'ined to have no influence on the total pro- of Grey this influence was very Barked. »ld up her milk for over a day at a time and then rue quantity. These results are quite similar other cows in the herd and show the problem operator has to deal with. He will rind that takes to milk by machine has some individual Is special attention. A peculiarly shaped need an odd combination of teat cup and •ctlv shaped udder will not milk out clean un - lin painstaking manipulation. A eareli Id U' likely to overlook these details, yet roperly attended to the milkers can not l&gt;e ictorilv as in the dairv herd have milked out clean Iking but at some time during their lacta old up their milk. It has l&gt;een nee. ,e cows snipped by hand after the machines Thru some mishap a little milk may be left in the occurs once it is liable to occur again; so a habit is d detail, such as a poorly adjusted teat cup. a \i ng mouthpiece, a swollen teat or udder, unsteady and other factors of like nature might bring this Sunday morning, Au« </seg>
            <seg id="p044">i ( 41 A large number of detailed notes of more ur less ii could lie riven to further show the experimental ai suits of the milking machine trials at the Nel ion !&gt;ut everv item of any importance lias been inent where go they would mereh the huhiIkt of relief pulsation to use. and similar &lt;i points can nut !&gt;&lt;• v range permittei the difference in i in II Ml : RKQIIRKI) In Mil K \\ I III \l WITH II \M Alone with oth Eigations have beei can l&gt;e saved ami ■d liv the lire n!' I undoubtedly the m hand labor, and tin Bavins device is acco In considering tora that are more or 1 would not correspond in ■vet The conditions have been mat ever, and the results would c&lt; which might l&gt;e expected on keep in mind the fact that the skill of t machine, together with his knowledge function, controls to a large degree the i ing. Also, the number and kind of cow l&gt;earing on the rate of milking and m certain extent at least, the practicaliilit The first trial was made when one milkers. Each milker is arranged to n iVc man was virtually milking six cows at once. Som suined. however, in changing teat cups to (it the difft in emptying the receptacles, so that some one of the t ial here. The exaci </seg>
            <seg id="p045">/ M M M \l t ,vert ps and ;entativ fact we \t expenmen M 4. . The milk was weighed ant also stripped the cows Twenty cows in all were milked. Time is lust when only one \i the barn is especially arrai ineed in the stalls to aecommo &gt; milk three &lt;&gt;r four cows ci| t&gt;7 miiiutt's to milk _'() cow- producing 157 7 pounds pent in stripping. The rate of milking lachines were used was slightly less than nount of milk produced that the 1 nearly dry. Cows that are far along in as much attention as fresh ones as it is keep them on: so that we can safel e when time alone is considered. I 1 can turn to any one of the tallies given The figures plainly show that the amount &lt;/ lii milk 'J(( inirs hi/ maekim . m*. .1 helper dripped &lt;&lt;ul, f milk J'.t ."&gt; ])(iiiinls were obtained by hinc had been detached from the tows. «quiring an operator and imp assistant. It amount of milk nnxluced that tho larirpr Machine milk Stripping^ Minutes ., . MinutM ., rv.|.iiiv.l '""" &lt;U quired 88 i:«t II ii."&gt; I -'7 1 II ill 128 i, j:&lt; 71 129 •'&gt; ."&gt;l ■'&gt;'■&gt; 122 !• H 71 122 :i :.i ■; | 57 128 2 11 &gt;taineil. an averacc i&gt;t &lt;ix milkinn </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 |Uirt t. K i l I'l ( Kit ,e l Is. tin Eiilk ami the time required t&lt;&gt; draw i In determining the minuti starting of the vacuum ] &gt;vi iii]i mar mI was closed only when the vac stopped. Thus the time necessary t ■id after milking (about 8 minut In the next sent the time required to milk cows second, when two milkers ised. Twelve cow animals being used in all by machine for some them in. The man familiar with their us&lt; for some time, knew Besides caring tor tin the milk from each possible after the milke delay at times, especi where the highest pro* records of the amount for butter-fal must lie mail n in ea( e of three days and include six const which milking l&gt;egan and ended of minutes a milker was attached to eac time spent in emptying, weighing, etc. pain because each milker milks two cow milk out quicker than her stallmate tin Other cow is milked dry. This time is t Em and the milk produced by them is tallies. No separate account is ml pjiing as there was at no time more amount can l&gt;e obtained from the aam ping after hand milkers. In other won perfectly satisfactory work, but hand Accordingly The data jjivt </seg>
            <seg id="p047">1/ 47 therefore sufficient to rive total weight ic factor we arc treating here \\ I. Tiim required to milk with one milk* pair in iiiiimt Pump I -Hit Hilda Have Prize Lottie atopp- time :11111a En- Grey Mil- |)«ir:i Liddia eil re. Ida Ida drad -M 1 I 13 15 12 15 8:12 !•*• nun. 11 I-' 11 II II I .V_&gt;7 M II II 13 12 13 !i 12 12 i&gt;:iKi M i 12 12 I. 1 II II s 5:25 8J 12 12 II II 12 11 II II 12 11 13 in 6:03 100 III '.:(&gt;:{ UNI II 13 12 II 1." 13 527 83 I 13 12 II 13 :&gt;:J7 sj l"&gt; 13 12 U 12 II K ,,_. _'."&gt; 7 JJ 2 I.' 9 111 16 I 20 11 III 12 9 lit 1 20 ii iii n lutes. I hat 1 lie t welve ci&gt;\\&gt; were milked in W2 minutes king mm average rate &lt;&gt;f 7 7 minutes per cow. cing an average rate &lt;&gt;t i i minutes per cow. l the milker was in actual operation only 7."&gt; words it was attached 12) minuter, mi an r was in a ctual operation only To t was attached l_". minutes, on an 1 of cows. The difference between the total «rs. The difference between the t • &gt;t al d time attached is 17 minutes, which le actual time attached is 17 minutes, which i 1 1 u. the milker both before and after milking. riling, and in changing the milker notice that the quantity of lly influence the time required in M </seg>
            <seg id="p048">dition of t he udder, the quantity. temper am Table XXXVII. Tin Pum| i rt - Rox- Spot Hilda M;i\ »■ Prise I v Mil- 1) Apr. Hi A. M. 120 Apr. Ill 1'. M 1:03 19 Apr. 1 1 A. M. ):_'() 1 1 Apr. 11 I". M Iiki 13 Iveraw IbR.'milk i hie cow every 5 7 n \\ lien I wo the t welve COWS, Illttk than in the preceding trial, the average tinu difference being almoM thought, for we would \|&gt;ert tin t lit" same length of time. We the fact that the operator had not manipulate the udders as mu ing as carefully when attending tw&lt; only one milker commanded hi produced was quite similar during Apr. ■ \ \1 1:15 16 19 Apr. u 1&gt; M . I:ii7 I l ill tveragi list &lt; i 1111 ii 11 saving in tune &lt;&gt;t two mm The milkers were attache* </seg>
            <seg id="p049">\X.\ c milked in Ms minutes when tluw milkers minutes with two milkers and 92 minutes ite per eow was one every 4 7 mini; inutes respectively. By opemting three lis riu twt reduced one minute as compared with inutes when compared with one milker. A i i lie operator gave ic to note that th&lt; ( re was in i great vana - ■ at ilifferent milk regulaiitv makes the i in imparison and in order to make the al arisoi two other tabk •eating of the time re 1 the same time the milking machine data u-li pair of cows IN minui. K'latoi- jr:iv»&gt; all his attention to nilk each pai llisolf. si) Till: cr tallies are pTen here. The &gt;f the time required to milk by in this table coven ■ peri' Ik with thru milk' Tine per pair in min Pump I Spot Hilda B»ve Prize Lottie stopp- time Grey Mil- Dora Liddia e&lt;t required telh dred 1 J l!t 17 .'(I 14 0 ".1 nun. 16 is 14 _•() 13 .Vim .V. 18 is IT is 14 5:12 52 is 16 13 If It .V01 00 21 17 14 .'(( 17 ."»:_&gt;&lt;) 56 -mi i3 a la i4 ."&gt;:oi as Is 17 15 19 U 22 1 III s 15.3 |7s 21 (I 111 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">men. The second table contains onh the foregoing milking machine trials. mechanical milker wa: used, fti is saved bv using one milker. is merely substituted for hand lalxtr on When either two or three milkers were was a corresponding reduction in time minutes and 39 minutes respectively win These figures are applicable to any ol a slight error is introduced by including the machines. At the above rate whei used we could have the following figure I MILK XXXIX. I nm iltjll to milk iiij hand. for six days 1 _' milk k weighed and Cm PoJo Pansy Flom •&lt;■ Lady Ki Milker M M M M Lbs. milk 12.6 I". H 16 .". Is n i Time. inin '.) n !i 7 Ml I I i I I I 7 7 I". .". s ( in. Table XL. Totals and averages derived from Tal XXXVI. XXX X X X \ III. Kumbn of mi Milk /',.„ ( Inr HI H Two I in H hi Thiw 1 1 l _■ Is The liumlicr iif i of milk produced differ somewhat in figures for the different milki ig arc quite representative and the allowable. The rate of milking l&gt;v lia I ■ i 1 1 N | i . This iatc &lt;•« ni«&gt;s| nun 1 very rUi </seg>
            <seg id="p051">,SI \ 14 I it -.1 ; u in it to milk different n Two milker-. Tlir milkers. Four milker-. |&gt;er:itcir tun o\ .era tor out 'I \l Mint, IM ' I s Mi 7 s 122 117 IOJ IM 136 JH KM 17ii :«&gt;! ."&gt;) 112 .'(It si His Ills .'.'4 uo m m with this table thai •e m connecti it requires .'{ houn per a tor with two i and 10 minutes to milk milkers milks the 16 minutes but sa Likewise, by using three one hour and 52 minutes, ver hand milking. The saved by tisinj; twn and ses proportionately aa the size of the herd in - we consider a herd of 60 cows the figures slmw s ami ")-l minutes to milk by hand. ."&gt; hours and milkers are used, and 4 hours and 40 minutes are used. Thus two hours and 14 minutes instituting two milkers for one hand milker. d by using three milkers. houn and 54 minu time of any number of this rate would milk 60 tuning of the table red and the amount -how comparatively the of time saved by having figures are deduced from 1 on the assumption that just twice as fast as one four milkers. These oltimns and are base milkers will work Ikers. The figures -how that '.id cows can Ik* ' !/■/(&lt; // milking is darn uriti iis compartd with lie operator with two consume* 2 hours ami &lt;1 with hand milking. ild milk 24 rows in ami is minutes i red and the tiint inuten \v&lt;&gt;ul&lt;l U 1 savt hand milking, 7 •cut the combined •c. 4 men working at ."is minutes. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">milked in one hour ami 4'J minute is minutes, and (iO cows in 2 hour one man milking by hand. Thre&lt; the same work in two hours and .'&gt;' S This shows that two men opei work of three men milking by can obtain figures to show the ti ber of cows when t w cows can l«e milked time of milking when l i we find that tli extra machines. Thil for the care and ham far as t he data olitai concerned it would no per operator, when t h and sampling of th&lt; needed to maintain man can oversee two milki milking without l&gt;eiii&lt;r rual especially where the cows i where the operator is not si The writers have machine was in practical opera tiol the milk was neither weighed nor milk by machine corresponded fai rl in the experiments cited here. 1 cows were kept, two men with four milkers mill one hour, including the time used in rinsing t he mi Mid after milking. No records of the amount o the different cows were kept nor was the milk s At another dairy two men operating four milker to strip the cows and carry the milk to the dairy house, milked in cows in two hours and thirty minutes. Before the installatini of the milking machinery in this dairy eight men had been pi minutes, and ml cows in _ hours an time would l&gt;c at the rate ot ."&gt; . 1 mini l&gt;&lt;' stated that at in could the operator jjiv </seg>
            <seg id="p053">i 1 1/ Phis is a very dear contrast an. I i if the milking machine when used U't'ii made &lt;&gt;t' the time required t« Iking equipment, but in view h more care than hand equipment t this point. The amount of time iun - tlie above experiments were in prog liles hecause the metliod used in the I'ni- in modifications on m lerefore would not Ik man in washini •count of the im • representative. The ilixing, and earing our and forty min as found to be one 1 Hid if tliis amount ng the figures would would not he fair. l&gt;e&lt; ausc a certain amount the parts and on the cd in hoilin nt could turn his hands to other thing! Furthermore the milk is cared for under ms and in consequence more time i - equi] -lit than some people would ie milk is not prepared for im media ti jiiired in caring for the machines is. there • upon the degree of sanitation and clean - irket for which the product is prepared. lours per day where the machine pai I ■rilized twice each day, &lt;&gt;r it might, if the product of inferior quality, lx&gt; washed ee times per week. The time required t amount to much more than one-half teagre care is not sufficient, however, as vino: bacteriological studies and is not rec- v if tilt it- were added to Ik- radically cham </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 .i.l l':tt Several months allei at the Nebraska Experiment St: curdled and soured from 36 to 48 when hand milking was carried \ i caring fur t lie milk 1 bring this condition the milking machine mine in what way ai in" quality &lt;&gt;f milk made, followed late results of these expe Practically all t after it is drawn fro Therefore we can nu by determining the number &lt;&gt;i I bacteriological fermentations an filth, and the number of bacteria indicates the conditions under i t animation it has received. In from which contamination can c utensils, and the milker. If the clean the air will soon become &gt;d( each particle carries myriads of IC and reproduction as soon as they find and hair of the cow offer a good lodging in the region of the thighs and udder, ai at the cow's slightest motion. An id* is found in the rough unsoldered seal strainers. Last hut not least the do hands especially, which often come in &lt; are sources of bacterial contamination ! les w (■( Han IH i; ixi 1.11 N( K &lt;t| THE MILKING M At HIM! I 1'oN TERIOUWJICAL CONDITION t •! MILK l From the Laboratories of Bacteriolu vereitv of Xe </seg>
            <seg id="p055">,vl k 1/ luring the pro. tllCS mtaminated in proportioD to ami in ii of the surroundings at tin- time the her hand, when milk is drawn direct lv ly chance of contamination would in Machine itself. This beta n in an almost sterile condition, provid - tlv clean and the surface of the odder when the teat cups are attached. To ption the writer has. under absolutely uch as a pint of sterile milk from the h remained sweet after Standing scaled. r more than two months. This was an e the box-stall in which the cow connected with the operation were Only the last part of the milk was taken from - drawn with a sterile milk-tube directly into With the milking machine and in the would lie entirely out of the question, n can lie e limi] naehiner would no ntamma nliness. Milkinjj n of the milk di lwii if they could lx&gt; to the cow without a thins; is impo Id I* 1 attach* Wl he l*niv« climes appeared to lie quite sanitary. l&gt;u; were found evervw th the milker did not cause aiiv he pulsator. rubber-tubing, connectors, and i problem. Tin parts wen the many places that could not The Ions; pieces of robber-tubing i' little time was consumed arn has been constructed with ce and is exceptionally free from liac- cptaclf. as i- the case when th&lt; finont while the stalk </seg>
            <seg id="p056">iron piping. The eeiliog and walls a summer the floor is washed down eat side during milking hours only. In are kept in over night a heavy beddii them. These conditions are far sun led. 1) most farms. The samples 1. I In- latest tvi machine-drawn milk were treat) that, altho the germ content n ficiency of the machine in sanit </seg>
            <seg id="p057">1 lie machines had recei 'com mended by the n. representative of the nilk from each of 1 I'thod-. The mlder and teats of eaeh ml in these samp* mi/in and hand-drawn i Number oi Method tit Mumber &lt;&gt;t ba 'xperimenl mflkma par e.e. i&gt;t milk n ■ Milk r 11 Ma II Ma II Ma II .1 •Ini i ilk drawn by machine with JI'.M hand-drawn milk there Vk; i\ &gt;y hand, it was found t&lt;- beyond that which i&gt; ults indicated that on the condition of the mill lplete series ot \v- XI. II milk from individ nth the ver\ &gt;y hand and three l&gt;y machine. «m1 milk of eight cows which lilking ami the fi hinr mil and much higher baei pf the thro*- sampl per r. c. (cubic i ten a sample of milk wm nilk from eight con uliiiiiii ut iiiacluin </seg>
            <seg id="p058">s ■ ual COWS as was dune m tl COWS, were used. ( &gt;iii machine, am 1 his nu't hod ffuardn up in cleanlm comparison. The mac him &lt; M a\\ er. T I ABLE M.I 11. I Marl I y Hi m M •arterial count showing imes the number inder i lie conditions •ctorv work. i third tcsi vening, April s. 190/, ty cit the milk drawn. Two </seg>
            <seg id="p059">1/ 1/ trial. In caring for thi the greatest care was exei ■ ruing it was rinsed, taken apart. olution, each part being given a The parts were then placed in limewater ley were rinsed with warm water before using. en they were rinsed with warm water before using. &lt;■ evening milking they were not taken apart hut washed by Iking they were not taken apart hut washed by e tubes, first tepid water, then hot water containing &gt;es. first tepid water, then hot water containing clear, hot water, after which they wen over ni«jlit. iter. after which thev were • /iiiixm itj hand ami nmchim iiiitknuj. Ma- IihikI and machine milking. Ma- tiiktii a i art and tack jMirt thoroly scnihbxl in tht nn apart and inch jxirt thoroh/ tcmkktd in tht gkt mil tak&lt; n apart hut tnmttd at in Tahlt XLII1. Method of Number of bacteria Parecataatf ht not takt n apart hut trtttUd as in TabU XLllI. Mt'tlllMt III' Number of bacteria IVr tent aeul Time mating par e.e. of milk after ni' milking I x-r e.c. nt milk after -laml- me n boon inc iWl li»urs P. M Machine IIITlMK) 1,7 Hand is*,; \ 1.7 \. M Machine M7260 s| Hand |s(HK) SI P. M Machine .'."(MiT 7v Hand 7KN&gt; \ 7n \ M Machine I&gt;7'&gt;&lt;N) cunllnl Hand 760 eunlleil Alien Heated in this manner the machines continued to affect Ik more than the comparison with hand-drawn ed. The samples in this experiment show a higher ntent than is usual, on account of the conditions under uit was made. It was necessary at this time to allow tlmost two hours to elapse bet ire— the time of sampling and plat- dS( mosphere in the barn was much warmer than when cding testa were made. The samples of machine-drawn </seg>
            <seg id="p060">and hand-drawn milk were treated identical! so that the comparison between then S( not influenced. There is no correlation between this t preceding ones, so the results are naral A further check upon the quality after they had stood for til) hi in the machine-drawn n rial count. During the fon Kitermine the iden rvation it seeine&lt; a preponderance showed the higl the numbers of a the following experiment but are the cau keeping properties. Bi ■li they arc developed, c *&gt; of certain digestive t ded as much as possible. \ In the next ex peri men Klize the machines. They wei ng. mouthpieces, and eonna morning. The parts were t ei evening milking. All metal parts wei the evening milking cold water, a sal water were in turn drawn thru the m merged in limewater over night. Tl treatment including the number of at lloueriers contained in the milk are iriveii ■ i in Ta XI. \ by determining the amount of aci&lt; i- Fahrenheit. With I esday morning, April Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p061">l ( onmtion howii in Kportionate an id-drawn mill 1/ 6] il much i in milking. Ma- il beamed for twi ned hi fhrei waters and litTll I'm I HTll \ M Machine ItilHM) llami I7i:«l NtM) M. M:i -liin*- 9200 •-HMI lllili.l 7IKMI l.VMI ;*2ou 247(1 M M.-i.-liinc I1.1HI as VMHt P. M M HlMI.I I !•."•() tIMI Machine H«tH 2071 1760 Hand '.is.'J JTivs obtained from five consecutive milkingo ii favor of machine-drawn milk when the is considered. In view of the fact that the .veil as the hand-drawn milk was strained nd the cows and was therefore exposed to air. these results arc undoubtedly as good ■ the conditions of the test. By carrying m liarn before emptying it and by using ion against contamination we could probably f bacteria in machine-drawn milk to the min - rae would 1k&gt; highly impracticable unless the illy arranged for the purpose. It was at first ng would injure the rubber tubing used with the ubing now in use at the Experiment Station has this treatment for more than a vear and is still The number of "acid producers" and "lique - colunms ti and 7 of the table appear to be fairly therefore need not Ix* regarded seriously. \ as a standard we can safelv conclude that with Nnnit i milk Acid- l.i&lt;|iiefyiii)r |ir(Hlu.iii)r </seg>
            <seg id="p062">given during this last test the &lt;| rted when drawn l&gt;y machine. The next step after having found for the machine. Accordingly tw taken. In the first the time of lx&gt;iling twenty to five minute water and washing powder solution thru it. \Y E experiment. Table X I. VI five minuter each im&lt; it water when not in us&lt; otherwise treatment similar to thi Tablt X \ Number of Date Time M«i inipiit Xi Oct. 17 I'M Ma 11:111 Machi Hand Marl Haii M Oct. IS A. M Machine 19101 Il.iii. I 5071 (let. IS P. M .MuchilK Hand 21730 Machine' I17."&gt;n llaml MIKI Machine 2968J Hand 1 4TJ7 H Oet. M A. M \M-r:itri- Averaft I' M A. M Machine 16380 Hand 17(1*1 Machine 427.')&lt;l Hand 12420 Average 17s It will I*' noticed that for this three-* drawn milk contained on an average twice a keeping the machines practically ste this method and if possible do away wit taken apart each day but wa of these modification ti.i. XL VI. 1 1 mi &lt;ij boiling ."&gt;l Oet. is A M ."&gt;."&gt; Oct. in I". M </seg>
            <seg id="p063">eparate average is made &lt;&gt;f the evening ve the r&lt; low some very different Hi; nut' very different figures In i\ ilk was drawn thru the inacliine after each bed, Ixiiled. and left in limewater. The the machine after A II tin boiled, and left in limewater. The jlitlv letw than in milk: drawn by hand under ilk drawn by hand under in in he morning's machine-drawn milk contained mine's machine-drawn milk contained any bacteria as the hand-drawn milk. We the hand-drawn milk. We ctena a mil the: e results thai the eare previous to the lilts thai the care previous to the ifficient. but before morning the parts of the ifficient. but before morning the parts of the ited enough bacteria to materially affect the ■i I enough bacteria to materially affect the i ilk. X1.Y1I »wi the results obtained when the inacliine After using the machine on the mornii was thoroly cleansed and boiled, after which until after the experiment closed three day-; wins thru three separate waters, lukewarm. la. and boiling water, and submerging in a only treatment given it. During this time the result litained when the machine machine on the morning of hoiolv cleansed and boiled, after which after the expert men 1 dosed three dayi iwing thru three separate waters, lukewarm. &gt;da. and boiling water, and submerging in a nilv treatment given it. During this time p bam over night. •a oj IkiiiiI mitl markim milkiitf. Mm - nitiis after each milking. Xo ft barn over nigh tin ad a (I much tut milking. \In- (irli milking. So fu 11 Xumlx'r l);i trria |&gt;it ■ • at milk NiiimImt I of milk 1 1&lt; Mrt iii .1 1 (it milking A rid- Total prcMlu -inir l.ii|iii'!'. l.l -Illlir lll.'IWI _' 11)11 IJim Hand 12800 ton lino Mctliixl &gt; ki A • 'lull l.l -liinc I020U _'l(l(l IJlHI Hand 12800 ton iuki M Machine 25130 1430 Hand 130 .'Mil I II Nil I M. Machine 25130 I i:«i 38130 Jsin I li Nil I M. Machine ")T.»7(» 15200 Hand l.'Tll s7(Ml \1 Machine 57270 I52U0 t-'Tn sTiwi .V«K( M Machine KhKKNI JiiTlK) Hand 70130 himki i h«, M. Machine i:{7:«H) 7:«hi Tmni Hand 9700 s(M) loo \ M. Machine 11:«mhi lutwi ."&gt;;ihi Minki 3900 2800 lifferenc* between the condition ol time, and in the morning after the i </seg>
            <seg id="p064">h I ■i had Ixt'ii inside over night; also the inatimi caused by not washing and li The bacteria in the marhim rapidly in numbers from milking to hand-drawn milk was low at night ai would indicate that there is bound t number of bacteria in morning's mi during the winter months whether t machine. The mistake made l&gt;v no is plainly shown here, as t he I rapidly when the machine v producing and liquefying bae total number in each experi the milk was not abnormally These experiment machine problem iron and clearly indicate tl more than ordinary &lt;■: ivelv at irregular interv Pday apparently hut a slight modi; from summer to winter conditions ch rially. The mornings machine-drav favorably with hand-drawn milk as \ It seems evident, then, that the macli boiled after each milking if a grade milk is to he obtained. The washii once a day was strenuously advocate one. except perhaps a few overzeal fact that the hand separator must 1m ie a most filthy source of cont thru it. Surely the hand separator milking machine nor does it offer a Ik bacteria. Sanitary milk, having a p obtained when the dairyman exereis in regard to sanitation and cleanlines most careful methods will l&gt;e indicate* ins &lt;!»' parts nt' the milkei </seg>
            <seg id="p065">M it an object when milk is the milkers can be modified to the most producer must remember that he is in this article which can not be placed on the ion on account of its poor keeping qual- iitu a first class grade of butter or d mi has been made of the relief filtc ho when neglected they are a continual Air rushes in thru these openings to re- each pulsation of the machine and unless tit will carry bacteria with it. This is onnector relief filters which are suspended Hoor while tlu machine is in operation. I hen- ahsoiU'iit cotton [. The use of these source entirely, as thev x peri men t a cit&lt; st before niilkin ion troiii tin ibing. lime has !&gt;eeii used in every trial on ■ properties and convenience. Other agi would have undoubtedly given better re - al properties would aid greatly in reducing . luit the use of a substance of this natu and could not l&gt;e recommended for l: ed for this bath should !«• rei If the antiseptic is to l&gt;e of any lieneht tin 1 in retarding bacterial growth it must he tubing. Often the operator e middle, and. leaving the ends pointing he bath. In consequence, air is in - md keeps the solution from reaching nt Station this trouble has been over - ing an inclined bottom on which the Kx \ position the liquid will naturally i lecause the air will lx&gt; driven out by it. Og the metal parts pure and sweet rreat advantage. Wherever it pentled upon more than anything H- lairv utensils. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">■1 .1 ■ „ VXSWKKi SIBMITTK1) in i&gt; why I hirteen milking p cultural hxperime &gt; i neae plants are owned by far ■uaiiu inc The proiif &lt;»|wi aim tmhiu-w n circular letter, roni | " MIM n &gt;ll(l I I1C US( the til &lt;.f the follow. i i Ki inn \ 1 1 1 »i a: rrui h [lrxlcr- tin ii | they ■|liesti«ni . The tx&gt;r being use*! t. thruout. r\\ hen was your pli 1. July. 1907. it . Uctoher. 1&lt;«I7. : April. 1&lt;M)7. them t.i lanlitat Ho ( i inc. The Fis under which 111 and the &lt;ir&lt;z !. September, I'.td, i. October, l'.HiT. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">\ .1 ■ except in cold weather engine &lt; &gt;1&lt; 1 style. M). All ilixed. Average. ilixed. Headed by Guernsey hull. 'umroon -tuck headed l&gt;v Ayrshire hull. *. i inilkiii}:? Breed? Average or se- 70. All kiniU. Average. Mixed. Avei i _'(). Shorthorn. Selected. ■Mi. Hobjtein-Frieaan. Mostly pure bred. Shorthorn and mixed. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">10. Holatein grades mostly. E. What feed do these animals « ■ Alfalfa hay and ; Corn, bran and &lt;■ Alfalfa an I&lt; irounu con Corn, t nan ; ai :v 111 Till v &lt; iiam mix &gt; Ml. Hi I-. II,. « Tin I V 1 \V(l 4. 1 8. 1-cn How many men employed with 1. Three to five. 2. One. 4 A. One. 4. Four. "). One and myself. (i. Man and hoy. 7. One beaidea myself. s. Two. 9. Two. One man handles thi and strips the cows. 0. One man for 2(1 head. &lt;i. \ 6. Twc 7. Tw« '.&gt;. Three 10. Three </seg>
            <seg id="p069">1/ milking machines ;ood as average isjh to tit the different sized cups f d after the machine.' It' so. Imw mueh milk ID to 1") per rent Hi to 1"&gt; per cent. •ally none. Cows thai do noi milk dry m as thai do not milk drv we sell. (\ iS \" :i&lt;&gt; quarts per milking from t&gt;»&gt; cows. \l"Hit 2N to :i&lt;&gt; quart* \t times tint much; »es not much; at other times quite a little. at other times quite a little. ws more than others. \s more than other M say about a cup to a cow. |)cd a few at first, l&gt;ut did not &lt;:et enough to pay. ■I a few at first, but &lt;1M not ir«*t enough to Verv little &gt;rv little from most of the cows; a tew. perhapt le from most of the cows; a tew. perhaps herd, are inclined to hold up their milk. of the herd, are inclined to hold up their milk. Yes. Nothing to speak of as a rule Ig In speak nt as a rule. •s a success under your conditions? ler your condition lecess un tin lied 1 think thev are better than poor milkers bey are better than poor milkers. Vi that I do not get as much milk by machine as \1 md hut can not say positively as 1 can not weigh from ne unless I milk onlv one cow at a time. When tabor is too high. Not prepared to saw 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">&lt; ( .1 people iii operate the ■ llU'tll iee&lt; wasning in use a per work H IllUIKl creamery /. Rather expensive for washing ami that is r, have nut given as mil positively lay it to the i &gt;. Keeping the teat-cups. Do not think the milker &gt;r: hail -W cows. Kb there ii ifter do not think anything imall herd. 10. \\ ere not last suiimu Injections. If I could have good tliem to machines. I fen ami in fitting teal _'. None. Mm '.i. No obiectioi A. MmithpitTi Pa|i]iiic&lt;i powh re iliink it will be o. Hard to keep t live steam. Ha (). \\ (' l)('llC\ climes smi| 1 1 me ny men wno dollars a month. I Sict men tu st liiuim the mac 1 1! s. I he success uf the machine man. Study your situatim "can't "; don't give up; and </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 1 think the machine w 'ho would do the v in tin- dairv. 1 Mv i&gt;l l'hev iln nut i living win ire lachine. Ik l.v haii.l • milking machine has been intro- lv. all i&gt;f the in tallationa cited ! i &gt;line eng i for furnish- illations cited hen March. 1907 ■d for furnish • main, satisfactory. In one ill In one dairv inr horse-power gasoline emiii ■line engine i t another, cold weather interfi he engine, while at a third, the engine is • ■ 1 • 1 while at a third, the engine is old ■Hi .-factory. With these exceptions the ftory. With these exceptions the led quite favorably a power for producing • favorably a power for produ plan! l&gt;ut i ci»n idered as being ill: idered as lieinjl to. v- thai the power i furnished by ■ ctory. l»ut the installation of installation of the gasoline engine i out ol w . I e ilairier \arie from HI to 70 hi not &lt;iiven. The breeding i- ; n oiii II) to Jl head lot riven. The breeding is mixed a herd of Holstein-Friesian rattle ■. a herd of Hoi leiii-1' lie: ian cattle atimeni towards dairy thorns. The sentiment towards dairv r,by the statements that pun bnd nents that pun the e 'ecoenized dairv breeds are ln-iii"; crossed on &lt;1 daily breeds are U'inj; crossed on he feetl used i not as good as might In- sed i not as good as might !&gt;&lt;■ une cases fed in a balanced ration. better than the feed the av&lt; fed in a balanced ration •ubtedly better than the feed the aver:ii;t ed to convert into milk. »nvert into milk. reported are operating two milkers ported are operating two milker ,\o are usintr four. In this las' </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 thus, only three plants arc using tn&lt; In three cases one man milks 'JO or Jn bead of cows alone. \\ 66 to 70 cows are milked, three to five men ami four i work. At one dairy a man and bov milk (id chines. ( &gt;ne man ham lit stripping i" a dairy where 31 When the question :i tte the machines is put. there opinion. Only two answers arc entirely others arc cither in the negative or place others are either in tli atiility as related to this particular w&lt; ability as related operator upon the results obtained is u operator upon the re question for consideration. All 1 mt two out Hi' the ten report i the milkers are removed, l&gt;ui rtion tor consider: All but two out 1 he milki taineil by stripping does noi ma I ! tained by stripping do The fact that some The fact that some cows hold up their strongly emphasized, one statement !&gt;&lt;■ Strongly emphasized milk out clean are eradicated i milk out clean are ei st rippt iijrs from t&gt;&lt;&gt; cows amount I day or 1 pound per eow each milkn To t he important question day or 1 pound per ( To the important question. your conditions'.'" four answer affirm a ictions. Three other reports a vour conditions'.'" four ai rtions. Three and of the right kind. They and of the right kind. They therefor* operators the all-important phase of the The objections offered arc numero operators the all-important phase The objections offered are n selves for the most part about three mi Ked. and the keeping of the milkers i •li correspondent {jives the difficultie his own conditions, so that the answers saved, and the keeping of the milker his own conditions, so that the answers will lx PYom the answers given it is apparei Sting with different degrees of succi men and farmers. The reports ai mit of a definite conclusion to fit all com may be expected of the machine milkei From the answers given it is apparent that t eeting with different degrees of succi dairymen and farmers. The report mit of a definite conclusion to fit all conditions, but thev show wl anil in the hands of different men </seg>
            <seg id="p073">II. tirst lactation apparently give letter results m do aged cows that have l&gt;een accustomed Alternate haml and machine methods of milking have a he milk flow Manipulation of the udder is absolutely necessary in e milk can he drawn !&gt;v the machine tting one machine can milk about the same hour as one man milking by hand. d in this test that only M) minutes was saved ing three machines in place of two wheii This saving of time would not balance the en the operator was using three machine ,vo machines in the hands of one operator in operating four machines can practically do the ilking bv hand. with two machines can milk IkM ween ten and and two operators with four machines about per ho 1 necessary to thoroly wash and l&gt;oil the milking r each usage, in order to produce milk with as tent as that resulting from careful methodl \\ • machines at irregular intervals or simply hem will increase the bacterial content of the urn operating the milkers must thoroly understand lanairement of dairy stock. He should also 1*&gt; j&gt;er - ttention to details in order to obtain the best results. From these studies it would appear that the milking ma- laree herds rather than small ones, and we l&gt;elieve ivould be impracticable to install them where fewer than thirty ■ milked the vear round. cc CONCLUSION ne or more years. •e not adapted to machine milking v work. lethods of hand milking. </seg>
            <seg id="p074"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>