<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>APPENDIX "C" QUESTIONS NEBRASKA UNIFORM EXAMINATIONS FOR Professional State and County Certificates, October 1905 to December 1906 Inclusive</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">QUESTIONS NEBRASKA UNIFORM EXAMINATIONS FOR Professional State and County Certificates October 1903 lo December 1906 Inclusive </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 NEBRASKA UNIFORM EXAMINATIONS FOR PROFESSIONAL STATE CERTIFICATES. December 15 and 16, 1905. CHEMISTRY PI. Work out a sum showing how much potassium iodide is uc«d from !••# grains of iodine. L Define and illustrate (a) chemical force, (b) chemical sym - , (c) chemical formula, (d) chemical equation. 3. Explain valence, showing its relation to the atom and to the molecule. Give an example. 4. Name the halogens. Why are they so grouped? L6. How are alloys and amalgams formed? Name some impor - t alloys. What metals are used in making them? 7. Distinguish between an acid and a base t8. Under what different circumst; j the atom of iron be lidered to exist bivalent, trivalent, and sextivalent activity? 11 - rate each. 9. Draw up a scheme for the analysis of a solution containing iron, barium, and potassium. 10. Give the process of manufacturing sulphuric acid, and nimi several of its commercial uses. GENERAL HISTORY 1. Discuss the Persian wars against the Greeks under the fol lowing heads: cause, comparison of antagonists, and result. i2. Had the Greeks or the Romans the greater genius for goy - ment? Discuss fully. 3. Give brief history of the life and work of Alexander the 4. Trace the cause which led to the fall of the Roman empire 6. What seems to you the best, and what the worst period of Roman history? Give reasons for answer. What were the Crusades, and what can you say of their lnflu- 7. What was the Great charter, and why is it Important? 8 Sketch the chief events in the life of Napoleon. 9 and 10. Tell in from two to four lines what you can of each of the following: Socrates, Charlemagne, Robespierre, Queen Elizabeth, Garibaldi, Mohammed, Raphael. Periel. • ■&gt;-, Joan of Arc, Chau - wr, Richelieu, Mary Queen of Scots, Peter the Great, Ferdinand, Togo, Solon, Luther, and Richard III. HNOi = • 114 (&gt;s =? (e) NaCl -t-Hj SU&lt; +MnOt =V Name the following: KU . SiO&lt; . Bl FQt , B NHj OH. OH </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 ENGLISH LITERATURE. Cl. Give a brief outline of tive in this drama? Macbeth." What is Shakespeare's 2. Who wrote "L'AHegro? What is the' theme of the poem? 3. Tell something of the life of Byron. How did it affect his works? 4. What is your favorite poem? Justify your choice. What was the character of American Literature in the lonial period? Name the "principal authors of this period. 16. Who wrote: — "The Newcomes" — "The Prairie" — "Endy - on" — "The Last Leaf" — "Conquest of Peru" — "Bracebridge Hall" "The Recessional" — Barbara Frietchie" — "Utopia" — "Tam O'Shan- ter?" 7. What is meant by poetic words? Illustrate. t8. Wherein lies the strength of the following extract? It is en from "Enoch Arden" at the place where Philip observes Enoch Annie. "Philip looked, Then as their faces grew together, groaned And slipped aside, and like a wounded life. Crept down into the hollows of the wood." ZOOLOGY. bl. What is a microtome? What power objectives are best for lnary laboratory work in Zoology? About how many times do y magnifj an object? §2. Tell what you can of the blood and its circulation in each the following named animals: clam, crayfish, earthworm, snake. 3. Discuss hibernation. 4. What is meant by animal instinct? How does it differ from intelligence? 5. What do you understand by evolution as commonly believed and taught by scientists? 6. Explain fully the life history of bugs and beetles, makiig clear points of difference. Describe the amoeba including such points as its structure, vements, size, food, habitat, etc. Explain the terms: embryology, protozoa, porifera, crin - , brachiopod. cephalopod. coleoptera. PLANE TRIGONOMETRY 1. The logarithm of the product of two numbers is equal to the sum of their logarithms. Prove. 2. Obtain the formula for finding the area of a triangle, given two sides b and c and the included angle A. Draw a figure and show thereon the following functions: e, co-sine, versed sign, conversed sine. 4 Prov6 that cos A esc tan \ — 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 15. Between 0 degrees and 360 degrees how many angles are ;re whose sines have the absolute value 3-5? Of these, how many ve positive and how many negative signs? 6. Explain the meaning of the expression vers-'y 7. A lighthouse was observed from a ship to bear N 34 degrees E and after the ship sailed due south 3 miles it bore N* 23 degrees E. Find the distance from the lighthouse to the ship in each posi - tion. Solve by formula. 8. Solve for x and y the system 19. How would you explain the meaning of logarithms to be - mers? Give the illustrations you would use. Define interpolation. ) Log 205 is 2.31175; what is log 20500? 20.5? .0205? 17 degrees, 1 minute is 9.4 • »Log sin 17 degrees. 2 minutes is 9.46676 Find log sin degrees. 1 minute, fi seconds. GEOLOGY. kl. Discuss the formation and movement of glaciers. If a glacier uld entirely disappear by ablation, what trace of its former exist - e would remain? What are the characteristics of glacial drift? Discuss the glacial drift deposits of Nebraska. 3. What are fossils and why are they valuable to the geologist? 4. How does lime stone originate. 5. Define aqueous, Igneous and metamorphic rock. 6. (a) What are the chief agents in weathering? (b) What r. ermines the number and size of the particles a stream can carry suspension ? 7. Discuss formation of a mountain chain 8. Define fault, crevasse, moraine, stalactite and conglomerate 9. How is a canyon formed? tlO- Name the chief characteristics of the following rocks: phlte, sand-stone, shale, gneiss and basalt. PHYSICAL GEOGRAPHY. 1. Compare young and old rivers. bi. Explain what occupations might result in a district at some ince from the ocean, well wooded, rough, swift rivers, temperate ate, some iron, no coal. Intelligent people. S. Explain all the ways in which mountains affect climate 4. What are continental shelves? Where are some of them? 6. Explain the cause, appearance, benefits, disadvantages of a ■in x + sin y = a. = 1). </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 6. What are mesas and buttes? How are they formed? 7. Explain the cause, kinds, and appearance of moraines 8. What are fiords? What causes them? 9. Explain artesian wells by a diagram. Are any found in Ne - braska. If so, where? 10. Explain how the Weather Bureau forecasts the weather. RHETORIC. 1. Name and describe four different forms of prose composition. What is a theme outline? What are the essentials of good outline? 3. Illustrate climax and anti-climax. 4. How secure unity, coherence, and emphasis in the para- graph? N'ame and discuss three or four qualities of good diction. i6. Define and illustrate metaphor. simile, metonymy, apos - phe and personification. 7. Scan the following lines and name meter: And eight years past, eight jousts had been and sti I Had Lancelot won the diamond of the year. With purpose to present them to the Queen When all were won; but meaning all at ou&lt; To snare her royal fancy with a boon Worth half her realm, had never spoken word. t8. Punctuate: Cambridge is the home of three famous wrl- Holmes who is known as the Autocrat Lowell whose quaint Yan - humor sparkles in the Bigelow Papers and the gentle author of ngeline our loved and lamented Longfellow. and 10. Write a two hundred word theme on some phase of ege athletics. PSYCHOLOGY. 1. What 4s reflex action? From what does it result? Of what advantage is it? 2. Define percept and give the conditions of perception 3. How may the imagination be cultivated in the right di- rections? 4. In what way does the child form his first concepts? L5. Of what importance to the teacher is a knowledge of the on of the feelings? L6. What are sentiments? How do they differ from the emo - s? 7. How do we know we have freedom of the will? 8. How can the moral nature be trained? 9. What Is the physiological explanation of habit? </seg>
            <seg id="p006">APRIL 5 AND 6, 1906. CHEMISTRY 1. (a) Explain by use of diagram the structure of the flame of a candle, or a gas jet, surrounded by air. (b) Where is the hot - tMrt part? (c) The reducing part? (d) The oxidizing part? 2. Ammonia — Its formula, weight of molecule in H atoms, sources, preparation, properties. 4. How much K will be required to make 2,000 gr. potassium chlorate? 5. Write on the allotropic forms of sulphur. 16. Write names and formulae for five sulphates. How test sulphates? Oin equ ISO,, II. HI+HjSO,, KOH ,O,. t8. Name good tests for usaale. Give formulae for two corn - ids of arsenic. k9. A dime is dissolved in nitric acid and a penny then im - ed in the solution. Describe the changes that have occurred write equations for them. 10. Give the source and properties of sodium potassium GENERAL HISTORY. PI . What contributions to modern civilization have been made ebrews, Greeks, and Romans, respectively? Give brief account of religion, arts and general culture of lent Egyptians. 3. Enumerate in order the chief events of Greek history, 4. (a) Contrast Athens and Sparta, (b) Discuss the develop - ment of the Athenian Constitution. 5. Discuss the Roman manner of gaining possession of terri - tory and governing it. 6. Give brief history of Punic Wars 7. Name four conquests of England and give brief account of each. Name five decisive battles in the world's history. By whom each fought and what hinged on the result? ». Discuss the French Revolution in about 150 words 10. Tell what you can in two lines, of each of the following: Mlrabeau, Pericles, Bismark, Demosthenes, Mazarin, Hannibal, Con - stantine. Henry VIII, Marie Antoinette and Solon. 13. Name N,O«, N,O,. N,O t , N,&lt;), Pb (C.H.O,),, H.fC.H.O.) C.O.. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 ZOOLOGY. 1. "Plants and Animals Distinguished." Discuss. 2. Give classification of animals and name a type of each class. 13. Write on the blood of animals, and in the comparison treat ecially the appearance and corpuscles of the blood of the different mal types you select. 4. Describe the spider as to reproduction, food, mouth parts, eyes, spinnerets, habits. Define paleontology, barnacle, cephalization, distoma. hemo - bin, sarcolemma, microtome, rhizopoda. 6-7. (a) Organisms tend to produce a great many more off - spring than can survive, (b) In spite of this tendency to increase Inordinately, the number of animals remains, on the whole, station - ary. Discuss at some length. 8. Give directions for preparing and mounting permanently sec - tions of animal tissue. 9-10. Discuss "Parasitism and Degeneration." TRIGONOMETRY. 1. Find x if sin x is equal to i the side of a regular inscribed decagon. 2 Prove: tan 2 A &lt;•(&gt;&gt;-' A-f-CCM* A = l. 13. Give formula for finding area of right triangle when a and are given. L4. Give the limiting if the fir with signs, in the r quadrants. Simplif. E7Q deffff &lt; 180 iegrei 1 tan- x 1+tan-' x tt. In a trapezoid, given the parallel sides a and b, the angles d y at the ends of one of the parallel sides; find the non-parallel 18. An equilateral triangle is inscribed in a circle whose radius y. Give method of finding area of triangle. 9. Define logarithm, co-log, anti-log, mantissa, characteristic, radian, natural sin, goniometry. LITERATURE. 1. What are some of the arguments Burke used in his "Con - ciliation with America?" 2. Who wrote Lycidas? What is its theme? 3. Why is Burns said to be a popular poet? Name some of his poems. L4. What are the essential differences between a tragedy and a edy? 5. Discuss th6 place of Chaucer in English Literature. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 «. Tell something of the life of one of the following: Dickens, Scott. Dryden, Shakespeare. 7. Isaiah prophesies the future state of Babylon, thus: "And thorns shall come up in her palaces, nettles and brambles in the forts thereof: And it shall be a habitation for dragons, and a court for owls." Explain the meaninp and the strength of the p 8. Who wrote: "Pilgrim's Progress." "As You Like It," "The Recessional," "The Excursion," "The Task," "The Last Days of Pompeii," "Enoch Arden," "The Lady of the Lake," "The Chambered Nautilus?" 9. Name five of the best American authors, naming also some of the works of each. Discuss the character of Brutus in "Julius Caesar." GEOLOGY 1. Discuss (1) the origin of stratified, and (2) the origin of Igneous rock. By what means may a given geological formation be iden - tified? ?,. Name the geological periods in order. 4. What can you say of the mineral resources of Nebraska? 5. Describe the glacial deposits of Nebraska. 6. Define: Loess, detritus, moraine* fossil and geode. 7. Give distinctive characteristics of gneiss, calcite, feldspar, asbestos and gypsum. 8. Discuss the origin of volcanoes. 9-1 it. Discuss the antiquity of man as revealed by the study of geology. PHYSICAL GEOGRAPHY. 1. By what processes is the face of the land changed? Explain 2. Explain the formation of a delta. 3. How may caves be caused? Explain 4. Tell what you can of the Grand Canon of the Colorado 6. Discuss the climate of Nebraska. 6. Give condition, surface, and material of the sea floor. 7. Disruss the principal ocean currents, and their effects. 8. What causes the amount of heat received by the earth from rsun to vary periodically, and what are the results? 9. Name the principal river systems of North and South America. 110. What are the products of Maine? Explain the causes lead to these products. PSYCHOLOGY 1. Distinguish between physiological and empirical psychology 2. What Is the function of the cerebellum? The medulla </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 13. What affects the intensity of attention? How may attention affected from without? How awakened? 4. What are illusions? Give examples. 5. How is representation connected with reading? 6. Give some suggestions for improving the memo 7. Define and discuss judgment and judgments. 8. Distinguish between inductive and deductive reasoning. 9. Define temperament. Discuss the old division into four temperaments. 10. Discuss habit. RHETORIC 1. Distinguish between narration and description. 2. How may unity, coherence, and emphasis be secured in the theme? t Distinguish between loose, periodic, and balanced sentences, give an example of each. 4. What are the essential features of a good story? 5. Define the following terms: Euphony, synonym, homonym, idiom and colloquialism. C. What is the difference between poetry and prose? 7. Write a letter to a superintendent of schools applying for a position. State education and experience, and give references. I. Name and illustrate five figures of speech. 9-1'". Write a review of some book you have read. JITXE l.~&gt; AND 16, 1906. CHEMISTRY. 1. How much lead nitrate is required to make ten pounds of load sulphate? 2. Discuss the allotropic forms of carbon. 3. Complete equations for: Copper plus nitric acid; Sodium chloride plus sulphuric acid; Iron sulphate plus hydrogen sulphate; Arsenious oxide plus hydrochloric acid. 4. Explain the endings ic, ous, ate, ite. L5. Sulphuric acid: Discuss its properties, occurrence, prepara - for commercial purposes. us&gt; Five liters of Co, weigh 9. 9 jr. Find the vapor density of CO,. ify results from the molecular weight. 8. What colors do Na, Sr, Ca, Ba, Cu, K, Pb. As, Sb impart to a flame? How test for iron in a solution? 17. Name K, Cr, O T , HNa, PO,.PbSiO, I &gt;,. Pb(C t O, )„ NaH(C\ H, O. ), K, C, O 4 . </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 GENERAL HISTORY. 1. Name the civilized countries which existed prior to 776 B. C. What wag the chief work or leading characteristic of each? 2. Name three great "world empires" in the order of their suc - cession. What did each include? 3. What characterized Greek political history? Illustrate from the Peloponnesian war. tt. Of what value was Roman dominion to the countries gov - ed? Of what advantage was the empire to the spread of Chris - lity? 5. Name five Greek and five corresponding Roman gods 6. Give date, purpose, leaders and results of the Crusades. kT. Where and by whom was Mohammedanism founded? Through t countries did it spread? Compare its doctrines and practices those of Christianity. 8. Give a brief history of the Wars of the Roses 9-10. Tell what you can in about two lines of each of the fol - lowing: Socrates, the Gracchi, Catiline, Rousseau, Homer, Hannibal, Miltiades, Charlemagne, Raphael, Joan of Arc, Peter the Great, Pom - pey, Pericles, Romulus, William the Conqueror, Marie Antoinette, Marat, Demosthenes. Xerxes, and Philip. ZOOLOGY 1-2. Give a comparative description of the digestive system of the amoeba, jellyfish, insect, bird, sheep. 3. Describe the crayfish as to its circulatory system, nervous system, and special senses. 4. Explain the terms: Spontaneous generation, parasitism, erhinodermata, sarcolemma, metamorphosis. 5. Give the life history of the house-fly Give directions for staining tissue for microscopic mounts at are the stains used commonly? t" . Describe the ordinary compound microscope. What power ctives are best for ordinary laboratory work? What directions the use and care of a microscope would you give to a beginner? 8-9. Discuss the survival of the fittest" as it is applied to ani - mal life. 10. Instinct and reason. Discuss. TRIGONOMETRY. 1. In a right triangle, jjiven the hypotenuse &lt;•. and also sin A=m. cosA=n: find the k 2. Compute the value of this expression: (a* Jab sin '2~*&gt; dt . 3. Find cos 3x in terms of cos x. 4. Prove: </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 15. Given one side of a triangle equal to 27, the adjacent angles ual each to 30 degrees. Find the radius of the circumscribed cir - i. Solve by formula. t6. Wishing to know the breadth of a river from A to B, I take , 100 yds. in the prolongation of BA, and then take CD, 200 yds. right angles to AC. The angle BDA is 37 degrees, 18 minutes, SO onds. Find AB. Solve by formula. 7. Log sin 35 degrees, 20 minutes is 9.76218. Log sin 35 degrees, 21 minutes is 9.76236. 8. What functions of an angle of a triangle determine the angle and what functions fail to do so? ■ 10. Obtain a formula for the area of a parallelogram in terms two adjacent sides and the included angle. LITERATURE. 1. State briefly the plot of 'Julius Caesar 2. Who were the principal characters in "Ivanhoe? 3. What is the poet's message in "Sir Launfal?" L4. What are efrects? Why do authors use them? Give exam of two kinds of effe&lt; io. Name your favorite poet. Give a quotation from his writings, y is he your favorite? 16. What period in English Literature is known as the "Eliza - lian period?" Who were the prominent writers of this period? e the title of the masterpiece of each. 7. In what department of literature did Macaulay excel? Her - bert Spencer? Milton? Webster? Longfellow? 8. Who wrote "The Faerie Queen?" "King Lear?" "Pilgrim's Progress?" "Essay on Man?" "She Stoops to Conquer?" "The. Ancient Mariner?" "Pickwick Papers?" "Thanatopsis?" "Pendennis?" "The Raven?" 9-10. Write a review of some book that you have read recently. GEOLOGY 1. Explain clearly the process by which sedimentary rocks arc formed. 2. Distinguish between igneous and metamorphic rocks. 3. What are the chief agents in the work of erosion? 4. What are fossils? Of what value are they to the geologist? 5. Explain the cause of springs and illustrate by a drawing. 6. Give the distinctive characteristics of gneiss, feldspar, asbes- tos, gypsum and calcite. 7. Define the following terms: Fault, stalactite, stalagmite. 8. Discuss the formation and movement of glaciers. 9. What are some of the theories of the causes of earthquakes? 10. Is Nebraska an interesting field for the geologist? Discuss. Find log sin 35 degrees, 20 minutes, 48 seconds, 0. 1'rove cos Jx= lin 1 x. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 PHYSICAL. GEOGRAPHY 1. Give an explanation of earthquakes. 2. How does the shape of a river valley change with age? Describe the character of the river and bordering country T-.etiT the mouth of the Mississippi. K4. ' e main river systems of Africa? Why are they What changes occur in ■&lt; ■? How does the appear - ance of a coast indicate its history? What parts of the Inited States are affected by the ice of glacial period? What evidences still remain of that period? BWhat cause* the dry climate of Utah? What is the climate southern Alaska? What causes it to be so? 8. Tell what you can of the storms of the I'nited States. 19. Explain the phenomenon of rain. What is the average rain- I of the locality in which you live? How is rainfall measured? 10. Define moraine, flood plain, talus, drumlin, and butte RHETORIC. 1. What is rhetoric? Is it an art or a science? Name four forms of prose composition and distinguish be - tween them. L3. Define and illustrate the loose, the periodic and the balanced tence. 4. Distinguish between an idiom and a colloquialism. Illus t^ate each. 5. Define and illustrate climax and anti-climax. 6. Name three or four essentials of a good sentence. How may each be secured? 7. Give rules for the correct use of shall and will. ». Write a letter to a publishing company ordering a book. *-!•. Write a review of some good book you have read. HOLOGY. f Explain how psychology may be studied experimentally. What do you know about the spinal nerves? L3. How do sensations differ from knowledge? What connec - ts there between the two? 4. Explain what is meant by the "threshold of consciousness." 5. How Is our imagination of another world affected by the things of this world? 6. How are artificial appetites produced? How do they differ i'om natural appetites? 7. What reflex influence has conduct on the mind? Explain 8. Is there any such thing as freedom of the will? Give reasons for your belief. 9. What do you believe to be the source of the idea of right •nd wrong? 10. What is the difference between instinct and reason? </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Jl'LY 23 AND 24. 1906. CHEMISTRY. 11-2. Hydrogen: Occurrence, preparation, properties both phys - and chemical, oxy-hydrogen flame, occlusion tests, uses. t3. At 70c per ounce what is the value of the silver in one-fourth nd of silver nitrate? 14-5. Dissolve a piece of silver in nitric acid. Write equation, at are the fumes? Put a penny into the liquid in which the silver been dissolved. Write equation. Describe result!. S. What is a radical? What is electrolysis? 7. Write names for the following: L8. Explain efflorescence and dellques. &lt;i give an ll lustra of each. 9. Explain the manufacture of quicklime, giving all equations, 10. How is acetylene obtained? Give equation. How is wood alcohol obtained? Give its symbol. How is ethyl alcohol obtained? Give its symbol GENERAL HISTORY. 1. What right have the Egyptians to be called civilized? 2. Sketch briefly the chief events in the life of Alexander the Great 3. What was the cause and what th« result of the Persian wars? t4. Contrast the Roman citizen of early Republican times with Roman citizen of the Post-Punic period. U'hat seems to you the best period of Roman history? What worst? Discuss. »',. What was the character of Roman rule in the provinces? 7. Describe the Teutonic barbarism of 476 B. C. as to persona) characteristics, government, and mode of living. 8. When, by whom, and under what circumstances was the Great Charter granted? What are its chief provisions? 19-10. Who or what is each of the following: Parthenon, Acropo- Bastile. Renaissance, Koran, Charlemagne, Richelieu, Plutarch, athon, Raphael, Aristotle, Sulla, Solon, Robespierre, Lycurgus, nibal. Homer, Socrates, Cicero, and Li TRIGONOMETRY. 1. Give characteristics &lt;&gt;f 65430, | 6543. .06543. .006543 Explain the terms mantissa, logarithm, versed sine, co-loga - m, interpolation, goniometry. natural sine. 3. As an acute angle increases, its sine, tangent, and secant also' increase. whil&lt; ant decrease. Explain Na.PO,, Pe(OH),. H,n&gt;,. H 3 As&lt;) 3 . HBiO,, KBrO, KBrO, KMit),, (^.(PO,),, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 4. Find the angles of a right triangle if the hypotenuse is equal to three times one of the legs. 6. Find area of regular pentagon if its diagonals are each equal to 12. t Express in terms of the functions of angles less than 45 de - »: sin 204 degrees, cot 139 degrees 17 min., cot — 52 degree* miii 8. Prove the formula: 2 tan z 9. In a triangle one angle equals 139 degrees 54 min., and the sides forming the angle hare :fce ratio 5 : 9. Find the other two angles. Id. In a unit circle what is the length of the chord correspond - ing to the angle of 45 degrees at the center? te: Solve by formula all problems requiring the use of logs. ) ZOOLOGY. 1. The adaptations among animals for self defense. Discuss. 2. Instinct and intelligence. Discuss. 13. What do you understand by (a) genus, (b) species, (c) fam , (d) order, (e) kingdom. L4. Describe the external features and internal anatomy of the ey bee or the earthworm. Use drawings. 5. Hibernation of insects and animals of higher classes. Discuss 6. What, in brief, is the modern theory of evolution? Name two or three men whose names are associated with the theory of evolution. 7. Tell briefly how to make both temporary and permanent mi - croscopic mounts of muscle, bone, and blood tissues. 8. Describe the special sense organs in each of the following amoeba, house-fly, fish, robin, frog. ENGLISH LITERATURE. 1. Deflm- and illustrate the use of types 1. What information concerning thie character of the Scotch people is given to the reader in the lines, "And they stood longest In the kirkyard when the north wind blew across a hundred miles of snow." What is I of the strength of the sentence? 3. Describe the character of Lady Macbeth. 4. What is the story of the Vicar of Wakefleld? Who wrote "The Faerie Queen," "The Excursion," "Annabel ,' "The Spy." "Maud Muller?" 6. Name lh- tant work of Milton, Hawthorne, Chau - cer, Dickens, Irving. 16. Find value of "a sin 0 degrees + b cos 90 degrees — c tan 0 deg." Bin 2x = • 1 + tanJ x </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 7. What is the place Longfellow holds in American literature? 8. Who were the important poets of the Revolutionary period in American history? What did each write? 9-10. Write a review of one of the following: Ancient Mariner, Silas Marner, Ivanhoe, Merchant of Venice, The Princess, Evangellne. GEOLOGY. 1. Name the geological ages. What organisms characterize each? 2. Discuss the origin of coal. i3. Describe the formation of a coral island. What conditions or coral growth? 4. Into what three general classes may rocks be divided? De - scribe each class briefly but clearly. 5. Define tlve terms breccia, geode, and conglomerate. What is the cause of the columnar structure sometimes ex ited by eruptive rocks? 7. What is a geyser? How may geyser eruption be accounted for? 18. What agencies are now at work modifying the structure of earth? 9. Name the distinctive characteristics of limestone, sandstone, clay and granite. 10. What mineral deposits occur in Nebraska? PHYSICAL GEOGRAPHY 11. Explain the ways in which a river works on land through ich it passes. 2. Explain the formation of a delta 13. Describe the appearance of an old mountain chain; of a new untaln chain. 4. What is a dune? Explain the movement of dunes. Are there *ny in Nebraska? Where? 5. Describe the effect of a glacier on a country Name and describe very briefly the physical districts of the ted States. L7. In what ways do mountains affect climate? Illustrate by in - ces. 8. Describe briefly some recent volcanic eruption and the vol- cano. 9. Describe and explain the trade winds. 10. In your opinion, what ocean current affects man the most? Give your reasons. RHETORIC 1. How may unity, emphasis, and coherence be secured in the paragraph? 2. What is a topic sentence? Illustrate. 3. What is a theme? What steps are necessary in the prepara - tion of a theme? </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 4. Ubb the following words correctly in sentences: avow, con - fess, admit, and a :c«. Explain the terms: euphemism, synonym, homonym, sole - cism, and caricature. 6. Name five figures of speech and illustrate each 7. What are the essentials of a good novel? B. What cautions should be observed in the choice of words? 9-10. Write a theme of 3&lt;io or 400 words on some topic sug - gested by the recent San Francisco disaster. HOLOGY. 1. Wliat are the functions of the cerebellum? 2. What is attention? Dpoa what does the degree of attention depend? 3. What is the difference between perception and conception? A percept and a concept? 4. What is an illusion? Illustrate. 5. What is imagination? Of what use is it In learning? 6. Of what value are rhymes and other devices to assist the KWhat are intuitive truths? What things are characteris - of th- S. What is tt . tion between the feelings and morals? 9. What an Mments? How may they be classified? 10. What do you think the conscience is? What Is its nature? CHEMISTRY 1. Define va able valence, radical, equation, isomerism. 2. Explain these terms: precipitate, metal, base, acid, salt. 3. State Avogadro's "Law of Gases." (b) How many elements are now known? Name a newly discovered one. iThe halogens la) Name them; (b) Occurrence; (c) Prep - tlon; (d) Properties; (e) Uses. 6. What is an alloy? An amalgam? B Aluminum: (a) Occurrence; (b) Reduction; (c) Prop&lt; ) Two compounds. 18. Describe briefly, the marsh gas, olefiant, and acetylene series hydrocarbons. Write symbols for the following: chloric acid, sodium chlo - , sodium perchlorate, potassium dichromate, lead acetate. AICI ST 17 AND 18, 1906 Write equations for: KeS+Ht 1=V and Cu+H»SO«— ? </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 GENERAL HISTORY. 1. Give a brief sketch of the Peloponnesian War. 2. What are the Iliad, the Odyssey and the Aeneid? LI. Enumerate and discuss briefly the causes which led to the ol Rome. L4 Of what value was Roman dominion to th« countries gov - ed? 15. Discuss briefly the influence of the Church during the Mid- Ages. L6. What general movements characterize the period known as Dark Ages? L7. Make a brief comparison of the governments of the United tea and England. 8. Trace the chief events in the life of Napoleon Bonaparte 9. Locate the following places: Memphis, Tyre, Carthage, Babylon, Nineveh. Troy, Jerusalem, Corinth, Mecca and Sidon. 10. What events are suggested by the following dates: 1215, 1066, 1785, 1789, 1492, 476, 1688, 1815, 1898 and 1783? ENGLISH LITERATURE. rl. What was Chaucer's influenoa upon English Literature? What when did he write? 2. Tell briefly the story of the life of Francis Bacon. Who wrote "Alexander's Feast," "The Faerie Queen," "Much About Nothing," "In Memoriam," "The Excursion?'' 4. Write not to exceed a page about Edgar Allen Poe. 5. Name one of the principal works of Joseph Rodman Drake, Bryant, Bancroft, Lowell, Celia Thaxter. 6. What is a type? Give two examples of the use of type*. 7. What is the lesson of "The Ancient Mariner?" g. What is the character of the father in the "Vicar of Wake- lield?" 9-10. Write a review not over two pages in length of "Julius Cat-siir. ZOOLOGY LI. Describe the external features and the internal anatomy of tapeworm. Give its life history. I Name and describe as to their characteristic features, a e animal of each of the following branches: protozoa, porifera, lenterata, echinodermata, annulata. 4-5. Describe epithelial, connective, cartilaginous, osseous, den - tal, adipose, and nervous tissues. bf,. Write on the comparative size, shape, color, structure, of the 1 corpuscles of these animals: man, camel, deer, pigeon, snake, proteus. lOapa </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 P Write a few lines about each of the following named men John Lubbock, Louis Agassiz. David Starr Jordan. t8. What is meant by "life cycle?" Mention the important nges in the life cycle of the fly and frog. As a rule, which have the ger lives, small or large animals? Crickets in Mammoth Cave have only rudimentary eyes, and primitive bird louse had wings. Explain. tlO. Give directions for the preparation of permanent microsco - mounts of blood, (b) Explain the terms: microtome, micrometer, ome, diaphragm in a microscope, "tease" in laboratory language. TRIGONOMETRY 1. Show by construction that 2 Sin A is greater than Sin 2 A - 2. If sin A = %■ what values have the other functions? S. How would you explain to a class the meaning and use of logarithms? 4. Give the algebraic signs of the functions in each quadrant. L5. Given tan x = the square root of 3 ; find sin x when x is an le in quadrant III. 6. Compute the value of: (»»— b») -ah sin 21 7. Prov« that b sin B 8. A pole is fixed on the top of a mound, and the angles of ele - ction of the top and the bottom of the pole are 60 degrees and 30 de - gree*. Prove that the length of the pole is twice the height of the mound. Solve by formula. 9. If the side of an equilateral triangle is "a'' prove its area to be PHYSICAL GEOGRAPHY. 1. What is the origin of the earth's shape? What is its shape and size? What are doldrums? What causes them? Where are they found? 3. Tell what you know of the ice found in the ocean ■ 4. Name all the agencies you know of that affect the surface the land. Describe with drawings the action of a river in making and widening a canon. BC. Describe, explain and illustrate the influence of mountains clima'.- other than because of altitude. T. Name and describe some famous volcano . It six A — sin 2 A. find A </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 8. How does soil form in a rocky country? What Is a talus? 9. What are bad lands? What causes them? Where is such district? L10. What was the glacial period? Did it affect Nebraska? What e» were left? GEOLOGY II. Define the terms conformable and unconformable as applied a series of strata. 2. Explain clearly the process by which sedimentary rocks are formed. LI. Name the geological eras in their order. What organisms? racterize each. 4. Explain the process of petrifaction. 5. How is a geologist enabled to determine the period to which » given rock belongs? 6. What are the chief features of the Carboniferous Age? Give a concise general description of a glacier and discuss fly the laws of glacial motion. 8. Define the terms dike, fault, moraine, delta and fissure. 9. What are Metamorphic rocks? 10. Describe the Bad Lands of Nebraska PSYCHOLOGY. 1. What is meant by New Psychology? KHow many nervous systems are there in man? What are principal organs in each? 3. Define attention. What is its importance? 4. What is meant by the term "summit of consciousness." 5. What is the aesthetic imagination? the scientific imagination? 6. How early in life does thinking begin? Illustrate. 7. What is a fallacy? Illustrate. 8. Does instinct appear in man? Illustrate. 9. How does Putnam classify the sentiments? What is the characteristic of each class? Analyze an act of willing into its four elements. RHETORIC. 1. Point out and name one figure of speech in each of the fol - lowing sentences: (a) He doth bestride the narrow world like a Colossus. (b) Sleep, gentle sleep, Nature's soft nurse, how have I frighted the*-" (c) The crescent in Europe is waning before the cross. (d) Grace is said before meat. His hands dangled a mile out of his sin </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 (g) And twice the Saxon blade drank blood 1(h) The hooded clouds, like friars, tell their beads in drops rain. I&lt; i ) Her hair drooped round her pallid cheeks likje seaweed on clam. Ij) Freedom shrieked when Kosciusko fell. 2. Distinguish between description and narration 3. Illustrate climax and anti-climax. 4. Define allegory, fable and parable. 5. Write a topic sentence and develop it into a paragraph. 6. Distinguish between the loose and the periodic sentence and give an example of each. How may emphasis be secured in the paragraph? I. What are the essentials of a good outline? »-10. Write a review of some good book. DECEMBER 21 AND 22, 1906. CHEMISTRY El. Explain by use of diagram the structure of the blowpipe ie. Which part of the flame is hottest? Which part is used for uctions? Which part is used for oxidation? 2. The volume of a gas varies inversely with the pressure up - on It. Discuss. L3. What is the source of ammonia, carbon dioxide, oxygen in air? 4. Write symbols for: ammonium nitrate, nitrogen tetroxide, potassium nitrite, hydrogen sulphate, hydrogen acetate. t5. Describe the manufacture of quick-lime. Give reactions, t product results when quick-lime is left exposed to moist Equation. 6. Explain the process of silver plating by means of electricity. 7. Give commercial uses of nitric acid, sulphuric acid, ammon- 8. Explain the chemistry of the burning match. Give equations 9. How test a solution for iron? Give an arsenic test 10. What colors will Na, Sr, Ca, Ba, K, Pb, As, 8b, impart to a flame? GENERAL HISTORY PL What contributions have been made to our civilization by Phoenicians? Of what value were they to the world of their times? 2. What are the Ilald and the Odssey? Of what value are they to the historian? IS. Name six or eight Greek gods and goddesses. What did each trol? 4. Give brief history of the Punic wan </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 r5. What do you consider the best and what the worst period Roman history? 6. Do you justify the term "Dark Ages" as applied to mediaeval history? 7. Discuss the life and character of Oliver Cromwell. 8. WTiat was the war of the Roses? 19. What do the following dates suggest to you: 1066. 1215, 15, 1492, and 476? 110. Why are the following battles important: Hastings, Mara - n. Tours, Waterloo, and the fight between the English and the nish Armada? LITERATl'RE. 11. Give the name and works of some author that belongs to time of Chaucer. 12. What period in English Literature followed the overthrow the Commonwealth? Who were the principal writers of this iod? L3. Name one of the principal works of Burns, Thomas Gray, uel Johnson, Addison, Thackeray. L4. Write not to exceed a page about Henry Wadsworth Long - ow. t5. Who wrote the "Barefoot Boy", "The Rise of the Dutch ublic". "Thanatopis", "The Conquest of Peru", "Representative ?" 6. What are effects? Why do authors use them? How may they be classified? K7. Who is the leper in "Sir Launfal? ' What does toe teach Launfal? 18. What is the character of the Templar in "Ivanhoe?" Of Jewess? 19-10. Write a review, not over two pages in length, of Macau - 's Life of Johnson. ZOOLOGY. 11. Give a clear description of the primitive animal cell, in - ing its composition and structure, method of division, and the esses it performs. 2. The sponge — Structure, life, food, organs, reproduction. 3. Discuss the life cycle of the mosquito. 4-5. Some forms of adaptations are (a) food securing, (b) self protection, (c) defense of young. Discuss. 6. Discuss "likeness" and "variation" in offspring. 7. Name five books on Zoology which are commonly accepted by scientists as authority on the subject. Discuss briefly the relation of bacteria to disease. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TRIGONOMETRY. 1. Explain these terms: radian, trigonometric function, logari - thm, goniometry, co-ordinates of a point in a plane. 2. Write the versed sine of A. Write the coversed sine of A. 3. Construct right triangle, given c = 6, tan A = 3-2. 4. Given two angles A and B, A and B being less than 90 de- r&gt;. i' 6. Given sin A = %• Find the other functions. 7. In a right triangle given c, and A = nB: find a and b. 8. How many angles less than 360 degrees have the value of rsine equal to + five sevenths and in what quadrants do they lie? 9. Prove: Sin (x+y) = sin x cos y + cos x sin y. 10. The sides of a triangle are 14, 16, 18 respectively. Find length of the perpendicular from the vertex of the largest angle upon opposite side. Solve by formula. PHYSICAL GEOGRAPHY tl. How is the weight of the atmosphere measured? Explain principle of the instrument. 2. What are monsoons? Where found? What causes them? 3. What do we know of the bottom of the ocean? 4. What part of the world has the most distinctive fauna? runt for the fact and name some of the peculiar species. 5. What are glaciers? Describe their cause, movement and 6. Discuss the distribution of volcanoes, giving the probable leasons. LT. What are geysers? What causes them? Where are they nd? How are deltas formed? Describe the delta of the Missis- sippi. Describe the probable cause of the California earthquake GEOLOGY. rl. By what agencies is the structure of the earth being tnodl - at the present time? 2. What determines the erosive power of a river? 3. Discuss the laws of glacier niotVn. 4. How are springs formed? Illusm '&lt; by a drawing. 5. How may volcanic eruptions be explained? 6. Into what three classes may stratified rocks be divided? What are the general characteristics of each claw? greee: show that sin (A + B) is less than sin A+sln B </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 7. What are fossils? Discuss their value to the geologist. 8. Explain the process of petrifaction. 19. What evidences of the former existence of glaciers are found Nebraska? 10. Name the geologic ages into which the history of the earth n.ay be divided. PSYCHOLOGY. 1. What do you understand by the term consciousness? 2. Describe the divisions of the cerebrum. 3. Discuss the kinds of attention. i4. Does sensation increase in direct proportion to stimulus? If , what is the relation • between the two? 5. What are the representative powers? What is their function? 6. What is thinking? What steps are involved in thinking? 7. Discuss intuitive truths. 8. What do you understand by temperament? 9. What are sentiments? What Is their relation to reason? 110. What is the strongest evidence we have of the freedom of will? RHETORIC 1. How may emphasis be secured in the paragraph? 2. What is a topic sentence? Illustrate. 3. Distinguish between description, narration and exposition. 4. What is the difference between tragedy and comedy? 5. Define rhyme and rhythm. 6. How does a metaphor differ from a simile. 7. What Is a syllogism? Give examples. 8. Distinguish between epic, lyric and dramatic poetry. 9 &amp; li&gt;. Write a review of some book you have read. rRASEA UNIFORM EXAMINATIONS FOB COUNTY (KRTIFICATI OCTOBER 20 AND 21, 1905 MENTAL ARITHMETIC. (Give complete written analysis of the following problems.) 1. Five times 2-17 of a number is 14 less than the number. What is the number? 12. A is 25 years old and B is 4 years old. In how many years A be 4 times as old as B? 3. The sum of eight numbers is 95 and the sum of seven of them 87. What is the eighth number? 4. A can do a certain piece of work in 6 days, and B in 12 days. In what time can A and B together do the work? </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 5. A boy bad 76 cents. He bought 3 dozen oranges, and had 3 cents left. What did he pay for the oranges apiece? Rapid Computation I Write only the answers to the following problems, numbering answers to correspond with the numbers of the problems. Time wed 16 minutes. (50 credits.) 2. How many times is 6X8X4X3 contained in 48 X 36? t3. A and B agree to do piece of work for $15. A can do the k in 8 days, and B can do it alone in 12 days. What should i receive? L4. If a merchant sells \ of an article for what % of it cost what is his gain, in per cent? 5. If Henry lose 2-7 of his money and spend 2-5 of the remain - what part of the original is left? PENMANSHIP 1. Give some devices for securing interest in writing 2. At what time of day would you give the writing lesson? 3. Which of the systems of penmanship do you teach? Give rations. K4. As a specimen of your penmanship, write a stanza of poetry not less than four lines. (20 credits.) 5. Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown by all examination papers submitted. CIVIL GOVERNMENT 1. What is government? Why is it necessary? 2. What is meant by arbitration? What is meant by appeal? Distinguish between direct and indirect taxation. Give ex - amples of each. 4. How may new states be admitted into the Union? 5. To whom are pensions paid? Why are they paid? What is a writ of habeas corpus? When may it be sus - ded, and by whom? 7. Give the qualifications for president 8. What is a revenue bill, and where does it originate? 9. Give the duties of the county judge, county superintendent and the county attorney. 10. Give the important provisions of the law relative to com - pulsory attendance of pupils at the public schools of Nebraska. ORTHOGRAPHY redits for spelling as shown by papers in other subjects.) 1. Divide into syllables, indicate the accent and mark diacriti - cal ly the following words: creditable, mountain, nuisance, docile, separate (10 credits.) 1. (5X3 + 4X7 — 1)h-(7 + 6 — 10.) </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Copy each of the following sentences, using the correct word selected from the words in the parentheses. (a) A (vale, vail, veil) of mist enveloped the mountain. (b) Nearly (all, awl) the men able to (bare, bear) arms had (bin, been) (draft, draught )ed into service. The women were weeping and (wringing, ringing) (their, there) hands. (d) Members of the cat tribe (clime, climb) by means of their • clause, claws). (e) A (horde, hoard) of savages rushed through the (breech, breach) into the (forte, fort). (f) (Feint, faint) (heart, hart) ne'er (one, won) (fair, fare) E(g) His (style, stile) in (right, rite, wright, write)ing was sed, chaste). K(h) The (medal, meddle) bore an (ingenuous, ingenious) (de - . devise). ■ (i) Solomon (accepted, excepted) rich (presence, presents) from Queen of Sh.eba. ■ (j) The cause invariably (precedes, proceeds) the (affect, effect I credits). In the following list some words are spelled correctly, and incorrectly. Rewrite, spelling all words correctly. (25 credits) affiliate rarify murmer paralel tenant recommend manyfold indefensable occulist icycle abhored onion supersede accelerated gorgeous committy catastrophy cavalier civillian chrystalizr theif alledged amature poultice •bycicle BOOKKEEPING. 1. Define personal account, property account. 2. What is commercial paper? 3. Write a negotiable note. ■ 4. Name four ledger accounts that will show losses and gains, four that will show resources and liabilities. 5. What is meant by protest. 6-10. Journalize and post the following: Close ledger to show loss or gain and present worth. Accounts not affecting these items need not be closed. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Began business with, cash $800, mdse. $1,200. I owe Henry Smith a note for $150. Albert Packard owes me $275 on account. I Bought of James Field an invoice of mdse. amounting to $485. ve in payment sight draft on Albert Packard for amount of his :ount, and paid balanco in cash. kSold Harvey Anderson an invoice of mdse. amounting to $67 5. ived $275 cash, note at 30 days for $250, balance to go on Sold mdse. for cash $350 Paid clerk hire in cash $40, rent $25 Paid note to Henry Smith $150. Mdse. unsold Invoices $905 AGRICULTURE. 1. What is soil? Describe the ideal soil i'. What are the conditions necessary for plant growth? 3. Qive the purpose of tillage. 4. Give directions for planting, care of, cutting and storing alfalfa. 5. Give directions for transplanting the elm; also the tomato. 6. Why should apple trees be sprayed in this locality? 7. For what are these especially desirable: Clydesdale horses. Plymouth Rock chickens, Short Horn cattle? t8. A "low" remains over western South Dakota for two or days. What is the wind direction in Nebraska, and the prob - weather conditions. 9. Give reasons for protecting the birds other than song birds LI". What purpose could a school garden be made to serve? wer in as few words as possible. PHYSIOLOGY AND HYGIENE. 1. Describe the composition and structure of a bone. 2. Distinguish between voluntary and involuntary muscular ac - tion and give an example of each. 13. What is a food? Name two kinds and tell the *£&gt;rk of each building up the body. 4. What is the gastric juice, how and what action? L5. Describe in a general way the difference between the veins the arteries. 6. What are the spinal nerves? Explain motory and sensory 7. Give five rules for {he care of the eyes. Name three important uses of the skin. • Describe how one takes cold and give methods of prevention lief. ■&gt;. Does alcohol create energy or build tissue? Discuss fully </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 DRAWING. il. Draw a cube directly in front of and below the level of the Represent the invisible edges by light dotted lines. Name and illustrate three different kinds of triangles, as to relative length of sides. 3. Illustrate an oval and an object based upon that form. 4. Illustrate a circle, showing diameter and tangent. 5. Make a border, having for the unit of design a simple ge- ometric figure. Use two positions of the figure alternately. ENGLISH COMPOSITION. El. Supply the proper punctuation marks in the following sen - : Science declares that no particle of matter can be destroyed each atom has its place in the universe and that in seeking that each obeys a certain fixed law. 2. In about two hundred words, compare a day's work farm in summer with that in winter. 3. Write each of the following words in a sentence: plaintiff, eligible, tenant, parallel, utensils. 4. Write a formal acceptance to an invitation to an evening reception. t5. Write a letter to the U. S. Department of Agriculture, Wash - on, D. C . requesting that your name be placed on the mailing for the bulletins on horticulture, cattle, or soil culture. Fifty credits for language used in answer papers on other sub- jecta. THEORY AND ART. 11. Name two school studies in which current topics may be ght with especial profit. 2. Discuss the value of instruction, drill, and test in school L3. Show how habits, bodily and mental, may affect school work character. 4. Name four natural and four artificial incentives to study 5. What is the value in having pupils make collections of wood, minerals and plants? 0. Name three characteristics of a successful teacher. 17. Define imagination, attention and memory. Give methods cultivating each of these faculties. 8. What are the principal objects of the recitation? 19. Give your methods of teaching the fundamental processes arithmetic. 10. Write out a daily program for a rural school of twenty </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 ALGEBRA 1. Write and define the signs of aggregation, also of operation 2. Define term, member, rational, surd, and multiple. 3. Factor ab — ay + y* — by 4. Perform the operations indicated 5. Solve — x 1 x « 1 x x 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 6. Expand (a +2b)&lt; 7. Extract the cube root of 8. Solve this by each of three different methods of elimination 2x+3y=21 3x + 2y=19 19. Separate 96 into three parts, such that the first part divided the second gives a quotient of 2 and a remainder of , ; ana tne &gt;nd divided by the third gives a •.ikmi^ih. of 4 n»i«' a remainder 110. If the product of two numbers is increased by their sum, result is 89, but if the product is diminished by their sum the It is 51. Required, the numbers GEOMETRY 1 Define postulate, and axiom; and give two of each State and prove a theorem having for its conclusion, "The lines are parallel." 3. Theorem: In an isosceles trapezoid. the opposite angles are supplementary. 4. Theorem. In the same circle or in equal circles, equal "horda are equally distant from the center. t5. Theorem: The area of a circle is one-half the product of radius into the circumference. 6. Find the locus off a point equidistant from two given in - tersecting lines. (Prove i Problem. To construct a triangle having given the three Theorem: Two mutually equiangular triangles aro similar t. Problem. The distance from the center of a circle to chord 12 inches long is 10 inches. Find the area of the circle. 10. Problem. To construct a square equivalent to the sum of two given squares. x«+*(» + b)-t-ab (xf»)(x+5) x* + 7x + 10 X -i x* + x(b + c)+bc (x+c)(x + 3) x« + 7x +■ 12 1 3 5 - 9 11 13 15 a« + 3a&amp; b + 6a« b* f 7a» b» +■ 6a* b&lt; + 3ab* + b« </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 GRAMMAR. 1. Denne inflection. What parts of speech are inflected? t. What is the office of a preposition? Of a conjunction? 3. Distinguish between transitive verb and intransitive. Reg - ular and irregular. 14. Illustrate in sentences (a) noun clause; (b) adjective clause; adverbial clause. Rewrite your sentences changing each clause an adverbial phrase. 15. Correct and give reasons: (a) It was not them it was her. Between you and I, she was mistaken, (c) She is older than by ten years, (d) Let you and I try. (e) Virginia is south of jn's and Dickson's line. 6. Distinguish between subordinate and principal propositions. Analyze the following sentence: The noblest soul is that ch chooses the right, not for gain or glory, but because 'tis right. Give sentences containing the past tense form and the per - tect participle of each of the following verbs: Lie, sit, lay, seek, see. 9. In what grade would you begin to teach technical grammar? What previous instruction would you have given in English? Ilii. You desire to attend one of the Nebraska state normal ools. Write a letter to the principal of the school in which you interested, asking for information. READING. 1. Name four books that you think children should nead. Give reasons 2. What is meant by expression, emphasis, pronunciation? 3. What preparation should the teacher make for a lesson in leading? 4. Name three of the best modern series of text books in reading. 5. Give some devices for securing natural expression in read- ing classes. L6. Name five American authors, and give the title of one pro - tion of each. 7. Give a quotation from your favorite author. s. How will you seek to improve the pupil's taste in reading? 9-10. The primary teacher says to her pupils, "Tell me that the wind is blowing without using the word wind." Give five state - ments that may be reasonably expected from primary pupils In an- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 ARITHMETIC PL Write in words, 792.0792. Also write in figures, sixty-four seventy-eight ten thousandths. 2. Define prime number, composite number. Give test for divisibility. 3 3 — of — 9 4 B mplify -s- 1 1 1 -Of- 2 3 5 14. If a miller takes % for toll, and a bushel of wheat makes pounds of flour, how many bushels of wheat must be carried to 1 to obtain 196 pounds, or one barrel of flour? LI. How do you change a common fraction to a decimal? How you change a decimal to a common fraction? Illustrate each pro- t6 A traveler, on arriving at his destination, found that his ch was ; hr. 20 min. slow. In what direction, and how far had gone? Analyze fully: If % of a factory is worth $15,000, what Is 7-10 of it worth? LS. A man paid $36 for a cow, and 5-6 of the price of the cow 2-9 of the cost of a horse. Find the cost of the horse. 9. If a garrison of 150 men consume 26 barrels of flour in 9 weeks, how many barrels will it consume in 22^ weeks? t.\ man paid $25 for having his house insured for three , at 1 14 P«r cent on 2-3 of its value. Find the value of the BOTANY. 1. What is a bud? What must it contain, and how is It pro - tected by nature? BWhat are the parts of the flower? What are the functions each part? • the development of the embryo to the self-sup porting plant. \h at are the purposes of leaves? 4. Describe a typical cross-section of the stem of an exogen and tell how it would differ from an endogen. 16. Distinguish between root and stem; what is the purpose the root hairs? iOive some characteristics of a family of plants that would p to distinguish it from some other families. Of what advantage is cross fertilization? spersal. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define and give an example of each of the following: flood plain, delta, coastal plain, lake plain, plateau. 2. What determines the width of the zones? Give boundaries and width of each zone. 3. What is the cause of ocean currents? Why do they not flow around the earth? Give the location of Cuba and Luzon; name the principal and tell something of the government of each. Xame the five races of men and tell what country is inhabited mostly by each. 16. Name and locate five important lake ports of the United tes; five important river ports. 7. Account for the present rapid growth of Seattle. 18. (a) Name two states containing the most valuable copper M. (b) Locate our three principal iron ore districts, (e) Where our oil fields? In the absence of maps and globes in the schoolroom what ices would you make and use in the study of geography? 10. Where are the "Bad Lands?" Describe them. HISTORY. 1. Name two early English navigators, and tell what regions each explored. 12. Name four European nations that made early settlements North America, and state what territory was settled by each. 3? State the cause and results of the French and Indian War. 4. Name four of the most important battles of the Revolution, and give name of opposing commanders in each. 15. Make a positive statement about each of the following: Pat - k Henry. Henry Clay, Grover Cleveland, J. Sterling Morton, John 6. Contrast Jefferson's and Hamilton's ideas' of government. 7. Discuss the causes that led to the second war with Great Britain. 18. What were the provisions of the Kansas-Nebraska Bill? w was it looked upon in the North? In the South? 9. Discuss briefly the results of the Civil War. 10. Review three topics of interest in recent American history. PHYSICS 1. Distinguish between mass an ' weight; between force and motion. 12. Compare the energy of two bodies, one weighing 3 lbs. and ing a velocity of 80 feet a second, and the other weighing 5 lbs. having a velocity of 100 feet a second. 3. What is meant by gravitational unit of force; and what by </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 4. Give the theory of the conservation of energy L5. What is mechanical advantage? Give a rule for determin - the mechanical advantage of a lever. 6. Define cohesion, elasticity, solid, liquid, gas Make a diagram for, and explain the working of the siphon 8. Give illustration of heat diffusion. L9. Show by diagram the effect of a plano-convex lens on parallel ■ of light. 10. Explain the incandescent light; also the arc light. NOVEMBER 17 AND 18, 1905 MENTAL ARITHMETIC tGive complete written analysis of the following problems. So - ong by algebra not accepted. II. A steeple 90 feet high casts a shadow 10 0 feet. How high the steeple that casts a shadow 125 feet? I lost two-thirds of my money, but found two-thirds of what I lost. I then had $70. How much had I at first? 3. Three-fourths of A's farm equals two-sevenths of B's. To - gether they have 551 acres. How many acres has each? 14. A horse can trot a certain distance in 3 94 hours. What part it can he trot in one hour? 5. The sum of two numbers is 100, and the first is to the sec - ond as 3-10 is to What are the numbers? Rapid Computation. I Write only the answers to the following problems, numbering answers to correspond with the numbers of the problem. Time wed 15 minutes. (50 credits.) 1 What is the average of 60, 75, 80, 45? »How long will it take a boy to earn 99 cents if he can earn cents in 2 weeks? 3. A man said that % of his money was four times his week's waves; he had $100; what was his week's wages? tt. What number diminished by 33% per cent of itself be - es 20? 5. If $30 amounts to $60 in 3 years, what is the rate of in ten»t? 6. How many feet of lumber in four timbers 4x4 I A can do a piece of work in 6 days and B can do one-half it in 4 days. In what time can they together do the work? PENMANSHIP 1. Give your plan for using the copy book 2. Describe a method of securing rapidity in penmanship. S. Write a few movement exercises and state in what grade or grades you would use them. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 14. In correcting illegible, slovenly writing, to which would ch the more importance, increasing the prai ulating a ;ter mental effort? I As a specimen of your handwriting tour or more lines some selection with which you are familiar. 16. Fifty credits will be allowed for applicant's penmanship as wn in all answer papers submitted. CIVIL GOVERNMENT. 1. What is meant by represeti iment? Giv* ample. 2. State two rights guaranteed by the Unit- - constitu - tion to a person accused of crime. 13. What period of American history should be carefully studied paratory to the study of the I'nited States constitution? Why? ti. Explain at least two of the following: habeas corpus, em ain, arbitration, reciprocity. Jia) What is meant by the President's Cabinet? &lt;b) Of how ny members is it composed? (e) Give the names of two members the present cabinet and state what departments are in their charge. t&gt;. What are the duties of a United States district attorney? 17. How ar&lt; enses of the national government met? Of state government? is meant by (a) "municipal ownership?" &lt;b) 'Refer - um?" St. What is patriotism? How do you teach patriotism? 10. What is the date of ia) the regular annual election in Nebraska; (b) tho annual meeting for rural school districts? ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Give tho proper abbreviations for the following: a&lt; ■. nt month, junior, doctor, debtor. 2. What are diacritical marks? Give four, and illustrate their 3. Write words illustrating the different sounds of a, oo, th, g, c. t4. Write each of the following words in two sentences, using word with a different meaning in each sentence: perch, express, ial, patient, addr F&gt; Wh;'t i:; p. dictionary? Mention three school uses. the following list some words are spelled correctly and some rrectly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly: (25 credits.) scienses mend crystallized mum alcaholie peaceable) knowlege excedo Cincinattl porus oculist privelego </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 psychology domlsile greivoui separate seige capllary icicle parallel recede diptheria superintendant feasible forceable I (50 credits for spelling in all other answer papers). BOOKKEEPING. 1. What are the necessary things in a note? LI. When money is paid out for interest, what Is debited and t credited? L3. What is meant by account current? What is meant by Ing an account? 4. In closing the ledger, into what account would you close iosa and gain? Why? 5. What is meant by endorsement? What legal effect has it? L6-10. Write up in daybook, journal and ledger and close ac - nta in the following: 1* Cash on band $2000. Bills receivable, George Jones' note, $100 I owe $240 on note to Henry Fielding. Bought 200 barrels flour at $6.45 a barrel. Paid freight and insurance $45. Bought 1000 bushels potatoes at $ .35 a bushel l» Sold Wm. Swan 100 barrels flour at $7.50 a barrel. Received in payment his note for $5"0. Balance in cash. Sold Edgar Smith for cash 800 bushels of potatoes at 37% cents. Sold Henry Rogers for cash 50 barrels flour at $7.40. Bought car load of hay, 20 tons, at $7.40 a ton cash, and sold Ksame at once for $7.60 a ton, taking in payment note on George , due in 90 days. 2» Sold out for $415 in cash AGRICULTURE. il. Define (a) soil; (b) subsoil; (c) organic soil; (d) virgin | artificial soil. 2. From what sources does the soil receive water? What soil conditions are favorable to the retention of moisture? 3. What kind of soil can best withstand hot, dry weather? Why? 4. "As a rule, the farmers that grow and feed the most clover haw the most fertile farms." Explain. 6. In what three ways do weeds injure other growing plants? </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 L6. Discuss the importance of careful seed selection under the owing heads: (a) kind; (b) condition. 7. Name four probable causes of failure of seeds to germinate. L8. What is the present Nebraska law relative to the killing of ils? Of what value is this law to the farmer? i9. Mention a pest and its prevention or remedy for (a) a farm p; (b) a domestic animal; (c) a fruit I tlO. What do you consider the most valuable results to be se - d from school gardening? Name some points that should be fully observed in agricultural experiment work. PHYSIOLOGY AND HYGIENE 1. Describe the epidermis and the d.ermis, giving structure, mod - ifications and glands. 2. Name the longest bone in (a) the arm; (b) the leg. 3. Name the special senses. Which one is the least acin man? 4. What is a cell? What besides cells go to make up tissues? i5. Name the organs of respiration, and locate them by a dia - m or full description. 6. Mention three classes of foods. To which class does lean meat belong? Oatmeal? 7. Describe the action of the biceps muscle. L8. Can the blood in the veins flow backwards? Why? What ses the blood to ascend in the arteries? 19. State briefly the theory of heating and ventilating a school - in. 10. Why is a pipe more injurious than a cigar? DRAWING. 1. Define construction lines, convergence, foreshortening, 12 Draw from memory some leaf-forms, giving names of forms resented. 3. Draw a basket filled with apples, 14. Define and illustrate by drawing, secant, segment, quad gle, rectangle. 5. What is the value of drawing? ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 1. In about two hundred words, tell of the benefit of tree culture. 12. Write a letter to your county superintendent, making in - ry about reading circle work, and meetings. (Do not sign your i name to the letter.) 3. Use these words in sentences; Rise, raise, blue, blew, write, </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 4. Writ tly: There were several obstacles to be come my handwriting was bad and my language was very incorrect nothing could daunt this excellent man he secured specimens of my rhymes and disj&gt;ersed them among his friends and set on foot a subscription for my benefit. How would you prepare your pupils for writing a composi - tion on corn? (Fifty for English in other sub THEORY AND ART. 1. What do you understand by the tertiw ibility, will. What are appetites? Name two natural and two acquired titef. 3. Discuss the meaning and use of emotion 4. Distinguish between presentative and representative powers. I. What arc interest and attention? Are they related? How? 16. Name n- .■mend to pupils of grades uht. LGive some advantages and some disadvantages of basing motions upon ; obtained in examination. LMow would you meet the evil of dime-novel reading in ool? 9. v thi fivt senses called the "five windows of the L]&lt;i. \\ hat study do you think has the greatest disciplinary value? y? GRAMMAR. 1. What is a verb-phras*? Give an example- ::. l"s&lt; th* word that as a different part of speech in each of four seni. 3. Distinguish between co-ordinate and subordinate conjunc- '. and wr illustrating each. 4. Construct a sentence containing the verb study in the plural rmber. future perfect, active, interrogative, progressive. Fill the blanks below with the correct words, briefly giving reasons th' (a) It i&gt; (Pronoun, third, singular, masculine.) It was . (Pronoun, third, singular, feminine.) That is .... Pronoun, third, plural.) (b) Every one should havi _ life insured 6. Illustrate (a) compound word; 1 1&gt; i compound phrase. compound clause; (d) compound sentence Arrange all the words in the following exercise in a column and opi»&lt;. word write the name of the part of speech to which </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 The hare •co/fed at the tortoise for his slowness, and challenged him to a race. "Let us mn," said she, "up to yonder rock, and you shall have tit of half a, mile." 8. Parse the italicized words in the foregoing exercise. L9. Analyze and diagram the following sentence: We may not able to accomplish all we desire, but shall we therefore sir led hands? klO. Write a letter to a book publishing company, ordering books. (Capitalization, punctuation, spelling, form and Ian. be considered. Do not sign your own name to the letter.) ARITHMETIC El. A man received 7 5 pounds of sugar in exchange for 10 hels of potatoes at 40 cents a bushel. What was the value of the ar per pound, and how many pounds might b&gt;e bought for a dollar? A farmer exchanged 96 bushels of corn, worth I bushel for wheat worth 10 cents a bushel and oats wot bushel, receiving the same number of bushels of each. How many bushels of each did h&gt; &gt;lve and explain. :!. Reduce to a simple fraction: i l-i. rA market woman bought the rate of 4 for 5 i sold then' at the rate of "&gt; for 9 cents. How much did sh&lt; 1_h* a ho,is&lt; and paid one-third of the pn h. Oi later he paid one-third of what remained, and the i payments! amounted t&lt; $1315. What was the price of the house? 8. What is the a ■'■*'&gt; pounds of coal at $7.75 a ton? 17. A flour dealer bought 326 barrels of flour at $5.25 a barrel, sold 56 barrels at a loss of $ .37% a barrel. How must he sell tfain $12 on the investment? IV real estate dealer sold two houses for $3600 each. On one gained li per cent and on the other he lost It per cent. Did he n or lose by the two transactions? Solve and explain. 19. A merchant paid $45 for the use of $3000 for with - t grace. What Ilii. A tree broke off 21 feet from the ground, and resting on stump touched the level ground from the base of the nip. What was the height of tin ALGEBRA. 2. How would you explain to a class that: (b) a 1. Simplify: 4a l - -■} ab'+a --[6a&gt; -3a-lb l ( — 4l I =a ll'a? </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 4. Find the L. C. M. of r6. If to two-thirds of a certain number g is added, the sum is more than half the number. Required the number. I There are three numbers such that the third less the second als the second less the first; the third less the first equals the aec - ; and the sum of the numbers is 24. Required the numbers. Kxpand by use of formula, putting all your work on your »9. Tho floor of a certain room, which is 9 ft. high to th&gt; , has an area of 21" sq. ft., each of the two side walls 135 sq. ft., I each of the end walls 1 26 sq. ft. Find the other two dimei tho room. iin numl» f two digits. The number ual to four tiim in of the digits; and the sum of the squares of the di^.- lal to fi&gt; mm. of the d quired tho numbers. I ing read; to beginners children who can read? 3. What is the test of a child's fitness to read in a given b&lt; it. How with other * Givu three NtlOU for your How do. aching of literature differ from the begin - and practice of i 6. Givi t it J - not fiction, whii i HS. u h" considered under the head of the "me • ■a and pi of preparing pupils to uh tho public libr 9. Show how i-t public H- What it: the dip I trained and an untrained wori GKOMETRY 1. Theorem: If two angles of a triangle are equal, the sides opposite are equal and the triangle is isosceles. Theorem: The sum of the interior angles of a polygon is «qual to two right ani many tl two as the figure has side?. j'+ Ox+91, x ! and x*+8x+15 Solve: x»-(-6x+tt , * 4-x— « ( x«— 4x+4 ' - x— C » I HEADING. 1. Nan, &gt;r of enunciation ami w it may corre&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 P3. Theorem: The line joining the center of a circle to the die of a chord, is perpendicular to the chord. 4. Define circle, radius, tangent, secair If the perimeter of a rectangle is and the length is ce the width, what is the area? Solve. k6. What part of a parallelogram is the triangle formed by draw - ; a line from one vertex to the middle of a non-adjacent side? plain. 7. A chord of a cii • I and th&lt; 26. How far from the center to the chord? 8. The square of the diagonal of a par; lal to Ihe sum of the squares of th&lt; other three div 9. Problem: To » ndicnlar to a given plane at given point in it. 110. A treo casts a .shadow long when a vertical rod feet high casts a shadow 4 ft How high is the tp BOTANY. (Answer any eight.) 1. What i3 protoplasm? 2. Give structure and use of plant cells What purposes may r 4. What is the principal office of 5. What are adventitious buds? Whs f,. What is a fruit? What is the fruit of the potato plant? 7. What service do insects render in the : 8. Describo a tuber. A bulb. A corm. L9. Explain how boiling water for drinkiiiL liable to disc; 10. Discusn eith&gt; vra or vaucheria. GEOGRAPHY. rl. What is meant by each of the followin dian, parallel? Discuss fully, "standard t sire recognized. 3. Compare island, peninsula, and isthmus. 4. Give a general discussion of the I, Highland. 5. What is meant by continental climate? By oceanic clin 6. Explain the so called land and sea bre* 7. Give an account of three of cipal rel ' the </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 8. What do you consider the three most valuable cereals? Give a reason for your answer, and tell where each is produced. 9. Name the countries of Europe which touch the Mediterra - . also those that touch th« North Sea. L Where and for what noted are the following: Galveston, It Ste. Marie, Richmond, Tuskegee, Butte? HISTORY. 1. Describe the first voyage of Columbus. Pell about the settlement of Pennsylvania. 3. Tell about Roger Williams. 14. Give an account of Braddock's expedition against quesne. BWhy was it necessary to form a government of greater pow - than under the Articles of Confederation? 6. What were the boundaries of the United States as deter - mined by th&lt;- 7. What was the Missouri Compromise? L8. What territory was acquired by the I'nited States by annexa - ? What 9. Give account of threti important inventions that have in - fluenced American history, and tell what each did. 10. Tell of the life and doings of William McKinley. PHY- 1. What is meant by iai solid; (b) liquid; (c) gas? 2. Define iai inertia; (b) momentum; (C) action and rea&lt; 3. Distingui.- 1 -n work and energy. 4. Desci barometer as to structure and use Distinguish I force pump and lift pump, using the diagram of each. 6. What is meant by density and by specific gravity? 'live the modern theory of heat. B8. What is meant by condu lion, radiation? Give illustration of each. 9. Explain what is meant by color (light effect) 10. Explain the telephone or the phonograph. DECEMBER 15 AND 16, 1905. PENMANSHIP. rl. If a pupil's writing is too fine or too coarse, what means may employed to remedy the evil? How much time should be devoted daily to the writing ex (iciso in a rural school? 3. What is the best time of day for the writing exercise? Why" 4. As a specimen of your penmanship, write a selection of not than five lines. (20 cred Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown in all answer </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 CIVIL GOVERNMENT. 1. Why is a state divided into districts, counties, townships and i-recincts? K3. (a) How is public education supported? (b) On what theory state and federal governments contribute such support? 4. Name three rights and three duties of each voter of Nebraska. dive the important differences between the Articles of Con - eration and the Constitution. t6. (a) What does the Constitution say relative to coining mon - (b) Wherein do gold or silver certificates and National Bank 3 differ? 7. (a) Give five requisites to a teacher's contract. i a) What officers, county, district, state and national, are to he elected at the next regular election? 9. Give the main provisions of the new law governing tli • t ideation of teachers. lo. (a) What is impeachment? (b) Which house of Congress possesses the sole power of impeachment? ORTHOGRAPHY 11. Correctly syllabify: decisive, decision, digestive, dig&lt; larative, declaration, mountains, musical, special, grandeur. L Indicate the sounds of the vowels in the accented syllables the following words; obeisance, mandamus, abeyance, national. 13. Show, by sentences of your own construction, that you un - -stand the meaning of: Miner, minor; dying, dyeing; session, ces - n; currant, currant; canvas', canv;i ■ 4. Write the abbreviations for: Treasurer, President, Member Congress. West Virginia, last month. L Rewrite the following abbreviations, and opposite each write word or words for which it stands: Anon., inst., A. B., I In the following list some words are spelled correctly and some incorrectly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly. (25 credits.) laudable untill ible fulfill n"ice excell fasonaM parsel diligence wellfare inn defendant Phillipine salabln Cincinnati ic&gt; r Manila irin boil stupefy sherift dilli- R&lt;&gt; tarii 1 ■ -Ming in all other ar </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 MENTAL ARITHMETIC. KGive complete analysis of the following problems. Solutions algebra not accepted. 1. If 2-3 of an apple costs % cents, what will 15 apples cost? 1. If 75 cords of wood can be cut by 6 men in 9 days, in how many days could one man do the same work? 3. If a certain number be divided by 8, the quotient will be 13, with a remainder of 7. What is the number? 4. A man owning 4-5 of a boat, sold 2-3 of his share for $400 At that rate, what was th&gt; f the boat? 5. A and B bought a carriage for $120. A paid $75, B the remainder. They sold it for $160. How much did each recei Rapid Computation. k Write only the answers to the following problems, numbering answers to correspond with the numbers of the problems. Time wed ten min i What is the cost of digging a cellar 1( ft. wide, 117 f.\ long, at $2.50 ?, cubic yard? A'hat is the ratio of a 2-inch square to a 3-inch square? At ; i, how man for $2.37%. 4. James has 6-11 as many mar lohn. If John has 55 marbles, how many has James? iof paper cost 10 cents, what will 1 quip 16. Whal _-3 of 24 and the nil which 9 is ill)»■ much is gained per lb. selling i: a; 1 cent an 0111 BOOKKEEPING (a) Namo the two general &lt;■ ! accounts. (b) eral rule for journalizing each. legal tender? Collateral 'iable paper? and Gain? I Worth? 3. Name three kinds of drafts with r&lt; me. 4. Explain fully resoun »ry; liability inventory. 5. (a) Define Bills Payable; Bills Receivable, (b) When debit Slid when credit each? i6-10. Journalize the following, post, and find Applicant's pres - worth, closing all a&lt; &lt; Dec. 1. Applies: plicant' 1 and not your sig - uenced business ■ folio win; mer - chandise, $650; Thos. Ix&gt;ng owes him on account. $."." </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 2. Sold merchandise to H. Lange, $112. Received In pay - t, cash, $62; his note for 15 days, $30; balance on account. Dec. 3. Bought safe for store, cash, $75. 4. A fire damaged Applicant's stock to the amount of No insurance. kDec. 5. Discount H. Lange's note at bank, receiving cash for seds, face, $30, discount, 25 cents. Inventories: Mdse., $ fixtures, $75; unpaid clerk hire, $20. THEORY AND ART. 1. Give a definition for memory and distinguish between spon - taneous and intentional memory. I (Jive some advantages that the teacher in the country has r the teacher in town. Would you teach a child what he could not fully under - stand at the time? Why? 4. How may a teacher keep out of ruts? 5. What is the meaning of the expression, "The spirit of the teacher?" 6. What is meant by a disciplined mind? 7. Explain the meaning of the phrase, "An educated man." DRAWING. 1. (a) Of what value is drawing to i; Why should drawing bo taught? LDeflno (a) tint; (b) shade; (c) hue; (d) perspei - king drawing. Draw an imaginary sketch, putting in the life element 4. Draw a familiar tree from memory and give its name. Draw a group of vegetables consisting of a turnip, an onion t: potato, and a pumpkin, observing carefully the relative sizes. AGRICULTURE. II. (a) W r hat is the purpose of crop rotation? (b) What is meant soil wearing out? I Define (a) humu uraft; budding. 3. What elements in the soil and air are considered plant food? 14. Mention five reasons why agriculture should be taught in public schools of Nebraska. 5. (a) What is propagation? ib&gt; Mention three conditions -ary to germination of seeds. i6. (a) In what forms is water found in the soil? (b) ways by which the soil's capacity for water may be increased. 7. (a i Give five general uses of the animal, (b) What gain is mud t ■ in c&lt; croDintosn i lit ci 1 it rod ucts ** </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 (a) Mention two reasons for the cultivation of soil. (bi b. is ol the most importance? 9. Define pollenation, and name some of the agencies which •erve to bring it about. Discuss the importance of field excursions in conn&gt; with the study of agriculture in the school. PHYSIOLOGY. 1. What are the ligaments? Of what use are tendons? 3. Give location and function of the salivary glands. 4. How does alcohol ■■stimulate" the heart's action. 5. What is meant by vital organs? Name two such organs. 6. Explain briefly the physiological process of keeping the body warm alcohol manifest in the breath so soon after a bev - erage containing it has been swallowed? A disinfectant? 9. Describe the importance of reflex action. 10. What is the sympathetic nervous system? ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 1. Give six rules for the use of capitals. erectly: all that glitters is not gold — Shakespeare meant by "The spirit of the L3. Make an outline for a biographical sketch of Abraham coin. 4. 'When I was a boy I worked my way down the river to York, to see the city. I met a bishop there. He said to me, down, my son, I want to talk to you. I know your father in Albany. You are Senator Whipple's son." I said to him, 'no sir, I am not Senator Whipplo's son. I am ho relation of his.' If the P had talked to me after that he might have made my life a littlo easier- — a little sweeter." (a) What mistake did the bishop make? (b) How did the boy get to the city? What were his worldly circumstai &lt;d) How was he different from Senator Whipple's son? \ hat did the bishop do after he found his mistake? &lt;fl What trait of character do you find in the boy? (g) What trait of character is revealed in the bishop? Prove your answers by quotations from the selection. (Fifty credits for English as shown by other papers submitted.) GRAMMAR 1. What three parts of speech may connect clauses? Illustrate Define and give examples of la dud; (b) ab- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 3. Write the possessive plural forms of: colony, wharf, woman, t-poonful, who. 4. Supply in each of the follow; .-rb in the in - dicative or subjunctive mode: (a) I wish it — in my power to hel] (b) If he — guilty, the eviden- not show it. ic) Though he — there, I did not see him. (d) [1 he — discreet, he will si ' ye — men, fighc. Construct a sentence having a noun in .n to the object. 6. Write a sentence having an infinitive used as an adverbial modifier. K7. Write a sentence containing a participle and change it into infinitive. Write a sentence containing a clause in direct quotation and then change) it to indirect quotation. 9. What is an antecedent? Give- an illustration. 10. Diagram, or, if you prefer, analyze the following sent* The fact that man's powers are limited is not sufficiently recog- ARITHMETIC. 1. Define (a) abstract number; (b) concrete number; (c) fac - tor; (d) multiple. I (tive the devices and the discussions and explanations you uld employ in explaining this problem in subtraction: 4 2 15 1 being the first time your class has encountered the so-called "bor - ring" pro 13. What is the shortest length that can be exactly measured either of four measures which are respectively 10 in., 15 in., in. and 30 inches long? ii. A and B together have $9500 and two thirds of A's money als 3-5 of B's. How much has each? 5. A cubic foot of water weighs 6 2 . ;J 2 pounds. Find the weight of a cylindrical inch which is .7584 of a cubic inch. 9. Find the cost of 60 boards 26 feet long, 10 in. wide and thick, at $24 per M. 7. In what time will $900 produce $93 at 6 per cent? 8. What part of a mile is 6 rods, 3 yards, 2 inches? 9. 11 36 men earn $1296 in 18 days, how much will 42 men earn in 87 days? 10. What is the distance from the lower corner to the opposite upper corner of a room 24 feet long, 18 feet wide and 12 feet high? </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 READING. 1. What is the aim of the reading lesson? LWhy should the material of the reading lesson be interest - to the children? L3. Mention the advantages of a preparatory conversation about reading lesson. 14. (a) What is sight reading? (b) What are the objections concert reading? 15. Is it possible to overwork the dictionary in the preparation the reading lesBon? t6. (a) Shall the teacher encourage the pupil of the grammar e to read a few good books, or many books as they come to hand? Why? K7. (a) Name five books which you can recommend to children read. • (b) State briefly your reasons therefor. 18. (a) Write a quotation from your favorite author. (b) Tell y he 13 your favorite. ALGEBRA 1. Define (a) term (b) equation (c) axiom. 2. Factor (a) Sab — bc+cd — 5ad. 2x l -*-llx+12 3. Find the H. C. F. of: x»— 5x»— 7x+35 and x»— 3x»— 7x— 15 4. Simplify: x x x» — 1 ' x*+l 15. What number is that which when multiplied by 16 gives same result as when added to 16? t6 Find two numbers the sum of whose reciprocals is 5, and that the sum of half the first and one-third of the second equals i the product of the two numbers. 7. Extract the cube root of the following: 8x« ;x 1 y»+.ttx I y &lt; -9xy 6 +y« 8. Solve the equation: x' 12x 9. Solve: i y v — '* 10. There are two numbers such that the product of the first and one more than the second is 660, and the product of the second and one less than the first is 60 9. What are the numbers? GEOMETRY 1. Classify and define triangles (a) as to sides, (b) as to angles 2. Theorem. If the diagonals of a quadrilateral bisect each other, the figure is a parallelogram. x'+xy-fv'=7 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 rt. Theorem. Through three points not in the same straight one circumference and only one can he passed. 14. In any right angled triangle the square of the hypotenuse equivalent to the sum of the squares of the two legs. 15. Problem. In two similar polygons, two homologus sides 15 feet and 25 feet, respectively. The area of the first is 450 are feet. What is the area of the second? 16. If from a point without a circle, a tangent and a secant drawn, the tangent is a mean proportional between the whole nt and its external segment. 7. Problem: To find a fourth proportional to three given lines. GEOGRAPHY. 1. What conditions united to make Chicago a commercial me- tropolis? 2. Name the six great powers of the world in order of their strength, and give the kind of government each possesses. 3. Define glacier, delta, longitude, continent, equinoxes. 4. What is meant by the "balance of trade"? 5. Name and locate five of the greatest institutions of learn- ing of the United States. 16. State where each of five leading mineral products of the ted States is found in greatest abundance. 17. Explain briefly that our happiness and existence are a pro - t of evolution somewhat dependent upon every part of the world every past age. 18. Locate the following: Panama Canal; National Park; U. Federal Military Academy. 19. Give the area and population, number of counties and chief ustries of Nebraska. ilO. (a) Why is geography taught? (b) What phases of the ject should modern teaching emphasize? PHYSIC8. 1 . What is meant by motion, and what by rest? 2. Explain the construction and use of the mercurial thermom- 3. Give Newton's three laws of motion. 4. To what is the bouyant force of fluids due? (Discuss fully.) 15. A rock dropped from the top of a cliff, strikes at the base 3 1-5 seconds. How high is the cliff? 6. What is the load that a force of 100 lbs. will lift by the use of three fixed and three movable pulleys? </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 I Explain by diagram or otherwise, the workings and use of Wh( volume and pitch of sounds. &lt;t Explain the echo. ■ Explain how tli' f a hot-bed is above that ido air. HISTORY. 1. What motive led to the founding of Maryland? .ive an account of the discovery of th&lt; pjii River. What was the Stamp Act, and how did the Americans look it' 4. Make a statement about each of the following: Stony Point, Arnold, Paul Jones, Valley Forge. 5. Tell of the Embargo, and of Impressment. 6. Most histories call New Orleans "a useless battle." Explain 7. Explain the so-called "doctrine of nullification." ra the results of the war with Mexico? What amendments to the Constitution came as a result of -i! War? I" important fact about each of the following: O. Cannon, James Russell Lowell, W. R. Harper, Folk, La Follette. BOTANY wer any seven. Retain original numl" 1. To what extent is the new plant already formed in the seed : n inatioii begins? L\ What is a bud, and what are the reasons for its formation? 3. What is meant by parasitic plants? Name some varieties. 4. Make diagram of a cross-section of the Maple, and of In - dian Corn; and explain the differ*-! Draw and explain differences between simple and compound 16. Discuss some changes that have been brought about in flow - ultivation. Cite instances to prove your answers. I What part of the flowei - the fruit in the apple? at in the cherry? sion of Bacteria. (Not more than 60 words.) JANUARY 19 AND 20, 1906. PENMANSHIP. 1 Define muscular movement. State its advantages I Discuss form and movement in the different grades and give relative attention each should receive. 3. Classify the letters of the alphabet according to the num - ber of spaces above or below the base line. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 4. When should the children begin to write with pen and ink? 5. What is the correct position for writing? Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown by all mination papers submitted. BOOKKEEPING El. Define account as applied to the ledger. Give th* title of accounts which will close with Loss and Gain, and of three, not inal, which will close with balance. 2. Write a non-negotiable note. 3. Distinguish between endorsement at length, and endorse - ment in blank, and illustrate each. 4. Write a receipted bill for the following 6 complete geographies at $1.00. 4 U. 3. histories at $.80. 10 Standard arithmetics at $.52. Make the bill complete in all details. 5. Name the book of original entry, and discuss its import. 16-10. Journalize the following, post in the ledger, and find and Blake's present worth, liabilities and net gain. I Austin and Blake of Omaha on Jan. 2, 1905, have on hand cash 23.18 and a stock of general merchandise inventoried at $6fc ey transact business as follows: (Jan. 3. Sold R. K. Wheeler on account mdse. valued at $76.50, :eived cash for petty sales $36.35; bought of Leach &amp; Co. on ac - unt 48 bbls. of flour at $3.65 a bbl., and 2 tons of feed at * ton. IJan. 4. Sold F. E. Mann for cash, merchandise amounting to 5.25. Jan. 10. Paid for rent of store one month $45, and for clerk hir« $10. KJan. 12. Bought of James Kern for cash 6 dozen brooms at .40 per dozen. t.Jan. 15. The inventoried value of merchandise on hand was 050.17. Close all accounts. ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Write the abbreviations for: merchandise, namely, lieutenant, credit, Attorney General. 12. Syllabify and mark the accented syllable diacritically in each the following words: machine, Colorado, granary, merchant, cor - al. 3. Write homonyms of these words: altar, ought, marshal, earn, quarts. 4. Define derivative, monosyllable, suffix, diphthong, synonym. 5. Write five compound words; five primitive words. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 In the following list some words are spelled correctly and some correctly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly: (25 credits) pulmonary candor greivan vengan* amonia academy mucillage Britian contagious measles illustrious necceuary corrider restaurant disipline tilable pavilion appartus Llope governer cataract seperata Anapolis achieve emmigrant CIVIL GOVERNMENT. Kl. ■ .suns why the American people are better adapted a republican form of government than are the people of Russia. I Name a provision of the U. S- Constitution which has not rated as it was intended, and state what amendment Is there - i advocated. 3. (a) Give the consecutive number of the present national congress, (h) Is the present session the long or the short session? 4. State briefly how treaties are made and what branches of our national government are concerned in their making. 5. Distinguish between customs, or duties, and internal revenue 16. How are U. S. supreme judges selected? What is their term office? 7. What is meant by extradition? 8. Nan i incumbents of the following offices: Speaker of the National House of Representatives, U. S. Commission - er of Ed; uy of Agriculture, the two V. S. sena - tors from Nebraska, and the member of Congress from the congres - sional district ol your resides fc~tate^ the provisions of law and the rulings of the State rintendent in this state relative to reading circle work and at - unty institutes. I It. Explain how you would correlate instruction in civil gov - ;ind curi a as to stimulate interest In botl. MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part I. ANALYSIS. 1. A watch and chain cost $150. and % of the cost of the watch, plus $15, equals $9 5: required the i ich. Analyze. 2. A cow cost $24. and 4-3 of the cost of U cost of a horse; i m. Anal </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Pi. A farmer sold % of his cows, and then had 25 cows remain - how many had he at first? Analyze. Present as you would to a fifth grade class: If 36 - worth $95, what are 60 sheep worth at the same rate? 5. Present as you would to a seventh grade class: If % of an acre of land cost $36, what will 5-9 of an acre eo MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part 2. RAPID COMPUTATION. tThe superintendent will detach this list before distributing, give exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for comple - ; then collect answer papers and pin to Part I. Applicants will te numbers of problems and answers only. II. A certain number diminished by 14% becomes 19. What the number? :!. If 7 pounds of coffee are worth $2.12, what are 35 i&gt;ounds 13. At the rate of 17 pounds of sugar for a dollar, how much be bought for $2.50? 4. Multiply 84.6 by 100 and divide the result by 1000. 15. The volume of a square prism is 36 cu. ft., and the area one of its ends is 9 square feet. What is the area of one of its M? ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 11. Give two rules for the use of the period and three rules for use of the comma. Give an outline for a composition on Indians. 13. What is the meaning of the following: "Night's candles are aed out." 14-5. "The side door of the house opened; a weeptng woman ne out; and with her was a tall Confederate Colonel of c;i llantly giving her his arm, he escorted her as far as the little gate, ere she bade him good-bye with much feeling. With an impul - e movement he drew some money from his pocket, thrust it upon •, and started hurriedly away that he might not listen to her thanks, ch was his pre-oecupation that he actually brushed int&lt; o was standing (a) What is the first act from which we infer the presence of a sympathetic trait in the Colonel's charai What « ■ &gt;nel not iks? </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 rA ith an impulsive movement, he drew some money from his pocket, thrust it upon her, and started hur - riedly away." What does this suggest to you as re - gards the man? What does it suggest to you as re - gard t tha woman? if) Why did hu not see Stephen? ••dtts for English as shown by other papers submitted.) AGRICULTURE. rl. Explain how weeds and underbrush waste valuable soil water dry weather. Have weeds ever any value to farm land? 2. Describe an experiment to prove that plants contain mineral matter derived from tha soil. 3. Give two distinct reasons why soil should be porous Li. When may it be said of land that it is "run down"? What • be done to restore such land? 5. What are parasites? What is the Bordeaux mixture? 6. Explain the importance of packing the soil about planted seeds. I What is the purpose of grafting? Illustrate with drawings method o2 grafting. 8. (a) Discuss the value of toads to the farmer or gardener K(b) State reasons why the English sparrow should, if possible exterminated. 9. What ia meant by balanced ration? Discuss the advantages of "diversified farming. DRAWING II. Represent an open crayon box in front and below the level th« I 2. Make a border design using as a unit some form of leaf. 3. (a) Namo the primary colors. &lt;b) At what place in the course of study should color first b« taught? LI. Name and illustrate five geometrical figures, the construc - of which should be taught in the grades. 5. Represent a landscape scene showing the horizon line. THEORY AND ART Answer any six, retaining the original numbers 1. What do you consider "perfect order" in a schoolroom, as applied to pupils? L2. Compare the value of the topical recitation, and the ques - and answer method. 3. Discuss the relation of the common school to the home and th« church. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 »4. Will you allow whispering in your school? Give reasons* your answer. 5. What will you do in the first thirty minutes of a new school on the first day? 6. Tell how intuition differs from reason. 7. Discuss: "Teaching, both in manner and in method, must be adapted to the capacity of the one taught." 8. Discuss this principle: "Observation before reasoning." PHYSIOLOGY. 11. Name the bone of the thigh, and mention the class of joints resented at each of its extremities. 2. Locate the following muscles: biceps, triceps, and sartor ins; also the tendon of Achilles. 3. Show how muscular exercises refresh the mind after a pe - tiod of study. LA. Explain how blood is transmitted from the arteries to the 9. tGive two reasons why the food should be thoroughly mas - ted before it is swallowed. 6. Explain dura mater; olfactory nerve. 7. Explain how the sensation of taste is produced. Of what part of the skin are the nails a modification? Give three directions for the proper tare of the nails. 19. (a) Give approximately the temperature that should be main- Mi in the schoolroom. (h) What exhalation from the lungs makes tilation of living rooms necessary? i&gt;riefly the effect of tobacco upon the heart. GRAMMAR. 1. Define and give example of (a) phrase, (b) clause. K'l. Write sentences containing (a) a participle with an adverb - modifier, (b) a participle as an object of a preposition. 3. Write the declension of ox, child, knife, woman 4. Diagram or analyze: LIf we compare life in the family with life in society, the differ - is vast. 5. Parse the underscored words: This is the lwera that was written by Longfellow. 6. Write the possessive plurals of lady, man, he, sister-in-law. T. Write a sentence containing a verb in the passive voice, in - dicative mode, present perfect tense. 8. Write to Ginn and Co., publishers, 110-112 Wabash Are., Chicago, asking them to send you a copy of Montgomery's American History. Enclose payment. 9. Write a sentence illustrating the use of the subjunctive mods. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 [Change to correct syntax, and justify your corrections (a) They were both alike, (b) I recall you was his advocate at the time. Every one must judge of their own feelings, (d) If he was there, he must have heard the speech. Which of the group is the taller? ARITHMETIC L faction, mixed number, common divisor, imp tion. Lievii-es :&lt; ou would in explaining this problem. 4. What is the value of a pile of wood 195 ft. long, 84 ft. wide, and 63 ft. high, a; $4.25 per cord? I The school tax of a certain town is $47fc2. If the r;i tion is :i mills on a dollar, what is the amount of taxable prop- 6. B paid |.ttS7f a pound for a bale of cotton; he sold it at gain of '» of ind ami for the bale. How many pounds did th« balu weigh? tl'h&lt;- sum of A's and B's age* and % of A's age all 3-5 of E's. How old I .\ farmer has three farms containing ively lt; - acres, which he wishes to divide into fields of equal size, kin*-' tin- fields as large as possible. How many fields wil m make? 19. A man insured his house for % of its value at 1 pei i hoiis* was (!• by fire and his loss was $1245. Find the ue of the hoi. Uh y in gallons of a cistern I ft. in dia: ]" ft d. READING 1. Give a brief sketch of Longfellow, and BUM one of h\* ular poen ry of one of Ami successful and popular prose humorists. 3. Name one of the best modern textbooks in reading for the primary gradee. Give reasons. 4. State some practical uses that may be made of the school library. ir method of teaching reading and literature in the advanced grammar grades. 6. Discuss the importance of the tone of voice in reading. 7. What are some of the &gt;•» of having pupils read ■ thing, which are in season and about cur' 1. Write in Roman letters 19&lt;&gt;6. Writo in word </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 ALGEBRA. tl. Write the symbols (a) of operation, (b) of relation, (c) of regatlon. Simplify: al a-l IH b-a i | 1 1+xt Simplify: x 1 1 — x EA cistern is supplied by three pipes ;th* first can fill it in ours, the second in 5 hours, and the third in 7 hours. How long it take all three together? 16. The sum of two numbers is 47, and the quotient of one fided by the other is ,') and the remainder is iiiired the mbere. 7. Kxpand: .uttiny all your work on the answer |&gt; 19. A mirror 56 inches high and ■ wide has a frai form width such that frame equals the area of mirror. What is the width of the frame? 110. The sum of two nun. 0, and the sum of their squares Etoquirad th« bbbbIm GEOMETRY. 1. Distinguish between theorem and problem. 2. Theorem: If two parallel lin. |1 by at ll, the exterior-interior angles on the sani the tran re equal. t3. Theorem: Two triangles are equal if two sides and tl ded angle of i '-qua! to two sides and the included angle the other. 14. Theorem: The biaectora of the angles of a triangle meet a point which is equally distant from the sides of the triaiiL Problem: To const ru&lt; t a circle having a given radius, and passing through two given points. 6. Problem: To circumscribe a circle about a given tria 7. Theorem: The bisector of an angle of a triangle divid - -ite side into segments proportional to the adjacent si&lt;: 8. Problem: To find a mean proportional i two given straight li 9. Find the area of a triangle if the sides are 104, 111 and L10. Problem: Find th»- iargest square that can be from p circular 2. Factor: a* — tiab+b* — c* tod— d* also a» b-ab3 +a^ b+ab? 1 1 1 + _+ o=;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 U. S. HISTORY. tl. Why were the European nations anxious to get to India in 15th century? 2. Show how the claims of England, France and Spain over - lapped during the colonisation period. Name the colonies which were founded as a refuge or an lum. and give purpose of founding each. 4. Tell of the capture of Quebec. ti. Make a list of five important battles of the Revolution, give ■ of American and English generals in command, and tell which won. What is a tax on foreign goods called, and what is the pur - of so eh a tax? 7. Explain why American trade grew so fast from 1800 to 1806. 8. List the original thirteen colonies as slave or free. 9. Compare the Kansas- Nebraska Bill with the Missouri Com- promise. What is a strike, and how are strikes settled? GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define: Basin, divide, river system L2. (a) What is meant by the term "central time"? (b) Explain cause of change of time in traveling east or west. 3. Explain the cause of whirl winds 4. Explain the direct cause of rain. S. Name five of the leading national powers of the world and mention a source ot strength of each. 16. Name the special characteristics of the Mongolian race and why said race is adapted to live in the country principally in - ited by it. 7. Name five states of the Union in which corn is one of the leading products. k8. (a) Name, in order, the five leading agricultural products of raska. (b) Name two industries that are rapidly being devel- I in Nebraska. 19. The successful teaching of geography requires a knowledge other branches of learning; name the most essential of these branch - and tell how each is applied in geography teaching. 110. To what extent should the committing to memory of names places, dates, etc., be required of pupils in the geography class? • reasons for your answer. PHYSICS. 1. Give definition for hardness and for Hastirijy 2. A stone attached to a string is whirled around the hand. If </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 t::. Give the mechanical advantage of an inclined plane 13 feet 5 used to raise a stone to top of a wall 5 feet high; first, when the :e is applied parallel to the plane, and second, when applied paral - to the earth's surface. Solve for both instances. Weight of «tone 100 lbs. 4. Explain how an iron ship floats, 15. Discuss the relation of the boiling point to pressure and to vation. 6. What is meant by local action, and by polarization, in cells? 7. How is one able to determine distance and size of objects? 8. Distinguish between sound and sound wave. BOTANY. 1. Tell of the germination and growth of the bean until the leaves appear. L Distinguish between underground stem and root, and give mples of each. 3. What is meant by terminal and what by lateral buds? 4. Tell how a perfect flower may differ from a symmetrical flower. 5. Explain the process of budding or grafting. I. What is honey, and how related to botany? FEBRUARY 16 AND 17, 1906. BOOKKEEPING. 1. State the essential difference between single entry and double entry bookkeeping. 2. (a) Write a sight draft, (b) Who are the parties to it and what relation do they bear to each other? 3. Define three kinds of endorsements. 14. What can be said for and against the teaching of bookkeep - in tho country schools? K. (a) What is a trial balance? (b) When is it used? 16-10. Jan. 10, 1906 — Continued my business with the follow - resources and liabilities: Cash $3000, mdse. $2000, bills receiva - $500, bills payable $350; book accounts — John Anderson $75, ard Hall $50. Jan. 11 — Sold to Joseph Smith, merchandise $125, receiving in payment, cash $35, his note for $50, balance on account. ijan. 12 — Bought of H. Johnson, on account, merchandise $700. d for set of office records $8. LJan. 13 — A fire in the basement of the store destroyed $200 of k. No insurance. ■ Jan. 14 — Howard Hall having failed and assigned his property bankruptcy, his account was settled on a basis of 50 per cent. Jan. 15. Journalize, post and close ledger. ntories: Mdse. $2400; oflice fixtures $50; unpaid clerk salary $ I </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 CIVIL GOVERNMENT 1 Name two of the purposes, as recited in the preamble, for which the I". S. Constitution was established. 2. What is an alien? How may an alien become a citizen? 3. Name the three great branches of government, and Indicate briefly the functions of each. 4. Define veto, quorum, consul, reciprocity, "graft 5. Explain as you would to an eighth grade class the terms popular vote and electoral vote for President. 6. What cabinet officer is concerned with foreign affairs? What department has charge of public lands? For what purpose, and how often is the U. S. census taken? at was the population of Nebraska and of the nation, according the latest census? 8. Describe the Australian ballot system and discuss its n 1». What duty is imposed by law iiuon school districts in Ne - jska in order that they may share in the apportionment of state ool funds? a brief review of the Nebraska railroad tux cases. PENMANSHIP. 1. Outline a writing lesson, naming the grade. 2. Why should the letter forms for younger pupils be larger than those for pupils of higher grades? 3. Explain two exercises for developing speed 4. What is meant by the muscular system? Name th' tat you aeek to obtain In penmai. (Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown by all an- ORTHOGRAI'HY 1. Define. V'owi nant. Fell how you would conduct a selling 1&lt; 3. Write the following words and give a synonym of Cheerful, pleasure, discipline, defective 4 Syllabify and give diacritical no lie vowels in he following words: Inquiry, lapel. frontal, coupon. In the following list some "lling words are spelled all correctly: exagerate pluricy cookou banana bushel falacy gauging sweed hemorago </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 shaddow tyrranical restoraunt billion enroll pronounciation cataract saillable absense governor receved MENTAL ARITHMETIC. PART I. ANALYSIS. 1. If 4 apples cost 12 cents, what will 7 apples cost? Solve and explain as you would for a third or fourth grade class. 2. What is % of V 4 ? Analyze and explain as you would for a seventh or eighth grade class. t3. If % of a yard of cloth cost | cents, what will % of a yard Analyze and explain as you would for a fifth or sixth grade 4. A man paid me $20 more than 2-5 of what he owed me. Soon after he paid me 3-5 of the remainder, but he still owed me $40. How much did he owe me at first? Give complete analysis. ■ ■ by arithmetic. No algebraic symbols permitted. 15. A and B agreed to plow a field for $120. A plowed % of the d and 5 acres besides and received $50. How many acres were re? MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part 2. RAPID COMPUTATION. The superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; then collect answer papers and pin to Part 1. Applicants will write numbers of problems and answers only. LI. What will be the post of l :, quarts of berries at 3H OH rt? §3. At $ % a bushel, how many bushels of salt can be bought $18? 4. How much greater than % of 4 % is 1-5 of 24? I How many quarts of berries at $0.12 a quart will it t;i for 4 yards of cloth at $&lt;&gt;.165 a yard? PHYSIOLOGY. 1. Describe and give functions of (a) periosteum; (b) dentine. Name three \ises of th* muscles. (b) Mention four bene - the muscles. 1. 4x7 + 7x6-^8x9 — 65=? </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 3. Make a simple, inexpensive bill of fare for one day, con - sisting of highly nutritious and easily digested foods. 4. Name and briefly describe the parts of the alimentary canal 5. Tell where and how the blood is mainly purified »6. Of what use are tears? By what secreted? What provision made for their escape from the eye in ordinary quantities? State reasons for bathing and habits of cleanliness. 8. State the function of the cerebrum. t9. What provision is made in the statutes of Nebraska for in - ction in the effects of alcohol and narcotics upon the human ? tlO. How do you fulfill the requirements of this law (a) before pupil is given the text book?; (b) after the pupil is given the book? DRAWING Bl. Represent an open crayon box to the left and below the eye the observer. 2. Represent a group of three objects based on the sphere. 3. Represent a roadway with fence at one side. 4. Of what special value to the pupil is the ability to construct the common geometrical forms? IB. In what particular is the ability of the teacher to draw uable in geography teaching? THEORY AND ART 1. Define (a) conscience, (b) consciousness. 2. Give three objects of a recitation. 3. How would you deal with tardiness in a country school? L4. Discuss this principle: "From the known to the related un - wn." 5. How are the powers of the mind developed and trained? 6. Of what use is drill work in teaching? How may this be abned? 17. Describe a way in which pupils below the third reader class be profitably occupied at their desks. fc. What daily preparation should the teacher ■qiake? 19. How may a teacher encourage a taste for good reading in the ntry schools? 10. Name two ways of teaching morals in the schoolroom AGRICILTURE. 1. Explain how the death of animals and plants contributes to the fertility of the soil. 2. (a) Name the five leading plants cultivated in Nebraska, (b) What peculiarity or habit makes each of value to us? 3. (a) What is plant disease? (b) Name a disease which affects </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 4. Explain why birds aro protected by law. 5. How should seed corn be selected? Discuss fuily in the light of recent experimentation. 6. What is the economy of propagating some plants by seeds and others by buds? il. (a) Give two ways in which nature often protects its plants m the frost. (b) How may the farmer do it? Name four useful domestic animals and give the use of each. 9. Name the five most harmful insects in Nebraska. It. Discuss the value of tree culture with relation to the future growth and development oi western Nebraska. ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 1. How will you assist pupils in acquiring a wide or extensive vocabulary? I Write sentences illustrating the difference in meaning of the lowing synonyms: Abstain, forbear; character, reputation; custom, bit; difficulty, obstacle; think, believe. 3. Rewrite the following, supplying the proper punctuation marks: Hes a comical old fellow said Scroogs nephew thats the truth and not so pleasant as he might be however his offenses carry their own punishment and I have nothing to say against him. t4-5. "Later on, down a side street, he pauses before a house th its face blown away. On the verge of one of its jagged floors an old four-posted bed, and beside it a child's cot is standing piti - ly, the tiny pillow still at the head, the little sheets thrown across i foot. So much for one of the navy's shells." — The Crisis. (a) What had happened to the house? (b) What was the room that became exposed used for? (c) How many individuals had used it? (d) Was the room in use at the time the catastrophe oc- curred? How do you know? lei Was it occupied? Why do you think so? (f) What two things make the whole especially pathetic? 6. Discuss the importance of letter writing as one means of teaching English composition. GEOMETRY. 1. Define Geometrical surface. Distinguish between axiom and postulate. 12. Theorem: The sum of the three interior angles of a triangle equal to two right angles. 3. Theorem: The bisectors of the base angles of an isosceles triangle are equal 4. Problem: To circumscribe a circle about a given triangle. 5. Problem: To construct a square equivalent to a given rect- angle. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 6 Theorem: The areas of two similar triangles are to each squares of any two homologous sides. Problem: The chord of an arc is 24 inches and the height of the arc is 9 inches. Find the radius of the circle. Ll'roblem: Find the locus of a point at a given distance from ven circumference. GRAMMAR 1. Illustrate by written sentences the past and past perfect teMM of fly. flow. flee. 2. Define declension, conjugation 3. Write sentences to illustrate: (a) Noun clause; &lt;b) adjective clause; (c) adverbial clause. 4. Diagram: "Ht &gt;rktt first t'tuyht ibe princip tiristianity knew well what would be the &lt;■ ■n*tynenceg." 5. Parse the italicized words in the above sentence. 6. Write a sentence containing: (a) A relative pronoun. an adjective pronoun. ici an adverb of manner, i d i an adjective in the comparative degree. 7 Write a letter of application for a position as teacher. S. "You may use my sled, Mary. Do you want to?" "Oh yes. indeed!" said Mary. "Thank you, Fred." (a) What "hint"' in the above about Mary? kibi What "hint" about the little boy who offered the sled? Write sentences to illustrate three different uses of the in- finitive necessary corrections in the following sentences and reasons for corrections: (a) He told me to sit it down and I sat it down ( b i I found it laying on the floor. shall give it to whoever seems to need it most id i I met a man whom I have no doubt was your uncle. Every man. woman, and child is going to the oelebration ALGEBRA 1. Define: in coefficient; 1 1&gt; ) exponent: (e) root; id) power ■1. r,. ») x»— 2a -iab (b) x' I Find the H. C. F. and 1. 4x + 3. and i a* --»-« a* ii 3 a* — • 2 aS+a-2 a* -2a- 1 1 1 . </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 7. Expand, by formula, putting all your work on answer paper. 8. Extract the square root of: x« 2x 1 m 9. Simplify: a«n-n +»m|n And explain. 10. Find two numbers, such that the first divided by the second f-ives a quotient of 9 and a remainder of 3, and their product is 240. READING. 11. Name the authors of each of the following poems: (a) The erican Flag; (b) Thanatopsis: ici Evangeline; idi Barbara itchie; (e» Tho One-Hoss Shay. I. Name the author of each of the following selections i a) The Autocrat of the Breakfast Table. |(b) Poor Richard's Maxims, (c) Rip Van Winkle. ( d ) The Last of the Mohicans. (e) Uncle Tom "a Cabin. 3-4. Give a nuxkl program for a Washington— Lincoln Day celebra- tion by your school. --rate four reasons why everybody should learn to read. 6. I M importance of learning ictrnl to read. 7. Give reasons as to which is the more difficult for a child learning to read: (a) "Does the fat rat see the cat on the mat?' ib) "Hiawatha lived in a wigwam with old Nokomis." v To what extent should the study of pictures be used in teach- ing reading? :ve hints for word study as related to the reading lesson. oar methods of conducting a primary class- In reading with those you employ in the seventh and eighth grade. ARITHMETIC. LI. Define and give examples of prime, concrete, integral, simple, denominate numbers. §How does long division differ from short division? ans of an example illustrate how you would teach long di begin: 13. A poke 63 feet Jong was broken in tw of which one h of the other. What was the length of the parts? 4 Divide 1-9 fe Explain ; hod. 6. Solve by comparison: 2x+3y=23 y=37. (x+3 - -f- x» + 4x* H (- - 4 3 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 The product of three factors is two thousandths. Two of them are five tenths and sixteen hundredths. Find the other factor. 6. From 1-12 of a bushel subtract 7-9 of a quart At what rate must $1250 be loaned to gain $125. 75 in 3 years, 3 months, and 18 days? At an annual school meeting a tax of $703. SO was voted. iTMdii valuation of a district is $65350, how much is As tax an assessment of |SI LI. The hypotenuse of a right-angled triangle is 20 inches, and base is 16 inches. What is the perpendicular? IA pupil wishing merely to "get the answer" to the problem, ■ adding, then dividing, etc., until he finally stumbles upon the Mr. Explain the trouble and give your remedy. BOTANY 1 Describe the cotyledons as to location and uses. K2. Name, illustrate by drawing, and describe two classifications root*. 3. Define and give illustration by citing examples of each; An - nual, biennial, and perennial plants. 4. Discuss propagation by means of budding and distinguish between budding and grafting. Give meaning of the following terms as applied to flowers regular, symmetrical. 6. Give physiological structure of the leaf ii88: Absorption, circulation, respiration, and assimila - tion, as carried on by the exogen. I. Give general discussion of Cryptogams M8CU88 structure, contents, and life of the plant cell 10. Discuss the flora of Nebraska. U. S. HISTORY. 1. Give a short account of the settlement at Plymouth 2. Tell about Hudson's voyage. 3. Give account of some religious observances of the colonists which would appear strange to us now. 4. Give the purpose of the Navigation Act. 5. Name and give result of each of five battles in which Wash - ington was commander. 6. Give the results of the Spanish-American War 7. Give the purpose and results of the Lewis and Clarke expedi- tion. 8. State briefly the substance and purpose of the Monroe Doc - trine. t. Contrast the views of Webster and Calhoun as to the per - manency of the Union. 10. Give the purpose of the "Homestead Law </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 PHYSICS. 1. Distinguish between Mass Motion and Molecular Motion, and give illustrations of each. 2. Distinguish between volume and weight. 3. Define pendulum and give uses. 4. Give method of finding the specific gravity of solids. a. Explain the use and principles of the Magdeburg hemispheres. 6. Discuss convection as applied to heating and ventilating rooms. 7. Explain the speaking tube. 8. Explain the solar spectrum. 9. Explain the tangent galvanometer. 10. Give two ways of arranging cells to form a battery, and give advantages ot each. GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define: equator, watershed, canyon, prime meridian. it. Account for differences in temperature, in the same latitude, ween places of different elevation. What effect is a great extent of sea-coast likely to have n (a) the climate of a country, (b) the occupations of the people? 4. Give the location of Hawaii and the Canal Zone; name the principal city and tell something of the government of each. 5. Give a general discussion upon the formation of mountains. §6. Name the special characteristics of the Malay race and tell y said race is adapted to live in the country principally Inhabited it. 17. Make an outline for a geography lesson on the leading in - tries of the State of Nebraska. 18. I'pon reaching Long Pine, Alliance, North Platte, or Mc - &gt;k. you must change your watch one hour. Will it be later or Her? Givo reasons. 19. Where is the great manufacturing section of the United tes, and what natural advantages does it possess for mauufac - ing? 10. Name in order of size and locate the five largest cities in tho United States. MARCH 16 AND 17, 1906. BOOKKEEPING. rl. (a) into what does Loss &amp; Gain account close? (b) When how? LI. State when to debit and when to credit bills payable; bills ivable. 3. How are promissory notes, checks, sight drafts, and sight time drafts disposed of in bookkeeping? 4. Explain inventory, days of grace, certificate of deposit, in - solvency, exchange. 13 apu </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 6. (a) What is meant by protesting a note? (b) How may the endorser ot a check escape responsibility? 6-10. The following are the ledger balances of the firm of Goetz tHurlbut after six months' business, ending March 16, 1906: Dr. A&lt; Cr. rMdse ltt.M Cash Interest &amp; Discount 17.39 The amount of merchandise on hand, as shown by inventory, was (5140.50, and the amount of fixtures previously charged to ex- pense $140.25. Make out the final loss and gain account, showing the gain or loss on the six months' business. CIVIL GOVERNMENT. a) What were the Articles of Confederation? (b) When was the Constitution of the United States adopted? 2. Discus* "initiative and referendum." 3. (a) What is naturalization? (b) What one political right dow a native born citizen possess over a naturalized citizen? 14. What reason can you give for (a) the existence of two houses Congress; (b) the different methods of choosing the members? 5. How is a territory represented in Congress? 6. What is impeachment? Which house of Congress has the •oto power of impeachment? Kin what two ways do the people contribute to the support the national government? Explain purpose and powers of the annual school district meeting. . 9. Discuss tbe railroad rate bill now pending in Congress 16. How is the value of property determined for purposes of taxation in Nebraska? PENMANSHIP 11. (a) What do you consider the most important characteristic good penmanship? (b) How would you lead your pupils to at - i it? 2. (a) Name three common faults of writing, (b) State how they may be overcome. 3. Give rules for spacing between letters and words 4. What kinds of class drill would you employ to secure free - dom o( movement? 5. Why should beginners make large letters? (Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown by all answer Stock J6274. * 6 »« 25 Personal Accts 1083.80 612. Bills Rec ' 4 Expense </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Which exercise should be more frequent, written or oral spelling? Why? 2. How should the written exercises be corrected? 3. Define: Synonym, homonym, antonym. 4. Give abbreviations for: Legislature, gentleman, post-office rer, bachelor of laws, amount. 5. Give two general rules for 11. How many times is 3 contained in four-fifths? Solve lain as you would to an eighth grade class*. it If % of a ton of hay cost $15, what will four-fifths of cost? Solve and explain as you would to a sixth grade class. 13. If % of the value of a carriage is equal to % of the value a horse, and the value of the carriage is $20 more than the value the horse, what is the value of each? t4. A and B agree to perform a piece of work, A receiving $2 B $3 a day; A works twice as many days as B, and they together ive $70; how many days did each labor? 15. A man in trade lost two-fifths of the money he invested, af - which he gained $700; he then had $3400. What was his total ? Give complete analysis. RAPID COMPUTATION. (The superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and give exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for comple - tion. Then collect answer papers and pin to Part 1. Applicants will write numbers of problems and answers on I 1. What is the difference between % of 24 and the number of which 9 if %? 5. Give two general rules for spelling and a word to illustrate *ch. In the following list some words are spelled correctly and e incorrectly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly: (25 credits.) alfalfia buisiness Igrammer • enough sieze Chicamauga separata Panama audible icycle Isuperseed bureau neccessary etiquette quadrille judgement woolly Britian liesure inteligent Imusilage artillery ventelate gorilla comparative MrVTll. »DtTUUUTIC </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 PI. % of a certain number, increased by \ of the same num - equals 34; give the number. tZ. At 8% cents a yard, how many yards of cloth can you buy $2.25? t4. A boy gave 25 cents for a knife, and sold it for 30 cents at per cent did he gain? 5. A teacher's grades in the five essentials in the February examination were as follows: Reading 93, arithmetic 65, geog - raphy 89, grammar 86, history 78. What was her average in these five subjects? DRAWING. 1. Upon what three type solids may all study of form be based? Which is more beautiful, a straight line or a curved line? &gt;? 13. Represent a crayon box above and to the right of the center vision. 4. Define vertical, perpendicular, horizontal, oblique and diag - onal aa used in drawing. 5. Draw a leaf of some common plant; conventionalize the Mine as a design for a textile fabric. AGRICULTURE. 1. What place have the earth-worm, ant and all burrowing animals taken in the work of soil making? Kia) Mention some of the advantages of drainage, (b) How it best effected? L3. Name the species of corn and wheat that prevail in ka. 4. Give the names of three kinds of swimming birds and tell what they ear. 5. In what way do scavenger insects aid man? 16. How does the parent plant give the young plant a "start life"? Explain the source of sweet potato plants and of Irish po - planU. 8. Give three ways in which the air may be cooled to form rain. 9. What are the distinguishing characteristics of roadsters and draft horses? t&lt;a) Give common instances of lack of care of domestic als. (b) Give the injury, financial or otherwise, from such neg- THEORY AND ART 1 Define: maxim, judgment, induction, deduction 2. Give the purpose of discipline. Z. Name the faculties of the mind especially cultivated by the study of: (a) Form and color, (b) geography, (c) arithmetic. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 Discuss: The concrete before the abstract: sense knowledge ore thought knowledge. 5. Give the use and value of the written test. 6. What constitutes a good question? LI. To what extent should the child be required to recite in words of the book? 8. What is your idea of the meaning of "being thorough"? ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 11. Improve the following: (a) The exercises harden not only muscles but also train the mind? (b) Running as fast as possl - , the burning building was at last reached. tt. Make a single sentence of the following: i began to think ously of matrimony. I chose my wife as she chose her wedding n. She did not choose her dress for a fine, glossy surface. She ie it for such qualities as would wear well. L3. Copy the following selection, supplying the proper capitals punctuation marks: tTou need be under no uneasiness cried i about selling the rims they are not worth a sixpence for i perceive they are only copper lished over what cried my wife not silver the rims not silver. 4. Write a letter of introduction. L5. Give methods of promoting (a) fluency of speech; (b) ac - acy in punctuation, capitalization and spelling. 6-10. 1 saw an old lady, who was evidently poor, crossing the street and carrying a basket of apples. She slipped, and some of the apples fell from the basket and rolled about on the ground. Rob - ert, a boy of ten years, ran out and picked up the apples for her. She thanked him and said, "God bless you, my boy, and your mother, too." (a) What hints did the old lady get from this act of Robert's? (b) What hints do you get concerning Robert? (c) What hints are given you about the old lady? &lt;d) Tell the effect of each hint upon your feelings. (e) What use would you make of the above narrative in teaching a lesson on character? PHYSIOLOGY. 1. Briefly describe nature's process of repairing a broken bone. 2. Describe the two general kinds of muscles. 3. (a) Name two parts of the body in which starchy foods are digested, (b) What fluid is employed in each case? 4. What is the lymph? 5. Tell some of the effects of too rapid eating. 16. How do you distinguish by the flow of blood whether an ury affects a vein, an artery or the capillaries? 7. Define respiration and state its object. 8. Define bronchitis, pleurisy. 9. Describe the process of hearing. 10. Describe the effects of alcohol upon the nervous system. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 GEOMETRY 1. Draw and name the different classes of quadrilateral figures. Theorem: If two angles of a triangle are equal, the sides opposite are equal, and the triangle is isosceles. 3. Theorem: The line drawn from the center of a circle to the middle of a chord is perpendicular to the chord. 4. Problem: To divide a given right angle into three equal Problem: Through a given point to draw a tangent to a circle. 6. Problem: To construct a square, having given the diagonal Theorem: Two similar polygons are composed of the same i umber of similar triangles, similarly placed. 8. Problem: The sides of a triangle are 104, 111, and 175 feet i aspect ively. Find the area. 19. The area of a square circumscribed about a circle is twice area of the inscribed square. ALGEBRA B.I. What principle is involved in transposition? In clearing equation of fractions? 4 Find the H. C. F. and the L. C M of x« - 5ax+4a», and x» - 3ax + 2a* -; mplifv: I 1 1 x y /. E. A certain fraction becomes equal to nine-elevenths if one is to twice the numerator, and equal to If 3 is subtra its numerator, and from its denominator. Find the fraction. The difference of two numbers is 6, and their product ex - ceeds their sum by 39. Find the numbers. ENGLISH GRAMMAR Illustrate in sentences, proper, interrogative, demonstrative ributive and numeral adjectives. imparison, and state what parts of speech are com - pared. mplifv: — x — [x— (x-5-.\ 3. 1 &gt;a*+12a+4 "ax+7a* r\ formula, puttinp all work </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 t4. (a) Write a sentence containing an adjective phrase, (b) te a sentence containing an adverbial phrase modifying an ad - iv«. 5. Write a compound-complex sentence. i6-7. Analyze the following sentence: As we travel inl&gt;u&gt;tl. places pointed out to us wlure ptfmtmu cities once gUn-d.. 8. Parse the italicized words in the foregoing sentence. t9. Write a letter to the Department of Agriculture, Washing- D. C, requesting a list of bulletins and circulars available for distribution. 10. State briefly the results at which you aim in teaching gram - mar, and how you know when you have secured such results. ARITHMETIC. 1. Write all the signs used in arithmetical operations, naming the use of each. Recently a brilliant eighth grade class of 12 pupils in one of our great cities, was giving a wonderful exhibit of oral solutions in arithmetic. Supt. C. A. Fulmer of Beatrice was granted permis - sion to give this class a simple problem in multiplication. The prob - lem was to multiply 67389 by 789, which he wrote on the blackboard asking pupils to solve on paper. At the close of 5 minutes, when the last pupil had finished, it was found that not one pupil had the cor - rect answer. What were the defects in teaching this subject? How would you correct such teaching in your school? 13. Explain the advantage of changing the form of a fraction not its value. Illustr &gt;u would to a seventh grade class. 14. From two, and two and one seventh hundredths, subtract t and two thirds thousandths. Express the answer decimally both figures and words. L Required the number of yards of carpet needed for a floor ■ ing and 15 feet wide, the strips % of a yard wide to be lengthwise of the room. t6. Explain whether there is a gain or loss in selling two ar - s at the same price when the gain per cent on one equals the loss cent on the other. 17. Find the difference between true and bank discount on a note $100 payable 9i» days after date, discounted at 6 per cent. 18. A and B hire a pasture for |30. A puts in 8 cows for 10 ks and B 6 cows for 12 weeks. How much should each pay? Solvo by proportion. 19. In marking pupils' answer papers in arithmetic, credit should given for correct results only. Give reasons for or against this hod of marking. in. How many gallons of water will a vat in the form of a cylinder hold, whose inside dimensions are — base 8 feet in diameter. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 READING 1. (a) What elements are included in expression? (b) Distinguish between emphasis and accent. L2. Indicate the advantage of the preparatory conversation about reading lesson. 3. How do you seek to interest your pupils in good literature? 4. (a) What is the value of story telling in teaching reading? (b) What three characteristics should such stories possess? 5. Name a production of each of the following authors: Oliver Wendell Holmes, Benjamin Franklin, J. Fenimore Cooper, Washing - ton Irving, Harriet Beecher Stowe, Joseph Rodman Drake, William Cullen Bryant, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, John Greenleaf Whit - tier, James Whitcomb Riley. b •-!&lt;). To what extent may the teaching of reading be corre - with language, history, geography and nature study without de - ng the real purposes of the reading lesson? BOTANY. 1. Distinguish between seedling and graft as applied to fruit- 2. Discuss the tuber. 3. Distinguish between simple and compound leaf, L4. Define: (a) Gamopetalous, (b) Irregular, as applied to era. 5. Discuss the structure of the bark 6. Give the characteristics of the flower of the Rosaceae. 7. Discuss the fern as to growth and propagation. GEOGRAPHY 1. Define: equinoxes, solstice, zenith, latitude, longitude. 2. Explain how latitude and longitude affect the time of sun- 3. Give the causes of the change of seasons 4. What kind of government has Great Britain*, Russia, Cuba, France, and Germany? Why is China bo isolated? How has this characteristic re - flected itself in the people? Name three unproductive regions of the United States and reasons therefor. Name and locate the state educational institutions of Ne- 8. Give suggestions for the first lessons in geography. 9. What movement is now being promoted to reclaim some of the arid regions of Nebraska? 10. Explain how the Government Weather Bureau forecasts tD8 *eatnHP. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 PHYSICS. 1. Define velocity k2. Is it true that a projectile thrown horizontally and one drop - perpendicularly under the influence of gravitation alone, will ke the surface at the same time? Discuss fully. 3. Which is heavier, a pound of pine wood or a pound of Iron? Explain your answer. 4. Give illustration and discussion of heat produced by per - cussion. 5. Discuss absolute temperature. 6. Give the mechanical principles. 7. Explain refraction. HISTORY. 11. Give an account of the voyage of the Cabots, and discuss importance to their country. 2. Tell the story of Pocahontas. 3. Give an account of the introduction of slavery into the colonies. 4. Review the explorations of LaSalle. 5. Gtv« a topical review for the study of the Revolutionary Name an Interesting event associated with each of the fol - ing dates: 1492; 1607; 1776; 1820; 1863. 7. Tell about the writing of the poem: The Star Spangled Banner 8. Discuss the Dred Scott Decision 9. Give an account of the laying of the Atlantic Cable. L10. Name five topics which should receive attention In teach - current events. APRIL 20 AND 21, 1906. BOOKKEEPING. 1. Give two general rules for the generalizing of accounts. 2. Name four essential conditions to a contract. 3. Write the following: (a) Joint promissory note, (b) Sight time draft accepted. 14. Make the proper journal entry when the bank discounts er persons' written obligations, giving you the proceeds in cash. 5. Name the book of original entry and give reasons for such designation. 16-10. The following is the balance sheet of unclosed accounts the Globe Hardware Company after six months' business, ending; April 16, 1906: </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Ell 16, 1906. was $4,140.25, and the amount of fixtures previously ited to expense $325. Determine the Globe Hardware Company's tent worth, and close its account in the ledger. CIVIL. GOVERNMENT. 1. What, in your opinion, is the most important clause in our constitution* k 2-3-4. (a) In whom are the legislative powers of your county state vested? (b) The law enforcing powers? (c) The law inter - ng powers? What authority passes on the constitutionality of legislative acts 0 6. Explain the ways and means whereby the national govern - obtains sufficient revenue for its running expenses. I All property in Nebraska is subject annually to three specific levies. S class and name the body determining it. 8. Who are entitled to vote at school district meetings? 19. Name the county and state officers of Nebraska to be elected the next general election. 10. What is meant by the direct primary system of nomination? PENMANSHIP 1. What relation have position and pen holding to the character of the writing? Make a copy of the capitals and small letters of the sys - tem you teach. 3. Explain briefly your methods in teaching (a) beginners; (b) advanced pupils. 4. In what grade would you introduce the use of pen and ink? 5. As a specimen of your penmanship, write some memory gem. 6. Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship, as shown in all papers submitted. ORTHOGRAPHY 1. Syllabify and mark the accent in each of the following words formidable} contumely illustrate inquiry genuine Dr. Acct. Cr. 10,372.20 ... Mdse. $C.4&amp; 6,2- Cash .... . 5,681.20 1,951. Globe Hardware Co 8,: 2,594.25 Personal account 1,083.80 50. Bills receivable . 638. 826. Km. use 234.56 39.33 ■' and discount .... 56.72 The amount of merchandise on hand, as shown by inventory </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 -. Give correct abbreviations for the following Captain Secretary Department Superintendent Numbers 3. Write sentences containing the following words and their homonyms: mane, wait, cede, I'll, hoard. 4. Define prefix, suffix, affix, vowel, consonant. 5. Give three uses of the apostrophe in the spelling of words. L6-10. Some of the following are correct, some incorrect. Re - te, spelling all correctly: rGive complete analysis of the following problems. Solutions algebra not accepted. ■ 1. How many times is % contained in 4? Solve and explain you would to a sixth grade class. §i. Sixty dollars is three-fifths of what B gave for a horse, and of the horse, increased by its three-fifths, is five times what paid for a sleigh; required the cost of the sleigh. I Twenty-four dollars is 4 per cent, of the sum of A's and fortunes; how much money has each, provided A has twice as ch as B? 14. When B was married he was 25 years old, and three-fifths his age was 3 years more than % of his wife's age; required the I of his wife. What is the principal method you use in teaching mental arithmetic? Part. II tThe superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; collect answer papers and pin to Part 1. Applicants will write bers of problems and answers only. 1. If % of a yard of cloth cost four-fifths of a dollar, what chieftian until! judgement diphtheria analysis indispensable phlegm Febuary recieva advertisment Artia discipline arraign government ecstasy changeable movable polotics leutenant stationery blamable turkeys lad\.i babys calcium MENTAL ARITHMETIC. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 P2. If two times a number, increased by 8, equal three times number, what is the number? L3. A grocer paid $6.40 for a bushel of cranberries; how shall •ell them a quart to gain 2 cents a pint? 4. Three-fourths of 8 per cent, is what per cent, of 30 per cent.? 5. Having % of a bushel of apples, I gave % of them away; what part of a bushel remained? ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 1. Punctuate and capitalize the following: The boast of her - aldry the pomp of power and all that beauty all that wealth e'er gave await alike the inevitable hour the paths of glory lead but to tha grave. 2. Correct the following: I did not like him saying that before all the others. How high did you say the Washington monument waa? He determined to immediately ask the teacher's pardon. It la my wish to most completely repair the injury I have done them. He waa taking a step the consequences of which he was not quite sure. L3. Tell by effects that it has been raining; that the man is old t it is spring. 4. Reconstruct the following sentences, so as to add to their ■strength: (a) The young men will, I fear, be discontented always, (b) I will come on Wednesday, perhaps, (c) William was the more attentive, but his brother studied more. (d) About the time of Solon the custom is said to have been introduced, and which still re - mains of writing in lines from left to right. 5. Write a letter of congratulation DRAWINO. 1. What points should be carefully observed in teaching draw- 2. What use may be made of drawing in teaching geography? 3. Represent an open crayon box below and to the left of the Li. Represent an outdoor scene, showing the horizon line, and a section of fence. 5. Make a border design, using two geometrical figures as AGRICULTURE. LI. Of what does soil consist? What is the source of the organic ter in the soil? 2. Give approximate dates for planting each of the following Held corn, winter wheat, oats, Irish potatoes, apple trees. 3. Why is the common house cat a great enemy to the farmer? 4. What is the advantage gained (a) by treating seed potatoes to a formalin bath before planting; (b) by spraying the foliage of the </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 5. Distinguish between budding and grafting. 6. Mention two ways in which the farmer may be benefited by the United States weather predictions. 7. What is the chief value of the state and county fair to the farmer? 8. How would you treat wheat seed to prevent smut in the future crop? 19-10. Make a drawing to illustrate an ideal farm garden, in - ding various small fruit, as well as vegetables. THEORY AND ART. II. Is knowledge, or mental development the true aim and end teaching? Give reasons. LI. Discuss the soundness of this statement: A thing known be told. 3. Give three decisive reasons for thoroughness in teaching. t4. (a) How long shall the pupil be kept on the same lesson out wasting energy and destroying interest? (b) How long on same study? 5. It is charged that our schools fail to develop independence of thought and action. Is the trouble (a) too much help on the teacher's part, (b) or too little help, (c) or is the help not given in the right way? Give reasons. PHYSIOLOGY 1. What advantages in having the heads of bones large? 2. Give three uses of muscles. 3. Why is milk so nearly a perfect food? 4. State objections to a strictly vegetable diet. I What is the shortest general path a particle of blood can e in going from one side of the heart to the other? 6. Explain why worrying is injurious. 7. Give three uses of the nose. 8. Why is it more healthful to sleep on a bedstead than on the floor? 9. (a) Give cause of dandruff, (b) Suggest a cure. 110. What recent enactment by our state legislature has had important bearing upon the use of alcoholic stimulants? GEOMETRY. 1. Distinguish between theorem and corollary. LI. Theorem: The bisector of the vertical angle of an isosceles ngle bisects the base and is perpendicular to the base. 3. Theorem: The opposite angles of a parallelogram are equal. 4. Theorem: A straight line perpendicular to a radius at Its extremity is tangent to the circle. 5. Problem: To construct a circle which has Its center In given line and passes through two given points. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 r%. Theorem: If two cords intersect within a circle, the product the segments of the one is equal to the product of the segments he other. 7. The sides of a triangle are 7, 9, and 11. Is the triangle right, acute, or obtuse? Give your reasons. K8. The bases of a trapezoid are 16 feet and 10 feet; each leg 5 feet. Find the area of the trapezoid. READING. (a) Name two short poems that you would recommend for ldren's memorizing, (b) Why would you recommend these? 2. Should stories told in the schoolroom be absolutely true? Why? 3. (a) Name three standard writers for children, (b) Name two standard periodicals for children. 4. (a) What famous poem is based on an event of the Revolu- (b) What famous poem is based on an event of the Civil 5. How do you conduct a reading lesson in supplementry work? 6. Give three suggestions on the teaching of current events. What is your method of dealing with the child who 1b "back - ward" in reading? 8. Outline a lesson on "The Village Blacksmith" for third grade pupil.. 9. What are figurative expressions? Give two examples, 10. Give a quotation from Longfellow. ALGEBRA. 1. Define (a) equation, (b) member, (c) term, (d) unit. 12. Explain the meaning of the minus sign in such expressions —7a, or —3 b. 5. Solve 1 — d a b L6. A can do a piece of work in six days, B in nine days, and eight days. How long will it take all of them to do the work? 7. Find toe square root of 9x&lt; — 18x+l f 8"x* — 54x3 8. Multiply 2^6 - 3^5 by V3 + H 2 10. The diagonal of a rectangle is 25 inches. If the rectangle were 4 inches shorter and 8 inches wider, the diagonal would still 3. Factor a* 4- b* — c* — d* — 2ab — 2cd, also 1 — 9x — lOx* x» — 7x+6 x* — Hx+48 x* + 6x 4. Simplify •- 1 »f + 3x— 1 x&gt; - 10x+24 x* - 8x» XXX 9. Solve 2x* — x+a=2a* </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 GRAMMAR. 1. Define substantive, antecedent, appositive, voice, participle. 2. Give the conjugation of the verb ate in the present perfect tense, indicative mode. Expand the following sentences, changing the italicized rds. first to phrases, and then to clauses: (a) Wise men are respected. (b) Wisdom is the principal thing. 14. "Robert and his friend read and discussed Dante and Mil - ." The foregoing contains eight statements. Express them sep - tely in eight sentences. 15. Analyze the following sentence: My mother's uncle visited before he sailed for Europe. 6. Use in sentences (a) a participial phrase; (b) an infinitive phrase. Tell how each is used. 17. Write a short letter to your county superintendent, acknowl - ing receipt of his reading circle announcement, and informing as to your attitude toward his plans. 8. Give two common errors of speech, and tell how you will correct the same in pupils. ARITHMETIC. LI. Divide 7975 by 26. Explain every step in the solution of problem as you would to a third or fourth grade class. 12. Explain as you would to a fifth or sixth grade class the erence between a factor and a multiple of a number. Take the uber 12 for example. tl. A man bought a house and paid % of the price in cash at time of the purchase. A year afterward he paid % of what then ained unpaid, and the two payments amounted to $5260. How h did he pay for the house? 14. (a) What is the product of .417 multiplied by .34? Explain you would to a class beginning this work. (b) Divide .00864 by .24. Explain. A man willed his estate worth $8000 as follows: To his i % of his money, to his daughter one fifth, and to his son seven - enths. If the widow should die, what proportionate share would son and daughter each receive? 16. A man bought a farm for $97.75 per acre, which price was per cent more than was previously paid for it. What was the pre - us price per acre? 17. How much less would it cost to make a brick sidewalk ft. wide and 260 ft. long, at $1.08 a sq. yd., than to lay a stone k of the same dimensions, at 22 cents a sq. ft.? 8. If four men mow 15 A- in 5 da. of 14 hr.. In how many days of 13 hr. can 7 men mow 19% A.? 9. Find the amount of $240.15 for 2 yr. 5 mo. 13 da. at 6 per </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 10. A tax U $16,020; the taxable property $784,750; the num - ber of polls at $1.25 is 260. A's property is $7800; what is his tax? tNote. — In your solutions and explanations make accuracy of k and statement your motto. Be careful to make every state - t in your explanations as clear, precise and brief as possible. BOTANY. Answer seven. Retain original numbers 1. Distinguish between root and stem, (a) as to position; (b) appendages. aj What are stipules? (b) What are thorns? 13. The leaf of an apple tree withers quickly when severed from tree, while the fruit remains firm for a considerable time. Ex - n the cause. 4. Distinguish between dehiscent and indehiscent fruits. 5. Give conditions favorable to germination of seeds. 6. What is the cambium layer? 7. Around the outside of many buds are dry, hard scales. Ex - plain their uses. 8. What are "rusts"? 19. Give five practical suggestions on tree planting and beautify - school grounds. GEOGRAPHY 11. Give latitude of following points: (a) Tropic of Cancer; (b) tic Circle; (c) North Pole, (d) What place is in longitude zero latitude zero? 12. Name and define two motions of the earth, and tell effect each. L3. (a) Give origin and direction of Gulf Stream. (b) Name e countries whose climate Is modified by It. 4. What kind of government has Turkey, Norway, Brazil, Swit - zerland, Porto Rico? 5. (a) What is the cotton producing section of the United Stats.? (b) What other countries produce it abundantly? i c I Where are the principal wheat producing regions of the world? 6. Name the races of men in order of thetr rank of civilization if. Give a brief discussion of the rainfall of Nebraska, and how it affects the occupations of the people. 8. What and where are the following: Manchester, Guam, Co - lon, Honolulu, Vatican? I* 9. What commercial advantage, if any, did we gain by the uisitlon of the Philippines? Give reasons. 10. Discuss the value of the sand table and map-drawing in the teaching of geography. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 HISTORY. 1. Name four European countries that sent explorers to the new world? Name one from each country. Of the colonists of Jamestown and Plymouth, who were the ter adapted to the country they sought to subdue, and why? Name the war which determined what European country uld have the mastery of the American continent. 4. Who were the Tories, and what effect did they have on the Revolutionary War? 5. Name the greatest act of Jefferson's Administration. L6. What were the principal results of the Lewis and Clark ex - ition? 7. Which did Lincoln care for most, the preservation of the Union, or the destruction of slavery? Give proof. iS. What was the chief cause of the war between the United tes and Spain? 19. Select any five of the following names and make a brief tement concerning each. Magellan, Raleigh, Wm. Penn, La'fayette, bert Morris, Daniel Webster, Susan B. Anthony. 110. Name, in your opinion, the greatest issue now before the erican people. Give reasons. PHYSIC9. 1. Why does a chimney draw? Explain with some care. dive illustration of balanced, and of unbalanced forces, and how they differ. 3. What is meant by the resultant of two forces? 4. Distinguish between velocity and momentum. 15. A person sitting in a swing throws a heavy weight hori - tally. How is he affected thereby? Explain. 16. An engine running at the rate of a mile a minute, exerts onstant tractile force of 3000 lbs. on its train. Express the work ig done in horse-power. 7. Explain the echo. »8. What are the conditions of an electric flow between two ints of a conductor? MAY lx AND 19, 1906. BOOKKEEPING. 1. Define (a) bookkeeping, (b) journalizing. I Give general rule for journalizing (a) accounts with per - 8, (b) accounts with property. 13. (a) Which side of bills receivable is always the larger when re is any difference? Why? 14. If you wish to know what is due on any account what book uld t«! consulted? 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 5. Write a letter of application for a position as cashier In a bank. 6-10. Make the day-book, journal and ledger entries required by the following transactions: 1. Bought of S. Smith on my note at 60 days, 500 yds. at 89c; 20 bolts ribbon at $1.20; 60 yds. lining at 8c. I Aug. 2. Sold J. Myers for cash 10 yds. silk at $1.50; 5 yds bon at II I Aug. 3. Sold Thos. Bent for cash 15 yds. silk at $1.50; 7 yds ing at 15o Aug. 4. Paid for rent $25. Paid for clerk hire $30 CIVICS. 1. Give the objects of the United States Constitution as set forth in the preamble thereto. tl. (a) Define the different departments of government under National Constitution, (b) Name the officer at the head of each these departments at the present time. 3. Discuss briefly how a bill may become a law in the National 4. What is the most important measure before Congress at this time? ' Give reasons. t5. State the qualifications necessary for one to be eligible: (a) the presidency; (b) to the United States Senate; (c) to the Na - al House of Representatives; (d) to the governorship of Nebraska. 16. (a) How many congressional districts in Nebraska? (b) Name congressman from your district. t7. Give the principal provisions in as few words as possible of new law governing the Issuance of teachers' county certificates in »ska 8. Discuss briefly the law relative to the teaching of physiology and hygiene in the public schools of Nebraska. t9. A provision in the school laws of Nebraska reads: "No ey belonging to the district shall be paid for teaching to any but lly qualified teachers." (a) Give argument for or against this (b) Who is a legally qualified teacher? 10. A ruling of the state superintendent says: "A contract be - tween the school board and the teacher is a mutual obligation, equal - ling upon both parties." (a) Give reasons that would justify the teacher or the board in annulling a contract, (b) Discuss the duty imposed upon the teacher to live up to the terms of her contract uitil released by the school board. PENMANSHIP 1. State definitely what should be done the first year in pen- I HI 2. Do you insist upon a definite position in writing exercises? </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 13. Name five points to be considered in estimating the excel - ce of the pupil's work in writing. 4. Discuss briefly the importance of each of the following ele - ments of good writing: Legibility, rapidity, neatness. i5. A* a specimen of your penmanship, write a letter applying a position as a teacher. ORTHOGRAPHY. 11. Mark the silent letters in the following words: Victuals, ards, sou-nee, often, heirs, gnaw, eyesight, acknowledge, awkward, thorough. Write the plural of each of the following, and give the rule t applies to those in Hal try, half, X, valley and church. tS. Write the present active participle of study, shoot, singe, i, sin, sign, tan. and carve. Give the rule that applies to each of last two. 4. Give the meaning of each of the following affixes, and word illustrating each: circum, sub, er, trans, and ness. 15. Give the diacritical marking of the first vowel in each of following: salmon, almond, apricot, homage, granary, alternate, ron, precedent, jugular, and they. 6-10. In the following list some words are spelled correctly and some incorrectly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly. Give complete written analysis of the following problems, 1. Elmina is 25 years old, and four-fifths of her age Is 4 years less than twice Elmira's age; required Elmira's age. 2. A gave 24 dollars for a watch, and V4 4- % of this is 4 times what he paid for the chain; required the cost of the chain. 3. How many times ia % contained in 4? appeal incalaubta appall alspice inexhaustible perceive cancell statment costume chieftian sugar rnissinforiu culinery seminary excel emmlgrant liquify lodgment milage miniture su prise potatoe tranquility thieving vegetable MENTAL ARITHMETIC. PART I. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 FWhen E was married he was 27 years old, and % of his age years more than % of his wife's age; required the age of his 15. A man receives $3 a day for his labor, and forfeits $1 each he is idle, and at the expiration of 30 days receives $50; how many ■ was ho idle? PART II. RAPID COMPUTATION. The superintendent will detach this list before distributing and give exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for comple- Then collect answer papers and pin to Part I. Applicants will write numbers of problems and answers only. 1. A man sold 13 cows, then bought 10, and then had 12; how many had ho at first? I Eight times a number, divided by 4, multiplied by 6, divided S, multiplied by 5, divided by 10, equals how many times the num- 3. % of 96 are how many times three-fifths of 10? 4. A bought 60 cows, and sold % of them to B, and three-fifths of the remainder to C; how many cows had he remaining? 5. Three-fifths of $40 is 2 times what A gave for a bureau; what was the cost of the bureau? THEORY AND ART OP TEACHING 1. What ir, tho practical use of arithmetic? 2. What is the educative value of geography? 3. How does the study of reading train the mind to think? 14. How may self-consciousness be overcome, (a) on the part of teacher; (b) on tho part of the pupil? 5. What is the highest qualification of a teacher? Give your reasons. 6. Why do pupils know so little after having studied so much? Do you use corporal punishment as a means of securing ends? Olvo your nea^ 8. 1) i« value of habit in education. 9. Wh;i ation should the teacher make for each day's work? 10. Give a model program, showing both study and recitation ds for tho average rural school. DRAWING. 1. (a) Define 'Point of Sight." (b) What governs the location of tho point ul sight? .- one definite rule ion oi converging lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 Give in order, the steps taken and the directions that should be given a grammar grade class in making a drawing from an object using a book as the object. io-6. Represent to the right and below the level of the eye yon box with the cover partly withdrawn. L7-8. Represent a group of three vegetables in which one is in t hidden from view by the other two. 9-10. Represent a roadway extending directly in front of the observer. Represent a fence or a row of trees at one side of the road. ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 11. Supply the proper punctuation marks in the following: Hav - detained you so long already I shall not trespass longer on your ience but before concluding I wish you to observe this truth. i2. Use correctly in original sentences the following words: nciple, expedient, eminence, impetuous, awful. §3. In not over 100 words, write a brief anecdote of an animal, ing the following introduction: To many animals the sense of smell of more importance than the sense of sight or hearing. 14. In the ordinary use of language, what word or words do we instead of each of the following: Dawn, billow, steed, azure, fowl - dazzling, crimson, vale, valor, heavens? t5. Write a letter to a school officer, or some person for whom have worked, asking for a letter of recommendation. (Give special ntion to form, punctuation, and neatness.) 6-10. In not over 200 words, write an account of the recent earthquako on the Pacific coast. PHYSIOLOGY. 1. Describe the spine. 2. Briefly describe the difference between muscles and tendons as to (a) structure, (b) use. I. Name four fluids which aid in digestion. 4. State the effects of alcohol upon the will. 5. State two uses of the blood. 6. Define and give use of two kinds of nerves. 7. Name the parts of the eye. S. Discuss the cultivation and preservation of the sense of touch. 9. Describe the structure and growth of the hair. L10. Mention five of the most important hygienic topics to teach dren of the first four grades. AGRICULTURE. 1. What is the purpose of tilling the soil soon after a rain? 2. How do grasses tend to renew worn-out land? 3. Name three insects, each useful in a different way, and tell how each 11 useful. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 4. What three things are necessary to seed germination? L5. There is always an open or "dead" furrow in the middle of plowed "land." Give two reasons why plants will not grow well In ch a furrow. Distinguish between insecticides and fungicides U7. Give two ways in which nature often protects plants from t. How may the farmer do it? 8. Name two advantages of raising pedigreed stock 9. Name three distinct classes of farm pests. 10. How may the district school become a miniature experiment rtation? GEOMETRY 1. Define circle, secant, tangent, radius, arc 2. Theorem: Two triangles are equal if two sides and the in - cluded angle of the one are equal to two sides and the included angle of the other. Prove. L3. Theorem: The diagonals of a parallelogram bisect each oth - . Prove. 4. Problem: How many sides has a polygon, the sum of whose interior angles is equal to eight right angles? Solve. t5. Problem: To construct an equilateral triangle having given • sides. 6. Problem: To inscribe a circle in a given triangle 7. Find the segments of a line 15 inches long divided into ex - treme and mean ratio. t8. Problem: Upon the diagonal of a rectangle 24 in. by 10 . a triangle is formed equivalent to the rectangle in area. Find the titude and the base of the triangle. ALGEBRA. PI. (a) Give the degree of each term of the following expression: +7abc+x* y* (b) What are simultaneous equations? A' rite the formula for dividing the sum of the cubes of two quantities by the sum of the quantities. Find the H C. F. and the L. C. M. of 6x* +x —2: 2x* f 7x— 4, and -7x+3 11 11 — H • b a* b* 4. Simplify -f- 11 11 a* b* a b S. A rectangle has its length 4 feet greater and its width 3 test leas than the side of an equivalent square. Find its dimensions ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 E6. A sum of money at simple Interest amounts to $2800 in three ■s! and to $2900 in (our years. Determine the sum and the rate of rest. solve 3x — V4x-x* 9. A rectangular field contains 25 acnes, and its length is to its width as 8 to 5. Determine the dimensions. 10. Solve 2x-3y«2 GRAMMAR. El. Name the part of speech to which each word in the follow - sentence belongs: O. come with me and see our little pet running ) in tho park. tl. Write a sentence containing only the following parts of •h and in tho order named: A numeral adjective, a common , a transitive verb in the active voice, an object complement, an adverb of manner. LI. Give the principal parts of the following verbs: fight, set, ng, have, hide, and sing. 4. Write one sentence containing three nouns in the nomina - tive case, each one used differently. Write the plural form of each of the following: hero, ashes, -in-law, oasis, domino, glory, deer, soliloquy, this, and gulf. Diagram, or if you prefer, analyze: The first of our native flowers to appear was the tvpulica, whxch I found on April fourth. 7. Parse the italicised words in the foregoing sentence. 8. Correct: (a) She gave it to I and Clara. ( b ) Those sort of people are disagreeable. (c) The least said, the sooner mended. (d) Easter ia observed in most all countries. (e) Neither John nor Mary were excused. 19. Select, classify, and give use of each dependent clause found the following: The Italian boy of Venice has the same loving regard for the life of a pigeon that the Dutch boy of Holland has for that of the stork. It has been believed for centuries that a flock of carrier-pig - eons once saved the city, when it was nearly conquered by enemies. 10. A. E. Nelson has been your bookkeeper. He wishes to find employment in Chicago. Write a letter of recommendation for him 7. Expand (2x+3v) 5 •3x+\4x =2 2xy— x* =7 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 ARITHMETIC rl. (a) Express the following numbers In the Roman notation 514, 617, 216, 1906. t(b) In a certain number there are 4 tens and 7 units in the rd period, 3 hundreds, 8 tens and five units in the second period, hundreds, 6 tens and 9 units in the first period. Express this mber in the Arabic notation. \dd the following: J. (a) Find the L. C M. of 84, 168, 252, and 420. (b) Explain as you would to a class. E4-. Of a certain farm one-sixth is in pasture, % is under cul - tion, and the remainder is woodland. If the woodland is 50 s, how many acres are there in the whole farm? t5. A gentleman left Omaha and traveled until his watch waa . 3 min. too slow; how many degrees had he traveled, and In direction? 6. (a) From the sum of 67.5 and .54 take their difference, (b) From the sum of 64.5 and .015 take their product. How many acres are there in a rectangular field 145 rds. lone and 86 rds. wide? 8. If it cost $84 to shingle a roof 36 ft. long and 21 ft. wide, what will it cost to shingle a roof 33 ft. long and 27 ft. wide? 9. What sum of money at 4 % per cent simple interest will produce $75-40 Interest in 3 yr. 4 mo.? tlO. A tax of $18,000 is levied upon a town which contains 1 polls, ■■■owed at $1.50 each, and which has taxable property asses - at $1,200,000. The town receives from the state $3600 as its share the railroad tax, etc. Find the rate of taxation, and the tax paid Brown, if his property is assessed at $5960, and if he pays for oil. READING kl. Give the author of each of the following: (a) Little Or - t Annie, (b) Little Boy Blue, (c) Eight Cousins, (d) Man out a Country, (e) Snow-Bound. 2. Define articulation. How may faulty articulation be over- 153.87 (b) $32.54 (C) $15.92 4.83 16.87 4.86 15.00 3.64 .98 8.34 .58 13.24 .76 43.41 6.88 42.79 24.48 15.62 9.24 4.79 8.43 .89 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 3. How' may too rapid reading be corrected? L4. How would you correct a child who gives indifferent atten - in the reading class? 5. How do you teach your class to "look up" words in the die - tionary? 16. Should children read stories when they cannot pronounce all words orally? 7. Why .should a child be carefully trained in reading aloud? 8. What is literature? 9. Name two stories that possess educational value for pri - mary pupils. 110. Give a short quotation from each of the following poems tell the author of each: (a) Thanatopis, (b) The Psalm of Life, Maud Muller, (d) Old Ironsides, (e) The Raven. BOTANY Answer any seven. tl. Give examples of monocotyledonous and dicotyledonous ts. How could you tell whether a little plant just coming through ground is monocotyledonous or dicotyledonous? 2. What is meant by growing buds? What by resting buds? 3. What purposes may roots serve? Give examples of each. 4. Give the offices of the leaf. 5. Define: Stamen, perianth, receptacle, calyx, berry. 6. Discuss occurrence and use of chlorophyll. 7. Discuss the structure of the cell. 8. Discuss the Marchantia as to occurrence, growth, and propa - gation. PHYSICS. 1. Give law for displacement of floating and of sinking bodies. 2. Explain the force pump, using a drawing. 3. Define a lever. By drawings illustrate the different classes. A carriage is suddenly stopped. The persons in the carriage said to be "thrown" out. Are they thrown? Explain. LI, Why can a boy throw an ounce of lead farther than an ce of cork? 6. Does evaporation occur from ice on a pond in winter? Prove your answer. 7. On what two things does the length of sound waves depend? 8. Distinguish between reflection and refraction. 9. By means of a drawing, show the effect of a double convex lens upon light rays. 10. Define (a) Volt, (b) Ohm. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 HISTORY. 1. Tell of the origin of the name "America." 2. Give a brief account of DeSoto's discoveries and explora- 13. Make a statement of not more than two sentences concern - each of the following: Patroons. Puritans, Huguenots, William n, James Oglethorpe. 4. Tell of the services of Benjamin Franklin in aiding the Rev - olution and in forming the new republic. 5. State the cause of the war of 1812. 6. Give the results of the war with Mexico. 17. Mention the most important three problems that confronted nation at the close of the Civil War. tvame the opposing generals in each of the following bat - and tell to which side each belonged: Saratoga, New Orleans, 1a Vista, Gettysburg. Manila Bay. 9. Name, in your opinion, the most important five events of Roosevelt's administration. 110. Tell something of each of the following: Daniel Boone, riet Beacher Stowe, Cyrus \V. Field, EH Whitney, E. Benjamin rows. GEOGRAPHY 1. Distinguish between (a) river basin and river system; (b) mountain chain and mountain range. Name the line or lines, indicating the boundaries of each tone. What determines the location of these lines? 3. Starting east from the Prime Meridian, what lands and what oceans are crossed by the Equator? ti. Compare the efficiency and the justice and the opportunities er the government of Great Britain with those under the govern - it of the United States. 5. Compare the races as to the number of people in each. 6. Including wealth, manufactures, commerce, possessions, pow - er, and civilization, which do you consider the greatest country of Eurasia? Give reasons for your answer. Iln not more than ten lines, give the principal features of surface and drainage of Nebraska. 8. What and where are the following: Danube, Hongkong, Port Arthur, Vesuvius, and Venezuela? Name the most important harbor of the Atlantic coast of the ted States. Why? 10. What do you consider the chief results to be attained in the teaching of geography? </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 JUNE 15 AND 16, 1906. ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Mark the first vowel In each of the following: bravo, gratis, financier, lichen, recess, isolate, docile, comely, diploma, cleanly. t2. Mark the accent in each of the following words: mis-chie - s, ex-qui-site, ve-he-ment, hos-pi-ta-ble, a-re-a, va-ga-ry, in-fam-ous, il-cle, com-bat-ant, ad-mi-ra-bly. 3. Distinguish between these synonyms: worth and value, hur - ry and hasten, sufficient and enough, empty and vacant, noted and notorious. Use the following homonyms in sentences: cite, site, sight; , by, buy; rite, wright, right, write. 5. Define: Syllable, monosyllable, trisyllable, polysyllable and give an example of each. K6-10. Some of the following are correct, some in-correct. Write correctly : Give complete arithmetical solutions to the following: LI. Two-fifths of A's money, increased by % of his money, als 69 dollars; how much money has A? 12. $60 is three-fifths of what B gave for a horse, and the cost the horse, increased by its three-fifths is 5 times what he paid a sleigh ; required the cost of the sleigh. 13. Janson's age diminished by its one-fourth and one-fifth, is years, and his age is four-fifths of his uncle's age; required the of each. A thief stole three-fifths of Harry's money, and before he : caught spent % of it; the remainder, which was $20 less than stole, was given back; how much money had Harry? 15. A man bought a horse, cow and sheep for $105; how much he pay for each, provided the cow cost 4 times as much as the sp, and the horse four times as much as the cow? impliment jamb pheasant instill oppurtunity nominative reccomend propel parliament Great Britian counterfeit hoing renoun aggrement dayly legins abominable merchantile bargain anteak sedentery admissible vigilence accompanying umberalla MPVTH A I </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Part 2 The superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and Itive exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion ir.*-n collect answer papers and pin to Part one. Applicants will write numbers of problems and answers only. 1. Four times Susan's age + 3 times her age — 5 times her Me, + 2 times her age, — 3 times her age, equals 13 years; bow old is Susan? 2. A man bought a horse for 175 dollars paid 31 dollars for his Keeping, and sold him for 250 dollars; what was the gain? man, having 50 cows, sold four-ttfths of them, and then ught 32 cows; how many had he then? 4. A gave 70 dollars for a watch, and three-sevenths as much for a chain, and sold them both for 90 dollars; required the loss. 5. B's horse cost 200 dollars, and three-fifths of its cost is 5 limes the cost of the sleigh; required the cost of the sleigh. PENMANSHIP. 1. (a) How much time should be devoted daily to writing? (b) What hour of the day is best adapted for this exercise? State the relative attention form and movement should re - ve in the different grades. 3. Give physiological reasons why beginners should make large 4. (a) Define muscular movement, (b) Mention three ad - vantages of the muscular movement. 6. Would you suggest as a suitable method for teaching cor- rect form a formal analysis of all the letters? Give reasons. ( Fifty credits for applicant's penmanship as shown by all answer papers.) CIVIL GOVERNMENT. 1. (a) Name three federal offices for the District of Nebraska (b) Give the function of each. 2. On what constitutional ground is the opposition to Senator Smoot of Utah based? 3. Distinguish between militia and regular army. 4. (a) What is the function of the Supreme Court? (b) Why *re the questions in this court not submitted to a jury? 6. State briefly the methods of electing the following officers ta) President; (b) IT. S. Senator; (c) Congressman. 6. What .is the significance of a writ of habeas corpus and what justifies its being called sometimes "The bulwark of liberty." L7. State clearly the difference between direct and indirect tax - on. 8. Name and locate the various state institutions for the men- </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 9. (a) Wbat Is the date of the annual meeting for rural school districts this year? (b) Give the three most important items of busi - ness to be transacted in and for every rural school district at such meeting. 110. (a) Give the sources of the funds from which is derived state apportionment of school moneys, (b) What are the pro - ons of law governing its distribution? BOOKKEEPING. 1. Define posting, notary, power of attorney, bills payable. C. O. D 2. Write telegram addressed to M. E Smith &amp; Co., Omaha, Nebraska, ordering shipped by fast freight twelve dozen pairs of overalls, assorted sizes. 3. (a) Write a letter of remittance, (b) Write a letter ac- rwiedging -the receipt of a letter of remittance. 4. Mention six essentials to a good business letter. 5. Give the uses of the check book. 6-10. The following is James Johnson's trial balance for the year. Make out the balance sheet showing the condition of his bus- $3125 $3125 AGRICULTURE 1. How should a poor and shallow soil be plowed? Why? Lribe a simple schoolroom experiment to show rise of ter in soil. 3. Name Nebraska's greatest forage crop, and state how the present method of farming is wasteful of its food products. 4. Describe the work of the codling moth, and suggest a meth - od of combating the same. I State the advantage to be gained from selecting seed corn m the field rather than from the crib. 6. Distinguish between plant diseases and plant pests, and name one of each. L7. Distinguish between the weather predictions of the U. ther Bureau and those of the almanac. Dr. tea Johnson $ 200 ;. (Inv. $200) . 800 Re&lt; 250 1 Bills Pay 2 S0 tnse 23 Andrews 300 Cash 1550 420 Discount 2 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 E8. In not more than seventy-five words, distinguish between versified farming' and "rotation of crops," and state the advan - es of each. 9. Name, in your opinion, the best breed of (a) beef cattle; airy cattle; (c) draft horses; (d) road horses. It. During the school year you make five excursions with your class in elementary agriculture, to nearby farms. State the object of each excursion. THEORY AND ART Ahat is the test of the child s ability to study? 12. What is the advantage of the child's conversing freely with teacher? 3. How do you deal with slang in your school? 4. Discuss the place and relative value of oral teaching as compared to book study. 5. Distinguish between theory and fact. 6. Name three studies that train the memory, and two that de - li the reasoning powers. Name three natural incentives to study. Name two artificial Incentives to study. 8. Show the advantage of variety not only in the busy work he primary grades but to some extent in all school work. 9. Select a familiar poem or story and show how it may be used as a language lesson. 10. What is the relation of a child's experience and environ - ment to his reading? PHYSIOLOGY. 1. Describe the structure of a joint 2. Distinguish between voluntary and involuntary muscles 3. Name the digestive fluids that act principally on: (a) su - gars and starches; (b) fats; (c) proteids (meats, eggs, etc.). 4. State the difference between chyme and chyle. 5. Trace the course of a particle of blood plasma that has es - caped through a capillary wall back to the blood vessel. What is meant by reflex action? Give examples. 7. Enumerate the principal organs of taste, the accessory organs 8. What is the relation of the so-called "black heads" to the Skin, to cleanliness? B9. In case of disease of the alimentary canal what food should given and why? 10. Win is alcohol a good medicine in collapse? ENGLISH COMPOSITION 1 Write a list of five words, each of which, without change In spelling or pronunciation, may be used in two or more distinct sig - nifications. Illustrate. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 CGive one sentence illustrating a correct, followed by another parenthesis illustrating an incorrect use of each of the following •ds: Party, don't, character, transpire, learn. L3. Illustrate in original sentences the correct use of the comma, dash, nimjk quotation mai t4. The fields are brown, the sky a leaden gray, the trees are with the exception of a few stray rattling tufts; there is no g of birds, and the bleak wind whistles mournfully, (a) What time year is it? (b) How do you know? 5. Make an outline of the topics to be considered in teaching letter writing. DRAWING 1 What is meant by Outline Drawing? Construction lines? Represent a simple object by using only horizontal am! tical lines. B3. How should drawing be taught in connection with the study leaves? 4. Arrange a design in the form of a rosette. L5-6. Represent an open crayon box below the level of the eye directly in front. Represent a group of four objects in which one object rests n the other three. 19-10. Represent an outdoor scene showing the horizon line mp and a fence. GEOMETRY. Select eight — 1. Distinguish between problem and theorem. I Theorem: From a point without a straight line one per - dlcular and only one can be drawn to that line. Prove. 3. State the theorems having for their conclusion: Two tri - angles are equal. L4. Problem: Having given the three sides of a triangle, to truct the triangle. 5. Problem: The area of a rhombus is 100 sq. ft. and one di - agonal is 10 ft. Find the other diagonal. 6. Theorem: The sum of the squares of the two legs of a right triangle is equal to the square of the hypotenuse. Prove. 7. Problem: To find a fourth proportional to three given lines. 18. Theorem: The sum of the interior angles of a polygon is al to two right angles taken as many times less two as the figure sides. Prove. t9. Problem: Given a line AB and two points M and N on the } side of the line. To draw from M to X a line which shall touch line AB and whose length shall be a minimum. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 ALGEBRA El. Define (a) power, (b) exponent, (c) fraction, (d) quadratic tion, (e) linear equation. 1 n x + n felt, _-| = n x-{-n nx 5. A's age is now two-fifths of B's. Eight years ago A's age was two-ninths of B's. Find their ages. 6. Solve by comparison: 2x — 5y = 66 I The sum of the two digits of a number is 9, and if the num - is divided by the sum of its digits the quotient is 5. Find the ber. xpand (2x — 3y)&amp; lultiply l 4\x 10. The perimeter of a rectangular field is 60 rods. Its area is 200 sq. rds. Find its dimensions. ARITHMETIC. *-&gt; 1. From the sum of 261, 3078, 5712, 312, 8936, 20386, 58724, JW8, 532 and 7028, subtract 72964. then multiply the remainder by 708, and divide that product by 6974. 2. Prove that a common divisor of 24 and 32 is also an exact divisor of their sum and of their difference. tZ. A farmer has three farms containing respectively 168, 216, 240 acres, which he wishes to divide into fields of equal size, ing the fields as large as possible; how many fields will each farm e? Tell the effect on the value of a fraction when you (a) multi - the numerator; (b) divide the denominator. a) Multiply the sum of 76.5 and .45 by their difference (b) Divide the product of 46.5 and .32 by .1 of .1 16. Illustrate as you would to a class the difference between 9 ft. and 9 ft. sq. (b) How many acres in a field 80 rds. long and rds. wide? §In a wagon load of ear corn the wagon and corn weigh 3900 ; the wagon weighs 1100 lbs. What is the corn worth at 39 cents bu? 8. A invests $3 as often as B invests $4 and C invests $5, and they together invest $24,000; then, A withdraws $2 as often as B withdraws $3 and C withdraws $4, and they together withdraw $18, 000; how much has each still invested? 2. Factor: (a)3x* + I x* + ax — bx - ab 3. Find the H. C. F. of 2x« + Ux 3 + 1 Ix + 3 and 3x« + llx" + 9x+ 2 3x+ 2y = 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 K9. A dry goods dealer bought $2460.30 worth of Persian lawn, marked it 33% per cent above cost. He sold half of it at the ;ed price, and then sold the rest at 10 per cent off the marked How much did he gain? BIO. Find the simple interest on $73.42 for 5 yr. 8 mo. 10 dy. 4 per cent. GRAMMAR. II. Write only one sentence containing only the following and e order named: A common noun, an adjective phrase, a transi - verb in the passive voice, an adverb of degree and an adverb of ler. • 2. Illustrate interrogative adjective, interrogative adverb, and interrogative pronoun. 3. In connection with what part of speech is each of the fol - lowing used: conjugation, declension, comparison? 4. Give all the inflections of the verb lie (recline) in the present perfect and past tenses, active voice, indicative mode. 5. Construct a sentence containing an adjective. Expand this adjective into an adjective phrase, and then into an adjective clause. 6. Select, classify, and give use of each phrase in the following :ices: (a) He caught a fish in his net; (b) [n the morning John started on his journey; (c) He sang softly fn his sleep; (d) Birds of a feather flock together. 7. i italicized words in the following : (a) What are you paving for wheat? (b) We knee seen your friend. t. Correct any errors found in the following: (a) He signed df, "Yours respectively." (b) Come and see me. (c) He laid e bed all day. (d) He don't say, "Was you there?" 9. Write sentences to illustrate participles with three different forms of ending, and indicate the part of speech represented by each participle used. 10. Write a letter of congratulation to a friend who has earned •With Honor" certificate under the new law. READING. 1. (a) Make and name the diacritical marks used to indicate all the sounds of "a"; (b) give an example of each. Distinguish between the two common faults of monotony and sing-song in oral reading. By the rude bridge that arched the flood. Their flag to April's breeze unfurled; Here once the embattled farmers stood. And flred the shot heard round the world." — Emerson Describe as you would to a fourth reader class the picture given In the above stanza. 4. What preparation do you make before assigning a lesson in reading to a class in the fourth reader? </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Give authors of the following: (a) Innocents Abroad, (b) imona. (c) Hans Brlnker, (d) The Scarlet Letter, (e) Wild Animals Have Known. 6. Name a book you have recently read that has added to your general culture and education. Explain in what way. How can you tell when a child has mastered a new word? 8. Suggest an easy drill in phonics for first reader pupils. 9. What should the reading lesson aim to accomplish for the pupils in the seventh and eighth grades? 10. (a) Give a short quotation from Hiawatha, (b) Give a brief sketch of the author of this poem. HISTORY. 1. On what did Spain, France and England, respectively, base their claims to American territor Give an account of the founding of the Massachusetts Bay Colony, and state why it grew so rapidly during the reign of Charles I. 3. Name the opening and closing events of the Revolutionary War. Give dates. Li. From what sources did the framers of our Constitution get r ideas of government? 5. Was slavery the real cause of the Civil war? Justify your answer 6. (a) What is the Klnkaid Law? (b) Explain "Ship Subsidy." I Name, in your opinion, the five greatest American inventions, five greatest living American writers, and the five greatest living rlcan statesmen. 18. Give the date of each of the following: Inauguration of ihlngton. Emancipation Proclamation, Mexican War, Admission of Mfca. 9. Name the war in which each of the following battles took place: AntieUm, Saratoga, Manila Bay, Palo Alto, Chickamauga. 10. Who are your authorities on United States history? Why? BOTANY 1 . Discuss the resting stage of the embryo, 2. Name some plants that are cultivated for their buds 3. What precautions with regard to the roots are necessary In transplanting trees? Why? 4. Why should transplanting be done in the winter or early spring? 5. What part of the following plants do we eat, the fruit or the seed: Corn, wheat, peanut, string beans, hickory nut? 6. Distinguish between fruit and seed 7. Parasitic plants have practically no leaves. Explain. 8. Name some plants, the stems of which are wed as food 9. Give the distinguishing characteristics of the Legumlnosa. 10. Give general discussion of bacteria. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define erosion, basin, delta, cyclone. 2. What is the earth's size, shape, movement? 3. Describe and account for the trade winds. 4. Name two important canals. What commercial advantages does each afford? 5. Compare France and Germany in (a) size, (b) products, (c) manufactures, (d) people, (e) government. §6. Contrast the achievements of the Caucasian race with those any other race of men. 7. Distinguish between export and domestic trade. t«. Compare the various sections of Nebraska as to climate, alti - e, occupations and commerce. 19. What are the natural commercial advantages of the Mis - ippi valley? 10. What and where are the following: Baltic, Havana, Madrid, Calcutta, Yokohoma? PHYSICS 1. Define gravitation. 2. Distinguish between mass and volume. 3. What is work? Give an illustration. 4. Explain the siphon. 5. Give two important effects beat may have upon a substance. 6. Distinguish between noise and musical sounds. 7. Wht are sympathetic vibrations? 8. What is meant by simple and what by complex vibrations? Distinguish translucent from transparent substances, and e examples of each. 10. Give two effects of the electric current. JULY 20 AND 21, 1906. BOOKKEEPING. 1. Define the two general methods of keeping accounts. 2. Give the general rules for journalizing (a) interest, (b) dis- count. 3. Name two ways of finding the present worth of a business. §4. (a) Explain the difference between drafts payable after date i drafts payable after sight, (b) What is meant by "acceptance" applied to drafts? 5. Explain the meaning and value of a protest as applied to negotiable paper. 6-10. James Moore began business June 1st, 1906, investing cash, $2,000. June 2. Paid one month's store rent, $50. June 3. Bought merchandise of M. C. King, for cash, $950. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 June 4. Sold James Donovan, for cash. 45 bbl. flour at $6 per June 5. Bought Mdse. of J. H. Miller, for cash, $240 LJune 6. Sold Jacob Brewer on account, 30 bbls. of flour at $6 bbl. June S. Sold A. Moseley, 20 bbls. of flour, for cash, at $5.50, 10 bbls. of salt at $1.50 per bbl. June 9. Bought Mdse. of J. H. Lane on account, $375.40 June 10. Received cash from Jacob Brewer to apply on ac - i. $144. IJune 11. Received cash from J. H. Lane to apply on account 75.40. Journalize the above items. ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. To which organ, the ear or the eye, should we most appeal In spelling? Discuss fully. 'lea correct combinations of letters, name three other things about words which should be learned in the spelling exercise. 3. Why are rules of so little advantage in learning to spell words in the English langauge ? 4. Indicate the sound of the first vowel in: bade, been, pretty, breath, breathe, learn, much, they, care, what. 15. Construct sentences containing the following words used cor - ly: aviary, iniquity, human, literally, wrest, stationery, station - verdict, capitol, climax. 6-10. Some of the following words are spelled correctly, some Incorrectly. Write all correctly. Great Britian necessary Emm grammer principally Ige sensibly untill psalter instill vigilant assign atmosphere announcment nestings mechanism suprised citizen togather flbors mayor sugar prodigious wholesome CIVICS. 1. Give reasons which led the Constitutional Convention to rvide for (a) two houses of congress; (b) a distinctly different meth - of electing the members of these houses. t Define five personal rights guaranteed by the Constitution the citizens of the U. S. </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 3. On what theory does the general government provide sup - port for public education? 4. Name the cabinet offices and name the present cabinet offi- cers. 5. What cabinet offices have charge of Indian affairs, U. S. mail. Naval Academy at Annapolis, interstate commerce, commercial re - lations with foreign countries? 6. Define direct and indirect taxes. 7. Define the different departments of government under the constitution of the state of Nebraska. 8. Name the officer at the head of each of these departments at the present time. 9. What is the law governing the distribution of the state ap - portionment with relation to (a) length of the school term; (b) the school population of the district? 10. State the duties of the county superintendent under the new law for the certification of teachers with regard to (a) conduct - ing the examination; (b) issuing certificates. PENMANSHIP. 1. Give devices for securing interest in penmanship 2. Which of the systems of penmanship have you observed to be '.he most natural for the child just learning to wri' 3. In correcting illegible, slovenly writing, to w'niih would you attach the more importance, increasing the practice, or stimulating a greater mental effort? 4. If a pupil's writing is too fine or too coarse, what means may he employed to remedy the evil? 5. When should children begin to write wl'.h pen and ink? 6-10. Write as a specimen of your penmanship, a stanza from your favorite poem, or a paragraph from your favorite prose author. MENTAL ARITHMETIC. (live complete analysis to five of ths following problems: :. 20 dollars is 4 dollars more than two thirin of 4 limes what B paid for a chain, and his watch cost 5 times as much as the chain; req.iiv&lt; a the cost of each. Having lost % of my money, I fouud -i o\ wluit I iost, and then had $70; how much had I at first? 3. A man bought a sleigh, horse, and harness for $152; for the sleigh he gave twice as much as for the harness, plus $6, and for the horse 4 times as much as for the harness, plus $6; what did he pay for each? 4. John and Henry can mow 30 acres of grass in a week, and % of what John can mow in a day equals what Henry can mow in a </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 E5. A, B and C found a purse containing $100, which they xl to divide in the proportion of % , % , and 1 V4 ; how much each receive? 16. A, B, and C ate 8 loaves of bread. A furnished 3 loaves I B 5 loaves. C paid the others 24 cents for his share. How ch money should A and B each receive? RAPID DRILL. tiTae superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; collect answer papers and pin to Part 1. Applicants will write bers of problems and answers only. 1. 4 times 50 years Is ten years less than 10 times the age of James; how old is he? 12. If 7 men can do a piece of work in 2% days, how long will require 6 men to do it? IS. B has 27 marbles, and % of B's number equals two-fifths C's number; how many marbles has C? 4. A watch and chain cost $150, and % of the cost of the watch plus $15, equals $95; required the cost of each. 15. A, B, and C. together, earned $70; A earned twice as much B, B twice as much as C; how much did each earn? AGRICULTURE. 1. Why should soil be porous? 2. (a) Name two plants that supply nitrogen to the soil, (b) Name two farm crops that remove chiefly nitrogen from the soil. Name three harmful insects; three useful insects. 4. What two things does every perfect seed contain? 6. Name three ways of propagating plants. 6. Oive two reasons why the farmer should study climatic con - ditions and observe the U S. weather predictions. 7. How does the ration of a dairy cow differ in composition from that of a fattening steer? L8. What is a weed? When are weeds harmful? When bene - 1? It. Name two benefits of school or home gardening to the pupil; to the teacher. 10. Give two reasons for the introduction of elementary agri - culture into our public schools. THEORY AND ART Select any eight. rl. Discuss the maxim: "From the simple to the complex," and how it applies to the study of arithmetic. 2. What is meant by self-teaching? Give two subjects in which self-teaching Is practicable. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 3. Give devices for language teaching in the third, fourth and fifth grades. 4. Discuss the value of map drawing in teaching geography. 5. Give reasons for or against teaching rules and formal pro - cesses in arithmetic. 16. Give your plan of dealing with a seventh grade boy who persistently inattentive. 7. Name some of the rights of children at school. 8. In what book do you find the expression, "Gather up the frag - ments that nothing be lost."? 9. Give some points that should characterize school government. 10. Give the objects of the recitation. 11. What is imagination? 12. Name ten books suitable for a school library. ENGLISH COMPOSITION. 1. Punctuate and capitalize the following: A traveler ran from his bed to examine the weather by mistake he opened the glass door of a cupboard instead of a window landlord cried the astonished man this is very singular weather the night is dark as egypt and smells of cheese. Give five rules for the use of capitals, and illustrate each by a sentence. 13. Write a letter to some publishing company, asking to have address of your paper or magazine changed. 14. Make a list of words corresponding to the following in pro - iciation, but differing in spelling; session, canvass, sealing, cur - t, counsel. Illustrate the differences in meaning. Write a ten or twelve line description of a room in such a way as to suggest the personality of the occupant. PHYSIOLOGY Be brief and to the point. 1. Give five organs found in the abdomen 2. Name the essential parts of the middle and inner ear. 3. Of what use is water to the body? LA. (a) Give the three parts of the brain, (b) Give the mem - es that invest the brain. 15. What is the mechanism of the human voice, 1. e., how are nds produced? 6. Describe the portal circulation. 7. How does nature stop a hemorrhage? 8. How is the head guarded from injury against blows? 19. How does alcohol produce what is known as the strawberry toper's nose? 110. (a) How could you tell from a large incised wound whet li - the bleeding is from an artery or a vein? (b) How would you go ut it to stop the bleeding in each caw? </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 REPORT l*«e pencil for construction work. 1. Represent a border design extending across the page of your fiamiuation paper. Represent a group containing an apple, a ball, a pumpkin, a tato, and a turnip, each in proper proportion as to size. tZ. Represent an out door scene exhibiting the use of (a) cen - r of vision, (b) horizon line, (c) receding lines. Make proper no - tion showing where each of the above appears. 4. Represent in a position to the left of the observer and be - low the level of the eye, a crayon box with lid half-way withdrawn. bf&gt;. State specifically how drawing may be used to advantage in ching (a) arithmetic, (b) geography, (c) nature study, (d) pri - ry language. ARITHMETIC Write the following numbers in words 1 (a) 7543257. (b) 64325460. (c) 500060005. (d) 7564320478. (e) 59876432549. LI. If you were to place a dash or bar over the Roman characters V. X, L. C. D, M, what would be the value of each? 3. Give methods of proof tor subtraction, multiplaction and di- Ttolon 4. A farmer had 66 bushels of oats and 93 bushels of wheat stored in sacks of the largest possible size; how many sacks has he used If they are of equal size? t5. A can dig a ditch in 10 days, B in 12 days, and C in 15 ys. What part of the ditch will be dug if A works 3 days, B 4 vs. and C 5 days? U6 How many days of 8 hours each will it take to count a mil - silver dollars at the rate of 80 a minute? 7. a. Divide 8.05 by .35 b. Divide 80.5 by .35. Divide .805 by .35. 8. In August, when grasshoppers and crickets are most harmful, 69 per cent of a meadow lark's food is composed of these enemies of the farmer. Out of 10 lbs. of food taken by these birds, how many ounces are of this kind? 9. Property worth $6,000 is insured for \ of its value, at % of one per cent. What will be the loss, including premium, to the owner, and to the company, in case of total destruction by fire? 10. The base of a triangular field is 360 yards, and the altitude to C15 feet. How many acres does it contain? </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 ALGEBRA. 1. Write the symbols of operation, and the symbols of aggre - gation. 2. Factor (a) x* +87x+86 nplify 4. If from % of a certain number 3 be subtracted, the remain - der is 4 less than the number. Required the number. 5. Required the square root of: a&lt; 4a" — -| h 2a* — 12a+9 9 3 PKxpand bv formula, putting all your work on the answer paper, x 2 8. Solve: y READING. 1. Define a diphthong. Name the proper diphthongs. What do you require as written work of a third grade class, ing "The Children's Hour" for a lesson? 3. How do you change from script to print in a primary read- ing class? 4. Define melody. Why is it important? 15. How would you direct an advanced class in gaining the ught from this quotation referring to Sir Humphrey Gilbert: "Do not fear! Heaven is as near," He said, "by water as by land." 6. W r hat division would you make of a twenty minute recitation period in a sixth grade reading class? 7. Name ten standard authors 8. Where in literature do we (Choose any five from this list.) find the following characters: Ichabod Crane John Alden Lochinvar Adam Bede Enoch Arden Maud Muller Poor Richard Sir Launfal Hamlet Oliver Twist 9. Describe one of the above characters briefly. ■ia*+72alH-l«b* Jit— 15 2»4-9a-(-20 a2-t-8a— 33 a* -f7a— M ■ ilve by addition and subtraction: 5x+y =13 4x+3y=17 XV = K </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 P10. What effects in the following lines from Whittier's 'Kan- Em i grants :" "We cross the prairies, as of old, The Pilgrims crossed the sea, To make the West, as they the East, The homestead of the free!" GEOMETRY Select any eight. 1. Define corollary, right angle, axiom, geometry. 2. Theorem: Two straight lines perpendicular to a third straight line are parallel. Prove. S. Define parallelogram, trapezoid, rhombus, rectangle, polygon Li Problem: To construct an isosceles triangle having given base and the altitude. 5. Theorem: The area of a triangle is equal to one-half the product of the base by the altitude. Prove. L6. Theorem: Two triangles having an angle of the one equal an angle of the other, and the including sides proportional, are iUr. Prove. 7. Problem: To inscribe a regular hexagon in a given circle. g. Problem: Find the area of a circle whose radius is 17 indie.. 9. Theorem: The angles at the base of an isosceles trapezoid are equal. Prove. 10. Problem: Find the locus of a point at a given distance from two fixed points. GRAMMAR 11. Name the part of speech of each word in the following tence: "Build thou more stately mansions, O, my soul!" 2. Use i be following in sentences: (a) Past indicative active form of mic. (b) Present perfect indicative active form of ic rite, (c) Past perfect indicative passive form of freete. (d ) Future perfect indicative active form of wear, (ej Present perfect indicative active form of flat. 3. Give a comparison of the following words: remarkable, far, good, much, bad. 14. Write sentences using the word that (a) as an adjective. ) as a pronoun, (c) as a conjunction. 5. Name the kinds of sentences as to form and as to use. C. Mention the simple subject and the simple predicate in: (a) Come home Friday morning, (b) What can we do? (c) What success It was! (d) When will the guns of the enemy appear? Parse each word in: (a) He went home, (b) It is rain </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 8. Write correctly: (a) It wasn't (I, me) that did it. (b) (Whom, who) do you think it was? (c) Have you ever (sung, sang) this tune? (d) We must catch (them, those) horses, (e) The miser gives nothing to (anybody, nobody). 9. Define participle, infinitive. Illustrate each L10. Write a letter renewing your subscription to The Nebraska cher. UNITED STATES HISTORY. 1. Name an explorer of Spain, of France, and of England, and tell the region each explored. 2. Tell of the founding of the Jamestown colony, its purpose, and development. 3. Name five causes that led to the Revolutionary War. 4. Discuss briefly the Constitutional Convention. 5. What territory has the U- S. acquired by purchase? 6. Name the states that belonged to the Southern Confederacy. 7. Give some positive statement concerning each of the follow- ing: Horace Greeley, J. Sterling Morton, James A. Garfleld; Ruth - erford B. Hayes, Andrew Jackson. 8. Give the causes and the results of the Spanish American War. 19. (a) Of what advantage will the Panama Canal be to the ited States? (b) How long a lease has the U. S. on the canal ie? 10. What amendment to the V. S. Constitution is being agitated strongly at the present time? GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define latitude, tributary, rotation, equator, monsoon In what longitude is a place that is one- fourth the way ind the earth weft from the prime meridianV-v^hat time would have when it was noon at the prime meridian? 3. Name and locate five of the world's greatest seas. 4. What form of government has each of the following: Eng - land, China, Brazil, United States? 15. What race is found in largest numbers in Africa, South erica. North America, Europe, Asia? 16. Give not more than two places where each of the following produced in large quantities: rubber, coffee, tea, diamonds, corn. 7. Of what does the commerce of Nebraska consist? L8. Name three articles that are exported from the United State*, two that are imported in large quantities. L9. Give an account of one of the principal religions of the Id. 10. Locate the following: (Select five) Everglades, Bad Lands, National Park, Transvaal, Canal zone, Manchuria, Palestine, Mt. Blanc, America, Selvas, Palisades, Maelstrom, Mt. Vernon, The Dec- </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 BOTANY. Select any eight. 1. What are cotyledons? 2. What changes take place in the seed during germination? 3. Define accessory buds, terminal buds, winter buds. 4. Whence does the growing plant obtain the salts used in its growth? Whence comes the carbon? Tell how the stem of an exogen grows in size, also how it ws in length. C. Define stipule, venation, petiole, pinnate, as applied to leaves. 7. Discuss two methods of pollenation. L8. Name two examples of simple fruit; two of aggregate fruit; d two of stone fruit. . L9. Give discussion of occurrence, appearance, and propagation Protococcus. 10. Give discussion of root pressure in the growing plant. PHYSICS Select any eight 1. Give definition of force. 2. How do you find the specific gravity of a solid? 3. Describe the structure of a barometer. How far will a body fall in five seconds provided it starts m nest and is acted upon by gravitation alone? 5. Define equilibrium, inertia. 6. Distinguish between kinetic and potential energy Name a conductor and a non-conductor of heat. Give one •tration of a practical use of each. 8. Give illustrations of the practical use of the inclined plane the pulley, the wheel and axle, and the lever. 9. Explain the speaking tube, 10. Give the law for intensity of illumination. 11. Explain the mutual action of parallel currents AUGUST 17 AND 18, 1906 BOOKKEEPING. 1. Explain the meaning and value of a protest as applied to negotiable paper. 2. State when to debit and when to credit bills payable; bills receivable. 3. Write a negotiable note 4. What is meant by endorsement? What legal effect has it? 5. Write a letter of application for a position as cashier in 6-10. Journalize the following </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 Jan. 10, 1906 — Continued my business with the following re - sources and liabilities: Cash $3000, Mdse. $2000, bills receivable $500, bills payable $350; book accounts — John Anderson $75, Howard Hall $50. 11. — Sold to Joseph Smith, merchandise $125, receiving in ment, cash $35, his note for $50, balance on account. 12 — Bought of H. Johnson, on account, merchandise $700. d for set of office records $8. Jan. 13 — A fire in the basement of the store destroyed $200 of stock. No insurance. IJan. 14 — Howard Hall having failed and assigned his property bankruptcy, his account was settled on a basis of 50 per cent. MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part 1. ANALYSIS. 1. A watch and chain cost $150, and % of the cost of the watch, olus $15, equals $95; required the cost of each. Analyze. lost two-thirds of my money, but found two-thirds of what st. I then had $70. How much had I at first. 13. At $ % a bushel, how many bushels of salt can be bought $18? ti. A can do a certain piece of work in 6 days, and B in 12 s. In what time can A and B together do the work? I A, B, and C ate 8 loaves of bread. A furnished 3 loaves, I B 5 loaves. C paid the others 24 cents for his share. How ch money should A and B each receive? Part II. tThe superintendent will detach this list before distributing, and z exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; n collect answer papers and pin to Part 1. Applicants will write aber of problems and answers only. II. If% of a yard of cloth costs four-fifths of a dollar, what will of a yard cost? 2. If two times a number, increased by 8, equals three times the number, what is the number? 3. A grocer paid $6.40 for a bushel of cranberries; how shall he sell them a quart to gain 2 cents a pint? 4. Three-fourths of 8 per cent, is what per cent, of 30 per cent. 5. Having % of a bushel of apples, I gave % of them away; what part of a bushel remained? PENMANSHIP. Bl. (a) How much time should be devoted daily to writing? ) What hour of the day is best adapted for this exercise? 2. What relation have position and pen holding to the character of the writing? </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 3. Give your plan for using the copy book. 4. Explain two exercises for developing speed. 5. Name five points to be considered in estimating the excel - lence of the pupils' work in writing. 6-10. Write as a specimen of your penmanship a stanza from your favorite poem or a paragraph from your favorite prose author. ORTHOGRAPHY 1. Mark the first vowel in each of the following: bravo, gratis, linancier. lichen, recess, Isolate, docile, comely, diploma, cleanly. 2. Give the proper abbreviations for the following: account present month, junior, doctor, debtor. 13. Write the present active participle of study, shoot, singe, trace, sign, tun and cunt. Give the rule that appli&lt; - li of the last 4. Write the following words and give a synonym of each: Cheerful, pleasure, discipline, defective. 5. Construct sentences containing the following words used correctly: aviary, iniquity, human, literally, wrest, stationery, sta - tionary, verdict, capitol, climax. C-10. In the following list some words are spelled correctly «nd some incorrectly. Rewrite, spelling all correctly: (25 credits) alfalfia audible grammer superseed sieze neccessary separate quadrille icycle liesure bureau musllage judgement ventelate Brltian comparative etiquette buisiness inteligent enough artillery Chicamaugv gorilla Panama woolly CIVICS. 1. Give the objects of the United States Constitution as set forth in the preamble thereto. 2. What is an alien? How may an alien become a citizen? 3. Distinguish between direct and indirect taxation. Give ex - it mples of each. 4. What reason can you give for (a) the existence of two houses of congress; (b) the different methods of choosing the mem - b««? 6. What is meant by representative government? Give example. 6. What is the significance of a writ of habeas corpus and what justifies its being called sometimes "The bulwark of liberty." </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 7. State briefly how treaties are mada and what branches of our national government are concerned in thetr making. 8. Distinguish bet.wfen Canto ■—, o, 1 diitio.), and internal rev- enue. 9. Who are entitled to vote at school district meetings? 10. Giva the important provisions of the law relative to com - pulsory attendance of pupils at the public schools of Nebraska. AGRICULTURE. Kl. Explain how weeds and underbrush waste valuable soil water dry weather. Have weeds ever any value to farm land? 2. What three things are necessary to seed germination? 3. Give the purpose of tillage. 4. "As a rule, the farmers that grow and feed the most clover have the most fertile farms." Explain. 5. What is the economy of propagating some plants by seeds and others by buds? 6. Explain the Importance of packing the soil about planted seeds. K7. Describe the work of the codling moth, and suggest a method combating the same. 8. Name two advantages of raising pedigreed stock. 9. Name the five most harmful insects in Nebraska. 110. What purpose could a school garden be made to serve? swer in as few words as possible. THEORY AND ART II. Is knowledge, or mental development the true aim and end teaching? Give reasons. 2. Give the purpose of discipline. L3. What is the advantage of the child's conversing freely with teacher? 4. What do you consider "perfect order" in a schoolroom, aa applied to pupils? 5. What will you do in the first thirty minutes of a new school on the first day? 6. Name three characteristics of a successful teacher. 7. To what extent should the child be required to recite in the words of the book? S. What daily preparation should the teacher make? 9. Name three studies that train the memory, and two that de - velop the reasoning powers. 10. What study do you think ha* the greatest disciplinary value? Why? </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 STATE SUJ KKPORT ENGLISH COMPOSITION 1. Write a list of five words, each of which, without change in spelling or pronunciation, may be used in two or more distinct significations. Illustrate. Lse correctly in original sentences the following words ''rinciple, expedient, eminence, impetuous, awful. 3. Write each of the following words in a sentence: plaintiff eligible, tenant, parallel, utensils. 4. Tell by effects that it has been raining; that the man is old; that it is spring. I Write a letter to your county superintendent, making in- Iry about reading circle work, and meetings. (Do not sign your n name to the letter.) PHYSIOLOGY. 1. What advantages In having the heads of bones large? 2. Name the longest bone in (a) the arm; (b) the leg. 3. Show how muscular exercises refresh the mind after a per- iod of study. Make a simple, inexpensive bill of fare for one day, consist - of highly nutritious and easily digested foods. 5. Give two reasons why the food should be thoroughly mas - ticated before it is swallowed. 6. What is the lymph? 7. Name the parts of the eye. 8. Name three important uses of the skin •. Define bronchitis, pleurisy. Describe and give functions of (a) periosteum; (b) dentine DRAWING Um pencil for construction work 1. Represent an open crayon box to the left and below the eye of the observer. 2. Make a border, having for the unit of design a simple geo - metric figure. 3. Represent a group of three vegetables in which one is in part hidden from view by the other two. 14. Represent an out door scene exhibiting the use of (a) cen - of vision, (b) horizon line, (c) receding lines. Make proper no - &gt;n showing where each of the above appears. 6. How should drawing be taught in connection with the study ALGEBRA 1. Simplify 4»*-|5b«+a-[6a*-3a-(b»-a)] [ 2. Define term, member, rational, surd, and multiple. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 4. Find the H. ('. F. and L. C. M of x* +1 12. and \2 -+-2x 15. 1 x + 1 1 2 4 :. 4 I 4 is. The sum of the two digits of a number is 9, and If the mber Is divided by the sum of its digits the quotient is 5. Find the number. Kxpand (gs+Sj) 4 by formula, putting all work needed on an - r paper. 3x-H4x --olve v -X* tlO. The diagonal of a rectangle is 25 inches. If the rectangle e 4 inches shorter and 8 inches wider, the diagonal would still 25 inches. Find the area of the rectangle. ARITHMETIC. 1. Define and give examples of prime, concrete, integral, sim - ple, and denominate numbers. .'. Write in Roman letters 1906. Write in words 3756.0498. 13. A farmer has three farms containing respectively 168, 216, acres, which he wishes to divide into fields of equal siie, king the fields as large as possible; how many fields will each farm make? 4. (a) Find the L. C. M. of 84, 168, 252, 420 ib) Explain as you would to a class. 2 :i S 5. Simplify i 1 1 1 1 1 1 4- 2 :$ 16. The baae of a triangular field is 360 yards, and the altitude 615 feet. How many acres does it contain? 17. A man bought a farm for $97.75 per acre, which price was per cent more than was previously paid for it. What was the previous price per acre? :&lt;. Factor: a* 2ab- | d* fcW -fa* h+ab» 2 9. Solve 2x* — x+a=2aS !» 4 r, </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 F8. Explain whether there is a gain or loss In selling two arti - st the same price when the gain per cent on one equals the loss cent on the other. 8. The sum of A's and B's ages t s 76 years and % of A's age equals three-fifths of B's. How old is each? L10. At an annual school meeting a tax of $703.80 was voted. htm nil valuation of a district is $65350, how much Is A's tax a assessment of $2800? GEOMETRY 1. Define postulate, and axiom; and give two of each 2. Theorem: The bisectors of the base angles of an Isosceles triangle are equal. L3. Theorem: The line drawn from the center of a circle to middle of a chord is perpendicular to the chord. 4. Problem: To inscribe a circle in a given triangle. L5. Theorem: The diagonals of a parallelogram bisect each er. Prove. 6. Problem: To construct a circle having a given radius, and passing through two given poll 7. Problem: To find a fourth proportional to three given lines. v. Find the area of a triangle if the sides are 104, ill and HEADING 1. la) Name two short poems that you would recommend for children V memorizing. (b) Why would you recommend these? \atne four books that you think children should read. Give reasons 3. Distinguish between emphasis and accent ■ line the author of each of the following selections The Autocrat of the Break fiist Table. Poor Richard's Max; Rip Van Winkle. &lt;d) The Last of the Mohicai Uncle Tom's Cabin. 5. Name three of the best modern series of text books in it«- four •.(&gt;&lt;)&gt; *hould learn to read. How can you tell when a child has mastered a new word? 8. Why should a child be carefully trained In reading aloud? •■ &lt;• -ons as to which is the more difficult for a child learning to read Koes the fat rat see the cat on the mat? &lt;b&gt; "Hiawatha lived in a wigwam with old Nokomls." 10. in literature do we find the following characters </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 Choose any five from this list. Ichabod Crane Loch invar Adam Bede Enoch Arden Hamlet John Alden Maud Muller Poor Ricbard Sir Launfal Oliver Twist GRAMMAR. 1. Define substantive, antecedent, appositive, voice, participle. Illustrate interrogative adjective, interrogative adverb, and interrogative pronoun. 3. Give the principal parts of the following verbs: flght, set, wring, have, hide, and sing. 4. Define participle, infinitive. Illustrate each. 5. Expand the following sentences, changing the italicized worti- ami then to i ected. Wiaiom is the principal tlm 6. Write a compound-complex sentence. 7. Write the possessive plurals of lady, man, he, sister-in-law, tooth. I Analyze and diagram the following sentence: We may not able to accomplish all we desire, but shall we therefore alt with 1 hands? ilak'' necessar\ i i the following sentences and jiive reasons for corrections: (a i He told it dowa and I sat it down, ibi I found it laying on the floor. ii) We shall give it to wl ems to need it most. i (1 i 1 met a man whom I have no doubt was your uncle. ry man. woman, and child is going to the celebration. :— ire to attend one of the Nebraska state normal schools. Write a letter to the principal of the school in which you are h ing for information. BOTANY. II. What are the parts of the flower? What are the functions each par I. What is the principal office of leaves? L Define and give illustration by citing examples of each: An - 1. biennial, and perennial plants. Li. Describe a typical cross-section of the stem of an exogen, tell how it would differ from an endogen. 5. Distinguish between fruit and seed. 6. What is honey, and how related to botany? 7. Give the 'characteristics of the flower of the Rosaceae. v. What are "rnsts"? 9 Discuss structure contents and life of the Dlanr cell </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define: Basin, divide, river system. 2. Account for differences in temperature, in the same latitude, between places of different elevation. 3. Give the causes of the changes of seasons. 4. What kind of government has Turkey, Norway, Brazil, Switzerland, Porto Rico? 5. Name the five races of men and tell what country is inhab - ited mostly by each. L6. Name the countries of Europe which touch the Mediter - ean. 7. Distinguish between export and domestic trade L8. (a) Name two states containing the most valuable copper em. (b) Locate our three principal iron ore districts. L9. Name the most important harbor of the Atlantic coast of United States. Why? 110. What movements are now being promoted to reclaim some the arid regions of Nebraska? HISTORY. PI. Name two early English navigators, and tell what regions explored. Stn an account of the founding of the Massachusetts Bay ony, and state why it grew so rapidly during the reign of Charles I. L3. Name four of the most important battles of the Revolution iame of opposing commanders in each. 4. Name the greatest act of Jefferson's administration. Why' Name an interesting event associated with each of the fol - ing dates: 1492; 1607; 1776; 1820; 1863. 6. What is a tax on foreign goods called, and what is the pur - pose of such a tax? 7. What was the Missouri Compromise? L8. Give the purpose and results of the Lewis and Clarke expe - on. bit Select any five of the following names and make a brief ment concerning each: Magellan, Raleigh, Wm. Penn, Lafayette, rt Morris, Daniel Webster, Susan B. Anthony. 10. Review three topics of interest in recent American history. PHYSICS. 1. Give law for displacement of floating and of sinking bodies 2. Which is heavier, a pound of pine wood or a pound of iron? Explain your answer. 3. Explain how an iron ship floats. 4. Distinguish between force pump and lift pump, using the </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 5. An engine running at the rate of a mile a minute, exerts a constant tractile force of 3000 lbs. on its train. Express the work being done in horse-power. 6. Give the modern theory of heat. 7. Make a diagram for, and explain the working of the siphon. 8. Give two ways of arranging cells to form a battery, and give advantages of each. SEPT. 21 AND 22, 1906. No new questions published by State -Department. OCTOBER 19 AND 20, 1906. BOOKKEEPING 1. What ledger accounts will close with loss and gain? What is inventory? 2. What is meant by "endorsement"? 3. How does a negotiable note differ in form from a non-ne- gotiable one? What is the legal difference? 4. What is meant by "acceptance" of commercial paper? 5. What is a "ledger account"? 6-10. Journalize the following: Sept. 1, 1906, Bought of Miller &amp; Co., for cash. Mdse. $260.76 Sold to E. A. Martin on account mdse. 25.80 Paid insurance, cash _ _ 30.60 Bought horse and wagon for use in business, paid cash 225.00 3. Bought mdse .1587.39 Gave in payment my note at 30 days. 4. Horse used for delivery was stolen. (What entry shall I make?) 4. Bought a horse for ... 150.00 Sold Mdse. for cash 123.50 Sold mdse. to J. G. Mahr . 89.50 Took in payment his note at 90 days. 5. Paid rent for one month 78.00 5. Sold to E. E. Day, mdse ... 129.00 Took in payment a note in his favor against L. D- Amos for the same amount. MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part I. Give complete analysis to the following five problems: 1. A farmer having sold % of his sheep and 10 of his cows. found that 15 sheep and % of his cows remained; how many of each had he? </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 F2. A can do as much work in 2 days as B can in 4 days or C In 6 days. In bow many days can B do as much as C can In days? 3. In a school of 80 pupils there are 32 girls; how many boys must iat there uia. " each four girls remaining? t4. A tree 90 feet In length was broken In falling so that one - of the longer part equals % of the shorter. How long Is each k5. A gentleman divided .'8 apples among an equal number of i and girls, pi girl 3 apples and to each boy 4; re - ed the number of boys and of girls. Part Two. Rapid Drill The superintendent will detach this part of the mental arith - metic examinatioi distributing the qu&lt; - ciM when all are ready. Allow inn minutes for completion: and pin t'&lt;&gt; Part One. Applicants will write numbers of problems and answers only. Kl. How many cords of pine wood may be bought for $24 at % » cord? 15 times a ;is water, and cork is .25 times heavy as water. How many times is silver as heavy as cork? 3. Paid S42 for a cow, which was seven-fifths of her value. ' was her value? 4. How many steps each 2 feet 8 inches long will be taken In going 16 van: ■ h how many handkerchiefs can be bought for $3? CIVIL GOVERNMENT. 1. Define; (a) government; (bj constitution. Mention two powers denied to the states and tell why they t3. Compare congress and the Nebraska legislature In the fol - ng particulars: . ;i , Number of members in the senate and house; presiding officers of senate and house. t4. la i In case the governor should resign, who would become rnor of Nebraska? (b) Who would become president In case of s death? What art- the arguments for the popular election of United States senators? &gt;es of Nebraska courts 7 What are the legal qualifications of a voter in this state? 8. What provision is made for the enforcement of the compul - sory education law? 9. Mention four important measures that were passed at the last session of congress. 10. Name three good text books on civil government </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 PENMANSHIP. PI. What system of penmanship do you prefer? Give reasons your preferen* In what grade should the child begin to use pen and Ink? Give reasons for your answer. L: - muscular movenMOl ? How does it differ from fin - movement? 4. Give two exercises suitable for muscular movement practice. 5. At what period of the day would you have writing exer - cises? Why? IG-I". Write as a specimen of your penmanship a selection of less than four lines from your favorite author. Give name of hor. ORTHOGRAPHY. tl. Mark the first vowel in the following: alter - :e, disputant, docile, opponent, recourse, national, squalor, legis - ure, extant, finance. IB the following homonyms: Gate, gait; 1, idle; loan, lone; hue, hew; cede, seed. Le singular and plural of: I, she, who, ox, -in-law. 4. Write abbreviations for the months. Give the meaning of the following prefixes and suffixes: cir - cuni, i a, non, trans, able or ible, er, less, ness, acy. 6-10. Some of the following words are spelled correctly, some incorrectly. Write all correctly: ilage -ial dayly impanel indict arrain hoping caprise implisit licorice traiter l&gt;revailence larceny alyze ciphon surplus* renown cansei fourty ninty lillies (lure ;&lt; initial AGRKTLTIUK Answer any nine. 1. What part do trees tafce'in developing a new country? 2. Of what use are different bacteria in soil? , .• ■: :■• reasons » matter or humus la neces- </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 4. Which Is the more valuable to the farmer, (a) the horse or the cow; (b) the pig or the chicken? 15. Why is a northern slope better for Nebraska orchards than southern slope? 6. How Is It that the barren lands of the west produce so well under irrigation? What is a "cover crop?" 8. What are cedar apples and what injury do they do? k9. Which is the more valuable part of a school garden, the k of preparing and putting it in. or the crop which is harv» - ft Name and (!■ ve noxious weed! of Nebraska, and tell each reproduces its kind. PHYSIOLOGY. Name and locate five bones of the body. Two glands. i)eflne voluntary and involuntary muscles. To which class the muscles of the intestines belong? 3. Wha: rion? Is water or alcohol digested? 4. Contrast the proper diet of ditch diggers with that of office m.-n Name in order the organs of circulation. 6 What organs constitute the nervous system? P7 How many teeth in a set? Name the classes with respect to and shape. 8. Describe the structure of the skin. t Briefly write the substance of a talk you might give your il as to rules of hygiene relating to eating, drinking, sleeping, iae and study, in their home life. DRAWING P steps of procedure in teaching a class ils to draw from an object. Choose proper object for illustra- L-esent two objects which may be used as an exercise in wing in which only horizontal and vertical lines are used. 3. Represent a boni 'ling across the page, in which two forms are alt' K • - 4. Represent a group of three objects based on the sphere, one object to be partly hidden from view by the other two. 6. Represent an out-door scene illustrating the following: (1) Horizon i converging lines, (3) the point of sight. COMPOSITION 1. Write correctly the following: (a) Consider William take month to think, (b) Someone cried out louder please sir louder. &lt;c) The night it was the middle of summer was fair and calm </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 Correctly capitalize the following, giving rules for all capi - tals used: (a) The book of psalms is the middle book of the bible, (b) The war with spain united the north and the south- in one grand cause. 3. Write a description of a landscape, indicating that it is fall. 4. What is the general principle to be observed in punctuation? 5. Write a short letter to a friend, giving an account of your Prst day of school. THEORY AND ART. 1. Discuss the principle, "Processes before rules." 2. Give three conditions favorable to close study. 3. Discuss two ways of studying the lesson. 4. What do you understand by intuition? What danger in stimulating the child's ambition beyond his natural ability? 6. Give a plan for stimulating the idle to study. 7. How would you teach patriotism? LBxpUil naxim: 'The minimum of punishment is maximum of excellence." Give two proper and two improper motives for study, and t if y your classification. (rive the essentials of a good question. GEOMETRY. 11. Distinguish between postulato and theorem; y and theorem. 2. Draw and name the different quadrilaterals. 13. Theorem: The line joining the middle points of two sides of triangle is parallel to the thirfl side and equal to one half of the ird side. Prove. 4. Give the conditions under which triangles are similar. 15. Problem: The homologous sides of two similar triangles are eet and 11 feet respectively. The area of the second is T42 sqmre t. Required the are; 1 i&gt;f :he first. 7. Theorem: In the same circle or equal circles equal chords are equally distant from the center. Prove. 8. Theorem:* In a right triangle the median from the right rngle to the hypotenuse is equal to half the hypotenuse. Prove. i9. Problem: Find the area of a trapezold of which the bases 73 feet and 57 feet, and each of the sides Is 17 feet. 10. Exercise: The area of the circumscribed square is double the area of the Inscribed square. Prove. 6. Having given a:b:=c:d, prove that a — b: a= c — d:c, </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 GRAMMAR. 1. Give the distinct i &lt;-n a phrase and a clause. Define: (.a) Fart; i infinit: tj. Illustrate in sen a&gt; Past perfect passive of "find"; ) future perfect active of "seek." t|. Write a sent' , laining an adverb phrase, and expand phrase into a clause. ■ reason why the order of words In a sentence is important. 16. Show that ti is are ambiguous: (a) The fear b&gt; The writer being a scholar is not doubted. What distinction make between the noun and the pronoun? iuguish between the grammatical and the logical (com - plete) predict ti. Diagram, or if t &gt;&lt; r, analyze: 'A ruler who appoints man to an office when there is in his dominion another man bet - tied for it sins against God and against the state." &gt;1 officer making application for a .11 as tea&gt; ARITHMETIC. Add $34 $41-1. $9*4.69, $43.87, $1.95, $127.83. I the quotient of 77 times 36o times 4 7."., divided by 11 times « times t. Find the least number of oranges which when arranged in. groups of 6. 7, I or 9 will leave a remainder of five in. each case. 4. &gt;f land at $63 an acre. Sold three-sixteenths of it at $71 an at at $65 an acre, und th. mainder for t ra than it cost. What was the entire »ain? man d % of his estate to his wife, % of the re - inder to his son. and the remainder to his daughter, who received . and what was the share 16. f them Is 8, another is 2.5. What is the third? 7. Divide 19 mi. 18"' rds. 2 yd. 9 in. by 7. 8. The difT time between London and New York is 4 hrs 55 min. 37 sec. What is the longitude of New York? 9. Find the simple interest on $280 for 3 ft. 2 mo. 12 das. at 7 per cent. A line long reaches from the top of a fort to the opposite side of a ri wide What is the height of the </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 READING. 1. Distinguish b&lt; ammatical and rhetorical punctual LAhat causes too rapid reading? How may these causes be oved? 13. How can children be taught to look for the main ideas in selection? 4. Indicate the emphatic words in the following: They are poor That li nothing; th&gt; r far Who, losing, h; Men; they most poor Of all, who lose and wish they might forgi .n Ingelow. ■ ; frast," in the above selection? 6. How may ■eft. 17. What is your guide in determining the length of lessons to ign to a i ass in the fourth gra 8. Of what value is supplementary reading? 19. Wh; ing of phonics important? Suggest a simple drill phonics for a sixth grade reading class. LI". Indicate and explain n the following from "Cob - r Keezar's Vision "O for the breath Of apples and nuts and wine! For an oar to row and a blow Down ;&lt;l ciiil river Hhi; ar in his blui And dropped on his heard "Old, old am I," said Keezar, 'And the Rhine flows far awa — J. Q. Whittler. ALGEBRA. 1. Define (a) radical qnantit multaneous equations. Give principle used in clearing of fractions, (b) Give principle used In transposition. 4. Find the (J. &lt; '. D.of: x' ( ) ( ) \l-a 1 a/ \l 6. A cistern is tilled by three pipes. By the first it can be filled in 80 minutes, by the second in 2&lt;&gt;o minutes, and by the third in Alii jr be filled if all are left open? ... . i a 3 ' »y«+y« </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 FT A certain fraction is equal to % if 1 is added to the numer - , but is equal to l t if one is added to the denominator. Required fraction. I HISTORY. 1. State the effi lumbus' discovery upon European na- tions 12. Give the motive that led to the founding of each of two of England colonies. Where was the first settlement made in n? 3. How was George III connected with the independence of rica? 4. Name n md mention an important event in the administration of each. m the effect upon history of any two of the following: canal, Squat reignty. 6. Tell something of how Cuba became a republic and what relation if ai ited States. tMake a brief statement about each of the following: Benja - klin, A 1 xander Hamilton, Stephen A. Douglas, Andrew on, Albert J. Beveridge. ian important event connected with each of the follow - 1607, 1 7, 1893. 9. What states have been formed in whole or in part out of Louisiana Purchase? the authors of three poems of merit, based of the 1 BOTANY 1. • Q which the seed does not produce plants to kind. How are such plants propagated? I. Distinguish between accessory and axillary buds. B3. Name two underground i low could you prove them be stems? ive the structure of the leaf tissue. How could you distinguish the Cruciferae? How the Le - icuminoMe? \ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 PHYSICS. 1. Define motion and rest as used in physics. Explain how you would adjust a pump to bring water from ell 73 feet deep. 3. Give laws for the pressure of liquids, due to gravity. 14. Explain fully why a rapidly rotating emery stone may fly pieces. 15. A plank 12 feet long and weighing 24 pounds is supported two props, one 3 feet from one end and one 1 foot from the other, at is the weight on each support? 6. Distinguish between condensing and non-condensing engines. LI. How is the "candle power" of a gas or electric light deter - ed? 8. We speak of one object as being blue, another as being red. etc. Explain what determines the color of an object. 9. Distinguish between sound and sound wave. 10. What is electrolysis? GEOGRAPHY. II. Define: (a) Continent, (b) equator, (c) axis, (d) meridian, ) water shed. 2. Give area, population, and chief products of Cuba. 3. Give width in degrees of each of the zones. 4. Name the three chief food plants of the world and tell where each is cultivated extensively. 5. Name the countries that touch the Baltic sea. 6. Contrast the agricultural products of France with those of England, and give reasons for any different 7. Give home, characteristics, and achieve. .ic;nts of the I 8. Give chief agricultural products of Nebraska and tell where is produced. 19. Why are these commercially important: Chicago, New York tral, Sault St*. Marie, Suez, Hongkong? 111. Name and locale three important coal producing regions of United States. NOVEMBER 16 AND 17, 1906 BOOKKEEPING. 1. In journalizing how do you decide what to credit and what to debit? 2. Write a check on a First National bank. :i. How would you make a trial balance? 4. Define liabilities, non-negotiable note. </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 (Write a receipted bill complete in all details for the following: 6 complete geographies at $1.00 each 4 U. S. histories at 8»»c each 10 aritl &lt;-h. 6-10. Journalize the following Received cash from Samuel May In full of account, (1VI1. GOVERNMENT I. Whk ily the ■ the savage living in his tribe Mien of a civilized nation? Explain why ■ •■ things that government does for the people In whom is legislative authority vested in (a) the horn - unty; ( d i tk&lt; he natic; 4. Name in your opinion the two eabta«1 offii*-:- of most import - r opinion .V What is the difference between a bill and a law? 6. Distinguish I property taxes, import duties, and in - ternal revenue*. Name five definite purposes for which the national govern - expends inn: 8. How will you help pupils to become familiar with the ma - of stabe municipal government? • . Name tl f any. that art- required by law to be taught in the public schools of Nebraska. What is the value of a current events paper in the school? PENMANSHIP 1. Give t hi • ■ for using the system of penmanship which ■ ■ Write the names of three American authors of note '. ; ■■• oi • reason why a child should not use a slate in learning to write 4. Why should children write large? • ,. l. Bought of Brown and Johnson for cash, Mdsc 12146.20 Sold office safe for cash 12.00 3. Paid cash for drayag. S.65 Sold mdse. for cash 21.70 Sold mdse. to Wm. Harris for his note at 60 days without interest . - 500.00 6. Bought mdse. for cash Sold mdse. to Samuel May on account 480.30 24. Sold Wm. Harris' note to the bank at 6 per cent discount. nought mdse. giving note payable In 80 day- 746.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Write rule for doubling final consonant. I Divide into syllables and mark accent of following: equator, untain, prairie, magazine, k&lt; i&gt;shaw, pitiful species, weapon, er. kd. Write sentences using the following synonyms: plurality, ority; insurrection, revolt; rebellion, revolution; general, unl - ■al; punish, chastise. 4. Choose the right word in the following: One man's pleasure is another's (pane or pain). The Lord shall (rein, rain, reign) forever. The (pail, pale) light of the moon is seen. A (vale, vail, veil) of mist hid the hill. Take my (yolk, yoke) upon you. (iive correct abbreviations: South Dakota, Tennessee, Ohio, Virginia, Wyoming. 6-1 &lt;t. Some words in the following are incorrect. Write all rreotly: ,1 Ill-I-I.M awtiini a lei ; : inmiaui' wrigle Birynge scholer Jocky glutton medi Ivory fatel piiding limet coin role MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part I. complete analysis of the following probk algebra not accepted. 1. A and B together have 34 apples, and % of A's number equals \ of B's number; how many has each? K\ hoy. after spending of his money for candies and one - h for peaches, found that 20 cents was two-sevenths of what re - ned; how much money had he at first? ::. Divide 49 into two parts which are to each other at % to %. 4. A and B engage to do some work for $54; A sends 3 men is, and B sends 4 men 3 days; how much sh&lt; uld A and B each </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 rS. A and B together can do two-sevenths of a piece of work In day; how long will it take them to do the work? Part II. (Rapid Drill.) The superintendent will detach this part of the mental arithme - aniination before distributing the questions, and give exercise when all are ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; then collect answer papers and pin to Part One. Applicants will write numbers of problem! and answers only. 1. What is the cost of bricks per thousand when a single brick costs nine-tenths of a cent? 12. One number is \ of another and their sum is 49. What are numbers? LI. A man spent &gt;4 of his money and $10 more, and had $6 How much had he at first? 4. Sold a horae for $100, which was four-fifths of his cost What did I lose? 15. If fire-ninths of a ton of hay cost $2.50, how much hay may bought for $22.50? THEORY AND ART II. Should or should not the teacher talk about school affairs public? Why? t What should a Teacher read? L3. What importance attaches to the teacher's personal appear - ! What to her voice and manner? 4. What do you understand by intuition? Lints would you make prominent in teaching arith- 6 What is habit? 7 What is patriotism? the relation of study to memory? t. What is the difference between teaching and educating? 10. Give reasons for or against prize giving. DRAWING. 1. lonalize a common leaf form and reproduce it in i»order design. 2. Represent an open basket below the level of the eye. 13. Represent an arple, a potato, and a pumpkin, all resting on plane surface. 4. Represent a roadway extending directly in front of the ob - ■n one side and a row of trees on the other. L5. Illustrate how you would teach a grammar grade class the &gt;f receding lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 COMPOSITION. 1. Give eight rules for capitalization. 2. Correct mistakes in spelling, English, and punctuation of the following: I s&amp;en the pointed spots od Iuh brest the swelling of his throat and the sparkel of his eyes as he poured out his whole heart into a long liqid molody. 3. Write a short conversation between two boys. 4. Fill blanks with better or best, worse or worst: Of all the boys Charles was the Of John and Harry, JoTin is the Of the two, Mary is liked the ... He is the . of all. 5. Write a business letter to a publishing house subscribing for some magazine for a year. PHYSIOLOGY 1. Nam? three common h n t &gt; i t s that tend to deform the human skeleton 2. Explain the relation I and muscular growth. 3. Name articles of food containing respectively (a) proteids; (b) fats; (c) carbo-hydrates; (d) salts. 4. Describe two functions of the liver. f&gt;. What is the purpose of the circulation? 6. What actions are controlled by (a) the cerebrum; (b) cere- bellum? 7. Explain "taste." \"ame (a) two secreting organs; (b) two excreting organs. 9. How can the body best be protected against injurious bac- teria? 10. Tell how alcohol affects the mu» AGRICTLTIRE. 1. Give three reasons for plowing the school garden in the fall. ' fruits and an enemy of each, not including birds. 3. Give three reasons why young people leave the farm, and suggest a remedy. 4. Why do we protect the birds and not the rabbits from hunt- ers? What are: Biennial, cambium, tillage, legume, smut? 6. What makes alfalfa and clover so valuable? 7. Name (a) a breed of draft horses; (b) of dairy cattle; (c) cf beef cattle; (d) of sheep; (e) of swine. 8. How should seed corn be gathered and cared for, briefly? 9. What plant does the chinch bug bother, the Hessian fly, the wire worm? Upon what are U- S. weather reports based? 17ap« </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 ARITHMETIC 1. Solve (a) 789x5678. (b) 63517429H-923. tl. ■ A lady wishes to purchase a piece of cloth wUcb may be without waste into pieces 4, 5, or 6 yards long. What Is the least ber of yards she can buy for the purpose? k3. A merchant sold a quantity of sugar for $1,180 and thereby ed &gt;X4 i if the cost. If he bad sold it for $1,000 would he have ed or lost, and how much? 4. What is the nearest number to 134 8 that exactly contains •M1 15. A owns a square farm of 160 A. How many rods of fenc» uired to inclose the farm, and divide it into four equal square df? 6. Divide (a) .40 by .32, (b) 4.0 by .032, (c) 4&lt;&gt;. by .0032. LA man.bought 7 % thousand feet of lumber for $155. Find cost of 19% thousand at the same rml I A farmer sold two loads of wheat, weighing respectively 60 lbs. and 4,345 lbs. His wagon weighed l.oeu pounds. Find Talue of his wheat at C4 cents per bu. 8. Find the simple interest of $358.75 for 1 year, 7 months, 15 days at 7 per cent. 110. The perpendicular of a right angle triangle is 72 feet and hypotenuse is 75 feet. Find the base and the area. GRAMMAR. 1. What is the distinction between a preposition and a con - junction? What is inflection? What parts of speech do not admit of inflection ? 3. Illustrate: (a) conjunction, (b) declension 4. Write sentences using, (a) a phrase as subject, (b) a clause as object, (c) a participle as object of a preposition. 15. "Men's evil manners live in brass; their virtues we write water." Analyze the sentence in full, or diagram. 6. It had long been the fixed principle of Caesar's philosophy that the only way to enjoy life was to banish the fear of death. I Parse the first verb, the first proper noun, and the first object a preposition in the foregoing sentence. I Write sentences to show the difference in meaning between pt, and except, much and many, most and almost, learn and k, funny and odd. 8. Distinguish between verbs and verbals S. Write a letter to the head of the educational department pf the state of Nebraska, mentioning some feature of his latest pub - lication. All Teachers of Nebraska." </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 in. Fill blanks with one of these words: he, me, I, him, we, they, us. Is it that you wish to see? I knew it was because I saw Is it because I saw Do you think it was • ? Xo, it was It is who were speaking to . That is my mother. I know if is I It is hear calling. READING. 1. Name a selection which should be read rapidly, one at me - dium rate, and one at slow rate. What figures do you find in the following from "The Gol den Milestone?" Leafless are the trees; their purple branches Spread th«mselves abroad, like reefs of coral. Rising silent In the Red Sea of the winter sunset. — Longfellow. 3. Indicate by a line under each group the grouping (phrasing) of the above selection. 4. Should children be trained to read by word, or sentence? Give reasons. t5. What is the real purpose of oral reading? How does it er from declaiming? L6. What Is meant by having material intrinsically worthy of dy? 7. What is meant by the atmosphere of a selection? s. What is type? Give an example. « 9. Why teach beginners sight words? in. Give a quotation from Paul Revere's Ride. ALGEBRA. 1. Define (a) Involution, (b) rational number, (c) quadratic equation. 2. Give an axiom based on each of the fundamental operations. 3- *«** (.) SESBU 4. Find the H. C. F. x»— y», x»— y», x' 5. If from three-fourths of a certain number 3 is subtracted, the remainder is four less than the number. Required the number. f Extract the square root of X* x\v 3i*y« 6. Solve by substitution: x+3y=19 3x + 2y=22 H + + xy* 1« 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 8. A certain rectangle is twice as long as it is wide, and if the h be increased by 4 feet and the width decreased by 4 feet the area will remain the same. Required the original dimensions. 1 l.i 1. Define (a) liue, (b) surface, (c) volume, (d) angle. t Theorem: in an isosceles triangle the angles opposite the al sides are equal. 3. Define (a) circumference, (b) tangent, (c) radius, (d) arc 14. Theorem: An angle formed by two chords intersecting with - the circui: •■asured by one half the sum of the inter - ted arcs. .V Problem: 'ruct an angle of 45 d&lt; . 16. Problem: The sides of a triangle are 7, 9 and 11 respectively. the triangle right, acute, or obtuse? Why? Problem: To construct a square equivalent to the sum of two given squares. 8. Problem: The chord of a segment is 16 in. and the distance from the center of the circle is 6 in. Find the area of the circle. PHYSICS. 1 . A stone dropped from a cliff strikes at the base of the cliff in 4 seconds. How high is the cliff? tain day the thermometer registered 82 degrees Fahr. at is the corresponding reading on a Centigrade thermometer? Tell how a solid differs from a liquid. 4 Distinguish between force pump and lift pump. 5. What is equilibrium? 6. What is distillation? horse power of an engine that will raise 1b. 120 ft. in ten hours? Define any three: Energy, volt, refraction, motor, wedge, ilynamo. 9. Distinguish l» olume and pitch of sound State four things upon which the resistance of a conduc - tor dei&gt;ends. GEOGRAPHY. 1. Define (a) parallel, (b) isotherm, &lt;c) glacier 2. What determines the location of the Tropic of Capricorn? 3. Which of the races has shown capacity for self-government? Which race is tribal in government? kx-j-1 1— x 4x— 1 SEOMETRY </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 4. Where and what are the following? Select three. Tundras, Madagascar, Mocha, Arel, Baikal, Barcelona. Cologne, Marmora. 5. New England and Ohio are great manufacturing regions What natural causes have helped to develop each? 6. Compare island, peninsula and isthmus. 7. Compare the soil of low valleys with upland soil, and explain the difference. What are the two leading beverage plants of the world? Where raised, and what ]&gt;art is used for beverage? 9. Products ma I from St. Louis to New Orleans by rail or by rh' pare the two methods of transportation, giving ad - vantages and disadvantages of each. the rhief sources of ineott rmers. HISTORY 1. Tell something of the Mound Builders. What motives led to the founding of Maryland, Georgia? 3. What were the "Five Intolerable »4. Compare the conditions in the United States, at the close the lsth century, with the conditions at the present time in the lowing particulars opulation; (c) means of trans - lation. "). Name five men who helped frame the constitution. 6. State the causes and results of America's war for commer - cial supremai 7. What do you understand by the "Monroe Doctrine"? g. What effect had the acquisition of Texas upon the si.- ruestion? 9. Give results of the recent elections in any five states of the union. 1©. Make a statement about each of the following: Henry Hud - son, Patrick Henry. John C. Calhoun, Robert E. Lee, William H. Taft. BOTANY. Select eight. LI. What provision is made for the food of the embryo while first roi '''ing develop- What is meant by growing, and what by resting buds? I. What three purposes may roots serve? L4. What is meant by definite and what by indefinite annual wth? 5. Give three purposes that leaves may serve. 6. What are incomplete flowers? 7. How are seeds scattered by nature? S. Name some plant barriers. 9. What ar. 10. Dis&lt; of the bark. </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 DECEMBER 21 AND 22. 1906 PENMANSHIP. rl Give reasons why form should receive more attention than vement in training the beginner to write. 2. Give the advantages of the muscular movement K3. Write the letters of the alphabet, grouping th«m according of spaces above and below the base line. 4. What physiological conditions require larger letter forms for younger children? Iir method of obtaining legibility, neatness and speed writing. 6. Write the preamble of the Constitution as a specimen of your penmanship. BOOKKEEPING. 1. Give rule for journalizing persons, property and allowances 2. Name four ledger accounts that will show losses or gains *nd four that will show resources or liabilities. 3. ree ledger accounts such that. you can tell without inspection which side, if either, is the larger. Give reasons. 4. DMtagaM :i shipments and consignments i a) Write a letter of remittain L(b) Write a letter acknowledging the receipt of a letter of lttan. 11, 1906 — Commenced business with the following resources liabilities: Cash $3,000, mdse. $2,000, bills receivable $500, bills able) $ 3 — Sold to Joseph Johnson merchandise $130. receiving in payment: Cash $40, his note for $55, balance on account. 15 — Bought of H. Smith on account, merchandise $ 7 &lt; hj . paid set of office records, |t. 7 — A fire in the basement of the st | ■■:. Insurancn $11 Nov. | — Journalize, post and close ledger Inventories: Mdse. $2,400; office fixtures $50; unpaid clerk •alary $. CIVICS. 11. (a) In whom are the legislative powers of the state vested; ) the law enforcing powers; (c) the law interpreting powers? 12. Give the most important law enacted during the last session congress. 3. What is a revenue bill, and in what branch of congress must glnate? ame four members of Pres. Roosevelt's cabinet. 6=10 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 (iive the different kinds of county certificates, the length of time valid, and the requirements for renewal without examination. t6. In whom is the judicial power vested in (a) the city or vil - e; (b) tho county; (ci the state; (d) the nation? L7. Name the two leading candidates for governor in the re- Mon. I (a) When will a V. S. s.-nator from Nebraska be chosen? (b) plain tho method. t9. All property in Nebraska is subject annually to three specific Mcfc eluss and name the body determining it. L10. Give the number of your congressional district, and name congressman-elect. ORTHOGRAPHY. 1. Divide into syllables and mark accent of the following words: irate, mandamus, obeisance, corporal, coupon. LWhat words should be included in thi J for the lling lesson? your method of correcting the written spelling lesson. 4. Write the following words and nonym of each: abase, h, clever, duplicate, poverty. L Write the following words and give antonyms for each: dif - lt, delicious, congratulate, benevolence, arraign. S-10. Rewrite the words given below, spelling each correctly: ExageraH rant pheasant auteak parliement umberalla capillary pronounciation alledged ' rophy paralell psychology inocenc mend nan: phlegm gaiety chieftian miuiture IncaiuaoKi oppurtunit? iniquity MENTAL ARITHMETIC. Part 1. Give complete analysis of the following five problems: II. A merchant owning 4 0 barrels of flour sold two-fifths of to A, and % of the remainder to B. How much had he left? Ilf 4 horses eat 2 tons of hay in 8 weeks, how long will It a S horses to eat the same amount? L3. A horse cost $200, and four-fifths of this is twice the cost ;i sleigh, and the sleij; times as much as the harness, luired tho cost of each. </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 E4 A watch and chain cost $4 2. What was the cost of vided one-fifth of the cost of the watch equals % the cost of chain? tA farmer had 4 0 sheep in one field, which was 4-5 of the ber in another field. If V4 of the sheep in each field jump Into field, how many would be in each field? Part II. ( Rapid Drill.) The superintendent will detach this part of the mental arithmetic examination before distributing the questions, and give exercise when all arc ready. Allow ten minutes for completion; then collect answer (tapers and pin to Part one. Applicants will write numbers of prob - lems and answers only. 11. A man earns $75 per month, and spends four-fifths of it w much does he save in a year? What will f&gt; lemons cost at th f 3 for 12 &lt;■• Lv, t will 15 pounds of flour cost at the rate of $4 per dred? 14. A &gt;:■ isht a bushel of cranberries for $3 I 11 h« sell them to ga 's a quart? Lrtain number increased by **, of itself equals 36. Find number. AGRICl'LTl'RE 1. i io'j lroji .hi 1 soil aud give methods of pre &gt;o rapi&lt;! &lt;vaporation. 2. Do \\ I? Give ' for your answer iZ. Explain how (old winter weather may destroy or P of the following year. 4. Describe tho idea: rotation of crops important? 6. Give directio- lecting, planting, ainl for corn 7. Explain tho purpose of spraying. plain &lt;he difference between a plant and a weed S. Name four useful and four harmful Name two breeds of dairy cattle, and two of beef cattle Also nani' A'ING. 1. What is the purpose of teaching drawing in the public I Make a drawing of some flower. Conventionalize and - form a bord. Draw a cylinder lying upon the side with one end visible lfy same to represent a common rolling pin. 4. Draw an open book below the eye and directly in front meant by iai sky line, ib) foreground, (c) back- </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 THEORY AND ART. 1. How does reason differ from memory? I What work in numbers would you attempt during the first r 'of the child's attendance? What purpose have you in mind when you select books and l&gt;apers for your own reading? 4. What measures a man's value to his community? 5. What do you consider the most important study? Why? 6. Give some devices for stimulating the idle pupil to study. 7. What ends are to be kept in mind in temperance instruction? Give reasons for or against the self reporting system of school eminent? 9. Give the purposes of the recitation ti©. When, if ever,* should the pupils recite in the words of book? PHYSIOLOGY. 1. Name the three great functions of the bony skeleton. tine of the occupations that tend to give work to all mup&lt; 13. &lt; changes or processes that food undergoes in the 4. Describe the process of digestion in the thoracic duct. 5. State the four chief uses of the blood. fi. What and where is the arbor vitae? 7. What is the difference between touch and pain? Mention two safe guards against the spread of disease. 9. Why would contact with the outside world "be agonizing" ■ the skin removed? flO. Explain why alcohol is not a food in the ordinary meaning urd. ENGLISH COMPOSITION II. Give reasons for each capital letter and each mark of punc - tion. including quotations, in the following sentence: "What a ion", Trench well says, "the word 'diligence* contains!" 2. Correct ttaeae erroi nit of thi i'jh'ed in a day. h We must appl.v t 1 evil, (c) The man i urt like a motionless statue, with the cktak pocrisj in his mouth. 13. Write a description of a schoolroom which will give an idea tho teacher in ehai 4. Insert the proper word in these blanks: (a) He was sitting Im) the door, (b) We sat down (in, into) the parlor, but soon went (in. into) the library, (c) Throw the paper (in, into) the basket, (d) What will you take (beside, besides) your trunk? Lar to a friend giving your idea of New Year </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 GEOMETRY 1. Theorem: If two straight lines intersect, the vertical angles iual. Theorem: The diagonal of a parallelogram divides the flg - nro Into two equal triangles. 3. Deflno circumference, concentric circles, quadrant. L4. Problem. To draw a straight line tangent to a given circle parallel to a given line. K5. Theorem: If four quantities are in proportion, they are proportion by division. 6. Define polygon. When are polygons similar? I The base of an isosceles triangle is 60 Inches, and each side nches. Find the altitude and the a Problem: To construct a square equivalent to a given rec - tangle. READINC 1. Give, and illustrate by words, five markings of the vowt-: an example. 'hod of teaching children how to study reading. 4. Name the author of any five of the following: Tom Sa The Mill on the Floss, Othello, A Child's Gar - den of Verses, T&lt;&lt; fowl, Nicholas Nickleby, How they Brought s from Ghent to Aix, Tent on the Beach, Bigelow Papers, Lady of Shalott, Ivanhoe, Moeses from an Old Mans*, The Spanish If one prose work by each of the following authors: gfellow, Holmes, Irving, Helen Hunt Jackson, Theodore Roose- L6. Why do most children read in an unnatural tone? How .dition? 7. How often and when should the teacher read for the class? ■low do you teach children to distinguish emphatic words? 9. Give a ten-]; b of Whittier's life. Name one of his poems. Is it profitable to teach children about •effects'' and figures of speech? Give your unbiased opinion with reasons. They will be respected in the marking of your paper. GRAMMAR Define language, grammar 2. Defln. . redundant verbs. Give examples of 3. Write a complex sentence; a compound sentence. Tell how differ. 4. Pa i followin. tinned as </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 5. Write, a sentence containing an indirect object. Write &gt; ontaining an attribute. 6. Diagram, or analyze, "Our greatest glory consist?, mt in falling, but in rising every time we fall." 7. Explain the uso of shall and will. the word "that" in sentences, as follows: (a) n pronoun, (b) interrogative pronoun, (c) adjective, (d) conjum y. Correct where necessary: (a) He looks like he was sick (►&gt;) Was you at the meeting yesterday? (e) We run all the why home last night, (d) Come and sec my pet rabbit, (e) John Robert. Lit, Write a totter I Itag to a a Christmas present. ARITHMETIC 1. Write two numbers to illustrate the Arabic system of nota - two numbers to represent the Roman notation. 2. (a) Add 7r.57 (b) 3452 :!74« 3. Gi multiples of 27; three factors of 27. 14. Define simple fraction; complex fraction; compound fr;i vo an example of each. I Henry bought some collars for $H. a pair of gloves for %, and 4 shirts at $ ~ What change should he r&gt; a |10 bill? Iibic foot of water weighs 1,600 oz. How many tons 1 144 cubic feet of water weigh? 17. An agent bought :!. &gt; bushels of corn at 37% cents, charg - 2 per cent commission, and $8.75 insurance. For how much a hel must it be sold to gain 10 per cent over the entire cost? I .sing machines at $75 apiece, and 9 at 25 apiece. After deducting his commission, he remitted $33 &lt; manufacturer as proceeds. What was the rate of commission? L9. If a pole 20 feet high casts a shadow 12 feet long, how h is the tree whose shadow at the same time is 90 feet long? in. What is the square root of 10.4976? ALGEBRA. El. Give five axioms, one based on each of the fundamental op - tions', and one from which the equation is derived. 2. Give formula for (a) square of a binomial; (b) division of odd pow. •i. Factor: a) a* c* +a s d </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 6. The differem . n two numbers is 16. and the greater U to the less as 7 to 5. What are the numbers? 1111 Solve x — 4 x — 6 x — 8 iiinomial theorem. Find two numbers whose product is 35, and the product of whose sum and difference is 24. PHY- 1. Explain the construction of a mercurial barom - 2. How would you find the volume of an irregularly shaped 13. What must be the initial velocity that a body may rise in air for six seconds? How high will it rise? 4. Define inertia, momentum, energy. &lt;;ive Newton's three laws of motion. 6. Give two effects of heat upon substances 7. Explain the dew point. aguish between simple and complex vibration of strings 9. Give laws for intensity of illumination. L Define any three: Ohm, volt, solenoid, magnet, pole amo. GEOGRAPHY 1. What effect has latitude upon climate? Why? \ame the six continents in order of size. 3. What is paganism, and how does it differ from Christianity? 4. (a) What relation exists between time and longitude? (b) ain the international date line. &lt;;ive an example of the effect of prevailing winds on climate 6. What seas are on the border of or within Russia? 7. Give the four chief occupations of civilized men. 8. Give methods of commercial transportation 19. (a) Name four articles exported in large quantities from United States, (b) Name four articles imported in large quan - m ■ ns for public education in Nebraska. •». Find : M, and x- +8x+15 (a — b\ , a-b\ H 1 + 1 l- -1 • + !&gt;/ V » + »•/ 8. Solve x+y=7 y+z=9 z+r=8 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 HISTORY. 1. What European was first to discover continental America? What nations had settlements in America when John Smith and hiu company came? 3. Make a short statement about each of the following: Roger Williams, Anne Hutchinson, Witchcraft. 4. Name two specific provisions of the Treaty of Paris, 1783. 5. Give boundaries of the United States as it existed at the adoption of the constitution. 6. State how negro slavery was introduced into America, and how it was abolished. 7. What was the doctrine of Nullification, who was its principal advocate, and what finally became of it? 8. Make a brief statement about each of the following: Lord Baltimore, John Paul Jones, James Monroe, U. S. Grant, Grover Cleve - land. 9. Name two recommendations made In President Roosevelt's recent message to congress. io. What case of special importance to Nebraska is now pend - ing before the U. S. supreme court? BOTANY. 1. Define the cell. 2. Give conditions favorable to the germination of seed. 3. Discuss buds as to location, protection and development. 4. What are the distinguishing characteristics of the stem? 5. By drawing and discussion, show the difference between simple and a compound leaf. 6. What is the stamen? 7. Make a drawing of a cross section of a maple and of a corn stalk, and explain any difference. I ' j i-n ■» tr 1 1 1\ L* i" ■ i ] riJQf~*iiQCti oYi of A fopviiiiTi i t m or f f* r n qc t f\ t o \ </seg>
            
            <seg id="p142">&gt; TABLE OF CONTENTS In Memoriam, A. K. Goiid&gt; .. i— iv Letter of Transmittal T School Legislation 1906 8, New Certification Law. . ;i UalOO Normal Institute HI — 65 Junior Normal Schools • Statistics. See Ap|&gt;endix B. Free Text-book Law The It. J. Barr Quarterly Centennial Anniversay «3— Mh Eighth Grade Kxaminations and Promotion Kxercises Literature and the: Community !*&gt;&lt;■ Normal Training in Hijrh Schools !'" Lectures, Addresses, Ileports and I'apers on Educational Prob - lems of To-day 18 Report of State Normal Schools IW9-413 Agricultural Education and Industrial Training 41 ' Report of the University of Nebraska Nebraska Teachers' Heading Circle Work and Teachers" Certifi - cates in Nebraska . Appaad Statistical Tables AppeDdix B ciska Uniform Kxaminatioi. n|&gt;endix C </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>