<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00047.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00047.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Sixth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction to the Governor of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1920-12-01">1920-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">cTu?enti3"Sixth biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction to the Qouernor of the State of Nebraska For the oiennium beginning Januaru 9, 1919 and ending January 5, 1921 JOHN HI. MATZEN STATE SUPERltlTEtlDETlT QF PUBLIC INSTRUCTlOtl </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE ACME PRINTING CO. Lincoln. Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Page Letter of Transmittal _ - _ 5 Official Roster _ 6 Nebraska State Superintendents 7 A Tribute to William H. Clemmons _ „ _ 8-11 Introduction , . 12 Standardization of Rural Schools _ 13-24 Nebraska Village and Rural High Schools _. 25-37 County High Schools ■. 3 8 Special "Rural High Schools" _ _. 38 Consolidated Schools _ 39-43 Consolidations in Nebraska 4 3-4 8 The Rural School Library _ 48-51 Accredited Schools 52-54 Institutions of Higher Education 54-57 State Certificates _ 57-62 Institutional Certificates 6 3-7 1 County Certificates - 72-74 Appropriations for Biennium 75 Financial Statements 1918-19, 1919-20 _ 75^76 Nebraska School Statistics _ 77-79 Normal Training in High Schools _ _ 79-89 School Tax, Number of Teachers, Salaries Paid Teachers 1919._ 89-91 School Tax, Number of Teachers, Salaries Paid Teachers 192O._ 92-94 State Aid to Weak Districts - - 94 County Superintendents, Salary, Graded Schools, etc 95-102 Average Attendance, Months of School, etc _102-110 Districts, School Houses, Length of Term 111-118 Census, Enrollment, etc _ 11 9-123 Disbursements to "Vocational Schools under the Smith-Hughes Act _ 124-125 Statistical Tables on Normal Training 127-129 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Page Accredited High Schools _ 5 2 Advantages of - 53-54 Standard of - 52-53 Appropriations for Biennium 7 5 Average Daily Attendance, Months Held, etc -103-110 Census, Enrollment, etc 119-123 Certificates ~ 57-74 City State — 57-60, 71 Consolidated Schools . 89-48 Advantages of _ - 42-43 Consolidations in Nebraska — 43-44 Defects of Old Consolidation Law 41 List of Consolidated Schools _ 46-48 New Redistricting Law _ 3 9 County High Schools _ 38 County Superintendents, Salary, Graded Schools, etc 95-102 Districts, School Houses, Length of Term _ 111-118 Financial Statements and Statistical Abstracts 75-79 Institutions of Higher Education _ 54-55 Introduction _ 12 Letter of Transmittal _ 5 Nebraska State Superintendents 7 Normal Training in High Schools _ 79-89 Combination Programs _ 84-86 Normal Training Program _ 8 4 Statistical Tables _ 1 27-129 Synopsis of Regulations _ 79-83 Official Roster _ 6 Rural School Library 48-57 The Library Survey 49-51 Special Rural High Schools 38 Standardization of Rural Schools _ _ 13-24 Minimum Requirements _ 14 Official Score Card _ 15-16 Organization _ 17-24 c? v ». *. Standard Rural Schools 2 4 State Aid to Weak Districts 94 School Tax, Number Teachers, Salaries, etc.. 89-94 State Normal Schools _ 5 5 Tribute to Hon. William H. Clemmons _._ 8-11 Vocational Schools Under Smith-Hughes Act 124-129 I County ». Emergency — General State Institutional Examination Dates Rulings, Interpretations _ lolleges and Universities 72-73 61 60, 62 63-71 73-74 61-62 55-56 iage and Rural High Schools _ Approval Blanks Course of Study _. _ Lab ratory Equipment _ Library _ Schools Approved _ _ Summary _ _ _ 25-37 31 27-28 28-31 31 32-37 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL . STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION LINCOLN His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Sir: I have the honor to submit, in compliance with Article XVI, Section 205, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, the Twenty-Sixth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. Most respectfully, JOHN M. MATZEN, State Superintendent of Public Instruction December 1, 1920 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Department of Public Instruction LINCOLN EXECUTIVE DIVISION John M. Matzen John Speedie Cora A. Thompson I. N. Clark State Superintendent ..Deputy State Superintendent Assistant Superintendent Rural School Inspector Archer L. Burnham Normal Training Inspector Frank R. Beers Assistant Normal Training Inspector Lulu S. Wolford , Assistant Superintendent ASSISTANTS Secretary Cecile Snapp. Ruth E. Wheeler Secretary Normal Training Dept., Bookkeeper Stenographer Theoda Fox. Helen M. Stacy Stenographer Eulalia Heinemeyer Stenographer Verneda Whitney Clerk and Statistician Caroline C. Cooper Clerk of Examinations Mrs. C. D. Wheeler Clerk of Examinations Etta Brown Clerk of Examinations </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA STATE SUPERINTENDENTS S. D. Beale 1 869-1871 J. M. McKenzie 1971-1877 S. R. Thompson 1 877-1881 W. W. W. Jones . 1881-1887 George E. Lane 1 887-1891 A. K. Goudy 1 891-1895 H. R. Corbett 1 895-1897 W. R. Jackson _ 1 897-1901 W. K. Fowler 1901-1905 J. L. McBrien 19 05-1909 E. C. Bishop, 1 909-1911 J. W. Crabtree 19 1 1- ( Resigned ) J. E. Delzell 1 911-1915 A. O. Thomas . 19 1 5-1 9 17 W. H. Clemmons . 1 917-1920 John M. Mazten 1 920 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Illlllllllllllllllllllllllllllll Ill Illlllllllllllllll Illl IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIHIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII A Tribute to HON. WILLIAM H. CLEMMONS State Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1917-1920. Born April 6, 1856. Died January 9, 192O. Age 63 years, 9 months, 3 days. The present report most fittingly includes an appreciative tribute to the Hon. W. H. Clemmons, who closed a most useful life, at the end of his third year of service, as State Superintendent of Public Instruction. Born in Ohio, in 1856, and when but seven years of age bereft of his mother, he was left, through the early breaking up o his home, in a state of dependence and privation. Bound out to a farmer in Indiana for a period of his minority, his childhood was laborious and severe. Yet by resolution, and ambition, he emanci pated himself, years before the allotted date, and at once began his life-pursuit of education, and its mission to men. Completing courses of study at Valparaiso Normal, and at The Indiana University, he was graduated with the degree of A. M. and began teaching. After a superintendency of the Tipton Schools, in which he proved exception ally successful, he came west; taught in Nebraska, at different points and then accepted the Presidency of the Normal School, at Fremont Identified with that institution, for some thirty years, he advanced it from days of weakness, to great strength; from glory to glory, unti it became Fremont College, and was known and honored throughou the West. Throwing his whole life into the college, he struggled with true genius, and indefatigable industry, against countless obstacles and vicissitudes, only to prove himself a master-teacher, and courageous iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii I iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii nun iiiiiiinii mi mini uiiiiiiiiiiiiiiuiii </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">IIIINIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII!lll!llllllllllllll!lll!l!lllllli:illllllllllllllllllllll!llllllllllllll!l!llllllllllllllllllll|l!l||H to the limit. Fremont College was eventually blended with The Mid - land University, and the new institution, still carries the older, In its heart, to a greater and nobler future. Meanwhile President Clemmons was elected in 1916, Nebraska Superintendent of Public Instruction. In his new office, he was characteristically energetic, and progressive, peculiarly efficient and farseeing. In the three years of his incumbency, he commanded the esteem, admiration and confidence, of all State educators; promoted the consolidation of rural schools; the policy of redistricting the territory, and all the most approved enterprises of his time. His biennial report of 1918, shows him to have been an up-to-date, competent, and constructive educator, whom the State will long remember with pride. Personally, William H. Clemmons was of a forceful nature, an iron will, the kindliest sympathies, indefatig - able zeal and ambition. He was opulent in altruistic purpose, and a soul that stood ever in reverence before God. A true man, and exemplary citizen, an inspiring educator, and an ideal American, he lives still in the hearts of thousands, to whom he opened the highway to education, and made leaders and benefactors of mankind. His pass - ing from earth was sudden, and tragic. After a busy week, in the northern part of the State, he came to Fremont upon Friday, January 9, 1920, and the same evening in the home of a friend, was summoned away to the higher life. At his obsequies held in Fremont, and later again in Tipton, Indiana, his memory was honored by multitudes of former students; by educators of eminence, by professional men from wide and far; and by citizens of all classes. One who had been his pastor for thirty years, in Fremont, and an uncle, of Toledo, Ohio, preached the funeral discourses, and members of his former Faculty, were bearers at the grave. The motto of his College was: 'The Light of Truth Leads," and the great educator has "followed the gleam." His memory is blessed, and his influence will continue, an ever up - lifting dynamic in the earth. REV. WM. H. BUSS. NIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIINIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIM </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 12 INTRODUCTION tThe extreme and unusual conditions which have existed during biennium have deeply affected the school affairs of the state. Qg the year 1919 we were still under the influence of the boom ting from the World War. The year 1920 has experienced a :ed reaction resulting in the tightening of the money market consequently rapidly falling prices creating a general business sssion throughout the country. The courage and loyalty of the friends of education throughout I he entire state is withstanding a splendid test in the trying times through which we are now passing and we are fully assured that the needs of our schools for the coming biennium will be met by the same liberal response that has been evidenced during the past two IThe people of Nebraska realize as never before that the biggest most important business of the state is the proper education of youth. They are fully convinced that the money expended in an :ient system of education is the very best investment within their eh, and that in no other way can we hope to build permanently a ter and grander state. tin contemplating the progress of public education in our state the coming years we are confronted by some serious and important )lems the demands of some of which are already very pressing following are a few of these: More equitable methods of taxation; r to secure an adequate supply of well trained teachers; To in - .se the educational opportunity of the rural child; Improved sani - ' conditions for all schools; A definite building program under state control. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 13 STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION JOHN M. MATZEN, State Superintendent John Speedie, Deputy I. N. Clark, Rural School Inspector STANDARDIZATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS INTRODUCTION The following plans are offered in the hope of improving rural school conditions. To this end definite standards have been formu - lated. Especially the physical Conditions of our schools should be bettered. The outlines below touch upon the essential phases of con - struction, equipment, and care. Even though where a reorganization of school districts into consolidations is not possible the opportunities for • improvement are many. A good school building with good equipment and attractive sur - roundings is a valuable asset to any community. Anything that con - tributes to the well being of the youth of our commonwealth is of first importance and should receive our closest attention. The requirements herein given are easy for districts with buildings of the correct type, or which contemplate erecting new ones. We be - lieve that these standards are also possible where the building is of the old type for little change would be required. The standards will be applied especially in the one-room rural school, but all schools not within incorporated villages or cities may be standardized when they meet the standards. If the school has more than one class room, each such room must meet the requirements except insofar as the requirements are-general. HOW A SCHOOL MAY BECOME STANDARDIZED When a school reaches the minimum requirements the county superintendent should report the same to the state superintendent. If the report is favorable someone from the department will make a visit to the school and give it an official rating. If the school justifies a score of 75 it will be classed as a Standard School. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">MINIMUM REQUIREMENTS OF STANDARDIZATION 1. The school term must be at least nine months in length. ■ The teacher must be a holder of a first grade county certificate or its equivalent. ■ The school grounds must be adequate, well drained, and kept clean. I The school building and out buildings must be adequate, comply with the law, and kept in good repair, clean and sanitary. I The school must have a good well on the grounds or the use of one nearby and provide sanitary methods for the use of water. I The school must provide single desks of suitable size adjusted to the needs of the children, and the room must contain at least fifteen square feet of floor space to each child. I The school room must be lighted from the left or the^left and rear with the window area equivalent to one-fifth of the floor space. I The heating must be of some approved type and the room must contain 200 cubic feet of air space for each child. 9. The school must be equipped with teacher's desk and chair, globe, ■ maps, blackboards, and up-to-date text books. Sanitary methods of cleaning must be employed. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 15 OFFICIAL SCORE CARD FOR NEBRASKA STANDARD RURAL SCHOOLS County Name No .-. .No. Standard I Official I. — Organization * Nine months' term. _ 5 Following Course of Study 1 Records carefully kept 1 Program posted 1 Bi-monthly examinations 1 Reports to parents and County Superintendent... .1 10 I II. — Teacher •First Grade County Certificate _ 5 Normal Training Graduate or equivalent 3 One or more year's experience 2 10 | III. — Grounds "One or more acres of ground, well drained and kept clean _5 Sod 2 Trees 2 Fence 1 10 I IV. — Out Buildings •Two separate closets, 50 feet apart, kept clean and sanitary, and free from marks 5 Entrances screened 2 Well lighted and ventilated 2 Ventilating shaft 1 (Same if indoor toilets are used) 10 | V. — Water Supply •Good well on ground or nearby, using drinking fountain or covered cooler with individual cups__5 Well curbing 1 Sink and drain » 2 Basin, soap, and towels 2 10 | </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 16 OFFICIAIi SCORE CARD — Continued Standard Official VI. — Building 'Single desks of suitable size with 15 square feet floor space per child. Light from left or from left and rear with window area equivalent to one-fifth of floor area. Heat from basement furnace, room heater, or jacketed stove, the room containing 200 cubic feet of air space for each child 10 Building painted 2 Walls clean and tinted or papered 2 Light colored adjustable shades 2 Separate cloak rooms 2 Room or alcove for library 2 20 VII. — Equipment E tier's desk and chair, dictionary, up-to-date books, globe, maps, and 20 lineal feet of [board 10 Reference books 2 Books of fiction 2 Bookcase and reading table 2 Well selected pictures 2 Playground equipment 2 20 VIII. — Sanitation Eirs swept daily, using sweeping compound; s, desks, furnishings and woodwork wiped y with damp cloth 5 Floor scrubbed when needed 2 Ceiling and walls wiped down once a year 2 Individual cups and towels washed when needed. .1 10 100 * </seg>
            <seg id="p017">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 17 NEBRASKA STANDARD SCHOOLS I. — Organization. .Every school eligible for standardization must have at least a nine months' term. It is believed that amount of time will be required to complete a course comparable with the courses of the best schools in the state. It is not intended that the state course of study must be followed without regard to the text used. The course of sutdy suggests the limits of the work — the branches of study, the essential points of each STANDARD RURAL SCHOOL, PIERCE COUNTY branch, and the amount of time required for their completion. Follow - ing the course will tend to better organization of the school, result in better grading, and furnish a better opportunity for supervision and comparison of school work. All records should be neatly and completely made. These records include the attendance and classification register, the library record, and a progress record. The program should provide for the study periods as well as recita- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 18 tion periods. It should be posted in a conspicuous place and faithfully followed. The bi-monthly examinations will enable the teacher to check up on her own work as well as that of the pupils. Reviews and tests following the completion of particular topics are especially helpful. Reports are always of interest to parents, and will a-id in giving the parent an idea of the child's progress. The reports should also include the child's attendance and punctuality. Monthly attendance reports should be sent to the county superintendent. This will aid in enforcing the compulsory attendance law. II. — Teacher No school will be standardized unless the teacher is a holder of a First Grade County Certificate or its equivalent. State certificates are deemed the equivalent. I) have preparation equivalent to graduation from a Normal Train - high school the teacher should have equal preparation in some r institution giving the same sort of training. It is highly desirable that teachers who are making a good record be retained in the same school if possible. They are better acquainted with local problems and will be better able to organize the school for effective community work. The rural teacher should be a country-bred girl, thoroughly in love with country life and country ideals. She should possess the qualities of leadership that will enable her to stimulate within the children the highest ideals of character and life. III. — Grounds While one acre of ground will be accepted for standardization a larger amount is to be preferred. The grounds should be large enough to accommodate all the pupils in their games, to provide for a lawn and parking spaces for trees and shrubs. The grounds must be suffi - ciently high to afford good drainage. It should be kept clean and free from rubbish. The building should occupy the highest part of the grounds. Too little attention is being paid to beautifying the grounds Trees, flowers, and shrubs are necessary not only for the beauty of the site, but will furnish an environment that will aid in developing a child's aesthetic tastes. The playground is not a luxury but a necessity. Boys and girls from </seg>
            <seg id="p019">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 19 the farm need the free play and the development of the body that comes from exercise in play, the same as boys and girls from the city. In order to protect the lawn and shrubs the school grounds should be fenced. A good fence can be made from gas pipe running through heavy posts. This is substantial and gives the grounds a good ap - pearance. IV — Out Buildings If there is one thing that needs attention more than another it is the condition of the toilets. These should be as clean and sanitary as tliose found in the best homes of the community. The teacher should make a daily inspection of these buildings. They should be kept free from marks. If outside toilets are used they should be located in opposite rear corners of the play ground. To comply with the law they must be at least fifty feet apart. The buildings should be cleaned and repaired before school opens in the fall. They should be rain proof, well lighted and ventilated. The entrances should be screened to prevent the view and to keep the dust and snow from blowing in. The following types of privies may be used: A. Dry earth closet. B. Septic tank container. C. Water tight vault, that may be emptied and cleaned at frequent Wherever possible inside toilets should be provided. V. — Water Supply Every school should be provided with a supply of pure water. The most practical and convenient source is a well on the grounds. If it is not possible to get pure water at reasonable cost from a well on the grounds, it should come from one on a farm near enough to insure a constant supply of fresh water. Schools should provide some sani - tary and convenient device for the use of drinking water.* A drinking fountain with bubbler or covered cooler or stone jar with individual cups will be accepted. The common drinking cup is absolutely for - bidden. The well should be protected against contamination by having a </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT tight curbing built around it. The waste water should run out through the sink and drain. Basin and soap should be provided. Individual clean towels should be used. Paper towels are cheapest and most practical. The children should be taught to keep faces and hands clean. They should wash hands: A. After the use of the toilet, B. Before eating the lunch. C. Any time that hands may become soiled by play out doors, or after doing the various kinds of hand work connected with the school. VI. — Building The school building should be adequate; large enough, with correct heat, light, and ventilation. The foundation, floor, walls, and roof should be in good condition. The class room should contain 15 square feet of floor space for each child. A class room 32 by 24 would be large enough for 40 pupils. It should be seated with single desks of suitable sizes to accommodate all sizes of enildren. When -new ones are purchased they should be adjustable. The seats should not be placed over 30 feet from the blackboard, a greater distance causing eye strain. A one-room school should be supplied with desks of five different sizes. When pupils enter school they should be assigned to seats of the proper size. In no case should a pupil sit where his feet do not touch the floor. Since pupils are seated in school for five or six hours a day they should be given as much comfort as possible. It is criminal to have children sit in seats that tend to deform their bodies. Proper seating will contribute largely to the good discipline of the school. Desks of only one size should be placed in a row from front to back. In getting the proper distance measure from the edge of the desk to the back of the seat, the following will be a guide: The light should come into a class room from the left or from the left and rear. The window area should not be less than one-fifth of umt ber of ] Desl Distance apar ge of childrei 6 9 inches 6 to 7 5 9 inches 8 to 9 4 10 inches 10 to 11 12 to 13 3 2 11 inches 12 inches </seg>
            <seg id="p021">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 21 the floor area. This will allow a sufficient quantity of light to enter the room. In no case should pupils be seated facing windows. The main source of light should be from the east or west. North light is good for the eyes but does not admit the sunlight. The light coming from opposite sides of the room is bad and should be avoided. The windows should not be placed less than three feet nor farther than four feet from the floor. They should be placed as near the ceiling as possible. The windows in the rear should be not nearer than six feet from the floor. The windows at the left should be set at the least possible distance between them but not too near the front of the rogm; about six feet from the front wall. The width of the room should never be more than twice the height measured from the floor to top of the windows. To improve the light of the old type of building, so common in Nebraska, the following sug - gestions should be followed: Wall up all windows which the seated pupils face. Darken the lower part of windows to the rear and right. If windows on the left are too low place a window board of sufficient width, on the window sill so as tr &gt; bring the light in the proper distance from the floor. If the district can afford the expense a better plan would be to remodel the lighting, by walling up the windows on the right, re - arranging the windows on the left, placing in a sufficient number. In installing a heating plant the main problem is to secure uniform heat throughout the room and at the same time receive fresh air com - ing directly from out of doors. In mild weather the air may be brought in through the open window. The basement furnace is the best arrangement for heating the school room if properly installed. In such a system the fresh air must be taken from the room through a foul air flue. The chimney should bt» 12 by 12 inches in the clear on the inside. The smoke flue should be an iron pipe and pass up through the center of the chimney. The foul air should pass out through the chimney surrounding the smoke flue. No unjacketed stove should be tolerated in any school. The room heater is perhaps the most convenient plant for the one-room school. This should have a fresh air inlet through the wall of the school house into the jacket against the middle of the hottest part of the stove. The foul air outlet should be from the same side of the room as the stove is located. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT An even temperature of 68° to 70° F. should be maintained in the room. The thermometer should be suspended so as to register the temperature at the breathing line. Never place it against the wall. The room should contain 200 cubic feet of air space for every pupil. This amount with proper facilities for ventilation will insure a con - stant supply of fresh air. In order to preserve the building and add to its attractiveness it should be well painted. The walls should be kept clean and tinted or papered. The following combination of colors are suitable for in - terior walls: Side Wall Cream Silver gray Bright sage Buff stone Ceiling Ivory Pearl gray Lichen gray Cream Dark walls should be avoided. The ceiling color should extend down on side walls about 18 inches to the molding. The shades should be light colored and adjustable Schools should have separate cloak rooms. These rooms should be entered from the class room. They should be lighted and ventilated. There should be a separate room for the school Jibrary. This room could also be used as a teachers' room. The s&lt;ame room could be used as a retiring room. VII. — Equipment Too often good up-to-date equipment is not considered a necessary part of the school. These should be figured in when the budget is made out. tgood teacher's desk with compartments where records may be which is provided with a lock and key should be furnished. 3d teacher's chair should also be provided. Every school should have a good up-to-date unabridged dictionary. A good supply of modern texts should be provided. Every school should have a good 12-inch pendent globe and a good set of wall </seg>
            <seg id="p023">OF PUBLIC INSTKUCTION 23 States, and a world map. The school should be equipped with at least 20 lineal feet of blackboard, either slate or composition board. The board should be 3 % feet wide and placed low enough for use by pri - mary pupils. The board may be either black or green. Every school should have a good bookcase that can be locked. A reading table and chair near the bookcase are convenient. Besides the text books there should be a good encyclopedia of from 4 to 10 volumes. A few other reference books and well selected fic - tion should be available. The bookcase should contain books only and they should be systematically arranged. A few good pictures neatly framed and artistically arranged are essential. Three or four are sufficient for a rural school. Over decora - tion should be avoided. Pictures of distinguished people and famous historical and geographical places are recommended. Every school should be supplied with a few good pieces of play ground equipment. Open air exercise is best for growing children. Suggestive Playground Equipment — 1. Swings 6. Volley ball outfit 7. Baseball outfit 8. Level baseball field 9. Running track 2. Teeter board 3. Slide 4. Giant tride 5. Turning pole 10. Sand box Games are best when — 1. They bring into action muse)"" of the entire body. 2. They make team work necessary. 3. They involve attention. 4. They permit participation of all children. 5. They are safe to the health of the children. Vffl. — Sanitation 'If the floors are not oiled they should be swept with sweeping com - pound daily. The sweepings should be burned or buried. The seats, desks, furnishings, and wood work should be wiped daily with oily or damp cloths. A feather duster should not be tolerated. When the cloths become dirty they should be washed thoroughly, dried and re - oiled. The floors should be kept smooth and scrubbed frequently. The ceilings and walls should be wiped down once a year. If the school does not have a fountain with bubbler there should be individual drinking cups which should be cleaned frequently. Individual towels </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT should be used. If the district does not furnish paper towels, the children should bring their own from home. These should be kept clean. Sanitation is a problem of good housekeeping. Things should be kept as clean and neat as they are in the best homes. STANDARD RURAL SCHOOLS z Name of School No. County Name of School No. County Pierce 22 31 Stark Valley 23 Banner 47 71 Clay West Buffalo 102 80 Union 102 Platte 5 6 8 36 48 Custer 33 62 Dames 38 78 Dixon 19 1 Douglas 13 Sarpy Avery 5 41 River View 5 46 16 49 18 61 Scotts Bluff Sunflower 68 Fillmore Harmony 38 Lake Alice 65 Garfleld 14 Lake Minatare .. 14 Hamilton 16 East Ward 1 Keya Paha Springview 56 North Ward Jamison 81 Sherman Cement Block.... 10 Lancaster Pleasant View.... 76 Stanton Bega 12 Plainview 104 Blandt 31 107 Cornfield 35 143 Washington 5 Merrick 8 7 Silverdale 13 25 15 39 31 56 50 Wayne ..: 10 Nance Timber Cr'k V'w 7 Webster 59 Big Cut 12 85 Liberty Knoll.... 16 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 25 5 Approved Rural and Village High Schools. NEBRASKA VILLAGE AND RURAL HIGH SCHOOLS HIGH SCHOOL EDUCATION More and more people are beginning to see the value of a high school education. Without it boys and girls are handicapped when they assume the duties of their life work. It is not only necessary that our young people are able to do the work on the farm or in the home, but must also be able to champion their cause wherever they may be. The time was when people thought that a high school education was necessary only for those who expected to enter one of the professions; teaching,, law, medicine, or the ministry. We believe now that if it is good for the few it is good for the many. The larger association that may come into the lives of boys and girls who attend high school is needed especially to fit them for the more complex duties of modern life. They need this larger association in order to more fully develop initiative and the power to adjust themselves to community needs, and to improve the opportunities that can come only to those who are prepared to make use of them. If our democracy is to endure, it will do so through an educated citizenship. Then only will the burdens of society, business, and gov - ernment rest upon those fitted to serve. It is the duty of the present generation to equalize the opportunity for every boy and girl to secure this education. PURPOSE OF APPROVAL Many of the smaller schools are unable to meet the standards set for accreditruent to the University of Nebraska, not being able to maintain more than nine, ten, or eleven grades of work, and with less substantial facilities for carrying on such a program. It is thought best by this department, in justice to the children who live in such districts, to apply such standards which may reasonably be met and which may induce greater educational progress. It is also the purpose of this department to establish standards for approval of schools giving high school courses in order that a more complete system of education may be developed. By this means also the work of these schools may be made to harmonize more fully with </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT I courses in higher institutions of learning, thus affording the am - ius child an open door to a more eilicient preparation for life. The ediate use is to provide a means of designating schpe4s in corn - ice with the Free High School Attendance Law. Schools comply - with these standards may collect tuition from other districts for resident pupils. |:hools are sometimes confused in the use of the terms "Accredited" "Approved" schools. The accredited schools are the four-year i schools whose work is accepted by the University of Nebraska, graduates from these schools enter the university without examina - . The schools are inspected by the university annually, and the •se of study harmonizes with the requirements of the university such schools. The approved schools are all the high schools in the state which meet the requirements of the state department of education, as schools qualified to receive free high school tuition from districts not granting free high school education. These schools may be nine, ten, eleven, or twelve grade schools. In each case they must meet the requirements as outlined by the state department. In the first place all schools ac - crdited to the University of Nebraska are approved by the state de - partment. These are approved without inspection from the depart - ment. The non-accredited schools may be approved for the ninth, tenth, eleventh, or twelfth grades when they meet the requirements as out - lined by the state superintendent. The course as outlined for the approved schools fits into the courses for the accredited schools, thus making it easy for a student to go from one to the other. REQUIREMENTS FOR APPROVAL Number of Teachers Required for Full Standard. 9 grade school 2 teachers 10 grade school 3 teachers 11 grade school 4 teachers 12 grade school 5 teachers The above standards will govern where there are a sufficient num - ber of pupils. In many schools, especially in rural schools, the number of pupils for each grade and each teacher is so small that some reduc - tion may be made without crippling the work of the school. In such cases the number of teachers may be reduced by one, except that no school will dp atinrnvprf wit h Ipqq thinn twn toanhorc </seg>
            <seg id="p027">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 2 7 Certification of Teachers To meet the requirements for full standard in the nine and ten grade schools, the teacher doing the' high school work must hold a first grade county certificate or the equivalent. The teachers doing the high school work in the eleven and twelve grade schools must hold a first grade state certificate or the equivalent. In any case the teacher must receive the endorsement of the county superintendent, as one qualified to handle the particular school in which she teaches. THE COURSE OF STUDY Grade Nine First Semester Second Semester Algebra 5 Algebra 5 English i 5 English 5 Science 5 Science 5 Agriculture or Agriculture or Physical Geography General Science Elective 5 Elective 5 (Select one) Latin (Select one) Latin Manual Training Bookkeeping Manual Training Civics Home Economics Home Economics Grade Ten English 5 Botany 5 European History 5 European History 5 Geometry 5 Geometry 5 Elective 5 Elective 5 (Select one) Latin (Select one) Latin Manual Training Home Economics Manual Training Home Economics Grade Eleven English 5 English 5 Physiology 5 Agriculture ..-..". 5 Physics 5 Physics 5 Elective 5 Elective 5 (Select one) (Select one) Algebra Solid Geometry Latin . Latin </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Schools that are very small may combine grades and alternate the work by years. Ninth and tenth grades may be combined, and eleventh and twelfth grades. Ninth and eleventh grades or tenth and twelfth grades should not be combined. School boards should consult with the county superintendent when choosing electives or fitting the course to the local needs of the community. Physics and chemistry should not be undertaken without a sufficient supply of usable apparatus for the laboratory work. The manual training and home economics should not be undertaken unless sufficient room and equipment are provided and competent teachers secured. CARE OF BOOKS AM) APPARATUS (The care of books and apparatus is of first concern. The school ild provide good bookcases or cabinets in which to keep materials. &gt;ok or piece of apparatus that is not worth taking care of is not :h procuring in the first place. The cases should have doors and s. When materials are taken from the school by the pupils a rd should be made, and checked off when returned. A good work 3 should be provided. LABORATORY EQOPMKXT The equipment listed below should be sufficient for the work in physical geoegraphy, general science and general agriculture. The teacher in ordering apparatus must consult the particular text to be used, thus varying slightly the apparatus secured. A few extras will be needed for botany. We do not advise the purchase of an expensive compound microscope for the work in botany. If physics and chemis - try are to be taken up some additional apparatus will be needed. When the classes are large additional amounts of certain kinds of apparatus will be needed. The work should be individual as nearly as possibl.e. Grade 1 Twel lve American History 5 American History English 5 Civics Chemistry 5 Chemistry Elective 5 Elective f( Select one) Arithmetic (Select one) Grammar Latin Latin </seg>
            <seg id="p029">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 29 AGRICULTURE* Quantity Description Price 2 Alcohol Lamps, 8 oz _ _ _ _ _ _ $ .75 4 Acid Measures _ _ _ 6 5 1 Babcock milk tester, 4 bottle_ _ 15.00 1 ' Card Board, 16x20 in _ 10 4 Evaporating Dishes,.... _ _ 1.00 1 Glass Funnel, 4 in 50 1 Graduate, 4 oz.._ _ _ _ _ _ _ .4 5 1 Harvard Trip Scale 13.20 4 Milk test bottles _. _ _ 1.25 6 Maple rulers (Eng. &amp; met.) 30 2 Meter-yard sticks _ _ _ _ 80 4 Pipettes combined _ _ _ 9 5 1 Spring balance, 25 lbs., % lb. divisions _ 2 5 ■"&gt; r. 6 Student Lamp Chimneys _ la 2 Test tube brushes _ _ _ .60 12 Test tubes ,5x5% in '. 30 1 Ring Stand (2 rings) 90 2 Tripod Magnifiers _ 1.25 12 feet Tubing, glass, % in. bore : 50 12 feet Tubing, rubber, *4 in _ __ .60 24 Vials with cork and label _ 1.20 1 set Weights from % oz. to 2 lb... _ 1.50 $42.80 *In ordering apparatus teacher should avoid duplicating material. GENERAL SCIENCE* Quantity Description • ■ Price 9 Alcohol lamps _ _ _ _ % .80 1 Ball with hook 25 1 Ball and ring apparatus _ _ L. 1.65 1 Balance, Harvard trip _ 13.2.0 3 Balances, spring 2000 grams or 25 lbs _ 2.00 1 Barometer, tube graduated .40 2 Bladders _ 60 Beakers, 2 5 Occ 6 0 A 2 Bells, electric _ _ 60 6 Bottles, wide mouth, 8 oz. rubber stoppers, 2 holes to fit _ _ _ _ _ 50 1 lb. Copper wire, bare No. 18 _ 1.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 1 lb. Copper wire, insulated No. 18 1.50 1 Compass _ _ _ 1.00 4 Dry cells _ _ _ 2.00 2 Florence flasks, flat bottom, 16 oz. rubber stoppers, 2 holes to fit .-. _ 90 1 Package filter paper, 6 in _ _ 50 1 Glass funnel, 4 in.._ _ _ 50 1 Graduate 2 OOcc _ _ _ _ „ T5 1 Hydrometer for light and heavy liquid 1.65 hi lb. Iron filings , _ _ _ 25 1 box Labels, Denison's No. 219 _ _ _ _ 10 2 Magnets, bar 6 in 55 1 Magnet, U shape, 5 in _ _ _. : 85 2 Magnifiers, tripod 1 in. focus 2.00 1 lb. Mercury _ 2.50 2 Meter-yard sticks 1_ _ _ 75 Vi doz. Needles, knitting _ _ 1 Osmos apparatus for diffusion of liquids 50 ■ Cake paraffin _ .30 r ■ Vi lb. Parchment paper _ 40 1 coil Picture wire _ .25 3 Pinch cocks _ .50 1 Prism, Triangular _ _ 50 1 Pulley, single _ _ 50 R Pulley, double . _________ _ 50 1 Pulley, triple _ 90 1 Ring stand with 2 rings _ 90 12 Rulers, Maple, 12 in _ .._ 50 1 piece Rubber sheet, 12 in. square : .25 12 Test tubes, 5 x % in _ _ , ".30 12 Test tubes, 5x5% in _ _ .30 2 Test tube brushes _ 60 2 Thermometers, C. &amp; F. readings 2.00 1 lb. Tubing, glass, % in _ 50 12 ft. Rubber tubing, % in _ 60 2 Tubes, thistle, 12 in. stems 1.00 1 set Weights, iron, % oz. to 2 lbs 1.50 1 set Weights, brassed iron in block 1 gram to 500 grams_ 5.00 $55.55 *In ordering apparatus teachers should avoid duplication of ma- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 31 CHEMICALS 1 oz. Calcium sulphate 1 qt. Formalin 40^ 4 oz. Hydrochloric acid 1 oz. Iodine 1 tube Litmus paper, 100 pieces, red 1 tube Litmus paper, 100 pieces, blue 4 oz. Manganese dioide 1 oz. Magnesuim sulphate 4 oz. Nitric acid 4 oz. Potassium chlorate 4 oz. Potassium Chloride 4 oz. Potassium Nitrate 1 oz. Potassium iodide 1 stick Phosphorous yellow Granulated zinc 1 qt. Alcohol, wood LABORATORY SAMPLES A very helpful part of the laboratory can be secured in the com - munity during the year. These will consist of soil samples — gravel, sand, clay, and loam; samples of lime stone for experimental purposes in the laboratory; specimens of various kinds of wood; seed samples; specimens of unthreshed grain; and samples of forage crops. LIBRARY Every school should be supplied with a good twelve-inch globe, a set of good wall maps, mounted in a case, a six to ten volume encyclo - pedia, and a good unabridged dictionary. The school will find a few good . reference books a very great help in the work of the school. While it is very desirable that a school have a well selected collection of books of fiction, it is not required. Many very valuable bulletins giving much information on topics of interest to the community may be obtained from the department of agriculture, Washoington, D. C, and also from the department of agri - culture of the University of Nebraska. APPROVAL BLANKS The blanks sent out by this office should be carefuly filled out and sent to the department with the recommendation of the county superin - tendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SCHOOLS APPROVED FOE HIGH SCHOOL WORK County No. Dist. Name of School No. Grades Adams _ _ _ _ 53 Ayr __ 12 Adams _ _ _ _ 11 Holstein 11 Adams 81 Prosser _ _ _ _ 10 Antelope Antelope Boone Boone Boyd Boyd Boyd Buffalo Buffalo _. Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo .._.. Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Burt Burt Burt Burt 21 Alder _ ........ 10 Burt Blackbird _ 10 Burt 7 Decatur _ 11 Burt 31 Elm Creek _ 9 Burt _ 34 Jefferson _ 10 Burt Riverside _1_ _ _ _ 12 Butler 25 Abie ._ _ 11 Butler 1 71 Bellwood _ 11 Butler 86 Bruno . _ 10 Butler _ 80 Butler 10 Butler 2 Linwood _ _ 11 Butler 17 Octavia 11 Butler 83 Surprise _ , 11 Cass 20 Avoca _ _ 11 Cass 85 Murdock , _ 10 Cass 56 Murray _ 11 Cedar 64 Belden ._ 11 O&amp;ucii* ... , n i ..i i 58 MtijTH^t IT - 1 0 31 Morning Star _ 10 4 Boone _._ 10 72 Loretto _ _ 10 62 69 %0 Gross _ _ 10 21 Naper 9 16 _ 9 22 1 0 36 _ 9 19 Amherst _ 11 11 Buda _ 9 41 Denman _ 1 1 54 Miller 1 1 12 Odessa _ 10 05 Pleasanton _ 10 60 Poole 10 15 Riverdale _ :.i._ 11 01 Watertown _ 10 13 _ 1 0 22 1 0 28 _ 1 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 33 County No. Dist. Name of School No. Grades Cedar _ 21 Obert 10 Chase _. Alpha 10 Chase _ 42 Lamar 10 Cherry 22 Brownlee 10 Cherry 30 Cody _ 10 Cherry 16 Crookston _ _ 10 Cherry 70 Merriman 10 Cherry 47 Nenzel _ 10 Cherry — 7 Wood Lake _ _ 11 Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Clay Clay Clay Clay Colfax Colfax Custer Custer Dakota Dawes Dawes Dawson Dawson Dawson Deuel Dixon Dixon Dixon Dodge Dodge Dodge Dodge Dodge Dodge Dundy Dundy Furnas Garden Garden 53 Lisco 11 Gage _ , 165 Barneston _ _ _ 12 Gage 155 Clatonia 10 10 Dalton 12 38 Gurley _ 10 9 Potter 12 12 Sunol _ 12 75 Deweese 10 49 Glenvil _ 10 73 Saronville 9 43 Verona ._ _ _ 10 12 Richland 9 56 Rogers _ _ 9 34 28 Berwyn _ 10 Comstock _ _ _. _ _ 11 3 1 0 39 Belmont _ _ 9 92 Marsland 10 76 17 Eddyville _ _ 11 North _ _ _ 10 35 Sumner _ _ _ _ 11 19 Big Springs _ _ _ _.. 12 17 _ i o 49 _ 1 o 46 Maskell 11 12 9 22 - 1 0 23 1 0 2 Ames 10 Nickerson _ _ 9 39 Snyder 10 27 Max 9 19 Parks _ 11 99 Hendley ._ 11 35 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 34 County No. Dist. Name of School No. Grades Gage 144 Pickrell 10 Gage _ 49 Rockford 10 Gage _ 161 Union Center 11 Gage 164 Virginia _...:.._ 12 Gosper _ _ 22 Smithfield _ _ 11 Grant _ _ 7 Ashby _ _ _ 10 Grant _ 5 ' Whitman _ _ _ 10 Hall _ 35 _ 9 Hall 12 Alda 10 Hall 34 Doniphan _ _ _ 10 Hall _ _ 25 Schnappsville 10 Hamilton _ 51 _ - - _ 9 Hamilton 74 .-. _ 10 Hamilton 61 Hordville _ _ _ 11 Hamilton _. 95 Phillips _ _ _ _ 11 Hamilton - 50 Stockton 11 Harlan 70 Huntley _ _ _ _ 10 Harlan 18 Mascot _ 10 Hitchcock _ _ 48 Beverly _ 10 Holt 228 Amelia _ _ _ _ _ 10 Holt 137 Chambers _ _ _ _ _ 12 Holt 30 Inman _ 12 Howard _ 14 Cotesfleld _ _ 10 Howard 4 Dannebrog _ 11 Howard _ 3 Elba ._ _ _ 1 1 Howard __ _ 67 Farwell _. _ _. _ 11 Jefferson 90 Daykin _ _ _ 11 Jefferson .~ 7 Endicott 11 Jefferson . 36 Helvey _ _ 9 Jefferson 97 Jansen _ 9 Johnson _ _. 10 _ 10 Johnson _ _ 1 Crab Orchard „ 11 Johnson _ _ 6 Vesta _. _ _ 10 Kearney 56 Hart well _ _ _. 12 Kearney*. Lowell _ 12 Kearney _ 64 Norman 9 Kearney _ 62 Wilcox _ „ 11 Keith 17 Brule 10 Keith * _ 12 Keystone _ _ 10 Keith _ _ _ 19 Vail 10 Kimball _ _ Dix _ _ _ _ 12 Knox _ 90 Verdel _ _ 10 Knox _ 117 Winnetoon 12 ' Lancaster „ „ 6 _ 1 0- Lancaster 22 „ 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 35 County No. Dist. Name of School No. Grades Lancaster 84 Cheneys 11 Lancaster 131 Davey _ _ 11 Lancaster 136 Denton 12 Lancaster _ 5 Emerald _ _ 10 Lancaster 42 Hallam _ 10 Lancaster 100 Malcolm 10 Lancaster 132 Panama 11 Lancaster 19 Raymond _ 11 Lancaster 95 Roca _ _ 9 Lincoln 65 Wallace 10 Lincoln 23 Wellfleet 9 Loup __ _ 5 Taylor _ _ 10 Merrick _ 18 _ 10 Merrick _ _ 31 _ 10 Merrick _ 50 ..10 Merrick , _ 15 Pleasant Hill 11 McPherson _ Tryon _ _ _ 11 Madison _ _ _ 83 11 Morrill _ 128 Broadwater 11 Nance '. 7 _ 1 0 Nance _ 16 : 10 Nemaha 39 Howe _ _ 10 Nemaha 82 Julian _ 12 Nemaha _ 36 Nemaha 10 Nuckolls _ 5 _ 9 Nuckolls _ 46 _ 9 Nuckolls 81 _ 9 Nuckolls _ 82 _ ; 9 Nuckolls „ _ 36 Bostwick _. _ _ 10 Nuckolls 45 Cadams _ _ 9 Nuckolls _ 77 Mt. Clare _ 10 Nuckolls 88 Nora _ __ 11 Nuckolls _ 1 Oak _ _ _ 10 Otoe _._ 101 Burr _ 11 Otoe 39 Lorton 9 Otoe 78 Otoe 12 Otoe 20 Unadilla 11 Pawnee _ 23 Armour 9 Pawnee '.. 54 Burchard 11 Pawnee 8 Du Bois 10 Pawnee _ 71 Steinauer _ 10 Perkins _ 1 Elsie 1 0 Perkins _ 12 Madrid 11 Perkins _ 65 Venango _ 10 Phelps _ 8 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 36 County County No. Dist, No. Dist, Name of School No. Grades Name of School No. Grades Phelps 74 Funk _ _ _ _ 10 Funk _ _ _ _ 10 Phelps _ 55 Phelps _ 55 Loom is 11 Loom is _ _ 11 Pierce 23 Pierce 23 _ 1 1 Pierce 3 0 Pierce - 30 Foster _ 10 Pierce 43 Pierce 43 McLean _ _ _ 11 Platte 9 Platte 9 _ 1 1 Platte _ 10 Platte _ 10 _ i o Platte 32 _ l o Platte _ 7 Platte _ 7 Duncan _ _ 10 Platte _ 29 Platte _ 29 Lindsay _ 10 Platte _ 40 Platte _ 40 Looking Glass 10 Platte 2 4 Platte Center _...?. 10 Redwillow _ Red willow Lebanon .„ _ 10 Red Willow _ 10 Red Willow _ _ 1 Red Willow _ _ 1 Richardson 19 Richardson 19 Barada 9 Salem _ 11 Richardson 59 Richardson 59 Saunders 48 Saunders 48 1 o Carey _ _ 10 Saunders _ 82 Saunders 82 Saunders 50 Saunders 50 Ithaca _ 1 0 Mai mo _ _ _ 10 Saunders 36 Saunders 36 Saunders 109 Saunders 109 Swedeburg 10 Saunders _ _ 20 Saunders _ _ 20 Vann 10 Saunders . — 9 Saunders 9 Yutan _ _ _ 12 Scotts Bluff 23 Scotts Bluff 23 _ io Scotts Bluff 47 Scotts Bluff 47 Henry _ _ _ _ 10 Scotts Bluff 36 Scotts Bluff 36 Lake Alice 12 McGrew _ ' 9 Scotts Bluff 18 Scotts Bluff 18 Scotts Bluff 30 Scotts Bluff 30 Melbeta _ _ _ 10 Scotts Bluff 42 Scotts Bluff 42 Sunflower _ _ 12 Seward 59 Seward 59 _ 1 o Seward __ :.__ 93 Bee 1 0 Seward 9 6 Seward _ 9 6 Cordova _ _ _ 11 Seward 82 Garland _ _ _ 10 Seward 27 Seward 27 Goehmer _ 10 Seward 2 1 Seward 2 1 Pleasant Dale _ 10 Seward 83 Seward 83 Staplehurst ' 10 Seward 99 Seward 99 Tamora _ _ 10 Sheridan _ 35 _ l o Sheridan 122 Sheridan 122 _ 9 Sheridan 96 Antioch _ _ _ 9 Antioch _ _ _ 9 Sheridan _. 3 Sheridan _. 3 Hay Springs _ 12 Hay Springs 12 Sherman 16 Sherman 16 Ashton _ 10 Ashton _ 10 Sherman _ 2 Sherman _ 2 Austin _ 11 Austin 11 Clear Creek _ _ _ _ *1 • Sherman _ 2 5 Sherman _ 25 Clear Creek „ _ _ _ 11 Sherman 32 Sherman 32 Hazard 10 Hazard 10 Foster _ 10 McLean _ _ _ 11 _ 1 1 _ i o _ l o Duncan _ _ 10 Lindsay _ 10 Looking Glass _ 10 Platte Center _..?. 10 Lebanon . ; . _ 10 Red Willow _ 10 Barada 9 Salem 11 1 o Carey _ _ 10 Ithaca _ 10 Malmo _ 10 Swedeburg 10 Vann _ 10 Yutan _ _ _ 12 1 o Henry _ _ _ _ 10 Lake Alice 12 McGrew _ ' 9 Melbeta _ _ _ 10 Sunflower _ _ 12 _ l o Bee 1 0 Cordova _ _ _ 11 Garland _ _ 10 Goehmer _ 10 Pleasant Dale _ 10 Staplehurst _ _ ' 10 Tamora _ _ 10 _ l o _ 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION County No. Disi . Name of School No. Grades Sherman 8 Hockville 11 Sherman 36 Wiggle Creek _ _ _ _ 10 Stanton _ _ 12 10 Thurston Thurston Thurston Thurston Valley Valley Valley Valley Valley Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Washington Wayne Wayne Webster Webster Webster _ 90 Eckley _ 10 Webster 60 Rosemont _ _ 11 Wheeler 33 Erickson _ 9 York 95 Henderson _ _ _ _ n York _ 94 Lushton _ 11 York 9 Thayer _ n SUMMARY OF APPROVED SCHOOLS 9 grade schools _ 36 1 0 Grade schools _ 135 11 Grade schools _ 62 1 2 Grade schools _ _ _ _ 2 3 Total _ _ 256 - - 1 0 9 _ g IB ■ - 9 22 - 9 6 Thuiston _ _ _ 11 3 - 1 0 6 9 10 1 0 36 1 0 63 Elyria io 39 Rose Hill _ _ io 6 Cuming io 5 Fontanelle io 36 Hill Creek 10 25 Irvington _ _ io 31 March _ _ _ io 41 Mattes _ io 29 23 McCarthy _ io New England io 13 Pleasant View _ io 37 Washington _ _ _ 10 9 Hoskins _ _ _ io 76 Sholes _ _ _ io 25 &gt; 1 0 47 _ io </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT COUNTY HIGH SCHOOLS County high schools shall be established in every county in which there is not located a twelve grade high school accredited to the state university. The governing board shall consist of five members called a board of regents. The board of regents has the usual powers that blong to a board of ducation. Name of School Address Secretary Arthur County High _ Arthur- _ _ _ Mrs. D. G. Williams Wheeler County High _ Bartlett _ _ Edith Bowler Rock County High _ _ Bassett Evelyn W. Towle Perkins County High _ .Grant Margaret M. Bailar Banner County High _ _Harrisburg_ _ _ Fred L. Johnson Sioux County High _ Harrison _ Vinnie N. Meyer Hayes County High _ _ Hayes Center Edgiththa Grant Chase County High _ Imperial _ _ : .rL Nellie E. Dick Kimball County High KimbalL _ Rachel McElroy Hooker County High _Mullen _ J. H. Garrett Keya Paha County High _Springview _ Abbie Pelletier Thomas County High Thedford Inez L. Oakes Deuel County High _ Chappell- Retta Brown Garden County High Oshkosh Esther M. Johnson McPherson County High _Tryon _ _ _ _ O. A. Johnson SPECIAL "RURAL HIGH SCHOOLS" u Two or more common school districts consolidating for high school purposes are designated by the School Laws as Rural High ochools. The governing body is composed of three trustees from among the electors of the high school district. They have the usual powers given to such boards. Name of School Address Principal Alpha Champion _ _ _ L. E. Stein Blackbird Lyons Dix _ - _Dix_ _ _ _ _ _ _George P." Young Lowell Lowell _ Martha Steenbock Minatare _ _ Minatare S. O. Enich Pioneer Union _ Bellevue _ _Chas. E. Saddie Stockville _.Stockville Pearle Elliott </seg>
            <seg id="p039">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 39 CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS .New Re&lt;listricting Lm The last legislature passed a law known as Senate File No. 261 which provides for the "districting of all the territory in the state lor high school and consolidated school purposes". It stipulates that the standard district shall contain twenty-five square miles. How - ever, it is permissable to establish districts larger or smaller than this when deemed for the best interest of all concerned. The law provides for a districting committee in each county consisting of the county superintendent and two persons appointed by the county board. It is made the duty of this committee to plat and establish the school house sites and boundary lines of the proposed consolidated districts within the county. When this work has been completed a date is set by the committee for a hearing at the county seat where any schocfl elector may file objections to the plan recommended, after which the committee may make any changes in its map deemed advisable. After this report and map have been filed with the county board twenty - five per. cent of the school electors of any proposed consolidated dis - trict may within forty days file a written protest or appeal with the state superintendent against the establishment of the boundary lines and sites as fixed by the county committee. Upon receipt of such pro - test or appeal the state superintendent is required to hold a hearing in the office of the county superintendent of the county wherein com - plaint has been made, giving ten days notice of the same to the objec - tors and to the members of the county committee whose work is : night to be effected. After holding such hearing and investigating the complaint made the state superintendent shall approve the boun - daries and sites as established by the county committee, or order a re-arrangement of the same. At any time after the completion of the districting and the lapsing of the forty day time limit, twenty-five per cent of the school electors of any proposed consolidated district not containing an organized high school district may petition the county superintendent for an election, which shall be called by the county superintendent by giving a twenty day notice. A majority vote of those voting is required for the propo - sition to carry. This election plan of consolidation applies only to proposed consolidated districts which do not contain an organized high school district. An organized high school district is one having more than one hundred fifty children on the school census. If the proposed district contains an existing organized high school district the petition plan of consolidation must be followed. This pro - vides that when fifty-one per cent of the school electors in a proposed consolidated district, residing outside of the existing organized high </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 40 school district, petition the county superintendent to be annexed to the existing organized high school district, he shall declare such ter - ritory to be annexed. From the foregoing it will be observed that the matter of con - solidation rests with the school electors, and it is necessary for them to take the initiative before anything can be done. This law does not force or compel consolidation; it merely establishes potential districts which will not become operative until the school electors of a pro - posed consolidated district decide, by the plan which applies to their proposed district, that they want consolidation. When I assumed the office last January as state superintendent I found a great deal of misunderstanding with reference to what this law actually provides. A circular letter was issued to all the redistricting committees of the state, setting forth the provisions of the law. This letter was given wide publicity and had the effect of bringing about a better under - standing and therefore a more favorable attitude toward the law. Up to date fify-six of the ninety-three counties have completed the work of districting and filed their maps with the county board. Hearings on appeals have been heard by this department in twenty-five coun - ties. An xcellent opportunity was afforded the state superintendent at these hearings to clarify a number of matters on which the people had been misinformed as to the real provisions of the law, or had an erroneous understanding of the intent and purpose of the law. From several counties no appeals have been received. This department is not advising consolidation unless it is thought that the conditions existing made it feasible and practicable. There are certain section of the state where the rough topography of the country, the poo conditions of the roads, and the siattered population, make it neces sary to continue the one room school for some time to come. In these sparsely settled sections with unimproved roads, where the on room school must be depended upon as a means of education, adequate equipment has not been provided and the length of term is far too short, mainly because of the lack of funds. This is a condition tha should be met by new legislation. "2&amp;9Fi Present School District Unit Too Small The questions that sometimes arises is, Why was it necessary to repeal the old law on consolidation and pass the redistricting act in its place? The members of the legislature realized that the rural schools have not been making the advancement that should have been made. Those who have been studying the rural school situation in Nebraska have come to the conclusion that one of the main reasons tne rural schools have not been keeping pace with the town and city </seg>
            <seg id="p041">r 1 o z o o z o r 5 &gt; c C/i C5 3 3 r &gt; z R p] Q O z </seg>
            <seg id="p042">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 41 schools is that the present rural school district unit is too small. That is, the one room rural school provides too small a group of chil - dren with which to work, making it necessary for one teacher to teach everything from the first to the eighth grade, and in some instances, as many as thirty to forty classes daily. Then again, in some of the smaller schools there are a number of one and two pupil classes. These conditions make it out of the question to do really efficient work, even though a well prepared and experienced teacher may be in charge. The purpose then of this law is to provide for larger dis - tricts so that children may be brought together in a larger group mak - ing it possible to grade and classify them in a manner that will make for efficient instruction and the keeping of children at home when they pursue their high school course. Then too, the high school program of study may be made to articulate with the life of the community. Defects of Old Consolidation Law There were several outstanding defects of the old law on consoli - dation. One was that it required a majority vote in each district affected to consolidate, and provided no uniform plan as to the amount of territory that might be taken in each consolidation. That is, it did not provide an equitable distribution of the territory. Where a majority vote was required in each primary district affected this made it possible for one district, if it happened to be centrally located, to prevent several surrounding districts from consolidating even though these surrounding districts might be unanimously in favor of consoli - dation. This was a case of a minority ruling the majority which, of course, retarded consolidation. Then too, as mentioned above, there was no proper division of the territory, making it possible for districts to reach out and take in territory not properly belonging to them, to the disadvantage of other districts that might wish to consolidate later. Had we continued to consolidate under the old law, where con - solidations were made on a sort of hit-and-miss plan, in several years to come we would have had strips of territory lying between organized consolidated districts. These strips would, of course, be too small to form a consolidated district and too far away to be annexed to an ad - joining consolidated district* The people residing on such strips would be in no man's land, as it were, so far as having good school facilities. The redistricting law makes provision for the proper di - vision of terrtory in the very begnning so that in the future when we have complete consolidation no one will be left on the outside, and consolidated districts will be of the proper size and valuation to main - tain a good school. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Standardized One Room Itural Schools We are urging one room rural schools to meet the requirements for standardization if it is at all possible for them to do so. These requirements are in regard to the building, the equipment, and quali - fications of the teacher. In some states slate aid is given one room rural schools that become standardized, and Nebraska some day may see the wisdom of doing this where consolidation is not feasible. Tht one room rural school, however, can never be made as efficient as the town, city or consolidated school, and does not meet the demands of modern rural society. There are too many recitations, no specialized work, too wide a range of work for one teacher to handle successfully, too few, pupils in each class, and insufficient time for the study of pupils that the work may be adapted to individual needs. Proper in - struction cannot be given in subjects relating to the two principal vo - cations of rural communities — agriculture and home making — and in such cultural subjects as literature, music, drawing and art. The de - mand for a high school education cannot be met in the one room sys - tem. The better class of teachers seek employment in those systems that provide the facilities necessary to give the child opportunity for proper development, and where they can employ means and methods in accordance with modern educational ideas. The country boy and girl have been faced toward the town and city with their attractions and allurements because the one room rural school has failed to reveal to them the possibilities of rural Jife. Consolidation of schools, we be - lieve, will provide the necessary remedy. Advantages of Consolidated Schools When the school population, conditions of the roads and !i&gt; - pography of the country, permit, schools should be consolidated d^ - cause of the many advantages of the larger school over the one room school. The larger group of children makes it possible to grade and classify pupils in a manner that makes for efficient instruction. It also makes it possible to have a high school within easy reach of every boy and girl, so that when they finish the eighth grade they may con - tinue their high school work and remain at home. Then too, instruc - tion in the special subjects such as agriculture, home economics, manual training, physical training, music, drawing and art is possible. In early times a high school education was not so essential to the success - ful transaction of the ordinary affairs of rural life as it is at the pres - ent time. Now it is absolutely necessary that each and every boy and girl obtain a high school education; otherwise, there will be two classes, those who are well prepared by the training of high school ed - ucation, and those who have failed to obtain adequate training. Some of the advantages of consolidation are summarized as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 43 Kcuuces tardiness. Better equipment. Eliminates truancy. Secures larger schools. Teachers retained longer. Attendance more regular. Secures graded conditions. More time for recitations. Insures closer supervision. ■ Better class of work is done. Keeps the boys on the farm. Petty jealousies interfere less. Better management is secured. Better returns for money spent. Special teachers may be employed.- Classes larger and more interesting. Buildings better heated and ventilated. Number of classes of teacher decreased. Keeps older boys and girls longer in school. Gives a school of more character and dignity. School becomes social center in the community. Better and more experienced teachers employed. Makes the farm the ideal place to bring up children. Popular with people, teachers and pupils where tried. Healthy rivalry awakened by inspiration of numbers. Course of study enlarged and enriched by special subjects. Morals of pupils protected going from and coming to schools. Health of pupils better preserved on account of transportation. It unites and centers the interests of a large section of people. It adds tone and dignity to education and to the farm community. It saves cost of sending children away to school and in moving to town to educate. School games are made possible on account of larger numbers, thus adding to the attractiveness of the school. It is the only method where it is possible to make a division of la - bor by graded classes, whereby teachers may have sufficient time to do good work and choose grades or special subjects for which they are best fitted. CONSOLIDATIONS IN NEBRASKA Perhaps no subject affecting the schools is so often discussed as that of consolidation. It has been twenty-two years since the first consolidated school was established in Nebraska. The growth since </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT then has been very slow and up to the passage of the present law there have been sixty-six consolidated schools established. During the lasi year under the new law thirty-four have been added to the list. Of the sixty-six consolidations under the old law twenty-one are in the epen country. Of the thirty-four established under the new law fifteen are open country consolidations. It was believed that the new law would bring about the consolidation of the open country more rapid - ly. The results so far, however, show slight increase in the open country The results so far, however, show slight increase in the open country consolidations. This fact seems to indicate that consolidations are affected about natural community centers. The small town will more often form such a center. The towns are already the center for the business, religious, and social life of the communities and to bring the school into this larger community is an easy step. Another point that is interesting is the method of establishment. Of the thirty-one new consolidations nine are by petition, all of them being around a town. The remaining twenty-two consolidations were formed by the vote of all the electors within the limits of the proposed districts, eight of these being around a town. Many people believed that the smaller t6wns would force consolidation because of their concentrated populations. This belief seems to be unfounded, how - ever, because fewer have been formed around the town, except by peti - tion, than in the open country. This shows that consolidation is as popular in rural communities as in villages. When we take into con - sideration the fact that by the petition plan only the rural people have a chance to vote we are forced to the conclusion that they are more interested in the consolidation of schools. Garage and Cottage, Sunflower Consolidated School. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 45 One-room school to be abandoned because of consolidation. The old type, incorrect heating, incorrect lighting, no ventilation. Auto Truck used for traiis]M&gt;Hatioii of pupils in a consolidated school. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 46 LIST OF CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS No. of Assessed i No. ot County Name of School Districts | ' Valuation Grades Antelope _ *Neligh _ 144 $ 750,000 12 Antelope _ Royal 113 _. 11 Banner t * 50 50,000 Banner t*Flowerfleld 58 69,000 Banner __t*McKinnon 61 60,000 Boyd _ * Pleasant View. 62 48,536 8 Brown _ Johnstown 9 139,649 Buffalo _. Watertown 101 92,116 10 Buffalo _ Denman 41 56,867 11 Pleasanton _. _ 30,000 Buffalo t*St. Michael.. 1 120,783 Cass _ Alvo 102 338,868 12 Cass _ Nehawka 103 316,986 12 Cass- Eagle 104 471,522 12 Cass *Murdock C-7 434,670 11 Cass- t * Wabash, C-15 254,335 Cedar Obert 21 129,992 10 Chase Enders _ _.. 41 43,765 11 Chase_ fLamar _ _ 42 29,049 12 Cheyenne Sunol 12 229,559 11 Cheyenne.._ _ Gurley 138 146,909 10 Clay — Trumbull 101 269,271 12 Custer. _. t * Climax C-19 75,000 Custer- t * Gates C-23 80,000 C uster t * M il bu rn C-12 105,000 Dixon Allen 70 I 323,600 12 Dixon _ __ Waterbury _.. 1 300,000 12 Dundy — Parks 19 172,470 I 11 Fillmore Milligan 1 250,000 12 Frontier _ tOraflno 28 81,560 11 Gage tUnion Center..... . 161 I 159,750 I 10 Gage Riverview 162 464,930 12 Gage Otoe 165 400,000 12 Gage Virginia _ _ 164 I 318,140 I 12 Gage- Filley 166 392,100 12 Gage Pickrell. „ 144 135,435 I 10 Gage Rockford 49 166,309 10 Garden Goodview ! Greeley Fish Creek _ Greeley Scotia _ Hamilton Phillips. 95 I 374,665 I 11 Hamilton Marquette 46 163,690 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 47 LIST OP CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS— Continued No. of Assessed i No. of County Name of School Districts Valuation Grades Harlan _ Mascot _... 18 155,850 10 Harla n * Ragan 9. 260,000 12 Howard *Elba _ _ 103 400,000 12 Howard *Cushing 103 200,000 Lancaster „ Waverly 145 734,018 12 Lancaster _ Walton 146 442,957 12 Knox t* _ 1 250,000 172,000 324,000 Knox * Center 2 4 Knox *\Vinnetoon _ 38 Knox .". * Santee 5 50,000 55,000 60,000 Knox _ t * 5 0 Knox _t* 5 Kearney Logan _ 243,310 8 Kearney * Wilcox:. _ 12 Logan Stapleton 31 108,457 12 Madison. tLiberty.. _ 83 214,443 10 Madison tCentral 84 141,19-9 10 Nemaha Julian 82 147,605 12 Nemaha "Brock 14 600,000 12 Nuckolls _ St. Stephens _ 5 150,374 8 Nuckolls Nora _ 8 3 153,066 11 Otoe _ t 1 0 120,000 Pawnee _ Lewiston 69 268,370 12 Perkins Madrid 152,000 12 Perkins Venango 147,700 11 Polk f Heitzman 2 8 103,254 10 Red Willow *Danbury _ 224,905 10 Red Willow. f Red Willow 1 235,045 10 Richardson fBratton Union.. 47 239,760 12 Richardson * Preston 6 289,000 Richardson *Dawson 15 500,000 12 Richardson _t* 1 4 350,000 Sarpy Gretna _ _ 37 203,385 12 262,241 12 Sarpy _ Springfield :..... 32 Sarpy Papillion..... 27 362,607 12 Saunders Mead _ 564,000 12 Saunders f Wan-n 2 0 196,000 10 Saunders f 22 199,181 11 Scotts Bluff * 70 Scotts Bluff tHope 33 54,704 161,164 9 12 Scotts Bluff jLake Aloce 65 Scotts Bluff *McGrew 83 133,448 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT LIST OP CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS— Continued No. of I Assessed I No. of County Name of School Districts Valuation | (Trades Scotts Bluff fSunflower 68 242,091 12 Scotts Bluff *Scottsbluff 1,941,763 12 Scotts Bluff t* Victory Hill 67 195,763 10 Seward Cordova 96 236,955 11 Seward t 97 248,128 I 9 Seward Tamora 99 184,028 10 Sheridan t Banner 35 I 82,190 9 Sheridan Clinton 26 90,643 10 Sherman _ f *Bloody Run _ 350,000 Thayer Bruning _ Wayne Sholes _ ' 76 206,653 10 Webster tGarfield _ 85 76,125 10 Webster tEckley 90 200,000 12 Webster *Inavale R 381,162 11 Webster *Cowles _ K 280,155 12 York *Benedict _ 722,000 11 ♦Consolidated under the new law, tOpen Country consolidations. THE RURAL SCHOOL LIBRARY A very important feature of the rural school equipment is the school library. The habit of reading good books is most excellent. The school can do nothing that will contribute more to the culture of the child than to supply him with the best out of the vast store of the literature of the past and present. The purchase of a few good books should always be a part of the school budget. In addition to the books, the reading table of every country school should be supplied with a few good magazines furnished at public expense. The Law. "6795 Sec. 96. School District Library — The school board or school trustees of every school district within this state may at its discretion set aside annually from the general funds collected for the use of the district the sum of ten cents per pupil as shown by the total number of pupils within the school dis- trict at the last annual school census. The amount so set aside shall </seg>
            <seg id="p050">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 49 be known as the district library fund, and shall be by the school board or school trustees of such district annually invested in books so pro - vided and shall be suitable for the public school library." "6796 Sec. 97. Same — care — rules. — The school boards or school trustees shall provide for the care of such library at the schoolhouse and shall prescribe the rules and regu - lations under which it shall be used by the district." A more effective library law is needed in Nebraska, one that will produce results. As it is the purchase of books is discretionary with the board. During the last few years very few books have been bought by a fund provided by the law. The law should be changed so as to make the purchase of library books obligatory upon the board, except in districts where a public library is maintained at public ex - pense. The Library Survey. On September 15, 1920, the following questionnaire was sent out to the county superintendents: 1. What per cent of your schools have libraries? 2. What is the average value of the libraries? 3. Did the school boards buy the books or did the schools earn the money for them? 4. Are the books mainly reference books (dictionaries, enclyclo - pedias, helps on geography, history, and literature, etc.) or are they mainly fiction? 5. Are the books usually well cared for? What in your opinion is the greatest need of the rural school library? Seventy-nine of the county superintendents responded, many of them promptly, and accompanied their reports with helpful sugges - tions. From these reports the following significant facts have been gathered : Sixty-three and one-fifth per cent of the schools have libraries. The average value of these is $37.67. Forty-eight counties reported that the money obtained for the purchase of the books was usually earned by the schools. Fourteen counties reported that the district boards usually purchased the books with public funds. In thirteen counties both means were used in se - curing the books. Thirty-seven counties have libraries composed largely of fiction. In nineteen of the counties reference works predominate. In twenty - two counties the books are divided about equally between reference and fiction. According to the reports the books of thirty-seven counties were kept in good condition. In twenty-five counties the books are fairly </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT B taken care of. Fourteen counties reported that the books were oor condition. ■ All the schools in ten counties have libraries. In eleven counties than twenty per cent of the schools have libraries. tYou will notice by this report that little more than one-half of schools have libraries. You will notice too that the value of these iries is all too small for the needs of the schools. The fact that iw boards are spending public funds for library books is especially iflcant because it shows a decided lack of appreciation of the value he school library and an indifference in complying with at least spirit of the law. A Place for the Books If possible a separate room should be given for the library. This room need not be large; a room ten or twelve feet by eight is large enough. This room should contain shelving for books, a few chairs, and a small reading table. It might also be used as a teacher's In some schools a small alcove may be used for the library. This should contain a few chairs and a table, and a book case with lock and key. In most schools perhaps no special place can be de - voted to this purpose. Then a corner of the room may be fitted with book case and table. It is of the utmost importance that books should be well cared for. The Selection of Books. I From the survey made it is evident that there is not sufficient i in the selection of books. In some cases made-to-order libraries e purchased. These books are made to sell, not to serve the needs the schools. There should be more books for younger children, lack of up-to-date reference books is also evident. These are ded especially to aid in the regular work of the school. These uld be provided before the library is stocked with fiction. There should also be books to suit community needs. The school library should be made to serve the grown people of the district as well as those still in school. The libraries should contain magazines and current literature, current event papers, farm journals, govern - ment bulletins, and books dealing with rural interests. Many valu - able reports issued by the government and the Nebraska State Uni - versity are available and should be placed in the rural library. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Survey on Libraries County County Supt. 1 ] 2 | 3 4 | 5 Adams _ _.Mary Dungan __ 851 5 X Fiction I G Antelope, C. A. Mohrman 51 50 Both Fiction I P Arthur _ _..Mrs. D. G. Williams...... 21 15 Both Both G Banner Fred L. Johnson 25 15 School Both G Blaine A. L. Shamblin _ _| _l Boone Bertha M. Scheckler 801 85 School Both F Box Butte _...Opal Russell 501 25 School Both I G Boyd Nellie May Edwards 99| 20 Both Both F Brown _. _..Mrs. Lenna Morris _ 15| 10 Board Fiction G B u ff alo _Katheryn Lau ghl i n. Burt W. T. Poucher _ 901100 School Fiction P Butler _Oma L. Cady 1001 12 School Both G Cass _ Alpha Peterson _ 80 70 School Both G Cedar _ Emma Schwerin _ GO 50 School Reference F Chase Nellie E. Dick _ 501 40 School Reference P Cherry. _ Edith Adamson 501 25 Fiction School P Cheyenne Anna McFadden _ 80 50 School Reference F Clay -L. J. Gilkeson _.100 50 Fiction School G Coif ax. F. J. Vogltance 95 j X| Both Both G Cuming, Emma R. Miller _ 851 50 Reference G Both Custer T. C. Grimes.. Dakota W. E. Voss _ 1001 251 Board Reference G Dawes Edna Rincker _ 201 25 School Reference P Dawson W. C, Bloom _ 75 25 Board Fiction F Deuel Retta F. Brown. Dixon W. F. Richardson. _ 951 40 Both Both G Dodge _.J. E. Marsh _ _ _ 95 75 School Fiction G Douglas Mrs. Mabel Johnson. ..100 4 0 School Both G Dundy.. _ Una Richards Fillmore Margaret Haughawout 90 7 5 School Fiction F Franklin _ Pearl O'Neal Both 5 0 25 School P Frontier _ Goldie P. Stark.. 10 60 School Reference F Furnas G. W. Fletcher. 75 50 School Fiction F Gage _ _ Bertha Foster. 7 5 40 School Fiction F Garden Esther Johnson.. 2 0 5 School Reference G Garfield J. L. Jenkins.. 2 5 10 School Reference F Gosper _ _.F. W. Montgomery... 80 2 5 Fiction P Board Grant Winnifred D. Moran.. 10 300 Board Reference G Greeley Margaret L. Tracy.. Hall Mrs. Ella M. Kern Hamilton Arthur S. Nelson 90| 35 School Fiction G Harlan Frances E. White.. 100J 50 Board Fiction G Hayes Edgiththa Grant.. ._ 15j 25 School Fiction p Hitchcock Evelyn Besack. ._ 25j 15 School Fiction F 60| 10 Y? n*i rfi Fiction I F </seg>
            <seg id="p053">4 li Sooker J. H. Garrett | oward W. G. Baker 50 37 Both Both Jefferson Eva B. Shuman 70 50 Both Fiction Johnson _ Helen Wright _ 98 25 School Fiction Kearney Minnie Norlin _ _ _ Keith Katherine Feather _ 6 30 School Fiction Keya Paha Abbie Pelletier 5| 10 School Both Kimball Rachel McElroy 10| 30 School Reference Knox- Allen S. Stinson _ 75 j 20 School Both Lancaster- _...Jeanette C. Nelson 100| 30 Board Fiction Lincoln Mrs. A. G. Cochran 20| 35 School Reference Logan A. C. Loshbaugh -j - Loup Mrs. Marcia Smith 1 35 School Reference Madison N. A. Housel 96| 15 School Reference McPherson O. A. Johnson.._ _ _ 50| 25 Board Reference Merrick Margaret McCutchen 100)100 School Fiction Morrill _. _E. F. Kelley _- _] _ Nance Chloe C. Baldridge 95| 20 Both Both Nemaha _ Bess E. Anderson 4 0j 50 School Reference Nuckolls Mildred Mauck 50| 15 Boaid Fiction Otoe Charles Speedie _ -j _ Pawnee Mrs. Bertha Kuhlmann 9 5 1 45 School Fiction Perkins Mrs. Margaret Bailar._ 34 j 1 0 j School Fiction Phelps_ Alice A. Swanson _ — J - Pierce Marjorie Parminter. _ 75 j 40 X Fiction Platte Fred S. Lecron. 100| 20 Board Fiction Polk Amelia Rasmussen _ 75| 75 Both Both Red Willow Julia C. Barnes 95| 25 Both Fiction Richardson D. H. Weber 80| 50 School Reference Rock E. W. Towle (Mrs.) 75 15 Board Reference Saline _. L. J. Bouchal „. 65 7 Board Both Sarpy Bertha Bishop 100 50 School Fiction Saunders _ E. A. Odman 100 85 Board Fiction Scotts Bluff Ada M. Haldeman _ 50 50 School Both Seward J. C. Greenwood _ 75 50 School Reference Sheridan Mrs. Pearle Summers 40 25 School Fiction Sherman. L. H. Currier 90 15 Board Fiction Sioux_ Mrs. Vinnie Meyer _ 50| 12 School Fiction Stanton S. E. Eddy 90| X School Fiction Thayer H. E. Barbee, 65| 45 Both Both Thomas Inez L. Oakes _| _ _ _ Thurston Ellen M. Brown... 50| 10 School Both Valley Lelia Moorman _ 70| 20 School Fiction Washington Mabel J. Marsh 95| 18 School Fiction Wayne Pearl Sewell 90[ 50 Both Both Webster Estelle Ducker 100| 55 School Fiction Wheeler. __Edith Bowler 5| 50 School Both ,V Vnrlr Tftlfor C. Lord I G P F F G P G G G G F F G F G G P G F F I P I F G F G G F </seg>
            <seg id="p054">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 51 The books for young children should be clean, wholesome — the kind that will give children a taste for good books. The books should be easy, the only kind that will create the library habit. In order to secure a wider use of the school library it must contain books that will be read. Traveling libraries secured from the Nebraska Public Library Commission are available and should be secured to supplement the small school library. Many of the rural libraries were started under the ten-cent law. This law should be revived and in addition a provision should be made - governing the selection of books. Every school should have a recom - mended list of books from which selections may be made when addi - tions to the library are contemplated. Suggestions. What is needed most is a teacher who understands and appreci - ates good books. Normal training classes in high schools should be trained to care for libraries and encourage their use. There should be systematic direction of pupils' reading. A better system for filing and loaning books should be put into operation. The giving of read - ing certificates would be a great help in encouraging reading among children, in directing them in the selection of books, and in teaching them how to use references. A list of all books, bulletins, and magazines should be kept by the teacher. The books and pamphlets should be dated and stamped with the price. The school board should adopt a few workable rules regulating the us^of the library. Use of the Library Every child should be taught the physical makeup of The booje and should know the use of title pages, preface, contents and indfex. Directions for the use of the dictionary should be given. Aside from the required supplementary reading, each child should become in - terested in general reading. The teacher must know the books be - fore she can arouse interest in the library. Encourage the children to keep a personal record of the books read during the year, supervise the selection, and set aside a library hour for book reports. These reports will serve to increase the pleasure in reading, and will teach the children how to read intelligently. The giving of library reading certificates will be an incentive. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">52 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ACCREDITED SCHOOLS {The University of Nebraska maintains two lists of accredited iols, a four-year list and a junior list. The graduates of the four - • list are admitted to the university (and to nearly all of the col - s and universities of the United States) without entrance exami - ons in subjects that are properly certified as completed within e schools. Unless a graduate of an accredited school, a candidate admission must be prepared to take examination in those subjects rhich he desires entrance credits. "Accredited" schools are such as, under annual inspection by the university inspestor of accredited schools, are found to have a'well - balanced program of studies, satisfactory laboratory equipment and library facilities, and a teaching force adequate in number and com - petent in scholarship and professional training to accomplish the work iney are undertaking. This list of accredited schools is published yearly in the University Calendar, the University Journal, and the High School Manual. Any public or private high school or academy desiring to be placed on the accredited list should make request to the inspector of accredited schools. The High School Manual, giving de - tailed information in regard to accredited schools, including genera' and departmental suggestions as to courses of study and methods of instruction, and the list of accredited schools, is sent upon application to the registrar of the University of Nebraska. I Certificates of graduation from schools which are members of North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools and iccrediting Associations of equal rank will entitle the holder to ission without examination. An "Approved" high school is a high school which has had its work, equipment and condition inspected by the State Superintenden of Public Instruction and the high school is given a rank which en ables it to receive pupils from districts other than its own, and to collect therefor free high school tuition for instruction of such pupils The free high school tuition, in such cases, is paid by the school dis trict from which the pupils are sent. 1. The University of Nebraska accredits, 2. The State Superintendent approves. STANDARD OF ACCREDITED SCHOOLS - Every business and all institutions of whatever kind require a unit of measure and a goal to be reached if they are to be successful in their undertakings. If a goal is to be reached we must go toward </seg>
            <seg id="p056">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 53 it and if we work intelligently we must measure our rate of progress, as well as keep in the right direction. This explains the need foi standards no matter in what we may be engaged. All experience tends to prove that this is as true of the teacher and the school as of anything else. Not only are these things true, but we are constantly erecting guide-boards using various standards. This gives the reason for introducing "Standards of Accredited Schools" into the report. They are as follows: 1. Not less than thirty units required for graduation. 2. The minimum academic and professional preparation of teachers equivalent to four years and that of grade»teachers equivalent to two years beyond a four-year course. In determining this equiva - lence, two years of successful experience to be considered quivalent to one year of higher preparation. 3. Not to exceed six daily recitations for each teacher 4. Laboratory and library facilities adequate to the needs ot instruction in the subjects taught. 5. The location and construction of the buildings, the lighting, heating, and ventilation of the rooms, the nature of the laboratories, corridors, closets, water supply, school furniture, apparatus and pupils and teachers. methods of cleaning such as to insure hygienic conditions for both 6. Efficiency of instruction, acquired habits of thought and study, general intellectual and moral tone of the school evidenced by inspection. 7. At least three instructors giving entire time to secondary subjects. SOME ADVANTAGES OF ACCKEDITMEXT Admission without examination to the University of Nebraska and nearly every college in the United States. Guidance in framing and steadying the program of studies and such groups as may be advisable. Expert assistance in selecting apparatus, texts and reference books. Annual inspection of school and, when desired, a confidential re - port to the school board. Public recognition of the excellence of the school by publication of the list each year in the University of Nebraska Calendar and in the University Journal. Eligibility for recognition by the State Department of Public In - struction as Normal Training high schools. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">54 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ACCREDITED SCHOOLS 1919-1920. Group A, 135 Four-Year Schools IThis group consists of sehools that are accredited to the North ral Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, and such other ols as meet the above standards: Group B, 162 Four- Year Schools » Schools fully accredited but not meeting fully the standards tioned above as. to the preparation of the teaching staff or labora - and library facilities. Group C, 82 Four- Year Schools The graduates of this group may receive 28 points on credentials from their schools, giving them conditional admission to college or university. Additional credits may be secured by examination or by completing satisfactorily 30 hours of work of college grade. 23 Junior Accredited Schools I The graduates of these schools may receive conditional admis - to the university upon the completion of sufficient additional in an accredited school to secure the minimum of 28 points. INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION I One of the unique things- — not to say glories — of the American - :e is that it makes provision for the education of all the children all the people. The kindergarten in some form and with many ying degrees of equipment and excellence is found in nearly all ts. Because of this condition the children as they arrive at the of school training and guidance have provided for them an open ir. Then comes the greater opportunity. This grade of instruc - i is followed by provision and many incentives to complete the tit grades. These steps of advancement and rounds of the educa - lal ladder bring them to the richer and more advanced courses study of the high school. Because of the place and value of the growth and development of American citizens the high school notwithstanding all it does for the youth of the people is not made the stopping place in formal in- </seg>
            <seg id="p058">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 55 struction and in the personal influence, guidance, and over-sight of teachers of culture, experience, and scholarship. The enriched life and example and trained minds and regulated hearts are selected by the state as guides and examples and to multi - ply the opportunities for instruction and for educational accomplish - ment. Hence : THE STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS While no institution is even ideally perfect, much less in its prac - tical, every-day life and concrete tests and activities, the people of Nebraska have a right to be proud of their State Normal Schools. If time and space would permit a full consideration of the things which make them of real worth and genuine appreciation to the peo - ple of the state it could be presented under four headings: (1) The steadfastness with which they adhere to the purpose for which they were founded and for which they are maintained; (2) The efforts they put forth to render themselves worthy and to insure a good account of their stewardship; (3) The constant efforts they make to be of genuine service to all parts of the state and to all classes of teachers in all grades and in all kinds of schools; (4) To be models to the teachers who go out from them in methods of work, in principles of education, in ideal goals to be reached in the lives of pupils and teachers and in the devotion and preparation of American teachers for. American schools. That these ends may be reached and their purposes fulfilled more certainly year by year the grounds are beautified, new equipment takes the place of the old, the libraries are enlarged and the teaching staff is increased. Thus the money invested in grounds and buildings, and the money and efforts spent to maintain the four schools yield a large rate of interest in intelligent teaching and management of the schools of the state and these, in turn, make a large contribution to the in - telligent, peace-loving and law-abiding citizenship of Nebraska. COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES Nebraska has provided not only the elementary school, the high school, and the normal school, but also, the state has gone a step far </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 56 beyond these ever necessary and highly important institutions. The state in its capacity as a corporate body and the people as individuals and in groups have assured the growth and development of the three classes of institutions already mentioned by the establishment of higher education. The state maintains the university, agricultural schools and experimental stations and the people as individuals and church organizations conduct colleges. This is in recognition of the fact that the university and the col - leges are maintained to accomplish two ends or purposes: (1) For that which each may do by itself and in behalf of its own selected goals; and (2) For the influence it may exert on the schools already n 'i mpH I The underlying principle involved especially in that which is sred by No. 2 may be stated both in a negative and in a positive u. From the negative side it is this: The lower does not push If up and send the higher on out of its way and by that means ire progress. From the positive side it may be stated thus: The 4er reaches down and lays hold of the lower and draws it up toward If. The primary grade, for example, in any school system, no mat - how good, has no appreciable influence on the high school which bove it. On the other hand the high school is constantly exerting influence according to its life, order, spirit, and character on the des below. 1 Because of this principle of institutional life and action the uni - ty and colleges are most potent factors in social changes and -ess and in promoting human welfare. (The normal school devotes itself for the most part to one kind istruction, education and training — that is to the vocation of the her and to the teaching profession. The university covers not the education for the teaching profession (in not quite the same and extent) but goes out in all vocational directions and seeks repare one class of young men and women for one thing and other jes for other forms of life activities. And thus the university in xtended and all-round life and efforts seeks that which seems best most desirable in the unlimited intellectual, industrial, economic, social fields. K While the colleges are more restricted in the scope, variety, and ngth of their activities they are most worthy sources of good itains of blessing, directors of thought, guides of youth, and ngs of inspiration. Whilp flip nprmlp nf Nphn«slca Vnv#&gt; nlwivs h ■ 1 fin tn fool a </seg>
            <seg id="p060">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 57 commendable pride in their Institutions of Higher Education it may be truthfully said that no biennial period in the history of the state has marked greater growth and excellence in her colleges and uni - versities than the one covered by the years 1919 and 1920. Enroll - ments have been increased; buildings have been erected; sources of knowledge have grown "from more to more"; and worthy, loyal, and patriotic American citizenship has been emphasized. The present vision, strength, and condition of these institutions speak well and promise much for the future. ■ STATE CERTIFICATES By Lulu S. Wolford, Assistant Superintendent. Nebraska's New Certification Law, passed by the Legislature of 1918, became effective July 19, 1919, making all teachers' certificates in Nebraska statutory certificates. All teachers are required by entitle them to teach in the public chial schools of this state. law to be properly certificated to private, denominational and paro- State Certificates are of two and General State Certificates. kinds, viz: City-State Certificates, APPLICATIONS — The law provides that city state certificates shall be granted upon formal application properly certified, showing character and amount of academic and professional preparation of the applicant, experience in teaching, the kind of certificate held and the kind of certificate desired. Each application thus provides a record of the candidate's educa - tional qualifications and experience. It also shows the class and grade of certificate issued, with date of issue and expiration. All applica - tions are filed alphabetically in the state superintendent's office, thus providing a complete record of each teacher receiving a city state certificate. City-State Certificates are valid in all districts of the state or - ganized under Article XXII and in districts organized under Article VI, when registered with the county superintendent without fee, and may be valid in metropolitan cities. FEES — Each application must be accompanied by a fee of $1.00. City State Certificatips </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 58 CLASSES — All City-State certificates are issued by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction, and are classified as follows: 1. Grade and Professional Grade. 2. High School and Professional High School. 3. Superintendent's and Professional Superintendent's. 4. Special and Professional Special. REQUIREMENTS FOR GRADE CITY-STATE CERTIFICATE — 1. Valid from Kindergarten to eighth grade inclusive. 2. Duration three years. 3. Applicant must be of approved character. 4. Scholastic requirements. 1. Applicant must be a graduate of an approved four year High School; must have earned a first grade county certificate;* and must present credits from the University, a standard college, a state normal school, or approved normal school in this or an - other state for 12 college hours work, 4 of which must be pro - fessional. 2. Application must be certified to by county or city super- intendent who has knowledge of facts stated therein. Grade City-State Certificate shall be convertible into a profes - sional Grade City-State Certificate, valid for life on the following con - ditions: 1. Applicant must show satisfactory completion of one year of normal school work or college work. 2. Applicant must give evidence of three years or aggregate of 24 months successful teaching experience. 3. To keep this certificate alive, holder must not allow three consecutive years to elapse without teaching. REQUIREMENTS FOR HIGH SCHOOL CITY-STATE CERTIFICATE — 1. Duration three years. 2. Applicant must be of approved character. 3. Scholastic requirements. 1. Applicants must secure a first grade county certificate; must pass state examination earning a minimum grade of &amp;0% in </seg>
            <seg id="p062">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 59 psychology, zoology, geology, English literature, rhetoric, general science, chemistry, trigonometry, physics and general history; and must present credits from the University, a standard college, a state normal school or an approved normal school in this or an - other state for 12 college hours in education. 4. This certificate may be issued also to a person of approved character who is a graduate of a higher course of a state normal school or other approved normal school in this or another state, when the course is comparable in all respects to the advanced course of the state normal schools of this state or the course prescribed by the Stale University for the training of teachers. This certificate may be convertible into a Professional High- School City-State Certificate, valid for life in the same manner as pro - vided for the convertibility into a professional certificate of a Grade City-State Certificate. * Certificate of equal or superior rank accepted in lieu of county first grade certificate. REQUIREMENTS FOR SUPERINTENDENT'S CITY-STATE CERTIFICATE — 1. Aplicant must be of approved character. 2. Scholastic requirements. 1. Applicant must hold a Professional High-School City- State Certificate, and must have at least one year experience ns principal of approved high school. This certificate shall be convertible into a Professional Superin - tendent's City-State Certificate valid for life in the manner provided for the convertibility into a Professional Grade City-State Certificate of the Grade City-State Certificate. REQUIREMENTS FOR SPECIAL CITY-STATE CERTIFICATE 1. Duration three years. Applicant must be of approved character. 3. Scholastic requirements 1. Applicant must have had at least one year of special work in an approved conservatory, training, vocational or industrial school, organized and equipped for the training of special teachers. 4. It shall be issued also under the following conditions: To a person of approved character who has had one year of practical experience as a competent mechanic in the craft or </seg>
            <seg id="p063">60 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT trade for the teaching of which the special certificate is issued. kThis certificate shall be convertible into a Professional Special -State Certificate valid for life in the manner provided for the con - ibility into a Professional Grade City-State Certificate of a Grade -State Certificate. GENERAL STATE CERTIFICATES General State Certificates shall consist of the following classes: 1. Professional State Certificates. 2. Elementary or Second Grade State Certificates. 3. First Grade State Certificates. 4. Emergency for City-State Certificates. REQUIREMENTS FOR PROFESSIONAL STATE CERTIFICATE 1. Issued by the State Superintendent. 2. Shall be valid for life unless allowed to lapse by reason of failure to teach for a period of three years. 3. Valid in all districts of the state organized under Articles 4. Applicant must be a person of approved character. 5. Scholastic requirements. 1. Applicant must have three years teaching experience; must secure a first grade county certificate, and in addition must pass state examination receiving a grade of not less than 80% in each of the following subjects: psychology, zoology, geology, English literature, rhetoric, general science, chemistry, trigo - nometry, physics and general history. or 0 2. Applicant must be a graduate of a standard college or university in this or another state, and must have had three years of successful experience as a teacher in the public, private, de - nominational or parochial schools of Nebraska. «. or 3. It shall also be issued to any person of approved charac - ter who holds a diploma from a state normal school or standard college of another state conferring the right to teach for life in that state, provided such right is based upon the conditions, preparation and experience equivalent to those required in this </seg>
            <seg id="p064">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 61 FEES— A fee of $1.00 must accompany application in cases two and three. Examination fee covers issuance of certificate in case one. Elementary and Second Grade State Certificates, First Grade Slate and Life Certificates are issued by the University, state normal schools, and such colleges and normal schools as are approved by the State Department for the issuance of teachers' certificates. EMERGENCY FOR CITY STATE CERTIFICATES. 1. An emergency must actually exist 2. The certificate is issued by State Superintendent. 3. Requests must come from the city and county superintendents and the board of education of the city where the emergency exists. 4. The person must be of approved character. 5. A fee of $1.00 must be paid to the State Superintendent. 6. Applicant must be graduate of State University or of a stand - ard college of this state. 7. Certificate is good for one year only. 8. The law is silent as to how many emergencies may be issued to any one individual or district. The new certification law does not repeal the provisions of the old law relative to the power of the state superintendent issuing emergency certificates. The law reads as follows: "Provided further, in emergencies arising from a scarcity of teachers in any county, the State Superintendent may at his discretion, upon the recommendation of the county superintendent, grant per - mission to teach in a specified district for a specified term of school, the person given such permission to teach being required to attend teacher's examinations and to write upon such subjects as the county superintendent may direct." "Provided second, the county superintendent may, at his discre - tion grant a first grade county certificate without examination, to a graduate of a college, university or state normal school, subject to such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the state superintendent of public instruction." RULINGS AND 1NTKRPRHTATIOXS The holder of an Elementary State or a Second Grade State Certifi - cate, when such certificate is based upon graduation from a four-year </seg>
            <seg id="p065">62 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT high school, plus the completion of twelve college hours (four of which are professional work), may be issued a grade city-state certificate. *The holder of a city-state certificate, issued prior to July 19,. 1919, may have a first issuance of this certificate under the new law without further examination or school attendance. KThe holder of a city-state certificate who has, in addition, one normal school or college work, plus three years or twenty-four months of successful teaching experience, may be issued a professional city-state certificate of the same class, good for life. College or nor - mal hours credit to be valid must be properly certified. The special city-state certificate entitles the holder to teach and supervise the subjects for which it is granted in all grades and in high school. The holder is eligible to teach any such subject as music, manual training, home economics, physical education, commercial art, agriculture, etc. Certificates From Other States. t Foreign Certificates and diplomas will be accepted as a basis to - is the various classes of city-state certificates, if they meet the dard required of the State University, approved colleges and nor - schools of this state, for the issuance of similar certificates. General State Certificates First Grade State Certificates and Professional State Certificates, issued by approved normal schools, colleges or universities in Ne - braska, as provided by law, are valid in any public school in the state. Therefore, these certificates are valid in schools organized under Ar - ticle III, VI and XXII, and in metropolitan cities. (Art. XXV, 7067; and Art. XIV, 6873-4-5-6. School Laws of Nebraska.) A Professional (life) State Certificate earned upon examination and issued by this department prior to July 19, 1919, is held to be valid in districts organized under Articles III, VI, and XXII, and in metropolitan cities. Under the new law such certificate issued since July 19, 1919, is valid in districts organized under Articles III and VI. I Notes: A grade in physical geography earned prior to July 19, , will be accepted in lieu of the examination in general science rd a professional state certificate. I A physics grade of 80 per cent or above earned for a first grade ty certificate will be accepted toward a professional state certifi- t Since the new law is not retroactive, this provision is made in to give the holder ample time to meet the requirements of the iw. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 63 INSTITUTIONAL CERTIFICATES (Revised and re-adopted by the State Board of Education, August 1920) The following rules have been formulated and adopted by the State Normal Board for the issuance of certificates, diplomas and de - grees by the state normal schools and all private and denominational schools under the direction of the State Superintendent, as provided by law: The following Certificates, Diplomas and Degrees are issued: 1. The Regular Normal School Diploma. This diploma is recog - nized by law as a first grade state certificate. 2. Bachelor of Arts Degree. 3. Professional Life State Certificate. 4. The General Elementary State Certificate. 5. The Elementary Rural State Certificate. 6. The Advanced Rural State Certificate. 7. A special teacher's certificate is granted by the State Superin - tendent in any one of the following departments, when the student has majored or earned 16 college hours credit in that department: Manual Training, Domestic Science, Public School Music, Public School Drawing. The student must also have met all the requirements for completion of the advanced or two-year college course. ENTRANCE REQUIREMENTS Classification: Students in the ninth and tenth grades or in the elementary rural course are known as Preparatory, those in the eleventh and twelfth grades as Secondary, and those above the twelfth grade as Collegiate. Entrance to Preparatory or Elementary Rural Classes enter the Preparatory class the student must have at least thp eighth grade or its equivalent and be sixteen years of age. Entrance to Secondary Classes To enter the Secondary classes the student must have at least 15 high school credit points representing the completion of a two-year high school course, or he must have a second grade county certificate. All students in the regular elementary certificate course are classi - fied in this group. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">64 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Entrance to Collegiate Classes To enter any of these courses the student must have thirty credit points representing the completion of a four-year high school course, or its equivalent. COMPLETION OF GENERAL ELEMENTARY COURSE To complete the general elementary course the candidate must have met the following requirements: 1. He must have at least 150 secondary hours in subjects of high school rank and in those subjects especially intended as a prepara- tion for teaching. The following is the required work for the Ele- mentary Certificate Agriculture _ _ 5 hours Algebra _ _ 10 hours High School English _ _ 2 0 hours Plane Geometry _ 10 hours European History _ _ _ _ 10 hours Civics _ 5 hours Physical Geography _ _ _ _ 5 hours Laboratory Science _ _ - 1 0 hours Observation &amp; Methods _ _ _ _ _ _ 5 hours Elementary Psychology and School Organization _ _ 5 hours Grammar, Arithmetic, U. S. History, Geography _ _ 2 % hours each in 2 of the subjects. Physiology _ _ _ 5 hours Physical Training ■. 1 hour Public School Music _ _ _ _ _ _ _ _ _ 1 hour Public School Drawing _ _ 1 hour The remainder of the required minimum number of hours shall be elective of secondary rank approved by the president of the school. 2. The standard time for completion of this course shall be sev- enty-two weeks above the tenth grade or its equivalent, making a total of 144 weeks above the eighth grade. 3. A student who has completed a standard three-year high school course may complete the Elementary Course in one year of thirty-six weeks provided he has the required minimum number of hours and has completed all the required professional and review work intended especially as a preparation for teaching before receiving his </seg>
            <seg id="p068">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 65 4. No student shall receive an Elementary certificate who has not been in resident attendance at least twenty-four weeks in the school granting the certificate. 5. A student who is recognized as of superior ability may on recommendation of the faculty receive an Elementary Certificate on less than 144 weeks time above the eighth grade, but 1U2 weeks above the eighth grade shall be the minimum. 6. The candidate for the General Elementary Certificate must also have grades in all subjects included in the first grade county cer - tificate. The grades must be earned in the regular state examination for county certificates, in an accredited high school, or in the regular classes of the Normal School. It is provided, however, that grades in orthography, penmanship, composition and reading (when not taken as a review) may be based upon the general character of the work done in English in the normal school. The grade in mental arithmetic may be based upon the work done in written arithmetic. No county certificate grade of less than 80% shall be accepted. JUNIOR STATE CERTIFICATE The elementary certificate may be granted to Juniors who are compelled to drop out of school to teach before completing the senior year. This certificate will be granted in case the candidate has com - pleted the junior year as outlined by the state normal schools, and is within 32 collegiate hours of graduation. The standard time in which this certificate may be earned is 180 weeks above the eighth grade and the minimum time is 168 weeks. ADVANCED COURSE To complete the advanced course the candidate must meet the following requirements: 1. The standard time for completion of this course is two years in advance of a four-year high school course, making a total of 216 weeks above the eighth grade. It is recommended that the follow - ing required and optional secondary subjects be taken in the high school, but in the event the\Atudent does not enter with grades in these subjects they must be taken in the normal school before graduation. Required Subjects for Entrance to Collegiate (iroup Algebra _ _ _ - - 2 points or 10 hours Rhetoric and Literature _ _ _ 4 points or 20 hours Geometry _ _ » 2 points or 10 hours European History _ _ 2 points or 10 hours </seg>
            <seg id="p069">66 Foreign Language (at least 2 years of one) _ 4 points or 20 hours Laboratory Science _ _ _ _ - - _2 points or 10 hours In addition to the above required subjects for which no substi- tutes are accepted the applicant must present fourteen additional points selected from the following subjects, making a total of 30 high school credit points necessary for entrance to the collegiate group: Agriculture _ _ _ 1 point Rhetoric and Literature - 2 points French, not more than _ - - 6 points Solid Geometry .....1 point German, not more than _ - _ _ _ _ _ _ _ 6 points Greek, not more than _.. — 6 points Latin, not more than _ _ _ _ _ _ 8 points History (European and American) 4 points Botany _ _ _ _ _ _ _ 2 points Zoology _ _ - _ — 2 points Chemistry _ _ _ _ _ 2 points Algebra, third semester 1 point Physics _ 2 points Manual Training _ ". 2 points Domestic Science _ _ _ _ _ 2 points Physical Geography 1 point Civics _ _ - 1 point Political Economy _ _ 1 point Physiology and Hygiene _ _ _„ _ 1 point Review taken in 11 or 12 grade _ _ _ 1 point Bookkeeping _ _ _ _ _ : 1 point Music (either vocal or instrumental) of such grade as any standard high school will credit for graduation not more than _ _ _ _ _ _ 2 points Normal Training _ _ _ _ 1 point Or any other subject of secondary rank approved by the President. 2. To graduate the candidate must have the following collegiate and professional work: Biology or Nature study _ _ _ _ _ _ _ 4 collegiate hours Psychology _ _ 4 collegiate hours English _ _ _ _ _ 4 collegiate hours History of Education 2 collegiate hours Theory of Education _ 4 collegiate hours Practice, Observation, Methods and Principles of Education to be done in connection with Train- ing School (at least 4 hours must be practice) _8 collegiate hours Two hours (collegiate) in each of two subjects selected by stu- </seg>
            <seg id="p070">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 6 7 dents and approved by president of school from the following: Arith - metic, Geography, Grammar, U. S. History, Physiology and Hygiene Reading. Each school reserves the right to add to the above list of re - quired subjects such additional work as its organization and equip - ment make advisable. 3. The required observation and practice is one-fourth of the student's time for one year and at least one-half of this time shall be devoted to making of lesson plans and to teaching one full period daily in the Training School. It is provided, however, that experienced teachers who have taught three or more years successfully may at the discretion of the president of the school be excused from one-half the observation and one-half of the practice work specified above. Such applicant must take in lieu of the omitted work another collegiate or professional subject of equal rank, approved by the president. 4. Students who enter with credits from schools whose stand - ing is not known shall have their credits tentatively accepted and later approved by the department concerned, either by examination or by subsequent work. Grades which have been thus approved shall have the same recognition as grades made in the regular classes of the school. 5. Full credit shall be given for all properly reported work from an accredited high school or from high schools approved by the state superintendent as schools of the first class. Full credit may be given by the president for recognized equivalents for the above named credits. 6. The candidate for . graduation must have grades in all sub - jects included in a first grade county certificate. These grades must be earned in an accredited school, or on county examination, or in the regular departments of the school granting the diploma. It is provided, however, that grades in orthography, penmanship, composi - tion and reading (when it is not taken as a senior review) may be based upon the work done in English in the Normal School. The grade in Mental Arithmetic may be based upon the work done in writ - ten Arithmetic. In all subjects taken in the uniform examinations, or given by the heads of departments to test the work given in non-ac - credited schools, 80^ shall be the minimum grade upon which ac - creditment will be accepted. 7. The candidate for graduation from the advanced course must have not less than 60 college hours. The eight hours required in ob - servation and practice in the training school and heretofore provided </seg>
            <seg id="p071">68 KEPOUT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT for is recognized as of collegiate rank and is included in the above minimum. 8. The student who majors in manual training or domestic- science may substitute some other work approved by the president for collegiate work in common school branches as mentioned in Section 2. 9. Students of more than ordinary ability may on recommenda- tion of the faculty graduate from the advanced course in less than the standard time of 21(&gt; weeks above the eighth grade, but 196 weeks above the eighth grade shall be the minimum. No variation shall be made from this rule except by action of the State Board of Education for Normal Schools in each— dase. 10. Students who graduate from the advanced course must have the following drills or semi-studies: Physical Education 2 hours Public School Music 2 hours Public School Drawing _ _ 2 hours By a drill is meant those subjects which require the time of a reci- tation but little or no outside preparation. 11. A student who presents a certificate as entrance credit or for credit toward graduation shall at the time of matriculation be granted, as follows, for a second grade certificate Agriculture _ _ _ 1 point Bookkeeping (if included) _ 1 point Civics 1 point Theory and Art (pedagogy) 1 point English 2 points Physiology and Hygiene _ _ _ 1 point Total _ _ 7 points In addition to t ne above a student holding a first grade county certificate at the tinsv of matriculation shall have credit for Algebra _ 2 points Botany 1 point Geometry _. _ 2 points Physics (if included on certificate) 2 points Total _ _ _ _ _ 7 points A student who has taken subjects on the examination for a pro- fessional life certificate and has earned passing grades shall have </seg>
            <seg id="p072">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 69 Chemistry _ _ _ _ 1 point General History ■ 2 points Physical Geography _ _ _ 1 point Composition and Rhetoric 2 points The above are allowed only on high school course requirements. In no case shall (hey be converted into Collegiate credit Credit on Collegiate Work Elective collegiate credit will be allowed to the candidate who has taken a state examination for earned passing grades as follows: professional life certificate and has Geology _ _ _ _ 4 college hours Trigonometry 4 college hours Literature _ _ 4 college hours Zoology 4 college hours Psychology : 4 college hours Total 20 college hours For each high school credit point or collegiate credit point earned as above noted, an allowance of lour weeks of time on the attendance requirement will be made. This time allowance will not be granted for any subject that has been taken at school during the time covered by the attendance report of the candidate. Time allowance is granted only when a subject is taken outside of the institution in which time attendance is claimed by the candidate. Work in Absentia 12. The maximum amount of work that may be done in absentia shall not exceed sixteen college hours in the advanced normal course. An additional credit of sixteen college hours may be so earned in the degree course. 13. No one shall receive a certificate or a diploma of any grade from a state normal school who has been in resident attendance less than twenty-four weeks in the institution granting such certificate or diploma. Amount of Work and Credit 14. The standard amount of work any student may carry is six- teen college hours during any semester in addition to two drill sub- jects. Permission to carry a larger amount of work than this will be granted only to strong students. The maximum amount of work which any student may carry will not exceed 900 minutes per week in </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 70 recitation. This is exclusive of the time for passing from one class to another. Music, physical training, military training, and other drills are not included in reckoning the number of minutes above mentioned. Credit for Teaching Experience 15. For teaching experience two weeks time credit may be given for each year of successful experience in teaching or supervisory work, provided that in no instance shall more than sixteen weeks credit on attendance be given for such experience. The regular nine months term shall be considered as a standard, but eight months may be considered as one year in case the applicant for accreditment has taught in a school providing less than nine months in a year. Bachelor of Arts Degree Graduates from the Advanced Course of the State Normal Schools who complete two years beyond the advanced course consisting of 64 college hours may be granted the Degree of Bachelor of Arts. City Certificates The City Certificate will be granted by the State Superintendent on payment of the fee of $1.00, to any student who has completed the advanced course of the state normal school, or a corresponding course in an institution recommended by the State Superintendent to grant state certificates. The City Certificate, however, is not necessary to be held by a student who has completed the advanced course of a State Normal School. This is the ruling of the state department and is also the law the words of which are quoted in the following ruling: "Students who have completed the advanced course of a State Normal School and have been granted a diploma by the Board of Ed - ucation of State Normal Schools, are legally qualified without further certification to teach in any school in the State of Nebraska as pro - vided by Section 368, Art. XXV of the Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913." Rural Certificates The Rural Elementary and the Rural Advanced courses are given by the State Normal schools only. The Elementary course requires a minimum of 72 weeks above the eighth grade and the advanced rural course a minimum of 144 weeks above the eighth grade. The mini - mum resident attendance for the Elementary Rural State Certificate is 36 weeks and the minimum resident attendance for the Advanced Rural State Certificate is 24 weeks </seg>
            <seg id="p074">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 71 Explanation of Terms The credit point is defined as one full study carried for one se- mester five periods each week. This is equivalent to five hours as the term "Secondary hours" is used in these rules. In case the organization of the school provides recitation periods of fifty minutes in length, instead of forty, then four fitly minute recitations a week for one semester is a credit point. Method of Passing Upon Credentials The Board of Education for the State Normal Schools will grant diplomas and issue the various grades of certificates in accordance with the following requirements: Each applicant for a diploma, certifi- cate or degree must be recommended by the faculty of the normal school he is attending and also by the President of that school. The President and Registrar of the school must certify to the Board of Education that each applicant has been recommended by the faculty and in all respects has completed the work and complied with the foregoing rules. CITY STATK CERTIFICATES ISSUED FROM JANUARY 1, 1920 TO JANUARY 1, 1921 Grade _ _ _ _ _ - 472 Professional Grade _ _ _ _ _ - 291 High School _ 217 Professional High School _ 8 5 Special _ _ _ 17!) Professional Special _ 15 Professional Superintendent's _ _ - _ 1 8 Total _ _ _ 1277 General Life (Prof. State) _ 80 CERTIFICATES ISSUED BY STATE SCHOOLS AND APPROVED AND RECORDED IN OFFICE OF STATE SUPERIN- TENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION Elementary and Second Grade State _ — _ _ _ 359 First Grade State _ 708 Life _ _. „ 147 Total - — - 1214 State Certificates Validated _ _ - - 125 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">72 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT COUNTY CERTIFICATES E. new county certificate law became effective July 19, 1919. The ions are as follows: I. Classes. 1. Second Grade. 2. First Grade. II. Requirements for Second Grade. 1. Approved character. 2. Academic — Pass state examination in agriculture, civil government, drawing, theory and art of teaching, arithmetic, geography, grammar, United States history, mental arithmetic, orthography, penmanship, physiology and hygiene, and reading. Required average 80% with no subject below 70%. 3. Professional — At least 8 weeks of Normal Training in a standard college, the University, State Normal School, or other approved normal school in this or another state, or in an approved high school approved by the state superintendent as bemg equipped to give such normal training. 4. Issued by county superintendent. 5. Fee |1.50. 6. Validity — Time — 2 years in county where issued and in any other county of the state when record is transferred by state superintendent. 7. Renewable - Once only. Requirements. 1. Approved character. 2. Issued by county superintendent where teacher laft taught. 3. General average must be raised by state examination to 85%, with no subject below 75%. 4. Applicant must present certificate signed by proper au - thorities of institution attended, showing credit for 6 college hour? earned in residence or absentia (subjects optional with county superintendent) . 5. Fee $1.50. 6. Validity — Time — 2 years. III. Requirements for First Grade. 1. Approved character. 2. Academic — Pass state examination in all subjects re - quired for a second grade county certificate, and in addition there - to, algebra, botany, geometry, and public school music. Required </seg>
            <seg id="p076">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 73 equivalent grades for the last lour subjects earned in high school by graduates of approved Normal Training high schools shall be accepted by the state superintendent in lieu of the examination grades. 3. Professional — At least 12 weeks of Normal Training in the University, a standard college, a State Normal school in this state or another state, or in a high school of this state approved by the state superintendent as being equipped to give such nor - mal training. 4. Experience — 1 year 5. Issued by county superintendent. 6. Fee — $1.50. 7. Validity — Time — 3 years. 8. Renewable. Requirements. 1. Approved character 2. Issued by county superintendent where teacher last taught. 3. General average tnutft be raised by slate examination to 85%, with no subject below 80%. 4. Applicant must present certificate signed by proper authorities of the institution attended, allowing credit for 6 col - lege hours of work earned in residence or in absentia in addition to the requirements for the renewal of a second grade county certificate, or 12 college hours in addition to the requirement for the first issuance of a second grade county certificate; it shall be renewable thereafter by the county superintendent of the county in which the holder last, taught by the presentation of a certifi - cate signed by the proper authorities of the institution attended showing the completion of 12 additional college hours earned in residence or absentia since I lie certificate was first renewed. 5 Fee — $1.50. (i. Validity — Time — 3 years. KXAM1XATIOX DATKS I- OK IMS One-day —^January 18 March 1 5 April 19 Two-day — May 2 3, 24 June 27, 28 July 25, 26 One-day — November 15 Reading Circle Examinations: March 15 May 24 July 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">74 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT A special examination in arithmetic, geography, grammar, history, and reading of the county subjects, and in all of the life subjects was given July 17, 18. EXAMINATION DATES FOR 192O One-day — January 24 March 27 April 24 Two-day — May 28, 29 June 25, 26 July 30, 31 One-day — November 20 In the year 1919 examination papers graded and reported to count; superintendents were as follows County certificate subj««ta _ 59 ,774 Professional Life certificate subjects. 1,4.47 Reading Circle ; 4,191 Total 65,412. In the year 1920 examination papers graded and reported to coun- ty superintendents were as follows: County certificate subjects _ _ 57,554 Professional Life certificate subjects 681 Total _ 58,235 Total for Biennium „. 123,647 CERTIFICATES ISSUED BY COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS IN 1919 First grade county certificates 2,263 Second grade county certificates 2,732 Third grade county certificates- _ 198 Total 5,193 CERTIFICATES ISSUED BY COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS IN 1920 First grade county certificates 918 Second grade county certificates-. 2,091 Total 3009 Total for Biennium -————————_„■__„_____„___„ 8 202 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 75 STATE SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION APPROPRIATIONS FOR BIEXMUM APRIIj 1, 1919, TO MARCH 81, 1921 Expen- Est. Ex- Total Ex- ditures penditures penditures April November April 1, 1919 30, 1920 1, 1919 Am't Ap- to Nov. to March to March Items propriated 30, 1921 31, 1921 31, 1921 Office Expense % 12,500.00 $ 11,995.85 $ 1,570.00 $ 13,565.85 Traveling Expense 4,000.00 3,233.14 766.86 4,000.00 Normal Training in High Schools 154,000.00 78,186.00 2,296.66 80,482.66 State Aid to Weak Disticts 20,000.00 5,225.60 1.000.00 6,225.60 State Aid to Rural High Schools 30,000.00 8,900.00 18,500.00 27,400.00 Transferring Certificates 5,000.00 3,000.00 3,000.00 Salary Superintendent 4,000.00 2,973.13 1,000.00 3,973.1:: Salary Deputy 3,600.00 3,000.00 600.00 3,600.00 Salary First Assistant 3,600.00 2,727.10 840.00 3,567.10 Salary Second Assistant 3,600.00 3,000.00 600.00 3,600.00 Salary Third Assistant 3,600.00 2,950.00 600.00 3,550.00 Salary Secretary 2,400.00 2,000.00 400.00 2,400.00 Salary Secretary of Normal Training and Bookkeeper 2,400.00 1,976.66 400.00 2,376.66 Salary Stenographer 2,160.00 1,680.95 400.00 2,080.95 Salary Stenographer 2,000.00 1,666.66 333.34 2,000.00 Salary Stenographer 1,920.00 1,494.19 320.00 1,814.19 Salary Chief Clerk 2,400.00 2,000.00 400.00 2,400.00 Salary Clerk of Examinations 1,320.00 1,100.00 220.00 1,320.00 Salary Clerk of Examinations 2,400.00 2,000.00 400.00 2,400.00 Salary Readers of Examina- tions and Extra Help 7,200.00 6,907.51 292.49 7,200.00 Totals $268,100.00 J143.016.79 $33,939.35 $176,956.14 FINANCIAL STATEMENTS AND STATISTICAL ABSTRACTS FIXAXOIA1- STATEMENT 1918-1919 RESOURCES Amount on hand at beginning of year $ 1,810,595.03 From county and township treasurers _ 12,135,057.42 From sale of district bonds 1,960,151.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">76 From tuition of non-resident pupils _ _ 372,074.18 From local fines and licenses 123,637.4(i From all other sources _ 1,723,495.53 Total :.._ : $18, 12 5, 0in.fi I EXPENDITURES Paid male teachers $ 801,167.44 Paid female teachers 7,647,702.05 Paid for buildings and sites _ 1,386,932.60 Paid for repairs „ 489,204.57 Paid for fuel 631, 485. 3 0 Paid for reference books _ 21,483.87 Paid for text books and supplies _ 592, 878. 2S Paid for furniture 264,322.8:; Paid for all other purposes 3,393,319.70 Amount on hand at close of year 2,896,513.91 Tot al !f 1 8,125,010.64 Financial Statement 1010-1O2O RESOURCES Amount on hand at beginning of year _ _.$ 2,904,292.83 From county and township treasurers 14,788,9(&gt;5.f&gt;2 From sale of district bonds _ _ 2,044,220.17 From tuition of non-resident pupils _ 491,620.80 From local fines and licenses _. _ _ 163,573.91 From all other sources 2,574,54 (1.20 Tot al _ $22,9 67,21 9.53 EXPENDITURES Paid male teachers _ _ _ % 1,271,064.48 Paid female teachers _ 9,636,566.21 Paid for buildings and sites _ _ _ _ 1,895,353.44 Paid for repairs _. _ _ 497,230.87 Paid for fuel ._ _ _ 810,474.96 Paid for reference books _ _ _ _ _. 31,311.12 Paid for text books and supplies „ 809,359.62 Paid for furniture _ _ _ 300,328.76 Paid for all other purposes _ _ 4,311,374.73 Amount on hand at close of year _ _ 3,404,155.34 try a i ' . . </seg>
            <seg id="p080">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 77 NEBRASKA SCHOOL STATISTICS Koi the School Year Ending July, HIIJ) Counties _ !):j School Districts '... 7,1 tiS Schoolhouses 7,s!m; Teachers employed Males S 2 2 Females : 12,73D 1^,555 Average monthly salary: M a les $107.37 Females 66.87 EXPENDITURE IS Teachers wage: Males .-. $ 7S 1,864.89 Females '. 7, 694, 700.56 $ 8,479,574.45 *-cmaies Y,i&gt;:i4,7U'J.bli $ s, ii'J,oli. i'o Uuildings and Sites 1,194,400.87 Repairs 44 5,435.19 Fuel 551,614.80 Li b rary Books 1 !i , 1 7 7 . 2 2 Text Books and Supplies 532,718.38 Furniture '. : 249,844.97 For all other purposes 1 ,867,1 36.2!&gt; $13,339, 902.17 Amount in hand of district treasurers $ 1,80ft, (132. 57 Value of school district property 32,674,217.47 Total indebtedness 9, 004,680. a i Children of school age (5-21) _ _ 391, 27u Total enrollment 302,975 Average daily attendance _ 209,476 Cost of education per pupil on enrollment 4 4.02 Cost of education per pupil on daily attendance 63.67 Graded schools (including all ward schools) 80S Teachers in graded schools _ 6,4 61 City schools organized under article 22 78 7' High schools organized under article 6 2 60 Village schools organized under article 3 206 High schools accredited to the University of Nebraska 380 Smith-Hughes schools: Agriculture _ 31 Home Economics 44 Trade Schools 1 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">78 County High Schools ..: __ 14 Normal Training High Schools drawing money 1918-19 145 Students in Normal Training High Schools 1918-19 3,987 High Schools offering Normal Training 19 19-2 «....„ 214 For the School Year Ending July, 1920 Counties _ — 93 School Districts _ _ 7,264 Schoolhouses _ _ _ 7,655 Teachers empolyed : Males _ _ _ _ 1,084 Females „ _ _ _ 12,705 Average monthly salary: Males _ _ _ $134.45 Females _ _ _ _ _ _ _ 86.26 EXPENDITURES Teachers wages: Males _ $1,271,064.48 Females _ _ _ 9,636,566.21 $10,907,630.69 Buildings and Sites _ _ 1,895,353.44 Repairs _ _ _ _ 497,230.87 Fuel _ __ , 810,474.96 Library Books _ _ _ _ 31,311.12 Text Books and Supplies _ _ _ 809,359.62 Furniture 300,328.76 For all other purposes _ _ _ 4,311,374.73 $19,563,064.19 Amount in hand of district treasurers _ __ $ 3,404,155.34 Value of school district property _ 42,145,280.75 Total indebtedness _ 15,070,715.66 Children of school age (5-21) _ _ _ 392,592 Total enrollment ._ _ _ 311,821 Average daily attendance _ _ 234,954 Cost of education per pupil on enrollment _ 62.73 Cost of education per pupil on daily attendance _ 83.39 Graded schools (including all ward schools) _.... 749 Teachers in graded schools _ _ _ _ 6,823 City schools organized under article 22 _ 87 High schools organized under article 6 247 Village schools organized under article 3 172 High schools accredited to the University of Nebraska 402 Smith-Hughes schools: Agriculture 38 Home Economics 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 79 County High Schools _ _ _ 15 Normal Training High Schools drawing money 1919-20 135 Students in Normal Training High Schools 1919-20 4,000 High Schools offering Normal Training 1920-21 216 DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS 1919 Outstanding bonds _ _ _ $10,921,810.45 Other indebtedness 1,196,652.07 Total indebtedness _ .'. $ 1 2,118,462.52 DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS 1920 Outstanding bonds $13,075,813.00 Other indebtedness ._ _ 1,994,902.66 Total indebtedness _ _....$! 5,070,715.66 VALUE OF DISTRICT" PROPERTY 1919 Value of school hon ses _ _ _ $2 5,106,965.59 Value of sites 4,327,997.12 Value of text bo &gt;ks 1,224,134.20 Value of maps, charts, etc _. 768,952.15 Value of all other property.- _ _ 1,198,665.90 Total value district property $32,726,714.96 VALUE OF DISTRICT PROPERTY 192O Value of school houses _ $31,238,857.13 Value of sites 5,418,363.82 Value of text books _ _ 1,554,484.56 Value of maps, charts, etc. .: _ 838,650.68 Value of all other property 3,095,124.56 Total value district proyarty $4 2,145,280.75 NORMAL TRAINING IN HIGH SCHOOLS SYNOPSIS OF NORMAL TRAINING REGULATIONS I. INTRODUCTORY. — Policy. 1. Normal Training high schools are not designed to function as normal schools. 2. Normal Training is but one phase of high school training. 3. This bulletin proposes to stabilize the normal training course. 4. The normal training course is both academic and vocational. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">80 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT II III 5. Graduates from normal training course may receive thirty - two entrance credits. 6. Combination of courses provide for wide election 7. Provision is made to prevent these regulations being retro - active. Article VII. 8. Courses of study in professional subjects issued by this de - partment. 9. School must have written curriculum. STANDARDS OF BUILDING AND EQUIPMENT. 1. Building — well kept — properly heated, lighted, ventilated — sanitary. Sanitary toilets. 2. Adequate laboratory and class room equipment — to admit of recognized high standard work. .• 3. Adequate,- up to date text books, and such supplementary li - brary material as to provide well rounded course in each sub - ject taught. 4. Must meet standard approved by this department NUMBER AND QUALIFICATIONS OF TEACHERS. 1. Superintendent — legally qualified to teach in a high school or city school district, and must have had not less than two years successful teaching experience, exclusive of practice teaching. 2. High School Teachers. a. Not less than three, exclusive of superintendent, devot - ing entire time to high school work. b. Where high school contains more than four grades there must be as many high school teachers as grades in high school. c. Must be graduate of standard four year college course, the higher course of standard normal school, or hold a professional life certificate or its equivalent. 3. Normal Training Teacher. a. Same academic and professional qualifications as denned above for other high school teachers. b. Must have had not less than two years successful teaching experience, exclusive of practice teaching, (one of which should preferably have been in a rural school). c. Normal Training teacher shall teach all normal training reviews, except those taught by Superintendent, or except penmanship and drawing when taught by a qualified supervisor of those subjects, and the professional training when not taught by Superintendent. Nor shall the Nor - mal Training teacher be required to teach the music or physiology when given as reviews. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 81 IV 4. Grade Teachers. a. Not less than four in number. b. Must hold a first grade county certificate or grade city certificate, or the equivalent of either. c. Must have had not less than one year of successful teach - ing experience, or not less than eight hours in education taken in a standard college or normal school. d. Not more than fifty pupils enrolled under any one teacher in any one grade. COURSE OF STUDY AND CERTIFICATION 1. The course of study in -normal training higli schools shall con - sist of a regular four year course as outlined in the bulletin issued jointly by the University of Nebraska and the State Department of Education. This bulletin is commonly known as the High School Manual. 9. The normal training course where offered shall be elective. Normal training high schools shall require for graduation a minimum of thirty entrance credits, as defined by the Ne - braska High School Manual. ■1. Graduates of the normal training course must have completed the following courses of study: a. Not less than four semesters or seventy-two weeks in English. b. Not less than two semesters or thirty-six weeks in each, American history, algebra, geometry, and professional training. c. Not less than eighteen weeks in each, (*5) agriculture. (*5) botany, civics, (*3) general science, (*4) physiology and hygiene, (*2) public school music. d. Not less than twelve weeks in each of the (*6) major re- views, except grammar which is given as part of a con- tinuous course in normal training English for ten weeks, e. Not less than six weeks in each of the (*6) minor reviews, except orthography which is given as a part of a continu- ous course in normal training English for three weeks. No credit can be given in any of the prescribed courses which have not been completed and taken for the time required in these regulations. S 6 High school grades, when approved by the county superin - tendent of the county in which the normal training high school is located, will be credited toward certification in the follow - ing subjects when taken as prescribed above: algebra, geometry, botany and public school music. 7 If county examinations are taken in any of these four subjects the right to claim the higher grade is not forfeited, provided </seg>
            <seg id="p085">82 V. VI the student obtains a number for Hie reporting of the grade to the county superintendent. 8. Students must obtain grades upon county examination in all subjects required by law for a second grade county certificate. Graduates from the normal training course in approved high schools shall receive, upon securing requisite grades on coun - ty examination, a second grade county certificate. !). After one year of successful teaching this certificate may be exchanged for a first grade county certificate without furthei examination, if requisite grades have been secured in all cer - tificate subjects. 10. A county examination number must be secured, according to the regulations governing the issuance of examination num - bers to which all grades are to be credited. 11. A minimum of two days observation of rural school work, preferably under the direction of the county superintendent, shall be required of every normal training graduate. The work in rural school observation should furnish the basis foi the course in rural school management. QUALIFICATIONS AND ATTENDANCE OF CLASS 1. Members of Normal Training Class must sign declaration of intention to teach. 2. Members of Normal Training class shall be defined as follows; a. Juniors — Completion of three years of prescribed curricu- lum, and three passing grades on county examination in subjects taken during the year (before report is made to State Department). b. Seniors — Completion of four years of prescribed curricu - lum, and six passing grades in county examination (be - fore report is made to State Department). 3. Class must enroll a minimum of ten (as defined above i. 4. Schools maintaining classes of less than ten may have the work approved for certification but cannot be approved lot State Funds. 5. Attendance report must not contain names of any who have not signed declaration of intention to teach, nor who are not qualified juniors or seniors (as defined above). 6. Attendance report must show compliance with courses of study prescribed in Sec. 3, Art. IV of this bulletin. 7. Twenty recitations per week or equivalent is maximum a pupil may carry. APPROVAL OF NON-ACCREDITED SCHOOLS. 1. Nothing in these regulations shall serve to abrogate that clause of Section 139, Article 10, School Laws of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 83 VII VIII school which can qualify under these regulations the State Superintendent of Public Instruction may designate a high school of lower grade for giving such normal training." SPECIAL PROVISIONS. 1. Where it is impossible for schools to comply with this bulle- Itin because of previous curriculum the following minimum substitutions will be accepted for the class graduating in 1921: a. Major reviews for minimum of nine weeks each. b. Minor reviews for a minimum of four weeks each except drawing and penmanship for a minimum of three weeks each and orthography for a minimum of two weeks. c. American History for a minimum of one semester or eighteen weeks. d. University Credits will be adjusted to these substitutes e. Only already approved Normal Training High Schools may make these substitutions. ■ These substitutions will be accepted only upon application by school concerned with full proof that such substitutions is necessary. NORMAL TRAINING CURRICULUM. * 13 Ci * ired lit i Val lue Subject Grade in which taken Mathematics 9 10 11 12 Algebra 2 * Geometry English *1 (Bookkeeping 2 4 (i weeks) 4 * * *2 Public School Music 1 * Social Science European History American History 2 2 * or * Civics 1 * or * Science *3 General Science 1 * *5 Botany 1 * or * *5 Agriculture *4 Physiology &amp; Hygiene Professional Training 1 1 * or • * fi Reviews Arithmetic-Drawing 1 * Geography-Penmanship 1 Grammar-Orthography Reading-Elective Review 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 84 XOKMAIi TRAINING PROGRAM Ninth Grade First Semester Second Semester Credit Value Credit Valui' Algebra Algebra 1 1 I English *1 (Bookkeeping 6 weeks) 1 1 1 English Elective Elective 1 *3 General Science Elective 1 1 Tenth Grade Geometry 1 1 Geometry 1 1 1 •5 Botany-2 Agriculture-3 European History *5 Botany-;! Agriculture-2 European History 1 Elective 1 Elective 1 Eleventh Grade English 1 English 1 i *4 Physiology &amp; Hygiene •6 Reviews 1 *2 Public School Music *6 Reviews Arithmetic-Drawing Civics 1 1 Geography-Penmanship Elective 1 1 Twelfth Grade Professional Training American History 1 Professional Training 1 1 American History 1 *6 Reviews •6 Reviews Grammar-Orthography Elective 1 1 Reading-Elective Review 1 Elective 1 1 COfBINATIOX XOMAL TKAIM.Nti AM) ( ol.l.lM.i; PREPARATORY First Semester Second Semester Ninth Grade Periods Periods English *1 (Bookkeeping English Algebra G 5 5 5 6 weeks) Algebra 5 5 Foreign Language Elective ££ L " e "' 8e 5 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 85 Tenth grade Geometry 5 Geometry 5 *5 Botany 2, Agriculture European History 5 *5 Botany 3, Agriculture 2 5 5 European History 5 Foreign Language 5 Foreign Language :-. 6 Eleventh Grade English Civics 5 5 English 5 B *2 Public School Music * 6 Reviews *6 Reviews Arithmetic-Drawing Foreign Language or 5 Geography-Penmanship Foreign Language or 5 Mathematics 5 Mathematics 5 Twelfth Grade Pedagogy and Rural School Management Observation and Methods American History S 5 E 5 American History *6 Reviews •6 Reviews Read ing-Physiology Physics or Chemistry 5 6 Grammar-Orthography Physics or Chemistry g 5 H-*11 — TOMHIXATIOX NORMAL TKAlMNii AXI) SMITH-HV&lt;JHKS AURKTl/ri'KK Second Semester First Semester Ninth Grade Periods Periods English *1 (Bookkeeping 6 weeks) E English 5 Algebra E Algebra 5 Smith-Hughes Agriculture 10 Smith-Hughes Agriculture 10 Tenth grade English E English S 5 Geometry E Geometry Smith-Hughes Agriculture 10 Smith-Hughes Agriculture 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">86 NOTES *1. Bookkeeping not required for certificate but required by law for course of study for rural schools. May be taken as minor reviews in straight normal training curriculum. *2. Public school music taken one period a week for not less than five semesters accepted, if in addition, music is given as minor review. *3. General science not required if physics or chemistry is taken for one year; or of Smith-Hughes vocational agriculture students. Course in Smith-Hughes vocational home eco - nomics accepted in lieu of general science; physical geogra - phy accepted in lieu of general science. *4. Students taking the following combination courses as out - lined in above programs must take physiology as a minor review: Combination Normal Training-College Preparatory; Combination Normal Training-Smith-Hughes Vocational Ag - riculture; Smith-Hughes Vocational Home Economics course in physiology, hygiene and home nursing accepted in lieu of regular physiology. *5. Smith-Hughes Vocational Agriculture two year course in Field Crops and Farm Animals accepted as satisfying re - quirements in both agriculture and botany. *6. Major reviews: arithmetic, geography, grammar and reading shall be taught a minimum of twelve weeks except grammar which is a part of a continuous course in English. See Course of Study. Minor reviews, drawing, penmanship and orthography, and under certain conditions, (see notes 1, 2 and 4 above), physiology, public school music and book - keeping for a minimum of six weeks, except the orthography, which is a part of a continuous course in English. See Course of Study. The reviews of composition, grammar, or - thography and reading shall be known as Normal Training English and will be accepted by the University as satisfying a part of the English entrance requirement, after the four points have been regularly earned previously. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 87 No. No. Normal county ggr sassy ras? ■&amp;» Tocher in Completing En- in Force Spools ( "" nly lulled 1919 | 1920 1921 1919 I 1920 1921 Adams. 79 ■» 19 I 17 26 5 1 10 i 4 Antelope KM •) 11 11 8 61 13 it Arthur 30 5 Banner 20 s 2 Blaine 34 Boone _ 78 BozButte*! 53 lit t; 41 I 26 i 36 i 2 1 8 IS •&gt; 6 14 20 I 6 I 11 12 Boyd tit; ■&gt; 13 19 26 6 | 30 20 Brown 38 Buffalo 135 ■' 11 18 I 17 5 I 15 12 ;■ ■ '•'&lt; 37 51 9 1 12 10 Burt. 4 37 I 32 29 2 15 9 7:. 3 7 2 Butler 85 17 18 23 4 17 ■&gt;:: 15 2 Cass l:&gt;4 Cedar *1 122 30 i 18 I 18 2 12 9 17 I 28 ! 11 6 I 17 1 99 Chase. l 2 :: i; 24 I 30 9 Cherry 161 1 8 1 6 1 5 I 42 I 115 86 5 Cheyenne 79 •&gt; li 7 I 12 13 I 26 ■2-1 Clay 85 5 4ti 28 I 46 4 1 10 o Col fax 56 32 I 9.9. 2t s :; Cuining 7!) 20 ; 26 i 13 3 1 7 -1 Caster 231 Dakota *1 34 4 31 42 24 I 7 I 88 77 o 16 I 23 11 3 1 12 12 Dawes 88 9 I 15 8 Dawson !lfi 5 26 18 39 22 I 21 1 Deuel 29 1 5 1 6 1 7 I 6 i Dixon 75 23 I 36 I 30 1 8 I 11 !. Dodge 95 4 23 I 40 1 31 4 | 7 6 Douglas *2 52 4 24 40 i 27 2 14 1 Dundy 63 2 9 7 I 16 5 I 29 2 Fillmore 85 6 25 I 31 44 4 | 7 3 Franklin 64 9. 20 I 11 14 11 j 14 9 Frontier Ill 2 2 2 15 18 I 29 1!) Furnas 79 6 53 j 58 j 45 10 I 25 I Gage : 156 5 19 | 38 39 14 I 34 12 Garden 84 1 ! * 7 4 3 I 32 19 Garfleld 39 1 6 13 9 13 | 13 9 CJosper 70 1 7 | 13 I 8 1 13 it; Giant 10 2 I 3 :i Ureeley 74 1 7 14 19 I 10 7 | 4 S </seg>
            <seg id="p091">OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT COUNTY No. Rural Teachers Needed in 1 and 2 Teacher Schools No. Normal Training Schools in County Non Trail Seni Compl nial ning ors leting- Nor. Train- ing- Seniors En- rolled Emerget Certiflca in Fore icy tes :e Hall 73 Hamilton 89 Harlaii 73 Hayes 4 8 Hitchcock 75 Holt *1 - 175 Hooker 32 Howard 77 Jefferson 9 1 Johnson 7 6 Kearney _ 6 8 Keith 54 Keya Paha. 55 Kimball 4 5 Knox. 151 Lancaster 4 1 Lincoln 168 Logan 3 1 Loup 2 McPherson 2 6 2 4 4 1 2 4 1 1 3 2 1 1 1 2 2 2 4 1 1919 25 17 11 2 15 17 3 4 23 17 19 4 13 6 19 29 26 1920 9 36 24 3 13 37 8 4 21 25 7 8 14 2 18 28 17 2 1921 18 27 25 6 12 40 7 6 30 22 12 11 2 7 8 35 7 2 1919 | 1920 6 | 9 1 | 6 13 I 16 8 | 17 15 [ 23 3 [ 10 ...... | 6 3 7 3 j 6 2 13 2 | 7 9 [ 28 10 | 8 3 | 5 5 [ 35 16 | 8 29 J 51 2 | 5 7 | 12 3 j 11 16 | 18 4 | 6 14 | 17 5 | ..... 5 j 21 7 | 19 5 | 38 8 | 20 6 17 3 j 13 6 17 1 7 2 16 13 21 1 22 22 12 4 28 3 1 2 | 18 1921 3 8 4 24 21 11 3 10 17 14 6 19 3 32 8 16 1 9 18 Madison... 32 (I 56 42 51 10 Merrick 70 3 13 22 23 Morrill 71 2 7 3 10 13 Nance 7 0 2 22 19 17 Nemaha 5 7 Nuckolls 87 1 15 10 10 18 5 28 29 32 3 Otoe 99 3 18 24 20 29 Pawnee 7 4 2 20 22 25 10 Perkins 63 1 1 3 5 16 Phelps 70 2 10 22 23 18 4 Pierce 85 2 15 13 9 Platte. _._,. 82 Polk 68 1 11 1 18 7 3 19 23 28 Red Willow 65 3 20 13 18 31 Richardson *1. 90 3 17 20 15 14 Rock 6 5 1 5 4 7 1 Saline. 107 7 56 46 70 12 Sarpy 4 1 Saunders 126 1 6 4 6 1 3 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 89 County Scotts Bluff 83 4 I 18 I 14 24 10 I 23 16 18 I 14 24 10 j 23 Seward 100 3 41 20 , 40 31 16 1 Sheridan 106 2 9 510 2314418 9. Sherman 74 2' 9 2113 1123 Sioux. 81 _ I ...... 13 I 37 Stan ton 55 111314111 61 9 Sioux. 8 1 6 I 9 Thayer*! 86 6 29 30 35 7 1 32 34 I Thomas _ _ 20 1 ...._ 2 4 1 I 14 10 I Thurston 26 i 1 j 81 41.7 I 15 2 Valley. 76 2 j 121 231 12 I 21 I 12. Washington 72 1 12 17 8 5 | 5 5 Wayne _... _ 79 _ 8 I 8 Webster 81 4 41 31 33 8117 41 31 I 33 8 I 17 I 1 Wheeler 42 1 9 17 15 .»... I 4 &lt;; York 77 2 2120124 .1 i ♦Private and parochial schools. SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES PAID TEACHERS— 1919 Number of i Total Wages Earned ]&gt;&gt;' All Amount of Qualified Teachers for the Tear Money Voted Teachers Whether Paid or Unpaid I'lHiXTV for Past Year Kmployed Males Females I Males Fe'alesl Adams Antelope- Arthur .. Banner..... Blaine Boone.. Box Butte.. Boyd Brown... Buffalo.. Burt Butler.. Cass Cedar.... Chase.... Cherry. Cheyenne.. $ 205,138.00 13 172 $ 21,481.96 $ 115,921.07 138,607.00 5 177 5,442.50 98,265.21 11,443.00 4 32 2,217.50 12,262.75 12,284.00 2 26 670. 00| 11,662.00 17,830.00 3 35 1,810.00| 14,464.50 137,624.00 4 135 5,214.80] 85,585.60 68,538.00 6 103 7,107.06 49,703.19 37,491.00 4 107 2,785.00 61,082.03 47,081.00 3 88 507.001 28,584.32 250,183.50 161 224| 17,243.33 139,661.34 142,513.00| 11 137 9,956.34 83,387.83 150,054.50 16 169 11,021.75 93,286.39 146,421.00| 11 186 10,975.50 115,302.40 161,028.00j 12 168 10,826.13 104,233.63 45,371.00| 2 75 690.00 32,002.98 150,472.00| 14 213 5,783.75 86,839.26 102,126.00| 8 126 6,898.25 60,194.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">90 SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES PAID TEACHERS— 1919— Continued. Number of. i Total Wages Earned By AM Amount of Qualified Teachers for the Year COUNTY j Money Voted Teachers Whether Paid or Unpaiil for Past Year Employed .Mali's. Females Males Fe'alea Clay _ _ 157,874.00| 24] 1621 14,679.381 97,471.53 Colfax 118,212.00 9 107 9,840.28 65,696.86 Cuniing 114,626.00| 71 102 7,008.551 68,479.83 Custer _.. 211,357.00 20 3311 10,942.751 168,545.25 Dakota 62,733.001 31 -71 3,475.001 44,830.85 Dawes 103,430.00 21 1231 3,663.001 59,149.57 Dawson 136,802.00 10 166 10,039.941 98,132.65 Deuel 18,450.001 2j 45 2,700.001 24,568.00 Dixon _ 104,080.001 9 134 10,060. 74| 83,290.20 Dodge 212,020.001 14| 193 17,058.451 135,083.86 Douglas i 1,893, 263. 00| 391 1,0391 98,435.37 1,146,823.41 Dundy 41,700.00 41 75 3,030.751 32,264.05 ■' 3Z Fillmore 132,577.001 5 164 5,018.75 94,295.08 Franklin 91,533.001 71 1241 5,207.501 68,363.45 Frontier 74,983.001 81 1371 4, 265.00| 60,588.75 Furnas 119,092.001 10 154 10,391.22 77,4!)4.:iS Gage 271,734.00 251 261 26,534.09 162,901.3!! Garden 43,320.00 4| 67 2,802.65 28,276.81 Garfield 29,401.00 5| 57 2,637.50 21,178.00 G ° s Pei- 38,701.00 2 67 - 1,395.00 31,012.50 Grant 23,274.50 3 21 3,295.90 13,281.00 Greeley 71,761.00 1 101 2,060.00! 50,809.43 Hal1 181,313.00] 10 288 12,687.50 121,572.67 Hamilton 143,470.001 13 163 7,998.25 90,498 76 Harlan 99,248.00 7 125 6,351.27 67,123 53 Hayes 24,175.001 Hitchcock 51,872.351 8 86 5,106.25 6,634.50 in 718.75 627.28 272.00 044.55 164.81 926.76 033.40 200.20 570.07 Holt. 117.512.-00f 12 219 105 Hooker 79.850.00J 21 37 660.00 13 Howard 84,620.001 9 110 T £*ff&amp;vaf\n (111 Arr aa •• n -&gt; _ *. 7,332.85| 10,721.52 6,387.12 6,019.67 4,665.00 6n 98 Jefferson 231,955.001 16 179 T/iVi nonn or 1 1 f a n n _. * _ Johnson _... 85,115.00 8 109 "K&amp;Q-rna-u to cere- «/\ « / - . 5 7 Kearney 78,555.001 6 102 r,:: Keith 60,119.00 5 70 Keya Paha 34,758.00 1 62 Kimball 48,370.00 58 I.' r. nv 1 I L&gt; -I I . 1 n nAA. Keith.. 41 600.00 24 36 Knox 148,298.00 8! 202 8,191.25 54,201.81 11,039.51 109 Lancaster 1,254,498.00] 61| 598 465 Lincoln 112100001 101 2^4 126 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 91 SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES PAID TEACHERS— 1919— Continued. Number of i Total Wages Earned By All Amount of Qualified Teachers for the Year Muney Voted Teachers Whether I'aid or Unpaid for Past Year Kmployed Males Females Males Fe'ales COUNTY !•'. males Logan -I 31 27 2,507.25 11,508.50 Loup 15,364.00 4| 36 1,170.00| 7,724.30 McPherson 19,147.001 5 27 l,436.75j 10,394.00 Madison 191,996.001 13 187| 15,889.00 112,127.28 Merrick 109,902.00| 3| 99| 4,030.00 69,459.00 Morrill 112,882.001 5j 95 4,482.50 59,365.27 Nance 87,537.00 3 98 2,525.00i 56,087.56 Nemaha 116,903.00 12 j 133 8,039.251 62,965.04 Nuckolls 138,607.00 10| 169| 7,586.25j 93,467.1(1 Otoe 119,748.00 15| 171| 14,584.33; 109, 66:!. 2:'. Pawnee 94,448.84 10| 115 6,067.50 ' 19,546.00 Perkins 41 74 870.00 29,508.19 Phelps 62,881.00 5j 108 8,530.00 63,976.87 Pierce 122,008.00 5 123 5,532.46j 66,741.66 Platte , 127,626.00 9 131 10,719.00] 81,756.75 Polk 116,973.00! 121 109! 9,668.001 64,691.40 Red Willow 60,330.001 4 134 Richardson 137,955.001 8 175 Red Willow 60,330.00 4 134 5,192.22j 78,209.51 Richardson 137,955.00 8 175 4,104.98 93,677.37 Rock 2| 64 860.00 25,351.46 Rock 21 64 Saline :..._.. 171,575.001 141 1891 Saline :..._ .. 171,575.00 141 189 14,342.69 105,987.40 Sarpy 89,294.00 5 83 5,260.00 55,208.04 Saunders 189,861.00 14 193 13,240.15; 122,949.54 Scotts Bluff 134,147.00 161 163 18.224.38J 111,353,12 Seward 113,428.50 201 140 15,521.27 84,149.10 Sheridan 105,309.00 11 149 6,199.621 73,321.76 Sherman 72,500.00 2 115 2,608.14 58,075.50 Sioux 49,578.00 8 82 2,295.00| 34,602.45 Stanton 68,230.001 71 79 Stanton 68,230.00 7 791 5,222.001 45,421.21 5,222.00 45,421.21 Thayer 106,317.00 12 1491 11,015.23 80,632.52 Thayer 106,317.001 121 149 11,015.23 80,632.52 Thomas 21,395.001 II 30 Thomas 21,395.00 1 30 480.00 16,644.00 480.00 16,644.00 Thurston 100,049.001 51 85 Thurston 100,049.00 5| 85 6,209.73 56,130.20 6,209.731 56,130.20 Valley 82,048.00| 6 122 4,206.75 60,101.87 Washington 131,249.00| 10 114 10,850.00] 73,369.17 Wayne 113,221.00 2 117 2,935.00 76,120.05 Webster 110,855.00 14 129 12,149.00 76,633.40 Wheeler 18,593.00 8 37 1,314.75 14,530.13 York 178,588.00 12 166 15,227.50 96,569.67 133,271,227.691 822 12,733]$ 784, 864. 89|$7, 694. 709.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">92 SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES Paid Teachers — 1920 — Continued Number of i Total Wages Earned By All Amount of Qualified Teachers for the Year COUNTY Money Voted Teachers Whether Paid or Unpaid for Past Year Employed Males I Females IMales Fe'alesl Adams_ f 238,458.00| 20| 190? 26,714.26$ 145,590.95 Antelope 215,814.001 81 171 12,465.98 115,644.55 Arthur 12,450.00] 1J 29j 720.00 15,128.50 Banner 19,091.001 0| 26 800.00 14,533.10 Blaine _ _ 18,575.00| 4] 31 997.00 14.056.44 Boone 148,019.001 51 133 6,650.00 101,915.76 650.00 101,915.76 Box Butte 95,148.00|j 5| 93 8,624.97 65,767.00 Boyd 68,032.001 201 103 13,728.00 69,195.62 Brown _ 81,247.00| 4| 87 5,160.00] 53,557.25 Buffalo _ 248,823.00| 13| 2511 18,853.00j 184,414.45 Burt — 238,707.00] 11 142] 15,944.76] 101,794.22 Butler_. 178,688.00] 20] 148J 21,272.671 107,288.92 Cass 174,552.00] 18] 186] 25,687.59 135,086.95 Cedar 183,240.00] 15] 188] 21,250.54] 126,446.21 Chase 52,638.00] 5] 66 2,235.25] 29,843.80 Cherry — 196,458.00 18| 212 12,682.00 102,873.44 Cheyenne 130,676.00 12 123 13,245.00 77,475.01 Clay _ 257,516.00 22 162 23,716.35 112,763.14 Colfax 130,054.00 9 108 12,656.31 79,491.16 Cuming 120,036.00] 9 109 12,332.50 79,834.20 12,656.31 79,491.16 Custer _ — 305,258.00] 25] 337 49,254.31] 209,768.82 Dakota 72,987.00 6 67i 7,010.00! 49,919.23 Dawes _ 99,174.00] 6| 121] 7,851.14 81,348.42 Dawson 165,753.00! 8 171] 10,689.90 123,086.29 Deuel 39,587.00] 5 42 6,170.00] 28,934.60 Dixon _ 132,016.00] 19] 132 16,435.60 97,351.40 Dodge 17 196 24,411.69 168,549.71 Douglas _... 13,050,182.00 70 1,102 148,038.49 1,558,398.26 1%..— ■■-. rr aaa aa ■ mm „ -. - „ 558,398.26 Dundy. 55,099.00] 4] 73 3,150.00 39,459.75 Fillmore 135,313.00] 12 1401 20,672.48 102,963.29 Franklin 1 10] 112 11,563.00 76,798.15 Frontier _ | 9] 142] 6,663.50] 76,146.63 Furnas 137,696.00] 19] 140] 20,206.91 95,415.39 Gage 390,919.00] 28 273] 35,880.25 203,877.74 Garden 54,902.00 8 69 4,007.501 40,949.40 l'_.,,.fiol,l on ron n/\ /. . . .„._„») _. .. Garfleld 33,582.00] 6 44] 4,245.00 24,832.00 Gosper 54,702.001 6 741 2,679.50 42,194.98 Grant 34,040.00| 4| 20 5,440.001 16,568.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 93 SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES Paid Teachers — 1920— Continued Nuniljir (if ttil Wiifc'i-s Karned By All Teachers for the Year Amount of . Qualified Money Voted Teachers for Past Year Kmployed COUNTY Whether Paid r Unpaid Males Females Males Pe'alf 223,941.00, 7 191 13,413.83] 155,460.07 Hall Hamilton 141,118.00 19 1 6 1 j 18.850.89j 105,976.37 Hamilton 141.118.00i It) 1 161 Harlan 91,323.00 10; 1241 10,612.44) 85,187.91 Hayes :!l,4 50.00j .....: j 23,336.50 Hayes 31,450.00 Hitchcock 67,453.00! 5 89 5,790.00 55,285.65 55,285.65 Hitchcock 67,453.00! 5 89 5,790.00 :i Holt 157,056.00 131 221 1 11,765.75 131,960.15 Holt 157, 056.001 131 221 11,765.75 131,960.15 Hooker 17,150.00 2 28] 1,148.75| 14,290.00 Hooker 17,150.00 2 28 1,148.75 14,290.00 2 Howard 100,535.00 10! 114| 9,584.97 73,730.45 Howard 100,535.00 10 114 9,584.971 73,730.45 Jefferson 187,162.00 23 155 24,668.10 112,967.89 Jefferson 187,162.00 23 155 24,668.10 112,967.83 •)■ Johnson 94,890.00 10 112 12,325.00! 68,796.26 Johnson 94,890.00 10 112 12,325.00 68,796.26 Kearney 92,353.00 7 103! 7,534.96 66,267.19 Keith 72,700.00] 7 74] 7,670.00 44,487.03 Keya Paha 37,335.001 7] 52 : 2,665.00 29,097.50 Kimball 67,020.00 | (il 47,642.90 Kimball 67,020.00 61 47,642.90 Knox 199, 237. 00 16 210 11,972.52 142,817.25 Knox 199,237.00 16 210 11,972.52 142,817.25 Lancaster Z. 1,254,498.00 52i 642: 82,383.54 760,421.53 Lincoln 278,978.00 16 244 18,867.59 159,487.53 Logan 4.340.00J 4| 29 3,775.00 18,229.52 Loup 19,844.00 .1 3 4 1,260.00] 18,657.90 Loup 19,844.00 .1 34 Madison 236, 501. 00, 17. 206 Madison 236,501.00 17 206] 20,510.02 142,931.20 MePherson _ 20,065.00 II 31] 630.00 13,303.45 McPherson. _ 20,065.oo li 31 Merrick 113,030.0m 6] 108J 6,392.50 86,270.98 Merrick 113.d30.00 61 108 6,392.50 86,270.98 Morrill _ ] 4| 106! 6,600.00 80,464.30 Morrill _ 4] 106 6,600.00 80,464.30 Nance 0!l,134.00| 51 lOOJ 5,765.49 72,968.81 Xance 9 9, 134. on 5i 100 5,765.491 72,968.81 Nemaha 116,259.00] 14! 125] 13,243.05 82,485.65 Xeniaha 115,259.00 14! 125 13, 243. 05 82,485.65 Nuckolls 1-18, 745. 00J 20] 160] 18,411.35] 101,582.51 Nuckolls 148,745.001 20! 160 18,411.35 101,582.51 Otoe 229,152.00 18^ 192 Otoe 229,152.00 18] 192] 21,211.90] 131,158.20 21,21 1.901 131,158.20 Pawnee 114,727.00]' 171 1141 14,776.85] 66,024.28 Pawnee 114,727.001 171 114 14,776.85] 66,024.28 Perkins 77,366.00] 9] 57 4,334.75] 31,163.11 Phelps 110,344.00] 8 99 13,363.23] 71,703.11 Pierce 138,828.00] 7 137] 6.986.59J 88,917.51 Platte 212,928.00] 13 125j 16,888.60| 89,489.65 Polk 121,926.00| 13! 110 14,741.50] 84,407.19 lied Willow I 141 130 Red Willow '. j 14] 130| 9.338.09J 88,940.35 Uirhardson 193,555.00! 14] 172| 20.230.50J 165,523.40 liirliardson 193,555.00! 14! 172! Hock 55,340.00! 4! 661 2,185.00! 29,222.10 Kock 55,340.00! 4| 66 Saline _.. 179,760.00! 201 1871 23,345.47 125,007.25 Sarpy _ _.. 98,039.001 6! 821 8,317.50 65,546.85 Saunders 211,744.001 23| 194 23,999.45 143,964.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">94 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SCHOOL TAX— NUMBER OF TEACHERS— SALARIES Sherman 137,030.00! 13 Sioux 62,803.00! 5 Stanton 87,936.001 5 731 6,345.00i 54,648.25 Thayer 131, 927. 00 j 18 Thomas 23,850.00! 3 1421 19,735.75| 93,785.50 Thomas.. 271 1,539.75! 13,943.25 Thurston 139,786.001 81 91 9,968.07! 69,668.09 Valley 92,903.001 7 118 6,300.00| 73,519.95 Washington 210,302.00j 8 73| 7,640.00j 68,003.45 Wayne 129,721.00 31 1161 4,575.001 94,616.65 Webster 129,027.001 161 127 15,200.641 87,952.35 "I Wheeler 25,129.00] 5 42j 2,235.00j 20,373.00 York 199,512.001 19 j 172| 25,248.95| 126,260.00 Total $24,935, 102. 00|l. 084 112, 705 j $1,311, 758. 59 j$9,864, 264. 61 STATE AID TO WEAK DISTRICTS A mo unt of appropriation _ _ _ _ _ $20,000.00 Amount of aid granted in 1919 $5,225.60 Amount of aid granted in 1920 _ 975.00 Total amount disbursed during biennium 6,200.60 Balance to revert at end of biennium._ 13,799.40 Since only a small part of the $20,000.00 appropriated in 1919 has been disbursed, a brief explanation may be in place. The limita - tions of the law make it impossible, under present high valuations, to disburse these funds. The law reads in part as follows: "The estimated expenditures for the current year shall be the amount necessary to maintain the school seven months, said estimate not to exceed Three Hundred and Eighty-Five ($385) Dollars." With a maximum levy of 35 mills only a few districts in the state raise less than $385, but the minimum cost now of maintaining a rural school for eight or nine months is $750. It can be seen that while these districts need aid as never before, and the funds are avail- able, they cannot be disbursed under the limitations of the law. Paid Teachers — 1920 — Continued Number of Total Wages Earned By All Amount of Qualified Tpachers for the Year COUNTY Money Voted Teachers Whether Paid or Unpaid for Past Year Employed Females I Males Males. Fe'ales I Scotts Bluff 21 185 30,237.64| 142,129.85 Seward 177,509.00 15 145| 20,378.161 105,442.80 Sheridan 127,077.00 12 1511 11,699.00 95,082.05 13| 111 9,405.00j 66,305.99 5| 811 2,930.00 44,883.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 95 = S3? O I -OOO • • [OOOt*C0OOOOO -O30O O ; -ooo • | ioooio-rooooo iocacc O :OOO : :OOOr-'C^OOOOi£3 :OC5C^* O i t- i— I © J iOOOt-OOOOOt- : O Ci ii i-i i-ti-H JC^I&gt;-MC^ r- X N O W i « i 1 ft , 1-Hr- i-H rH ■D O j j To O © ~T* : ©~ : © © © : : ©~ I \ I j j '■ i~ O |OO0|&gt;|O:OO0 :© ■©" :"©©'©* :©:©*©'© :© © :-.£©© io:©©© :© © ! o» ia O | h ; O O N : © ■ r-4 \ ■*? : cn *H : ■ 5 X T3 Q !» ■/. M tfi C a- Oi w 4fr ©-* ■ i :OU3oOLA©tA30© :©©3O©©© -5©00 ©W ;lflMC. inoOMTPO'liOCOOOO ■ 3C X IA : ,iHNtDb-d0P5fN i-fTr^-C^^&lt;t~- :^C0 «D Cl ir-t-^H^^tC^ 1 iaCCOCOTCSCO : CO CO ©c; ; :nA-^*eqtHACQM(e i t* n O o t- a j-^oo us -n* ;t-*-*oor~io^ct-i^co h r, m i- oo - . ■ r. '-"&amp; m afr' ' i-i i-i r- i-i n 00©»-tr-t(MI&gt;WOC l flCDi-'C0C^C0C030t^-Nt^ &lt;^&lt;t s -I&gt;-^t— ri iH 1-1 5 &gt;&gt; .§ = E - ©©© ©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©© ©.©© ooooooooooooooooooo ©©'©' ooooooooooooooooooo ©©© ©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©© C-lr—i— &gt;^C-r— t— ■ r— r-JC^i™ 4^— MC^r-rHr^r- 1 h N r- i— li— &lt; 3 i 5fr j j I j I ! j. : [ I 1 I | j j | J "J ! fe J j I a ■5 I i i i j I' 1. i 1 i &gt; 1 a I i S t »! '! ! tl J I 1 illlilllllllillllsljlli! z z ■J. I I I I f !■■ I I I • i ; i ] ! ; ; i i ; i i ! •: I i j i I I : | :::!::':: i i ! liSiit-'pijciiiiMiiiiliJi i i.SJJS IS'^s i i i ■ 'z i J i , h!i]'l!|J|£IlllljJ*JJil ,2 • J2 - .iKftaj-cJK-ss ST3-OC . .9 . , • -a . • o o N I ! s i ■ i I I [• I i s i i i i i i ; o i s ii Jn ld.2 J j J j g» g J a £ $ i § &lt;&lt;&lt;!&lt;i;BnKn»BP5nnououuuoooOOO </seg>
            <seg id="p099">96 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 1 Sgsg ■o § a Is o *■; i oo o i c» ; o us in I t- | O O : r-&lt; : 5 N li N ; oo o : t- i ■* O3 to O I N t- ! N I * » « IH i t-"* i tO i 04 00 C* inn in &lt;m ; i ; • • i I ; ! I O ! | © | : O : o O o : O jo : US : 00 i I I ! io io • • io !oo ;oo ■' jOjO iO:OO;OO I o I o joioioioo' ;. o :o ;o ;ot- :oo I o I O ioo;o«n;oo : "» ! co I ■* I t~T | e'oi !» |« JO • rH N ! o • cq I i i i ; i ■ • ■ o o i °. °. i 1-i O : at O ; ■* o i 1A LO ■ CO IH I i i i j i I i i i i 1 | t I I I I I.I.I II I •oel o ©■*-&gt; II- ■ o.Sio o I I|l rHtDcOOSCqWmmt-COT-lrHiHiHMCOtOlft rt « TH r-l iootooioo loo iioo I us us m n oo io ;om :cqo I 6 oi eq oo :«■* iodi-i icocoiOM'Oit- :r-ii-i : n oo I N Ol_ rH_ ■* e&gt;3 M | CO O | rl Q ! o m o o i* — — - i d w n io : •« (0 H O i O CO H C4 i r-l IT3 CO* m i i i O iH O O .1/3 I IH T(&lt; o O t- I N * io oo e : ft M H t- « i rl U) t^ i (■ i" » « e i-l i-l rt I IH is p ooooooooooooo ooooooo oo ooooooooooooo ooooooo oo ooooooooooooo ooooooo oo' OOOUSOOOOOOOOO OOOOTfOO OO N . *. *. *. M . ". "I •". °°. * « M n i-h s t-H &gt;oo&gt; t- a; t-l d N C* i-l rH r-T r-T r-l M tH rH r-&lt;" Q r-T N r-T rH rH rH ri" Q ,-T r-' i ■ ■ Ik b "D &lt; J I | J g La Sit utfeoMoa^BMoflHaog^iiah'og^ i-i B a ( 5 « e ■ ■2 I I I I \i i i I | I | II I i I I I I i j j I j I I o i . J J. J I I I f I ! ; &gt; j I B t* "H &gt;» I I J I j&amp;iiii'iiHIj! ill !*5 e a § I ! I I I I I ! I I I I 1 1 I I ! ! I ! ! I j i M I 1 .1 | I I. f- I I 1 I I 1 I I I J I I I j lid £ J j J 1 1 -i -J ■ Ilflf Jill ililiidllUJIIJ </seg>
            <seg id="p100">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 97 = = £ m a, 3 °-0 U CO C "O OS O IOOONOOO I !O lOtOOOOO I I lOO O JOOOU5OOO ;O I O &lt;* O O O O -OO n jcoo'ot^oo'o to iooo'oo'ioo io'o CO ;00U5«OU5OO !O iOUSOOCOO : i !u5O t-- ; 01 o » h n 10 ei ; ;«c ;oc&lt;itooOM | iesoo ** ! "" O 1-1 O i H I l&gt;" S H M » i IO IO t-H iH rH it- ; ,_, : t -I - I t I I § ■o ■ 1 il e ■o a) 2 is = £i oS g|5S O :O iOOO :O i :O :O ■ i iOO : I iO I oio;oooi©;io;o ;oo i!o oioioo'oio j o I o io© I© O:O:OO©:U5 t©i© :O©: :: © ; &gt;o : © i © 10 o j eo : m : « :o« i© ei I 10 i « t^ us i h I us ie&lt; | io h ! r-T II I I I I I I I II I s OOU5 iO :O :O i.-HOOOCJlOOO iOlftlOO IACCN ;i-( :O :W |(Olfliau:iaNOH ! IO CD N in W-**«-*r :U5 :CO j^* it^t^^wmlftt^W :cqOr-&lt;00 MC^U^ JOS :t*« jCOCSOSVrHOTflrt i u&gt; X tf K «O ■* iH R I M I t- M M N « ■ tS ! H H N » Iff] ; I-I- I -I- 1 • m i-H mi |H M *4 . I rH II 00000000 0000000000000 00000000 0000000000000 ooo'ooo'oo o'o'oo'ooo'o'o'oooo 00000000 0000000000000 l"_ (•_ « N U H «9 H «t-l&gt;l&gt;asii'(-Nff«l&gt; 1-1 r-l 1-1 Ti 1-H N IM N D Q Q 1M H iH r-T r-&lt; r-T N 1-t" i-J rH ri N 1— ■ 9 u •o &lt; I J I I J I I 4 1 j ! J £ J j j j j &gt;i ] I j j i I J 2 t a iaE i I i S - §&lt; 5 ri I 5 a&gt; ''*&gt; ' 5 *i iiliiliilllilillisiyill &gt;ISoi»!&lt;OJ2Uht-SOBb&lt;22li.OlIle.OO — c — B o&gt; a a ~7. I I I I I I I j I I i ! ! i i I I ! ! .: ! I i i \\i N J j I il J5 Is J I IS ! ! o d — sc c s 5 3 -3 ; S !13ijJ|J d J^4 h lj5ii*iSil : § 0 | i • • : i : ■ : • i ; ] j • • i i • ■ : i ■ : I I 1 3 [ j J j I j « j I I j f I j j : I j j 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">98 I i I 3 a I I t I - iooooo ioooo i o [ o* t fH I da ra S o— ; d in © d © iddt^d © d &lt;o « o £-o e -ocooom : © © t- © i in : us i t- ec (J ■-; ■ . ® : f"H CC t- © ; W ■ so : © 30 - = 5^- I •■ "■ * it- •» r* i 10 h" I h n * I i i o ■ o © © ©~~ ■ jo j T© I ' &lt;~5 ■ i ©~ &lt;O :©:©©©©;■© I © 'j i i © ■ I O § „ ; © | © oo d d &lt;* !« d i to M n| ■•©!©©©©:; r j :N:.:i© • w x^5 j©;inco©o :oo | © | us • cv K 5™ i ! » itieeuj loo j© 1!^! tJ •O : rt : « ffl M N i i-l i m C © © Fo © ia © to © S T©"©^ F©~©~© © us 10 © 5~ •O»5 . i © © N us t- t- N ;©in ■ o a c in t- n x ■» i »« -*cg i x &lt;r « ei a e o iaod ■ •) |^ « to n e ui .:£3 m^; ; -w e &lt;c n ■♦ » © C- rH i c-. w » oo m © gP B . *. * •• *^ • *^ *» » ;mm j io »s t- t- « oo -r a; S aj « ° ; ■«" n e n t-" m h j -o tt I H « m n te ■«." n _ S « n t-OT*iD(.Nii)!CONN u) n f O « in~m to tc 5-~ O £ ■O O r-t rH 2^22 S . ag°a &amp; f||l " """" H rt " Sj !Ml , ■ § e §§ §§§§§§§§"§§ §.§§§§§ M^"^ 2=3 22 =&gt;o©©©©©© = o ©o©o©&lt;m Set — til H N 3 H H n" N H n rt" ,-" r-T r-J G r-" |H r-T « H i r,' "J S I X J . ' V5 •" : i ■ i : i i '■ '■ j j i i i '■ i i ■ i i *» ! ji J MiJ JIN \i J_ lllillllil.lllllillill I I M ! ! I I i ! I! I i I i i i i I &gt; i i s iiiiifliSiiiiiiiii:: j c liJiig-gsi MS io ; ; j j ; ; ■ ; 1 : . — ■ -*-j flJiiilii uk iJloiJ ° liiilllliillliillllll </seg>
            <seg id="p102">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 99 5 8 Sal c $ s || B.3 c ah. ■oSi- - S s s j im j JT»co ! loooocooooooo I lo ! I . . i °? °. ; o o o «&gt; © o o O5 o o i eo ;m : o ■* iooeuioujt^iaoia it-^ it- :coto ; -OOO^HOiNt-ccOM : n I I I' I 1 II : : i w- ... •o ioo -oo ■'!•© 5^ i~©~©~©~©^ i~5 ; : ; r ;O ;©© io© i ! !©© ■©©©© ;© i© ;©© io© !©'© !©«©'© i© i ;oo ; © n ;©© ; : ;©© i u io o o i© i : 00^ : O Oi :©© :©© : ifl o O O :© :M : rl CO : H IO i V N !«•*■©©" |© : W i CC : rH © © : irs •&gt; ©© !©0©©©t-©0-. © © |~©~© © © © © © io N ©t^ : jOOOOOOOMHW -©lOlflOOOOOO OOtt :»NOM»HOrHNO :taOi^&gt;nte\O&lt;Snt~ ■;»HC0^r^©NT-tf00000'&lt;5- ;t-3JNOJU5«MtDX 00 t- O « « «" « O &gt;f » u N tt V V !&gt;' M S-" &gt;-l IH •»■ ft N.N :©CO5Oi-Ht-t-^©W oo W ?0 O0 go CO O) US 7 "?© C0~~ e-&gt;t- ;Hce*aNMt-»icocsr(^ioc. aetef^x i xn I » © iH • M t- CO © M tc rH 00 Oi CO M CV 00 i— "t- ■* t- f W t- 11 | rHrHi-Hr-lrH H ©©© ©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©© ©©©_©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©© ©■©© ©©©©©©©©©© ©*0©'©'©©©©0 ©©© ©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©©© *~l a= © m us t-_ tn « c; ci r-i i-h co r- i—_ c; © c-. t- m t- c. &lt;^ "-■ "- 1 C Q "- 1 "-I r+ r- C-) i-( rl CM C-f i-i" r-i* i-h i-T e{ r-T ci i— * r-* ■— " Oft- •Si m i | I ff i i | I J £? a S ' 1 S ! o p a ! = » 1 s * § s i I i 2 s 5 = i 5 • ° b : § i ± = 85^| I Si Ilil ill Hl^il sill B — B — a I !!!!!!!!!! iTTTTTTTTTTl j JJJ I | I I j JilJiiJ'MjiiMMiiiJ li ildi|li"a 3 illi^Illl 5 | ill SoS&amp;,&lt;mo^s^:g:o&lt;H^:H&lt;jfc &lt; K:g-: pa?: &gt; y. U z ::;:;:• !l if! ! til it!! If' i.|iiii!yiij|jj^iiii^rl r oOues~ooot.333esSj3j3i:J;o3scaoicii &lt;&lt;&lt;J&lt;KBpqB(HBHBHOOUOOOOC)UOOO </seg>
            <seg id="p103">I? 1_ ill c ooo 1 ! o o o -r ! 1 I ; o o i-i ! liaooo ooo iOeooia I •■•&gt;•• ; t- c o o ooo ii«T*oo ;©o'»h ; « d s oi OOO ; -* — o oo ;oom : oo o o -r o i-i us I e»_ oo o t- | is u h ; i-c oo n t- i-JV«e \ ei oo en ti jVcflt-T ;© to I 1 I I - I 1 I r - rr © i :!©!©©:!!©©!::: ■©: © ii©j©O . © « j© US © i © O ! © © i © 1 © i © © •, • © © j © oo oo ! us © j O © i © 1 «S ! i w us ; m •* | •* \** II i i i il: I I I I I I : •8*1 * »4J §-g-s§ 1111 lOOOOOOOOON tOO i O O O r* i n o&gt; OK ID |O0&gt;COOOOU3OU3 19* I » 5 O X : Hi » S » » «i9H»daa«ic ir-Io I ie « h e j n w m h n «&lt;oe*&lt;Oi-ioot-use&lt;s : us © m n n » ; K is n a a © US N_ C5 © TH e$ N ; N ©^ I IO © b- © i l"_ « O&gt; t- I II) 00 O H* It 8 i M H »" IO I N O !-&lt;"»-." rH 1-1 i-l • i 1.1.1 e 0»ia©l0Mt-00C0©l0S©f»^'Ot-*»M;e"»'MT!«MN Ht»^n«t*U)noo^ifr)H H CO « t- ffl C3 5© * fll r- r— rH l-H iH Noan^iooot-^no^HHniaHAaoMNaHODH »-&lt; 1-1 r-l rH f-l § Ii ooooooooooooo oooo oo o © oooosoooo©ooo © © © © © o © © ooooooooooooo oooo oo oo ooomooooooooo oooo oo oo M^^^WOllflt^OOVMNW t~ iH C» t- US Ci t- Oi lHNNe^1-&lt;'i-Hi-4i-i' r H'e&lt;Ji-«'i-&lt;l-lQi-le&lt;lr-Ci-HQi-lr-&lt;Gl-&lt;"l-' X I 1 I »{J N 1 J J*&gt; I I I ! |].| III I o&amp; &lt; &amp;.oMo«MM«owHatfe)&lt;i&lt;!a^oa £ &amp;. — e ■o c - c i c [ if n m n \ * h It * u v 2 8* ; a +* *■ !? -d.sg g££ || g j j § fi|f^a w |"| fc .-ga§; j l s ii: H - 8sS-as ea i 8 I i i I i i i | 1 I | II I I I | I J I I I | iiiftiiif iillmf JilllJili </seg>
            <seg id="p104">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 101 1 1§§-S ■o c d ■a 3 "SS O Q •S as a o m o ioo • o ioo U3 I O « O3 : O iH C4 : O CO iooo ieo ! i !*f&lt;o io • ; • loo looo!'* iioojo ioo tOOOicO: ■: l ~ '. i- i io d :OOO:tC : oo o j CO ■ e o :ocoeo;o e a it- { &gt; to &lt;— i \ m &lt;c IV ! V jeo it-^ci' i ■« • H ■ • • • H rt I ■• : I i i i till I i : ioo ! °. O i o o ioiiiooiii-i-iiioo; I o ; o o • o © ; :O jio'o: [iii loo ;O:;:OO iiiiiiooi : O | i»O i i : o O i&lt;c iit^rti iirtoi \*- III I i 1 I •! I I 1 "- 1 &gt; i I I _i I I t I I I i I I i Hi OB "SS-gJS oov i i 10 o ce ioo ioooeamoo : oooo io xo ta I (• ■• K !ioo : o = m « cj c t- iooioio IO O9 (4 i |Nf-*cq i M I* i (C O t- (• IO N Id : o r- d X LT3 CJ ~ - ?J r. C»5 IwOO'Vt^'^'^'W :t-lQ©t~ ft O) O I'J'^fO r^ iVC^iHt-OO'^'r-l irHMrH^O t- U5 r-C i f^ O CO ■"»• : IM* eq" t-T |&gt;T o;" CO i 00 CO CO OO t— ( : ; : : i &lt;O©t-t-&lt;©mt~C"-U3C£&gt;00 i0^rlt»^S&gt;t*THgottcOu3 IO H ri lOWtfcocoooNNNto ionttoiTS«u)^»H« 1-1 N rH ; H rl rH it: ¥ oooooooo o oooooooooooo oooooooo o oooooooooooo oooooooo o oooooooooooo oooooooo o oooooooooooo t~t~COC3U3r-lll3rH -^* t^t-t-OiOii-tt^CSlt^t-^b- t* t-T I-I i-T i-H cj" IN ci D Q N Q r-T r-T ri rH r-T «" r-T rH r-&lt;" rH C) r-i" ■ a h i [ N i I '\t \\ I MJ I I f J jr I I ' H SililiiSiilJlHi^iJl^ii c •O c a c z a. ■7. [ | | in | ! ill | j { ; ) || i I r i | | I N | | &amp;JJ § N | g : [ i I f f | j { { j | | i | | t [ j j j t | [ i" [ m I j f {■ I { I a i j j f 1 ! i ! i Ililliiiiillil liiJ </seg>
            <seg id="p105">102 j 55 tin I — - I IS ll « c •a a&gt;5 - i - -fc = »£^ an IIP joooo© i ia |©©o© j© :©tH©© :■** i©©t--© !© :©Ci©© ;t^ i O ifl M O :© ;u^c^©^© :co iw-*©© I \a O««« O rtactli [ r* 1 • rt : M ! : • i-H ■ i i ■ i i i • © i © jo i © I © : © : © ! © : 00 [ CO ! rH* j i-T IH M3 00 t- © CO I- ©© •© • •© : :© :© :■: j : T" ©©;©;;© i©jo; o © i © : © I © | © O©:© © © j Irt : N j CO I t- ©©■N jio: is is m ia • • m • e^ ! ill! I I I I I I i : © • I © : \O : CO ! : O ! n 1 JS" S « •" S *^ • "^ on i « to &lt;e V * d i^ T| l r t. I °. M . *". °. 'O M . rt -i-ioo ! a » «3 o io © ■*»&lt;t- i f ffi X M H iCOCP CO^CO^C^cT c^ I " ! r-i i : : O ei © _** 00 • «CO3rH©lOO5«5t-^l&lt;«5r-l(Mt~rHtC^.in^.t- r-l 1-1 . rH t«HM»niO«N00HlOMH*»l«lOU)rlNCr. iH r-l r-l C4 rH iH rH rH - oo ft CO © o ? ° 0©©©©© 000 © ©©©©©©©' °. . 000©©0©©©0 ©O©©©©© 22 oo©©c;©©©©© © d © ©' © © o ©© ©©oo©©©©©©© ©o ©■© o cq © t&gt;^ rH h ffl . w , * m n ** n t~i^cst~i~r~© rH (M Q rH rH im" ei rH rH rH rH rH rn" Q rH rH rH H r." C-q ■ *&gt; CO ■ c : i : I : : = : ■ ; ■ '■ : i • ■ : i : : : — ~ [I|}iifi||'|f!&lt; ■ : : : i &amp; N I I iid I U ! I !"§ I IgllggJI jlglllllllll I rl i £ it : 3 c 0) a 3 03 ri 1 1 1 n ii 1 1 ii ii ii ii ii I I I I ! : I IE I'll it ii- '{ill ■iliif jll!!Jli{lll!i AqAjJ-h &lt;^jg&gt;oaa5Sr1-ggg§g I I i 1 J I I i || | 1 \i | ! |j lllliillillllllilip [I i a ll II I j i -r-&gt; 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">103 OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION * rooosccoousc-. N-J l NOC30oo.-it-cousooiNOtc-*u3 3 t csocjoofesi-ic: sfMt-Ht-oioieOTMOKOt-n '"'o'- N N i-HrHrt CO C] N CO &lt;N pji-ie*i-lt-l'J&gt;r-li-lN ° = r t r w • &lt;» £;= I ?* (£ -5 t~ &lt;M « O t- :;ot--»-;Or-iooOOOOOOU5t-NU2e-l «"*!=: "jt M O C C r : 3 o©i-(NI-«De:SOO-1"'"» i eOiat-t-Cse&lt;lt- &lt;! 'x: c t- t- -r ro |iaw&gt;-ieoM^"»o«erHOt-C5«r-i-i_rH_M«9 W : c Jj'd ,_,* « i-J rH i-J r-i" r-i" i-J t-&lt;* n i-4 i- Jjj H |H I I I I j jH jh |««*lrt jH'HN [ j ■! •fi I!:::-: : : I % "**\ &amp; # Ml M %3 LLJ l 1j llll! iliMi ii- ra |Sfc . I 1 j i i i I S - : — i I _LJ_____L_J : ! i— ■ t005«&gt;tO=0MMe&lt;I00IMr-l'*l0'«&gt;t-«0esiOmMC:Ot~00 0 5 ■ a « h ri M h n io f c: * t- n oo t- t- u oo * t- 8 « is « g i &gt; c co im* n rt h n n n" n n rt rt H « rt * H ih n 1 Sil. . g S Q 3 s ; g i I o ■ S33o'«#'l&lt;(iHeo» ia » r* in so •* w co oo co « « -* §j Ji - cj* oo* cc" fC to t- X B5 SC r" tC C«" 1" N O CO ■* US 5S «C M "5 M W SoS? S oot-Mffiic'5c:C&gt;^"r-usO'rt~Ni-icoeot-c:-»i-iO«c o w^- in » n t) « — -r -f us c-. i-H c&gt; N ■♦ co im t- « t* -r &gt;' . . ..... ; ...... ; ... I I j I I |||| \ Iliiii^iiliJiJilJiiiiil 1&lt;&lt;fl H aHBBB«BOUOOOUOOOOafl </seg>
            <seg id="p107">104 ■ °gi g OO5l-U505Ot-T»"O)05l-00e0i-lrHC0t-IO OlOCOOSi-li-^OOSOOOOOOOOai^r-lt-^O » H M » « Ol » » « H ID &lt;f ffl M M O M OO e*CO!-( rt H rl « W H »N rl ! ■* i-i o o 10 ! (fi tc Ol 1A V j ■*_ iH_ •* ■* 00 i o * V » » i I M«n»*(-rl(-IOHM01 «*M&gt;**tON»« CO ; m &lt;c c-. t- -«o ■ t- n » m w i * n ■* o oo i N O o ■» in i t- m &lt;n o i-h : O rH_ N M O5 I I : O : j eo n i ! j i i i i N ; j I i i OJ i ■O Z « ; Oi [ lH H H j : : I : : ; ! i : : : : j I | : : i | 5*3 i O O) : co &lt;e i-H lH : O O O t*- ■ 1-4 TH N IO j j i : i : CO | I i ; cm ia o CO C&lt;l ■ l-H : co It! &lt; % Miaao^iAiatoiau3t«t-nt-t-oo^&lt;t« e^cqmococct-tot-eoooos^-^r-iMN-x" N n « N H H « IO H M « H ; tr c-i ~. c-i • m -« co cc | i-i as n &lt;c_ O5 ; ih m n « So?* t0«nnoat-viHi&lt;(coififloonNu3ff{ ineocsoin^ooo^-vt^cocsr-tt^esiait- ooeJi-ie^NTfoootoooinoooos'inOmw t-«(-uocit-at-oooaoinoi«t-t- MtOinrH^NrHCOOO i-HtOMPJ i t* m n n us • as -^ t- o; t- j in r-i o co oo i en co o O5 oo i » r« « is « : i-i ■*»&gt; C4 ■««• i N </seg>
            <seg id="p108">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 105 as SSs s y =— &lt;oot-ot-e«-*«&gt;weoe&gt;seoi-i'*wr-ie&lt;iMiHt-o«c«r-i loooomcwomooooot-oi^cjooocom-j-cjc-. mo °. M . "". H . °. °. 9 . * rt . rt . n ° M ° n » O O » M f t- « to ■*. oo t-" «" o t-" rt ■* n" n" o t-" rt ■» t." •»" oo io" h n » h" io riTHr-l « Ol M r; — — — ?1 r,;,___ :: _ •vcot-oo !t-r-itoeoco'fl&gt;oocONc:m'»wooooocoin O3&lt;M00C&lt;l inHMHNH»ciO!Ct-t^^tOMMt-t*r COOOt-rH jUHOlllMnHI'TMHHl-CnHse^ 1-1 « H cq~ rn" H ih" rt : : ' IN ' H :ii: t ~ii:iiie^i'-&lt;;ii;; r Hie-) • i ; i • I I ; : i : I i ' ■■■■■■■ :!!:•: i • • • ■ ■ ! ri I j j i m j | i j I I r-i t-i fS ; i i I f~ I I i i I ! i ! ; i i i ! ! i I ! I I : ■ • ■ • '.'•:::: i • • ; : : : : : : i i i : I i '&gt; : i I : I j ■•:::•. : i i ■ I I 1 i I I cojnto ;o ;ooo ; • irn ; ;&lt;mooc= • ,-. ; ;t- / th n ! 04 I 10 co j i j &lt;x&gt; [ is h a in ;co i I ! ! j i i I I i i ; '■ !__!__!___ ' ' « I i : OOOC5U500«iCOU5«Mt~c^^-llOt-«&gt;l01flo0300C:COrH t- io so « cc o « n n m h b- e M •» rt n n t- io in » « ; 1-1 lH CO CO CO CO iH iH rt in" im" CO rH h rH fff M J I OS &gt;. CS-^*OOf-&lt;as^»'S^TrOO'*^c&lt;)COO^C&gt;1COO"300t^COr-&lt;*Q cc~ iM-»--»"!Ocor~cDu50«oooooor-esioccc-5-j — m-r^. °. °. °°. "^ * "i '".";»'» i- «» M » t t&gt; m n o s n fll^ClCJNC;C5WnQOH300tO«!nwCC;VHlflCr-' L ooeoco&lt;oooorHcou5e-jc^S5i-ic-. e^cooo-r3;t~^^:r-^-i (MNrt T-i-fcoin iocoi-Hc&gt;icocoirac^ « « :; :: I |J i || I I j I | | | | iilialjalllliiillllllili ■ h v, Q Z 'J </seg>
            <seg id="p109">106 Is- Am |^ Hi o«Hfoo«Nn»HC)oi«&gt;caNSO«a n i&lt;Haon^oooH9iao90QNHO«N^aoo^ irt » ui » m « n h oi «"■ in" o h" ri V n 10" h n o » u" t-T rt « e&gt;5eqC0(Ni-lr-lT-(r1r-IN rHric-li-IC^ « .-I i-HCOCOOlOt-NO^O^fi-tCOO^USt^ | H t* » OOCOOSCiCOC&lt;ia3rHC^THOC5QOlOt-tDM I C5 tD h 00 WNC^C0t-NC0C^00C0^f«DOrHr-^fC0 j H U3 IO CO tH Ofl CJ iH US r* rH : W r-T 00 j vi A ■^ • Scoc^e^T-iN • &lt;x&gt; ■ irt I icoco It* i J as I i i i : : : : i i W i-J | i : : i I j : j j i i : i I | iH rH : : : : : ; : ; i i ! I : i ■: : : I N I : ; to CO 111 J Sm fi) CO |U3OOTt&lt;OiHrHa01OrH • 00 t- • ■ 00 : C3 i! I III LA O kfi ■ I , ; • ON-^'Mtocoasco'^oo^-coco ifl t* w t^ o c: CO CO -r OS Nrt«O»00Nl0OHO^Ht'' 1 1 1 MIOtD«ni l OtHCOCOC^COrHOO^flOLftOOr-4^'T-lCOrHT-lt^OO U5t*OOC^OOi-HCJOOrHtD-^'COl£5^f»a3Ci»-HOlftO'^* M ifl irac^CO^f"*p(MC^rHW00 N N CO M M 1* — CO ii- \\\H JJ ' J i i iiilllllllillilllllli "3 1 b </seg>
            <seg id="p110">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 107 ca ? as o T— N H W t- OO tf TTi-H |lfl!ONO»l&gt;t l nMM»MWHNHr. X OO r-i t- -f t miM Ir-HC^rHOO^fi-tOO OOlMCOmiNOO^miOiMOt--* hi Q Hi W --1 O o H CO 3 !Z! O 1 I a I M r-l &lt;N ' i-l H M M M NtHCOtHtH 1" i N « rill o-5 Tl 00 it- • « IP eq CO i -r ?1 1. &gt;. .23 * Sail Ml &amp;j i— H^r ! oi ■ofl-cs— ooo;- = := = ;sa&gt;.e.c.fi.^o=: = 3«c; O CD M N M N W O M r-t^i-HQOCSUDt-COQOOOT-li-lt*. OO NC^^ffit'H^rlHMHOOC.OOWtOO'ffMXMlO C^Wt-i— ICC&gt;r»COCS&lt;OiOCOdOOOt— (MOtOCOOCOfOOW OOCJHNNXfNWOOOWHrlMCi^^MOCMN^C: CO* M iH i-( r-l WC^(M«MCO rHi— I CO N t-1 M» iH r-t M cooot-coto o m ci io.h c*j -^ o t-i'COcj r- oo co *r eb x r. x inc:c^eOcoc^inoc5ioior-co^ i^ 4 ooocOi-iK!cci-tioc&lt;i tc-r* -i-imc^' tc i- f tc m h :o n io t w r cj fi io </seg>
            <seg id="p111">108 (0 &gt;&gt; jrt BO _ oil , 4) V c^oec^cceooot-cootc^c- ea c*T o a* •* u&gt; oo ■*" us oo V M MH N H rt N T» « 111 « H O!H !(• OH cn-^iooNOO i « o &gt;o » t- t^ o o-j oo • eo i* « OMiocoeo"© :eo'-*V r-4 rH CO N N : rH M I I S?fs III W N rH Csj H N W C4C4U3COPQ94 • U5 O O iHt-OOO-**"* ! 00 C4 X » «c t- o n co j « n cq iH Oi T* i-H I I i » H N N i : I j I I ; i i I ! i-t j I | : t-l 1 I j I i : rH i j ! I i i i : I i I I | S -- U &lt;y ■* t- t- t- I" • IH T)&lt; Tl&lt; i Cl 00 i [ | : ua : C4 M CO X I CO N H • iH i-H j i ■ OLAT-iT-tC^COO(HOOa3-&lt;9&lt;0 M t-N4S«OC&lt;ffi«N i-T co eJ *i c» OO O fll M N M IO IO H M OJ ft COr-tU5t"OONOlC5COCOrH -^taOTpOOOWCOrHOOi-t rHOOOOt««PCOrH-«r&lt;X&gt; tH N t» M tH -^ &lt;! i i i i ' ! i I i i i ! ! jjjajioic^jjii ■ i i « : J; S « a i B 2 iSiHlillifl £ 5 &amp; £ £ S £ £ £ 5 5 3 111 : • : | • : : ! • : : i i : i j I i I I I I I I I 1 ■[ I | j I iitJiiiiJi ! : s </seg>
            <seg id="p112">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 109 ■ S. 2 as «M(-»HM*»0IU0eilSO*lflUBO5St»MOBS*t- adCSOO0000C00^C00000i-HLACDOab*tAt*CDi-H00C5OC0 rnoirtc&lt;ioascoot-iflcqOtM-»j«?coa:cocoirtoooococp « » « w » » a is" « n * ia m co" t-' n te ai" * ei to ■o&lt;~ in a-" HN H Hrl MOM CO ri H H H N N r&lt; r-lr-l rl OIiH US US « H 9 S H * t- N f » H US US H CO H iH * ■oii*ust'OOpjoN«)QHOeMb.ooesoo ■C»T-&lt;OrJt-0000C0t-U300C0ON05M!5D ■ H » » » H (. H » H » H « t- » » US O I o" oo" ej w n cf e« ci ih r-T • • : rH j r-c i-H | "» « i CO IO j rH j &lt;M ri i i " | i I I. I I I ! i ill &lt;u! fil : i i ! i I "- 1 « Ell i j i ! i r* I I ! I ! ! r " 1 i 1 i CM i O OS • « • T-l rH CO : H i O r- -* i : y-&lt; i I °&gt; I O KS) t- ! io | CO i «e en ci 1 ■ III eM»H«0rlt-HOnOO01M*o»Mirn»HMt- I-li-H^'iH»W-*Mt-'*00-*OU5MOr-li-100TCMO00M «H«»to«t-«e)neinHHHrinNnnoi«i9go iH CO r-l i-&lt; • CO ■* CO ■* N* H H M N « H riH « &gt;. i-INUSt-OOONCOOitOt-OJfft-OOi-IOOr-ltOOOOWlfflr-l OMt-iet-USaOi-tOl.USKMMi-l^raoeqOMceOteaOte US O H 4&lt; M N O H U) t« « CO 1O H kO 00 30 '^' 1A (0 30 t* t* n T-le^i-lt~U5O5C0c&lt;IC&lt;lC©Wini~lcqCsmc£&gt;t'-©CC!»-l^t-&lt;M eo us co e* rH r-i so **_ m t- n n n n us n (Mrs I I I ! I I I [] I I i I ! [ I j I i I [ i I I I I I 1 I I I j I j I I I I t I j j I j I J j I • j ! !:!;;:!! i i i : ■ ■ : i : j ■liilJiiiiiJJili^iiJiiii 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">110 ■ 01 « KL Zx OOOOSOOrHCOtDWOOOStCt-^iHinr-ieOOWCOCOiai-l 00 meo?Pc^ooincoooooc^ii-Hi-(ooo50oc^ooor-tcoecoi-t rn wininto_ine^inr-^oooi-&lt;_cieot-«i-is-jwino5-*M^ oo c^i-HC^t-t^c^MOC5COi-Hini-Hc^«c^int^ocOi-4c^oo -^r « ■* H N :^ i-l M C] rq « rH r-i i— IJ rHrHNrHN CM «&gt; 00 ooooooooo5'«j &lt; ooo&lt;ci &lt; 0'*ominTj"eoe&lt;ioO'*oo I t- csot-t-i-&lt;oocsi-&lt;t--MOOe &gt; 3i-ieC'*j*©ccweoeq«ooo co e^cooo^^^covt-^AcscoooteNoaONiomioao I i-« N r-l rH ej CO N NM rH ej p4 ipI eq cq ! r-t in rH I iH j • !n i m h n :n i ico i h n n im • i o : [ j (O I . I I I I I I I I I i I- M : : ! : i : 1 j i I I i j i i i I n i i ! ! I I I j m i to co ! CO i r " 1 i I i i o&gt; £ | C] ! i o i » i I 1 I rH : N I in ! &lt;M ! m I i n I I o MC&lt;ICJMNtOt-T)&gt;OsinoOOMr-l00050005tOMOOl-l eOeO«OD3rHi-l»-«»&lt;UJOOt-lOOmi-lrHOOt-iH«OU5000 NrHNM M rt" CO &lt; «' H H i-HN rtNNNci' M OmenoinooiootDinoicorHtDcorHeqaiNrHinrHO m t"t^-COOOCOONOeOrHt^rHC^05-^«c&lt;ICOin^rtOOO CO t^OStOCOi-^rHOS-^COCOtOt-OCOrH^Nr-lteoWt--^" in rH m ■* to o o 'J" ■* in ■*" m* cT co en co" o o ■*■*■* rH oo t-T e»i ■^coininmc^t-t-t-rH3^mc&lt;iincorHoo-^rH(x&gt;i^-^m cz ■*cocoin i: :i ■.- -; i-. :i :i ci - n n * to n m i-&lt; 00* CO I . I Illllilllllllllllllll If! I I I 1 I \ I I I .1 I -I I I I I I I .1 I I . J ■ i J « N K£lsllllllIlllgg|?IIISI "3 I </seg>
            <seg id="p114">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 111 g 7. s. 'm See x - - » is « 0 h « ©t-o i ! |«&gt;e^'*©comr-it- «r-»v » t- rHi-IN r 1 ■: I - i « US H O / ,. &lt;" V rt, 9 SIS 'Si 3J « H I £.££ M C. UJ « H :O N » irt t-H M H LO IN r-lrHrH^Hi-HN ■o rH CO W i-^ ?; | §11 P IBS w o a o o w o t- CO b- rH eg t-t-OOt» NNtOMlflNNHiH t- l-H fc 1 X -r t-oioo^fi-tcii-^tcm t« c. o h in » t SO f t- 1— ■M 3*X E-i o s I ■' 1— - 7. z 1 " ai y. 0 « i { s i ! M i is j ■ ' j M lIlilS«J||Ji : J^fclii|ii|f i X&lt; T. 5^ = " 1 T^4 ' * " J &lt;z r-l ! H » CO rt » N N ! ir-l i • T)&lt; © r-l ! i t- t- • ■*• i-l i • ■ : M IH ! 5i.b?Z = t- a: oo o t- 'o x » oo w k » a; &lt;!&lt;;&lt;iinBnfflfflacQBBoooooooooQQO </seg>
            <seg id="p115">112 &gt; 6 o~ a; ill COt-b-005 ICO'* I I ! U) CQ H « O |O 111) n « O Ul * id » t. o ■«&gt;&lt;© ! « n w « t&gt; :io ie-je-j^inm iHr-lrHrHiH i H H i ■ iiHrHrii-lr-l in _ _ _ _ _ I i i r I I t IH I -I |I 5 i O5 «&gt; U5 ! IA IO (0 kA H £ ! n n e h jMHN ! " ! ! Ui rH : X n M f m } 5 s si CaoOCDOCOi-&lt;rHOOt-©OOC^CO'*&lt; | n Ifl IA ! to 12 N OO li) i-l CO rH i-H f « f O « M ■ US'* tD M l» fe_ Nl « « n » |io«e«ifl«n«gn : ■- i - i - iot-r-ioor* n ffl f ! * « CO itOMrHlrHr-H COM •=2 3 302 ■ c 2 ococst-Or-iiniairsoot-ONb-i-icooi-iotecooNM COOOOS-^«;Dait^OOCOW)^*«OrHt"OOOOOlOOOOCOOOO 1° OMiawifMtcwNOJMoo^ojHwcfixtemn^ff)© eoooooia«oo3t-oococow«o co t« oo n m ce o t-o rH 7 ! rH h Mi i i i i i . i i ! • ! i ■ i i i i i • : ! i : i : I ! i i i i ; i r ; I : • ! : i i I I I I I I I I III tllllllli ill 1 I M I I i]l linn iiijiiii JiillliilllliitJilil ill • £oosS(,!;3i(iiijo°Si«ai*i(Sooo^ • I </seg>
            <seg id="p116">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 113 Slg rH |CS : t&gt; H » O S K |r- ': S~. O | IS Ifi 00 N » » « { CO :^* : CD IA CO CO U3 Q0 if"' ; n U3 i^lrtWCB^WCO rH jrH ItNrHrHi-HrH i H : rt H -rHrHrHrHrHrHiH • I I I |lOrH ! I Ul « H I- I H IO ! I H I rt t- « ! \ I-H ! ! j i ■ i i i i • ! i § 0 — — _ 3=S| rH CO « 5© N rH i ■ N ! i ! 00 | rH : rH t^ ! ! ! i I O 0 3&gt;ZC 5S=I t-«IHIlliI&gt;«OU)l- iU5O5 !t-eOU5^fiHtOOT(&gt;©iH© a i i xn &amp; o a 3 — "III «H(.M*MH»[- llH&lt;O I IS &lt;B M ID rt t- !rH©M© H n r-lrfOOrH It id*BN« :H»»M o II 3 111 z t _rHOSrHrHMCa00t--*'&lt;»'00«OMIrH.-HlOt-ina!00t--«t'© i-l I-H rH H rl 3 o a o 2 EH g 5 05 - u £.2 1° rH rH rH rH ' HI ri} i I 1 1 ■ i i i 1 IILI'lrlll It 1 1 11 II 1 il-II I I Nil 8 Mill I I I I I aSs-.lsJgg^tigl-E-gSgltfgjSfgSrJ 5g5^|§g§gg% i gsg§|§3gs5 a «-3 ! I </seg>
            <seg id="p117">114 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ■ -■&gt; I! o in I cc co ! rH rH I I h o « « is « ! m ! I lo | si oo o icocecocceqin ico ■ x | f o us irHrHrHrHrHrH IrH i ■ i i rt jrHi-HrH in © ©" rH 1 i I I H H « * H ffl I I IrH I irHcN | 1 i I I I i I I CO CO 1 to o M N I « u: h oo n us i- « I i f IS O 1O I rH in i I N © X S- CM j rH rH C4 © ih" B to r: » x 5 wzc 5 5 3i HNt-H«oon«Hb&gt;«&lt;oitoooa a te n o t- *00H*HHHrtM&lt;lHrtU) rH n N H « «O M » O H I oc~rHrHe*rHe4*&lt;o&gt;e&gt;cBioe&gt;*&lt;cooooecoe&gt;oeo oo rHrH I- « O » » rt H rH ID M N H fl U3 rH «&gt; Pi S o 2 Z IAH»nu3VAKONMO)H«a)Tl&lt;C4iacOAOO CO »wu&gt;NTHCOH»t-OON-ft-O»00MH Q» I-l iH t-4 iH rH r-l 00 I %4 r-l rH t-( rH ri i-l I i ! E ! M I I ill 1 1! 1 1 I MINI! 1 1 1 ! 1 1 1 i I [ 1 I I I I I i ! I I I i I 1 f I I I i 1§ L \li\ MM! llllliiliililllllllll i "3 «-» o I </seg>
            <seg id="p118">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 115 en as = - n u l. t-«O iNMt-r-1 |t-t- :n«IOISt-t-i&lt;t-NUi rHlH i H rt H H I I ir-lr-t | ir-liHrHC«i-liHTHiHiHrH I ! 1M00 IN It- | | | INMCSrt I I If It-lO rH rH i N . I I I i III" ill ■ 25-2 IterHiaooMOiOooo IH iH r-l N rH rH i I i i I i i i I rH © O5 rH rH PS I- rH i j ! IrH f rH w 0 SHoS «o&gt;«ciu:on«aiioHioiiiao«i«iof»x4HO N NrHCOrHrH rH rHCJfCQrH rHM N-* rH - P — T. - Bill n««Nrin««i&gt;OHoot&gt;t-oiHaHu)uMeiiiffi&lt;s t-t— CO rHrHOt-t— t"O» MNVIAIAnnHn 1-i Pi E a 2 2 mcooaoNt-aoiooeocimmtcaoaotoofi-ii-ir-it-us OOrHNeQMOOiat-t-COt-aiOSrHlOt-t-OSWOOOO^OOr-* rH rH rH rH cq rH O OD - o £.2 1° a0rH00e)C400iHiarH00eqc000t-e)lAOC-OOMOfU&gt; rH rH rH rH 94 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 f I ! I II II I ! II II II II II II I ! II I 1 r I I I I 1 I If I if 11 If Iff] Itlltilfililiilfi lift!] I i i I j i I I i I i i i I I I i I I II i I i i i ! i i i i ! ; i i ; ! i i M ! I i i fill diiJi iiliJlf i ] &lt;«!&lt;i(UBBBnBSBROOOUOOOOUPQa I g U </seg>
            <seg id="p119">116 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT m T. Ill Oi 3 e V Oooeaooo • | n i •- I I is te t- t- n ; 10 ■ to I ih oo ih us | | eo in : « B 1&gt; » ; ■*■ m : rH rH rH ; rH rH I CO CQ : &lt;o co i rH ih I &lt;M I ! : — i fl i — . ! N CO i i i ! ! ! 1 i : : ! j I IMH *H« . rH CO i i 1H ! lao^ce^eNwian ! « ■* M Cg rH rH I I N n e t- « o eo oo ! ** I i ■ H osMZc 5«sS r-lN rH NViaiaoOHHTIi I- CO O 3 OS a « I 2 «rt«««H«!K!n«Hffl«XH0&gt;»HfflOl»rtHN Nxc!Teeif-oo«i9KBH(-i-ei»«»on«5 rH rH rH rH C-J rH %4 - u coooooiotcosc-ooMteeoto e « a t- uit- o oo© rH rH rH 94 rH iiiMiMiiiin m i I i i'l i iJiiJiJiJiJiJJijiJiijJji QOQOO'ftfcfefcOOOOOOWIBIilWBKWIllh ! I &gt;■ </seg>
            <seg id="p120">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 117 so ■ x h &lt;- Cl i « «. N O r-l O I :om w : is o » &gt;i) t-. in : o e i-l ir-lrHNl-lrHi-l : j «H tH i O oo i co t- i i-t r-i us us : i CO t- O t^ : t-h r^ : I i H C4 H « M '• r* — — : I " "i I i ! « i i | : 1 ! ! ! ! Ijll 1 "! I t i i I 1 H ■* M in N fCOC^OON I H I II ■ O CO CO | i-( i r^ ■ H o gljZc rt»H«NNH*H*«Mt-t.eoi-no lAeqeor-ir-itccomi-i eq h eq « id n ! ■*!&lt; CO O CO r-l i M 1O M rl M o - ■/. - •*fwcoiot~es©cot*-oowcoot~c£&gt;cot-«c CJCOi-i l— I U3 O W W W r-l -«f -(f CO t— r-t : 'C o f oo oo i N rt 11) to n Pi S u 2 i-* iH i-t ,_, 4-1 |5 E.2 3D 2 rH r-t r-l ,_, I 1 | I I I || || || || || | || | || |! I I I I | I- i I I I I I I i | I t { I I I I 1 --I I I I 1 I I 1 i i I i I j I I I I I I I i I j I 1 1 U I I J I I I i I I I ! 1 1 i I 1 1 I 1 1 fSmjilfjiifi jii iffliJ z D 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">118 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT e "3 ■ a C- 2+j a) jlO I CO CO t-h tH O C5 -fl- i iOrH &gt; a N » » O « |CO i (• t« t- IO t- « » ;COLA : U3 t* V CO CD i H ! ri rid HHH ri i iiHiH ; ,— ,-, ,— _ _ jeo | I {HHHHWrt « | t- ! h |eo ! 11 til III; to SsSg o n t- CO C4 ! i « &gt;«• I eo ■»• b- so io ■* I ■♦ eo to ! *" rt InoH co rH IO i T-t iH I- • *N*«H»rl«o)«fflXHM ! » t- S V « e 00 CO 00 |H CM HHHMNri CO !nu)H COH IO O &lt;M o ~ on 4) 001»M1"ON«MN[. I^IO ! oo t- D O * IO © rt rt meomeot-N-* i« ! « us t- m h » io : : eq eo z •oocqiHiocoooocqooTtiooi-icMt-inootaoot-- us tCHt0S»Ht-01rit-M0ONfM0»»fO U5 " t-t iH rH tH tH to o 2 S2!J2^f ocot ~ c&gt; ' HO '* t ~ r ~ NIO '* &lt; »'*'- |eo 'M ■* •H IH iH rH rH CM II r ! ! ! i S I II ! | ! ! I i ! ! I • 1 Mi! ji|| I |l|lll ! s ! i I I l IS X </seg>
            <seg id="p122">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 119 CENSUS ENROLLMENT 1919 . Children Children Subject to Subject to Compulsory COUNTY Census Compulsory Education Enrollment Education Meeting Ke- quirementa 1 Adams — 6,875 4,249 3,142 2,166 4,883 3,867 Antelope. _ , 5,319 3,066 Arthur. 1 491 232 3,066 Arthur- 153 375 Banner 508 303 190 346 Blaine 678 385 308 516 Boone .-. 4,686 3,172 2,151 3,634 Box Butte — 2,366 1,561 1,380 2,062 Boyd 2,947 1,855 1,263 2,549 Brown 2,199 1,259 834 1,391 Buffalo _ 7,017 I 4,343 3,393 5,486 Burt 4,008 2,613 2,279 2,689 3,644 Butler 4,864 3,140 3,670 Cass.._ _ 5,906 3,888 3,261 2,961 4,523 Cedar 5,845 3,576 Chase 1,513 995 4,200 796 1,205 Cherry _ 3,673 2,268 Cheyenne 2,748 1,779 992 2,785 1,757 2,329 Clay 4,612 3,022 2,956 3,862 Colfax.. 4,069 2,190 1,827 3,090 Cuming _._ J 4,545 2,604 1,785 2,512 Custer 8,420 5,296 4,877 7,362 Dakota _ _ 2,322 1,297 969 1,578 I 1,823 Dawes _ 2,882 1,810 2,032 Dawson 4,916 3,323 2,842 4,193 Deuel 946 I 569 108 783 Dixon — 4,150 2,622 2,102 3,419 3,482 5,371 Dodge — 7,270 4,023 Douglas 46,874 28,244 20,648 34,629 Dundy 1,629 969 533 1,319 Fillmore 4,231 2,664 2,364 3,376 Franklin 3,308 I 1,917 1,736 2,450 Frontier 2,883 1,919 1,195 2,140 Furnas 3,761 2,431 2,264 3,265 Gage 8,996 5,739 5,020 6,846 Garden 1 470 i mt 927 1,129 Garfleld 1,194 774 613 1,047 1,090 Gosper 1,545 770 528 230 G rant 437 276 426 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">120 REPORT OP STATE SUPERINTENDENT CENSUS ENROLLMENT— 1919 COUNTY Census Children Subject to Compulsory Education Children Subject to Compulsory Education Meeting Re- quirements Enrollment Greeley 2,955 1,680 3,989 1,453 3,602 2,321 5,465 Hall 6.646 Hamilton Harlan 4,162 3,184 2,578 2,172 3,346 1,899 1,538 2,435 Ha.es Hitchcock 1,078 Holt 2,011 5,701 1,208 3,496 1,216 2,716 1,675 4,504 Hooker 430 311 342 375 Howard Jefferson 3,861 5,213 3,101 2,248 3,140 1,932 1,718 2,584 2,758 4,027 Johnson 1,605 2,467 2,047 Kearney 2,694 1,401 1,294 Keith 1,622 1,164 924 1,329 898 Keya Paha r Kimball 1,182 1,549 6,702 803 893 536 846 1,009 4,572 Knox 4,227 13,312 3,085 Lancaster— - Lincoln 22,466 6,315 12,710 3,482 18,663 4,098 391 4,831 Logan 679 341 Loup . 760 519 383 639 McPherson 607 355 165 406 Madison 7,100 4,355 2,578 3,941 2,217 5,308 Merrick Morrill 3,466 2,773 2,202 2,439 Nance 3,041 2,943 1,814 1,253 1,556 2,436 1,576 Nemaha 4,127 2,122 2,243 2,947 1,809 3,178 Nuckolls 4,155 6,138 3,266 1,268 2,726 2,597 3,689 2,205 3,439 Otoe Pawnee i 4,226 2,525 Perkins _. 656 584 1,037 2,085 Phelps 1,589 1,315 Pierce 3,967 2,603 1.737 2,775 3,557 2,723 2,885 4,668 Platte 7,052 3,269 3,578 6,139 1,221 3,989 2,427 Polk 1,908 1,659 Red Willow 2,453 3,553 1,326 3,024 Richardson ■p «, 680 516 916 Sallne I ' ' 3,212 3,119 4,257 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 121 CENSUS ENROLLMENT —1919 Children Children Subject to Subject to Compulsory COUNTY Census Compulsory j Education Enrollment Education Meeting Re- quirements Sarpy... 2,849 1,786 1,532 2,232 Saunders. 6,616 4,283 3,672 5,111 Scotts Bluff... Seward 7,078 3,262 3,112 5,557 5,170 3,261 2,441 3,615 Sheridan.. Sherman.. Sioux 2,899 1,887 1,522 2,757 3,859 2,470 1.7U7 2,809 1,558 987 703 1,171 Stanton Thayer _ Thomas Thurston.. Valley 2,759 1,829 2,894 1,401 2,165 2,202 4,624 3,348 516 340 84 420 3,025 1,890 1,544 2,501 3,165 2,052 1.326 2,804 Washington.. Wayne 4,175 2,590 2,248 3,096 3,383 2,038 1,490 2,747 Webster... Wheeler- York 3,605 2,122 1,887 2,903 955 618 451 684 5,156 3,273 3,101 4,146 Total.. 395,236 241,285 195,239 302,975 CENSUS ENROLLMENT— 1920 Children Children Subject to Subject to Compulsory COUNTY Census Compulsory I Education | Enrollment Education | Meeting Re- quirements Adams Antelope- Arthur Banner Blaine 6,503 4,222 3,505 2,735 5,027 4,152 4,975 3,120 470 168 42 331 249 I 477 338 418 587 408 295 474 Boone.. 4,870 3,209 2,475 ::,74S Box Butte.. Boyd 2,686 1,953 3,089 2,053 1,536 2,336 1,218 2,511 Brown.. 2,348 912 586 1,978 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">122 iLLMENT— 1920 COUNTY Census Children Subject t&lt;i Compulsory Education Children Subject to Compulsory Education Meeting Re- quirements Enrollment Buffalo 7,066 4,483 2,792 3,118 3,790 5,776 3,580 =EEE 4,042 4,791 5,745 2,460 2,652 3,562 4,694 4,361 3,753 3,816 5,724 1,503 3,629 3,409 1,022 948 1,311 Cherry 3,381 2,748 2,089 1,179 3,059 Cheyenne 1,828 1,529 2,381 3,892 Clay Coif ax 4,506 3,908 4,474 8,248 3,047 2,859 2,327 2,065 2,251 3,051 C u m in g. 2,616 2,704 6,319 Custer 5,541 1,549 3,645 Dakota 2,532 2,742 4,908 1,195 1,853 Dawes 2,150 1,681 2,159 Dawson 3,187 2,916 4,315 Deuel 987 771 819 886 Dixon 3,927 7,148 48,110 2,550 2,196 3,814 3,190 Dodge Douglas Dundy 4,508 28,808 1,031 22,504 5,396 36,651 1,664 900 2,566 1,418 Fillmore 4,061 3,200 2,898 2,501 2,205 3,347 Franklin _ _ 1,237 1,996 Frontier 1,956 1,415 2,224 3,349 7,294 Furnas .. 3,670 8,894 2,390 5,506 2,246 Garden 5,203 1,487 1,181 1,583 1,007 939 1,251 Garfield 807 680 1,036 Gosper 967 689 1,143 Grant 415 385. 364 373 Gr^y 2,977 6,691 4,119 2,997 1,756 1,488 3,919 2,325 Hamilton 4,183 2,814 5,560 3,423 2,674 773 2,381 Harlan 1,999 1,924 xiciyes . .. 885 657 642 Hitchcock 2,060 5,841 1,341 3,741 1,219 1,803 Holt 3,093 4,379 Hooker 397 242 332 397 Howard 4,017 2,400 1,716 2,838 4,000 3,364 2,107 1,719 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 123 CENSUS ENROLLMENT '—1920 Children Children Subject to Subject to Compulsory COTJNTY Census Compulsory Education Enrollment Meeting Re- Education quirements Johnson.. Kearney_. Keith 2,981 1,825 1,781 1,763 2,577 1,475 2,160 2,608 2,160 1,605 988 876 1,448 591 970 Keya Paha... Kimball- 1,158 703 970 1,705 1,174 1,043 1,162 Knox 6,778 4,635 3,438 5,231 13,905 18,916 Lancaster... Lincoln 24,033 6,677 15,184 18,916 4,192 3,687 5,207 Logan_. Loup 671 511 404 574 517 462 601 Madison.. 4,549 3,899 5,575 244 375 McPherson.. Merrick 375 375 2,401 2,325 2,710 1,834 2,738 Morrill Nance Nemaha... Nuckolls.. Otoe 2,152 2,738 1,754 1,574 2,403 2,248 3,156 2,562 3,156 2,597 2,283 3,414 3,623 3,341 4,548 Pawnee... Perkins... Phelps..... Pierce Platte Polk 2,042 1,870 2,623 728 645 844 1,723 1,555 2,029 2,517 1,847 2,852 3,021 2,582 3,411 1,976 1,872 2,555 Red Willow- Richardson... Rock 2,459 2,361 2,968 3,222 4,985 3,977 4,985 751 562 915 Saline... Sarpy.... 3,226 3,208 4,219 1,900 2,526 2,105 3,814 5,077 Saunders... 4,291 5,077 Scotts Bluff... Seward 5,610 3,947 6,894 3,250 2,930 3,863 Sheridan.. Sherman- Sioux 2,024 1,453 2,669 2,080 1,667 2,512 1,052 832 1,219 Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston.. 1,595 1,402 2,156 2,199 3,407 2,820 3,407 60 164 174 1,826 1,696 2,610 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">124 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 3,316 2,053 1,702 2,997 Valley. Washington 4,020 2,647 2,220 2,307 Wayne 3,445 2,140 1,718 3,047 Webster.. 3,374 2,140 2,045 2,769 Wheeler... 841 647 552 686 3,181 4,292 York 5,232 3,461 Total 392,592 250,689 211,101 311,821 VOCATIONAL SCHOOLS UNDER THE SMITH-HUGHES ACT Reimbursements to Schools for Bieiinium. Home I Trade and School District [ Agriculture I Economics I Industries Total $ 240.931 Alliance ? $ 1$ 240.93 894.39 894.39 Arlington... 779.62 J 779.62 Ashland 1,110.93 610.30 1,721.23 Auburn... 1,065.00 1,065.00 Aurora 1,181.25 1,181.25 •Barnston 618.75 618.75 Bayard-. Beatrice Blair 337.50 Bloomfield *Bratton-Union 1,575.00 Broken Bow 1,237.50 Cambridge 1,168.75 Chad ron Ely Center 1 , 2 37 . 5 0 leridge 1,125.00 vid City, * Eagle Edgar Exeter Fairbury 1,237.50 1,237.50 1,781.25 2,046.35 Fairfleld 1,031.25 750.00 843.74 " * " </seg>
            <seg id="p128">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 125 VOCATIONAL SCHOOLS UNDER THE SMITH-HUGHES ACT — Continued Home I Trade and School DUtrlct | Agriculture I Economics I Industries Total Franklin 1,606.251 , I 1,606.25" Friend. 1.181.25J 712.50 j 1,893.75 Geneva 1,125.00 675.00 742.50 746.25 1,800.00 Gering... 742.50 746.25 •Giltner... xGarden Co. H. S. Grand Island Gresham.. Hastings 300.00 330. 00J 472. 50| 630.00 Havelock.. 556.86 1,029.36 •Holmesville.. xHooker Co. 1,275.00 1,275.00 Kearney Kearney... 712.50 | 712.50 712.50 xKeya Paha Co 1,102.50 xKeya Paha Co 1,102.50 | 1,102.50 xKimball County 1,812.17 562.50 I 2,374.67 562.50 •Lake Alice... Laurel 1,237.50 750.00 1,987.50 •Lewellen Lexington- Lincoln 108. 00J 108.00 xLogan County 1,237.50 975.00 582.18 843.74 810.00 375.00 450.00 900.00 337.50 2,212.50 Lyons... 582.18 843.74 810.00 Madison... Milford •Milligan 1,237.50 1,612.50 McCook... 450.00 • Nehawka 1,634.40 2,534.40 Newman Grove Oakland 337.50 Omaha... Ord ll.549.46j 11,549.46 xPerkins County... •Phillips... 590.62 506.25 590.62 506.25 Plattsmouth.. •Ragan... Randolph 350.31 350.31 337.50 xRock County.. 337.50 650.00 Scottsbluff _ 1,837.50 2,487.50 Seward... _| Stapleton 1,237.50 901.00 578.56 2,138.50 1,759.81 Stromsburg 1,181.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">Steele City 403.13 ♦Sunflower Tecuniseh 1,237.50 500.00 375.00 375.00 703.12 582.15 727.50 Tekam ah 1,237.50 •Union Center 1,012.53 University Place... •Virginia 1,203.11 Waltnill 1,215.00 •Waverly... Weeping Water... Wisner York 618.75 •Consolidated schools. xCounty high schools. Note: Amounts given above due February 1, 1921. will be increased by reimbursements THIS YEAR Agriculture Day Schools 3 8 Home Economics Day Schools- _ 63 Day Trade Schools. _ _ 1 Numerous evening and part-time classes. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">127 OP to i E 9 .-4 « IA * OH I X 1-1 "+- 2 C5 00 V m O us 4- | jl"! &gt; a d 1 M 1-) SO — H • CO N IA CO M 4— 0) 1 0 CO U5 00 M | W M sa -1 ip ■o si 5 :C1 us o co oa us * CO * US t- t- 4- 3 0 W OS U3 r- IA US M US * T-t IA CO US H , - i OS L 4-1 ill Q a N c: — — - r: — A CO 00 US M — OS • t- • O r-i OS 4- ■ 1 lO CO t— U5 N H CO t- eo us 4- 3 ■— c I i 0) &lt; — -r I ■»r I-l n c . o &amp; 1 : i Illll OWO Z H s I .&lt;! CO CO CO H us m cm ; US OO N CO e at O 3 o o ■ p o d ° § i ■_ ! ] CO US o H i i-l t- — s 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">128 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT STATISTICAL TABLE II I I II I II 4 || 12 I G5 11 8 54 8 25 3 2 S-6 |j 28 49 27 46 [ .... 44 7 3 7-10 jj 39 5 36 4 40 9 3 llormorejj 29 29 25 8 Total 1 1 108 | 119 11 |] 100 I 104 8 1 134 27 8 •In Private and Parochial Schools. tDoes not include cost of inspection. Number H. S. Teachers Number Schools accredited to Uni. Accredited Schools offering Normal Training in r No. Accredited Nor. Tr. &amp; Smith- Hughes Schools t, = 7-10 A 10 29 39 21 B 75 37 5 I I I I I C 5 I I I i 8 29 39 21 I I H. E. Ag. 66 4 31 5 I 39 49 39 19 I Grade jGrade 11 12 .... | 3 1 1 1 2 11 or more .... | .... Total 99 | 117 I 5 97 | 102 I 4 | 146 2 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 129 19 i c - - z W No. com- pleting Nor. Tr. • a II O t, &lt;U tj O °! &lt;; Average No. completing Nor. Tr. U ill u c c oi.x c Hi 4— fPer Capita Cos if All Schools Had Received State Aid I I 11 | 12 | Grade IGr'de I 1,041 295 | 361 1,122 342 I 443 1,081 271 | 418 5X7 139 | 183 •15« | *52 I I 1 13 18 24 28 | '13 4 5 6 7 I 4 7 9 10 I I | $13.11 15.28 12.62 11.32 I I $37.81 38.71 31.46 36.33 Seniors Enroll- Com- ment pleting- $26.22 $75.62 18.71 47.40 14.24 36.84 12.52 40.1fi $17.47 $47.70 I I *4 II I 3,987 1,047 1,457 I 19 S I 7 | $12.81 I | $35.07 I 939 363 367 j 13 1,067 426 448 I 14 813 337 319 | 20 760 295 303 | 26 *159 *44 '81 | »17 3,738 1,465 1,518 19 — ! — il II 5 6 8 10 •5 7 5 6 8 10 •9 8 $13.31 $34.06 $37.27 $95.33 26.61 49.10 34.20 81.47 24.60 62.69 24.60 62.69 16.44 41,25 | 19.07 47.85 -I | || $17.92 | $44.79 $28.62 $69.82 II i </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>