<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00063.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00063.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska for 1927-1928</title>
               <date value="1929-01-01">1929-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For 1927-1928 i </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1929. From: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. To: His Excellency, Arthur J. Weaver, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska, Subject: Biennial Report of 1927 and 1928. 1. In compliance with the requirements of Section No. 3305, Chapter 34, article 1, revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1922, the follow - ing Biennial Report for the calendar years 1927 and 1928 is respect - fully submitted. 2. During the past two years, the National Guard of Nebraska has reached a high standard of efficiency and in its development has made most gratifying progress. Each year, training has materially improved and in a logical and progressive manner. The community interest in our units and the moral assistance of committees of Chambers of Commerce in the cities where the units are located, as well as many where no troops are stationed, has been most helpful. 3. The character of supply and equipment is not altogether satis - factory as we are still using war time stock and the uniforms, in my opinion, should be classed as shoddy; however, the Federal Gov - ernment has promised us new uniforms for our enlisted men in 1930 and I am sure these will prove most beneficial. The ordnance is of the best and since the Federal Government has allowed us caretakers in the form of motor mechanics, all trucks have been placed in the best condition possible, and notwithstanding the fact that they were issued from the World War supply, are considered serviceable in case of an emergency. 4. By virtue of the National Defense Act and Miltia Bureau regulations, the Adjutant General of Nebraska, under the direction of the Governor, is required to execute the approved policies of the War Department as well as the laws of Nebraska in so far as applic - able to the National Guard. In addition to this, records of veterans </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3 of the Civil War, Spanish American War and World War are kept in this office and we are daily called upon for certified copies of these records. A complete record of all Federal property issued to the National Guard, as well as all funds allotted to the State, is also kept in this office. The amount of property accounted for, and now in the State, is over a million dollars in value and the aanoscf'~disburse - ment from Federal funds is something over five hundred thousand dollars; this in addition to the training programs required, supervision of training of the National Guard units during their armory drills and being in charge of the annual field training, gives some idea of the work performed by this office, and is handled by total personnel of six, which is much less than most States with a like number of units employ. CAMP ASHLAND Additional improvement has been made at this camp site by the Federal Government including a permanent kitchen and mess hall for each company, two kitchens and mess halls for officers, an admin - istration building, and contracts have now been let for supply houses. OTHER FUXDS Since the passage of the act by the last session of the legislature, making it possible for the Governor of the State to receive from the Federal Government monies taken from the Nebraska units during the World War which were known as "other funds", the Government has returned to the reconstituted units of Nebraska approximately |30,000. Every unit in Nebraska voted to return these funds to the Adjutant General of Nebraska, as trustee, to be used in the con - struction of a memorial building at Ashland, which will be used as a welfare building and recreation hall; this building will be in memory of the veterans of the World War who created the fund, thereby mak - ing it possible to have it returned to the present organizations. IXSPKCTIOXS Annual armory inspections are made by Officers of the United States Army detailed for that purpose. The results of our last armory inspections evidenced close conformity to schedules and gave the Ne - braska National Guard a very satisfactory rating. ARMORIES As reported before, the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Nebraska National Guard have to contend is the rental of armories. It is almost impossible to rent suitable buildings </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL at reasonable rentals for armories for the National Guard units which .give adequate protection to Government property that the State is required to protect, and, at the same time, have ample space for armory drills and training. In this regard, Nebraska is behind many of the other States who have constructed armories and the State is frequently criticized by in - spectors on this account. It will be much cheaper in the long run for the State to construct its own armories and we expect to intro - duce a constructional program in the near future which we hope our legislature will give favorable consideration. UNITED STATES ARMY OFFICERS AND SERGEANT INSTRUCTORS DETAILED TO THE STATE The following is a list of United States Army Officers and Sergeant instructors who are detailed by the War Department to the State of Nebraska for instructional purposes and who render very valuable service and have done much to assist in placing the Nebraska National Guard at its present high standing among the other States ot the union. Lt. Col. Morris M. Keck, Inf. DOL., Lincoln, Nebr. Major Emil H. Burgher, MC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebr. Capt. McGregor Snodgrass, QMC. DOL., Lincoln, Nebr. Capt. Leo J. Farrell, Inf. DOL., Omaha, Nebr. Master Sgt. Lee R. G. Ward, Inf. DEML., Omaha, Nebr. Sergeant Emet G. Roach, Inf. DEML., Lincoln, Nebr. Sergeant Zack Scarborough, MC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebr. Sergeant Hjalmar Strom, QMC. DEML., Lincoln, Nebr. ARMORY DRILL Armory drill attendance has shown a steady increase during the past year and has exceeded the expectations of both the State and Federal authorities. Assemblies are held each week on regular sched - ule for each unit. Programs are prepared by regimental and bat - talion commanders and schedules are submitted in advance covering the detail instruction given. Under the United States laws, each officer and enlisted man is allowed a day's pay by the Federal govern - ment for each drill attended. Attendance is mandatory and penalties are provided for non-performance. CONCLUSION In conclusion I wish to express my appreciation to the officers and enlisted men of the National Guard, and to the officers and non- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5 'Commissioned officers of the regular army, who have, through their hearty cooperation, assisted in bringing the Nebraska National Guard to its present high state of efficiency and the personnel thereof to a much higher standard. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. FINANCIAL STATEMENT, NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OP JANUARY 1, 1929. Total Appropriations Warrants Drawn Balance Support — $175,000.00 $125,424.25 $49,575.75 STRENGTH BY COMPANY AND DETACHMENT OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OF DECEMBER 1, 1928. 134th Infantry Enl. War. Officers Men Officers State Staff &amp; State Det 7 21 Regtl. Hq. &amp; Regtl. Hq. Co 9 57 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 1st Bn 3 22 Company A 3 63 Company B 2 62 Company C 3 62 Company D 3 61 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 2d Bn 3 25 Company E 3 62 Company F 3 64 Company G 3 63 Company H 3 63 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 3d Bn 3 23 Company I 3 63 Company K 2 59 Company L 3 58 Company M 3 62 Service Company 4 '90 1 Howitzer Company 3 55 Medical Dept. Detachment 5 31 71 1066 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 6 85th Division Train, Q. M. C. Hq. &amp; Hq. Det 3 12 137th Motor Transport Co 2 42 138th Motor Transport Co 2 45 119th Motor Repair Section 1 20 119th Wagon Company 3 51 120th Wagon Company 3 51 Medical Dept. Detachment 2 15 16 236 110th Medical Regiment Hq. Staff 5 Service Company 4 31 Band Section 23 1 130th Ambulance Co 2 45 166th Hospital Co 5 60 110th Veterinary Co 2 37 130th Collecting Co 1 62 Division Surgeon's Off 3 7 22 265 1 Grand Total 109 Officers 1567 Enlisted Men 2 Warrant Officers STATE STAFF AND STATE DETACHMENT Name, Rank, arm of service or Corps. Official Mail Address Paul, H. J., Brig. Gen. A. G. D., State Capitol, Lincoln. Stein, H. C, Major Q. M. C, State Capitol, Lincoln. McConnaughey, W. E., Major Q. M. C, State Capitol, Lincoln. O'Connell, Frank B., Major A. G. D., State Capitol, (Dept. Agri. ) Potter, Herbert M., Capt. Ord., 910 North 11th St., Beatrice. Yoder, Byron E., Capt., Q. M. C, 1901 Sumner St., Lincoln. Stout, Richard F., Major, J. A. G., 722 Stewart Bldg., Lincoln. 35th Division Train Q. M. C. Headquarters Poteet, Marcus L., Major Q. M. C, 807 Terminal Bldg., Lincoln Williams, Claude J., 1st Lt. Q. M. C, 3325 South St., Lincoln. Blodgett, M. A., 2nd Lt. Q. M. C, 661 South 26th St., Omaha 187th Mot. Tr. Co. Ellis, Harry H., 1st Lt. Q. M. C, Holdrege. Leffler, Delbert C, 2nd Lt., Holdrege. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7 138th Mot. Tr. Co. Olson, Nels Arthur, 1st Lt. Q. M. C, 537% No. Broad St., Fremont C, 240 East 1st St., Fremont. Yakish, Wesley H., 2nd Lt. Q M 119th Mot. Rep. Sec. Chadderdon, Lester E.. 1st Lt. Q M. C, 501 West Ave., Holdrege. 110th Wagon Co. Hovis, Victor M., Capt. Q. M. C. 515 Washington St., Lexington. Neff, B. Clarence, 1st Lt. Q. M. C, Lexington. Parsons, Orval C, 2nd Lt. Q. M. C, Lexington 120th Wagon Co. Henninger, Guy N., Capt. Q. M. Atkinson, William J., 1st Lt. Q. Mattson, Herman M., 2nd Lt. Q. C, Court House, Kearney. M. C, 1925 — 5th Ave., Kearney. M. C, Kearney. Med. Dept. Det. Rose, Wallace E., Capt. M. C, Kearney Phillips, Ross M., Capt. V. C, Kearney. HEADQUARTERS, 184th IXF. Thomas, Amos, Colonel Inf., 824 Omaha Nat. Bank Bldg., Omaha. Douglas, Robert G., Lt. Col. Inf., Capitol Bldg., Lincoln. Fisher, Edwin D., Maj. Inf. 1st Bn., Box 193, Falls City, Nebr. McCormick, Clyde E., Maj. Inf., M. G. O., 808 So. 59th St., Omaha, Grasborg, Bert C, Maj. Inf. 2nd Bn., 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha, Cline, Earl M., Maj. Inf. 3rd Bn., 703 1st Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln Tukey, Allan A., Capt., Inf. Adj., 613 Peters Trust Bldg., Omaha. Capsey, Harold C, Capt. (Chap), Box 585, Geneva. Utterback, Wm. G., Capt. Inf. (Regt. Sup. Oft.) Box 452, Neb. City, Thornton, Thomas Q., Capt. Inf. P. &amp; T. Off., 604 Mer. Bank Bldg., Omaha. Headquarters Co. Wilson, Howard R., 2nd Lt. Inf., 101 Telephone Bldg., Omaha. Service Co, Beckley, Harry A., 1st Lt. Inf., 613 Grant Ave., York Myers, Clarence, 1st Lt. Inf., 51 Platte Ave., York. Payne, Joy O., Warrant Officer, York. Anderson, Raymond J., 2nd Lt., 415 W. 7th St., York, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Howitzer Co. Allison, J. Ned. Capt. Inf., Box 618, Gering. Nelson, John Fred, 1st Lt. Inf., 1865 — 12th St., Gering, Hinze, Alfred F., 1st Lt. Inf., Gering. Laughlin, Leslie J., 2nd Lt., Gering. Hq. Co. 1st Bn. Yager, Leslie Jr., 1st Lt., 116 Fourth Ave., Nebr. City. Sharrar, Clyde M., 2nd Lt., Nebr. City. Hq. Co. 2nd Bn. Davis, Guy T., 1st Lt. Inf., 4413 Leavenworth, Omaha. Crocker, Judd William, 2nd Lt., 2423 Manderson St., Omaha. Hq. Co. 3rd Bn. Gillaspie, Trev. E., 1st Lt. Inf., Post Office, Lincoln. Dier, Clifford L., 2nd Lt. Inf., 2036 Holdrege, Lincoln Co. A. Thurman, Ray A., Capt. Inf., 5th &amp; 3rd Ave., Nebr. City. Spinner, Richard C, 1st Lt. Inf., 1206 Second Corso, Nebr. City. Shinn, George H., 2nd Lt. Inf., 605 — 4th Ave., Nebr. City. Co. B Schneider, Wm. P., Capt., 506 West 20th St., Falls City. Myers, Mervan F., 1st Lt., 16th &amp; Dewey Sts., Falls City. Co. C Stoll, Fred H., Capt. Inf., 915 North 12th St., Beatrice. Coonley, Dean, 1st Lt. Inf., 109 South Sunnier St., Beatrice. Collier, Harold LeRoy, 2nd Lt. Inf., 2nd &amp; Market Sts., Beatrice Co. I) Miltonberger, Butler B., Capt. Inf., 1202 No. Locust St., No. Platte Petersen, Fred C, 1st Lt. Inf., 1018 West 3rd St., North Platte. Mills, Milton Wright, 2nd Lt. Inf., 9 So. Maple St., North Platte. Co. E Stone, Fred W., Capt. Inf., Scottsbluff, Eatwell, Ora Albert, 1st Lt. Inf., 2121 D Ave., Scottsbluff. Reubel, Herman F., 2nd Lt. Inf., 1224 — 4th Ave., Scottsbluff. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 9 Co. F Eby, Louis R., Capt. Inf., Post Office Bldg., Hartington. Lang, Carl M., 1st Lt. Inf., Hartington. LaRue, Wayne A., 2nd Lt. Inf., Hartington, Co. G Rieber, Alexander, Capt. Inf., 827 No. Briggs Ave., Hastings. Riley, Ivan C, 1st Lt. Inf., Hastings State Bank, Hastings. VanFleet, Robert J., 2nd Lt. Inf., 315 Saunders Ave., Hastings. Co. H Miller, Aca F., Capt. Inf., 118 W. 14th St., Grand Island. James, Percy Floyd, 1st Lt. Inf., 104 W. Black St., Grand Island. McElroy, Francis L., 2nd Lt. Inf., 912 W. 1st St., Grand Island. Co. I Hoke, Edwin F., Capt. Inf., Post Office Bldg., Lincoln. VanKirk, Rolla C, 1st Lt. Inf., 802 First Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln, Stewart, Clarence J., 2nd Lt. Inf., 2535 South 10th St., Lincoln. Co. K Frimann, Claude T., Capt. Inf., 507 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha. Peterson, Emil B., 1st Lt. Inf., 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha. Co. L Elsasser, H. F., Capt. Inf., 3708 North 21st St., Omaha. Thomsen, Alfred 1st Lt. Inf., 2028 No. 65 Ave., Omaha. Welpton, John B., 2nd Lt. Inf., 3264 Francis St., Omaha. Co. M Geesen, Edward J., Capt. Inf., 641 Seward St., Seward, Campbell, Chas. H., 1st Lt. Inf., Box 416, Seward. Morton, Abraham F., 2nd Lt. Inf., Seward. Moil. Dept. Dot. Ensor, Rolland R., Major M. C, Box 83, South Side, Omaha. Achenbach, William H., Capt. D. C, 1000 Central Ave., Nebr. City. Attwood, Norman H., Capt. M. C, 813 Med. Arts Bldg., Omaha. Whitcomb, Glenn D., Capt. M. C, 926 Med. Arts Bldg., Omaha. Gerrie, Wallace A., Capt. M. C, 428 Aquila Court, Omaha. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 10 110th MEDICAL REGIMENT Headquarters Hilton, David C, Col. M. C, 305 Richards Block, Lincoln. Bartholomew, Philip H., Lt. Col. M. C, 1244 So. 25th St., Lincoln Evans, J. North, Major, M. C. Pollock Bldg., Columbus. Deppen, Earl N., Capt. M. C, A. D. J., 911 Sec. Mutual Bldg. Lincoln. Leonard, John Chester, Capt. Chaplains Corps, 2626 Central Ave. Kearney. Service Co. Ball, Harry R., Capt. M. A. C. Stearns, Harry A., Capt. M. A Hancock, Ernest W., Capt. M. 1120 N St., Lincoln. Ci c/o Post Office, Lincoln. C, 1021 Sharp Bldg., Lincoln. Strickland, Henry H., 1st Lt. M. A. C, 709 South 29th St., Lincoln Havlicek, Lumir C, Warrant Officer, (Band Sec.) Crete. 166th Hospital Co. Matthai, Jay Henry, Capt. M. C Johnston, Leonard Ray, Capt. D Johnson, Rodney K., Capt. M. C Wells, Francis A., Capt. M. C, i Stone, Ralph L., 1st Lt. M. A. C. Eisler, Herbert M., Capt. M. C. C, Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln. D. C, 1924 Perkins Blvd., Lincoln C., Friend. 826 Sharp Bldg., Lincoln. ., 3226 Dudley St., Lincoln. !., 2312 Washington St., Lincoln. 180th Ambulance Co. Swanson, Leonard A., Capt. M C, 412 North Hastings Ave. Hastings. Smith, Joseph W., 1st Lt. M. A C, 937 So. Denver St., Hastings. llOth Veterinary Co. Alford S. W., Capt. V. C, 1325 North 37th St., Lincoln. Skidmore, Louis V., 1st Lt. V. C, 3859 Dudley, Lincoln 130th CollectinK Co. Evans, Carroll D., Jr., Capt. M. C, Pollock Bldg., Columbus. Dot. Med. Dept. 35 Div.. (D. S. O.) Brooks, Earl B., Major M. C, 705 First Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln Bennett, John R., Major D. C, 214 Sec. Mut. Bldg., Lincoln. Norden, Carl J., Major V. C, 227 North 9th St., Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1927. General Orders, No. 1. 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1927, to December 31, 1927. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 3, 1927. General Orders, No. 2. 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Monday, May 30, 1927, con - secrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the Ameri - can Republic, the National, flag will, in accordance with paragraph 449 of the Regulations for the United States Army be displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist in the observance of the day by Veteran organizations, Commanding Officers of organ - izations not in the Federal service will place their respective com - mands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 8, 1927. General Orders, No. 3. 1. Pursuant to authority granted In MB 354.1 Nebr. -16, April 22 r 1927, being Training Authority No. 43-1, together with Change No. 1, June 23, 1927, and Change No. 2, July 1, 1927, thereof, the State Staff Corps and Departments, 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, and the 110th Medical Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 8 to 22, 1927, inclusive, under command of Colonel Herbert J.. Paul, Adjutant General's Department, State Staff Corps and Departments, and upon completion of this tour of duty, the above named organizations will be returned to their home stations. 2. The following named organizations and detachments will re - port at their earliest possible moment on August 6, 1927, taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff Corps and Depart - ment consisting of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, A. G. D.; Major H. C. Stein, QMC; Captain W. E. McConnaughey, QMC; and eighteen enlist - ed men. Service Detachment of the Service Co., 134th Infantry, con - sisting of one 1st Lieutenant and sixteen enlisted men. Telephone De - tachment of Regimental Headquarters Company, 134th Inf., 2nd Lieu - tenant, one Sergeant and three enlisted men. Headquarters Detach - ment, 35th Division Train consisting of one 2nd Lieutenant and twelve enlisted men; and the Service Detachment, Service Co., 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain S. O. and twelve enlisted men. They will form an advance Detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to the Commanding Officer, Ashland, Nebraska, August 6, 1927. Major H. C. Stein, QMC, is designated Camp Supply Officer. 3. Upon arrival in camp August 6, 1927, Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134th Infantry, will immediately establish mess for all advance troops and will see that at least one regular cook is Included in the Service Detachment. Commanding Officers of the above organizations and detachments will forward with same suffi - cient tentage to establish camp in their respective areas for advance detachments. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Divi - sion Train, and 110th Medical Regiment, will see that tentage and equipment necessary for establishing commissaries are forwarded with advance detachments. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 13 4. A rear detachment consisting of the State Staff Corps and De - partments and the Camp Supply Officer will remain in camp August 23, 1927, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 5. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., will be handled by letters from this office. 6. In compliance with Par. 4, National Guard Regulations 27, July 15, 1925, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will report to a medical officer for same during the annual encampment, August 8 to 22, 1927, inclusive, for that pur - pose, and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Camp Surgeon before the close of the encampment. The Com - manding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, will designate such medical officers as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph and will cause to be published the names of same at the beginning of the encampment, in order that those requiring examination may know to whom they are to report. 7. Outside of advance detachments above enumerated, no troops, details or detachments will be permitted to go into camp in advance of first day of camp, i. e., August 8, 1927. 8. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 31, 1927. General Orders, No. 4. 1. The Commander-in-Chief announces with profound sor - row the death of 1st Lieutenant William C. Hoffman, 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Lieutenant Hoffman enlisted in Company F, 2nd Ne - braska Infantry, June 23, 1910. Appointed Corporal October 20, 1910; appointed Sergeant September 16, 1911. Honorably discharged June 22, 1913, expiration term of enlistment. En - listed in Headquarters Detachment, 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, June 29, 1923. Appointed Sergeant, August 10, 1923. Transferred to Service Co., 110th Medical Regiment, June 1, 1924. Honorably discharged June 28, 1924, expiration of enlistment. Re-enlisted in Service Co., 110th Med - ical Regiment, July 3, 1924. Warrant as Sergeant continued on re-enlistment. Honorably discharged April 18, 1926, to accept commission. Appointed 1st Lieutenant, Medical Administra - tive Corps, and assigned to Hospital Co. No. 130, 110th Med - ical Regiment, April 19, 1926. Served to date of death, August 7, 1927. 3. Lieutenant Hoffman earned his commission in the National Guard of this State through his energy and pain- National Guard of this State through his energy and pains - taking efforts to always make good in every grade he was filling, and while he had only been a commissioned officer a little over a year, he had thoroughly demonstrated that the trust was well made and he had demonstrated his fitness as a Medi - cal Administrative officer. 4. Lieutenant Hoffman will long be remembered as one of the efficient officers of the Nebraska National Guard, the sym - pathy of which is extended to his family in this their hour of sorrow. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL H. C. STEIN, Asm. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Sept. 1, 1927. General Orders No. 5. 1. Pursuant to authority contained in letter of allotment dated August 25, 1927, (M. B. 325. 4-Neb.-4), the 130th Hospital Company </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 15 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby re - designated as the 166th Hospital Company, 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard. BY ORDER OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1928. General Orders No. 1. 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1928, to December 31, 1928. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. .C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 30, 1928. General Orders No. 2. 1. Upon the recommendation of the Regimental Commander and under authority of the Secretary of War contained in letter MB 325.4 (Inf.)-Nebr.-6, dated April 21, 1928, Headquarters Company, 2nd Battalion, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, stationed at Sidney, Nebraska, is hereby disbanded and will at once be mustered out of State and Federal service. Captain W. E. McConnaughey, Q. M. C.i Nebraska National Guard will muster out said company and promptly forward to this office the muster-out roll and all books and records of the company together with the discharges of enlisted men </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL which were not delivered at the time of muster-out. Pursuant to Par. 23 (2), National Guard Regulations No. 15, the officers rendered surplus by this order, i. a., 1st Lieutenant Charles H. Gardner and 2nd Lieutenant Claude R. Golding are hereby transferred in the respective grades in which they are commissioned, to the National Guard Reserve of Nebraska. v_ 2. The Regimental Commander, 134th Infantry, Nebraska Na - tional Guard, is authorized to reorganize Headquarters Company, 2nd Battalion, 134th Infantry, with station at Omaha, Nebraska. When the new unit Is ready for inspection for Federal recognition applica - tion should be made to the Corps Area Commander through this office, and Form No. 113-M. B. and a complete roster furnished. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 15, 1928. General Orders No. 3. 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Wednesday, May 30, 1928, consecrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National flag will in accordance with Par. 2, sub-par. 11, Army Regulations 260-10 be displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist in the observance of the day Veteran organizations and Commanding Officers of organizations not in the Federal service will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 17 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 25, 1928. Ceneral Orders . No. 4. 1. Pursuant to authority granted in MB 354.1 Nebr.-18, July 3, 1928, being Training Authority No. 43-1, together with Change No. 1, dated July 20, 1928, the State Staff and State Detachment, 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, 110th Medical Regiment and the Detachment Medical Department, 35th Division, will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska! August 6 to 20, 1928, inclusive, under command of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, Adjutant General's Department, State Staff, and upon com - pletion of this tour of duty, the above named organizations will re - turn to their home stations. 2. A camp supply detachment, consisting of Major H. C. Stein and two enlisted men of the State Detachment, will go into camp at the earliest possible moment on August 3, 1928, and will remain in camp August 21 and 22, 1928. 3. The following will report at the earliest possible moment on August 4, 1928, taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff and State Detachment consisting of two Captains and nine - teen enlisted men; Service Detachment, Service Company, 134th Infantry consisting of one First Lieutenant and fourteen enlisted men; Headquarters Detachment, 35th Division Train, consisting of one Second Lieutenant and six men; and Service Detachment, Service Com - pany, 110th Medical Regiment, consisting one Captain, S. O., and ten enlisted men. They will form an advance Detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the recep - tion of troops and will report to Major H. C. Stein, August 4, 1928. 4. Upon arrival in camp August 4, 1928, Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 110th Medical Regiment, will immediately estab - lish mess for all advance troops and will see that at least one regular cook is included in the Service Detachment. Commanding Officers of the above organizations and detachments will forward with same sufficient tentage to establish camp in their respective areas for advance detachments. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train and 110th Medical Regiment, will see that tentage and equipment necessary for establishing commissaries are forwarded with advance detachments. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL I. A rear detachment consisting of two Captains and nineteen en I luted men of the State Staff and State Detachment will remain in camp August 21. 1928, for the purpose of necessary: detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. •. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., have been handled by letters from this office. 7. In compliance with Par. 4, National Guard Regulations 27, July li, 1925, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will report to a medical officer for same during the annual encampment, August 6 to 20, 1928, inclusive, for that purpose, and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Camp Surgeon before the close of the encampment. The Command - ing Officer. 110th Medical Regiment, will designate such medical officers as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph and will cause to be published the names of same at the beginning of the encampment, in order that those requiring examination may know to whom they are to report. S. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival in camp and company and detachment commanders will cooperate with the medical department in seeing that all men are pres - ent and that their men are so examined. The following named officers are designated to make the examinations called for in this paragraph and will report to the Camp Commander at 9:00 A. M. on the morn - ing of August 6, 1928, for instructions pertaining thereto: Major Earl B. Brooks, M. C. Major John R. Bonnett, D. C. Captain Ernest W. Hancock, M. C. Captain Rodney K. Johnson, M. C. Captain Norman H. Attwood, M. C. Captain Wallace A. Gerrie, M. C. t. Travel directed is necessary in the military service of the BUte. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Asst. Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 19 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 27, 1928. ■General Orders No. 5. 1. Before a Special Court Martial convened at Lincoln, Nebras - ka, June 27, 1928, pursuant to paragraph 1, Special Orders No. 7, Hq. 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, of which Captain Harry R. Ball, MAC-llOth Medical Regiment was President and Captain Harry A. Stearns, MAC, 110th Medical Regiment, Judge Advocate, was arraigned and tried — Pvt. Guy S. Bauman, 166th Hospital Co., 110th Med. Regt CHARGE — Violation of the 54th Article of War. Specification — In that Pvt. Guy S. Bauman, 166th Hospital Com - pany, 110th Medical Regiment, did fraudulently enlist on August 3, 1927, by willfully concealing the fact that he had been convicted of a felony and had served sentence for same in a Federal penitentiary, having been convicted in the District Court in the U. S. Southern Dis - trict of California and sentenced by Judge B. F. Bledsoe to the U. S. Penitentiary at Leavenworth, Kansas. PLEAS To the charge and Specification, "Guilty". FINDINGS Of the Charge and Specification, "Guilty". SENTENCE To be dishonorably discharged the service and to forfeit all pay and allowances due or to become due. 2. The sentence having been approved by the convening authority and the record of trial forwarded for action of the Governor, Com- Commander-in-Chief, Nebraska National Guard, the following are orders thereon: "In the foregoing case of Pvt. Guy S. Bauman, 166th Hospital Co., 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, the findings and sentence are approved and will be duly executed. ADAM McMULLEN, Governor of Nebraska, Commander-in-Chief — NNG." </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 20 S. Pvt. Guy S. Bauman is therefore dishonorably discharged from the Nebraska National Guard, effective this date, and will forfeit all pay and allowances due or to become due. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, Chief of Staff, NNG. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Anbt. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 27, 1928. General Orders No. 6 1. Before a Special Court Martial convened at Lincoln, Nebras - ka, June 27, 1928, pursuant to paragraph 1 Special Order No. 7, Hq. 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, of which Captain Harry R. Ball, MAC-llOth Medical Regiment, was President and Captain Harry A. Stearns, MAC, 110th Medical Regiment, Judge Advocate, was arraigned and tried — Pvt. Cedric H. Brockman, 166th Hospital Co., 110th Medical Regiment. CHARGE — Violation of the 54th Article of War Specification — In that Pvt. Cedric H. Brockman, 166th Hospital Company, 110th Medical Regiment did fraudulently enlist on August 3, 1927 by willfully concealing the fact that he had been convicted of a felony and had served sentence for same in a Federal penitenti - ary, having been convicted in the District Court in the U. S. Southern District of California and sentenced by Judge B. F. Bledsoe to the U. B. Penitentiary at Leavenworth, Kansas. PLEAS To the Charge and Specification, "Guilty". FINDINGS Of the Charge and Specification, "Guilty". </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 21 SENTENCE To be dishonorably discharged the service and to forfeit all pay and allowances due or to become due. 2. The sentence having been approved by the convening au - thority and the record of trial forwarded for action of the Governor, Commander-in-Chief, Nebraska National Guard, the following are his orders thereon: "In the foregoing case of Pvt. Cedric H. Brockman, 166th Hospital Co., 110th Medical Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, the findings and sentence are approved and will be duly executed. ADAM McMULLEN, Governor of Nebraska, Commander-in-Chief — NNG.' 3. Pvt. Cedric H. Brockman is therefore dishonorably discharged from the Nebraska National Guard, effective this date, and will for - feit all pay and allowances due or to become due. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General Chief of Staff, NNG. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 18, 1927. Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Original Enlistment Record To: All Company Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Paragraph 3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 7, dated Febru - ary 10, 1926, is rescinded and the following substituted therefor: In case of separation from the service, the original enlistment record will accompany the closed service record and be forwarded with M. B. Form No. 100, "Report of National Guard Duty Perfor- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL med". Due to the fact that the company headquarters is not an office of record, It is requested that all original enlistment papers in your possession for men that have been discharged prior to January 1. 1927, be forwarded to this office. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN HJP/W January 21, 1927. Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Unauthorized Solicitation of Funds. To: All Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Adjutant General of Florida is published for the information of all officers, Nebraska National Guard: 'STATE OF FLORIDA MILITARY DEPARTMENT Office of the Adjutant General St. Augustine January 17, 1927. Subject: Unauthorized Solicitation of Funds. To: The Adjutants General of all States 1. It has come to the attention of this office that a letter on stationery headed: Company "A", 124th Infantry, Florida National Guard, Hollywood, Fla., signed: W. H. Harper, Sergeant, has been sent to the National Guard Organizations of other States. 2. This letter solicits the purchasing of a book on the Miami Hurricane and states that profits derived from the sale of this book are to go to the relief of members of that company who were rendered more or less destitute by the storm. S. Authority for this solicitation was not granted by this office and the letters were sent without the knowledge of the company commander. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 23 4. It will be appreciated if action be taken by each Adjutant General to prevent funds being sent in response to this letter by units of their State. J. Clifford P. Foster Brigadier General, A. G. D., FNG., The Adjutant General Florida." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 24, 1927. Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Rifle and Machine Gun Practice To: All Infantry and Quartermaster Corps unit and sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Courses to be fired: The following courses only are auth - orized during the year 1927. For rifle practice: Course D, Par. 16, Section II (page 12) T. R. 150-10. For Machine gun practice: Course B, Par. 60, Section X (page 37) T. R. 150-35. 2. RECORD PRACTICE. Record practice for rifles, and pre - liminary and record practice for machine guns, only will be fired during the 1927 field training period. Organizations are required to complete the preparatory exercises and instruction practice at their home ranges. No instruction practice except a limited number of sighting shots for initial adjustments of the rifle or machine guns will be permitted during the field training period. 3. PREPARATORY INSTRUCTION AND PRACTICE. a. No man will be permitted to fire records practice with the rifle, who has not completed the preparatory exercises prescribed in Sections II to IX, inclusive, T. R. 150-5, and who has not fired suffi - cient instruction practice to demonstrate his ability to apply the principles taught in the preparatory exercises (See Par. 61, T. R. 150-5 and Par. 12, T. R. 150-10.) </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL b. No man will be permitted to fire preliminary or record practice with the machine gun who has not completed satisfactorily the preparatory instruction and exercises prescribed in Sections II to IX, inclusive T. R. 150-35, and who has not fired the instruction practice shown by Table I, Par. 58 a, T. R. 150-35, or such modification thereof as may be authorized by the regimental commander. 4. RECORDS OF PROGRESS OF INSTRUCTION. Blank forms to show the state of instruction of individuals before starting range practice and score cards for instruction practice will be mailed to unit commanders without request. Score books (Form 82, AGO) are available and will be furnished on request from unit commanders. Regimental, battalion and company commanders will require that these be kept in the manner required by Training Regulations, and regimental and separate battalion commanders will require that these records, certified by the sub-unit commander, be brought to camp and submitted for all men authorized to fire, before record practice is begun. Officers will bear in mind that in signing these forms they certify on honor that the records therein presented are true and correct to the best of their knowledge and belief. 5. AMMUNITION. a. Ammunition allowances are governed by Circular No. 31, A-13, Militia Bureau, October 11, 1926. The quantity of ammunition that may be expended at home stations for instruction practice will not exceed the following: Rounds of .30 caliber ball Unit ammunition expendable for instruction practice. b. Organizations are authorized to fire ammunition now on hand, within the above allowances for instruction practice. Ammuni - tion to replace the initial allowance, and in addition sufficient am - munition to complete the allowance for instruction practice, will be shipped to organizations without requisition. Machine Gun Company Rifle Company 720' Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. Inf. Regt Service Company Inf. Regt Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. Inf. Battalion 240 360 240i Hq. &amp; Hq. Det. Dlv. Tn Wagon Company Div. Tn 240 600 Motor Transport Company Div. Tn Motor Repair Section Div. Tn 4S0 240 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 25 c. All packing cases, cartridge cases, clips and bandoleers will be saved and turned into the Ordnance Officer at camp. d. The restrictions as to the use of small arms ammunition published in letter from the U. S. Property and Disbursing Officer, dated November 12, 1926, subject "Small Arms ammunition" are hereby removed. 6. TARGET RANGES. a. The attention of all organization commanders is again called to the provisions of Circular No. 5 B, Militia Bureau, 1926, which was published in Circular Letter No. 15, Adjutant General's Department, State of Nebraska, April 2, 1926, and particularly to Paragraphs 3 and 4 of the Militia Bureau Circular, which limits the cost of estimates for immediate action. b. There is yet time to secure approval and complete con - struction of local ranges under the above authority, in order to allow the firing of instruction practice at home stations. c. Blank forms for leases will be furnished on application to this office. In submitting projects, organization commanders must be careful to furnish all the information required by Paragraphs 5, 6 and 7 of Militia Bureau Circular No. 5 B. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 4, 1927. Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Care of Public Property and Disbursement of Public Funds. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau is pub - lished for the information of all concerned and in publishing the letter, I wish to again call to the attention of all responsible officers, the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 26 absolute necessity of safe guarding all Federal and State property from loss, theft, or unnecessary wear. 2. While none of the irregularities spoken of in the third para - graph have been called to the attention of this office, it is well for all to understand that such things will not be countenanced and it is always just a question of time when those participating in these irregularities are brought to justice. 1. On page 48, Report of the Chief of Militia Bureau for the Fiscal Year ended June 30, 1926, attention was directed to the large number of Reports of Survey and Inventory and Inspection reports re - ceived and acted upon in the Militia Bureau, during the period covered by the report. It was stated therein that Reports of Survey, Inven - tory and Inspection Reports covering Federal property issued to the National Guard, which had been lost, destroyed, stolen, or rendered unserviceable by fair wear and tear in the service, had a total value of $3,823,367.70. Appendix N of the Report shows by States the principal items lost or stolen and dropped on Reports of Survey dur - ing the Fiscal Year 1926. Appendix O shows by States the value of the property dropped by Reports of Survey and Inventory and Inspection Reports during the Fiscal Year 1926, and the value of the Federal property in the hands of the National Guard. A careful study of the data contained in Appendices N and O above referred to, undoubtedly sustains the opinion frequently expressed in reports from various sources, that one of the weak points of the National Guard is the lack of care in handling public property. 2. The information outlined above was placed in the Report of the Chief, Militia Bureau, in the hopes that the situation would be brought to the attention of responsible officers of the National Guard in the various States, with a view to improving the situation in this important matter. I am happy to say that several States have already Office of the Chief of the Militia Bureau Washington n Reply refer January 26, 1927. ro MB 400.241 Neb. -1 Subject: Care of Public Property and Distribursement of Publt Funds. ro: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 27 initiated action which will undoubtedly have the effect of correcting some of the deficiencies which have existed in the care and preserva - tion of public property in the hands of the National Guard and I hope that other States which have not taken this action will do so at the very earliest practicable date. 3. During the past year a comparatively large number of irregul - arities in the disbursement and expenditure of public funds have been brought to the attention of the Militia Bureau through investigations conducted by the Department of Justice and by the Inspector General's Department of the Army. These irregularities have involved the pay - ment for attentance at armory drill, the payment of caretakers and the sale of public property. In some cases the State authorities con - cerned have initiated suitable disciplinary action; in others, indict - ments have been obtained and cases have been prosecuted in the courts. In the recent debate in the House of Representatives on the War Department Appropriations Bill, with special reference to items pertaining to the National Guard, the charge was made on the floor of the House of Representatives that there was wholesale padding: of pay rolls and fraudulent payments to enlisted men as caretakers. While such accusations were properly answered at the time, the number of irregularities brought to light during the past fiscal year is undoubtedly responsible for the impression in certain quarters that there is laxity in handling of public funds in the National Guard. Of course I cannot condone such irregularities nor can I intervene to protect individuals. At the same time I am very much concerned lest these continued irregularities shall have the effect of bringing the good name of the National Guard into disrepute and cause a loss of the public confidence. In my opinion, these are matters of primary importance to all officers of the National Guard and particularly to those in positions of responsibility. 4. The primary purpose of this letter is to bring these matters to your attention and to suggest that you insist that all officers charged with responsibility for public property in the hands of the National Guard, for the preparation of pay rolls, for disbursement and ex - penditure of public funds, and for delivery of pay checks, must exer - cise the greatest care and do all in their power to prevent the loss of public property, irregular disbursements and expenditures. CREED C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 9, 1927. Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Requisition Blank Forms and Publications To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There is being forwarded you this day list of forms and pub - lications to the left of which you will find the correct form number and which can be used as an index from which you can immediately get the number of the form desired. 2. Your attention is invited to the necessity of forwarding your requisitions to this office quarterly, when same will be immediately taken care of, as continuous requisitions dribbling in from day to day interfere with the routine work of the office entirely too much, and same will only be honored quarterly in the future. Requisitions should be forwarded to this office January 1st, April 1st, July 1st, and September 1st; forms for payrolls will have to be anticipated the quarter ahead or sufficient forms will not be on hand at the end of the quarter to make up same. Requisitions received between these dates from this time on will simply be filed and acted upon on the above mentioned dates. 3. In using this form as requisitions, a letter of transmittal is not necessary, but the form should be made in triplicate, two copies being sent to this office and one retained by the Unit Commander. 4. This form is promulgated for the express purpose of cutting down the work of the Unit Commander, and as can be seen at a glance, will save him much clerical work. The blank lines are for the pur - pose of requesting publications desired which will have to be written in. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 29 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 18, 1927. Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Limitation on Number of Armory Drills During Fiscal Year 1927. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter of the Chief, Militia Bureau is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT Office of the Chief of the Militia Bureau Washington MB-240.91 Nebraska-10 February 9, 1927. Subject: Limitation on Number of Armory Drills during Fiscal Year 1927. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. (Through the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area) 1. The Secretary of War directs you be informed that in addi - tion to the thirty-six (36) drills which were authorized in our letter of May 28, 1926, for the first three Quarters of the Fiscal Year 1927, authority is hereby given to hold such additional drills during the Fourth Quarter, Fiscal Year 1927, as will bring the total during the Fiscal Year 1927 to forty-eight (48) drills. 2. The maximum number of forty-eight (48) drills hereby au - thorized for the Fiscal Year 1927, cannot be exceeded in any case. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 24, 1927. Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Form No. 100 M. B. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. In lieu of Instructions contained in sub-par. 13 (b), Par. No. 1, on page 2 of Militia Bureau Circular No. 1, A-l, dated January 6, 1927, the following will be observed: All three copies of form 100, M. B., will be mailed direct to the Adjutant General's Office where dis - tribution will be made. Under no circumstances will same be mailed to the Regular Army Instructors. 2. Your attention is particularly invited to sub-par, (c) on page 2 of the Militia Bureau Circular above referred to, which says that the names of all officers and warrant officers will be entered on Form 100 in payroll order, i. e., Christian names first followed by middle initials and surname. 3. In view of the importance of Form 100 as affecting pay of the organizations, it is very essential that all papers, i. e., enlistment papers, service records and company orders accompany this form at the end of each month. In the event this is not done, the forms will be returned for the necessary papers. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 5, 1927. Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Number of Armory Drills during fiscal year 1927. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 31 1. The following letter of the Chief, Militia Bureau is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT Office of the Chief of the Militia Bureau Washington MB 240.91 Neb.-lO February 23, 1927. Subject: Number of Armory Drills during fiscal year 1927 To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. (Through the Commanding General, 7th Corps Area) 1. In Circular Letter, MB 240.91, dated February 9, 1927, you were advised that in addition to the 36 armory drills authorized for the first three quarters of the fiscal year 1927, authority was granted to hold such additional drills during the fourth quarter, fiscal year 1927, as will bring the total during the fiscal year 1927 to 48 drills, and that the maximum number of 48 drills, therein authorized for the fiscal year 1927 could not be exceeded in any case. 2. The instructions above referred to were not designed to place a limitation on the number of armory drills that might be held in the fiscal year 1927, but were designed to fix the number of drills for which Federal pay could be allowed under appropriations available. It is realized that if National Guard units were limited in armory training to the hours for which Federal pay is allowed there would be little hope of ever attaining a very high degree of efficiency. The National Guard has to give many hours of time to military work that is not covered in the periods for which Federal pay is allowed. It is believed that Federal pay for armory drill is merely a recogni - tion of units having had sufficient instruction to warrant an expendi - ture of Federal funds to compensate them in part for work done. 3. The last sentence of paragraph 2 of the above mentioned letter should not be construed as prohibiting the holding of drills or giving of instruction in time not covered by the authorized number of armory drills. On the contrary the holding of extra drills and formations for instruction whereever and whenever that can be done should be encouraged. CREED C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 32 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 5, 1927. Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Administration of the present dual status provisions auth - orized by law. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter of the Adjutant General of the Army Is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: 'The Adjutant General's Office Washington In reply Refer to AG 210.14 (12-15-26) Res. February 5, 1927. Subject: Administration of the present dual status provisions auth- orized by law. To: Each Corps Area and Department Commander, each Chief of Branch, and the Chief, Militia Bureau. 1. In order to carry out the intent and purpose of Sections 37 and 38, National Defense Act, the following is published for the in - formation and guidance of all concerned: a. Where the Chief, Militia Bureau, reports to The Adjutant General of the Army a change in status of a federally recognized Na - tional Guard officer who holds appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps, such officer will be tendered a new appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps, under the provisions of Sections 37 and 38, National Defense Act, in the grade and section corresponding to his National Guard commission. b. Whenever a member of the Officers' Reserve Corps is fed - erally recognized as an officer of the National Guard, he will be tendered a new appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps, under the provisions of Sections 37 and 38, National Defense Act, corresponding in grade and section to his National Guard commission. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 33 c. All federally recognized National Guard officers holding fire-year appointments in the Officers' Reserve Corps will be tendered new commissions in the Officers' Reserve Corps, under the provisions of Sections 37 and 38, National Defense Act, as amended, at the earliest practicable date. 2. A new form, combining application for federal recognition and for appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps, will be issued by the Chief, Militia Bureau. This will be made a part of the papers re - quired to complete the action incident to federal recognition. 3. All notices of appointment in the Officers' Reserve Corps of federally recognized officers of the National Guard will be routed through the Chief of the Militia Bureau, the Corps Area Commander and the office of the State Adjutant General concerned. It is desired that all acceptances or declinations of such appointments be routed through the State Adjutant General, the Corps Area Commander, the office of the Chief, Militia Bureau, and the office of the Chief of Branch concerned, to The Adjutant General of the Army. All con - cerned should take steps to expedite action in such" cases. If ac - ceptance or declination is not received by The Adjutant General of the Army within sixty days of date of notice of appointment, the ap - pointment will be canceled, and if the individual concerned already holds a commission in the Officers' Reserve Corps, he will be honor - ably discharged therefrom, without prejudice. BY ORDER OF THE SECRETARY OP WAR: ROBERT C. DAVIS Major General, The Adjutant General." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 5, 1927. Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Mothers' Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. The second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the Mothers of our country, as the day on which we should express the love and reverence which we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization, who may be sep - arated from their Mothers on May 8th, the duty which they can ful - fill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mothers' Day. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 12, 1927. Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: "Other Funds To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Work has been completed in this office whereby a list of all Reconstituted World War Units have been submitted to the Secretary of War, and as a result of this work, it is expected that checks for "Other Funds" of the Reconstituted Units will be sent direct to Com - pany Commanders. 2. An Enabling Act, permitting the Secretary of War to turn over all remaining monies in the "Other Funds" account which were taken from the Nebraska Units during the World War, to the Gov - ernor of the State, was passed by the last session of the legislature and copies of same will be sent to the Secretary of War as required. 3. The list of Reconstituted Units submitted was without parti - cular regard to the merit of the present Units but simply done to comply with a ruling of the Judge Advocate General's Department and in order to get the funds back to the State where they belong. 4. After a conference with all Commanding Officers, it has been decided and agreed that checks received by the now active organiza - tions of the Nebraska National Guard will be indorsed by the Com - pany Commander and forwarded to this office where this money will </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35 be put in a common fund together with the rest of the money that we expect to receive from those Units which were not reconstituted, and this will be pro-rated by a Board appointed by the Adjutant General and consisting of a representative of each organization; probably Colonel Thomas for the 134th Infantry, Colonel Hilton for the 110th Medical Regiment, and Major Poteet for the 35th Division Train, as this is considered by all of us to be the only just and equitable means of distribution that can be made. 5. Each Unit and Sub-unit Commander is therefore cautioned against cashing checks when received, placing it in his Company fund, or doing anything else with it than as outlined above. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 13, 1927. Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1928. To: All Unit and Subunit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for information and guidance of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT Office of the Chief of the Militia Bureau Washington May 5, 1927. MB-240.91 Nebraska 12 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, F. Y. 1928. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. (Thru Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area.) The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the num - ber of drills to be held during the fiscal year 1928 will be limited as follows: (a) During the first and second quarters, not to exceed twenty-four (24) drills. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (b) During third quarter, not to exceed twelre (12) drills in addition to any part of the 24 drills not held during the first and second quarters. (c) During fourth quarter, not to exceed twelve (12) drills, in addition to any part of the thirty-six (36) drills not held during the first, second and third quarters. (d) In no event will the number of drills for which payment is made with Militia Bureau funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year, for any organization of the National Guard. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 19, 1927. Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Commissions in the Officers' Reserve Corps. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The National Defense Act and regulations issued thereunder provide that every Federally recognized National Guard officer may receive an appointment in the O. R. C. and a commission in the Army of the United States in the same grade and branch, this commission to be concurrent with Federal recognition of the National Guard officer. 2. For this reason the five year commissions formerly held in the O. R. C. are being cancelled and officers of the Nebraska National Guard are being offered commissions as outlined in paragraph 1 above. 3. The question has been raised as to loss of rank when an officer accepts a commission under the new plan, but this question is raised only because of the fact that the matter is not clearly under- Stood. 4. The date of an O. R. C. commission has no bearing whatever upon the rank within the grade. Section 5 of War Department </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 37 Bulletin No. 4 (page 33), dated May 9th, 1925, states: "That the eighth paragraph of section 127a of the National Defense Act of June 3, 1916, as amended, be, and the same is hereby amended to read as follows: "Unless special assignment is made by the President under the provisions of the one hundred and nineteenth article of war, all officers in the active service of the United States in any grade shall take rank according to date, which, in the case of an officer in the Regular Army, is that stated in his commission or letter of appointment, and, in the case of a reserve officer or an officer of the National Guard called into the service of the United States, shall precede that on which he is placed on active duty by a period equal to the total length of active Federal service and service under the provisions of sections 94, 97, and 99 of this act which he may have performed in the grade in which called or any higher grade. When dates of rank are the same, precedence shall be determined by length of active commissioned service in the Army. When length of such service is the same, officers of the Regular Army shall take rank among themselves according to their places on the promotion list, preceding reserve and National Guard officers of the same date of rank and length of service, who shall take rank among themselves according to age. 5. This Department desires that all officers of the Nebraska National Guard accept appointment in the O. R. C. in the same grade and branch in order that they will be ready to function with the Na - tional Guard in case of a Federal emergency. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 3, 1927. •Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: State Pay For Camp. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The last session of the legislature made sufficient appropria - tion, on the Governor's recommendation, whereby we will be able to </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL pay all enlisted men one dollar per day out of State funds for each day in actual attendance at our annual encampment, this in addition to Federal pay. 2. This increase in pay should enable each unit commander to get the most desirable recruits as it virtually eliminates the pay sacrifice that many of the young men have been compelled to under - go in attending camps at a time of year when their earning capacity should be at its peak, but it is desired that unit commanders, in sel - ecting their recruits now look to quality more than quantity as this increase should make it possible for every unit commander to have a waiting list. 3. Along this line, your attention is called to the necessity of holding your strength down to a reasonable number, and in no event should a unit commander bring more than sixty-five men to camp as an increase over this number will make it necessary to reduce the State pay accordingly for next year. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 12, 1927. Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Wearing of Uniform at Paris Convention of American Le- gion. To: All Oflicers of the Nebraska National Guard. 1. Information has been received from the Headquarters of the American Legion that the uniform will not be worn in Paris by mem - bers of the Legion attending the Convention there except at one large parade in the City of Paris and at such ceremonies as may be directed at the various cemeteries in France. At these ceremonies, and in the parade, the wartime uniforms will be worn with the in - signia of rank held at the time of such service. 2. Members of the Nebraska National Guard are authorized to wear the wartime uniform with insignia of rank held at the time of such service on the occasion indicated in paragraph 1 above. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 39 3. Except under the conditions stated in paragraph 2 above, the wearing of the uniform by members of the Nebraska National Guard attending the Convention is prohibited. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 13, 1927. Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1927. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, Ne - braska National Guard. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1927, having been set, i. e., August 8th to 22nd, 1927, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Pars. 110 and 932, National Guard Regulations, 1926, respectively, and tables of organization for National Guard effective January 1, 1926. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted paragraphs as non compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of Company Officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the United States Property and Disbursing Officer as to the exact hour of departure from home station, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation requests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company Commanders are authorized to purchase one day's travel ration for enlisted men at one dollar and twenty cents per ration, and will follow instructions received from the USP &amp; DO per - taining thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained; i.e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 40 conduct must be correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The Commanding Officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear them on leaves or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Train - ing Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack, cots and mosquito nets will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing; i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment consisting of axes, water bags, G. I. cans, colors field desk, lanterns, marking outfits, rakes, ranges, typewriters, shovels, tools, and all cleaning materials; all tentage of whatsoever nature, including poles therefor together with latrine screens and poles. Information pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment and harness will be furnished in a separate Circular Letter. No tent stakes and target material will be brought to camp as they will be furnished there. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except the initial allowances, 1927, and the cal. .22 long rifle, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP &amp; DO, securing memorandum receipt for same. All empty cartridges, (brass), in packing boxes, Belgian aiming devices, all arm racks and lockers, all rifles and pistols and in fact, all arms with which each respective organization is equipped together with all other ordnance with which the individual and Companies are equipped, excepting Machine Gun Companies which will bring two machine gun carts and two ammunition carts, also excepting the Howitzer Com - pany, which will bring one mortar cart, one mortar ammunition cart, and one 37mm gun carriage. However, these organizations will bring all guns to camp. 9. Special Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer prop - erty, including lister bags, is to be carried. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 41 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken; i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in duplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in dupli - cate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. Telegraphic reports of strength when entraining are NOT required this year. 11. Messes. All Company Officers will mess with their organiza - tion and should provide themselves with tables and chairs. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, together with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, Q. M. C, will establish Officers' messes for the Field and Staff Officers and their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff Corps and Department and Instructors as may be assigned To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. MOUNTS. Mounts will be furnished to the respective organ izations as follows: a. SSC &amp; D 1 Col. AGD., 1 Capt. AGD., 1 Major, QMC, 1 Capt. QMC, 1 2nd Lt. QMC, 1 Capt. Ord. Dept., 2 orderlies, 1 Senior Inst., 1 for the Governor. thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 8th, 1927. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA P»:_ L : ii_. . ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 26, 1927. Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Transportation. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 134th Inf. 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., 1 Aux. Bn. Adj., 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T., 4 Orderlies, (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hqs.) 35th Div. Tn. 1 Major, 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 Orderly, 110th Med. Regt. 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 2 Majors (P. &amp; T., Veter - inarian D. S. O.) 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 2 Orderlies. b. The responsible officers for the following Sub-units will furnish riding equipment with grain and feed bags. SSC &amp; D Capt. W. E. McConnaughey, 10 sets. 134th C. O. Regimental Hq. Co., 6 sets. Inf. C. O. Battalion Hq. Co., 3 sets, each. C. O. Service Co., 2 sets. C. O. Attached Medical Det., 1 set. 35th C. O. Headquarters Detachment, 4 sets. Div. Tn. 110th Med. C. O. Service Company, 8 sets. Regiment 2. Mules, Draft. Mules will be assigned as follows a. Camp Quartermaster 4 134th Infantry M. G. Company 4 each Howitzer Company 3 Service Company 9 35 th Dv. Train. Wagon Co. No. 119 4 Wagon Co. No. 120 4 b. Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows: USP &amp; DO — All harness and wagons required for Service Company, 134th Infantry, Wagon Companies of the 35th Divi - sion Train and Camp Quartermaster. The C. O.s of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Companies will furnish the neecssary harness for the animals assigned them. 3. Motors: a. USP &amp; DO will transport all available trucks and am - bulances stored at the State Arsenal to Camp. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 43 • b. The Commanding Officer, Motor Repair Section No. 119, 35th Division Train, QMC, will detail two truck drivers for the pur - pose of transporting Artillery Repair Trucks to Camp, leaving Hold - rege so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 8th. c. The Commanding Officer, Amb. Co. No. 130, 110th Medical Regiment will detail four truck drivers for the purpose of transport - ing two ambulances GMC, leaving Hastings, Nebraska, so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August gth. el. The Commanding Officer Motor Transport Co. No. 137, 35th Div. Train will detail two truck drivers for the purpose of transport - ing Class B Liberty truck with rolling kitchen complete, leaving Holdrege, Nebraska, so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 8th. c. Commanding Officer, Co. "K", will detail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting Class B Liberty truck so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 8th, not later than 9:00 A. M. Drivers will report to Captain W. E. McConnaughey, QMC - NNG., immediately upon their arrival. As no Federal Funds are available for the expense of this movement they will take receipts for actual expenses incurred enroute, for which they will be reimbursed by the State. 4. The Commanding Officers of the following organizations will furnish truck drivers immediately upon arrival of their first Units to Captain W. E. McConnaughey, QMC-NNG., as follows: 134th Infantry 8 35th Division Train 2 110th Medical Regiment 2 5. Permanent truck drivers will be detailed to the Camp Trans- portation Officer for the tour of Camp beginning August 9th from the organization as follows: 134th Infantry 3 35th Division Train 1 110th Medical Regiment 1 BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 27, 1927. Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1927. To: Officer Responsible For Same. 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ A is inclosed here - with for excess baggage (freight) involved in movement of your Com - pany to Ashland, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows: a. Number and description of packages and correct weight should be inserted. All military impedimenta except personal baggage must be weighed and listed according to its commercial name, for example, Fire Arms or Ammumition, not as Ordnance; Clothing or Blankets, not as personal equipment; Tents, canvas, or Poles, tent, wood, or Stove, field range, iron, not as Quartermaster Property, giv - ing the separate weights and manner of packing, so as to ascertain the classification and rates and to enable recovery in case of loss or damage, (Par. 15, N. G. R. 72). b. Opposite "Est. Cost $ ", insert the total actual cost after ascertaining same from the agent. c. Opposite "Loaded in car No. ", "Initials of Car — ' insert the car number and initials. (1. Only Federal Property to be transported on this Bill of Lading. e. Use typewriter, single space and disregard lines. Only fill in the three columns "Number and Description of Packages", "Con - tents" and "Weights". 2. Bill of Lading will be disposed of as follows: a. Original and three memo copies to be signed by your local Agent b. Shipping Order to be surrendered to local Agent. c. Original surrendered to Agent at Ashland, Nebraska, prop - erly executed. d. Two memos to be immediately delivered to U. S. Property and Disbursing Officer upon arrival at camp. e. Retain one memo for Company files. 3. The above must be strictly compiled with. Attention invited to National Guard Regulations 71 and 72 and M. B. Cir. No. 9 A-6 1927, the provisions of which must be strictly compiled with. You </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 45 are advised that you are acting as Agent to the USP &amp; DO in this shipment. 4. There is also inclosed herewith, a supply of W. D. MB. form No. 34 Property List, which should be prepared as outlined in Par. 30, N. G. R. 71. 5. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable rate for the pur - pose of transporting baggage and equipment from the Armory to the Depot and return. Invoices in duplicate should be furnished this office with Public Voucher No. 330 properly executed for the incom - ing and return movement. These accounts must be in by the last of August so that settlement may be made on the whole, to see that this allowance has not been exceeded. 6. Transporation will be provided by this Department for haul - ing organization equipment and baggage to the Rifle Range from the Sioux City-Ashland branch of the C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. on the DLD High - way. Immediately upon arrival, the Officers in charge of Companies should designate a baggage detail for handling this equipment and see that they stay there until the unloading is completed. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major Q. M. C. — N. N. G., U. S. P. &amp; D. O. — Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 28, 1927. Circular Letter No. 19. Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encamp - ment, 1927. To: Officer Responsible for same 1. Government Transportation Requests No. WQ is inclosed herewith, to cover Railroad transportation for your Company to Ash - land, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows, after the man- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ber of persons for whom transportation is required has been ilc - termined: a. Enter with pen, ink or indelible pencil under the block, "Number of Persons", the total to be transported. b. Opposite "Est. cost $ ", enter the TOTAL cost. c. Signature of Responsible Officer with title thereunder on the lower right hand corner of the Request. d. Postal card report (WD MB No. 36) will be completed as required thereon and turned in immediately upon arrival at Camp to the USP &amp; DO, (Camp Quartermaster's Office). 2. If, prior to the surrender of Transportation Request to the ticket agent, it be found necessary to alter entries made thereon, such changes will be fuly explained over your signature and rank in the blank space under Par. 2 of the instructions on the back thereof. Postal card report required above must be absolutely correct, show - ing the number of persons actually travelling as members of your party. 3. In view of the fact that all accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations when actually used, must be charged against the officer responsible for the error, the suggestion is made that, prior to leaving, you familiarize yourself with the provisions of N. G. R. 70. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN Major QMC-NNG. USP &amp; DO — Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 28, 1927. Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Travel Rations to Annual Encampment, 1927 To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, Nebraska Na- tional Guard. 1. In accordance with Par. 3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 16, 1927, Company Commanders will purchase the necessary travel </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 47 rations. The components of this ration are found on page 9, Extracts from Manual for Army Cooks, July, 1917, or A. R. 30-2210, Par. 2 (d). 2. Public Vouchers, W. D. No. 330 with extra sheet, W. D. No. 330 (b), are inclosed for stating accounts due and must be accom - panied by invoices in duplicate. Ration Return QMC No. 223, certi - fied to by the Company Commander and approved by the Regimental or similar Commander, must be submitted with the above to the USP &amp; DO — Nebraska as soon as possible after arrival in Camp. 3. To expedite the payments of vouchers attention is invited to the following: a. Complete the Voucher in detail. b. Certificate that account is correct — See note at bottom of page c. Certificate that articles have been received, etc., to be signed by Company Commander and completed in accordance with No. 4 and agreement lettered C, with the word "oral" opposite C on back of original Voucher. d. Indicate under the block, "Gov. Reg. No. Contract or Order No.," etc., "Travel Rations, Co Regt. (so many) enlisted men." e. The use of colored inks or carbon paper other than black and alterations or erasures will not be accepted. f. It is suggested that the rations be purchased from one firm to avoid holding payment of Vouchers to determine whether the amount authorized has been exceeded. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN Major QMC — NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 48 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 29, 1927. Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Passengers Carried on Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment, 1927. To: All Company Commanders, All Field and StaS Officers, Ne - braska National Guard. 1. In accordance with Par. 2, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 16, 1927, the following table will be used for the guidance of all Com - pany Commanders to whom transportation requests are issued: Officers to Whom Requests Issued. Company and Additional Passengers to Be Carried. 134th Infantry Capt. J. H. McAlpin Regtl. Hq. Co. (Less Tel. Det.) Field &amp; Staff, Omaha. Capt. C. J. Ayers Service Co. (Less Service Detachment). Capt. J. Ned Allison Howitzer Co. 1st Lt. R. H. Thurman 1st Bn. Hq. Co. Capt. W. H. Achenbach, D. C. Capt. V. E. Tyler Co. A, Capt. W. G. Utterback. Capt. R. L. Runyan Co. B, Major E. D. Fisher. Capt. F. H. Stoll Co. C. Capt. B. B. Miltonberger Co. D. 1st Lt. C. H. Gardner 2nd Bn. Hq. Co. Capt. F. W. Stone Co. E. Capt. L. R. Eby Co. F. Capt. A. Rieber Co. G. Capt. A. F. Miller Co. H. 1st Lt. Trev Gillaspie 3rd Bn. Hq. Co., Major E. M. Cline. Capt. E. F. Hoke Co. I, Lt. Col. R. G. Douglas. Capt. B. C. Grasborg Co. K. Capt. H. F. Elsasser Co. L. Capt. E. J. Geesen Co. M. Major R. R. Ensor Att. Med. Detachment. 35th Division Train 1st Lt. C. J. Willams Hq. Det. (Less Serv. Detachment) Major M. L. Poteet. 1st Lt. G. Sonneborn Mot. Tr. Co. No. 137 1st Lt. N. A. Olson Mot. Tr. Co. No. 138. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 49 1st Lt. L. E. Chadderdon....Mot. Rep. Sec. No. 119 Capt. V. M. Hovis Wagon Co. No. 119. Capt. G. N. Henninger Wagon Co. No. 120 Att. Med. Detachment. 110th Medical Regiment Capt. H. R. Ball Service Sec, Service Co. (Less Ser. Det.) Field &amp; Staff, Lincoln; Det. D. S. O. W. O. L. C. Havlicek Band Sec. Serviee Co. Capt. L. A. Swanson Ambulance Co. No. 130. Capt. J. H. Matthai Hospital Co. No. 130. Capt. S. W. Alford Veterinary Co. No. 110. Capt. J. N. Evans Collecting Co. No. 130. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC-NNG. USP &amp; DO — Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p050">eg I 5 £ DO 1 i 9 •a s 1 6°° . I?! . °° ► *» »« a) S * "3 ■a o 02 &lt; K a ? « ■&lt; &lt;! k n 5 z | 1 1 |i! t - I b *■ « • ■ Z B t- |1 = 1 i; » w -S 1st 1 * s =. - = § 2 I » c jS — CX « -O OS ~ — L~ ~ ~ — 5 I 5 •o S ® • S ° o a &lt;s CO § W Hi " O (B t" si a C3 U o iH O CO a 3 *-H » m n&lt; « cq •» ■H c- t* la U3 t«tOo) « B c iH tH iH 3 M | ■w N 1 o o . ni ° ** .a 3 t1s 6 og m CC O &gt; X h. n O 5 O » cc *J c: - Q ■o5d uoS 2 g e o S </seg>
            <seg id="p051">■a a &gt; f. &gt; c &gt; ™ a &gt; c s." 2 ■ ■ CO at- o o* « g bC boS . N _ "O |3|-iiH So IH rH rH W rH rt rH i-l M S •^1 in H 1--5 t»00NH WHiOOO o -^ .-I 2 o 1 - o pq 2 3 Si o DO 3 M s o 5= e X O a) « 6 Zz 6 Uai do 0-i H i— i -r 6 o 6 &gt; d o *j a a) B c b g O S 5 o i-H tH US a d G a 6 O 6 - S H d U — S o C s d^ C?T3 d^ d </seg>
            <seg id="p052">REPORT C op n THE ADJUTAN 1 ' gen: IRAL - is O IB :. .il s 5^ 1^ I o &lt;i e m OO 01 a i 5 • St. bh .. a.-" ca „ rn tn &amp;&lt; • • 3 2 *j •»-' w ~- c o o •■ e OOfct, . &lt;; o TJ ca &lt;; o o =3 d s c I? O 3 I" 5 c « o 3 1 s o 03 a 6 U bo &gt;r S5 rH iH tH tH ■H 1H iH 5 o ■ ED H CO o S a, . 11 to to 01 CO eq us d C3 Q. S O O c _o CS * 60 £ s o 0) c re 0) -^&gt; s c s 2 E c 2 B C 0) S = * a "I S o S o c o w £ X "3 u d J s o c _o s 1 C 6 o "i c X 6 u K d C •a a Q 6 &gt; l&gt;&lt;! CO O CO CO tH 6 2 S H S h 6 a a 6 w ai o ;*&gt; VI (C 2S ?&gt;: h a ■°a SO IS o a s ■- a a &lt;x&gt; °X 5 B I 0 S a </seg>
            <seg id="p053">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 53 Movement No. 1. 3rd Bn. Hq. Co. Co. "I", and Hq. 35th Division Train will load in one baggage car. The Service Section, Service Co. and Veterinary Co. and Det. Div. Sur. Off. will use one baggage car. Movement No. 2. Regt. Hq. Co. and Att. Med. Det. will use one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Co. "A" and 1st Bn. Hq. Co. will use one baggage car. Co. "CV will reserve one-half baggage car for Band, 110th Med. Regt. Movement No. 5. Co. "G" and Amb. Co. No. 130 will use one baggage car. M. T. Co. No. 137 and M. R. Sec. No. 119 will load out baggage car August 7, 1927, for Train 22 at 5:30 P. M. for Hastings. Set out there for Special. Movement No. 6. Wagon Company No. 120 and the Att. Med. Det., 35th Div. Tn., will load together. Where organizations are to load equipment on baggage cars fur - nished other organizations, equipment will be piled on trucks or plat - form in such manner as to permit of rapid loading of same, as trains must not be delayed for this purpose. 2. Tickets: Government Transportation Requests on the Railroad con - cerned will be exchanged for tickets at the local ticket office. Re - quests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. Railroad Equipment Baggage cars to be set the day preceding the movement to permit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is nec - essary. Tourist cars or coaches to be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner in ample time to permit trains to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based in most instances, on last year's camp attendance. 4. Baggage: 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, etc., (Par. 28 NNG 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bills of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bills of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC — NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 2, 1927. Circular Letter No. 23. Subject: Welfare Work To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chaplain, 134th Infantry is published for the information and guidance of all concerned, and it is requested that all aid be given to this Chaplain in his work. "It is desired to make the work of the Chaplain in the annual en - campment as helpful to all ranks as possible. For this purpose all officers are requested to cooperate with the Chaplain to the fullest possible extent and to inform their organizations of the provisions made. The Chaplain of the 134th Infantry will be in camp available for any service in his line of duty and for consultation. Religious serv - ices will be conducted, entertainment and motion pictures planned, writing tables with stationery provided and the Recreation Hut open at all times. The Chaplain's Office may be used by visitors as their headquarters and information center. Officers commanding organizations are requested immediately on arrival in camp to furnish to the Chaplain's office, through the Camp Adjutant, one copy of roster of all men in camp for use in the in - formation and post offices. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 55 Attention is called to the necessity for instruction in the form of addressing mail coming to camp. This form should be called to the attention of relatives and friends by all ranks. Rank and organiza- tion must be given as: PRIVATE PAUL JONES, Company "B", 134th Infantry National Guard Camp, Ashland, Nebraska. All ranks are urged to feel at liberty to call on the Chaplain for any service he can render or for personal consultation. HAROLD C. CAPSEY, Capt., Chaplain, N. N. G." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">a a 3 O ft •^ o o 00 s &lt;i r-i hi 4d C3 o M -* ? m - so H -&lt; Q 05 „ •«! m ? tt H J 5 55 2 3 fa a c O 2 H 6 I I &lt; X ! T. •6 X &lt; • •o o J= . a •2 g S - a » — o § 1 • 1 2 s a I CU - — -i g e o&gt; i I h o z "SSI I l | K I o « oj 6 ! i a S *" S fl 5 2 I * 3 &amp; -d | | S| "III Is - -f 5 &lt;z h a at CS ffl tj si a ! ■a A 03 X a 5s s. a 3 t^ c 2 e &lt; IS — ■ ff&gt; a to o . &lt;» . &gt; 3 h O O 6 O 6 r, t~ UHhhuhh"mh HtOcOt-HxHt" rH !l lilt S c _o I e I o fa O t- CO CO S d d'H -dd35d5»d 1 M d C 0) S o s d • « </seg>
            <seg id="p057">B O S I &lt;i h o • S rt a," 3 e e •3 I- 6 Z . t- &amp;] ■o . a m i&lt; 5a: e •a c m o "3 •a 1 1 s 03 £' 3 3 e CO j-« a) meg fc. &lt;! &gt; to &gt; = I-' — 93 5^ K * * &amp; * * tig ►a d no M d O C8 W M K -* KO 5D H CC N C M ffl W •* iH N N W WLOM C4 CO 00 00 IO 00 :i a c :i B 3 a aS C §|lss fcoa o » 2 S e o s 3 s o I c a a a 5 oo a, moo rt t*_, M . w be s3 1^1 5w o • BO ■ ,9 H **** bi r 9 H O , 3 . 55 «« . d 2 cdSoUofljod u oi 3 £&amp; ■°a — . o If s! o a! si — &lt; C s a) &gt; o -5 •I I </seg>
            <seg id="p058">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 58 Movement No. 2. The Band, 110th MR., and Co. C will load In one baggage car. Amb. Co. No. 130 and Co. G will load in one baggage car. M. T. Co. No. 137 and M. R. S. No. 119 will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 3 Wag. Co. No. 120 and Att. Med. Det. 35th Dn. Tn. will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 4. 3rd Bn. Hq. Co., Co. I, and Hq. Det. 35th Dn. Tn. will load in one baggage car. Service Co. 110th M. R., Vet. Co. No. 110 and Det. Dv. Surg. Off. will load in one baggage car. 1st Bn. Hq. Co. and Co. A will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 5. Regt. Hq. Co. and Att. Med. Det. will load in one baggage car. 2. Tickets: Government Transporatlon Requests on the Rail - road concerned will be exchanged for tickets at the Camp Quarter - master office. Requests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. Baggage: 150 pounds of personal baggage will be trans - ported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, etc. (Par. 28, N. G. R. 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Excess baggage con - sisting of property other than checkable baggage will be handled in baggage cars, but is paid for by the Government on Government Bills of lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from this station, at freight rates. 4. Passengers and organizations to be carried will be those that are shown in Nebraska Circular Letter No. 21, 1927. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC — NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL. 59 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 10, 1927. Circular Letter No. 25. Subject: Unserviceable Clothing and Equipment, To: All Responsible Officers, Nebraska National Guard 1. Reports of Survey and Inventory and Inspection Reports should be submitted immediately to this office for the different classes of property so that action may be had during the annual physical inventory. FOR THE ADJUTANT GENERAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC — NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 10, 1927. Circular Letter No. 26. Subject: Repair, Renovation and Maintenance of Clothing, Individual Equipment and Organization Equipment. To: All Responsible Officers, Nebraska National Guard 1. It is directed that you furnish this office, not later than No - vember 12th, 1927, separate estimates for the following: a. Repair and renovation of Clothing and Individual Equip- ment b. Maintenance of Organizational Equipment. 2. In no case will any obligation be incurred until estimate called for above has been approved by this office. FOR THE ADJUTANT GENERAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC — NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 18, 1927. Circular Letter No. 27. Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Inviting attention to copy of letter received from The Chief, Militia Bureau, relative to Limitation of Armory Drills. WAR DEPARTMENT Militia Bureau Washington MB 240.91-Mo.-ll October 10, 1927. Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, (Thru the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area) 1. There has been some misunderstanding of the provisions of Militia Bureau letters MB 240.91 of May 28, 1926, February 9, 1927 and May 5, 1927, on Limitation of Armory Drills. 2. Because of the phrasing of the letters, it has been construed in some quarters that the Secretary of War through the Chief, Militia Bureau, was limiting the number of assemblies which might be held during a certain quarter or year. (See Par. 11, NGR. 45). The letters were not intended to convey such a meaning. While each organization is required to hold the minimum number of assemblies authorized from time to time by the Secretary of War, the State authorities may prescribe as many more assemblies for a unit as they desire. The Secretary of War in the letters above referred to prescribed the maxi - mum number of assemblies for which Federal pay is authorized within the limits of available appropriations, which number is also the mini - mum number of assemblies which must be held. The letters while un - fortunately using the phrase "the number of drills to be held", do not limit the number of assemblies which may be held by an organization. 3. However, no matter how many assemblies may have been held, in the preparation of pay-rolls only those assemblies for which Armory Drill pay is authorized should be entered on the pay-roll. If the </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 61 number of assemblies held during a quarter exceeds the number for which Federal Armory Drill pay has been authorized, only the par - ticular assemblies for which such pay is claimed may be entered upon the pay roll. 4. The responsibility for the selection of such assemblies rests with the various organization commanders and the individual mem - bers must abide by this selection, the presumption being that all mem - bers of any organization have been notified through advance publica - tion of training schedules as to which assemblies are to be used for computation of pay. (See Par. 18, NGR. 45). To illustrate, assume a company has held sixteen ordered assemblies in a quarter on dates as follows: January 2, 9, 16, 23, 31, February 6, 13, 20, 22, 28, March 4, 11, 18, 21, 26, 31. Assume further that at each assembly the strength requirements for Armory Drill pay purposes have been met; that 12 assemblies have been authorized for the quarter by the Militia Bureau, and that the organization commander has selected the 12 assemblies for entry on the pay-roll. Assuming further that he has selected the five held dur - ing January, those held on February 6, 13, 20 and 28, and those held on March 11, 18, and 26, only these assemblies may be considered as "authorized assemblies." The officers belonging to the organiza - tion may use only these assemblies for qualifying for Armory Drill pay and no enlisted man may be paid for any assembly he may have attended on any date other than the dates selected. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 62 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 25, 1927. Circular Letter No. 28. Subject: Examinations of Candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Adjutant General of the Army, dated August 19, 1927, addressed to the Governor of Nebraska, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. Ap - plications for this examination should reach this office not later than November 3, 1927, to enable us to prepare for the competitive ex - aminations which will be held November 9th to November 12th, 1927, inclusive. WASHINGTON AG 051.11 West Point (8/19/27) Off. August 19, 1927. The Governor of Nebraska Lincoln, Nebraska. My dear Governor: The regulations for the selection of enlisted men of the National Guard for appointment to the United States Military Academy provide that the candidates shall be apportioned among the States, Territories and the District of Columbia according to the enlisted strength of their respective National Guard organizations. Candidates from the States and Territories will be selected by the respective Governors thereof from successful competitors in a preliminary examination of a scope and nature similar to the regular examination for entrance to the Military Academy, to be instituted and conducted by the Gov - ernors, and to be held between November 1 and November 15 of each year. Under the statute authorizing these appointments, the Governors are restricted in their choice of candidates to enlisted men of the National Guard who conform to the requirements mentioned. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 2, 1926, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of nineteen and twenty-two years and must be not less than </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 63 five feet four inches in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. Similarly, service with a National Guard organization prior to its recognition by the Federal Government, may be considered, the date of enlist - ment of the soldier governing, and not that of the recognition of the unit. The requirements for admission to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the inclosed pamphlet, a supply of which is being sent you under separate cover for distribution to those concerned. The candidates so selected will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is sched - uled to be held beginning on March 6, 1928, and the appointments available on July 2, 1928, will be awarded to the qualified candidates in the order of merit established at that examination, which is com - petitive among all National Guard candidates. You are, therefore, requested to select, in accordance with the fore-going, one candidate from among the enlisted men of the National •Guard of your State, and to designate him for the entrance examina - tion mentioned, using therefor the inclosed blank form. These cadet - ships being awarded as a result of competition, alternates cannot be considered. There is no limitation to the number who may compete in the preliminary examination and it is suggested that this matter be widely advertised throughout the National Guard organizations of your State so that every enlisted man who is eligible as to age and length of service may be afforded this great opportunity. In the past, some States have failed to take advantage of the opportunity to designate candidates, while other States have desig - nated their full quotas and are constantly asking for the privilege of making more appointments. As a result it has been decided to re - quire that designations shall be made promptly following the No - vember preliminary examination, and in no case later than December 15, 1927. When sending in your designations, it is requested that you inform the Department as to the number of other desirable can - didates, if any, you may have available. The allotments of those States which allow the opportunity to lapse through failure to fill their quotas by December 15, 1927, will be given to other States. Very respectfully, BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. LUTZ WAHL, 2 incls. Major General." </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 9, 1927. Circular Letter No. 29. Subject: Annual Physical Examinations and Efficiency Reports. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF THE MILITIA BUREAU Washington MB. 201. 5 Gen.-5 November 1, 1927. Subject: Annual Physical Examinations and Efficiency Reports. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, (through the Com - manding General, Seventh Corps Area.) 1. a. Your attention is invited to the following sub-paragraph of National Guard Regulations No. 20: "22. f. Annual physical examination, — Once each calendar year every officer of the National Guard will be physically examined and report of examination sent through chan - nels for file in the Militia Bureau." b. The above mentioned physical examination is required for every officer and warrant officer of the active National Guard and National Guard Reserve under the provisions of paragraph 4, National Guard Regulations No. 27. c. In compliance with the provisions of the National Guard Regulations indicated above, the physical examinations for the cal - endar year 1927 should be completed in December and reports sub - mitted. It will greatly facilitate the administrative work of the Militia Bureau and avoid unnecessary correspondence as to delinquent re - ports if a thorough and complete check is made for the purpose of determining that no omissions have been made in making the re - quired examinations and in rendering the reports of them. Such action will be greatly appreciated by the Militia Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 65 2. An efficiency report on each National Guard Officer for the calendar year 1926 was required to be rendered on December 31st, by paragraph 20 6 'A, National Guard Regulations, 1922, and the same requirement for the calendar year 1927 is made by paragraph 74, National Guard Regulations No. 20. An examination of the records of the Militia Bureau, pertaining to all States, shows that many efficiency reports for the calendar year 1926 have not been received, but that there has been a most marked improvement in this respect over the receipts of previous years. It is requested that your cooperation in rendering these efficiency reports, both for officers of the active National Guard and the Na - tional Guard Reserve, be continued for the calendar year 1927, and that they be rendered as soon as practicable after December 31st. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 30, 1927. Circular Letter No. 30 Subject: Over-strength of the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF THE MILITIA BUREAU Washington MB. 325.4-Nebr.-5 November 18, 1927. Subject: Over-Strength of the National Guard To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, (through the Com - manding General, Seventh Corps Area.) 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Strength Reports submitted by your State on Militia Bureau Form No. 100, covering the quarter ending September 30, 1927, show an overage in strength of your National Guard, as follows: |Actual Strength as| Strength of your Guard in Authoribed | of September 30, | excess of Authorized excess of Authorized Strength 1927 Strength 1777 1962 1S5 2. By direction of the Secretary of War, this situation is brought to your attention with a view to the immediate reduction of the actual strength of your National Guard to conform to the strength auth - orized therefor by the Militia Bureau under letter dated November 22, 1926, (MB. 325.4-Nebr.-5). 3. The Commanding General, 7th Corps Area, is requested to have this overage in your strength especially noted by the Disbursing Officer at his Headquarters charged with the making of payments for Armory Drill for the quarter ending September 30, 1927. CREED C. HAMMOND, Major- General, Chief, Militia Bureau." 2. From a casual glance at the Form No. 100, submitted to this office, it is plain to be seen that almost every unit and sub-unit com - mander is carrying a lot of dead material; in other words, a paper strength that does not actually exist, and it is therefore imperative that you immediately reduce to your maintenance strength or it is going to affect the pay of all of the National Guard of this State. 3. Do not procrastinate but discharge this dead material at once. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 7, 1927. Circular Letter No. 31. Subject: Over-strength of the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Supplementing Circular Letter No. 30, Nebraska, November 30, 1927, "Reduction in Strength" the maximum allowed under re- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 67 cent apportionment of strength of the National Guard as published in M. B. 325.4-Neb.-5, November 22 1926, is as follows: Enlisted Men Rgt. Hq. Co. Inf 64 Serv. Co. Inf. (Less Band) 64 Serv. Co. Inf. (Band) 36 How. Co. Inf 64 Bn. Hq. Co 25 Rifle and M. G. Co 64 Att. Med. Det. Inf 32 Hq. Det. Dv. Tn 14 M. T. Co. Dv. Tn 48 M. R. S. Dv. Tn 20 Wag. Co. Dv. Tn 54 Att. Med. Det. Dv. Tn 16 Serv. Co. Med. Regt. (Less Band) 35 Serv. Co. Med. Regt. (Band) 25 Amb. Co. Med. Regt 48 Hosp. Co. Med. Regt 64 Vet. Co. Med. Regt 40 Coll. Co. Med. Regt 64 2. As will be noted by the above, each unit and sub-unit is given a reasonable number over and above their maintenance strength, and each organization having in excess of the number published above must immediately discharge a sufficient number to come within these figures. This allowance must not again be exceeded until authority for same is granted by the Militia Bureau. 3. Inasmuch as the over-strength now existing in the Nebraska National Guard has never been authorized by any source, that part in tables of organization allowing noncommissioned officers and specialists to be carried as such until absorbed is not applicable, and all unit and sub-unit commanders will, therefore, have to reduce their noncommissioned officers and specialists to come within the number authorized by tables of organization for the strength above set out, in order to qualify for pay. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA December 15, 1927. Circular Letter No. 32. Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There are enclosed herewith blank efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1927, and which should have your immediate attention. 2. Before attempting to make this report, you are directed to make a thorough study of the instructions contained thereon, which are full and explicit and, if followed explicitly, will bring the proper report to this office before the expiration of the month. 3. After having given a thorough study to the instructions on both sides of the efficiency reports, make out your reports and for - ward same without further delay to the officer to whom the instruc - tions direct you. This is a small matter if given your immediate at - tention. Let us all get them in, in proper form, and AT ONCE. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA January 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 1. Subject: Interpretation of N. G. R. pertaining to enlisted men at - tending drill with organizations other than their own and also taking the R. O. T. C. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. In answer to a letter from Major T. F. McNeill, Inf. Dol., Instructor on duty with the Adjutant General, as to whether or not </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 69 enlisted men belonging to the Nebraska National Guard who are at - tending the University of Nebraska and who are taking the R. O. T. C. and attending drill with a National Guard unit other than their own, may receive compensation under the provisions of Par. 10b NGR-58, and also be counted as constructively present with their own organiza - tion under Par. 7b NGR-58, the following decision from the Finance Officer, U. S. A., Omaha, Nebraska, is quoted for your Information and guidance. "Paragraph 7b NGR-58 authorizes attendance of enlisted men at R. O. T. C. institutions to be credited as constructive attend - ance with their own N. G. unit only for the purpose of qualify - ing the officers of the unit for drill pay, and such credit, so far as shown by law and regulations, is not affected or limited by any other lawful act of the enlisted man. Paragraph 10b NGR-58 authorizes, under prescribed condi - tions, enlisted men of the N. G. to attend and receive pay for attendance at drills with an organization other than their own, and such attendance or right to pay therefor is not affected by any other lawful act of the enlisted man. This office finds nothing which would preclude action being taken under both sections of the regulations and payment of the enlisted men under the latter section." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 21, 1928. Circular Letter No. 2. Subject: Chart, "Property Records of Responsible Officers", To All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There is inclosed herewith. Chart showing Titles and Form numbers, use and disposition of same, which should be studied care - fully and followed closely to avoid unnecessary correspondence. 2. Your attention is invited to the necessity of forwarding your Requisition to this office as indicated thereon; e. g.. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL a. Requisition for Blank Forms should be in by the end of each quarter and should cover your requirements for the ensuing quarter. b. Requisition for Clothing and Equipment must be sub - mitted as indicated thereon so as to allow this office time to check against Property Records to see that Equipment Tables have not been exceeded, based upon your strength, and to prepare Official Requisition on Corps Area Headquarters. c. Requisition for Cleaning and Preserving Material must be submitted at the time indicated thereon, anticipating your needs for the following year. Requisitions received after date indicated will be held until the next period. 3. This Chart supersedes all Charts on this subject issued pre - vious to January 16, 1928, which should be destroyed. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 28, 1928. Circular Letter No. 3. Subject: Correction, "Property Records of Responsible Officer". To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The fourth line of the Chart, PROPERTY RECORDS OF A RESPONSIBLE OFFICER, 'Requisition, Cleaning &amp; Preserving Ma - terial, N. N. G. 6' should be corrected to read "between Jan. 1st and March 1st." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 71 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 7, 1928. Circular Letter No. 4. Subject: Correct Designation of Units. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Your attention is invited to the designation of units of Ne - braska National Guard as shown in the National Guard Register 1927 which is considered correct and will be used in the future. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 7, 1928. Circular Letter No. 5. Subject: Target Practice, Small Arms, 1928. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. Courses to be fired: The following courses only are auth - orized during the year 1928. For rifle practice: Course D. Par. 16, Section II( page 12) T. R. 150-10. For machine gun practice, Course A. Par. 58, Section X (page 37) T. R. 150-35. For pistol practice: Dismounted course, Par. 51-63, T. R. 150-20. 2. RECORD PRACTICE. Record practice for rifles; instruction, preliminary and record practice for machine guns; and instruction and record practice for pistols, will be fired during the 1928 field train - ing period. Organizations are required to complete the preparatory exercises and rifle instruction practice at their home ranges. No in - struction practice except a limited number of sighting shots for initial adjustments of the rifle will be permitted during the field training period. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, 3. PREPARATORY INSTRUCTION AND PRACTICE. a. No man will be permitted to flre record practice with the - rifle, who has not completed the preparatory exercises prescribed in Sections II to IX, inclusive, T. R. 150-5, and who has not fired suf - ficient Instruction practice to demonstrate his ability to apply the principles taught in the preparatory exercises (See Par. 61 T. R. 150-5 and Par. 12, T. R. 150-10). b. No man will be permitted to fire instruction or preliminary practice with the machine gun, who has not completed satisfactorily the preparatory instruction and exercises prescribed in Sections II to IX, inclusive T. R. 150-35, and who has not fired the instruction prac - tice shown by Table I, Par. 58a, T. R. 150-35, or such modification theerof as may be authorized by the regimental commander. c. Instruction practice with pistol at home stations is auth - orized but not required. 4. RECORDS OF PROGRESS OP INSTRUCTION. Marksman - ship forms to show the state of instruction of individuals before start - ing range practice, and in addition score books for rifle instruction practice will be mailed to unit commanders on requisition. Regi - mental, battalion, and company commanders will require that these be kept in the manner required by Training Regulations, and regi - mental and separate battalion commanders will require that these marksmanship records, certified by the sub-unit commander, be brought to camp and submitted for all men authorized to fire, be - fore record practice is begun. Officers will bear in mind that in signing these forms they certify on honor that the records therein presented are true and correct to the best of their knowledge and belief. 5. AMMUNITION. a. Ammunition allowances that may be expended at home stations for instruction practice will not exceed the following: Unit ( Cal. .30 Cal. .41 Machine Gun Company 4800 3000 Rifle Company Hq. &amp; Hqrs. Company, Inf. Regt Service Company Inf. Regt Hq. and Hqrs. Company Inf. Battalion Hq. and Hq. Det. Div. Tn Wagon Company Div. Tn Motor Transport Company, Div. Tn Motor Repair Section Div. Tn 6000 2400 3600 2400 1200 48 3600 600 2000 1500 500 500 400 300 1000 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 73 b. Organization commanders should submit requisitions for the ammunition required for instruction practice. AMMUNITION SUPPLIED FOR INITIAL ALLOWANCE MUST NOT BE USED. 6. TARGET RANGES. a. The attention of all organization commanders is called to the provisions of NGR 58. Organization commanders desiring ranges should submit application to this office so that leases may be furnished and the instructors on duty with the unit may make the inspection as required. 7. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 3, January 24, 1927, is hereby revoked. 8. Chart "Records Involved in Qualification of Arms" is en - closed which shows titles, form numbers, remarks, etc., which should be studied carefully and followed closely as it will save time. This Subject: Initial allowance, small arms ammunition, maintenance strength. To: Responsible Officers Concerned. 1. Initial allowance of Ball Ammunition Cal. .30 and Cal. .45 will be shipped your organization based upon the Maintenance Strength, Equipment Tables National Guard, applicable to your unit. 2. This ammunition is to be held intact and under no considera - tion will any of it be fired or disposed of, except upon authority from this office. 3. Several units used part of the 1927 initial allowance after In - structions had been issued to the contrary. This condition will not ■hart supersedes all other charts on this subject issued prior to Fet uary 15, 1928, which should be destroyed. b- BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 8, 1928. Circular Letter No. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL be tolerated for the 1928 initial allowance and unit commanders will be held responsible for strict compliance with these instructions. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 21, 1928. Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Armory drill pay for Field and Staff Officers, To: All Field and Staff Officers, Nebraska National Guard. The following radiogram received from the Chief, Militia Bureau, this date, is published for the information and guidance of all con - cerned: "General accounting office advises that payments of armory drill pay rolls, made after March 31, 1928, where provisions of paragraph 14 (g), National Guurfl Regulations 59 have not been complied with, will be suspended." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 24, 1928. Circular Letter No. 8. Subject: Disposition of other funds. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. It is desired that a decision be arrived at as to the distribution of the funds which were taken from the Nebraska units who served </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 75 during the World War and which was recently turned back to the State of Nebraska. Your attention is invited to previous communica - tions, one of which was dated some time in May and one some time in October 1927, which gives information regarding this fund and about which we have held several meetings of the Commanding Officers of organizations with a desire to arrive at a conclusion as to a just and equitable method of distribution. 2. We must first take into consideration the fact that none of the present units have contributed a single dollar towards this fund and that it rightfully belongs to the men who served during the World War but it comes back to us as reconstituted units, on account of its being impossible to reach those to whom the fund more prop - erly belongs and along this line we should take into consideration the desires of those men, many of whom are dead and gone and of whom there is nothing but a memory left. 3. If this money is pro-rated and distributed among the pres - ent units, a share would of necessity be deducted for future organ - izations, which would leave the amount to us pro-rated and distributed so small that no one unit would derive much benefit; so the problem which now arises is how to dispose of this money so that it will be equitably made use of, so that those who created the fund will be satisfied and so it will insure the greatest benefit to the present mem - bers of the National Guard and those who are as rightfully entitled to same who join up in the future. 4. Since our organization, there have been numerous changes in units which greatly complicate a division of this fund. For instance, one unit will shortly be demobilized because of lack of support in that particular community; it was necessary to muster out three other units on account of lack of officer material to continue the organiza - tions and, after old units are mustered out, new units will be mustered in, so the question arises as to whether or not it would be fair to the persons who happened to be members at this particular time to ex - pend same and make no provision for those future members who will be as justly entitled to it. 5. After numerous conferences of the respective Commanding Officers with this office, we have concluded that a much more equit - able and just use of this money can be made through the building of a Memorial Recreation building on our camp grounds at Ashland. The fund is just about adequate to construct a very suitable building which could be used by the entire personnel of the camp each year. This building would have a large auditorium, dance hall, stage, read- </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ing and lounge rooms, a large balcony overlooking the river together with rooms for a hostess and visitors to the camp; this would give the present personnel immediate benefit and would 'be a benefit for the entire National Guard for all time to come. We have had an architect draw up a rough outline of what this building is to be and in case we can get a copy of same in time it will be inclosed with this letter, otherwise, we will send it at the earliest possible date. 6. The building of a Memorial, in memory of the World War soldiers who created this fund for us, has the approval of Col. Amos Thomas, 134th Infantry, Col. David C. Hilton, 110th Medical Regi - ment, Maj. Marcus L. Poteet, 35th Division Train, and all junior field Officers who have met with us from time to time in our deliberations. 7. It is desired that the Commanding Officer of each unit and sub-unit present this matter to the personnel of his command at the first meeting after receipt of this letter and communicate the attitude of the command on this subject to this office. The matter should be fully explained to the men as to just what the fund is, its source, and the fact that a rather inequitable division and unsatisfactory arrangement, lacking permanency, would necessarily result if the fund is to be pro-rated to the several organizations. It also should be explained to them that the Recreational building would be a per - manent addition to the camp and would be a continuous benefit to them. While the Commanding Officers of the several organizations and this office feel that a Recreational building would be of much greater permanent value, it is felt that this matter should be taken up with the unit Commanders and their personnel and their attitude de - termined before any final decision is made. 8. There is inclosed herewith for your guidance and benefit a copy of form to fill in for the minutes of your next meeting and a certificate to fill out as to action taken on same and which should be sent to this office at the earliest possible date. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. The meeting was called to order by Capt who acted as temporary Chairman and appointed. as temporary secretary. ur iu.cjiid i. ii^vj wr v^w , Held , , 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 77 Upon motion duly made, seconded, put to vote and carried. ..was elected Chairman of the meeting. Upon motion duly made, seconded, put to vote and carried. ..was made secretary. At said meeting of Co Reg't. NNG., at which officers were present and enlisted men were present, the officers of said Company explained in detail the policy of the U. S. War De - partment providing for refundment of World War funds and other funds to reconstituted National Guard organizations. The officers of said Company further explained in detail the proposal to use all of such funds allotted to the Nebraska National Guards for the con - struction of a Memorial Recreation Hall at the Nebraska National Guard encampment site at Ashland, Nebraska. Thereupon, it was moved by and seconded by that Co , .Reg't. NNG., hereby approves the said proposal to use all the refunded World War funds, and other funds, now due and payable or subsequently to become due and payable, to Co. Reg't. NNG., or other members thereof under the policy of U. S. War Department providing for the refundment of World War and other funds, for the construction and equipment of a Memorial Rec - reation Hall at the Nebraska National Guard encampment site at Ashland, Nebraska, and that Co , Reg't. Nebraska Na- tional Guard, hereby sets over, assigns and transfers all of its right, title and interest, in and to any and all of said funds, to the Adjutant General of Nebraska, to be used by him, in his discretion, for the con - struction and equipment of such Memorial Recreation Hall at said camp site. After a discussion of said motion, said motion was put to vote and carried. There being no further business transacted by members of said Company, the said business meeting of said Company was adjourned. Chairman Secretary 'CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, ISS: County. J We, , Chairman, and ■ Secretary, of the meeting of the officers and men of Co. Reg't. NNG., State of Nebraska, held at. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Nebraska on April , 1928, hereby certify that the foregoing is a true and correct copy of the minutes of said meeting held at said time and place and of the proceedings had at said meeting. Chairman Secretary CERTIFICATE OF COMPANY COMMANDER State of Nebraska, Iss _ County. I I, , Regt. Nebraska National Guard and Commanding Officer of Co Reg't. NNG., hereby certify that the foregoing meeting of the officers and men of said Company was held at the time and place stated and that the foregoing proceedings were had and that the foregoing minutes of said pro - ceedings had at said time and place are in all respects true and correct. Commanding Co Reg't. NNG. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 3, 1928. Circular Letter No. 9. Subject: Mothers' Day. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. You are directed to bring to the attention of every officer and en - listed man of your command the desire of the Secretary of War that each officer and enlisted man write a letter to his home on Mothers' Day, the second Sunday in May, (May 13, 1928), as an expression of the love and reverence we owe to the mothers of our country. BY COMMAND OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 79 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 14, 1928. Circular Letter No. 10. Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills F. Y. 1929. To: All unit and sub-unit Commanders. 1. The following letter is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the num - ber of drills to be held during the fiscal year 1929 will be limited as follows: (a) During the first and second quarters, not to exceed twenty-four (24) Federal pay drills. (b) During third quarter, not to exceed twelve (12) Federal pay drills in addition to any part of the 24 drills not held during the first and second quarters. (c) During fourth quarter, not to exceed twelve (12) Fed - eral pay drills, in addition to any part of the thirty-six (36) drills not held during the first, second and third quarters. (d) In no event will the number of drills for which payment is made with Federal funds exceed eight (8) in any one month, or forty-eight (48) during the fiscal year, for any organization of the National Guard." BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 19, 1928. Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Reports of Survey and I. &amp; I. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. Your attention is invited to the necessity of making Reports of Boards of Survey and Reports of I. &amp; I with each copy being clear. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL legible and plain, so they can be read as easily as the first page. 2. In the last two or three weeks several copies have reached this office that were so dim it would be impossible to read them and, while we have forwarded these Reports rather than send them back, we are afraid they will come back to be made over. 3. With the paper that Is used in these Reports, not more than three copies should be attempted at one time. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 19, 1928. Circular Letter No. 12. / Subject: Memorial Building. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. It is regretted very much that owing to the lateness of the vote cast by three or four of the organizations it is impossible to con - struct the Memorial Building before Camp this year. 2. At a meeting of the Officers held at this office June 16, 1928, it was decided to place this money out on interest, which should give us around a thousand dollars to help in furnishing same, however, the construction will be commenced in ample time next Spring to assure us of its completion by the next Camp. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 25, 1928. Circular Letter No. 13. Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1928 To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. We are called upon by the Chief, Militia Bureau, to submit a Return of Strength on the evening of June 30, 1928, and, as June </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 81 30th comes on Saturday, all unit and sub-unit Commanders are re - quested to wire this office their strength as early in the morning as possible on June 30th, in order that we may compile same and tor - ward to the Chief, Militia Bureau, on that day. 2. The following form of telegram, giving Officers and enlisted men separately, should be used: "Co. A, three Officers, sixty-three enlisted men. (Signed) Smith, Captain." 3. DO NOT FORGET TO WIRE THIS IN SATURDAY MORNING, JUNE 30th. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 27, 1928. Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Annual Armory Inspection 1928. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. There is, with some humiliation, submitted herewith the re - sults of the Annual Armory Inspection of the National Guard of the Seventh Corps Area 1928, for the information of all concerned. 2. It will be noted that under the headings "Average state of discipline"; "Average state of morale and esprit"; "Status as to care and storage of property" and "Condition of records", Nebraska was the only' one that received "S" under each heading. Of course, we might do worse than receive "Satisfactory" but where the other states are getting "Very Satisfactory" we should receive the same, as we have always considered ourselves the best in the Corps Area and it is sincerely hoped that the Company Commanders will commence now to lay a foundation for the next Armory Inspection, in order that </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL we may be rated among the best, if not the best, in the Corps Area and won't have to be held up another year as the poorest. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 12, 1928. Circular Letter No. 15. Subject: New National Guard Armory Drill Pay Plan. To: All Unit and Sub-unit CommandtTs. 1. In compliance with the amended Section 110, National De - fense Act, promulgated in Section I, Circular No. 19-A-10, Militia Bureau, May 23, 1928, — the following described armory drill pay plan for the National Guard, State of Nebraska,, is announced: 2. The National Guard of Nebraska will submit pay rolls for the initial pay period for two months only, July and August, 1928. There - after, all pay rolls will be three month periods as follows: (September, October, November (December, January, February (March, April, May (June, July, August. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">5pJOD3J JO UOIJipUO^I ■r. -s. -r. r. -s. -f. -r. v. v. &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; I 01 E a *dOJJ JO 33EJOJS Tg 3JE3 OJ SE STl)E)g A. -A. A. A. A. 'A. A A. A. &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; jurist pin: -i[i; -iOUI JO 3JEJS 'Ay f. -A A. I. J. A. A. A. A &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; a •a - ! ! §55 SLs&lt; aui|dpsip jo 3jEjs agEjdAy /. X •/. -I. S. A A A V. &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; S3IJJEJ 3JEAUJ SS^gRi22?;g 0 -^^ uonBziuE3a() •03 -=&gt;icis| "— c o -*■ 'c 3 O O •© O s « _ « la ■&gt;-&gt; U s &gt; . O O I- w 6-- i,« tS tP fcS -^ ~ z&gt; ai as s s si &lt;^ °° r *^r o« rs. ov in = Id §g|SS5ISi a S?3S2 OO "^S a ie " £ B v a . = B - I] -I ao &gt;n &gt;o r&gt;. tx 00 O &gt; if. R^O 00 O&gt; E* rm — rvj^^^ rvi ~ («4 — r\) tM £g "l y3 r&gt;. »r» r&gt;. r^. 00 t ■ ■o?5 i i o &lt; - 3 n — c "■ I 3 Z u I E s ?l H * H = : m : « ~ : (vj fiooo^f^oo^o; b5 g g g g g g g og _^_R S 8 g §8 g f^&lt;g a H "a 2 H "•8 u a T 2. &lt;n •* ■* w u~. •* 5 t: — ss§Si s s a -| 3 3 B XjOJDBJSIJESUn O*O^»-ti-t©Ov0 t^l **} r^ f^ «a o 1| I I 1 j *l &lt; Z 2 &amp; &amp; z £ £ ft = 0 3 £ s </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 13, 1928. Circular Letter No. 16. Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1928. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, Ne - braska National Guard. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1928, having been set, i. e., August 6th to 20th, 1928, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section III, National Guard Regulations 45, 1927. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein as non compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of Company Officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the United States Property and Distribusing Officer as to the exact hour of departure from home station, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation requests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company Commanders are authorized to purchase one day's travel ration for enlisted men at one dollar and twenty cents per ration, and will follow instructions received from the USP &amp; DO per - taining thereto. 4. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained; i. e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct must be correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements By Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The Commanding Officer will make a thorough inspection of the train before troops entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp, and report to the Camp Commander immediately upon arrival any defects or faults found with railroads transporting troops. 5. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company Commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 85 clothing to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear them on leaves or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Training Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing; i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional Equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment consisting of axes, water bags, G. I. cans, colors, field desk, lanterns, marking outfits, rakes, ranges, typewriters, shovels, tools and all cleaning materials; all tentage of whatsoever nature, including poles and stakes therefor together with latrine screens and poles. Information pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment and harness will be furnished in a sep - arate Circular Letter. No target material will be brought to camp as it will be furnished there. All tentage, G. I. cans, rakes, ranges and shovels will be stored in the respective kitchens at the Rifle Range this year, which will do away with the necessity of hauling same back and forth at each camp. Spring cots will be furnished upon arrival at camp and they will also be stored in the mess halls. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition except the initial alowances, 1928, and the cal. .22 long rifle, will be brought to camp and turned in to the USP &amp; DO, securing memorandum reecipt for same. All empty cartridges, (brass), in packing boxes, Belgian aiming devices, all arm racks and lockers, all rifles and pistols and in fact, all arms with which each respective organization is equipped together with all other ordnance with which the individual and Companies are equipped, excepting Machine Gun Companies, which will bring two machine gun carts and two ammunition carts, also excepting the Howitzer Company, which will bring one mortar cart, one mortar ammunition cart, and one 37mm gun carriage. However, these organizations will bring all guns to camp. 9. Special Equipment. All Signal, Medical and Engineer prop - erty, including lister bags, is to be carried. 10. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken; 1. e., Property Records, Individual Records, Stationery, Service Records, </seg>
            <seg id="p086">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 86 Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in duplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in dupli - cate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. Telegraphic reports of strength when entraining are NOT required this year. 11. Messes. All Company Officers will mess with their organiza - tion and should provide themselves with tables and chairs. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things to - ward contentment and good morale of an organization. The Com - manding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, together with the Commanding Officer, 35th Divi - sion Train, Q. M. C, will establish Officers' messes for the Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff and Instructors, as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 6th, 1928. 12. Enlisted Men's Motor Transportation. No motor trans - portation will be permitted in the enlisted men's camp area this year. Enlisted men bringing motor transportation to camp will be required to register same and to have passes for same going in and out of the grounds from where they will be parked on the south side of the main highway (where the picket line was last year) and they will be re - quired to stay from taps until 4:00 P. M. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 17. Subject: Transportation. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 87 1. Mounts: Mounts will be furnished to the respective organ- izations as follows: a. State 7 Officers, 3 Orderlies, 1 Senior Inst., 1 for the Governor. Staff 134th Inf. 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 5 Majors, 3 Bn. Adj., 1 Aux. Bn. Adj., 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 1 P. &amp; T., 4 Orderlies, (1 for Regtl. Hq. and 1 each for the Bn. Hqs. ) 35th Div. Tn. 4 Tn. Hq., 4 to Ea. Wag. Co 3 to Att. M. D. 110th Med. Regt. 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 2 Majors (P. &amp; T., Veterinarian D. S. O.) 1 Adj., 1 Supply Officer, 2 Orderlies. b. The responsible officers for the following Sub-units will furnish riding equipment with grain and feed bags. State Maj. W. E. McConnaughey, 12 sets. Staff 134th C. O. Regimental Hq. Co., 6 sets. Inf. C. O. Battalion Hq. Cos. 3 sets, each. C. O. Service Co., 2 sets. C. O. Attached Medical Det., 1 set. 3 5th C. O. 120th Wagon Co., 11 sets. Div. Tn. C. O. Headquarters Detachment, 4 sets 110th Med. C. O. Service Company, 8 sets. Regiment 2. Mules, Draft: Mules will be assigned as follows: a. Camp Quartermaster 4 134th Infantry M. G. Companies 4 each. Howitzer Company 2 Service Company 20 35th Dv. Train. Wagon Co. No. 119 20 Wagon Co. No. 120 20 b. Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows: USP &amp; DO — All harness and wagons required for Service Company, 134th Infantry, Wagon Companies of the 35th Division Train and Camp Quartermaster. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The C. O.s of the M. G. Companies and Howitzer Com - pany will furnish the necessary harness for the animals assigned them. 3. Motor Vehicles: a. USP &amp; DO will transport all available trucks and am - bulances stored at the State Arsenal to Camp. b. The Commanding Officer, Motor Repair Section No. 119, 35th Division Train, QMC, will detail two truck drivers for the pur - pose of transporting Artillery Repair Truck to Camp, leaving Holdrege so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 6th. c. The Commanding Officer, Company E, 134th Inf., will de - tail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting class B, Liberty Truck, from Scottsbluff, Nebraska, so as to arrive at Ashland, Ne - braska, August 6th. d. The Commanding Officer, Company F, 134th Inf., will de - tail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting class B, Liberty Truck from Hartington, Nebraska, so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebras - ka, August 6th. e. The Commanding Officer, Co. K, will detail two truck drivers for the purpose of transporting class B, Liberty Truck so as to arrive at Ashland, Nebraska, August 6th, not later than 9:00 A. M. Drivers will report to Camp Transportation Officer im - mediately upon their arrival. As no Federal Funds are available for the expense of this movement they will take receipts for actual expenses incurred enroute, for which they will be reimbursed by the State. 4. All organizations having Government owned motor vehicles assigned them, will immediately after arrival in camp and unloading of equipment have these vehicles report to the Camp Transportation Officer, to be placed in the camp pool for the duration of camp. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 89 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Welfare Work To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chaplain, 134th Infantry, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned, and it Is requested that all aid be given to the Chaplains in their work. "It is desired. to make the work of the Chaplains in the annual encampment as helpful to all ranks as possible. For this purpose all officers are requested to cooperate with the Chaplains to the fullest possible extent and to inform their organizations of the provisions made. The Chaplain of the 134th Infantry and the Chaplain of the 110th Medical Regiment will be in camp available for any service in their line of duty and for consultation. Religious services will be con - ducted, entertainments and motion pictures planned, writing tables with stationery provided and the Recreation Hut open at all times. The Chaplain's Office may be used by visitors as their headquarters and information center. Officers commanding organizations are requested immediately on arrival in camp to furnish to the Chaplain's Office, through the Camp Adjutant, one copy of roster of all men in camp for use in the in - formation and post offices. Attention is called to the necessity for instruction in the form of addressing mail coming to camp. This form should be called to the attention of relatives and friends by all ranks. Rank and Organization must be given, as: PRIVATE PAUL JONES Company "B", 134th Infantry National Guard Camp Ashland, Nebraska. All ranks are urged to feel at liberty to call on the Chaplains for any service they can render or for personal consultation. HAROLD C. CAPSEY, Capt., Chaplain, NNG." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">00 a I L-5 O rH 6 » od&lt;j &gt;, 3 «» — ■*• a o -o ■H d a I &lt; US 500? 5 mb c -5- I ■ Og&lt;! 3 00 ! is o a) a _0 p •a 0 o 6 a I HI CD i I .53 o £ co o bog US — BO rt rH 1H iH iH iH t ° &lt; g % * H J eo 2 •&lt; ■&lt; t. « tf g h n a h z I ° I » 0) CM I 2 s at i 00 CD iH "*« " c o =3 I -no a a J I 08 s II I H-- - -I - H I 2 I 5 ■° s ® !sh ; f s.. - 5 ££ o &lt;a c O c — "5 I o 00 t* CO IO M CO CO o u a 6 3 OH m &gt; fc r-&lt; a x OS t- BO 5 1 B 6 o HOOt- &lt;0 Cvl 5 u a&gt; C3 s o O» t* t* CO IO CO CO CO 00 c S U o -sg </seg>
            <seg id="p091">5 a 0) 02 ■i-J a o 1 1 = 1 — . U C &lt;J = ► r.ij PI 00 c ,&lt;|oia Jl •3oo o-* .. fc N N • • • • t-1 tn 3 © O O Cfl OQgO J J&lt;&lt; &gt; • &gt; (- &gt; *- J&lt;! J&lt;! J&lt;! : s s ? eo -&lt;J © eq z o w f o *J ta O * tH • 3 • s « o a a co a _ » . S . &gt; •h^f^b&gt; . &gt;' i' - &gt; &gt; ■- M - 1H T-l —I *H r-l iH rt — . to 5S la to CO C0 U3 t-h IP ia fH O U3 0 O w o J IE S S s 3 e O o S h X ■3 -r. 5 a B s 'c ■3 a o I "5 c e CO rH d d O o o b d J3 O T-H r-i 13 C a C H e cq = 6&amp;S-. Uo.o 5 u o .fcP o d M 6 . O o .6 I d a: *j s &lt;j S &gt; o "tig 1,5 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">1 I to *2»d o _; io a o o — 2 »i! " r" w ■" J; 9*j'"o_ S^do° &lt;&lt;! d &lt; g£is^ 6^ .k&gt;o ■ &gt; I ► H l» &gt;-' o aj o ja aa hid a o* 2 ► IO &gt; .»:^ . j &lt; &lt; t- * i _: ri &lt; JO -° § a §S .. a o "I- 1 • ea ■ . &gt; \ &gt; oo iJtOiJN to 3 1 g in a 6 U la ■c c H tH rH M S I 2 'I c 5 rt o &lt;2 53 OS 00 OS O&gt; us &lt;*&lt; s s a s o c i S g c I 5 2 o c I X be s a c O d 2 c o S t "3 a a o s = 5 T-l d □ e o d .O o o en GO Hrt Q CO to xA "3 0) a 5 Q l b £ I a 6 0 6 ? g 6 2 S^-e 4-&gt; qj DQ C t- ® o f* O m d </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, 93 Movement No. 1. Co. "I" will load In one baggage car. 3d Bn. Hq. Co. and Hq. 35th Div. Tn. will load in one baggage car. Vet. Co. No. 110, F. &amp; S. 110th M. R. and Det. Dv. Sur. O. will load in one baggage car. Movement No. 2. Co. "B" will load in one baggage car. Co, 'A" and 1st Bn. Hq. Co. will load in one baggage car. Regtl. Hq. Co, and F. &amp; S. 134th Inf. will load in one baggage car. Co. "K" will load in one baggage car. Co. L will load in one baggage car. Med. Dept. Det. and 2d Bn. Hq. Co. in one baggage car. Movement No. 3. Co. "C" will reserve space for Band 110th M. R. Movement No. 5. Wag. Co. No. 120 and Med. Dept. Det. 35th Div. Tn. will load in one baggage car. 137th M. T. Co., and 119th M. R. S. will load in one baggage car. 2. Tickets. Government Transportation Requests on the Railroad con - cerned will be exchanged for tickets at the local ticket office. Re - quests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. Railroad Equipment. Baggage cars to be set the day preceding the movement to permit loading baggage "and installation of field ranges, where it is necessary. Tourist cars or coaches to be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner in ample time to permit trains to leave at designated time. The above number of passengers is based, in most instances, on last year's camp attendance. 4. Baggage. 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hard baggage, etc. (Par. 28 NGR. 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bills of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bills of Lading, covering such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC-NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 20. Subject: Passengers Carried on Transportation Request, Annual Encampment, 1928. To: All Company Commanders, All Field and Staff Officers, Ne - braska National Guard. 1. In accordance with Par. 2, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 16, 1928, the following' table will be used for the guidance of all Company Commanders to whom transportation requests are issued: Officers to Whom Requests Issued. Company and Additional Passengers to Be Carried 134th Infantry Capt. J. H. McAlpin Regtl. Hq. Co., Field &amp; Staff, Omaha. Capt. C. J. Ayers Service Co. (Less Service Detachment.) Capt. J. Ned Allison Howitzer Co. 1st Lt. Leslie Yager, Jr 1st Bn. Hq. Co Capt. W. H. Achenbach, D. C. Capt. Ray A. Thurman Co. A Capt. W. G. Utterback. Capt. Win. Schneider Co. B Major E. D. Fisher. Capt. F. H. Stoll Co. C. Capt. B. B. Miltonberger Co. D. 1st Lt. Guy T. Davis 2nd Bn. Hq. Co Capt. F. W. Stone Co. E. Capt. L. R. Eby Co. F. Capt. A. Rleber Co. G. Capt. A. F. Miller Co. H. l«t Lt. Trev. Gillasple 3rd Bn. Hq. Co Major E. M. Cline. Capt. E. F. Hoke Co. I Lt. Col. R. G. Douglas. Capt. Claude Frlmann Co. K. Capt. H. F. Elsasser Co. L. Capt. E. J. Geesen Co. M. Major R. R. Ensor Att. Med. Detachment. 35th Division Train 1st Lt. C. J. Williams Hq. Det. (Less Serv. Detachment) Major M. L. Poteet. 1st Lt. H. H. Ellis Mot. Tr. Co. No. 137. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 95 1st Lt. L. E. Chadderdon.... Mot. Rep. Sec. No. 119 Capt. V. M. Hovis Wagon Co. No. 119. Capt. G. N. Henninger Wagon Co. No. 120 Att. Med. Detachment. 110th Medical Regiment W. O. L. C. Havlicek Band Sec. Service Co. Capt. L. A. Swanson Ambulance Co. No. 130. Capt. S. W. Alford Veterinary Co. No. 110, P. &amp; S. Det. D. S. O. Capt. J. N. Evans Collecting Co. No. 130. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC-NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 21. Subject: Physical Condition of Enlisted men. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. Each year there have been brought to camp men who were not physically fit and who required operations of different kinds and, upon requesting that same be taken care of at camp, we have so far taken care of them. These men have been of no particular value to the service as a whole and have been an additional burden and ex - pense to both the State and Federal Government; so, commencing with this year, the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed but have been brought about in line of duty. 2. Each year a number of venereal cases have been brought to camp and there treated. These men are of no value to the service, are a burden upon the State and Federal Government and endanger the health of the other men. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL S. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will advise their commands that commencing this year no venereal cases will be permitted in camp, that a rigid physical examination will be given all men upon their arrival at camp, and any man found with a venereal disease will be returned to bis borne station at his own expense, without pay or al - lowances, and will be required to refund both railroad fair and sub - sistence expended on him in bringing him to camp. 4. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders will make every effort to ascertain that his men are physically fit before bringing them to camp and that they do not come under the heads mentioned above and will read this letter to his command at every armory drill between the time of receipt of same and the time of entraining at camp. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 17, 1928. Circular Letter 22. Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment, 1928. To: Officer Responsible for same. 1. Government Transportation Request No. WQ is inclosed herewith, to cover Railroad transportation for your Company to Ash - land, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows, after the number of persons for whom transportation is required has been de - termined: a. Enter with pen, ink or indelible pencil under the block, "Number of Persons", the total aggregate to be transported. b. Opposite "Est. cost $ ", enter the TOTAL cost. c. Signature of Responsible Officer with title thereunder on the lower right hand corner of the Request. d. Postal card report (WD MB No. 36) will be completed as required thereon and turned in immediately upon arrival at Camp to the U8P ft DO, (Camp Quartermaster's Office). </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 97 2. If, prior to the surrender of Transportation Request to the ticket agent, it be found necessary to alter entries made thereon, such changes will be fully explained over your signature and rank in the blank space under Par. 2 of the instructions on the back thereof. Postal card report required above must be absolutely correct, showing the number of persons actually travelling as members of your party. 3. In view of the fact that all accommodations in excess of those authorized by regulations when actually used, must be charged against the officer responsible for the error, the suggestion is made that, prior to leaving, you familiarize yourself with the provisions of N. G. R. 70, and 71. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Nebraska. Major QMC-NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 18, 1928. Circular Letter No. 23. Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1928. To: Officer Responsible for Same. 1. Government Bill of Lading WQ A is inclosed here - with for excess baggage (freight) involved in movement of your Com - pany to Ashland, Nebraska, which should be completed as follows: a. Number and description of packages and correct weight should be inserted. All military impedimenta except personal bag - gage must be weighed and listed according to its commercial name, for example, Fire Arms or Ammunition, not as Ordnance; Clothing or Blankets, not as personal equipment; Tents, canvas, or Poles, tent, wood, or Stove, field range, iron, not as Quartermaster Property, giving the separate weights and manner of packing, so as to ascer - tain the classification and rates and to enable recovery in case of loss or damage, (Par. 15, N. G. R. 72). b. Opposite "Est. Cost $ ", insert the total actual cost after ascertaining same from the agent. « </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. Opposite "Loaded in car No ", "Initials of Car ", insert the car number and initials. •1. Only Federal Property to be transported on this Bill of Lading. e. Uae typewriter, single space and disregard lines. Only fill in the three columns "Number and Description of Packages", "Contents" and "Weights". 2. Bill of Lading will be disposed of as follows: «. Original and three memo copies to be signed by your local Agent b. Shipping Order to be surrendered to local Agent. c. Original surrendered to Agent at Ashland, Nebraska, prop- erly executed. d. Two memos to be immediately delivered to U. S. Property and Disbursing Officer upon arrival at camp. «•. Retain one memo for Company files. 3. The above must be strictly complied with. Attention invited to National Guard Regulations 71 and 72, the provisions of which must be strictly complied with. You are advised that you are acting as Agent to the USP &amp; DO in this shipment. 4. There is also inclosed herewith, a supply of W. D. MB form No. 34 Property List, which should be prepared as outlined in Par. SO. N. G. R. 71. 5. Transportation may be hired at a reasonable rate for the pur - pose of transporting baggage and equipment from the Armory to the Depot and return. Invoices in duplicate should be furnished this office with Public Voucher, Standard Form No. 1034 and 1034-a, properly executed for the incoming and return movement. These ac - counts must be in by the last of August so that settlement may be made on the whole, to see that this allowance has not been exceeded. 0. Transportation will be provided by this Department for haul - ing organization equipment and baggage to the Rifle Ranges from the Sioux City-Ashland branch of the C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. on the D-L-D High - way. Immediately upon arrival, the Officers in charge of Companies xliould designate a baggage detail for handling this equipment and nee that they slay there until the unloading is completed. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major QMC-NNG., USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 99 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA July 19, 1928. ■Circular Letter No. 24. Subject: Travel Rations to Annual Encampment, 1928. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, Nebraska Na - braska National Guard. 1. In accordance with Par. 3, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 16, 1928, Company Commanders will purchase the necessary travel rations. The Components of this ration are found in T. M. No. 2100 - 152 Section II, Paragraph 4c (copy furnished to each unit, recently). 2. Public Vouchers, Standard Form No. 1034 and 1034a with extra sheets are enclosed for stating accounts due and must be ac - companied by invoices in duplicate. Ration Return QMC No. 72, certified to by the Company Commander and approved by the Regi - mental or similar Commander, must be submitted with the above to the USP &amp; DO — Nebraska as soon as possible after arrival in Camp. 3. To expedite the payments of vouchers attention is invited to the following: a. Complete the Voucher in detail. b. Certificate, that account is correct — See note at bottom of form 1034. c. Certificate, that articles have been received, etc., to be signed by Company Commander and completed in accordance with No. 4 with the word "oral" opposite No. 4 on back of original and duplicate Voucher. d. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across the face of the Voucher, "Travel Rations, Co Regt. (so many) Enlisted men." e. The use of colored inks or carbon paper other than black and alterations or erasures will not be accepted. f. It is suggested that the rations be purchased from one firm to avoid delay in payment of Vouchers to determine whether the amount authorized has been exceeded. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC-NNG. USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">H CM B. d3 3 •a .1 •Sb Oh 2 "s •a a u a c o o «^5 S — 3 ■ • B S fc Oh' CO i IS II *^ .fi 00 u 6 o *-l go i-H iH i-t c H 2 ■ « 1 E a e E i gis B fc O _, J *J B°°^ all ai If* III I |s M S I* — . — 1-1 to in CO T-t CO CO B a 2 £ 5 g«5 III a 0) 2 5 s c 2 0) 6 a&gt; 2O I I a o H o IH •a a a ■ — CO A O eo rt hhn ■ »H £3 rH i-H &lt;n 66'3a&gt; 66^^ .f^S I d o d U _C3 5S 2 I g o E a D </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 T GE¥Ti FERAL, 2 "5 ■o . 00 &lt;i ho — — 6 = . So, oo \ —I M &lt; CO CO d -si s -hiS -3- £ u — • &lt;! &lt;■ a ■ jdi hi - rH rH iH iH f* rt o ca a . =5 la =■1 t*(01OAt&gt;OOHU3 CO CO i-l CM CO CO t- c- « CO co eo OS t- U3 CO a a o o ho c | 3 5 3 o 6 5 s. I 0 B _o 3 3 N 'H a tx O d a x B a •a 6»S«»tidd IS d Q .dw .« vU a*; . - g 5^^ ddl^S*-^ h 6 o 2 s o S CD £ s 6 |B|fcS 6 • ® d a d </seg>
            <seg id="p102">DJUTANT GENERAL u_ 00 00 00 00 00 M 94 « N N V. \ \ \ e © © © o •4 94 TC •« 04 M hi as ho so 9 9 3 3 S ki s I o I 'a a s s s &lt;■ eu . cu &amp;i &lt; e M e a°s e s° e*e e*o*o c. a_ a_ a_ a Ut)0«U«0fO S &lt;^ n© a?. ta o IB 3 I g CO a &gt;' u &gt; u &gt; u &gt; •- &gt;' 6 ss 11* r^ M o ■w (M — M 5 s S 1 I ! c e 2 e c S "3 "3 c 5 I &amp; s o M . e d S « ESS 2 2 6 0 H CO u •Km Q I a c s ? S I i-s ~ Cue- I pi | 1 — ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 103 Movement No. 1. Co. "C" and Band, 110th M. R. will use one baggage car. Wag. Co. No. 120th and M. D. Dept. Det. 35th Div. Tn., will use one baggage car. M. T. Co. No. 137th and M. R. S. No. 119 will use one baggage car. Movement No. 4. Co. "I" will use one baggage car. 3d Bn. Hq. Co. and Hq. 35th Div. Tn. will use one baggage car. Vet. Co. No. 110, and Det. Dv. Sur. O. will use one baggage car. 1st Bn. Hq. Co. and Co. "A" will use one baggage car. Movement No. 5. Med. Dept. Det. and 2nd Bn. Hq. Co., will use one baggage car. 2. Tickets. Government Transportation Requests on the Railroad con - cerned will be exchanged for tickets at the local ticket office. Re - quests for berths to be exchanged with the Pullman conductor for accommodations actually furnished. 3. Baggage. 150 pounds of personal baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barrack bags, bedding rolls, hand baggage, etc., (Par. 28 NGR. 71). Each piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be in - cluded on Bills of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bills of Lading, cover - ing such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. 4. Passengers and organizations to be carried will be those that are shown in Nebraska Circular Letter No. 20, 1928. BY DIRECTION' OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC-NNG. USP &amp; DO — Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 104 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 1, 1928. Circular Letter No. 26. Subject: Canvas Cots. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. In letter of instruction sent from this office, canvas cots were not enumerated among the articles to be brought to camp. Owing to the fact that we have secured spring cots for all of the enlisted per - sonnel, canvas cots will be left at home. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 1, 1928. Circular Letter No. 27. Subject: Discharge of Enlisted Men. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. This office is repeatedly being called upon to issue orders dis - charging enlisted men and to date the orders back from one to six weeks. This practice cannot be continued and from the receipt of this letter on, orders will be issued when application is reecived by this office and on the date received, so unit and sub-unit commanders must govern themselves acordingly. 2. Request for orders to discharge men should be mailed direct to this office and not sent through channels as that almost invariably delays getting out the order several days. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 105 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 15, 1928. Circular Letter No. 28. Subject: Armory Drill Pay To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. 1. The following radiogram from the Chief of Militia Bureau, August 10, 1928, to the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "By direction of Secretary of War the requirements that sixty per cent maintenance strength be in attendance in order to qualify officers and warrant officers belonging to organization for armory drill pay are waived during months of July and August, 1928, for those units inital pay periods of less than three months under provisions of Militia Bureau Circular No. 19, May 23, 1928." 2. The State of Nebraska was assigned an initial pay period of two months (July and August 1928) by Nebraska Circular Letter No. 15, July 12, 1928. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 24, 1928. Circular Letter No. 29. Subject: Oaths on Armory Drill Payrolls To: All Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. The following letter, dated August 11, 1928, from the Comptroller General of the United States, to the Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "Your attention is invited to the fact that the oaths on numerous armory drill pay rolls in .the accounts of Finance Officers were administered by persons acting in an official char- </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL acter other than a Summary Court Officer without showing any evidence of authority to administer oaths. Paragraph 34, N. G. R., 37 provides that: 'Oaths for administrative purposes. Paragraph 138, Manual for Court-Mart ial, 1921, does not confer power on the persons therein named to administer oaths in National Guard adminis - tration. A summary court officer is authorized by section 105, national defense act, to administer oaths for administrative pur - poses; as to others having that power the law of the State must be consulted. (M. C. M. 138).' It is respectfully requested that the oaths on all armory drill pay rolls paid in the future, if administered by other than a Summary Court Officer, bear the impress of the seal pertinent to the official character in which the person acts in administer - ing the oaths, or show a citation to the section of the State law that authorizes the individual to administer such oaths. C. C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." 1. Paragraph 3360, chapter 6 H.34, Art. 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1922, reads as follows: "Commissioned officer may administer oath. All commis - misioned officers of the Nebraska National Guard are hereby authorized and impowered to administer oaths and affirmations to written affidavits necessary for the due administration of military business. (1909 p. 384; Ann. 7262; Comp. 4471; R. S. 1913, 3962.)" BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 16, 1928. Circular Letter No. 30. Subject: Repair, Renovation of Clothing and Individual Equipment and Maintenance of Organization Equipment, F. Y. 1929. To: All Responsible Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. It is directed that you furnish this office, not later than No- vember 15, 1928, separate estimates for the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p107">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 107 a. Repair and renovation of Clothing and Individual Equip- ment. b. Maintenance of Organizational Equipment. 2. In no case will any obligation be incurred until estimate called for above has been approved by this office. 3. Major repairs of heavy tentage that was left at camp, Ashland, Nebraska, will be repaired by the USP &amp; DO — Nebraska, insofar as Federal Funds will permit. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 6, 1928. Circular Letter No. 31. Subject: Examinations of Candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The annual preliminary examination for the selection of one - enlisted man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive examination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office beginning November 12, 1928, at 9:00 A. M. 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an applicant must be an enlisted man of the unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1929, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years and must be not less than 5' 4" in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and con - not be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. The requirements for admis - sion to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the inclosed pamphlet. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War De - partment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 5, 1929 and the appoint- </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL menta available on July 1, 1929, will be awarded to the qualified candidate in the order of merit established at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously, applicants have presented themselves to this office to take this examination who were in no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. Company Commanders will make any members of their command who have a desire to take this examination conversant with the requirements of the inclosed pamphlet, and while some believe that a High School graduate can pass this examination, it has been demonstrated that unless they have had at least one year in college, in addition to their High School education, it will be time wasted. 5. Owing to a shortage of funds, it will be impossible for the State to pay any part of the expenses of applicants in coming in for this examination. 6. The return of this pamphlet is requested. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 14, 1928. Circular Letter No. 32. Subject: : Requisition for Blank Forms and Publications, To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Requisition for blank forms and publications, form number 22, NNG., are being received from day to day and will not be honored only as outlined in Nebraska Circular Letter Number 2, 1928. 2. Some responsible offiicers conceived the idea that the requisi - tion period for forms had been changed to correspond with the armory drill pay roll period. This is not the case and you are cautioned that you should anticipate your needs for the ensuing quarter. Requisi - tions are due in this office at the close of each quarter. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 109 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT NEBRASKA December 28, 1928. Circular Letter No. 33. Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There are inclosed herewith blank efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1928, and which should have your immediate attention. 2. Before attempting to make this report, you are directed to make a thorough study of the instructions contained thereon, which are full and explicit and, if followed explicitly, will bring the proper report to this office before the expiration of the month. 3. After having given a thorough study to the instructions on both sides of the efficiency reports, make out your reports and for - ward same without further delay to the officer to whom the instruc - tions direct you. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Let us all get them in, in proper form, and AT ONCE. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. SPANISH WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who parti - cipated in the service of the Spanish-American War in the First, Sec - ond, and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry: fUJll'AN X A *'l a *x^—r i iii.il nrjULOXiii x tank Name Anit. Dae Rank Name Anit. Due Tt. Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Tt. Allen, Roller C 3.20 Pvt. Freeman, Charlie 0 3.20 Pvt. Gelvln, Robert N 3.20 •vt. Buri, George J 3.20 'Tt. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 'vt. Morgenstern, Henry A. 3.20 •vt. Shively,, Blon 3.20 Pvt. Hensley, Minor N 3.20 Pvt. Kremer, Cochron A... 4.00 Pvt. Sommers, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W 3.20 Pvt. Wompler, Elmer B 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY B — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Garinger, Albert JO. 80 Andrews, Chas. J 4.00 Rank Name Amt . Doe Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Black, John 4.00 Pvt. Grainger, Louis 1 1.60 Pvt. Killhom, Perry A 4.00 Pvt. Ressekuie, Herbert L. 4.00 COMPANY C — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Johnson, Hans $3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 Campbell, Roy G 3.20 Pvt. COMPANY D — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alley, John S $4.00 Pvt. Alley, John S $4.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M 4.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie. Samuel B 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.00 Pvt. Bioom, John J 4.00 COMPANY E — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Ami . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name A int. Dae Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Amerman, Arba B 1.60 Pvt. Amerman, Arba B 1.60 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Moffet, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Moffet, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Llsk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Peclnovsky, Jos. W... 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W... 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 Pvt. Bays, Wm 80 Pvt. Bays, Wm 80 COMPANY F — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P...$3.20 Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P...$3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W 3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua .... 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua .... 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston .... 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston .... 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 COMPANY G — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Sgt. Name Amt. Due Burlington, John $3.20 Anderson, Hugh S 80 Deaver, Harvey W 3.20 Dowis, Jonathan E 3.20 Merryman, John R 3.20 Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Mohler, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Underwood, Henry C. 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 111 COMPANY H — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name .Amt. Due .A mt . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H $3.20 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H $3.20 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 Pvt. Brisbine, Lewis H 2.40 Pvt. Brisbine, Lewis H 2.40 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W 1.60 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S... 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S... 4.00 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 1.60 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 1.60 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Winagel, Anthony J... 2.40 Pvt. Winagel, Anthony J... 2.40 Pvt. Peterson, Hanc C 4.00 Pvt. Peterson, Hanc C 4.00 COMPANY I — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Hotsell, Leon V $4.00 Berndtson, John E 4.00 Bordwell, Frank J 4.00 Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 COMPANY K — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name A n it . Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Delong, Herbert B $3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L... 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Pvt. Fingado, Harry, Jr 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N 3.20 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 3.20 COMPANY L, — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Rank Name Amt. Due Name A nit . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Pvt. Downs, James W J3.20 Downs, James W $3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B 3.20 Humphrey, Mortimer Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H... 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H... 3.20 B 3.20 COMPANY M — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Cpl. Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin A 3.20 Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L... 3.20 Pvt. Jack, Cecil B 3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 Pvt. Kennedy, Phillip S 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF — SECOND REGIMENT Rank P. M. Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Brown, Robert S $4.00 Mus. Murnhouse, F. Edd... . 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY A — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Rank Name Amt. Due A nit . Due Rank Name A mt. Due Rank Name A mt. Due Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H...$3.20 Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H...$3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Paine, Lewis A 3.20 Cpl. Paine, Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K 3.20 Pvt. Blough, Clay C 3.20 Pvt. Blough, Clay C 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T... 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T... 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Tuffs, Prank 3.20 Prt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Prank 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Prt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David A 3.20 Forman, David A 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Woodruff, Charles .... 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles .... 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William .... 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William .... 3.20 COMPANY B — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Prink, Alberto D $3.20 Whitmer, James K 3.20 Crow, Wallace H 3.20 Grossett, Chas. E 3.20 Briggs, Ernest G. Rank Name Amt . Due Cpl. Cpl. Pvt. Jackson, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Prank 3.20 Wag. Art. Pvt. Williams, Prank 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Wilson, Eli A 3.20 (Died in service) .. 3.20 COMPANY C — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Rank Name Ami . Due Name Amt . Due Rank Name Anil. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George $3.20 Cpl. Miles, George $3.20 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 Cpl. Spencer, Hiram C 1.60 Spencer, Hiram C 1.60 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 3.20 Cpl. Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 Pvt. Kime, David 1.60 Pvt. Kime, David 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Ira E 3.20 Pvt. Lee, Ira E 3.20 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E... 1.60 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E... 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R... 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R... 3.20 Pvt. Shank 1 in, Sylvester .... 1.60 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester .... 1.60 COMPANY D — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Anit . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Aint . Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M. 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M. 4.00 Pvt. Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 Ludwick, George L 4.00 COMPANY E — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Ami. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name . An it . Dae Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick ?3.20 Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.2ft </seg>
            <seg id="p113">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 113 Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W... 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J... 3.20 Rank Name A nit. Dae Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E 3.20 Pvt. Vandervort, Sam'l M. 3.20 COMPANY F — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dne Rank Name Amt. Dne Pvt. Grofton, George $3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 COMPANY G — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dne Rank Name Amt. Dne 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli $3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T 80 Cpl. Hays, Robert A 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F 80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V... .80 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H 80 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L 80 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E 80 Pvt. Fisher, Leo 80 Pvt. Ritter, David 80 Pvt. Gainey, John H 80 Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D... .80 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr... 3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry 80 COMPANY H— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dne Cpl. Borland, John A $4-00 Pvt. Johnston, George H... 4.00 Art. Neill, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvali 4.00 Pvt. Bowers, Henry H 4.00 Pvt. Meitner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 4.00 Pvt. Davis, Harry E 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Serensen, Ole C 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry 0 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 4.00 COMPANY I — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dne QM Sgt. Rainey, Jacob A $4.00 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 Cpl. Giblin, John S 4.00 Pvt. Schuelke, Herman A... 4.00 Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore.. 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. Walker, Joseph H 4.00 Pvt. Humpal, John J 4.00 Pvt. Way, Rueben D 4.00 Pvt. Penland, John W 80 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY K — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Ant. Dae Pvt. Erickson, Francis T...$3.20 Pvt. West, Charles 3.20 Cpl. Hill, John T 3.20 COMPANY L — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Jack, Charles H $2.40 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Clarenden, Alvin T 4.00 Pvt. Evans, John 3.20 Cpl. Sage, John M 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Wellman, Frank P 3.20 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Art. Carter, Charles J 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, Wm. C 80 Pvt. Powell, Joseph A 3.20 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt. Sloan, John H 2.40 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Collins, James R 3.20 Pvt. Cottrell, Eugene W 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 COMPANY M — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Alfreds, Frank H $5.60 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W. 5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Schwart, Wm 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncon C 5.60 FIELD STAFF AND BAND — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, Roy D. $9.60 RB Mus. Lyon, Harry C 1.60 RB Mus. Parkhurst, Harry .. 3.20 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L...12.00 COMPANY A — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W. $32.55 Pvt. Horahan, Chas 5.60 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 Pvt. HJnckley, John S. .... 1.60 Cpl. Steinbach, George 12.72 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Matthew 1.60 Pvt. Koontz, Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N. 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. O'Leary, John J 2.40 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 Pvt. Pace, Perle R 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Pierce, Frank W 10.84 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Art. Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Schneider, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Allen, Thomas 4.80 Pvt. Smith, John J 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 Pvt. Taylor, James J 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 115 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Trombly, Warden Pvt. Collins, John H 1.60 Pvt. Gallenbuck, Frank J. 1.60 Pvt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 A. F 18.39 Pvt. Wolf, Chas. T 2.40 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr. 2.40 COMPANY B — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Covell, Herbert E. $33.64 Sgt. Spencer, Chas. L 33.64 Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. Bradford, George H. .80 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Pvt. McGrew, Frank 80 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W. 33.64 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas 80 Pvt. Place, John F 21.36 Pvt. Custer, Elisha 80 Pvt. Ray, Evert P 20.42 Pvt. Francisco, John H 80 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust ....33.64 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Roop, Scott D 80 Pvt. Greenlee, William .... 3.20 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E 33.64 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Schwartz, Wm 80 Pvt. Habbick, George W... 1.60 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N 80 Pvt. Jarvis, Chas. T 80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E. 33.64 Pvt. Keanes, James N 80 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 Pvt. Line, Jno. M 17.59 Pvt. Whalen, Edwin F 3.20 Pvt. Metts, Edmond M 80 COMPANY C — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. White, Thomas R. $27.46 Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Cpl. Dillion, Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip .... 2.40 Pvt. Costello, Michael F. 13.30 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P. .. 8.58 Cpl. Sydow, Emil 27.46 Pvt. DeRivieres, Francis L. 4.80 Cpl. Miller, Wm. E 27.46 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Cpl. Burkett, Harry B 2.40 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W. 27.46 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E 27.46 Pvt. Howell, Harry H 22.74 Pvt. Keliher, John F 4.80 Pvt. Long, Wilber W 5.75 Pvt. Mitchell, Edward F. 2.40 Pvt. Norton, Ernest H 11.41 Pvt. Henske, Fred 80 Pvt. Hawkins, Elgin C 8.58 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F 2.40 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.80 Pvt. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albin F. 2.40 Pvt. Zurubsky, James 7.64 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Pvt. Sheil, Daniel J 7.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY D — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Ant, Dae Rank Name .Ami . Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D. $ 4.80 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B. ..26.74 Pvt. Jansen, Nels P 23.91 Pvt. Juul, John M 30.52 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C 80 Cpl. Christensen, Pvt. Kregersen, Henry ....22.96 Christian A 36.18 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry 1.60 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M 8.00 Mus. Howell, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G 8.00 Pvt. Allwein, John C 1.60 Pvt. Anderson, Edward .... 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew .. 3.20 Pvt. Pool, John E 4.80 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S 4.80 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Sutton, Frank E 6.40 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Warren, Walter H 6.40 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 Pvt. Wiederholz, John J. ..28.63 Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 COMPANY E — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Siddell, Bert E |13.01 Pvt. Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Pvt. Flenniken, Robert B. 13.96 Pvt. Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L 80 Pvt. Lewin, Samuel C 80 COMPANY P — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A. $36.69 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P 36.69 Art. Becker, Otto 36.69 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Baughman, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Hon. Anton 1.60 Pvt. Brunker, Frank 1.60 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius 36.69 Pvt. Johns, Olvey 0 80 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Johnson, Wm. L 36.69 Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Karges, John 36.69 Pvt. Kment, Joe 1.60 Pvt. Owens, Victor L 80 Pvt. Knott, Fred 80 Pvt. Phillips, George W. .. 1.60 Pvt. Loss, Isaac 36.69 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H 80 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Nicholson, James T. .. 1.60 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Underhill, Charles ....36.69 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 Pvt. Olson, Chris 80 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 117 COMPANY G — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Aint . Due Rank Name A int. Due Sgt. Burnett, Hamilton Pvt. Forsman, Oscar 29.72 H $29.72 Pvt. Fuller. Guy W 1.60 Cpl. Larson, Felix G 29.72 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S 29.72 Pvt. Arnold, Isaac C 21.72 Pvt. Howard, Edward 29.72 Pvt. Jones, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Knapp, Willie R 29.72 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Larson, Axel W 29.72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt. Bowerman, Wm. F. .. 4.80 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. Conner, Clement T. ..29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 Pvt. Lehman, Paul 29.72 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Morton, Frank H 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William .... 4.00 Pvt. Pickard, Harry M 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A 29.72 Pvt. Ryan, William 29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac 80 COMPANY H — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt . Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Headwell, Axel $31.09 Pvt. Jackman,, Wm. N 6.55 Pvt. Keever, Oscar W 13.16 Pvt. Robinson, Andrew M. 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Edson J 31.09 Pvt. Thomas, James T 3.20 Pvt. Leichty, John 6.55 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T 31.09 Pvt. Moyer, George E 5.60 Pvt. Robinson, Edward .... 3.20 Pvt. Matson, Albert 5.60 COMPANY I — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Derienger, George ....$36.61 Pvt. Lewis, Charles E 4.80 Pvt. Brown, Frank H 4.00 Pvt. Carroll, John W 4.00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry Pvt. Center, Albert 4.80 D. S 37.56 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R... 9.24 Cpl. Dickenson, John W. ..12.07 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander .... 3.20 Cpl. Felts, William B 6.40 Pvt. Fairchild, Homer 1.60 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M 4.00 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A... 4.00 Cpl. Meyer, Otto 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 1.60 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Hanks, Harry E 1.60 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L 4.00 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Hutchinson, Albert L. 1.60 Pvt. Palmer, Archibald G. 5.60 Pvt. Jones, Lloyd 0 4.00 Pvt. Ray, Warren Hopkins 2.40 Pvt. Marqwadt, Fred W. .. 1.60 Pvt. Roberts, James W 9.24 Pvt. Miller, Fred S 9.24 Pvt. Selby, Arthur L 9.24 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F... 9.24 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus 37.56 Pvt. Padol, Adam 80 Pvt. Stohe, John G 4.00 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>