<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Steps to Nebraska Farm Ownership</title>
               <date value="1926-02">1926-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">illetin 210 February, 1926 1 Steps to Nebraska Farm Ownership RANKIN WHERE THE FACTS WERE OBTAINED itdied in each area except the one in Losran Cooperating : University of Nebraska U. S. Department of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station Bureau of Agricultural Economics E. A. Burnett T. P. Cooper Director Chief </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Farmers will continue to seek land ownership. Page The first step in Nebraska farm ownership is usually birth and youth in the country. Pages 4-6. The farm-tenancy stage has occurred more frequently than any othe except the farm-boy stage among the farmers studied; it has average&lt; nearly 10 years. Pages 7 and 8. Tenancy, farm labor for wages, rise in land value, and owner-oper atorship of farms have been the most frequent sources of accumulatior to the present generation of Nebraska farmers in the order named Inheritance, gift, non-farm labor, i portant to much smaller numbers, ment, and marriage are reported a few. Pages 9-11. nd other business have be* Homesteading, non-farm sources of accumulation the order of imp Rise in land value stands first i different sources of returns as indicated by amount received p« Nebraska farmers become landlords at an average age of 40 vears and retire at average age of 50 years. Page 22 Both assets and debts were several times as great at time of be coming owner as at time of becoming tenant. Pages The " ladders " most frequently climbed to ownership were farm boy, tenant, owner (FTO) 29.7 per cent; farm boy, hired man, tenant, owner (FHTO) 25.2 per cent; farm boy, owner (FO) 14.8 per cent; and farm boy, hired man, owner (FHO) 5.5 per cent. Pages 23-27. First land ownership was secured usually by purchase but some- times by gift, inheritance, homesteading and marriage. Pages 27-30. Are the hired-man and tenancy stages before farm ownership longer now than formerly? Pages 30-32. Pages 12-15. Only one-ninth of all operators studied had received wages on th fathers' Nebraska farms; only one-fourteenth of them in the o&gt;ui in which they are now farming. Page 15. A quarter of all operators have been tenants on their fathers' fan and 3 out of 5 have been share or share-cash tenants on Xebra^ farms of others than their fathers. Page 15. About 4 out of 5 of the present owner-operators owned their fi land in Nebraska. Page 16. About 2 tenants out of every 3 expect to become owners; less th a sixth of all tenants studied already owned land. Pages Hi- 17. Many tenants were also landlords. Page IX. Work without wages ended at 21 years of age and land owners came at 30. Pages 19-21. ira&lt; jra? </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Steps to Nebraska Farm Ownership -I. O. RANKIN » OWNERSHIP GREATLY DESIRED Farm ownership by the actual tiller of the soil is widely regarded as highly desirable. The farmer himself has sought it for both economic and sociological reasons. The agricul - tural economist and rural sociologist have, under most con - ditions, agreed with him that it was good in its effect both upon the economic productivity of the community and upon its social structure. In the recent past (1896-1918), farm ownership has brought great economic advantage thru the rise in land value and has usually given greater stability to the population than tenancy or any other form of land tenure likely to be con - sidered under modern conditions. Ownership may not bring wealth thru rise in the value of farm land during the next few years, and Nebraska tenantry will doubtless continue to avoid many of the worst evils com - plained of by the tenants of other states, yet ownership is still worthy of careful consideration and will probably con - tinue to be eagerly sought and earnestly recommended. Ways and means of acquiring land will doubtless long be studied by every Nebraska farmer, so it is worth while to see how present ownership has been gained. Changes in methods of getting land. — The methods of getting land have changed rapidly in the past generation trom homesteading to purchase, inheritance, and gift. Now, however, methods are less subject to change. The methods of today and yesterday will be those of tomorrow with much less change than followed the disappearance of the more pro - ductive part of the public domain which greatly lessened the opportunity for homesteading. Gradual evolution has re - placed rapid revolution in change in method of obtaining Nebraska farm land. A study of the basis of present owner- 1 Based mainly upon the results of a survey conducted in 1920 in cooperation with Drs. C. J. Galpin and L. C. Gray of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture. Acknowledgments are due the mem - bers of the resident and non-resident teaching staff of the University of Nebraska Department of Rural Economics for suggestions at every stage of the survey, but especially during the tabulation and interpretation of results. Dr. G. A. Peterson while still a graduate student, aided greatly by planning the tables upon which Table 9 and later pages are based. Final check of all tables and other numerical statements was made by Miss Eleanor H. Hinman. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 ship is, therefore, of more value than a study of the earlier methods used when land was easier to get and methods of getting it were changing more rapidly. EXPERIENCE OF A THOUSAND FARMERS This bulletin presents a study of the methods by which a thousand Nebraska farmers of today obtained the farms they are now operating. Very few of them are the original home- FIG. 1. — FARM EXPERIENCE OF OPERATORS' FATHERS AND FATHERS-IN-LAW Nino-tenths of the fathers of the farmers stud in-law were farmers — the greater part of th death or retirement. steaders. They have gained their farms by the methods which will be used in the future as nearly as we can forecast those methods. It is hoped that the farmers visited are rep - resentative. Page 1 will help the reader who knows Ne - braska to decide that point for himself. From 100 to 125 farmers were visited in each area shown on that map except the one in Logan County. No data from this or any other sandhill area are included in most of the tables, but they are included in text discussion wherever they supply any ma - terially different light. In all, the study is based on 1034 farms, or upon 982, if we exclude 52 studied in Logan County which are not included in the tables. Not all have yet at - tained ownership. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Steps to Farm Ownership 5 SO t-NC* ■* -■ — O X t~ t-^iO — o § oxn««« -J •- * ! o 1 as o&gt; *~ 05 ra ~ — — os oo — eo si -&gt; © ' o S L 1 ooioNQOoifioqcfiousooia •■ e 5. 3CXX« i-i Qt-t-N 3 r NNiOt-Q0Ot»O •VftOOS© t-00 *° OOC~dflOO— iNOt-gO^UR OOX« Oft-C* - |, ii OQ B Cl»OT^VOM»«ifl o»t-N et-i-d — '~ ~ s a « s -■ (oio»ot-««f wio- ««»io let* £ I li I s ■S i I J I o - — ~ — — r=— x?i ?i — | g, oMMlii ►5 fflioeo*-.^ —mesas — oow I . ooq«--i^nt : qwK!ax-»o x ■ -, ©oases onxn « « '! MH — C ' 5 II I —"— S.a a -o !|1 || s r! ■H ?ll C C C !il p s | </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 SONS AND SONS-IN-LAW OF FARMERS Birth on a farm is usually the first step toward the owner - operatorship on a Nebraska farm. The operators of more than 9 out of every 10 of the Nebraska farms studied are farmers' sons, and 8 out of every 10 who are married have farmers' daughters as their wives. The owner operators are somewhat more generally sons and sons-in-law of farmers than are the tenants, but part-owners are more nearly ex - clusively farmers' sons than either full owners or full tenants. It is difficult to say whether the fact that men of non-farm parentage are more likely to remain tenants results from lack of financial assistance or from inherent inability to progress to ownership. About three-quarters of the hired men found on the farms studied are farmers' sons, and nearly three-fifths of all who are married are married to farmers' daughters. Here again, farm ownership is more frequent than farm tenancy among both the fathers and fathers-in-law who are farmers, but there is more tenancy in this case than in the case of the fathers and fathers-in-law of the farmers for whom these hired men were working. Among the fathers of the present owner farmers, ownership at time of death or retirement was 11 times as frequent as tenancy. Among the fathers of tenants the ratio of ownership to tenancy was only 4 to 1. but among those of part-owners it was about 23 to 1. The part-owners, then, were more exclusively sons of owners. They were not, however, so exclusively the sons-in-law of land-owning farmers, as they married daughters of tenants ■The number of cases in this table and all following ones indicate the number of persons whc answered the question concerned, not the total number of operators studied. =Some of these land-owning tenants let their land lie idle; some rent it to others. Tabu: '2. — Years us hired //(&lt;/(/. tenant, and otptu r Tenure Farm work with wages Tenancy ( &gt;wnership Y&gt;iir~ Yeart Year, .11 tenures 1 446 6.7 Owners 140 6.7 Part-owners 73 5.2 Tenants 226 6.9 Share-cash. ... 114 7.3 Share 80 5.9 Cash 32 7.7 Managers 7 12.7 843 9.7 585 13.7 227 9.3 353 15.7 139 8.8 151 11.1 475 10.1 80 2 9.6 264 11.3 34 9.5 159 8.2 :« 10.5 52 10.4 13 8.0 2 4.5 1 32.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Steps to Farm Ownership 7 or of men of the non-farming occupations about as frequently as did either owners or tenants. These facts suggest the presence of a more or less definitely defined strain of per - manent tenants. Possibly certain families may, generation after generation, rise to the tenancy stage but fail to emerge from it as owners. NUMBER OF YEARS ALL TENURES WNERS PART-OWNERS ALL TENANTS SHARE-CASH HARE CASH hired uan radwr owner S3 FIG. 2— YEARS AS HIRED MAN, TENANT, AND OWNER •ars spent in the three stages shown here cannot be added to the length m to determine the average age of obtaining ownership because mers have skipped one or more stages. Those who did not report time in stage are omitted from the calculations for that stage. YEARS AS HIRED MAN, TENANT, AND OWNER In Table 2 especial attention is called to figures showing the length of the hired-man and farm-tenant stages. The reader is cautioned against assuming that those who reported the years they spent in a given stage are the only ones of the 1034 farmers studied who passed thru that particular stage. Some were unable to remember how long they were in each stage. The figures are therefore to be regarded only as indicating the number of cases upon which the averages are based. Obviously every one of the 491 tenants has spent time in the tenant stage, but only about 97 per cent of them reported the length of time they had spent in that stage. Only less obvious is the case of farm work without wages which was ended at ages definitely reported by only 3 out of every 4 farmers studied. From Table 1 and later tables, however, we know that more than 9 out of every 10 of the farmers studied were born on farms and spent their </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 8 boyhood on farms. Probably everyone who knows anything about farm life will agree that practically every able-bodied boy who grows up on a Nebraska farm has worked there without wages. The only question is, " At what age did such work end? Just when did wages begin to come from the boy's father or from some other employer?" Years of farm work. — Most of the discussion of the hired-man stage will be found in connection with some of the later tables of this bulletin. It can be seen more clearly from Table 2 than later, however, that this stage was about a year and a half shorter in case of part-owners than in case of either owners or tenants. This may result in part from the fact already noticed that part-owners are more exclusively the sons of land-owning farmers than are either the present owners or the present tenants. Full owners and full tenants spent almost exactly the same number of years in the hired - man stage. The owners are nearly ten years older than the tenants. This gives us a rough comparison which does not support the contention that the hired-man stage is decreasing or increasing in length. Much more definite evidence on this point will be presented in connection with the later tables of the bulletin. Non-farm work. — More than a quarter of the farmers studied have done work other than farm work. Some of them were born in towns and stayed there for a portion of their lives, but a far greater number are country men who went to town but later returned to farming as their occupation. Thus, the presence of those who have had non-farm experi - ence is much more a back-to-the-land movement than an onto - the-land movement. Non-farming experience occupied an average of 7 years in the lives of those who reported on this point, — 10.2 years among owners, 3.8 among part-owners, and 6.5 among tenants. Years as tenant. — The farm-tenancy stage has occurred more frequently than any other except the farm-boy stage among the farmers studied, and has lasted nearly 10 years, — 9.3 years among owners, 8.8 among part-owners, and 10.1 among tenants. There is greater variation from group to group of tenants than among the three main tenure groups just named. The share-cash tenants studied have already averaged 11.3 years in this stage, the share tenants 8.2, and the cash tenants 10.4, and most of them are not yet ready to leave the tenancy stage for owner-operatorship. It is not </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Steps to Farm Ownership 9 surprising that part-owners have shorter periods of tenancy as well as of farm work with wages than either full owners or full tenants. Perhaps the real cause for surprise is that they have not shortened their tenancy periods still more as a result of being satisfied with owning only a part of the land which they farm. This is doubtless, in part at least, because they are farming on a larger scale than either owners or tenants. The following reasons may help to explain why the part - owner tenancy periods were not shortened more, and why the present tenants have already been in that stage longer than the owners, who are older men, had to spend as tenants be - fore they could attain ownership. (1) The amount of savings one must accumulate before he can make sufficient payment to get a farm large enough for profitable operation has been increasing for at least a generation. (2) Perhaps part of the present tenants represent the accumulation of those who prefer to remain tenants permanently. (3) Part of them are kept from attaining ownership by misfortune or inefficiency, altho this reason probably operated less during the period 1896-1918 than during the time of agricultural depression preceding 1896. (4) Unsettled conditions during war and reconstruction doubtless influenced some to keep their assets in a more fluid condition by remaining tenants rather than to freeze these assets by investing them in farm land. (5) A few who leased their farms before enlisting were temporarily tenants until they could regain possession of the land which they owned but had leased for a period of years. SOURCE OF ACCUMULATION AND AGE AT ITS RECEIPT The sources. — In considering Table 3 it must be remem - bered that the schedule was so framed that those who have engaged in the occupations listed at losses or without positive gains would not report them. As those who make money at a given enterprise are, perhaps, on the whole older and more experienced than those who lose money in the same enterprise, Table 3 doubtless shows a greater average age for the persons listed than would a table showing all who have engaged in such enterprises. The eleven sources from which Nebraska farmers have accumulated means, listed in order of frequency with which they were reported, are: (1) tenancy, (2) farm work, (3) rise in land values, (4) owner-operatorship, (5) inher - itance, (6) gift, (7) " other work," or non-farm work, (8) " other business," or non-farm business, (9) homestead- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Steps to Farm Ownership ing, (10) other investments, and (11) marriage. Only five reported accumulation from any other sources. Tenancy is notable in this list as having been a source of net income to almost twice as many of the farmers studied as any one other means of obtaining income except farm work. Among owners, however, it is exceeded by owner-operatorship and rise in land values. Age at accumulation from each source. — In tabulating the age at the accumulation from these eleven sources both events and periods had to be considered. Inheritance, gift, and marriage are assigned to a definite age or date in the life of the individual, but farm work and other similar items extended over periods of years and might have been tabulated either under the date of termination of the period or at the average date or middle of the period. The former plan was followed, so the ages given in Table 3 are those at which the receipt of returns from a particular source was completed or found still in process at the time of the survey (1920). Farm work is the earliest source of income in the lives of owners and part-owners and, except for gift, in the lives of tenants. The tenants continued farm work almost to the age of 25, or nearly a year longer than the average owner or part-owner. Gifts came next in the young farmer's life, being received at an average age only about a month greater than that at which he ended his farm work as a source of return. This suggests that these gifts came largely at times when the young man was first establishing his farming operations on his own account either as a tenant or as an owner-operator. Next came " other work " (non-farm work) which ended at an average age of about 28, but was not very generally reported. Homesteading ended at an average age of 29 but only a few present owners and tenants have been home - steaders. Inheritance and marriage came next at the ages of 31 and 32 followed by " other business " of a non-farming character at about 33 and " other " or non-farming invest - ments which continued to nearly 39. Rise in land values and owner-operatorship also continued as sources of accumulation of means till nearly the time of the survey. Order of importance. — We have seen the order of importance of the different sources of accumulation as indi - cated by the number of operators affected. As indicated by the amount received per farmer reporting accumulation from </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Steps to Farm Ownership 13 each source the order is: (1) Rise in land value, $15,914, (2) "other investments" of a non-farming character, $11,996. (3) farm operation as owner, $10,326, (4) inher - itance, $8,435, (5) marriage, $4,505, (6) tenancy, $4,428, (7) "other" or non-farming business, $4,351, (8) gift, $3,784, (9) homesteading, $1,765, (10) " other work," $1,099, and (11) farm work, $628. Of course the amount accumulated from a given source might by no means tell the whole story of the importance of that source. Farm work is a much more important step toward farm ownership than its place in this list might seem to indicate. It is of the greatest importance because (1) it is a period of probation or of apprenticeship during which progress is made toward the mastery of a most difficult call - ing, (2) the purchasing power of the dollar was much greater when these farmers were hired men than at any time since, and (3) the dollars which give the first foothold are more important than any others. Some other sources of accumula - tion which are more important than the net amount dis - tributed might seem to indicate are homesteading, gift, and inheritance. Accumulation from these sources came to these particular men some time ago when the purchasing power of the dollar was greater. Much the same is true of other or non-farm work and business. Rise in land values. — Rise in land values presents three claims to attention: (1) It is more frequently reported than any other source, except tenancy. (2) The average amount per person secured from this source was one and one-half times as great as that from any other source. (3) The total amount gained in this way was nearly twice as great as the total amount from any other one source Farm operation as owner. — It is often said that because of inefficiency or uncontrollable circumstances, farmers make little or nothing from farm operations but reach comfort - able circumstances if at all because of the rise in value of farm land. A large number who estimated their accumula - tions from this source reported amounts which averaged about $10,000. Some, even of the tenants, were included in this number because they had been at least reasonably suc - cessful owner-operators in their earlier farming experience. Tenancy. — Of the 807 men who had passed thru or were still in the tenancy stage, 669 or over four-fifths re - ported accumulations from tenancy averaging over $4,400. They had been tenants for an average of ten years. Those </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 X O N— tC-. nxs^xo — — — n C3C CSU-S ~ — oan--xxu c cm" so — 10 -&lt;r « 5 — NIC t--H m _• N — 'n't- WNt- -7 x O«NN!C — -r J. Cl- I-- NNS-TKN i" *¥■« OB S?J§5f||I &amp; hZ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Steps to Farm Ownership 15 who are now tenants have made distinctly more from tenancy than the present owners made because (1) they have con - tinued longer in the tenant stage, and (2) they have been in it during the more recent period when the purchasing power of the dollar was smaller than when present owners were passing thru the tenancy stage. OPERATORS' FARM EXPERIENCE Wages. — Only one-ninth of all operators studied had worked on their fathers' Nebraska farms with wages, and one-fourteenth of them in the same county in which they are now farming. In practically all areas the wages were paid by the fathers who had smaller farms rather than by those who had the larger ones. This difference according to acre- age leads one to conjecture that the difference between work for fathers with and without wages may have been a dif - ference in method of giving money rather than in amount given. Wages may have been a means of teaching thrift and the business-like administration of funds adopted by fathers who could bestow less land later. Some weight might be given to the fact that the tenants and part-owners who more generally received wages from their parents are younger men than the owners, and were on their fathers' farms during times of greater prosperity which enabled the fathers to be more liberal. The tenants' fathers have not, in most cases at least, given them land or helped them purchase it, so they may have been a little less inclined to ask their sons to work without wages, forseeing that they would be either unable or unwilling to aid them to establish themselves as owner - operators. A quarter of all operators had been hired men on Nebraska farms not belonging to their fathers. Tenancy. — A quarter of all the operators had been tenants on their fathers' farms, and a fifth are still farming in the same counties in which they had been tenants on their fathers' farms. A fifth of all the tenants studied are still tenants on their fathers' farms, and another fifth on the farms of their fathers-in-law, mothers, and other relatives. 1 Over a quarter of all the operators studied had worked for wages on Nebraska farms other than those belonging to their fathers. About 4 out of every 5 operators have at some time been tenants on Nebraska farms which did not belong to their fathers. 'The Nebraska Farm Family: Some land tenure phases — Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 185, Page 4. 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 First ownership of land. — Among the present owner - operators about four out of every five owned, their first farm land in Nebraska. They probably never owne'd any anywhere else. Two out of three owned it in the county in which they are still farming. Substantially the same is true of part - owners, but the tenants who have owned land at all have not so generally owned it in Nebraska or in the county in which they were farming in 1920. Only half of the 982 farmers reported the acreage of the first land they owned, averaging 158 acres. The owners' first land averaged about 161 acres, the part-owners' about 139, and the tenants' about 181. The tenants' 181 acre acquisitions were undoubtedly worth much less both per acre and per farm than the smaller acreages obtained at earlier dates by owners and part-owners. This supposition is supported by the fact that a considerable percentage of these land-owning tenants are not operating their land themselves, or even rent - ing to anyone else. Similarly, there is undoubtedly a much greater difference in the value of the owners' and part-owners' first acquisitions than is indicated by the difference between 161 and 139 acres. Nearly one-third of the part-owners studied were in the Grant area in Perkins Countv, where land in farms had an average value of $50 per acre in 192( compared with from $127 in Clay County to $207 in ( County. 1 First additional land. — Between a fourth and a fifth of all operators reported additional land which they had secured averaging 253 acres, or about one and two-thirds times as much as the first land owned. This additional acreage is even more exclusively Nebraska land than the first land secured. Very little of it lies in any other state. Some, even of the tenants, have not only secured first land ownership, but have taken the second step of securing additional land. The average acreages in all tenure groups are so much greater at time of securing additional land than at the time of secur - ing first land ownership as to suggest that (1) the first land had been sold and the larger tract bought in place of it rather than in addition to it, or (2) that the additional land was in a newer region of cheaper land. TENANTS' ECONOMIC STATUS AND PLANS About 2 tenants out of every 3 stated in 1920 that they expected to become owners, about 1 out of every 6 definitely 1 Agriculture : ReportB for the States. The Northern States. Fourteenth Censn Vol. VI, Part I, p. 691, 1920. Washineton. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Steps to Farm Ownership 17 r.uti Tenants 1 economic status and plans 1 All Share- Share Cash tenants cash 472 275 146 51 74 40 25 9 1) 56 28 19 9 55 32 13 7 17 3 •&gt; 3 ■i 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 264 169 66 29 35 16 12 7 98 37 48 13 75 53 20 2 2 stated that he did not expect to, and the remainder failed to state any intention on this point. About a sixth stated that they had taken no steps toward ownership, or at least failed to show what steps they had taken, but the remainder reported that they were making progress toward owner-operatorship by accumulating savings or purchasing land or equipment. Of course, the desire for land ownership would be greatly dulled if there should come a conviction that the long rise in the price of farm products and consequently of farm land that followed 1896 was to be followed by a decline of long dura - tion. There would still remain some of the advantages of ownership, but such a decline would sweep away the principal economic incentive for owning instead of renting farm land. The outstanding reason for tenancy instead of ownership is limited resources. The other reason most frequently given is that by renting the tenant can secure a location which he likes better than any which he would be financially able to purchase. 309 169 112 28 85 56 12 17 78 50 22 6 177 95 65 17 74 40 25 9 Jwning land ..easing land owned acquired by Purchase Inheritance Homesteading Gift Marriage Not specified Reason operator is tenant Limited resources Location more suitable Miscellaneous Not specified . . 3 rospects of ownership Tenant expects to become owner Tenant does not expect to be owne: Not specified Accumulating capital Already owns land I ru-l -Kit's n&lt; i Stapleton area data. ■da </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 Some tenants now own land. — Reference has already been made to that group of tenants who already own land but do not operate it. It includes less than a sixth of all the tenants studied — nearly a sixth of the eastern Nebraska tenants and about a twelfth of those in the southwestern areas studied. In three-fourths of these cases the land is being leased to someone else, but in about a quarter there is no report of its being leased, so it is only fair to assume that it is land which it would not pay either the owner or anyone else to cultivate even at the high prices for farm products prevailing just before 1920. Land owned by tenants was obtained by purchase in nearly three-fourths of the cases, by inheritance in about one-sixth, and in the remainder by home - steading, gift, or marriage. Eighty-four tenants who own land among the 495 studied in the 9 areas had a total of 20,639 acres with a value of $1,587,385 or about $80 an acre, excluding 800 acres for which no value is given. Information on this point was not secured from tenants in the Geneva area in Fillmore County. Why tenants do not farm the land they own. — T\ reasons given by the land-owning tenants for farming other people's land instead of their own usually fall into one of three groups: (1) they can rent farms better adapted to their needs, (2) they can secure other farms at a cost so low that it pays them better to farm rented rather than owned land, or (3) circumstances have made them tenants temporarily, but they expect to farm their own land soon. The lack of adaptation, as reported in individual cases, is usually in size of farm, improvements, soil fertility, or school and other community advantages. One man was renting because his health did not permit him to remain in the part of the country where he owned land. Sometimes the rented farm could be operated more profitably because it was larger than the tenant's own farm. Many of those who reported that it " paid better " to rent were tenants of near relatives — fathers, mothers, or, in one case, a wife. One of these kins - man tenants went to his own farm each year to put in wheat which he hired cut at harvest time. One case of temporary tenancy occurred on account of a man's having rented his own land while he was in military service and on his return being a tenant until he could regain his farm. Another man expected to inherit the farm on which he was a tenant at the time of the survey. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Steps to Farm Ownership 19 N N « S9 -- O -h 00 M *Q -* X onto ?5 oi •-• oo -4 cc » oi ■*? t; tt ic nnnnttw Si^^£:2rf^&lt;N?i (MWN NNKNr!*C*fM nx« r...Ttizi-i---.o © ? X3n t~ t^ © Tf N QO OS t- as oi o ■* oo o NNN N ri ZZ N M TZ n -V -j- ?1— -NECMnOACDie "5 i f § Iltjliiiwljl : S :S^f.2S-S Saigas 5 WOt-OtDt-tOt-50 CC5t-Kt-«N *-, TJ I"= 5O — W U3 ■"* M = Iti!; * §££Ei= Zfeii.fa=iJ </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 AGE AT EACH STAGE Age at quitting work without -wages. — Work on fathers' farms without wages ended at an average age of almost ex - actly twenty-one (20.9) years. Owners had worked a year longer and tenants eight months less without wages but part - owners averaged just a little less than twenty-one years when they stopped such work. Perhaps these differences arise in part from (1) a general tendency to reduce the relation to a money basis at an earlier age now than formerly, aided by a greater prosperity during the period when our present tenants were coming of age than when the present owners were reaching twenty-one, and (2) the establishment of a land - owning farmer class in which ownership comes after a shorter period of farm work. Age at quitting work with wages on fathers' farms. — The period of work with wages on fathers' farms ended a year and a half later in life (22.5) but was reported by less than a seventh as many as reported similar work without wages. Present owners ended their work on their fathers' farms with wages a month earlier and cash tenants a year and a half earlier than they ended their work without wages on their fathers' farms. Of course, this is not meant to indicate that the same individual in any case worked without wages on his father's farm after having received wages which were terminated. Comparatively few men fall in the group of those who worked both with and without wages on their fathers' farms. It may reasonably be assumed that those who fall in both groups worked first without wages and later for pay on their fathers' farms. Age at quitting work for wages on others' farms. — The average age of quitting work on farms other than fathers' was 22.9 years, less than half a year greater than the average age of quitting work for wages on fathers' farms. Between a third and a half of the members of each of the tenure groups reported the ages at which they quit work for wages on others' farms. Those who are now owners had quit such work about two months younger than those who are now part-owners and more than a year younger than those who are now tenants. Those who are now cash tenants had quit such work on others' farms more than a year younger than those of any other group and three and a half years younger than the present share tenants, who continued to work for wages on others' farms until they were more than 24 years of age. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Steps to Farm Ownership 21 Age at end of tenancy on others' farms. — Share and share-cash tenancy on the farms of other than the tenants' fathers ended at an average age of a little over 30, while cash tenancy ended at an average age of a little under 31 or 4 or 5 years later than the termination of tenancy on the farms of fathers. Age at close of non-farming occupation. — Nearly a quarter of all farmers studied reported some non-farming occupations which had been left at an average age of about 28 years. Variations from this figure shown by the different tenure groups were so slight as to be practically negligible. Age at first land ownership. — First land ownership was obtained by 529 operators at an average age of about 30 years, just over 29 in case of present owners, about 31 in case of present part-owners, and 32 in case of present tenants. Only a sixth or a seventh of the present tenants have yet attained land ownership and,' because many of the remainder will do so at later dates, these figures cannot be accepted as final for the tenants, as they can for the owners and part - owners. If we could give a final figure by predicting the age at which each tenant would acquire land the true average would be much higher, as the tenants already average over 36 years of age and most of them do not yet own land. Age at first additional land ownership. — Almost as soon as a farmer has secured his first land he is likely to begin planning to secure additional land. He may want it to bring his farm up to the size required for the most profitable operation, or to secure greater benefit from an expected rise in land value, or he may merely be looking for a good and familiar form of investment for the money he has accumu - lated. It may be a purchase of adjoining land or of land close enough to the original purchase to be operated with it, or it may be a purchase of land lying at some distance. This second purchase of land may follow a sale of the original so that it is really securing other and perhaps more land rather than adding, in the strict sense, to that which is already owned. Among the farm owners studied this additional land ownership came about eight and a half years after the acquisition of the first land, or at an average age of 38.4 years. The present owners obtained their first land when about 18 months younger than the part-owners and two and a half years younger than those of the present tenants who own land. Both part-owners and tenants, however, had secured </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 first additional land earlier in life than had the owners, per - haps because of having secured smaller acreages at first and having secured additional land in a greater percentage of cases by selling that which they already had. Age at retiring and at becoming landlords. — So far as the rather meager data obtained go, they seem to indicate that Nebraska farmers are retiring at the age of about 50 and are becoming landlords at the age of about 40. Of course, many never become landlords and some become landlords long before retiring or even before passing from tenancy to owner-operatorship. A man who acquired land while still a tenant may become a landlord quite early in life without ever becoming an owner-operator. It is by no means rare for a comparatively young man to remain a tenant on his father's or mother's land or on estate land long after he has become a land-owner, or for such a man to rent land from a landlord not related to him and while a tenant on this man's land to be a landlord both as regards land which he himself owns and as regards land of which he is one of the heirs. All such cases tend to reduce the age at becoming landlord below the age at retiring. Of course, these are not presented as the usual ages of retiring or of becoming landlords. Table 8. — Act rage assets and debts at beginning of ten ownership At time of becoming Tenant Owner Ans. Av. Arts. Ar. .ssets Cash Farm equipment Other property Assets acquired As farm hand Other employment Other business As tenant Inheritance Gift Marriage Homesteading Fortunate investment )ebts Personal Operating Other .... 292 $523 279 $2,877 l 501 809 414 2,627 39 3,146 138 3,182 ... 283 550 97 707 86 745 22 2,111 19 1,426 14 4,779 . . . . 309 3,689 32 2,613 97 10,090 112 860 75 3,518 1 2,000 16 5,506 6 1,750 , 7 1,204 4 520 9 18,300 56 319 64 3,606 . . . . 287 760 147 2,540 10 3,600 104 4,501 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Steps to Farm Ownership 23 PROPERTY AT BEGINNING OF TENANCY OR OWNERSHIP Table 8 compares the assets and debts at the beginning of tenancy and of ownership. As the average date at which these men became tenants was about 10 years earlier than that on which they became owners, the difference in their economic condition is really overstated if expressed in dollars, because the dollar has shrunk in value. The average amount of cash on hand at time of becoming a tenant was a little over $500, but was between 5 and 6 times that much at time of becoming an owner. The farm equipment on hand was valued at nearly three and a third times as much at time of becoming an owner as at time of becoming a tenant, but there was relatively little difference in the amount of other prop - erty on hand at the two stages. Work as a farm hand had yielded about $550 apiece to those who reported the amount at the time the tenancy stage was entered upon, and only about one and a third times this amount at the time the ownership stage was entered upon. " Other employment " and " other " non-farming business had each contributed about 3 times as much to the farmer reporting them by the time he reached the ownership stage as by the time he entered the tenancy stage, but both of these sources of return were reported by much smaller numbers than was farm work. Inheritance, reported by 3 times as many operators, had contributed almost 4 times as much by the time ownership was reached. In case of gifts the ratio of amounts on hand at beginning of ownership and tenancy periods was 4 to 1, and in case of fortunate investments, 37 to 1. THE AGRICULTURAL LADDER While rising toward ownership the farmer has sometimes been thought of as climbing a ladder whose successive rungs are farm boyhood, hired farm laborer, tenancy, part-owner - ship, full ownership, retired farmer, and perhaps at some stage non-farm labor or non-farm business. Of course, there are other stages or rungs which could be added to the list but these are the ones most frequently used. Not every farmer makes use of- all of them. Each selects those which his circumstances or preference and natural ability enable him to use most successfully for his purpose. Still further rungs or stages in the upward climb which might be enumer - ated are: mortgaged ownership, debt-free ownership, ex - panding ownership during which other farms are being secured, and retired farmer and landlord. This upward </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Steps to Farm Ownership 25 extension of the agricultural ladder, however, was given little attention in this study, which stops with the attainment of ownership without even giving much attention to part-owner - ship as a step to full ownership. For brevity and convenience in the following paragraphs it will be well to refer to each one of these stages by its letter: F indicates the farm boy stage of work without wages on the home farm, H the hired farm laborer stage, T the tenant stage, O the owner stage, and L left the farm for occupation elsewhere. If it occurs as the first rung of the ladder it indicates that boyhood was spent in town or city — not in farm surroundings. These letters may be used to indicate very briefly the stages thru which operators have passed toward ownership and the order in which they have passed thru these stages. For example, the FHTO group includes all who have passed thru the farm-boy, hired-farm-laborer, and tenant stages, and finally attained ownership. Similarly, the FTO group indicates those who have climbed the same ladder except that they have omitted the hired-farm-laborer rung. We have seen what these principal stages or rungs are, but now wish to see (1) in what order men have passed thru these stages, (2) in how many cases a given stage has been used and in how many cases omitted, and (3) how these dif - ferent combinations of stages have been associated with dif - ferent methods of finally accomplishing the possession of farm land. Kinds of " ladders." — Table 9 shows that the ladder most frequently climbed to farm ownership in Nebraska has been FTO — that 29.7 per cent have passed thru only the farm-boy and tenant stages on the way to ownership. The other important ladders or series of steps or rungs, in the order of their frequency, were FHTO (25.2 per cent) , FO (14.8 per cent), FHO (5.5 per cent), and FLHTO (4.2 per cent) . This order is in general agreement with that of an earlier study except that in that study the FO group stood first, including 34 per cent of 2112 owners studied in Illinois, Iowa, Kansas, Nebraska, and Minnesota. 1 Only a seventh of the Nebraska land-owners studied were able to take this short cut to ownership which omits the farm-laborer and farm-tenant stages and goes directly from 1 Spillman. W. J. The Aericultural Ladder. American Economic Review, Vol. IX. No.- I. March 1919. 170-9 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 26 FARM BOY HIRED MAN TENANT NON-FARM Part. Ml T-n, tuner Optra FIG. 3. — STEPS TO FARM OWNERSHIP Over 90 per cent of all the land-owninir farmers studied were born on farm 40 per cent worked as hired men. and nearly 70 per cent had been tenants. Or about 17 per cent had ever lived anywhere except on the farm. Th include no Stapleton area data and therefore differ somewh; text and of Table farm boy to farm owner. The L - group, — those me whose first experience was gained in town, — includec about 1 owner out of every 20, but the FL-- group was larger, including 1 out of every 9 or 10. This means that less than 1 out of every 6 has had his home off the farm during any important part of his life. The areas. — The relative importance of the different groups varies greatly from area to area. The greatest variations, appearing in the FO group, show at opposite extremes the two areas populated by those of most immediate foreign descent. Among the Bohemian or Czecho-Slovak population of the Milligan area in Fillmore County, nearly two-thirds have gone directly from work on the farm with - out wages to farm ownership, omitting the hired-farm-laborer and the tenancy stages. Among those of Swedish descent in the Stromsburg area in Polk County, on the other hand, only 1 out of every 25 has been able to avoid the hired-man and tenancy stages in this way. Next to the FO group the FHTO group shows the greatest variation from area to area and the FTO group also shows some variations offsetting those of the FO column. Of the 616 owners of farm land whose ladders to owner- ship we are about to study, 375 are now owner-operators, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Steps to Farm Ownership 27 157 are part-owners, and 84 are tenants who own land but either rent it to someone else or allow it to lie idle while they rent from other owners all the land which they cultivate. A glance at Table 9 shows that 86.1 per cent of all these owners have passed thru the F or farm boy stage. By tenure classes the percentages for those passing thru the F stage are 84.3 per cent of the full owners, 88.9 per cent of the part-owners, and 85.7 per cent of the 84 land-owning tenants. The hired-farm-laborer stage (H) followed next in time order but not in frequency. It is here used to include all work for wages either on a father's farm or on any other farm. All together, 240 or 39 per cent of the farmers studied have passed thru this stage. Of the 616 owners, more than half secured their first land by purchase, about a sixth by inheritance, a twelfth by gift, a seventeenth by homesteading, and 1 out of 70 by marriage, leaving about 1 in every 7 who failed to specify how he attained first land ownership. The FHTO and FLHTO groups were marked by a particularly large proportion — nearly three-quarters — who secured first ownership by pur - chase. The LHTO group stood highest (92 per cent) in ownership by purchase. Less than two-thirds of the FTO and FLO groups got their first land by purchase and the proportion was smaller in each of the others except the FLTO and LHO groups. The FO group of farmers secured their first land very largely by inheritance and gift. FIG. 4. — METHODS OF ACQUIRING FARM OWNERSHIP Purchase is the outstanding method of gaining ownership among farmers of all tenures — particularly among those who are tenants. Gifts and inheritance brought farms to very few tenants and to fewer part-owners than owners. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 28 OWNER-OPERATORS How present owner-operators got their first land. — Nearly three-fifths of the present owner-operators got their first land by purchase with or without aid from their fathers or others in securing credit. One out of every 6 obtained land by inheritance, 1 out of every 9 or 10 by gift, 1 out of every 17 by homestead, and 1 out of every 63 by marriage. These figures vary greatly from area to area in ways partly explainable on the basis of the nationality of the farmers and the age of the area. In the newer western areas purchase and homesteading are much more prominent than in the older areas where homesteading was done mainly by the men of a previous generation and where inheritance and gift are now more important. In the Thurston County area about Walthill it is still more markedly true that purchase and homesteading were unusually prominent among the means reported as used in acquiring first land ownership. In this area Indian reservations have artificially delayed settlement by white men. The Clay County area was for some reason higher in acquisition by purchase and lower in that by inheritance than any other studied except the Walthill area in Thurston County. The Milligan area in Fillmore County, inhabited largely by those of Bohemian or Czecho-Slovak descent, stood much higher in gift and inheritance and lower in purchase than most other areas. More than a quarter of the full owners, and a sixth of the part-owners in the Grant area in Perkins County got their first land by homesteading, as did nearly a fifth of the full owners in the Walthill area in Thurston County. Owner-operators' ladders. — The majority of the owner - operators have climbed three ladders to ownership — FTO (28.3 per cent), FHTO (19.5 per cent), and FO (19.5 per cent). Only about 8 per cent reached ownership with only the farm-boy and hired-farm-laborer stages preceding it, (FHO). A few of the owner-operators had been born off farms, and more had lived for some part of their lives in towns or cities, (L+ and FL— ). PART-OWNERS Pre-purchase stages. — Of the 157 part-owners studied, 142 or 9 out of every 10 started toward the ownership of land as workers on their fathers' farms either with or without wages. Thus only about one-tenth of the part-owners </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Steps to Farm Ownership 29 attained land ownership after a start from a town home, altho about 1 out of every 7 of them had passed thru the FL -f- group either with or without passing thru the tenant stage. That is, 1 out of every 7 had spent some time off the farm and had returned to it later in addition to the 1 in every 15 or 16 (6.4 per cent) who had come to the farm from town without having worked on his father's farm at any previous time. Means of getting possession of land. — About three-fifths of the part-owners got their first land by purchase. Inher - itance came next as a means of acquiring land, accounting for 17 per cent of part-owners' first land. Gift, homestead, and marriage were the remaining means, in order of fre - quency, of the acquisition of land. Purchase, then, is the outstanding method of gaining land ownership among part-owners as well as among full owners. This is especially true of those who have passed thru the laborer stage either on the farm or in town. They have less frequently obtained land by inheritance or gift. Both full owners and part-owners had nearly passed the stage at which many further gifts were to be expected, as gifts of land seem to be received almost entirely by the younger men. The full owners, somewhat older men, had a slightly higher percentage for acquisition of first land by gift. Part-owners' ladders. — Part-owners even more than full owners are concentrated in certain groups, especially in the FHTO group which contains nearly a third of all part-owners. That is, the part-owner has more generally climbed the more frequently used ladders to ownership and passed thru both the hired-farm-laborer and tenant stages. On the other hand, greater proportions of part-owners than of full owners fall in the L and FL groups of men who came originally from towns or cities or have lived there after boyhood on the farm and returned later to the country. Most of the land of the L and FL groups has been secured by purchase and little or none at all by inheritance, gift, marriage, homesteading, or other means. TENANTS Of the 74 land-owning tenants, 55 or about three-quarters secured their first land by purchase as compared with little more than half of the total number of land-owners included in the study. Of the remaining 23, 7 had inherited their land, 6 homesteaded it, only 1 had obtained it by gift, leaving 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 acquisitions by marriage and 7 unspecified. About two-fifths of the land-owning tenants fall in each of the FHT and FT groups. These groups are classed in the tables as FHTO and FTO even tho some of their members have attained owner - ship by inheritance or otherwise even before reaching the tenant stage, and none of them are now in the owner group in the sense of being owner-operators. All but one of these land-owning tenants had their boyhood on the farm, but 9 or more than a ninth of them fall in the FL — group of men who have worked for wages off the farm after working on the farm without wages during their boyhood. Tenants show fewer peculiarities due to nationality, locality, or other causes than do full owners. This arises in part from the statistical accident that the tenants studied fall into fewer groups with greater numbers in each group. The FO and FHO groups, for example, cannot appear in a tenancy table to subdivide and make small groups which give prominence to chance variation. Perhaps the principal reason for the greater regularity of the tenants' showing is to be found in the fact that while climbing toward tenancy they were further removed from such disturbing elements as pioneer conditions, serious financial depression, migration, and a boyhood or early manhood passed in a foreign country or in other parts of the United States where the prevailing ideas and methods are different from those which predom - inate in Nebraska. The tenant ladders and their relative percentage frequency are FHT, 38.1 per cent; FT, 36.9 per cent; FLHT, 5.9 per cent; FLT, 4.8 per cent; and LHT, 1.2 per cent. ARE THE APPRENTICESHIP STAGES GROWING LONGER? There is a general impression that farm ownership is now being attained later in life than formerly. This sounds rea - sonable if only the rising price of farm land is considered. The rising prices of the products of that land, however, tend to offset soaring land prices either altogether or in part. Tables were made showing the average age at which the owners studied had gained their first land during the five - year period ended 1920 and earlier years divisible by five back to 1880. They seemed to indicate a much greater aver - age age at gaining ownership during recent years than thirty or forty years ago. Only a few of what seemed to be the safer conclusions based upon them are included here. In the present study it is possible to base such tables only upon surviving farmers who own the land they till. The sur- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Steps to Farm Ownership 31 viving farmers of the group including those who gained their farms within the last year can hardly be fairly comparable with those who gained their first farm land ownership forty yeai's ago and are still tilling their farms. The younger men are probably representative of the age at which ownership is being gained during the present or very recent time. The farmers who began as owners forty years ago and are still farming, however, must be those who attained ownership at an unusually early age even for that period. The men who were more advanced in age when they gained their first ownership of land in 1860 have now passed the stage of active farm life. It does seem safe to conclude, however, from these tables made by Dr. Peterson, that the part-owners passed thru the tenancy stage more quickly than did the owners. The fact that those who gained their farms by the FHO ladder have been owners longer than the remainder seems to indicate the comparative disappearance of that method. Tenancy is prob - ably more nearly universal today than formerly and the hired-man stage much less general, altho the FO ladder is also probably more frequently used now than in earlier years when Nebraska farm homes had not been long enough estab - lished to permit men to gain their land directly by gift or inheritance without passing thru either the hired-man or the tenant stage. The observed age differences upon which these suggestions are based are not, however, sufficiently great to be more than suggestive. The FTO owners remained on their fathers' farms a little longer, were tenants about the same length of time or a little less, and came to ownership about two years younger than did those who climbed the FHTO ladder. Probably those who remained longer working without wages for the fathers re - ceived more help in securing land ownership than those who left the F stage of working on their fathers' farms without pay to become hired farm laborers on the farms of others. Those of the FO group stayed even longer on the home farms without wages, but presumably they could have gained their land only by gift, inheritance, or unusual credit extended per - haps by their fathers or secured with their fathers' aid. The men who left the farms to do other than farm work or who were born in town became farm owners later in life than those who had always been on the farm, perhaps be - cause they had less parental help than the farm boys who had always stayed on the farm. The surviving owners who secured their farms forty years ago or more spent less than </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 210 32 18.5 years on their fathers' farms without wages as com - pared with 21.3 in case of those who obtained their farms within the last five years preceding the survey (1916-1920). Those who have been farm owners for forty years spent five years as hired men and three years as tenants while those who had owned their land less than five years spent six and a half years as hired men and eleven years as tenants and gained ownership distinctly later in life. M Other Nebraska Survey Bulletins Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Uni. of Ne Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 180. 1922. pp. 28. figs. 8. Linco Out of print, but available mimeographed as a digest. The Nebraska Farm Family. Some Land Tenure Phas Uni. of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 185. 1923. pp. 31. fii 8. Lincoln. Out of print, but available in mimeogr; form, as a digest of Bulletins 185, 191 and 196. Nebraska Farm Homes. A Comparison of Some Conditions of Owners, Part-owners, and Tenants. Neb. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. pp. 48. f Lincoln. Out of print. Digest available. Nebraska Farm Tenancy. Some Community Phas of Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1923. pp. 50. f Lincoln. Out of print. Digest availabl Landlords of Nebraska Farms. Uni. of Nebr. Agr. I Sta. Bui. 202. 1924. pp. 38. figs. 4. Lincoln. Tenure and Farm Investment in Nebraska. Uni. of Nebr Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 205. 1925. pp. 36. figs. 4. Lincoln Out of print, but available as a 17-page mimeographei digest. For copies addres College of Agriculture Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>