<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00037">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Effect of Maturity and the Ethylene Chlorhydrin Seed Treatment on the Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes</title>
               <date value="1931-08">1931-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 57 The Effect of Maturity and the Ethylene Chlorhydrin Seed Treatment on the Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes H. 0. WERNER Department of Horticulture LINCOLN, NEBRASKA AUGUST, 1931 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Summary . Literature Review .'. _ Experimental Methods Seed stocks used . „' Greenhouse testing methods ,' ( Experimental Results . ' Results from major experiments..... n Duration of the dormant period 'ZZZ ."."" 12 Effect of ethylene chlorhydrin treatments ......'."1....." 12 Relation of tuber maturity to dormancy and sprout growth"."! 10 Effect of storage temperature on tuber dormancy 29 Results from miscellaneous experiments 30 Methods of terminating the dormant period 'jO Effectiveness of the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment when ap - plied at intervals after cutting seed potatoes ... 33 Influence of soil in which seed pieces are planted 33 Relation of size of seed piece to sprout growth of dormant potatoes : n , Position of the eyes on the tuber as a factor affecting jrrowth response in dormant tubers .... 37 Sprout growth of irrigated and dry-land-grown seed potatoes 38 Literature Cited '. . on </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY •■■ 1. Tests were conducted, principally by greenhouse plantings, to determine : (a) The duration of the dormant period in lots of potatoes in which immaturity of various degrees was acquired by several methods and the response of such lots of seed when planted at intervals after both warm and cold storage, and with and without ethylene chlorhydrin treatment (short-time dipping of cut seed pieces in a 5 per cent solution and draining, followed by 24 hours in an air-tight chamber). (b) The relative efficacy of various recommended methods in terminating the dormant period of Triumph tubers of various de - grees of maturity. (c) The effect of various practices upon the efficacy of the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment. 2. The emergence from the dormant period was found to be a gradual transition and not an abruptly occurring incident. As length of time after harvesting increased, tubers sprouted more promptly when planted and produced more sprouts per seed piece. The number of sprouting eyes per seed piece also increased. 3. In .field tests planted in the- Bermuda Islands during September the lowest yield increase from ethylene chlorhydrin treated seed was 17.5 per cent and the highest 62.0 per cent. These yield increases are an indication of the relative advances in sprouting produced by the treatment. The most mature potatoes responded most promptly to the treatment. 4. When Nebraska grown potatoes which were approaching the end of their dormant period were planted in January at Hastings, Florida, ethylene chlorhydrin treatment did not appear to hasten emergence or increase yields, but it did increase the number of stems per plant. 5. Potatoes harvested when immature ripened in storage more quickly than did the tubers that were* allowed to remain on the vines from one to three. months longer. The emergence rate, sprout curve, and number of stems were used as a basis for comparison. 6. Cutting vines early and allowing potatoes to remain in the field till October produced tubers that sprouted more promptly and vigor - ously than late-harvested stock, but not quite so quickly as early-har - vested potatoes. • . 7. Tubers that were immature because of late planting responded more slowly than mature potatoes in the early part of the season, but sometimes more quickly by the end of the season. 8. Tubers that were immature because of stocks having been planted late sprouted more slowly than those which were immature from having been harvested early, but when both lots were stored the same length of time, the former produced more sprouts. 9. By using the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment on seed tubers from lots of seed of various degrees of maturity and from monthly plantings during the winter, the following general results were obtained : (a) Ethylene chlorhydrin induced prompt sprout growth in all potatoes that had not completed the dormant period. As tubers advanced toward the end of their respective dormant periods tho response to the treatment declined. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">and^Utnfbefof' SS 111^-,^ **" were most mature when treated SGCUred from the Potatoes that =£•£ HHS^rrS •-"•-" si tte reduced numbS of °JS "" ""» « check.) from potato.,* that we?" troaS i h ii c S"'" e ! i "" h period was about completed treated when their dormant required in cold storage lwnlcn tnree or four months were e/ree'uv^me'ta*:! Sffif eVKS" „"", fo ""' i «• "• *« - inb.r,. Sodium thiocyanat" nSSeS (5%,, ™ *fi"* nE '» "•"»« «uri b Larc!p i ." l s:' i n" C oTi l o tE h r;,r -"■■ - - 1 "' --- (c) Using large seed pieces. • •'■' '■ ■'■■'. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Effect of Maturity and the Ethylene Chlorhydrin Seed Treatment on the Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes H.O. WERNER Western Nebraska dry-land Triumph potatoes (Solanum tuberosum L.) vary in maturity at the time of harvest, from some that are very immature to others with vines which are entirely ripe. Variations in maturity may be due to such factors as early frost, drouth, destruction of vines by hail or early blight, time of planting, and strain type (whether early or late maturing) . The question of seed maturity and its influence upon duration of the dormant period is of con - siderable commercial importance, since these potatoes are annually being planted in south Texas as early as December 26 and in southern Florida, Bermuda, and the West Indies as early as September and October. In order to supply the most satisfactory seed to these regions it is necessary to determine the facts concerning the duration of the dormant period and the sprouting habits of tubers of varying maturity as well as the influence of such factors as time of harvesting and method of storage upon dormancy. Furthermore it is necessary to know how such tubers respond to the more important chemical methods of terminating the dormant period and how the efficiency of said treatments may be increased or impaired by the method of ' application. LITERATURE REVIEW The literature dealing with dormancy in potatoes has been quite completely reviewed in papers by Rosa (7) and Smith (8) to which readers are referred. That which follows is not a complete statement, since the only papers mentioned here are those which raise points pertinent to these studies. Appleman (1) stimulated growth of immature or unsub - erized tubers by removing the periderm around the eyes and by cutting close to the eye or by making wounds close to the eye, He also used several chemicals to break the rest period and reported the most satisfactory results with ethyl bromide. The effectiveness of ethylene chlorhydrin and the several thiocyanates in stimulating growth in dormant tubers was discovered by Denny (2), who later (4) reported upon var - ious details including the relation of temperature to the effect - iveness of and injury by the chlorhydrin treatment. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 Smith (8) reported upon the gaseous exchanges which occur in potatoes when treated with ethylene chlorhydrin. He reported much more prompt growth from immature tubers stored in a humid atmosphere than from those stored in a dry atmosphere. He also reported that changes within the tuber which were necessary for sprouting, occurred much more rapidly in tubers harvested from green vines than in tubers which remained on the vines until maturity. In one of the most recent papers dealing with the question of tuber maturity as a factor influencing dormancy, Rosa (7) concluded that the tubers most mature at harvesting have the shortest rest period, as indicated by their more rapid sprouting when planted. He reported further that the rate of sprouting in mature tubers increases rapidly with length of storage but. that tubers that are immature when harvested emerge from dormancy more slowly. He considered emer - gence from the dormant period as a gradual and not a sudden change. He reported marked acceleration in the sprouting of tubers held at high temperatures (28°— 30° C.) and some retarding as due to low temperature (4° C), especially in the early part of the dormant period. He also found that sprout growth was greatly hastened by high humidity when the storage temperature was intermediate (22° C). Loomis (5) has called attention to the importance of high storage temperatures and high soil temperatures for early germination of dormant tubers. He also reported that early in the dormant period growth occurred earlier with three- and four-ounce tubers than with those weighing one and two ounces — also that composted soil stimulated early growth of tubers planted in it much more than did sarid. He reported no gain in early growth from storage of tubers in damp moss. EXPERIMENTAL METHODS The major experiments were planned so as to determine, with the Triumph variety, the significance of tuber maturity in relation to (a) the duration of the dormant period, and (b) the response to chemical treatments (principally ethylene chlorhydrin, C1CH.CHOH) that are used for inducing growth in dormant tubers. Minor experiments were conducted to determine the extent to which various methods of handling seed potatoes before or after planting affect sprout growth, and also to determine the best method of using the ethylene chlorhydrin seed treat - ment. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">. The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes ■ ■ _j SEED STOCKS USED Tubers of varying maturity were produced for the major experiments by (a) harvesting on different dates (planting date the same) ; (b) by planting on different dates (harvest - ing on the same date) ; and (c) by cutting off vines of grow - ing plants on different dates but harvesting late on the same date. Only a portion of the experiments and treatments within these experiments are being reported. Those selected are con - sidered most truly representative and suffice to establish the essential facts. Wherever there is any lack of harmony in results from several similar experiments, the condition is dis - cussed. The experimental material dealing with the maturity ques - tion was secured in the following manner. For the 1927-28 preliminary tests (used also for testing several chemical and physical methods of terminating the dormant period) Triumph potatoes from lots of seed planted at Alliance on May 14, June 1, June 16, and July 1 were used. The maturity of these various plantings was estimated at 100, 95, 85 and 15 per cent respectively, when the vines were killed by frost on September 19, after which all lots were harvested. 1 For the 1928-29 tests the Triumph material produced at Alliance provided lots of tubers of varying maturity as fol - lows: Series 1 — Seed of varying maturity secured by altering harvesting date. Lot D — Planted May 10, harvested Aug. 2, when 90 per cent mature. Lot G — Planted May 10, harvested Oct. 2, when 100 per cent mature. Series 2 — Seed of varying maturity secured by early cutting of vines. Lot H — Planted May 10, vines cut Aug. 2, harvested Oct. 2. Series 3 — Seed of varying maturity secured by altering . planting date. Lot G — Planted May 10, harvested Oct. 2, when 100 per cent mature. Lot R — Planted July 3, harvested Oct. 2, when 25 . per cent mature. Other lots which were included but for which no data are being presented are : in Series 1, Lot F, harvested Sept. 5, and 1 "Maturity" was estimated for each experimental lot of seed and was based on the general condition of a)! vines of the lot on a specific date. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 a complete and comparable series, Lots K, L, M, planted June 5; in Series 2, Lot J, planted May 10, vines cut Sept. 4, and Lots N and O, planted June 5, with vines cut Aug. 17 and Sept. 4 and all harvested Oct. 2; and in Series 3, Lots M and P, planted June 5 and 22 and harvested Oct. 2, and another complete set harvested on Sept. 5 instead of Oct. 2. All of the tubers of the previously enumerated Alliance lots were placed in cold storage at a temperature of 38°-40° F. within one week after harvesting. In order to determine the effect of higher storage tempera - tures, 6 lots of Alliance-grown seed were held in a cellar with temperatures of a decreasing order, the mean daily tempera - tures having been from 75° to 65° F. in August and Septem - ber; 65° to 56° F. in October; 55° to 45° F. in November; and 45° to 40° F. in December, when the last lots were re - moved. The cellar-stored lots and their comparable cold-storage lots were as follows : Lot S— Planted May 10, harvested Aug. 2. Com - parable to cold storage Lot DL Lot U — Planted May 10, harvested Oct. 2. Com - parable to cold storage Lot G. Other lots which were included but for which data are not shown were Lot T, comparable to cold storage Lot F, har - vested Sept. 5, and a series, V, W, and Y, planted June 5 and harvested respectively on Aug. 17, Sept. 5, and Oct. 2. During the same season (1928-29) tubers varying in matur - ity due to harvesting date were also used. These were pro - duced on dry land at North Patte. The field plantings were made April 15 and the lots of tubers used were harvested on July 20, August 10, September 1, and October 10. The tubers for the main series of tests with these lines of potatoes were stored in the same cellar used for storing the previously described Alliance potatoes. Another series was stored (from harvest time until December) in a room where the tempera - ture averaged between 70° and 75° F. This experiment is discussed briefly without reporting the data. For the 1929-30 tests Triumphs grown on dry land near Alliance from stocks planted on May 27 (A) and June 29 (B) were used. The vines- of the May stocks (A) were about 65 per cent mature and the June stocks. (B) about 8 per cent mature when harvested on October 2. This relative imma - turity of both lots was due to the cool, damp weather that pre - vailed for about 25 days prior to harvesting. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">• . JL The Dormancy op Triumph Potatoes GREENHOUSE TESTING METHODS In the major experiments the required amounts of seed of the various lots to be. used in any test were brought out of storage on the day previous to the testing or planting date, for the greenhouse test. The total number of seed pieces needed from each lot were cut, at the rate of ten seed pieces to the pound. As they were cut an effort was made to see that the seed pieces from each tuber were divided between two piles as nearly as possible. The seed pieces in one were given the etnylene chlorhydrin treatment; the others were used as un - treateo checks. In all the 1928-29 tests, unless otherwise specified 50 seed pieces of each lot of seed were used both for the check and treated series. In the 1929-30 tests. 100 seed pieces were used. The ethylene chlorhydrin treatment used was as follows Immediately after cutting, the seed pieces were dipped into a 5 per cent commercial (40 per cent) ethylene chlorhydrin solution for about one-half minute, after which they were re - moved and allowed to drain for a few minutes, when they were placed in small clean muslin sacks, which were stored in a metal, practically air-tight container of about seven cubic feet capacity for 24 hours. Prior to 1929 these treatments were administered in the head house of the greenhouse. As a result of some unavoidably low temperatures encountered there during the midwinter, the efficacy of the tests was some - rimes seriously impaired. Consequently in the 1929-30 tests all treated potatoes were provided with uniform temperature conditions by being placed inside an uniced refrigerator in a laboratory held at room temperature. While the treatment was being administered to the one lot of seed, the cut seed pieces of the check were also held at room temperature (70°-75° P.). Immediately after the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment was completed, the treated and un - treated pieces were planted in separate flats for sprouting tests. All seed- pieces were covered to a depth of about one. inch when planted. In 1927 and earlier, sand was used as a testing medium, but in 1928 and later as a result of the work of Loomis (5) and some preliminary tests by the author (Table 6) composted garden soil was used. (Compare Charts 5 and 1 and see Figure 5.) Prior to 1929-30 all seed pieces of one treatment of one lot of seed were planted in only one flat. This one-flat method was found inadequate because of the difficulty of providing identical temperature and moisture conditions for all lots which of necessity were in different portions of the green - house. In the 1929-30 tests, the 100 seed pieces of each lot of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 SEto wlrf jffiw^ f ° UI " *?** (25 pieces each &gt;&gt; and those nats were distributed so as to expose each lot of seed to thp t?on 1O of S conditions prevailing wifhinthepor- Tr, L greenhouse being used for the experiment. «i« ♦ a . seed -niaturity experiments, lots of each line were Planted at monthly intervals from October to April The exact dates are given in the tables and charts. 1 he total number of sprouts above ground in each lot wprp counted two or three times a week from the time the Trst sprouts emerged until the 40th day, when the tests were iZ™L}^To a T«v, amiOUeh S ° me — -tinuedT? w «? U ~n R "f- winter months the greenhouse temperature ™, B l T Uy , T er than in the fal1 a "d spring, and the ™° p u n *^ sunlight was considerably less. Consequently in some of the midwinter-month plantings, the growth was fesHL reS, d r ri^ ** VY %V° US teStin ° P e^ iods Te ApJi test the reduction in growth was due to excessively high tem - peratures, which are unfavorable to potatoes At the termination. of each test,. notes were taken on each seed piece with regard to the number of eyes producS sprouts, the number of above-ground i and below-ground sprouts, and with regard to whether the seed piece wfsd or mant and whether sound or rotten. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS In order to give a reasonably fair and complete description 3nrW tf P T 6 ° f a l0t ° f Seed when P lan^d at intervals during the storage season or when given any treatment de- K? t Tf^vf grOWth ' !t has been found very des"rab?e to present data by several methods. The average number of SSrffhP'-'* 01^ emergence of a s^out f/om "SSh seed % L ! ot 1S a x falr means of indicating, not perhaps the end of the dormant period but rather the period when sprout growth can be initiated in a lot of seed potatoes ; Thl Sal sriSh 1 ' &amp; rr uts pr ? duced by an^ *™™£S£ of 5U S HmT™* d 1 omm - anCe Within a lot of P° tat oes at any gfven time and also, in a general way, of the probable tuber set that can be expected from a lot of potatoes. A few general facts acquired by these several methods of presenTing data </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes can quite appropriately be discussed at this point before pro - ceeding to the more detailed discussions. The emergence data of every lot of tubers tested resulted in essentially the same type of curve, when the total number of sprouts emerging were platted against definite time inter - vals. This curve was somewhat similar to a typical growth curve with (a) a low initial rise occupying a variable period of time, (b) a more rapid intermediate rise, and (c) a flatten - ing out at the upper end (Chart 1). When a lot of seed was very dormant the curve was relatively flat (Chart 1, Section 1), but with fewer dormant lots, the curve became steeper until finally during the period of greatest activity, it was almost vertical, (Chart 1, Section 5). = The few very early sprouts that occurred in most lots were generally from the eyes located .close to the cut surface. Apple - man (1) demonstrated that such eyes produce early sprouts because of the increased oxidation of the adjoining tissues. In the case of a very dormant lot of seed potatoes (Chart 1, Rl), 3 the long interval between the emergence of the first sprouts and the period when the greatest number of sprouts were emerging was probably due to the suberization of the cut surfaces, which shut off the oxygen supply and interfered with the necessary oxidation. Growth of most of the sprouts occurred only after the necessary internal changes had been accomplished, gradually and slowly. The degree of apical dominance within tubers and the eyes of tubers had a very direct bearing upon the shape of the curves. When apical dominance was well established in a given lot of tubers, the curve rose rapidly but flattened out at a relatively low or intermediate point (Chart 1, Section 1). When apical dominance was very poorly developed, the curve was relatively flat in the early period of growth, but then rose rapidly and flattened out at a relatively high point (Chart 1, Section 5). In the case of the apically dominant tubers the number of single-sprout pieces was very great (Chart 2). These single sprouts emerged very quickly. When not apically dominant, many of the seed pieces produced multiple sprouts which competed with each other for food and consequently the emergence of all was somewhat retarded. RESULTS FROM MAJOR EXPERIMENTS The length of the dormant period in the various lots of seed ■ 'Section number refers to subdivision, within the chart. Each subdivision repre - sents data from lots planted on one testinK date. •Rl and similar combinations of letters and numbers refer to seed lots and the time when the last test was made in the greenhouse. Rl represents lots from seed planted in the field July 3, harvested October 2, 1928, and then planted for Kreen - house test on October 15, while R2 represents seed from the same seed lot but planted November 14, and R3 on December 14, etc </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 and the effect of the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment upon the tubers of these seed lots at various periods during the stor - age season were considered in all tests in these major series. 4 These two phases are discussed in a rather general or sum - marizing manner, in connection with each lot of seed or series rather than in detail, since the latter plan would involve much repetition which would be productive of but few additional facts. Summarizing statements concerning these two phases are therefore inserted in the fore part of this presentation of ex - perimental results, since much of the later discussion might seem incomplete without a knowledge of the facts thus pre - sented. Duration of the dormant period. — No definite period of time can be named as the length of the dormant period. The duration of the period will depend upon various factors such as tuber maturity at harvest time and temperature and humidity of the storage room. The emergence from the dormant period is a gradual transition and not an -abruptly occurring incident. * When each lot of seed was held for an additional month growth was more rapid and tht sprout-emergence curve be - came steeper, provided, of course, that temperature con - ditions in the greenhouse remained the same. As the tubers of all lots became older (measuring from har - vest time) apical dominance diminished, as did the number of days for the average emergence of sprouts per seed piece, while there was an increase in the number of sprouting eyes and number of sprouts per seed piece (Charts 2 and 3). Al - most invariably the sprouting of tubers of any lot of seed varied more from early to late in the storage period than did that of the various lots of seed planted on anv one test date. . Effect of ethylene chlorhydrin treatments in the green - house tests. — Ethylene chlorhydrin induced prompt growth m all lots of dormant seed potatoes. The difference between the growth of the checks and that of the treated lots of seed t * T Tfc- d f ta fr °r m i th6 vario " s lot » an &lt;» treatments are summarized in Tables 1 to lot. T.nS,M P » C j r V ine .B rowth - produced by the end of 30 days from most of the which, in showing the number of sprouts above ground for each seed lot by any r^Whe ssH^i i^. i f? n i f ,n th 5h t^ I . i ?sri h 9 2r Ivit&gt;r - are Biven in chart ° chlorhy'drin SSftnfESi. "^ CharU dMl " ilh 8 « d lota b ° th tr-W with ethylene </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes was greatest in the case of the most immature potatoes (Chart 1, A and B, and Tables 1 and 2). The growth curves of the various lots of potatoes held much the same ratio to each other when seed was treated as when not treated. Matur - ity of dormant seed tubers, while important, was never a limiting factor of consequence; that is, no tubers used were ever too immature to respond very promptly and vigorously to ethylene chlorhydrin treatments. In the tubers no longer dormant, the treatment was of little consequence regardless of the degree of maturity at harvest time. During the first month or two of the testing season the treated tubers produced the most growth. The number of seed pieces producing plants, the average number of days for emergence, and the total number of stems produced were used to measure the relative response of a lot of seed (Tables 1 to 3 and Charts 2 and 3). As the storage season advanced the treated tubers produced the first plants more slowly than did the comparable checks, but by 20 to 30 days after plant - ing the treated lots were growing much more actively, as shown by. the larger total number of stems per lot. This increase was due to the fact that there were more growing eyes per seed piece as well as more sprouts per seed piece in the treated lots (Tables 1 to 3). The ethylene chlor - hydrin treatment reduced the apical dominance of the tubers. This retarded the first sprouts, which were from buds located in apical positions, but it stimulated the growth of the other buds, which of course produced sprouts a little later since non - .ipical buds (both within tubers and within eyes of tubers) were more dormant at the time they were treated than apical ones and also because there was competition for food on account .of the increased number of stems growing from each seed piece. This condition was very noticeable throughout the entire season, from November 15 until the last planting on April 22.. During the early months the treatment more than doubled the number of sprouts per seed piece, but toward spring the difference was considerably reduced (Charts 2 and 3). This early stimulation of more buds per seed piece may be as im - portant an action as the early stimulation of growth in the dormant tubers. In the ethylene chlorhydrin plats there was more seed-piece rotting than in the check lots. (Tables 1 to 4). This was especially the case in early fail and late spring. This was partly due to the higher temperatures, at which ethylene chlorhydrin has been found to cause more damage. At all </seg>
            <seg id="p014">- •■ — seta*. ■■*««. ■ ! — - - ''W -lZJEZJI... 5 Ptant »«. except the top row. which wore takon nt 7 toys" All ptanttam *of P o h n t&gt;t0 i :r . a ' &gt;h ( l 1 wer ? take " 30 days after * flat crew lamer than the E plants which encount t .ri"l E S ftti Ken f eraIly he individual plants with fewer shoots per shoots per flat. Note the greater density of Trowth V&amp; ETr\ l m 8 !?S 2 rS r , e sp b r o C u\ UB e C m e°4e n h c C e SZ? Sg&amp; ,f. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes times the most matijre lots appeared to be damaged least by this treatment. Any given lot of seed generally produced as much early growth when treated and planted on October 15 as did this same lot untreated, when planted in January and February ; or, in other words, by the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment the same growth was achieved three or four months ahead of the normal time (Charts 1 and 5). The same relationship was evident with regard to the number of sprouting eyes, or the number of sprouts per seed piece (Charts 2 and 3). Effect of ethylene chlorhydrin in the field tests. — Some co-operative experiments with Nebraska potatoes of varying maturity, both with and without ethylene chlorhydrin treat - ments, were conducted in the Bermuda Islands s in the fall of 1928 and at Hastings, Florida, 0 in the early months of both 1929 and 1930. The data from these experiments will be reported in a later paper, but it seems appropriate to make a brief statement of the general results at this time. In the Bermuda' Islands all lots of potatoes responded very promptly to the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment, administered either as a gas before shipping the potatoes from Nebraska or as a liquid immediately after the cutting of seed tubers for planting in Bermuda. The tubers were from North Platte, from plantings made April 20th, and were all quite mature. They responded much more promptly and exten - sively than those from Alliance, which were from late-May plantings and were more immature when harvested Sept. 2nd. The time of harvesting at North Platte (July 20, Aug. 10, Sept. 2) had little influence on emergence time in Bermuda. This was true of both treated and untreated tubers. The ethylene chlorhydrin treatment caused an increase in yield of 18 to 50 per cent with North Platte stock and 17.5 to 62.0 per cent with the Alliance stock. In experiments in 1926, treated seed outyielded untreated by 50 per cent (reported in 1926 report of Dept. of Agriculture, Bermuda, 3, 6). By the time potatoes are planted at Hastings, Florida, that is, early January, they have almost passed through their dor - mant period. Tests during two seasons failed to reveal any earlier emergence in any lots of seed as a result of the ethyl - ene chlorhydrin treatment. The treatment, however, did in - crease the number of stems per seed piece. The seed tubers from the 1928 May plantings in Alliance produced 3.3 per seed piece for the untreated and 4.1 for the treated, while • Work in Bermuda was conducted by E. A. McCallan, Director of Agriculture, partly in cooperation with Dr. F. E. Denny of the Boyce-Thompson Institute for Plant Research, Yonkers, N. Y. • The work at Hastings. Florida, was carried on by Dr. L. O. Gratz, of the Florida ABricultural .Experiment Station. .■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 with the seed tubers planted July 3 at Alliance, the untreated produced 3.7 in comparison with 4.2 stems for the treated. Similar differences occurred in 1929. Doubtless due to peculiar seasonal conditions these ethylene chlorhydrin treat - ments did not bring about any significant yield increases in these Florida tests. It may be seen that the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment was very practical when given very early after harvest, as indicated by the September plantings in Bermuda. While it has been effective on lots of tubers representing different degrees of ripeness, a considerable degree of tuber maturity would seem to have been desirable. With plantings made later, that is. in January, the treatment did increase sprout growth but there is still some question concerning the effect on yield when used at this date. When the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment was used in west - ern Nebraska in June in some rather large-scale experiments on cold storage potatoes, it did not alter sprout growth or yields in any perceptible manner. The same can be said of some tests with Irish Cobblers planted near Lincoln in April, 1926. Relation of tuber maturity to dormancy and sprout growth. — Immature potatoes, as previously stated, were produced by several methods: (1) by early harvesting of early-planted stocks; (2) by early vine cutting of early - planted stocks, and (3) by late harvesting of late planted stocks. The 1928-1929 experiments are used as a basis for the discussion which follows. (For sprout growth see Fig. Immaturity due to time of harvesting. — Potatoes that were immature because of time of harvesting produced sprouts more promptly than did the more mature or late-harvested tubers (August 2 D contrasted with October 2 G in May plantings, Chart 1 and Table 1). This difference, which is indicated by the average emergence date and sprout emerg - ence curves, was apparent in each monthly planting from October 15 to April 22. but mostly during the early months. With the immature stock there were also quite generally more sprouting eyes as well as more sprouts per seed piece (Charts 3 and 4). The response of a lot of seed harvested on the intermediate date (September 5) was quite generally intermediate between that of the stock harvested in August and October. In a similar test of lots of seed planted on dry land at North Platte in April, 1929, and harvested on July 20, August 10, September 10, and October 10, the response was essentially in the same manner; that is, on any one date </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes the early-harvested stocks. which were most immature when harvested grew most promptly, and the late-harvested stocks which were most mature when harvested grew most slowly (as measured by sprout emergence curves), and they pro - duced the fewest stems per seed piece. When tubers which had been stored the same length of time were compared from both lots — that is, when the Octo - ber testing of August harvested stock (D 1) was compared with the December testing of October harvested stocks (G3) etc. — the mean plant-emergence date from the seed pieces of immature . stocks (early harvested) was generally still earlier than that of the mature stocks (Table I). 7 The growth curve of the early-harvested lot rose more rapidly in the first portion of the sprouting period but at about 25 or 30 days. it flattened out at a lower point than did the curve of the late-harvested stocks (Chart 1). The mean number of sprouts per seed piece as well as the number of multiple - sprouting seed pieces was by far the highest in the late-har - vested (field-mature) stocks (Charts 2 and 3 and Table 1). All these differences diminished as the storage season ad - vanced. Apparently when maturity was obtained by late harvesting, and tubers were stored the same length of time as were those harvested early, those that remained on the vines the longest made the most desirable growth and were the least apically dominant but did not produce the first sprouts quite so early. Immaturity due to early vine cutting. — Potatoes which were immature because the parent vines had been cut off at the surface of the ground on August 2 — May 10 planting har - vested October 2 (H) — sprouted more promptly during Octo - ber and November than those which remained on the un - damaged vines until harvested in October (G), (Table 1 and Chart 1). The average sprouting time was more nearly the same for both lots beginning with the December tests, but the cut-vine stocks (H) still continued to be slightly earlier. The cut-vine stocks (H) also produced slightly more sprouts per seed piece than did the mature-vine, late-harvested stocks (G). \ The average sprouting dates of these August 2 cut-vine, field-stored potatoes (H) were generally later than those of the tubers harvested on the same date(D), but due to the tendency toward a greater number of sprouts per seed piece (Table 1 and Chart 2) the sprouting curves from the tubers of the cut- vine lot were generally the higher (Chai-t 1). ~ Other compnrable lots are D2 with G4, D3 with G4. D4 with G6, and D5 with G7. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">** ttIO T1JIATED ! . /'-&lt;* M l/l I 1 111 II 111 1 lrf-1-l li I 1 1//1 1 1 111 I 1 ; °1 i? » S3 2a IB U »« 40 10 »0 » 4O 10 10 JO 40 10- » » 40 W M SO^ 40 10 JO M 40 Chart 1. — Curves showing sprout emergence rate from seed potatoes varying in degree of maturity and planted at monthly intervals from October, 11)28, (1) to April, 1929, (7) both with and without treat - ment with ethylene ehlorhydrin before planting. (See Tables /and /and Figure/.) </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Table 1.— Summary of sprouting record of dry-land (Alliance) seed stocks planted on May 10, 1928, but harvested on different dates — 50 seed pieces used in each lot • I Percentage of seed pieces Average number of days Moan number of sprout- Mean number of stems Percentage of seed B producing aprouia for sprout emergence 1 ing eyes per seed piece'- per seed piece pieces rotting pl'aTted (DJ "(Hi I '""(el (f&gt;7 (H) W~"~W JW (O (dT (H) (0) (D) ~(H&gt; . (G) g .in • Vines ! Vines Vines . Vines Vines g ES Har- Aug.^. Uar- Har- Aug.' 2, Har- Har- Aug'2, Har- Har- Aug. 2, Har- Har- Aug. 2. Har- &gt; vested hSr, vested vested har- vested vested har- vested vested har- vested vested har- vested Aug. 2 vested Oct. 2 Aug. 2 vested Oct. 2 Aug. 2 vested Oct. 2 Aug. 2 vested Oct. 2 Aug. 2 vested Oct. 2 £ Oct. 2 Oct. 2 Oct. 2 Oct. 2 Oct. 2 UNTREATED CHECKS O Oct. 15 .. 98- 100 88 28.7 28.6 32.7 1.10 1.04 1.02 1.10 1.06 1.02 2' 0 4 "9 . Nov. 14. ... 100 100 100 16.2 18.9 21.6 1.14 1.14 1.12 1.40 1.50 1.24 0 0 0 Dec, 14 .... 100 96 98 11.8 20.9 19.2 1.34 1.25 1.47 1.44 1.B4 1.86 0 4 • 0 £1 Jan. 14 . ■• 100 100 94 15.9 21.1 21.2 1.50 1.52 1.45 1.92 2.14 1.94 0 0 4 g Feb 15 .. 100 98 98 17.8 20J) 21.4 2.08 1.43 1.50 2.74 2.20 2.27 0 0 0 ,-, Mar. 20... 00 96 98 15.2 18.0 16.1 1.94 1.94 1.76 2.60 2.63 2.20 0 4 2 g Apr 22 96 | 100 94 17.6 17.6 18.2 1.95 2.02 2.03 2.51 2.64 2.68 0 0 6 « SEED PIECES TREATED WITH ETHYLENE CHLORHYDRIN K Oct.15 86 100 8-1 17.6 24.1 18.7 1.68 1.28, 1.50 2.17 1.82 2.14 14 0 16 Nov 14 ... 98 88 82 20.4 21.5 22.5 1.86 1.66 1.36 3.06 2.59 2.17 0 10 16 Dcc.14 .- 100 100 98 21.4 24.6 24.8 2.00 1.80 1.90 3.14 3.20 3J5 0 0 0 £ Jan 14 100 100 100 24.2 22.8 23.0 2.18 2.16 1.98 3.28 3.48 2.74 0 0 0 H Feb 15 100 00 96 21.6 22.6 21.5 2.12 1.96 2.07 3.34 3J6 3.56 0 0 2 Mar 20 00 I 96 100 17.7 18.0 18.9 2.36 2.19 2.08 3.90 4.00 3.68 0 4 0 % Ap"'22 •'■•■ 97- 1 92 58 18.5 17.4 18.9 1.62 2.24 1.81 3.08 3.97 3.23 0 0 42 g 'Average number of days for sprout emergence is based on all seed pieces producing sprouts, not on all seed pieces planted. 03 '"Sprouting eyes" refers to eyes the sprouts from which were through the soil when the test was terminated. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 60 Table 2. — Summary of sprouting record of dry Mind- grown seed stock from July 3 (R) planting « in li)2S when tested at monthly intervals during dormant period, without and with ethylene &gt; chlorhydrin treatment — record based on 50 seed pieces ________ __ i _ == __ == ___ ;:= ____ Percentage of seed Average number of Mean number of Mean number of Percentage of seed c/_ r, i «__r • pieces producing days for sprout sprouting eyes per stems per seed pieces rotting H Date planted sprouts . emergence seed piece piece f in greenhouse .__ |_ " : . : , Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated h _fct~15~ ~26~ 92 40.7 15.0 1.08 1.50 1.08 2.20 0 v8 . Nov 14 ■ 98 100 21.0 18.1 1.18 1.50 1.44 2.94 0 0 W Dec 14 ■•■ 94 100 16.6 '2\A 1.49 1.80 2.15 3.38 6 0 g Jan 14 100 100 21.6 22.8 1.28 1.86 1.96 3.76 0 0 Feb 15 100 96 18.8 20.2 1.84 2.08 2.60 3.79 0 0 W Mar. 20. ■'■:... 96- 96 15.1 16.1 1.75 1.96 2.68 3.51 0 2 C Apr. 22 ._._;___ 96 100 17J3 j 17.9 I' 1.81 2.05 2 ; 58 2.93 4 0___ | ■Firty-nix per cent »f Iho sctil pii'cps were still dormant 15 daya nflrr the _PU wjti' planted. ...... -1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">• The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes Apparently cutting the vines early and storing the tubers in the field (H) was a satisfactory practice, for it resulted in sprouting curves higher than those of field-matured tubers (G) and very comparable to those of early-harvested stocks (D). The average sprouting dates were, however, generally closer to those of the late-harvested (G) than to those of the early-harvested stocks (D). With another line of tubers produced by plants that had the vines cut off at the surface of the soil on September 4 ( J) , the responses were intermediate between those of the vines cut August 2 (H) and the vine-matured stocks harvested October 2 (G). Evidently the maturation processes essential for the re - newal of growth in tubers were accomplished more quickly when tubers were isolated from growing vines than when allowed to remain on the active vines for a long period of time, or till the latter were mature. When tubers of late-harvested lots (G) were stored for two months longer than the tubers harvested the same day but above which the vines had been cut early (so as to be removed from the vines the same number of days — comparison such as G3 with HI or G4 with H2) not only did the plants gen - erally emerge earlier but they produced higher growth curves and more sprouts per seed piece (Table 1 and Charts 1 and 2). The two months of additional vine maturity was advan - tageous. Immaturity due to late planting. — When immaturity of seed tubers was due to late planting (July 3), sprouting was delayed considerably more by October 15, 13 days after harvesting, than with May 10 planting (Chart 1). However, on November 14 and on December 14 this imma - ture stock was sprouting about as promptly and vigorously as the mature stock. After a rest of 135 days (February 15) and longer, the immature, stock was always ahead. The immature stock always produced more shoots per seed piece than did the mature stock (Tables 1 and 2 and Chart 2). The growth responses of lots of seed from June 5 (M) and June 20 (P) plantings, representing intermediate degrees of maturity, were generally of an intermediate degree throughout the testing period. Evidently a certain degree of maturity was essential for sprout growth, but apparently this was adequately acquired in these late-planted 1928 stocks during the first 43 days after harvest. The early-planted seed stocks in both 1927 and 1928 pro - duced relatively very mature tubers,' while those from the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska- Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 PPODUC^Q GtVEA&gt; /OUMbEQ OF 5TEM5 gV.| c "gCK~W»TgeATTO | TPlATW&gt;~mm.gAit CHUaOHVPOiiO *p|o » "-y ■„ y, „ "&amp; ~*r ■ — »-PlA*T*D U* QQCCitHOVftC OCT.lS D w DO HHi^lBHHMHHBMI^HMMHHIt^ 2.17 i^ H l.CHb B^^B^^^BHBi^BI^HHMHHiHHHHIHT] I ju ~ C« 1.02 IHHHBiHB^HlHHBB^ia^^^^vt • &gt;i rff^^ _ ' *-/tOVtM»Eg 14 S U W =B ***L y l&lt;(ii ,y Zzzzzz^ =^ — I •» "^* *-^^^ \s////////////\ ~T^T h itL *•»* \// /S/S/Jfi~^ *&lt; ••** 1^ T771 IQk^ pt--———,. ■ mtfli tk^f^ , , \SS/{f//{fff/f/\ VW » — ■— '^ 9 »." II || ' .'"'■! **** ™»'»» '"&gt; l"'SSg T , li V///ft&gt;?m "f* 1 Vf/JJJJJiJjri utot l&gt;™^ W^BI^B^^^^^B^B"~ O //////} J\ H • »A I^M — — , ji&gt; Q 1.96 J~~~~ * T *^ — Tfli€&lt;ffffffiiiA IV - ■ - a-FEBlJUAIJY l» ~ _ ,„_ ■ *• MA^CM *O "^'^" ESHS ' J u ?mT^ == ' fr ' ZZ3ra "»■ u;; " JI '"■' 0 „, — r A !?'!r-?^ *O-PtAA»T«O MAYIO- HAQVESTED AU&amp;. I «)UK&amp;EQ OF STEka JJ" . " "Vl/»«»CUT4U«.-l-HAIJVES-rt0 0rT.J '*•»*» &lt;•• " •&gt; - HAQVE*TEO OCT. i I I | | Q- " JULY'S- » » Chart 2.— Distribution of seed pieces producing given numbers of ethylene chlorhydrin seed treatment was used. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">The Dormancy op Triumph Potatoes .asp oewr or sseo p/ec£3 WITH GIVE/0 /DUMBER OF SPgQUTMkr EYES uyrl CHECK- UAJTQEATED I TglATTO-mm.CJte CMU&gt;QHVOm&lt;« "taMIAAjl PC? CEAlT SfluJ] PKQ CK^T | »o. |c no »o *o ao f wo. [o to ao to ao 1-PLAijTW U&gt; «QEEstHOU«B OCX &gt;» °* &gt;■'&lt;&gt; ■^^■^■■^■■■■^■■^■Z^) Illll^— ■ M^^^M I H I.O4 BMI^^^HII^BMaBHBHMHHn L*O &lt;=&lt; LOi M^^^^^^HHHII^^^HHHD ISO i^ - T77 iA - ° u4 "^^ ==1 *-«*^ &lt;? ' -IB MiMi^^^^aMiM=&gt; LftOM^ - ■■■ H US ■■■■■■■KZ3 I.BO—^— ■ r/w//. &amp; I.4T i^—^^—^E=EZ2Z3 L90 r^^^j 9 l-»g^^^^ I h*b^^m^m ,u, a 4-JA^UAlJY ♦♦ t&gt; 130 —^^M I »,»— : ,,,,,,,,rrTTrm H L5^ A.lfc wwwm o ub i iw i mi ■ ■ L^a— — — W /^ P U* — —^^^E=-H L»*^— — — r^ " &gt;-9* —^^^= r////l I 2.19 1^ i&gt;w^^ « "* E22ZZ3 I 1 1 I | 5 1-7! —^— I II 19* yum ' 7-APPlU XZ &lt;&gt; 1^. 1 =p wi ■■^—n— lvj ♦t&gt;-PtAA)TEO MAV 10- WAQVEyrtp AU&amp;.A. " ' /Ml OT «PQOUTIrt6 tTtJ H- ■ •■;•'• " - VlrtESCUT AUCi.*- HAtJVESTtOOCT.? ' * * 4 &amp; I ••■•..»■ • MAt}VE%TED OCT K I Q- • JULY * • &lt;• " 1 Chart 3. — Distribution of seed pieces according to the number of sprouting eyes for various lots of seed planted at monthly inter - vals from October, 1928, to April, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 late-planted stocks were not entirely immature, the vines showing signs of maturity. However, the 1928 stocks were probably the most mature of any used during the three years. On the other hand, in 1929 the tubers from early-planted stocks (A) (May 27) were taken from vines that were only partly ripe, while the vines of the late plantings (B) (June 29) were still entirely green and shov/ed no signs of matur - ity. Figure 2. — Sprout growth of four lots of Triumph seed potatoes. Seed pieces were treated with ethylene chlorhydrin (A) in compari - son with the check (C) the seed pieces of which were soaked in water fov one hour before planting.' The photographs were taken December 23.- In 1927 these various lots had produced less growth at the end of 46 days than did comparable lots in 1928 (2G and 2R for May and July) or 1929 (Lots 2A and 2B) in 30 days. This difference was probably due to the fact that sand, a less satisfactory sprouting medium, was used in 1927. As matur - ity of ;;eed decreased the sprout growth was also less in both treatments. (For sprout emergence curves see Chart 1.) In the series of tests conducted during the winter of 1927 - 28, when potatoes from Alliance-grown stock planted in the field at intervals from May 14 to July 1 were tested by monthly plantings from October to March, the mature, early - planted stock was habitually the first to sprout (Chart 5, A and B, Fig. 2). (The slower growth rate and smaller num - ber of sprouts per 100 seed pieces shown in the 1927-28 tests are undoubtedly due to the use of sand in sprouting the seed pieces. See Table 6 and Figure 5.) </seg>
            <seg id="p025">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes In the 1929-30 testing period the late-planted (immature) stocks not only emerged more slowly on each date but their growth curves were practically always below those of the early-planted stocks, as was also the final number of sprouts per seed piece (Table 3 and Figure 3). This was undoubt - edly due to the fact that in 1929 the tubers from late - planted stocks were not so completely developed as in former years and that tubers from the early plantings were not so mature as in former years because of later planting and better fall growing conditions. It is believed that the earlier sprouting of late-planted 1928 stock (R) late in the storage season is due to the fact that the tubers of the early-planted stocks (G) were much more mature when harvested and consequently they reached the period of highest efficiency (regarding prompt growth) at an earlier date than did the late-harvested stocks. The premature death of the vines due to drouth rather than ordinary senility may have caused abnormal conditions within these early-planted, late-harvested tubers (G). During the three years at harvesting time, the growth activity in plants from late plantings was least in 1928, whereas it was the greatest in 1929. This probably had much to do with the development of the buds within the eyes of the tubers. Immature tubers produced by late planting (R) did not produce sprouts as promptly as did the stocks which were considered immature because of early harvesting (D) or early vine cutting (H). However, the tubers from early cut-vine stocks had the lesser advantage (Tables 1 and 2 and Chart 1). By the end ol' the period — March 20 and April 22 — the late-planted and late-harvested tubers (R) were growing more promptly and vigorously than those of the other lots (Charts 1, 4, and 5). The length of time the tubers were off the growing vines or in storage appeared to be the factor limiting promptness and amount of sprout growth — that is, the tubers with the longest rest period responded most promptly, until the period of maximum activity was reached at about 6 to 7 months, when an inci*eased length of time ceased to be advantageous. A certain minimum degree of maturity was necessary for prompt growth early in the fall. This maturity may have been of an anatomical as well as biological or chemical nature. It was apparently acquired more rapidly when the tubers were off the vine (D or H) than when they remained at - tached to a growing vine (G). The 1928 July-planted stock (R), stored two months longer before planting in the greenhouse than those from the May- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 H. tK Hf «, -* * j ] Balk 3 '^ 8^ 0^ f^ h 3^ days a «er, Planting from mature (RA) and W a 5i™ii5? ) Seed P ot , at ° es (Parent stocks planted May 27 SSmt- % ?' 192 ,9. respectively). Photographs taken 30 days after Planting dates which were the 14th of each month from October hv^ r . h iT 6 ?* February). Check in left flat, ethylene-chlor - nydrin-treated stock in right flat. planted stock (G) (comparisons such as R3 with Gl, R4 and W), emerged most quickly and produced the highest sprout curves and decidedly more sprouts per seed piece (Tables 1 and 2 and Chart 1). Two additional months of storage in rnnrSt R u^ fi beneficial than the two additional W??i?S, aC -?Qo5 ed b /^ G in the fi eld ( on the growing plant. With the 1927 and 1929 tubers an additional period in stor - age sufficient to total the same number of days from plant- Z™ me - stin «, tln V e di d not result in the late-planted stock surpassing the early stock, although the latter was practically equalled frequently (Chart 5 and Table 3) A comparison of data from tubers of each lot stored for the same number of months (Dl with R3, D2 with R4, etc.) indicates that the tubers produced in the early part of the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Table 3.— Summary of sprouting record of early and late-planted Triumph seed potatoes grown on dry land at Alliance in 1929, when planted at monthly intervals throughout the dormant period — 100 seed pieces used in .each lot _^_ .-.--'.—: Percentage of seed Average number of Mean number of Mean number of Percentage of seed X pieces producing days for sprout sprouting eyes per stems per seed pieces rotting, sprouts, parent emergence, parent seed piece, parent piece, parent stock parent stock O Date of stock planted stock planted , stock planted planted planted O teTp n .Sg "^r"^BT M (A) 27 Dj^~$$£~| Jun B e &gt; 29 M^ 27 .| M&amp;7 j J»2?29 &gt; — . .... UNTREATED CHECKS . SEED PIECES TREATED WITH ETHYLENE CHLORHYDRIN Hj Oct 14 I 100 89 14.3 24.5 ■ 3.01 1.82 2.92 2.00 0 81 ' mS. i4. '.:::::: iqq 92 15.1 16.0 2.68 2.50 3.90 4.53 0 29 « 'Six per cent of seed pieces dormant at end of 40 days. I Thiriy-four per cent of seed pieces dormant at end of 40 days. 'Two per cent of seed pieces dormant at end of 40 days. 'These averages too low because of not considering high percentage of tubers that were still dormant at end of 40-day test period. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Table 4. — Performance of early- and late-harvested dry-land-grown tubers planted at monthly p intervals after harvesting, with storage in a warm cellar — 1928 crop — comparable to Lots D &gt; and G in Table 1 •* Percentage of seed Average number of Mean number of Mean number of Percentage of seed H pieces producing days for sprout sprouting eyes per stems per seed pieces rotting, * sprouts, parent emergence, parent | seed piece, parent piece, parent stock parent stock Date planted stock harvested stock harvested stock harvested harvested harvested on CQ in ; : : r ' greenhouse (S) (U) (S) ' (U). (S) (U) (S) . (U) • (S) (U) Aug. 2 Oct. 2 Aug. 2 Oct. 2 Aug. 2 Oct. 2 Aug. 2 Oct. 2 Aug. 2 Oct. 2 W . . UNTHEATED CHECKS M Oct. 15 32 86 ;i;i.5 I 23.9 " I 1.00 1.00 1.13 1.16 68 14 % Nov. 14 :.. 100 98 :tl.6 i 17.4 1.14 1.27 1.18 1.33 0 2 Q Dec. 14 100 I. 100 21.6 j 15.S j 1.14 1.40 1.40 L60 0 0 « SEED PIECES TREATED WITH ETHYLENE CHLORHYDRIN td Oct. 15 H6 «0 | 26.2 \ 2.J.!) ! 1.28 1.07 1.67 1.60 64 40 P Nov. 14... 100 100 26.7 25.6 1.34 1.92 1.86 2.44 0 0 rj Dec. 14 ..;■■■■■ 100 100 24.7 19.2 1.74 L40_ 2.52 ■■_ _Jj60 _0 0 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes growing season (D) when weather .was warmer (tubers con - sequently more elongated) produced sprouts earlier, espe - cially early in the fall, but they produced less total growth and fewer stems than did the tubers produced late in the seas - on (R). In this instance the age of the parent plants and the storage periods were about the same. When a similar comparison is made with the tubers from the August 2 cut - vine set (H) , the late-planted stock (R) is found to have been ahead (Chart 1). Early production and field storage were not equal to late production and cold storage. Effect of storage temperature on tuber dormancy. — In 1928, lots of seed from May-planted tubers, harvested at different dates, were stored in a potato cellar (58° to 45° F.) at harvest time for the purpose of comparison with cold - storage stock (42° F.). On each of the first three monthly planting dates, samples were removed for testing. . | I I |i| I I I' I I I I |z[- 1 I I I N LW^ S on &gt;5 tam "&gt; dec. n 7 .&amp; K. M &amp;_ 1_L i T ir Ju - * _,. ; )A — 4-4 i ; \/r» : r t ? iv a &gt;n o | I VA. y \s\ I l^^gT y I I r H\ I I I 10 ZO SO 40 10 XO .40 40 10 ZO SO 40 /JUMBE1J OF DAYS AFTEP PLAyOTlAjQ \/l) GQEEAlHOUSE Chart 4. — Curves showing sprout emergence rate from cellar-stored potatoe.s of several lots of seed when planted in October, Novem - ber, and December, both with (E) and without (X) ethylene chlor - hydrin seed treatment. Seed stock from May 10 plantings (Lot S harvested August 2 and Lot U harvested Oct. 2, 1928) can be compared with Lots D and G of Chart 1. The higher storage temperature delayed the sprouting of early-harvested lots. The cellar-stored lots (S) harvested August 2nd had sprouted more slowly in October and Novem - ber than the cold-storage lots (D) (Table 4 and Chart 4). By mid-December the sprouting of both lots was about the same. Possibly the delay in the early-harvested, warm-stored lots was due to a period of induced and deeper dormancy from which emergence was slow and- gradual (White, 9, and Denny, 2). </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 The lot harvested October 2 (U) grew much more promptly when stored in the cellar than when placed in cold storage (G). In fact the cellar-stored potatoes of this lot grew at about the same rate as, or more promptly than, did the early - harvested, cold-storage lots. The different behavior of this lot of seed may have been due to a greater degree of dor - mancy at harvesting time, rendering it less susceptible to fac - tors which may have caused a period of induced dormancy in the other (early-harvested) stocks. Potatoes harvested on September 5 performed almost identically like those harvested August 2. (On September 5 early plantings were maturing rapidly.) Another set of tests was conducted with potatoes planted on June 5, 1928. With these potatoes the cellar-stored tubers sprouted more promptly on each date than the cold-storage tubers. The amount of seed-piece rotting was very much greater with all cellar-stored seed planted in October than with cold - storage seed. With potatoes grown at North Platte and planted in April and harvested at intervals from July 20 to September 1, the tubers of the warm-room storage grew more promptly on each fall planting date than did the cellar-stored tubers. The higher storage temperature generally caused more prompt growth during the early-storage months. It also frequently caused an increase in the number of stems per seed piece, but, as has been shown, under some conditions high storage temperature retarded the prompt growth of some lots of seed. RESULTS FROM MISCELLANEOUS EXPERIMENTS Methods of terminating the dormant period. — Several methods of inducing growth in dormant tubers were tested on potatoes which had been grown by planting on different dates on dry land at Alliance in 1927. These tests were con - ducted at different dates from October 10 to February 16. The methods tested were the following : A. Standard 5 per cent ethylene chlorhydrin dipping, method with cut seed. B. Dipping cut seed for one hour in a 5 per cent solution of sodium thiocyanate. C. Soaking cut seed in water for one hour immediately after cutting (as a proper check on B). D. Periderm removed around all the eyes of all seed pieces. E. Check; — planted at once after cutting without any treatment. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">The Dormancy op Triumph Potatoes I i I i 1 1 1 — ~~i 1 1 — «« __ MATURE STOCK FROM MAY 14,1927 FIELD PLANTING £»c MMAT &lt;- &lt;£ SEED STOC &lt; FPOM JUtV 1. 19X7 FtELti PLAdllAlr. I ' I I / o «o — 1 — : ,^ &gt; j &gt;y= 5 - I .?&amp; J &gt;-^f% r -'4 f^faj 1^^"' /y Chart 5. — Sprout emergence curves for mature and immature potatoes (from May 14 and July 1, 1927, field plantings) when cut seed was treated before planting as indicated. Planting dates for tests were: 1, October 10; 2, November 8; 3, December 7; 4, February 16. The experimental unit consisted of 50 seed pieces from each lot for each treatment. Data for May and July seed stocks as tested on four dates are graphically shown by sprout emergence curves in Chart 5. The seed lot given the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment (A) grew most promptly and vigorously with the greatest num - ber of stems per seed piece (Chart 1). The response to sodium thiocyanate (B) was somewhat less prompt and less complete. Soaking the seed pieces in water for one hour (C) generally delayed emergence, the growth rate being slower than for tho checks. This method seemed to hasten suberiza - tion of the cut surface, thus, shutting off the oxygen supply and thereby preventing growth or even bringing about a period of induced dormancy. The percentage of seed pieces rotting was higher by this method than by any other. Remov - ing the periderm (D) caused somewhat earlier growth than in the check (E) but the response was much slower than with the chemical treatments. If there was any difference the scraping method was less effective in the early part of the storage period (October 10) than later in the winter when tubers were more mature. The response of both mature and immature potatoes to these treatments was very similar (Chart 5 and Figure 3). The principal difference was the relatively greater effective - ness of the chemical treatments with immature tubers, in con - trast with the other methods, throughout the entire testing period, but especially so early in the period (October). </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Table 5.— Effectiveness of ethylene chlorkydrin treatment oil suberized seed: pieces * treatment- Check Treated _Check_ JYeated_ Check Treated Check Treated Check- Treated f, Atone 6 - 96.7 100.0 29.3 23.0 1.21 170 131 2 qi n n — W 3 hours 86.7 100.0 28.7 26.3 119 I43 142 o'm ■«? n « 9 h °u^ 93.3 100.0 26.4 23.3 18 177 121 I'fi? «7 n H tat wm tc^TnaTed If the 2 cndT4j!da r y r ilU " d a " d thC ° heCk8 """ h ° W '" B ' r Und ° r 9ttmC " !m P&lt;'™t«re conditions during the treating interval. The £ ■ . ■ • . . a ■;■,.■;, . „ v - ; ■; . ■ 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes The ethylene chlorhydrin treatment was considered the most effective method and consequently \yas adopted for later tests. Effectiveness of the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment on suberized seed pieces when used at intervals after cutting the seed potatoes. — Triumph seed potatoes were cut at various intervals of time ahead of planting, or of treating with ethylene chlorhydrin, so as to determine the effect of the healing or suberization processes on sprout growth. Fifty seed pieces were used from each lot for each treat- ___ ment. This test was con - "1 1 I ' Jt^^] ducted in November, 1928, jr /"'/&amp;■ with tubers that would not | / //y ■/ have sprouted completely / h / until January. When planted / •■-■ /tf within 33 hours after cut - g / jl /jf ting, sprout growth was not t*°~ ~~f ii~TJ\ delayed, but when this was A jl )"*. increased to 48 hours or I *'/ il ' more the emergence of g ** ■ ~S/#F — 'gist sprouts from check-lot seed o &amp;y&amp; g/j i pieces was materially de - */r &gt;&lt;/// layed (Table 5. Chart 6, and ° l i i Figure 4). When treated r . . A *»~&lt;»'«™*"«i»«*nN 11 with the et ji y]ene c hlorhy - "^owinT^erctforfn 611^^! Jin the effectiveness of tL ness of ethylene. chlorhydrin treatment was apparently treatment applied after cutting not decreased until seed at the stated periods. The curves treating was delayed beyond show the percentage of seed r&gt;A !,_„_,, ; _ +„ ao !,_„__ Pieces that produced sprouts by 2 i hours— -i.e., to 48 hours a given number of days after alter cutting the seed, lhe planting. effectiveness was further re - duced as the treatment was delayed to four and six days respectively ; however, even then the average emergence date was advanced ahead of that of the untreated check. Influence of soil in which seed pieces are planted. — In early November, 1928, cut seed pieces, both treated and un - treated, were planted in the various synthetic soils described in Table 6. As the moisture-holding capacity of a soil increased, dor - mant seed potatoes sprouted more promptly. When seed pieces were treated with ethylene chlorhydrin the same order applied in a general way, there having been some slight shift - ing which can be accounted for partly by error due to the </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 . . ■ ' : .' .'•-. ■ ■' ■ - ■ ■ •: Figrure 4. — Sprout growth 30 days after planting from seed pieces treated with ethylene chlorhydrin at specified intervals after cutting. Lot Jl was treated immediately after cutting, while J2, J3, and J4 were treated 3, 9, and 24 hours respectively after cutting and J5, J6, and J7 were treated 2, 4, and 6 days after cutting. Thirty seed pieces were used in each test. The treated lot is to the left (marked E) in each flat while the untreated check cut at the same time but not treated is to the right. small number of pieces. The sprout growth was most prompt from the lots planted in the 100 per cent compost soil, fol - lowed by the 67 per cent compost, the sphagnum moss, the garden soil, the 33 per cent compost, and then the pure sand and wood shavings lots, the slowest of this series (Figure 5 and Table 6). The use of pure garden soil (silt) without composting re - sulted in slow growth, probably because of the reduced aera - tion and greater physical resistance. Sawdust and wood shavings Avere less satisfactory than the composted soil. Sphagnum moss was a very satisfactory medium. The medium in which seed pieces are planted is an import - ant factor in speed of growth of untreated seed pieces, but. it apparently is of less significance when the ethylene chlor- 1 " hydrm treatment is used. Ethylene-chlorhydrin-treated pieces planted in a medium such as sand respond more slowly to growing conditions than do untreated pieces planted in composted soil or sphagnum moss. Relation of size of seed piece to sprout growth of dor - mant potatoes. — Pieces weighing 15, 30, and 60 grains (100 pieces of each) were cut from a uniform lot of tubers, and half the pieces of each size were treated with ethylene chlor - hydrm on October 31, 1929, to determine the effect of the treatment on seed pieces of different sizes. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 ■t-3 TABLE 6. — Growth response of seed pieces planted in various types of soil — 30 seed pieces in each a : treatment - ■ g " . . — o Percentage of Av. number of Mean number of Mean number of Percentage of g ■ . seed pieces days for sprout sprouting eyes sprouts per seed seed pieces &gt; producing sprouts emergence per seed piece ' piece rotting z * PG ° ' 01 Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated Check Treated : : : : — : — o Garden soil 93.4 66.7 26.3 25.7 1.14 1.50 1.29 2.00 6.7 33.3 " 100 per cent compost 76.7 80.0 22.7 19.6 1.26 1.42 1.35 2.08 23.3 20.0 H 67 Pe^ n san C d OraPOStl . 33Per 100.0 96.7 23.9 21.7 1.03 1.65 1.07 2.75 .0 3.3 5 33P C r en^d OmPOStl . 67Per 100.0 86.7 26.5 26.5 1.07 1.34 1.17 1.96 0 13.3 . g 100 per cent sand 86.7' 100.0 33.8 25.4 1.04 1.40 1.12 1.93 0 .0 « Sawdust .. 100.0 100.0 28.5 25.7 1.13 1.60 1.13 1.83 0 0^ Sphagnum moss. . 96.7' 100.0 24.7 23.2 1.04 1.63 1.14 2.63 0 0 o Wood shavings 100.0 96.7' 34.7 27.2 1.10 1.40 1.10 2.04 0 0 £ ■At end of 44 days 13 .3 per cent of seed pieces were still dormant. g 'At end of 44 days 3.3 per cent of seed pieces were still dormant. W </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 \ ' ■ . - . ■ ■ river ««i. lr Per Cent con ?P ost . 6 ? Per cent sand; E5, pure fln^ro J thG i °i eCks th . e sma11 seed P ieces rew m °st promptly and produced the most sprout growth withip 42 days (Table Ireat^T^l % e reSponse was prompt and was doubrlhS 6 f a tf St PleC f S ' a , nd the weieht of the s P rou ts was double that of the sprouts of the smallest pieces rhe i prompt growth of the small untreated seed pieces was PiS&amp;Sth? 6 *t the f fact «»* their W were fn cfo" limty to the cut surfaces than were those of large pieces The larger cut surface of the large seed pieces and the resultant 2T£ ™ f g f tOta - SUrfaCe ga?e more 5&gt;Porti3S ?or Thtn?,f P o ? rat M h ! Se Pleces and t0 activate the tissues. The cut surfaces that were some distance from the periderm did not subenze as rapidly as those close to the periderm Table 7.— Effect of seed-piece size on sprout growth, token all pieces were cut from tubers of the same size Weight Mean number per »eod piece Total weight ot Mean number of seed Sn Pn .,-. .7. sprouts per seed of days for Pieces Sprouting eyes- P-ece (gram,) emergence' (grams) . !L_ ._ Check Treated' Check 15 1 -° M 10 Li «2.4 ill iiJ~ 30 H 2 "° 10 2-i 20.0 44 A 30.5 60 1&gt;4 2 - 7 ' lf) 2.6 18 j ,8.8 37 ., but a a b l ofeT; o n uVd y;7w " re C — dl 'Ethylene chlorhydrin treatment. '•..'" 27.7 18.8 21.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes Apparently the effectiveness of the ethylene chlorhydrin treatment increases as the size of the seed piece increases up to a certain size but not greatly beyond that size. Position of the eyes on the tuber as a factor affecting growth response in dormant potatoes. — In view of the fact that in tubers that are apically dominant the apical eyes sprout most promptly, it was thought desirable to determine whether the response of apical and basal eyes of dormant tubers to ethylene chlorhydrin differs. For this purpose small seed pieces in the shape of triangular pyramids were cut nut of both the apical and basal ends of medium-sized Triumph tubers. One hundred seed pieces of each type were secured, and half of each were treated with ethylene chlor - hydrin on October 31, 1929. All were planted on November 1 and grown in the greenhouse for 41 days. The 50 pieces Of each lot Avere distributed into six flats with an equal num - ber of apicaland basal end pieces in separate rows in each flat. The mean weight of the 100 pieces of each type were as follows : apical, 13.9, and basal, 14.3 grams. The plants from the apical pieces emerged practically five days earlier than those from the basal pieces (Table 8). The percentage of pieces producing sprouts by the end of 41 days 'was higher from the apical pieces. There was little dif - ference in the number of sprouting eyes or sprouts per seed piece. When treated with ethylene chlorhydrin the growth of both apical and basal pieces was accelerated according to the data depicted in the sprout-emergence curve (not published) ex - cept that the apical pieces responded more slowly than the basal pieces, as indicated both by the mean emergence date and sprout-emergence curves. Table 8. — Sprouting record of apical and basal seed pieces cut from the same seed tubers . 1 Percentage Average . Mean location of Mean of seed number of Mean Percentage weight of »*d pkk-,. weight of pieces days for number of of seed top. from in parent seed pieces producing sprout sprouts per pieces over each seed tuDer (grams) sprouts emergence seed piece X rotten piece ■ ■ (grama) UNTREATED CHECK Apical pieces I 13.9 74 24.4 1.00 66 19.3 Hasal pieces | 14.3 52 29.2 1.00 66 18 0 TREATED WITH ETHYLENE CHLORHYDRIN Apical pieces ... .'I 13.9 98 19.9 1.53 58 28.3 Basal pieces ... I 14 A 92 13.1 1.48 50 34.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 57 Apparently apical seed pieces of dormant tubers sprouted more promptly than basal pieces when not treated but less so when treated with ethylene chlorhydrin. Sprout growth of irrigated and dry-land seed potatoes. — Dry-land and irrigated seed potatoes of the same line were planted on November 15 and also December 1, 1929, to deter - mine whether culture caused any difference in dormancy of the tubers. The dry-land lot was in this instance probably the least mature, the irrigated plants having been more severely Table 9. — Sprout growth of irrigated and dry-land-grown seed potatoes tested on ttvo dates in the fall of 1929 I ■ Average number Mean number Mean number Portion days to emergence of sprouting eyes of sprouts per Culture of seed date when planted per seed piece seed piece pieces — ' ■ — — — — - Nov. 15 Dec. 1 ] Nov. 15 Dec. 1 Nov. 15 | - Dec. I Irrigated Apical 22.3 30.7 1.2 1.9 1.3 i 2.0 Basal 23.8 33.4 1.2 1.8 1.2 l.S Mean 23.1 32.1 ... " ... Dryland Apical 24.7 I 29.6 1.1 1.3 1.1 l.S Basal 26.1 32.5 1.1 1.9 1.1 1.5 Mean 25.4 32.1 ... damaged by an early September frost. The apical and basal end pieces were planted separately. Fifty pieces of each were used. The irrigated stock emerged somewhat more promptly when planted November 15, but later when planted December 1 (Table 9). The difference was not very great] in either in - stance. The irrigated stock apparently was capable of pro - ducing more sprouts per seed piece than the dry-land stock. The apical pieces sprouted more quickly than did the basal pieces. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">The Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes literature cited 1. Appleman, CO. 1U14. Study of the Rest Period in Potato Tubers. Maryland Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 183, pp. 181-226. '2. Denny, F. E. " " ' 1926; Hastening the Sprouting of Dormant Potato Tubers. Amer - ican Jour, of Botany, 13:118-125. ' ;j_ l!'2T. Experiments on the Use of Chemicals in Hastening the Sprouting of Potato Tubers. Rpt. Dept. of Agr. of Bermuda, . pp. 57-67. ■ . 1928. The Importance of Temperature in the Use of Chemicals for Hastening the Sprouting of Dormant Potato Tubers. Am. Jour, of Botany, 15:395-409. 5. Lnomis, \V. E. 1927. Temperature and Other Factors Affecting the Rest Period of Potato Tubers. Plant Physiology, 2:287-302. 6. McCallan, E. A. 1H27. Report of Potato Work in 1927. Leaflet No. 11, Bermuda Dept. of Agriculture. 7. Rosa, J. T. 1928. Relation of. Tuber Maturity and of Storage Factors to Potato Dormancy. Hilgardia, 3:99-142. S. Smith, Ora 1929. Effect of Various Treatments on the Carbon Dioxide and Oxygen in Dormant Potato Tubers. Hilgardia, 4:273-306. it.- White, R. P. • 11)28. Potato Experiments for the Control of Rhizoctonia, Scab, and Blackleg, 1922-1927. Kansas Agr. Exp. Sta. Tech. Bui 24. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>