<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00083.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0083.0006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT</title>
               <date value="1938-07-01">1938-07-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">F. M. Davis 1877-1880 A. G. Kendall 1881-1884 Joseph Scott 1885-1888 John Steen „ 1889-1890 A. R. Humphrey 1891-1894 H. C. Russell 1895-1896 J. V. Wolfe.. r ...1897-1900 George Follmer 1901-1904 H. M. Eaton 1905-1908- E. B. Cowles 1909-1912 Fred Beckman 1913-1916 G. L. Shumway 1917-1918 Dan Swanson 1919-1932 Harry P. Conklin 1933-1934 Leo N. Swanson 1935- COMMISSIONERS OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS OF NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT PERSONNEL OFFICE OF COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Leo N. Swanson Commissioner C. R. Hough , Deputy H. B. Lawson State Surveyor Edith Peterson Abstractor G. B. Thomas _ Bookkeeper Verna Donelson Secretary Wilma Bauman ; Stenographer Department of Surveying Hugh Dillon ; .....Deputy Russell O. Adams _ Deputy Willis K. Brown Deputy Russell M. Erickson Deputy Percy Bell Deputy T. C. Dougherty , Deputy Jack Gavenman Deputy H. W. Strohm ...Deputy Custodianship Nebraska State Capitol Building and Grounds Tom Riggs Assistant Custodian James Pine Steam Fitter H. P. Mitchell Electrician J. C. Anthony. Terrace Supervisor Manuel Kahler Foreman of Grounds Janitorial Duties Eighteen Employees Scrubber Two Employees Elevator Operator Two Employees Guides Two Employees Carpenter One Employee Doorman One Employee Night Watchman One Employee Day Watchman : One Employee Waxers - : Two Employees Helper One Employee Lawn Four during summer months; one during winter months </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Lincoln, Nebraska, July 1, 1938. To His Excellency, Roy L. Cochran, Governor: Sir: In compliance with the constitutional requirement, I have the honor to submit the following report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, who is also the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, for the biennium beginning July 1, 1936 and ending June 30, 1938. Under the present law the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ings is the Custodian of the Nebraska State Capitol Building and of the Capitol and Governor's Mansion grounds. During the past two years this task has been a very difficult one in the matter of the collection of revenue on state owned lands. In the greater number of these counties the productive value of these lands has been very low due to crop failures. The permanent and the temporary school fund has suffered tre - menduous losses down through the years through investments of the permanent school funds and through loss of uncollected rentals. Ne - braska is an agricultural state, and it should invest permanent school funds in farm mortgages as well as Municipal Bonds at a certain per cent of interest and mortgages be amortized to pay out in ten to twenty years. At one time this permanent school fund lost through the Whitney Irrigation District $39,024.00. At the time of the purchase of these bonds the community and the tax payers 'were in excellent financial conditions. All losses incurred through bad investments should be re - imbursed by the Legislature to the permanent school fund. The temporary school fund with all of its drawbacks has made admirable gains, and with a few changes in the laws income to schools could be increased. I believe the following laws should be passed: (1) A law to make leases to run five years only. (2) A law to have leases paid on January first of each year; if not paid, advertised and sold; thereby no delinquent lessees. (3) A law to compel Board of Educational Lands and Funds to classify and reappraise all school lands and to keep close check on same. (4) A law to deal with extensions of time on all Sales Contracts whereby 10% of principal be paid and balance amortized in ten years. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Land reported lost in the Missouri River has been found in the State of South Dakota, and it has been leased for a twenty-five year contract. This land has been out of production to the State of Nebraska since 1885. The total acreage is 377.40 plus accreation at an annual rental of $250.00. r Nebraska has 48,075 acres under prospectors' leases for oil and gas at ten cents per acre. This in itself brings a substantial income into the temporary school fund. Mineral leasing should be encouraged as Ne - braska has many places where drilling has been done and traces of oil or gas have been found. As Custodian of the Capitol I am proud to turn over to his Excel - lency, the Governor, a building free of debt and taxes. With a WPA project to -wash all walls, ceilings, and corridors, also cleaning of all furniture, I feel that after this. is completed an appropriation should be made to paint many of the rooms and all of the ceilings as the ceilings have only been calcimined. I am also pleased to report that since taking over the custodianship I have been able to cut the heat rate from 52tf per thousand pounds of steam to 40tf per thousand. The electricity rate has also been reduced from two cents per kilowatt to one and a half cents in summer and one and one-third cents in winter. This, I believe, should also be reduced or changed to the University from the Penitentiary • at a rate of one cent per kilowatt. Floodlighting the Capitol Building has been a problem and a pleasure. Floodlighting a shaft is very much different than lighting a dome, and experiments were made for several months until the present system was installed. More lighting should be installed if the Legislature sees fit to appropriate the money. During the past several years people were permitted to sleep on the Capitol lawn during the hot summer nights, thereby damaging the grass. This, however, has been stopped. Nebraska is the only state that actually houses all its own state activities in the 'State Capitol Building. However, the population has increased considerably during the past four years but we are still able to operate on our same budget. We have employees working in the building from basement to attic. I believe that at this time it would be well to finish the Historical Building across the street to the southeast, thereby allowing the state departments about 230,000 square feet of additional space for which there is a great need. Yours respectfully, LEO N. SWANSON, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT STATE OWNED LANDS OR SCHOOL LAND AND ITS ORIGIN At the close of the Revolutionary War, the United States came into possession of a vast area of land reaching from the Alleghenies to the Mississippi River, known as the Northwest Territory. When Virginia was admitted to the Union, she asked to have land in the Northwest Territory set aside to be used to help support schools. The land was surveyed and platted into townships six miles square and containing thirty-six sections. Section sixteen in every township was reserved for the maintenance of public schools. Other states as admitted to the Union were given the same consideration. The same grant was made to the original thirteen states. When California was admitted to the Union in 1850, sections sixteen and thirty-six of each township were allotted for school purposes and extended to all states. The Enabling Act which admitted Nebraska to the Union was passed by Congress on April 19, 1864. Sections sixteen and thirty-six in every township were granted to the state for the sup - port of common schools. The first statute relative to the control of a school land provided that the Sate Auditor shall be made Commissioner and have general charge of the administration of these lands. This statute was passed in 1867. In each county the lands were to be ap - praised by three persons and offered for sale to the public. No lands were to be sold for less than $5.00 per acre. Following this statute, the new constitution of the State of Ne - braska adopted by the vote of the people in 1875 created the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. From this time on the Commissioner was elected by the people. The constitution also created a Board of Educational Lands and Funds composed of five constitutional officers : 1. Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. 2. Governor. 3. Secretary of State. 4. State Treasurer. 5. Attorney General. The Board's duties were to care for the leasing and sale of lands as well as having general management of all funds. The Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings was to serve as secretary and have full management, and he was to report to the Board. C. R. HOUGH, Deputy. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Rules and Regulations Pertaining to the Leasing and Sale of Educational Lands LEASE CONTRACTS The Board of Educational Lands and Funds may at least once each year designate a day and an hour for offering in a public manner, at the office of the county treasurer in the respective counties, lease con - tracts on all of the educational lands which may be subject to lease in that county at the time of such offering. The same shall be subject to lease at an annual rental of six (6) per cent upon the appraised value thereof. Provided, if two or more parties desire to lease the same land, the officer having control of the auction shall lease to the person who will pay the greater amount of cash bonus in addition to six (6) per cent upon the appraised value as annual rental. If after due diligence to lease the land at an annual rental .of six per cent upon the appraised valuation, the land may be offered for lease at less than the appraised valuation and the board may lease it to the person or persons who will pay six per cent upon the highest offered valuation as annual rental if, in their judgment, it is to the best interest to the State to accept such bid, but they may reject the same and pass said land without leasing at said auction. Lease rentals are due in two installments, January 1st and July 1st of each year. If rentals are not paid within six months aftsr due, the lease holders are declared delinquent and notice is sent them if their post office addresses are known. If unknown, notice is given by publi - cation in a local newspaper. Ninety days after date of such notice lease contracts are declared forfeited and are subject to auction thereafter. (See Fees.) Delinquent lease holders are not permitted to bid at the sale of the leases they have forfeited, but at any time before the hour advertised for the commencement of such sale they may reinstate their leases by paying all back rentals, fees and cost of advertising. (See Fees.) All school lands under lease are subject to reappraisement at any time the Board of Educational Lands and Funds so elects. AH leases expire twenty-five years from the first day of January next ensuing after the date of the lease. A lessee has the right at the expiration of his lease to apply to the county treasurer for a new lease and receive the same without compe - tition, at the same time surrendering the old lease, paying rentals six months in advance, and a lease fee of one dollar. This will do away with the public auction only in cases where the former lessee does not apply for new lease. In such cases the lands will be advertised and leased at public auction to the highest bidder, and all improvements on the land appraised by the county board. Improvements to be included in such appraisements shall be all buildings, fencing, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT wells, windmills, pumps, tanks, irrigation improvements, and also costs for labor expended in breaking sod on said tract of land and reducing same to cultivation, and for alfalfa or other crops growing upon said land. The appraisement shall be made within thirty (30) days after the acceptance of the bid. (See Sec. 72-218, Session Laws Nebraska, 1935.) Where lands are forfeited on account of non-payment of rentals, the movable improvements are sold under the direction of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds as provided by Sec. 72-219, Nebraska Session Laws, 1935. The amount of school land authorized to be leased, direct or by renewal, to one person is limited to 640 acres. EDUCATIONAL LANDS MAY BE PURCHASED FROM THE STATE AS FOLLOWS: Lands known as isolated tracts, lands situated in the irrigation districts, and lands for the use of churches, cemeteries, schoolhouse sites, county agricultural fairs, public roads, and for sewage disposal purposes. Any lessee of land situated within the areas irrigated, or to be irrigated, from irrigation works constructed or controlled, or to be constructed or controlled by the United States, or its duly authorized agencies, or any lessee of any forty-acre tract or government sub - division, any part of which is under irrigation, may purchase the same. (See Sec. 72-211, Nebraska Session Laws, 1935.) The law also provides that if any forty (40) acre tract is adjacent to other school land which is wholly or partly under irrigation, and therefore subject to sale, such tract may be sold even though not under irrigation if, in the opinion of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds it is expedient to sell the same. Any irrigation district in which there are or may be any educational lands belonging to the state which are or may hereafter become sites for reservoir purposes may purchase from the state for reservoir sites such educational lands, or portions thereof. (See Sec. 72-211, Nebraska Session Laws, 1935.) The law provides that the Board of Educational Lands and Funds shall make a list of all isolated tracts of school lands containing less than forty (40) acres, all undivided interests in realty, and all city lots held by the state of Nebraska in trust for the permanent school fund, appraise same, and, upon the expiration of the leases or upon forfeiture of lease titles, offer the same for sale at public auction, to be sold by the county treasurer of the county in which the lands are located to the highest bidder for not less than ninety (90) per cent of the ap - praised value. The purchaser shall pay not less than twenty-five (25) per cent in cash on day of sale and the balance to be secured by sale contract running ten years at six (6) per cent annual interest, the purchaser having the right to pay all of the unpaid money, or any part </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT of it, in multiples of five (5) per cent of the total purchase price at any interest payment date. In the event the purchaser, or the assignee, does not pay the annual interest upon the unpaid purchase price within six (6) months after interest becomes due, the land shall revert to the state. SALE CONTRACTS The owner of a sale contract may at any time pay any portion of the purchase price thereof to the treasurer of the county in which the land is situated; provided, all interest at that time earned and due has first been paid. And when the principal is paid in full other than the first of the year, interest upon the obligation having been paid for the entire year, the county treasurer receiving such principal payment may refund to the payor out of any interest money then in his hands the interest so paid in advance in excess of the amount earned and due at the time said final payment is made. Refund receipts are furnished by the land commissioner for this purpose. All unpaid principal on sale contracts, excepting those covering isolated tracts and lots as heretofore described, draws interest at five (5) per cent per annum, payable annually on January first of each year in advance. A sale contract holder making final payment to the county treasurer should also surrender his contract that it may be forwarded to the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds with receipt showing full payment. NOTES No assignment of a school land lease or sale contract is valid until recorded in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ings, and an assignment will not be recorded if any interest or rental is due at the time it is offered for record. The original sale or lease con - tract must be sent in with the assignment or the latter will not be recorded. Contracts will be returned with recorded assignments. When a subdivision of not less than forty acres in any contract is assigned, a new number is given, the assigned portion of the ledger account and a certified copy of the original is given to the assignee. When assignment is made as above, the original contract must be re - duced and the interest or rentals, as the case may be, is adjusted to the new conditions. Whenever a lease or sale contract becomes lost or destroyed, a certified copy of the same may be procured by filing an affidavit of lost contract. Such copy may be used in lieu of the original for the purpose of passing title. When interest on a sale contract, or rental on a lease contract, is not paid when due, the county treasurers will collect "penalty" interest </seg>
            <seg id="p009">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT at seven (7) per cent for the time purchaser or lessee has been tardy in making such payments. Improvements on leased land and the owner's equity in land under sale contract are subject to taxation. County treasurers are requested to send in school land receipts at least once each wesk. Sometimes tardiness in this particular leads to considerable unnecessary correspondence and occasionally to delinquen - cies being charged against contract holders who are not in arrears, but whose receipts have not been sent to the land commissioner's office. Lands escheating to the state under the alien act are appraised and leased in the same manner as educational lands. FEES For the issuance of a lease or sale contract $1.00 For recording assignments, for each contract assigned 1.00 For recording affidavit of lost contract 1.00 For certified copy of a contract 2.00 For recording any instrument, for each 100 words 10 For notice of delinquency of lease or sale contract 1.00 For reinstatement j qq For recording order of forfeiture, where redemption is made before auction, for each contract # 50 Where publication in newspaper is required in lieu of ordinary de - linquent notice, the actual cost of such publication is charged where redemption is made. For copies of maps or plats, each hour's work 40 Note: Fees payable to the state should be remitted by draft or money order payable to the state treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT WORK OP BIENNIUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1938 Lease Int. on Bonus and Prin. pd. on County Rentals Sale Conts. Penalty Int. Sale Conts. Total Adams $1,979.40 $173.60 $66.98 $2,491.00 $4,710.98 Antelope 14,498.98 584.60 630.03 156.00 15,869.61 (Uni.) . 240.00 .49 240.49 Arthur 4,503.60 73.83 4,577.43 Banner 10,127.35 198.58 10,325.93 Blaine 4,371.65 413.26 117.69 700.00 5,602.60 Boone 2,454.73 1,264.50 144.75 950.00 4,813.98 Box Butte .... 14,861.96 135.00 469.60 15,466.56 Boyd 11,033.01 3,721.51 627.34 304.00 15,685.86 Brown 10,889.07 125.20 380.96 11,295.23 Mineral .... 245.51 245 51 Buffalo 11,063.91 328.17 11,392.08 Burt 318.84 326.41 313.94 1,110.00 2,069.19 Butler 949.40 19.55 968.95 Cass 456.00 36.23 41.25 533.48 Cedar 950.44 29.43 .. 979.87 (Agr.) . — 2,858.83 288.00 33.13 3,179.96 (Uni.) 473.60 473.60 Chase 23,488.89 500.00 579.88 24,568.77 Cherry 63,839.80 3,559.10 1,628.00 6,795.00 75,821.90 Mineral .... 116.00 116 00 Cheyenne 40,379.43 1,238.69 41,618.12 Clay 566.56 126.80 18.92 200.00 912.28 Colfax 70.36 74.60 2.13 200.00 347.09 Cuming 301.83 301.83 Custer 35,677.29 8,167.31 1,591.87 2,197.38 47,633.85 Mineral .... 104.00 104.00 Dakota ..-. 2,299.85 34.42 162.43 38.25 2,534.95 Dawes -&lt; 13,066.72 1,733.52 459.89 160.00 15.420.13 Mineral .... 804.00 804.00 Dawson 9,109.59 4,582.65 241.54 1,728.00 15,661.78 Deuel 13,540.85 331.71 13,872.56 Dixon 1,896.56 622.95 123.06 256.20 2,898.77 (Agr.) 108.00 1.66 109.66 Dodge 65.26 65.26 Douglas 220.00 212.20 15.75 1,610.00 2,057.95 Dundy 18,742.83 450.03 19,192.86 Mineral .... 224.00 , 224.00 Fillmore 1.50 . 1 50 Franklin 6,091.07 815.70 344.07 7,250.84 Mineral .... 396.00 * 396 00 Frontier 18,374.58 3,849.86 1,023.22 23,247.66 Mineral .... 176.00 176.00 Furnas 14,388.66 3,341.60 1,030.18 1,008.00 19,768.44 Gage 1,098.00 4.42 1,102.42 Garden 21,969.66 2,018.02 574.42 12,024.00 36,586.10 Garfield 5,380.22 185.40 162.16 5,727.78 Gosper 3,828.53 100.00 90.75 4,019.28 Grant 4,450.28 866.60 61.72 5,378.60 Mineral .... 272.00 272.00 Greeley 3,921.60 168.50 136.85 1,508.00 5.734.95 Hall 4,623.67 151.06 172.49 4,947.22 Hamilton 7.26 6.00 13.26 Harlan 7,103.57 1,489.02 578.28 206.00 9,376.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT WORK OF BIENNIUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1938 Lease Int. on Bonus and Prin. pd. on County Rentals Sale Conts. Penalty Int. Sale Conts. Total Hayes 15,288.70 312.11 446.66 2,156.53 18,204.00 Mineral .... 320.00 . 320 00 Hitchcock .... 18,455.60 530.19 18 985.79 Mineral .... 1,494.42 1 494 42 Holt 22,452.07 2,477.92 767.72 9,030.50 34,728!21 (Uni.) 2,279.94 909.50 83.17 3,272.61 Hooker 4,129.54 97.22 110.72 4,337.48 Howard 4,417.37 679.61 299.40 600.00 5,996.38 Jefferson 2,550.35 1,206.00 102.81 219.60 4,078.76 Mineral .... 605.00 605.00 Johnson 1,132.42 15.00 . 1,147 42 Kearney 3,451.32 51.59 3,502.91 Keith 16,030.20 1,076.49 435.04 3,087.16 20,628.89 Mineral .... 467.30 467.30 Keya Paha .. 9,006.54 411.90 339.21 9,757.65 Kimball 22,894.43 144.00 1,070.42 24,108.85 Knox 11,667.01 2,996.45 762.05 15,425.51 (Uni.) 845.58 750.00 27.59 1623.17 (Agr.) 2,470.02 2,232.90 211.14 4,914.06 Lancaster .... 3,321.00 633.54 144.70 401.46 4,500.70 Saline 1,902.30 1,379.70 147.29 1,830.33 5,259.62 Normal .... 336.00 336 00 Lincoln 22,164.45 7,021.15 622.45 2,872.80 32,680.85 Mineral .... 2,350.87 2 350.87 Logan 4,869.00 1,736.29 230.06 1,728.00 8,563.35 Loup 4,275.08 161.69 4 436.77 Mineral .... 64.00 64.00 Madison 2,626.02 80.88 . . 2,706 90 (Uni.) 265.80 300.00 4.70 570.50 McPherson .. 5,018.10 129.60 190.64 5,338.34 Mineral .... 576.00 576.00 Merrick 5,720.69 188.10 201.90 330.45 6 441.14 Morrill 17,276.67 6,191.08 714.46 3,487.60 27,669.81 Mineral .... 84.00 84.00 Nance Nemaha 999.96 35.45 l,035"41 Nuckolls 1,272.60 489.60 3.29 1,765.49 (Uni.) 247.55 .95 248.50 Otoe 1,350.00 120.60 340.00 1,810.60 Pawnee 57.84 2.00 59.84 Perkins 21,354.73 288.00 588.76 .... 22,231.49 Phelps 3,151.20 1,173.60 274.61 4 599.41 Pierce 8,260.64 733.99 281.64 2,000.00 11,276.27 (Agr.) 826.16 7.73 833.89 Platte 1,272.20 52.31 1 324.51 Polk 1,540.12 126.00 76.86 75.00 1,817.98 Red Willow .. 12,261.24 4,188.55 1,071.52 1 220.00 18,741.31 Mineral .... 220.00 220.00 Richardson .... 720.35 855.80 88.99 1,665.14 Mineral .... 4.00 4.00 Rock 9,399.12 1,055.50 288.68 1 820.00 12 563.30 Saline 516.45 2.40 518.85 Sarpy 843.06 18.28 : 6 • .S4 Saunders 185.00 78.37 6.73 187.50 457.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT WORK OF BIENNIUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1938 Lease Int. on Bonus and Prln. pd. on County Rentals Sale Conts. Penalty Int. Sale Conts. Total Scotts Bluff .. 4,935.82 10,339.56 1,122.66 1,862.25 18,260.29 Mineral .... 132.00 132.00 Seward 266.70 266.70 Sheridan 28,803.07 1,612.70 759.70 3,132.00 34,307.47 Mineral .... 128.00 128.00 Sherman 7,413.02 580.46 328.60 300.00 8,622.08 Sioux 17,371.86 3,485.85 497.68 6,619.81 27,975.20 Mineral .... 2,143.75 2,143.75 Stanton 259.02 259.02 Thayer 1,590.05 891.00 41.60 252.00 2,774.65 Mineral .... 112.00 112.00 Thomas 1,956.65 159.04 2,115.69 Thurston Valley 2,476.41 615.60 78.67 3,170.68 Washington .. 6,660.56 490.93 113.42 153.62 7,418.53 Wayne Webster 398.58 858.80 55.46 168.00 1,480.84 (Uni.) 1,974.91 1,022.10 137.62 3,134.63 Wheeler 7,884.58 1,414.10 432.09 432.00 10,162.77 York 3,566.68 123.00 12.37 3,702.05 $772,277.61 $101,024.22 $28,783.01 $77,989.69 $980,074.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS July, 1936 to June 30, 1938 Total Acres Total Acres Appraised COUNTY Total Acres Total Acrc3 Under Sale Under Lease Value of Acquired Deeded Contract Contract Unclassified Leased Lands Adams 20,480.00 19,240.00 1,240.00 $ 23,510.00 Antelope 31,400.00 19 640.00 480.00 11,280.00 127,240.00 (Uni.) 1,600.00 1,400.00 200.00 2,000.00 tr" Arthur 25,720.00 25,720.00 37,160.00 &gt; Banner 26,880.00 961.40 25,918.60 79,640.00 g Blaine 25,530.45 240.00 800.00 24.490.45 35,883.90 ° Boone 23,675.28 19,998.76 880.00 2,796.52 18,860.76 O Box Butte 40,960.00 1 224.36 160.00 39,575.64 140,512.97 2 Boyd 22,655.72 7,199.21 2,503.47 12,953.04 92,066.84 S Brown 41558.90 556.40 80.00 40,922.50 86,495.84 5 Buffalo 30,813.29 22,042.09 8,771.20 96,179.03 j» Burt 17,487.88 17,047.18 80.00 120.70 240.00 2 819.46 g (Agr.) 640.00 640.00 2 Butler 21,699.63 21,179.63 520.00 12,683.33 S Cass 19,733.98 19,633.98 10.00 90.00 4,300.00 frj Cedar 26,964.36 26,285.36 679.00 15,088.00 w (Uni.) 1,920.00 1,600.00 320.00 6 374.00 w (Agr.) 25,405.47 24,391.63 40.00 973.84 24,167.05 g Chase 33,280.00 2,026.48 640.00 30,613.52 195,097.07 *0 Cherry 250,965.76 11,341.71 4,386.78 235,237.27 522,212.06 2 Cheyenne 43,840.00 853.00 42,987.00 292,106.81 h Clay 21,240.00 20,660.00 180.00 400.00 4,000.00 Colfax 14,453.64 14,358.26 30.23 65.15 1,172.70 Cuming 19,044.70 18,999.70 45.00 (Agr.).. 960.00 960.00 Custer. 92,179.31 28,255.94 8,796.06 55,127.31 302,410.30 Dakota 7,163.19 5,808.51 25.50 677.34 651.84 13,215.85 (Uni.) 320.00 320.00 (Agr.) 640.00 640.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS July, 1936 to June 30, 1938 _!__ Total Acres Total Acres Appraised COUNTY Total Acres Total Acres Under Sale Under Lease Value of . Acquired' Deeded Contract Contract Unclassified Leased Lands £ awes 49,280.00 1,212.43 1,140.00 46,927.57 107,601.92 Dawson 36.185.15 23,837.72 4,174.28 8,117.02 56.13 66,482.35 °? uel 16,800.70 1,908.20 14,892.50 114,618.61 r- D "f° n ;--- 16,025.02 14,802.80 274.40 893.82 54.00 17,847.75 &gt; (Uni.) 640.00 640.00 2 _ (Agr.) 2,240.00 2 200.00 40.00 1,800.00 ° godge 18,558.58 18,507.72 50.86 O Douglas 9,160.23 8,920.69 60.00 40.00 139.54 2,000.00 2 Dundy. 33 257.01 , 978.98 32,278.03 145,909.85 S £ lllm °re 20,648.51 20,608.51 40.00 S Franklin 20,471.85 12,666.49 879.00 6,926.36 96,945.55 gj Frontier 34 560.00 9,082.00 3,560.00 21,918.00 185 492.00 S £urnas 25,602.80 11,244.20 2,159.00 12,199.60 117,993.31 2 Gage 24,637.31 24 425.31 12.00 200.00 7,200.00 3 Garden 63,962.85 4,175.26 1,262.25 58,525.34 189,994.20 » Garfield 20 480.00 1,361.58 240.00 18,878.42 45,056.05 o3 Gosper 16,640.00 12,680.00 480.00 3,480.00 34,668.00 m Grant 30,872.82 3,796.30 911.46 26 069.78 95.28 36,987.22 § Greeley 20,475.30 13,235.30 440.00 6,800.00 40,359.13 * "all ■ 19 538.25 17,007.75 93.25 2,406.71 30.54 41,294.15 2 Hamilton 20,487.56 20,480.00 7.56 121.00 2 Harlan 20,400.69 13,914.36 1,400.00 5,040.56 45.77 70 589.19 Hayes 25,920.00 1,699.85 560.00 23 660.15 132.136.05 Hitchcock 25,494.87 1,773.46 28.80 23,732.61 167,590.87 Holt 87 696.60 11,340.59 2,920.00 73,436.01 178,133.32 (Uni.) 8,322.10 3,520.00 802.10 4,000.00 17,660.00 Hooker 26,127.53 120.00 26,007.53 35.270.51 Howard 23,041.44 17,211.86 716.82 5,107.73 5.03 50,147.59 Jefferson 20,484.08 18,368.65 560.00 1,555.43 33,894.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS July, 1936 to June 30, 1938 Total Acres Total Acres Appraised COUNTY Total Acres Total Acres Under Sale Under Lease Value of Acquired Deeded Contract Contract Unclassified Leased Lands Johnson 13,440.00 13,080.00 360.00 10,860.00 Kearney 18,581.40 15,781.40 120.00 2,680.00 29,100.33 Keith 45,662.40 6,707.76 563.20 38,308.92 82.52 130,337.02 t* Keya Paha 26,382.46 1,350.85 200.00 24,831.61 72,660.69 &gt; Kimball 36,599.01 723.34 160.00 35,644.25 71.42 188,507.37 2 Knox 42.253.81 26,700.62 2,268.16 13,285.03 116,251.01 ° (Uni.) 4,480.00 3,480.00 160.00 840.00 8,602.00 O (Agr.) 33,491.20 30,487.59 1,724.61 1279.00 17,825.50 2 Lancaster 31,236.84 30,409.34 80.00 747.50 29,700.00 5 (Saline) 32,789.44 31,722.75 429.07 637.62 15,152.40 S (Normal) 12,804.80 12,724.80 80.00 2,800.00 " Lincoln 97,892.89 20,699.62 .4,766.02 72,355.45 71.80 191,207.37 « Logan 20,480.00 1,574.89 1,305.11 17,600.00 40,140.00 2 Loup 20,393.28 1,748.95 18,644.33 37,144.99 S McPherson 31,092.63 600.00 240.00 30,252.63 41,746.71 § Madison : 24,639.38 22,359.38 2,280.00 24,044.00 w (Uni.) 2,240.00 1,920.00 160.00 160.00 1,772.00 « Merrick 14,976.21 12,250.71 187.35 2,538.15 39,054.50 $ Morrill 62,677.58 6,723.76 5,936.25 48,775.76 1,241.81 150,519.97 * Nemaha 11,946.89 11,599.74 271.95 75.20 8,082.90 2 Nuckolls 21,049.10 20,449.10 160.00 440.00 11,676.00 3 (Uni.) 4,881.68 4,764.58 117.10 2,403.92 Otoe 21,992.44 21,592.44 160.00 240.00 12,600.00 Pawnee 20,034.85 19,954.85 80.00 1,928.00 Perkins 31,523.75 86.95 160.00 31,276.80 179,230.20 Phelps : 20,228.60 17,468.60 640.00 2,120.00 28,080.00 Pierce 20,480.00 14,560.00 400.00 5,520.00 54,148.00 (Uni.) 3,197.67 3,197.67 (Agr.) 10,114.56 9,594.56 520.00 6,422.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS July, 1936 to June 30, 1938 __ Total Acres Total Acres Appraised COUNTY Total Acres Total Acres Under Sale Under Lease Value of Acquired Deeded Contract Contract Unclassified Leased Lands Platte . 23,655.48 22,566.38 1,040.00 49.10 11,560.00 M Polk 16,787.68 15,867.68 920.00 16,324.00 T Red Willow 25,485.30 10,052.00 2,866.50 12,566.80 105,874.00 5 Richardson 10,400.00 9,550.00 - 280.00 570.00 14,693.00 o Rock r. 40,232.40 3,320.00 920.00 35 992.40 79,683.80 n Saline 20,480.00 20,360.00 120.00 3,945.00 o Sarpy. 8,988.27 8,747.64 240.63 7,862.20 g Saunders 26,323.93 26,114.29 169.64 40.00 500.00 g Scotts Bluff. 25,467.65 9,821.77 4,527.84 ll ; 118.04 39,497.10 % Seward 20,560.00 20,480.00 80.00 2,030.00 M Sheridan 94 627.74 4,714.87 2,445.00 87,243.24 224.63 237,536.13 o Sherman 20J477.20 12,320.62 1,077.20 7,079.38 60,074.17 Z Sioux 80,972.22 1,243.23 1,236.77 78,492.22 143,732.20 « Stanton 15,360.00 14,940.00 80.00 320.00 20.00 3,800.00 *S Thayer 20,472.35 19,351.35 600.00 521.00 14 810.00 w Thomas 25,600.00 ... 3,849.30 21,750.70 16,029.50 W Valley. 20,474.88 16,882.74 720.00 2,850.88 21.26 19,592.28 S Washington 13,855.46 12,220.26 240.00 1,160.00 235.20 38,920.00 © Wayne 15,360.00 15,360.00 W (Agr.) 15,648.98 15,638.64 10.34 H Webster 20,480.00 18,833.87 960.00 680.00 6.13 7,240.00 (Uni.) 17,803.48 15,605.18 759.24 1,420.86 18.20 16 764.44 Wheeler 21,120.00 1,243.00 1,080.00 18,797.00 60,425.00 York 20,480.00 19,760.00 720.00 32,642.63 TOTAL 2.985,898.70 1,282,225.83 80,279.92 1,619,901.50 3,496.60 6,458,521.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Thousands of Oollars *i*|gaaa-aaggaaaaaa "I itee-K i 6.TITQ7 mn-z | /S.S6/3* t»rr-4 sa ajv.ti itff-a am i ti.it 9. a mra-ao^^ m M itzatin 1 r I I— ■— . 84.890t3 iii IHIbLmJ||||H|— isa.Q33£4 /OSS^K fBm ■■§ BH ■ I ZIO.474 7Z I9OO-O2 247 782 /ii IX2A gg |^_ bb W^O5 IJSt^ BHi ■■■■■■ H ■■■ 37O.O37P4 /SOS -JO o^ g^g — gn^ B sgisssfo I9/O-2 |^B m BB1 ■■§ ■■ ■■■ ■■_ 331 30S42 I9IZ-4 gg m yg gg __ ___ - 3/J 242 S3 Amounts Received by Sfofa oPNe6ns*a oa font*/ /2v Sc/too/ Lands Ay eMnnia/ &gt;tf«;9 /. Q&gt;» /?r»r» AfctrmAo At**-tor* Myx&gt;r/j. IS3S-e |aa aBa BB 7T9to042 1337-8 jjj jj| y— - — — - w '.-, . 1 ...... 77224437 Amount* /ntca/re* by Stota of m*rv**o oa /fcntol /br ScAooS torn** ty 0/cn»/ a / Period, /9I7 to »3*. *wn AmMwr «"A«V« /cwt* tOuM/nya M?x~*. </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT REAPPRAISEMENT OF SCHOOL LANDS School lands are reappraised by a standard of classification. Where classifications are made, the State Surveyor views each forty acre tract of school land for the purpose of obtaining all the necessary information relative to the type and rating of the soil, its adaptability, and the topographical characteristics of the land. A map is drawn showing the actual condition of each forty acre tract. Normally, school lands are divided into four types, namely: cultivated, hay, grazing, and waste lands. Each type of land is divided into more than one different grade according to its degree of productiveness. In arriving at the productive value of the cultivated land, the soil type and region in which it is lo - cated are the most important factors. Hay and grazing lands are usually divided into three classes each. This classification map referred to contains, in addition to the above data, all information relative to movable and immovable improvements together with the value of same. Under the law the State has a prior lien on all movable improvements on state school lands in the event of unpaid rental or interest on contracts. After the land in a particular county has been mapped and classified, a public hearing is held at the county seat town. The County Commis - sioners sit in jointly with the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ings, not to determine the individual lease value but to arrive at a fair value per acre of the various types of land in the county. C. R. Hough. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">RE-APPRAISAL OF LANDS MADE BY CLASSIFYING AVERAGE PRICE PER ACRE Values Range — Types Per Acre COUNTY Valuation Agricultural Grazing Hay Land Old New High Low High Low High Low Boone $11.87 $ 9.52 $36.00 $12.00 $14.00 $ 3.00 Bovd " ' 8.30 7.11 17.00 | 5.00 7.00 1.50 $10.00 $ 5.00 Cass 54.26 47.78 60.00 45.00 10.00 | CM],.!' 34 47 23.20 50.00 10.00 20.00 5.00 24.00 8.00 M Cheyenne 7-35 6.56 13.00 4.00 8.00 | 1.00 10.00 4.00 &gt; Deuel 7.41 7.77 13.00 4.00 3.00 1.00 2 Dundv' '"'"" 5.60 4.52 16.00 | 4.00 3.50 1.50 12.00 6.00 O Franklin 11.91 12.73 30.00 11.00 12.00 8.00 18.00 | 11.00 o Furnas 11.72 9.09 25.00 5.00 7.00 5.00 10.00 6.00 O Hall 15.66 16.61 50.00 10.00 24.00 | 6.00 40.00 8.00 g Harlan 17.06 13.54 30.00 11.00 12.00 8.00 18.00 11.00 g Hitchcock 5.22 7.05 16.00 | 5.00 4.50 2.50 8.00 4.00 53 Jefferson 22.00 21.65 55.00 15.00 20.00 10.00 35.00 | 25.00 £ Johnson 36.11 | 30.16 55.00 15.00 30.00 20.00 45.00 25.00 O Keva Paha 2.98 2.96 • 10.00 2.00 6.00 | 1.50 14.00 3.00 g Kimball 6.18 5.28 11.00 4.00 3.00 1.00 g Knox 10.68 9.35 40.00 | 5.00 18.00 2.00 22.00 7.00 g Madison 10.40 10.53 25.00 5.00 12.00 5.00 15.00 | 5.00 ™ Merrick 18.39 | 15.60 30,00 5.00 15.00 5.00 30.00 10.00 g Morrill 3.05 3.01 60.00 2.00 6.00 | 1.00 8.00 4.00 Eg Nuckoll's 23.33 25.27 55.00 15.00 30.00 5.00 35.00 25.00 O Pawnee 40 00 24.10 53.00 | 13.00 23.00 13.00 38.00 18.00 g Pie r c e 12.08 10.10 40.00 5.00 12.00 2.00 22.00. | 6.00 H Polk 15.49 I 17.74 40.00 10.00 25.00 12.00 Red Wmow' 6 - 23 8 - 42 18 - 00 6 - 00 6 - 00 I 4l0 ° 9 - 00 5&gt;0 ° Richardson 27.15 25.78 55.00 15.00 30.00 20.00 Scotts Bluff Z1Z ."" 3.12 3.46 60.00 | 2.00 6.00 1.00 8.00 | 4.00 Seward 35 00 25.37 60.00 20.00 30.00 10.00 40.00 20.00 Stanton • ~ 11.53 | 13.09 50.00 10.00 24.00 6.00 Webster 12.56 12.78 30.00 11.00 12.00 | 2.00 18.00 11.0C Wheeler 4.65 3.26 18.00 4.00 4.00 1.00 12.00 4.0C York " 49 96 37.37 65.00 ' 17.00 30.00 10.00 35.00 I 15.0C </seg>
            <seg id="p021">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT SCHOOL FUND: TEMPORARY AND PERMANENT The temporary school fund is derived from the following sources: interest on permanent school funds, rentals on lands under lease, interest on balance due on lands sold, bonuses received as premiums to secure lease contracts, interest on delinquent rental, and interest and money received for fines, etc. This temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year to the dif - ferent counties of the State that qualify according to laws set forth for the support of the public schools. The permanent school fund is derived from the sale of educational lands, and escheated lands. This fund is invested in interest bearing bonds in amounts at present as follows: Permanent School $10,937,132.25 Permanent University 284,180.12 Agricultural College Endowment 660,594.22 Normal Endowment 82,713.88 Soldier's Relief 1,942,061.51 Bessey Memorial 5,600.00 $13,912,281.98 VALUE OF SCHOOL LANDS June 30, 1936 Appraised Balance Due Value of On Sale Leased Lands Contracts Totals Common School $6,284,069.76 $1,074,862.14 $7,358,931.90 University 47,009.18 64,497.63 111,506.81 Agricultural College 54,708.85 22,689.71 77,398.56 Normal School 28,000.00 28,000.00 Saline 15,142.40 13,352.02 28,494.42 Totals $6,428,930.19 $1,175,401.50 $7,604,331.69 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ESCHEATED ESTATES July 1, 1936 to June 30. 1938 Estate of Elizabeth Daniels, deceased, which, after all claims were paid, consists of the following: 1. House and Lot— South 40 feet of Lot 4, Block 3, Boulevard Park Addition to the city of Omaha, 4118 No. 17th St., Omaha, Nebraska. 2. Administrator's check for $1,587.79. (This estate was reported Nov. 9, 1936 and ordered advertised for sale). . ■ Estate of Magnus Anderson Brown County Reported to the Board by the Attorney General's office Nov. 9, 1936. March 29, 1938 Certified Copy of Final Decree ordered recorded. Estate consisted of 560 acres in Brown County described as the SW% SWtt of Section 25, the SE^i, E% SW% and NW% SWVi of Section 26, North, Township 27 and NE% and E% NWVi of Section 35-27, all in Range 22 West. Fees remitted to general fund for recording, delinquent notices, reinstatements: Total $5,459.35 APPROPRIATION FOR THE BIENNIUM Salary of Commissioner $10,000.00 Salary of Deputy Land Commissioner 5,280.00 Salary of Office Employees 14,880.00 Office Maintenance 2,000.00 Wages of Capitol Employees 75,000.00 Fuel, Light, and Water 60,000.00 Maintenance of Capitol Building ... 18,000.00 Expense of Serving School Land Notices and Supplies to State Surveyor '. 2,000.00 Reappraising School Lands 5,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT On page four of this report the history of educational lands was given. You will note that since 1875 the constitutional office of Commis - sioner of Public Lands and Buildings has been intact. On January 29, 1935 the Legislature for the first time read House Roll "404", a bill for an act for a joint and concurrent resolution to amend Section One, Article Four, Constitution of the State of Nebraska 1875, and the several amendments proposed by the Constitutional Convention of 1919 - 1920 and adopted at a special election held on the 21st day of September, 1920, relating to executive state officers of the State of Nebraska and to abolish the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. On April 19, 1935 House Roll "404" was read for the third time and by a vote of 62 to 22 the bill was advanced to the Senate. On May 24, 1935 the Senate by a vote of 12 votes in the affirmative and 14 votes in the negative failed to receive a constitutional majority. On May 25 a motion was made that the rules be suspended and to reconsider in - definite postponement of House Bill "404" and that the same be re - turned from the House and placed immediately on third reading. The motion prevailed and by a vote of 20 in the affirmative and eight in the negative a constitutional three-fifths majority was received and the bill was declared passed, and the title agreed to. At the general election held November 6, 1936, the constitutional amendment was submitted to the voters of the State of Nebraska. To adopt the amendment 246,682 votes were received and to defeat the amendment 210,143 votes were received. By these votes the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings was abolished but at the same time two candidates from the two parties ran for the said office. • The successful candidate received 266,972 votes and the defeated candi - date received 254,164 votes. In an action brought by the successful candidate to determine the status of the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings we quote from the majority opinion of the Supreme Court: "We therefore conclude that the amendment was properly sub - mitted and adopted as a part of the Constitution by the electorate of Nebraska; that, by virtue thereof and the proclamation of the Governor, the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings ceased to be a constitutional office on and after December 15, 1936, that a construction of the constitution after adoption of the amendment in question requires this Court to hold that the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings continued as an executive state office thereafter; that the official acts of the petitioner since November 3, 1936, are those of a regularly elected and qualified executive office of the state, that petitioner is entitled to his salary for the term for which he was elected, as fixed at the time of his election; and that the appropriation of funds for carrying out the duties of his office is a valid and subsisting appropri - ation." The duties of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings </seg>
            <seg id="p024">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT are to act as custodian of the Nebraska Capitol Building and the Capitol grounds and to serve as secretary to the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Legislative Bills #383 and 392 passed by the last session of the Legis - lature transfers the custodianship of the Capitol Building to the Governor and the appointment of the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds by said board. Custodian of Nebraska's State Capitol Building has complete control and all powers necessary and incident to properly maintain Nebraska's Capitol and Capitol grounds. It shall be his duty to see that all visitors at proper hours are properly escorted over the Capitol Building. It is his duty at all times to have charge of and supervise the police, janitors and other employees in and about the Capitol Building and grounds. HEATING AND PLUMBING Early in the year 1935 we repacked four hundred and twenty-five gate valves on the heating lines that were leaking and installed new diaphragms in the pressure reducing valves and also repacked them. We also went over all radiators arid installed five hundred new thermo - static elements in radiator traps that were found defective due to pro - longed use and perhaps overheating. There were eighty-eight drip traps installed on the heating mains in the basement to overcome surg - ing and hammering in heating lines and to secure economical and more efficient operation. We are now able to maintain a vacuum of ten to fourteen inches at the pumps. We overhauled and cleaned the oil filters of the indirect heating equipment and added new oil and have had them in operation con - tinuously. We overhauled the air pumps of the Johnson Control of the heating equipment and put in new rings and valves, also changed the chain drive to Texrope drive, the chain drive having become so badly worn that it was impossible to tighten the chain. Many thermometers were replaced on the Johnson Control system broken by vandals, and we had the mechanic of the Johnson Service Co. check and repair it. The Jennings Hytor Vacuum Heating pumps were overhauled, and two new shafts were installed, and all glands repacked. Check valves were replaced where needed, and we repaired those that re - quired it. Many changes of various offices caused radiators to be placed in new positions. We also repaired approximately two hundred and fifty radiator control valves by re-washering or by new diaphragms as needed. Large expansion joints were repacked in the heating mains at the center of the tower in the basement. We replaced ten pieces of pipe that had eaten out in the heating system during the past summer. Time alone can determine the extent of this damage done by corrosion. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT There were a multitude of small jobs that were taken care of which are too numerous to mention but which were very essential to the com - fort of the patrons and occupants of the Capitol Building. In addition to the regular faucet washer repairs, stoppage, etc., we found time to overhaul all of the Sloan flush valves in the building. On closet and urinals the hard alkali water had eaten the brass lining of the top cylinders on these valves which were replaced with new cylinders with monel metal linings. These seem to stand up better in the water than the brass lined. We also overhauled the sewer ejectors and installed new floats and repaired ejector flush valves. We emptied and cleaned the two 7,500 - gallon water storage tanks on the fifteenth floor of the tower. With the assistance of the Baker Ice Machine Company's mechanic, we over - hauled the ice machine, installing new wrist pins, rings and valves in the compressor. We cleaned and repacked the condensing coils and in - stalled several new control valves on this equipment. Several hundred pounds of calcium chloride salts weie added to the brine tank. New copper coils were installed in one low pressure gas water heater. The screw pump that is used to circulate the hot water on the low pressure lines was overhauled, and two new shafts were made and installed in the pump. ELECTRICAL Traffic in the tower has put a strenuous burden on the two passenger elevators going to the fourteenth floor. The drum on one e'evator was removed twice to provide a wedge system whereby it could be kept tight on the shaft. Bearings were replaced twice on the drum end and once on the commutator end of this same machine. One elevator car has had the drum removed and one bearing replaced. Both drums at the present seem to be holding. New cables on the hoist side were installed on the first elevator in June, 1938. Commutators on the motor generators for the above cars were turned and undercut in January, 1938 and one spare armature purchased. The switchboard has called for constant watching due to its over - loaded condition. The warming up and cooling offi causes the buzz bars to loosen and arc. Several small bars and bolts have been replaced to - gether with one main fuse bolt. The 6,600-volt transformers have been stepped up to their maximum to take care of line loss from the penitentiary at peak load. This has resulted in a normal voltage and efficient lamp service through the day but a too high voltage at night. This, of course, results in short lamp life on those burning at night. Hojwever, the efficiency gained, lack of heating of panel boards and reduction of current cost has more than offset the additional lamp cost. Manufacture and repair of extension cords has been constantly in - creasing due to additional desk lamps, calculating machines, fans and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT I ■ ■ ■ . other equipment lacking sufficient convenient outlets. Many departments have had additional ceiling: lights installed filling the fuse panels to capacity and in some instances causing frequent fuse and fuse clip changes. ; The floodlighting was supervised by this department with the in - stallation done by a contractor. The voting machine was overhauled completely with fifty units dis - mantled and cleaned ready for coming session. One new bearing was installed on motor generator set servicing this equipment. Three motor generator sets have been added for International Busi - ness Machine equipment. The switching arrangement on the blue print machine was modernized, and many small installations were completed by this department in the basement and in other parts of the building. MISCELLANEOUS Considerable work has been done to repair the leaks on the second floor terrace. Some of these leaks have been stopped by replacing the mastic solution around the tile, and by the use of lead caulking and water-proofing. This work is not completed. We have replaced all the mastic seams and water-proofed the tile roof covering the fourth floor. Cracks and holes have been repaired in the entire copper covered roof of the building. These cracks have been caused from the natural expansion and contraction of the metal. These cracks have all been patched with the same weight copper, interlocked seams and soldier. There have been 1,060 windows checked and repaired, replacing glass and broken parts where needed, and all bolts and screws tightened. We have serviced the Venetian blinds whenever necessary. Cords have been replaced, and if the webbing had become broken, the blinds were removed, slats washed and reassembled. Many door checks have been overhauled and doors have been rehung. On the south door on the first floor it was necessary to design a new ball-bearing hanger for the top hinge to keep the door from slamming. This was also necessary for the east revolving door in order that it might operate more easily. We have done all the welding required to keep the building and equipment in repair, as well as numerous miscel - laneous jobs on furniture and fixtures. Area classified and mapped prior to the commencement ' of this biennium '. _ 365,019.70 Area classified and mapped during this biennium 218,007.08 Total number of acres classified and mapped 583,026.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Classification and reappraisal of school lands authorized by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds during the last biennium, but not classified by July 1, 1938: County Acres Holt (area unclassified July 1, 1938)..... _ _... 55,324.01 Custer _ 55,447.31 Howard _ 5,107.73 Garden — _ _ _ _ 58,526.34 frontier _ _ _ _ _ 21,238.00 Buffalo „ _ 9,971.30 Total number of acres authorized for classification .....205,614.69 Permanent classification maps are now being made by means of a Works Progress Administration project. I recommend that funds be ap - propriated to carry on this work by the regular employees of this de - partment. I also suggest that recommendations be made to the next legisla - ture for an appropriation of sufficient funds for the employment of one full time deputy state surveyor and expenses and material, that the surveying and land classification work of this department be facilitated. In enacting Sec. 72-204, Senate File 58, Laws of Nebraska, 1935, the legislature made no provisions in the appropriation bill for carrying on this work other than an appropriation of $5,000 for expenses of re - appraising school lands, which was $5,000 less than the amount appropri - ated in 1933 for the same purpose before the laws provided for the de - tailed classification and mapping of each tract of school land. The passage of the classification law has increased the work of this depart - ment to the extent that the services of two full time deputy surveyors were needed. However, by assigning all surveys applied for, other than those of state owned lands, to the present force of deputy state surveyors, who receive their salary and expenses from the applicants, it has been possible for me to devote the larger portion of my time to the field and office work in connection with the classification and re-appraisal of school lands. But this has not proved sufficient. The field work of the classification of Holt County is in progress at the time this report is written. The classification and re-appraisal of this county was autho - rized by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds on March 23, 1937. By the time the field work is completed, the maps prepared, the classi - fication of land under each lease listed, the hearings held and the re - appraisal approved by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, the new values and rentals can not become effective at an earlier date than July 1, 1939. It will require all of the next biennium to complete the classification work and re-appraisals already authorized by the Board during this biennium. One full time deputy state survey would facili - tate this work to the extent that re-appraisals could be made effective within one year after the date of authorization. H. B. LAWSON, State Surveyor. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING State Surveys During the last two years the following applications for surveys have been received and filed in this office: No. Name of Applicant ' County 602 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co Thayer 603 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co York 604 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co Polk 605 County Board „ _ Gage 606 Mrs. Lora Hakanson, et al _ Clay 607 Lancaster County Rural Pub. Pr. Dist Lancaster 610 John T. Seward, et al _ -..Cherry 611 Henry Wolken _ — _ Gage 612 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist...._ _ Lancaster 613 Board of Educational Lands &amp; Funds Dixon 614 County Board _ Merrick 615 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist Kearney 616 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist Lincoln 617 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist _ Adams 618 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist Keith 619 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist Phelps 620 Central Neb. Pub. Pr. &amp; Irr'n. Dist _ Clay 621 Department of Roads &amp; Irrigation _ Seward 622 Paddock Township Board Gage Fees collected by the -Department of Surveying and submitted to the State treasurer: December 15, 1936 _...$ 58.40 December 10, 1937 - _ 76.52 June 4, 1938 _ 44.00 Total ..._ $178.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ■ ■•■■"•' • I ■ SCHOOL LANDS CLASSIFIED AND MAPPED County Acres Scotts Bluff 11,118.04 Knox _ 15,266.23 Morrill ; 47,788.9? Cherry — 12,349.56 Keya Pafaa . _. 24,471.03 Cheyenne _ _ 42,985.01 Cedar „ 1,966.91 Pierce _ _ 6,000.00 Polk _ 920.00 Hall 2,486.21 Washington . _ 1,140.00 Stanton _ _ 400.00 Boone 2,796.52 Banner (final maps incomplete) „ _ 25,918.60 Holt (field work incomplete) 22,400.00 Total (15 counties) .218,007.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">rOAWES ! sioux 1 i ] ) SHERIDAN \ CHERRY I I I H. /0.00 I I | *■' *O j I I .... &lt;*»• tM I Ac.e35.H37.Z7 i: ir i "* butte ] - -* i "■ £ I Mr/ -*HO,SIZ.9 7 I j /aoo J j T -«k. j&gt;« i, I, _^ f"scorrs"iLuFF| *1 i GRANT F ho °ker T"~tthomas f I MORWLL GARDEN j I £^*£ K " "ZfftF" "?%?*' I ll'-^ff Ac-45.775.7i L j j aJ^AM Av-73 \ BANNER " 1 I**' '+IXHSOJS7 ! -^.-a-M^. T T — " ■ ' 1 \ - | *.*&amp;*„ H. taoo KW.#SaS*«» ARTHUR MSPHERSON ! LOGAN I %sg , -:;- -«"• i£» pass? -..jaßai KIMBALL 1 CHEYENNE 1 J— l'-llf L-^JJJf. J_±liff_._L /Ic.J^,«6*jj Ac. 4i.M7.00 I I KEITH j j ?:» r.is t^sasr 4 rrzsr~ \ lincoln i ■l^ 1 !rfer [ H*.*I79J3O.X&gt; ' L. 1.00 I NEBRASKA \_M_ . 1_1" "*___] VU**/3*0a7.07 I Vol.o/3t.13*.03 . Val'*lOS^3t.OO *••**»* I -V-/700 /y. /««, I /y. /*&lt;» Ac. Acrea ar\M4a*t lam*. \ L ' " s • i- ! Z. • *&gt;&gt;• Total oppraiatd valuation. * 3y /»,.«« ytr&gt;««« H 'Hif* appraisal pv acrm. h T / s^« | J!!SS"' f^i^" l 1 l:;.tff j /&gt;k. 7-oj jX. IS </seg>
            <seg id="p031">! KEYA PAHA T" BOYD \ I Ac. 24.a31.c1 \ Ac- it.353.04 Kr/.'s^cxcsA^^ [ Val-'7Z,CtO.C.9 I ,/""\ //'/TOO I' /.SO^*^ f*^\r~*~&gt;-^ S *'l I *&lt; I KNOX j CEDAR j^^X-* j Ac- 15.404 03 I Ac-1.97t.84 I D (XON \ BROWN ROCK HOLT ! *"*£*f 5 ' I *"'«*"*« .V j &gt; ! /. ■ ; L , «00 (6/.*/S«Z»| *""*&gt; I A-.J-L3SIOO *•**■ Ar'tSZO \ H-4200 DAKOTA I ! ! I ! w.t1t3.Z4000 L' ZOO \ j /VO/V£- 'N j \ H.iroo \A*-Joio 1 I Actl.7SO7o AC.Z4.4SO4S Ac18.L4433 \ Ac . 15,87a.4Z \ Actf.mOO \ *"**** I y a ,.»JgOoaA , c \ac- U0.70 ( K,l.'/«I*.SO ! Vcl.fSS/nu.3o \ 1b,.*Jt,44.93 \ Vat 'USfiSt.OS \ V.1.**0.4/i.M 1 \ *I**SAI«X&gt; •. „ . saM j NONE \ Voh *efil3*(iK H- ISO j H. 10.00 \ H'AOO H. 10.00 H- MOO BOONE ". CM IL- 6.00 • !" ' 3a °° *'- 73 I *„. /.OJ A.. 1.39 I »k. i J» Ac Z7963Z |^f^_._L.l 1 r J |*t.J*M.} •" 1 !( J 1 V K./.*«««o-7tf^- __ TcOLTAX DODGE IvKshingY LOGAN I ! VALLEY GREELEY //.je.oo P^ TT S &gt;»c.«J^ 'TtJSw* ! OI«STFR W/XS3UU VbI.t4O,9SSJ3 ]*'•*** j "'''%"" // • /400 l/zriTio * A/, /000 CUSTER #, /w //./«.«&gt; 1 . r- 1 - 1 H '" % \I- • '*°° \ \l-ssoo L- 1.00 L. COO L- ZOO riiu-'c lA, 111 l . A,.»oOft ~&gt;__-^ '^Atr-JA* I a*.im . «,„„ A..**i ±a,.j.os i NANCE M-"" s-' \ r.'ss t:';s rtrvf - - i i:ss -.:- te SSJ TZZT 1 ; -BU^LX) .I HAUT"]^ fvORK jSEWA^ ■ , Ac.t1.918.00 lA*\'3.44OJOO Ac*/MOO \Ac-tABO.OO *"'£,£:„ \2,1.*4\00C100 I I *.h*A»*SOO TjOHNSOS ; VaI'*IOSS3t.OO \WI U4.Ue*&gt;\ vU-»M0eosO \ Vol-UZ100.33 V.h**Vlo.oo ■ I *' I '2*Z i NON£ I H-JSM J 57Tj«A«» **&lt;&gt; pJilw /..*«. ! z.. wo \ l. *oo f-'ffj '■ GAGE \„. ssjoo A,, A4* I A,\»J* I A,./3.14 \Ar. O.SS ! "'■^ - M'^!! \ 1 |L' 15.00 T'""r"ed^.'l^7l webster"| NiKmiaJ™^ I^S? "| MSS. r^fiSfc //. /^a» j "• &gt;/• Joa&gt; -v-Jaoo H. 3000 M - S f;°° \ &#132;.,0.00 ! l-iooo Ar.36.00 " L . IJjOO l. 400 \ l. 100 \L. aoo \ 1.. z.OO L- zoo , t. *a» . I XK.^/oa Lj?tiiiii J A ,, eJ4 I /&lt;k. 4&lt;&gt;e AY./4.00 Ar. 13.39 \ A,- 7.98 jA, . fS£S | J 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">: HI KEYA PAHA T BOYD DAWES I Ac.14.a31.6l lAc 11,953.04 Vbl-*32.0t6« ..^« w "i sheridan "i • cherry h--^^;;? .^T ?&gt;^ /• /a&lt;w j . •■ ■' : iTaj? , j a,. aa.tsT.gr BROWN ROCK HOLT L MU'»t3XS3*J3 L I Ar.JSSM 00 box buttTJ ?: ~? ] £ 3 sasssJi --— £2K£* V t T ~r r-L- J \ I k 1 GRANT HOOKER T THOMAS T BLAINE ! LOUP \ GARFIELO ! WHE I j Ae&gt;ttfl*9.ia I Ac-2t.007.33 Ac 21.75070 Ac24.490.4S Ae-ta,t4433 j Ac-io.aia.4t j AcV. "■ \ „. soo I H . gso H , lso H. 10.00 H'AOO IH. 10.00 I H.l* \ ' t-t/.es l&gt; .ao i- .so ! /., to \ l&gt; too ] /.• /.oo \ l- /. Ac.4Si77S.Tt L | **•/*! I Av/.JS A»- 7J Aw /.OS Ay. 1.39 Ay IM **• * **&gt; '*iscisas7 : «»&lt;^. I I * — j — | l 1 1 V H. taoo V*.4m££*o • A^MUR MSPHERSON ! LOGAN I ! VALLEY | GR£ *•' '&lt;*» H. IaOO 11'.^^°° AcJdMtS AcIZtOOjOO j AcZBOM Act. f." JOfl L . ZOO ; **'•'•»?'««» . K,/.*4/,74t.7/ I Val-t40.140.00 rUSTPR M/'/VXUS Kr/'A CHEYENNE pL^.ll^ L -^ff. L^.^ ,i .c^z,/ _itl±2— .. -±^ «••««. j ! KBTH | I T'SSST" "SHERMAN I HCX // " A * Q3 HJ^ySv, M.OOW7M \ LINCOLN ; a,- s.4S i ™' H %™ T "'''. *-• too \ **-H.aatSQ I h. io.oo 1 h- tcoo h- t ... f i-'IOO A..7.J9 *" *&lt;° \ Ac.7t,353.4S \ 1 1 \ I PERKINS M-*/s/.r07.J7 OAWSON I BUFFALO j H Ac-J1.17t.80 I H ISO ° Ac-a.U7.Ot ■ Ac.0,771.20 I Ac. U*'*/nj30.?0 j L ' lO ° ! Vo/-*ttJOtJS \ V1' * 96.179.03 *•'• H- 1100 *"' *** H- 35.00 | H' 40.00 I «• jA QWA L- 100 . ! i« I i. «.OO j L&lt; \SI\J f\ SI ■'■■: A " S -1J I ■^"* *' S i Arm lO** | &lt;«* i,» ,».».._ CHASE ! HAVES FRONTIER GOSPER I 'phcT^T — T-;7pXs{jp V A no underlease: *.«*»* \ ac^^s I L. 4 ««iJ!!S!S i&gt;,^S« K*/*'/31G37.07 j Vol-Hit.13t.05 • Val ' * ISS^49t.OO \ibltM.iCSOo\ vbl.t/s,oaom • Val 'tiSLlOO.33 \V° *n&lt;t *• I*oo H - it oo I //. /*oo 1//./9OJ Ih - ii.oo H ' 3SOO j " Moart fan*. ! J-' t- -?«&gt; Z.- , l^.jy-f !*. 4.00 \L- t.SO \ L woisia valuation. I I / *" • 538 *** i /«r.*J« A,. 13.14 \A»* lO.SS i *' robot per aerm. " I T 1 ' T 1 '. misol f* r ocr,. OUNDY J HITCHCOCK ! RED WILLOW I FURNAS HARLAN J FRANKUN j V approval p,r ocr: Ac3t.Z7*O3 Act3.731.C1 I Ac.ltSt.eo I Ac.tt,lS9.tO \Ac-Sfi4O.S6 Ac. 6.92636 A r//«, C LEO „ SWANSaM "2 Z??** 5 \ *+'"&amp;*t6T *&#132;*'IOSA74OO Va,-* 117,99331 J Vat .*7ofie9J9 \ *.l-*96fi4S.*S \ Mr JZ*,**?*^™ H. 16.00 | yy. /&amp;00 H* MOO \ H' tS.OO H. 30.00 H - 30.00 H »na a &amp; BmUm^.Ju^USia. 4.-I*o \L. £50 \ ". *Z \ L- S.OO !L. SOO \ L.-Z.OO ! L | Ay. 4-St | Ar' 7.0S \ A,, SJ4 | Ar* S.OS | A,. M00 \ Ar- 13.99 \A, </seg>
            <seg id="p033">-__ V BOYD \ ■ 1Z.353. 04 K&gt;/. *32.04644^*^ ~~~f KNOX j CEDAR P-U . j Ac. 15.404 03 | Ac , 1i9n .84 lr,|V O i7l HOLT i \M'*M.67OSI j M .s4 Si6t9aS \ UI * UN V "' 400 ° H&gt; SaOO \Ac.333St 1 .. ! L' 2.00 \ L&gt; &amp;OO j l 6/.»/?«Zw[~"^^-\ . _-« , I *"■ SJ * \a..23 2o \h-4100 DAKOTA I Ac. 77,436.01 \ r " , . J „. &lt;000 war? R^H s- i P?Sa#S *•■'■&lt;» I m.Hau*&gt; WAYNE I ,— I T. j ;.^o ! jthurstonJ) __ __ I H.troo l_f.ll^t • L L GARFIELo'TwHEELER ' a^."/* I MADISON TsTANTONf CUMING l^T? AciefiTSAt Ac -19.79700 j &gt;tcj;««&lt;» BU RT VALLEY GREELEY N-iioo j PLATTE j j DODGE R^SHiNGTON -4,..i:««UM Xc.^aOOXIO I i-&gt; AOO I Ac 1.04000 \%'X mn \ \ Ac- /.lf 000 Hfisssiza vbt.*4o,9saj3 \*" • *** i K&gt;'-*V***&gt; \ ' "t, \ none \u.i*3af&amp;oof I- COO L . t.OO H ! t • *■*&gt; L/looJ. \l.-IS.OO A.. I*7 Jjr.jw j NANCE l^-.//// \r-'^\ ' '''^^--Wjna^""? SHERMAN 1 HOWARD*"]! A " 0A " J ~\^' \ BOTLER I SAUNDERS V £;"££, Ac-7oma AC.S./07.7J iL-.—J- 1 ' .•^POLK !Ac 32060 I Ac 40.00 //. JdOO f iUFTALO | HALL l""*^ S YORK j SEWARD j jAc . 90.00 \ 771.20 U.«w.7/ j/. Ac- 7/aoo I i LANCASTER ! Voi ,*4J00.00 \ 9t.179.03 I K,1./41,C94J5 / NONE \ V.I-»M.(42M M-*iO3HOO . M . 6a0 0 L'IOOO I e.OO \ l. 6.00 ! l. 10.00 L "° 00 I t;t z lu4o\ OTOE 7 /o.*e HAMILTON I A..4513 A».tsn \ lt^ m *^ 40 ActlZoo k -KEARNE^I ADAMS T CLAY TrLLMORE SAUNE j -.^ ,«. -.- \AclfiOO,oo j Ac.1J40.00 1 ,&lt;c. OOOOO j _L Vai.H3iioo.33 V.I.HVKMO Vbi-*4\ooaoo k.,.*3.msm&gt; T jOHNSONnTNEMAHAA \t.2o» \ A,.*.** \A,.,a00 I i *'^ j GAGE "• «^» ) r 1 * 1 1 1 i.' 13.00 \Z~.taT2 t *&gt;_ I FRANKUN I WEBSTER NUCKOLLS THAYER ; JEFFERSON jAc soaoo L^&lt;^l£S^-.^-^rr i^SSi\ j Ac.wcse i A..V004* \acss7.» j A*.saoo \ac, SS so 3 I«^ r^^r^f^* \ j //.TOOO^ H-3000 \H- 55.00 \ H-SOIOO H ■ SS.OO tZL 2^ S3 00 I* " SS £ ) \L- MM \L. 2.00 L. S.OO L.,0.00 J. . ,000 A..36.00 H^S3.OO I I Ay.f3.SS | /^ y . 79J j A.. 2528 \A* .ZOA2 \ Ay.21.08 \ [A, * 24.10 | A,.25.T7 m </seg>
            <seg id="p034">CLASSIFICATI ,/--w : - v .';■/,,;■; "■■ .■':■'■ ■ ■■■'■' : ;. . ■ ■ v ■ sec tv COUNTY - ||? , r ,f / fc&amp;cl ■ Cu/S/vo-tec/ area ill 1 , J . v v ' i . I J „ _ ■ I- = Sbm bu,/d,nfs % w/ndnv//s Vs^xWN \n?^^VC'-^ - S~a~,ps %, /afoons / V &amp; R = f?o///np /one/ sxJ ' j -'/ "V n\J = zom/ a«///^ /&lt;»/,«/ ./ _ * % "%. ilt \*y 1 Gff = Gerr//y rof/inj fond f" » n, Mv ii^ &gt;GA? - Very yenHf ro/ZSnj ** "* "^ &gt;^ tf&gt;%i&amp;}f, NL - /Veor/y /eve/. -j T.," ° : , '1^ - Tripp very fine sanc/y /oam 1 '""'■■ •"n&gt;'\-''""'\/3' 1 ";;&gt;- •/,, |i) ,/ -■ x ' .^ .- Ho/Jrej,; very /&gt;ne sandy /oarr, Cv "%' m /;. ''^£/ '"'"" " ' ■ -^^ « RoseAc/c/ jranc/y /oam I '/(il 1 ** _____-— " Z./ a £oure/ Sine sandy /oam I __^ — —^"^ 1^! = Va/en-f/ne sant/y /o—~&gt; ""1 C" • Co/jby v*ry Sine sandy Zoom | A "\. ,^ D - Dune sand Ks~\y-*- V *.'i,' i? ,/ Jr9 \ N N x \ V V v v \ /I •? :&gt;: -,: :■■■ ■.;■'■■; ; . Hi -" i </seg>
            <seg id="p035">SIFICATION MAP IC TWP RGE_ xjnty / I ' I I■ - ■ „ , v v., J. SUB'N. Ci.ASSIFiCAT/ON $P^llH*r| nX\\&gt; \\\^ vT vx^ V 1 N£N£ A-/--38ac. h/os/e-Zoc. Kk^ - W" -A- /* ■ 4Oac. - fl 4^Ra;r^^\^x : Sx\^x^^^ Nw - G-2-40OC &gt;^ 4 / P V •1 &lt; §%ssm -i ?$&amp;&amp;&amp;&amp; r 3£ - G-2.40QC. V". "'" &gt;&gt; v c, v Ci L.. ■&gt;/"-":.: V;Vmp&gt;-- ""^ /v£s£ //-/« 200c G-o*-2o«t. Hit \ /&gt; x IS£1 ■■ 1 *-/»«*»-*• g^-^?&gt; &lt;£, i 1 " 1 ' 1 * '1 fl.' y "^ = tortc/ under cu/ftisai e /an $ //\ fy \ jy NOTE ■- Vo/ve to 6* p/acecf v/*on eacA ;;' 1(/ y S'\ *) &lt;^ c/atS'f''ca*&lt;6n by Soorc/ of £c/t*COi e /o"0f * C^ TCs."'C"n. O&lt;r / '*' Couo/y Board m wh/cft */te /ar&gt;c/ ..)/ It 1/ )t I!^^^ </seg>
            <seg id="p036">! | CLASSIFICATION SEC -TWP_RGE_ i COUNTY / Cu/S/i/a-tecf' area ' ,i } i l j , -i — ■— — + i i ■ Gerrf/y rott.n? /and f \ ' •*$&amp; J VVfej^X N^ r^ r^ f ----- 4f )il|^ A/eoriy tmv./. -4} jyr- : : 'V I ii^Z'^b Tr,pp rerj, fine sanc/jr /ocm \ ••/, ':,,,,^ •;»»^3-"^&gt; ' v^',./ -' "" /^ )vC&gt;^l Rose£iK/ sane^ Zoom I W' 1^ ___ — — " A" n * loure/ Sine sandy /oano I __^- — "" ?./ "j^ . si Co/Ay v ,ry fae sanJy /oon, A "\ } V \,^ </seg>
            <seg id="p037">J MAP _rge_ : v ■■■■■ " ■■'■•■■;.,.■■: ■ ■ V " / * . I — SUB'N. CLASSIFICATION J\ \\\n&gt; W \^ V^ \xX"^\ N \O NEME A-/- 38 ac. h/os/e =Z oc * S£ " *-"*'*&gt;*. G-3-20QC. ~x? '-'//n--; v, ,o- v, " \,W w,;,;.-&gt;:-^ -- cy K^^k % n \""""s &gt; V i W '" vl " h/-/--2Ooc G-/&gt;*-2O«c. ...«'*"• ' o ""^7""^ .-■' ''"' 'i^'Cs* ''^ J*V " H-2--3Oac. G-/ ■ /Oat AIV ,|, V"^ VV ' IS£ " 1 «-&gt;'*-™°'- g-^-//«. Jf. _____^ -V / /P - /.a/)a t/ncfer- cu/f/vaT/or&gt; '~Y \ **~~c " 1^" j** s3^ — &lt;? * Gr-azino /and . *° Vl. // Hoy Z-d y y\ 1j S aY /Vor^- •- Wo/c/e •*&lt;&gt; 6* /&gt;/acet/ u/oon e*c4 f /f V y&lt;^ &lt;^, c/o 'f'Srcatt'cn by Boort/ »/* £c/ucet/So"of *?■. r . _- — . o/* /&lt;4 ff foui /&gt;&gt; Board /n vv/t/cA tfre /aid </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>