<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00017">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00017</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>TWELFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB FOR THE YEARS 1899 AND 1900, TO THE GOVERNOR.</title>
			            <date value="1901">1901</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-29</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Laura Weakly</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Validation</item>
				     </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-24</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
				     </change>

				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWELFTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

IF THE 

BOARD OF TRUSTEES 

F THE 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTE 

FOR THE 

DEAF AND DUMB 

FOR THE YEARS 1899 AND 1900. 

1 THE 

GOVERNOR. 

NCOI.N. NEB 

ATE JOURNAL COMPANY. PRINTERS. 

IHO1</seg> 


            <seg id="p003">
l 

LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL. 

Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, 

Omaha, Neb., December 12, 1900. 

honorable Wm. A. Poynter, Governor: 

Sir— In compliance with section 12, chapter 22, of the Com 

iled Statutes the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute 
or the Deaf and Dumb have the honor to transmit herewith 

he twelfth biennial report for that institution upon the work 
icoomplished during the period ending; November 30, 1900. 

Very respectfully. 

J. J. Cardwell 
B. F. Allen. 
Chas. Nownes, 

Board of Trustees </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
BOARD OF TRUSTEES 

Hon. J. J. Cardwell President 

Hou. B. F. Allen Secretary 

Hon. ('has. Nownes. 

OFFICERS, TEACHERS, AND EMPLOYEES. 

Henry E. Dawes, M. A., Supt., f 1,800 per year and living. 
Win. Sievera, Steward and Bookkeeper, $1,200 per year; live* 

outside. 

S. R. Town*, M. D., Physician, $300 per school year; lives outside. 
Mary C. Dawes, Matron, $400 per year and living. 

Ansou T. Colt, B. 1&gt;., Teacher, |80 per month, lives outside. 
Janie M. Washington, M. A., Teacher, $65 per month and living. 
Waldo H. Rothert, B. A., Teacher, $80 per month, lives outside. 
Norman Shreve, M. A., Teacher, $55 per month and living. 
Alvin E. Pope, M. A., Teacher, $55 per month and living. 
Lyman M. Hunt. Diploma. Teacher, $70 per month; lives outside. 
Lillian Bamford, Diploma from State Normal, Teacher, $60 per 

month: lives outside. 

Cora Jack, Diploma from the State Normal, Teacher. $50 per 
month; lives outside. 

Edith Hand. Diploma from Tremont Normal. Teacher, $42.50 per 
mouth and living. 

na McNamar. Diploma, Teacher. $t£.5O per month; lives out 
side. 

Ida &lt;i. Hendee. Teacher. $»'&gt;0 per mouth; lives outside 
Ora Vivian, Teacher. $50 per month; lives outside. 

It. Andrews. Diploma. Kindergarten Teacher, $50 per 
hit It : lives outside. 

Mary McNamar. Assistant Kindergarten Teacher, $35 per 

utsidf 

S. S. Videtto. Manual Training Teacher, $80 per month; lives 
outside. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
416 

LAND COUlfHHIIONBB'8 REPORT. 

tmie L. Plotts. Sewing Teacher. $50 per month; lives outsidtvd 
Blankenship, Diploma. Art Teacher. $40 per mouth am 

living. 

YV. N. Paxton, Printing Teacher. $55 per mouth: lives outside 
E. N. Reynolds, Teacher of Horticulture, $55 \ter month; live; 

outside. 

Margaret Murphy, Teacher in Laundry. $22.50 per month an&lt;: 
living. 

Luster A. Kay. Stenographer (works mornings and evening: 
while attending Commercial College). §5 per month an&lt; 
, living. 

John Zadiua. Supervisor. $30 per month and living. 
Lulu Hall. Nurse. $27.50 ]K'V month and living. 
Amelia (iillinian. Supervisor. $25 per month and living. 
Lena Goedicke, Baperviser, $25 j&gt;er month and living, 
('has. Sexton. Engineer. $75 j&gt;er month; lives outside. 
Thos. Byrnes. Engineer. $55 per month; lives outside. 
Chas. Kelley. Fireman. $25 per month and living. 
John Holter. Teamster. $20 per month and living. 
Anna Jansen. Cook. $25 per month and living. 
Hannah Kuennniann. Second Cook, $20 per month and living 
Kitty Petereen. Dining-Koom Girl, $15 per month and living. 
Eniina Bradly. Dining-Koom Girl. $15 ]ter month and living. 
Mary Washington, Laundress. $25 per month; lives outside. 
Kena Parkhurst. House Girl. $15 per month and living. 
John Kosenthal. .Janitor. $15 i&gt;er mouth and living. 

Frank Chase, Janitor, $5 ]&gt;er month and living. 
Harry Myres. Janitor. $10 j»er month and living. 


I 


1 

l 

ii 

ii </seg>

            <seg id="p007">REPORT. 

Nebraska Institute kok the Deaf am* Dcmb. 

Omaha. Nbb., Decemlter 12, I'.MM). 

the Governoi 

The Hoard of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf 
id iMmiti have the honor to submit the following report: 
There were iu the institute November 30, 1M0, 166 pupils, 
ale and female. 

The whole number of pupils enrolled during the bienuium was 

8 

The highest number of pupils iu the institution at auy one 
me was 1«7: the lowest number. 164; the average, 169. 
The number of pupils removed to other states was seven: the 
umber moving into the state from other states was live. 
The average cost per capita for the biennial term, based on 
lily average attendances, was $419.35. 

The average salaries of teachers and employees for the bienal 
term was f 23.77.'?. 17. 

The number of deaf and dumb children in the state uot in 
hool under twenty-one years of age. by the census of 1900. is 
;arlv 141. 

AFACITY 

The crowded condition of the institute was relieved by the 
i-upaney of the new building March 1. 1900. Our present 

iiildinga will comfortably accommodate 1*00 pupils, viz.. 190 
ales and 80 females. 

Two pupils were so benefited in their sj»eech as to be allowed 
enter the public schools. The number of graduates was two. </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
418 

LAND COMMISSIONERS KEPOBT. 

ESTIMATES 

Of ti\e amount of appropriations Thar will be 

needed for the 

proper maintenance of all 

departnif 

of 

the 

institution 

¦nts 

for the years 1901 1902. 

•Superintendent |3,600 On 

Matron 800 00 

T&lt; aehei-s 26,200 00 

Employees •. 8,000 00 

Fuel and light 8.000 00 

Board and clothing 

17.000 00 

Supplies for industries 

2.000 00 

Furniture ami bedding 

I'.IMIII DO 

Bowks and stationery 

i.ooo no 

Telephone 

300 00 

Repairs find improvements 

2.000 Oft 

Incidentals 

500 00 

Paints, oils, and "la 

.00 01 ? 

Drags and medicine 

too oo 

Horses, wagon, feed, harness, et 

SI HI (Ml 

Postage and expense 

::on 00 

«73.800 on 

Extrao 

I in 

i 

a 

Fitriiiys fur hospital 
Fire protection . . . 

|2»Mt 00 
s.ooo on 
I.ooo oo 
500 00 
200 00 

fold storage plant 
Typewriters 

Greenhouse 

Fruit, ornamental trees and shrul 
Ridewalks 

100 HO 

500 On 

Gymnasium and equipment . 
Water supply and connections 

i. nini On 

1.200 00 

•«17.7.-)0 00 

Dcficifn 

i 

Employees' wajres 
Fuel and lights . . 
Board and clothing 

11.000 00 

Tun Ot) 
2.000 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
419 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Supplies for industries * 100 

Books and stationery • 150 00 

¦'mi (V) 
Repairs and improvements " w w 

50 00 

Incidentals 

1,781 32 

New dynamo and repairs 

New school building: 343 17 

f6.324 49 

&gt;MPARATI VE STATKM BNT 

Showing amount of appropriations for all departments of the 
institute for the biennial term ending November 30, 1900, 
and the amount of estimates submitted for the years 1901- 

liHi: 

De- 

Appro- Esti- In- Deriations. 
mates. creasf. erease- 

pnations. mites. create. 

Superintendent f3,6OO $3,800 

Superintendent 
Matron 

Matron 890 *M 

Tea.hei-8 25,000 2B.200 1.200 

Teache 

Emplovees' wa-es 6,000 *M&lt;&gt; -'.000 

Fuel and lights 7,000 8,000 1.0&lt;K» 

RiMni :m.l rlothinc 16.000 17.000 1.00Q 

id and clothing 

plies for industries 1.500 2.000 500 

Furniture and bedding 1.250 2,000 750 

800 1.000 200 

intl stationery 

((hone and telegraph.... 240 :'&gt;00 60 - 

800 2.000 1.200 
200 500 300 

•airs and improvements 
iilt'iitals 

500 500 

ind glass 

:?00 300 

mil mt'dicint 

1. harne 

\\ a 

800 800 

:;oo 300 

ige and expr* 

1WJ2.390 S73.300 flO.010 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
420 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S BEPORT. 

Extraordinary, 

Appro- Esti- In- De 

priation-. 

mates. crease. crease 

Water supply and connections $1,000 $1,200 |200 

Fittings for hospital 200 200 

Fire protection 5,000 5,000 

v 

Typewriters 500 500 

Cold storage plant 1,000 1,000 

Greenhouse 250 250 

Fruit, ornamental trees and 

shrubs 100 100 

Sidewalks 500 500 

Gymnasium and equipment 9,000 9,000 

New dynamo 6,000 6,000 

New school building 25,000 25,000 

Boiler, engine, pump and 

coal house 7,700 7,70&lt; 

139.700 |17,750 #16,750 $38,700 

S16J50 

Total decrease $21,950 </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
421 

INSTITtTE FOB THB DEAF AND DUMB. 

¦* i rl 

aaas(«g psiBmiisa 

§ § S2£ 3 

oo 

1061 'IE RM«W 

ainuspijaa pwnwsa 

«. 

a 

T 


«» 

5? S S S S 5 5 S 3 s - 1 1 8 1 5? 

ti 

t» 

&gt; 

§SSSS§SSS§SSSS8 S 

Siiiiiiiiiiilii 1 

«¦ 

I &lt;- 

S8«SS3?sSSo« p» 

81 suoi»«udojddv . gg;£rg8?S3'"'£S 5 
8681 'I Jaqraao»a S§ 55» g 

-T 

5 

«• 

3 

B 

¦ : : ¦ b.s 

* b : 1 8 : : * 

s 


5 it 

o'ss.-gSSjgJeSs.l-si 
Ilillllililllli 

1061 'l£ q««W 

5. LI 

© o — w i 
1 8 |2 | 

! g§ 

SSSRSSSISSSSS Z B 
&lt;X)6I 'I Jaqtn»a»a 9lCOX x&lt;sconf -«• - « «: 
«•« - I* 

8^5SSSSSS=^2?SS 8 

gSiSSSoSSSiSsSSS S 

»s 

"S" 1 "**]!!?? </seg>


            <seg id="p012">
422 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

CHANGES IN THE BOARD. 

The term of Dr. A. Hugh Hippie, of Omaha, as a member o 
the Board expired May 15, 1900, and Chas. Nownes, of Papillior 
was appointed to the position June 1. 1900. 

We submit appended hereto, as* a part of this report, the re 
port of the physician giving the hygienic condition of the insti 
rute: also the report of the superintendent, giving full and de 
tailed information as to the progress, present condition, am 
needs of the school. 

It is gratifying to note the advancement made and the rapidh 
increasing recognition of the institute and its possibilities ii 
behalf of the deaf and dumb both at home and abroad. It i: 
also gratifying to state that this appreciation of the work of th* 
Institute has served as an incentive to greater effort, not only oi 
the part of officers and teachers, but all connected with th&lt; 
school in whatever capacity, and kindled a desire to have in Ne 
braska not one of the best institutions for the education of th( 
deaf and dumb but ///*• beat. Every effort being made to increase 
efficiency to the fullest extent compatable with the means place&lt; 
at our disposal. 

ACKXOWI.EIHi.MEN 

In closing this report we desire to express our appreciatior 
of the cordial support and encouragement rendered the Boarc 
by Governor Poynter in every effort made in behalf of an 
economical and business-like management of the institution, an.1 
to Superintendent Dawes for the kind and uniform courtesy ex 
tended to us at all times in the discharge of our duty, and tr 
Steward Sievera for the many acts of kindness and aid rendered 
the Board in its work. 

Respect fill lv 

submitted 

J. J. Cardwi 
B. F. Allen. 

Chas. Nownes, 
Board of Tru </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
423 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AXI&gt; DUMB. 

1 

PHYSICIANS KKI'ORT. 

Gentlemen — It is gratifying to note a marked diminution in 
lie amount of illness during the two years just closed. 

Chicken-pox is the only contagion* disease that has come 
imong us. and lias caused no anxietv of course. 

Ii gives me pleasure to report that the sanitary arrangements 
ive been and are in most excellent condition. 

In 1NWI, directly after leaving his home in I'lattsmouth, Willie 
Harrington came to the hospital with -walking typhoid" and had 
nearly recovered, when suddenly he suffered perforation of the 
dowels, with death following in a few hours, on November 8, 

1S!)!&gt; 

November 11. Hurt l'ilsbury was taken with appendicitis, a 

second attack, and for safety in operation was removed to Imniannel 
Hospital, in care of I&gt;r. B. B. Davis. An operation was 
successful a few days later, ending in a permanent cure. Ethel 
Batten bandaged her own finger in carbolic acid on retiring at 
night : so long a time passed before it could be known, most of 
the finger was destroyed and an amputation was necessary. This 
was done by l»r. B. B. Davis at Inimanuel Hospital. Three cases 

of rheumatism and several of lung fever are all the cases of 
severe illness of that year. Miss Hall, the nurse, has given the 
minute record. » 

One of the greatest needs of our school is a department for 
physical culture. It is always useful to growing children in 
keeping them strong and well, and also in calling out energies 
that migh( never appear but for something to call them forth. 
Nothing is more painful than the hours out of schoolroom spent 
in aimless waiting about, when the best of supervisors is often 

her wit's end to furnish recreation for the growing boy or 

girl. Well directed play for the smaller pupils, games, with various 
physical drill and exercise, varied according to age and vigor 
are becoming an acknowledged essential in the development of 
youth, and especially so with youth that are in any way defective 

!'&lt;• tht' Honorable Board of Trustees: </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
424 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

as in hearing, which hinders so much the natural process of 
mental and physical growth. A physical department with a gym 
nasiuni would add very much to the power of our unfortunate 
hoys and girls and to the good our institution could accomplish 
for them. 

A bright, clean second story in the small cottage for hospital 
purposes is an acquisition worthy of note. With heat for use at 
night, would render it quite complete. I have not continued the 
instruction in physiology during the present year. 

Dr. S. R. Towne, Physician. 

REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT. 

To the Honorable Board of Trustees: 

Gentlemen — In submitting this, the twelfth biennial report 
of this institution for the time beginning December 1, 1898, 
and ending November 30, 1900, I wish to state that harmony and 
good will have prevailed throughout the institution, and much 
excellent work has been accomplished. A vigorous effort has 
been made to realize the ideal of the school and to surround the 
pupils with those influences that shall tend to produce in them 
a healthy growth of moral sentiment, leading them to respect 
the rights of others as well as their own. 

The school work has been thoroughly organized and graded, 
and a record is kept of the standing and grade of each child. 
The state course of instruction and system of records have been 
adopted and are in use. One great advantage of using the same 
course and system used throughout the state is that every one 
is familiar with these and readily understands the conditions 
when told the grade of the child. It has also aroused an ambition 
among the children to keep up with their classes, which has had 
a wholesome effect upon the disposition and conduct of all the 
school work. 

Our new buildings have added much to our comfort and convenience. 
They are each well adapted for the purpose for w hich 
they were constructed. The schoolhouse is of pressed brick </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
425 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

nd s. me. whh slate roof, and fitted with inside and outside 

ire escapes. The inside finish is of hard wall plaster, and the 
rikmI work is hard pine, maple, and oak, finished with oil in 
he natural color of the wood. Each of the fourteen schoolrooms 
s provided with wall slates on all sides of, the room, and two feet 

slating above the wall slates for display purposes or exhibit 

&gt;f permanent work. Each room is furnished with a roll top 
iesk and a revolving chair for the teachers' use. 

The i-bapel, located on the third floor, is a large commodious 
room having a seating capacity of about four hundred. The 
platform is fitted with foot-lights and double doors in the rear, 
which make it a very desirable place for our religious, social, 
and society meetings as well as for amateur plays and pantomime 
performances. 

The boiler, engine, and pump house is so planned and arranged 
that the coal does not have to be put in wheelbarrows to be 
brought to the furnace. The fireman does not have to leave the 
building to weigh the coal. The boilers are so placed that the 
engineer can go entirely around them and inspect the settings 
so as to be sure at all times that they are in perfect condition. 
Two of the boilers are fitted with American stokers. These 

atomatic feed machines are giving splendid satisfaction, because 

their economy in the consumption of fuel. The fuel is "fed 

underneath the fire, which insures complete consumption of 

¦mbustible substances in the coal. 

In overhauling the steam heating and lighting systems they 
were found to be in much worse condition than the expert examination 
indicated. The electric wiring was entirely renewed 
and a new ( 'rocker-Wheeler dynamo, with a capacity of four 
hundred lights, was secured. The old dynamo, is now used as 

a motor and furnishes the power for our laundry and manual 
training department. The steam heating system in the main 
building and small cottage was entirely renewed, using such of 
the old pipe and fittings as weiie fit to be used. The appropria- 

tion -for this work was not equal to the estimates made, and, in 
addition to the plant being in a much worse condition than 
estimated, the price of pipe and fittings advanced, in some cases </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
426 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

as much as :i(M» per cent, making it impossible to complete this 
work and keep within the appropriation. After the work was 
planned and begun it could not be left half finished. Therefore, 
I am obliged to report a deficiency in the general and special 
repair funds: for the details see the financial part of this report. 
The radiation in the large cottage was not changed, but new 
connections were made so that the warming of the building 
can be better done than heretofore; but the system in this build 
ing should, within the near future, be overhauled and reconstructed 
in accordance with up-to-date ideas of steam heating. 
In the new system of heating all the exhaust from all the pumps 
and engines (six pumps and two enginesi is returned to the heating 
system. After the steam has furnished the power required 
it is used to heat the buildings and the condensation is returned, 
hot, to the boilers through an automatic receiver aud pump. 
This is much greater economy than throwing the exhaust our 
doors, thereby wasting both heat and hot water. 

There will also be a deficiency of about $1,000 in the fund fo 
employees' wages: this is due to the increased amount of labo 
required because of the new buildings. In addition to the ear 
of the buildings, the yard and grounds were left in bad cor 
dition and had to be cleaned up and new lawns made. 

EXHIBITS 

In the spring of 1890 we were invited to prepare a small schoo 
exhibit to be sent, with other exhibits from America, to the ex 
position at Paris. We accepted the invitation and sent an ex 
hibit which was representative of all departments of the school 
The international jury of awards gave us the silver medal foi 
educational work among defectives, and asked that an articW 
be prepared on the origin, growth, scope, and results of our worl 
among defectives, to be used by the secretary in his report t«' 

the French government. The article has been prepared and sen 
as requested. 

At the Nebraska state fair and exposition held at Littcolr 
August 31 to September 7. 1900. we made a full and complete 
exhibition of our school work, except the work in articulation </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
427 

INSTITUTE KOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

and lip reading, which cannot be exhibited without the pupil 
being present. I'pon this exhibit we received twenty-eight first 
and ten second premiums. These results are extremely gratifying 
and encouraging, in that our work was placed in direct comparison 
and competition with the work done in the schools for 
the hearing. We endeavor to teach our children that in the 
struggle for a living they must do their work better than can 
be done by any one else in order that they may succeed. Nothing 
but the very best can be accepted by their teacher in any 
department. Not the best that the child can do, but the best 
that can be done, is the criterion by which our work must be 
judged. Perfection is the ideal that we hold before these children, 
and perfection must be the ideal for which they strive if 
they win in the comj)etitive struggle of life. 

METHODS OF INSTRUCTION 

riic methods of instruction remain as in the past. Speech 

is given to al that are able to profit by such teaching. Learning 
to talk is one of the hardest tasks that the deaf child undertakes, 
and those only succeed who have great perseverance, 
patience, and energy. While much depends upon the teacher 
the child is not exempt from his or her share of the responsibility. 
There must be a union of desire, determination, and effort in 
order that the best results may be accomplished. Given a child 
with a desire to learn to talk, and with sufficient energy to 
enable him to do the work required, and a fair speaker will be 
produced: but if there is indifference instead of determination, 
carelessness instead of practice, little or no satisfactory results 
will be obtained. 

The work in the various schoolrooms continues to be in some 
form of English, the sign language being used only when necessary 
for the child to get a clear understanding of the English 
used. The rule governing the use of the English language is 
¦that it must be used ar all times and under all circumstances 

where it is possible for the child to get a clear understanding 

of the instruction given and the information conveyed. In this 
way the child gets manv lessons in English outside of those </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
LAND COMMISSIoNKlt's REPORT. 

428 

taught in the schoolroom and finds practical use for his new 
language. It is regarded as evidence of marked improvement 
when a child desires to express his daily wants in the English 
l-ather than the sign language. 

BEPHESENTATIVKS IN COI.LE 

Two of our graduates are attending the National College for 
the Deaf at Washington, D. ('.. Miss Effie Goslin. of Lancaster 
county, class of ninety eight, and Miss Emma Morse of Boone 
county, class of ninety-nine, are the two representatives. They 
report that they are doing well, and we hope that they will be 
able to complete the college course and redeem Nebraska from 
its unenviable position of having no graduates from the College 
for the Deaf. It is believed that with a continuation of the 
present course of study and the thoroughly competent corps of 
teachers we shall continue to turn out graduates of this school 
thoroughly fitted and trained to receive a higher, or college edu 
cation. 

The members of the class in the eighth grade, which will 
graduate in 1902, are strongly imbued with a desire to take a 
full college course. They are putting forth every effort to master 
the work laid out. and their enthusiasm reflects beneficially on 
all the lower &lt;•! asses. 

TYPKWKITKl 

Through the kindness of the state senate we have been able 
to have one typewriter in use in the schoolroom during the past 
bienniuin. Its use corroborates all that has been said heretofore 
in reference to the advantages of the machine in the study 
of the English language. Desire, effort, and use are stimulated 
bv the machine. A thousand dollars could be wisely spent in 

the purchase of typewriting machines to be used in the more 
advanced classes. It is false economy to withhold from these 
children anything that will aid them in their mastery of the English 
language. The use of the machine would be more economi : 
cal than the use of pencils, paper, and slates. Time would also 
be economized as much greater speed can be obtained by the 
use of the machines than with pencils. All the arguments are </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
429 

INSTITUTE FOR THE UEAF AND DUMB. 

in favor of its use. and there are nuiie against it. Machines are 
being introduced into niany of the common public schools of 
this and other states. All the aids required by the hearing 

child in the study of the English language are absolutely essen 
rial for the deaf child. 

YMXAS1U.U 

Physical culture and development have been encouraged in 
every way jM&gt;ssible. Both boys and girls have formed athletic 
associations. These clubs meet regularly for practice and drill, 

each member buying his or her own equipment and contributing 
voluntarily to a fund for the use of the club. These funds are 
also contributed to by the officers and teachers of the school. 
These enterprises should be encouraged by the erection and 
furnishing of an up-to-date gymnasium and the employment 
of a thoroughly competent physical director. A building 
adapted to our use could be constructed and furnished at a 
cost of WMHHI. I'hysical culture is as important as intellectual 
and moral: in fact each is more successfully accomplished if 
the other two are well developed. 

I.D STORAGE PLANT. 

An ice-house or cold storage plant of sufficient capacity to hold 
a years supply of ice and a few weeks' supply of vegetables and 
such meats as might be desirable to have on hand would be an 
economical investment for the state. Nearly as much is paid 

out for ice each year as such a 
building could be built at a cost 

structure would cost. Such a 
not to exceed $1,000. and with 
many years. The old ice box. 
kitchen, is in no way adapted 
not economical in the care of 
to make it satisfactory. This 

proper care should last a great 
built in the basement under Xht 

the use required of it. It is 

ind cannot be repaired so a 

should be torn out and a properly constructed refrigerator substituted 
in its place. This could l&gt;e done at a cost not to exceeed 
SWK). and should be done even if the cost were greater than that 

lollllt </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
430 

LAND COMMISSIONER^ REPORT. 

children's accounts. 

The book of children's accounts, left by the former superintendent, 
shows a total balance due these children of $283.41. 
These claims were presented to the claims committee of the 
last legislature and a request made that they recommend an 
appropriation for the amount due. to be paid to a trustee, and 
by him distributed to the parents and children. No action was 
taken by that committee in reference to these claims. I do not 
know that the state would be liable for these losses, but the 
children certainly should not lose the money. They had confidence 
in the agent of the state and that confidence should not 
have been betrayed. Many of them come from poor families 
who cannot afford to suffer this loss. The items are too small 
to be worth litigation even if a judgment could be collected. 
Notwithstanding the fact that there may be no legal claim 
against the state I would recommend an appropriation to reimburse 
these children for the losses sustained and that the state 
proceed to collect from the former superintendent and his bondsmen, 
if .he had any, the amount of these items. Appended hereto 
is a list of the names and amounts due as shown by the book 
marked "&lt; 'liildren's Accounts Ledger No. 2." 

Amounts due as per ledger 1897 

Helen Oliver 

e 

. . *1 so 

( 'heater Higby 

#:{ 01 

Fritz Dunker 

. . 1 Ttl 

Likv Foy 

5 25 

Cora Pillard 

. . 4 67 

.John and Hy. McFadden 

114 

Ethel Lloyd 

4(1 

Willie Stickler 

1 41 

.Vinelia Miller 

10 

Maude Zweiful 

2 30 

Russel Weisy 

. . 12 Mi 

Sarah Slartin 

¦2 56 

Herman and Julius 

Myrtle (rivgg 

4 48 

• Plenz 

. . 4 ."il 

Arthur Nelson 

1 41 

Stover Bros 

.'.a 

Tat Regan 

06 

Glen Smith 

. . 1 67 

Win. Shold 

17 

Richard Biiifihain . . 

&lt;).¦&gt; 

Cora French 

4 97 

Win. Harrington . . . 

21 

Pearl Tidd 

75 

John Kubat 

... 4 4:t 

Walter Donahue 

•2 00 

Orvina Johnson 

74 

Fred Wendell 

0 20 

Isaac Witwer 

. . 5 10 

Josie Anderson 

:{ :\8 </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
431 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Earl Warren 
Marr Dineson 

tO 55 

( ha*. Brouhard |4 24 

1 7C 

(leo. Hansen 5 21 

Eugene Hogle 
Helen Me* 'did 
Pauline Hand 
•Inliii Marek . 
Edward (Jilson 
Harrv Ivarr . . 

6 30 

Shirley Parlette ....:.. 2 17 

•28 

Miner l&gt;avis 4 10 

ii :,r, 

Certrude Trissell 2 81 

1 20 

I 'lam l&gt;iiiii-ansiiii 2 45 

I 'heyeuue ( 'ounty 7 50 

!U 

n 4 

Earnest Whited 1 55 

Bel gum Hoys . 
Eddie Brohard 

04 

Petersen girls 16 

4 .")(» 

Poor fund 65 

?rin Thavei 

.11 

Adolph Lamm 50 

Ira Kouderbush 

10 44 

Patterson children 3 45 

Kalph Coniiell 

05 

05 

Erne Goslin 1 35 

M. Stillalian 19 

1!l 

Forell children 1 16 

Zilia (tanian 5 'Mi 

Lenora Menu 30 71 

Austin Beetle '.i 35 

ustin Beegl 

Emma Morae 05 

&gt; 

Alexander Miller 1 45 

Vlexauder Millci 

1 45 

Mary Delaney 23 48 

A. I&gt;. Strain &lt;MJ 
Old accounts transferred fri 

mi 

sfprred from ledger Xo. 1 and shown on 

pages 470 and 471 of ledger No 

Mr. -lames Cain $0 54 

Harrv Mercer $0 50 

Lenora Xeedlow :! 25 

Elizabeth Young 62 

i 'lias. Bronhard •"&gt; 00 

IHI 

Marv Hedrick 1 18 

Marv Heddrid \3 

i:; 
45 

lord Khilev 54 

\Ven&lt;-il Clier 45 

Michael Everts 78 

Edward Sietcit ."! 00 

William Martin 10 

ward S 

tleuiiif McDonald !) :{(l 

Mary Burns !)2 

Elizabeth tiiasnichlans. '1 00 

Kdgerton girls 1(1 04 

Myrtle Kistler ."&gt; 33 

Mvrtle K 

hiva Barker 25 

Marv Lcacli :!1 

Wornie Hall 03 

Jolin Moore 5 00 

John M 

t*ii y Peters 2 40 

lVarl I'arker 2.T 

Louie McBride 59 

til 1'ai 

Walt, i- K-an (.40 

E-ran 

Fred Morris 42 

Marv Henry '.',2 

Marv H&lt; 

Willie Chambers 1 75 

•lames ( 'ain 1 (14 

Lenora Xeedlow 20 

lames ( 

Minnie McKay 70 

Edward Allen 20 

in ru 

Ernst 4 31 

Keliustrow 

r.r&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
432 

LAM' 

o.UMISSIoNEU S 

KEI'OK 

COOKING SCHOOL. 

The economical land healthful preparation of food for 

The economical iand healthful preparation of food for huiua 

consumption is both a science and an art. &lt; &gt;ur girls sh&lt;i 

consumption is both a science and an art. Our girls should I* 

taught how and what to buy. how to prepare and serve ec 

taught how and what to buy. how to prepare and serve econoin 

cally and scientifically the best and most nutritious 

cally and scientifically the best and most nutritious food 

Our school is too small in numbers to warrant the emplt 

«_&gt;ur school is too small in numbers to warrant the einploymen 

&lt;»f an instructor in cooking with no other duties than thost 

&gt;f an instructor in cooking with no other duties than those in tli 

• lass room. If a thoroughly trained and coni|&gt;etent scientit 

lass room. If a thoroughly trained and competent scientiti 

were to be employed, the state should receive the benefit 

¦were to be employed, the state should receive the benefit in tli 
preparation of food for these children. 1 believe that it woul 

preparation of food for these children. I believe that it 

J&gt;e wise to employ a scientific cook, to have charge not &lt; 

J&gt;e wise to employ a scientific cook, to have charge n 

The instruction given to the girls in cooking, but to In- i 

The instruction given to the girls in cooking, but t&lt; 

11 

«ble for the preparation and serving of all the food con 

ble for the preparation and serving of all the food consume* 

in the institution, flu- other hired cooks doing their work 

li the institution, the other hired cooks doing their work und 

her direction. If one-half that is claimed ran be sax 

ier direction. If one-half that is claimed , 
uientitic preparation of food, there would ht 

scientific preparation of food. There would be a saving 

amount equal to or greater than the salary of the s,- 

amount equal to or greater than the salai 

cook, and. in addition to the economy, many of our girl 

»ok, and. in addition 

onomv. mam 

perhaps some of the boys, would receive needed iustr 

Perhaps some of the boys, would receive ueede 

knowledge of the means of livelihood as cooks and waitei 

iuowledge of the means of livelihood as cooks and \\ 

«&gt;ur food would be prepared in a more wholesome and he; 

&gt;ur food would be prepared in 

a in. 

manner. 
In making this recommendation for a change in the do 

janner. 

n tor a 

department and the establishment of a cooking school 

lepartiuent and the establishment of a cooking scho 

not wish you to think that I am criticising tin- work d 

not wish you tit think that I am criticising the work do 

present in this department. It is all that can be expected 

.resent in this department. It is all that can be expected und 

this system. In fact there is greater harmony in supt-i 

reater ha nn o 

and more economy in the preparation ot food than vv&lt; 

lid more economy in the j 

ever had before. It is the system that should be ch 

ver had before. It is the system that should be chang 

With slight modifications and rearrangement of the room 

With slight modifications an 

rearrangemei 

used lor kitchen and storage supplies this work could I 

aseri tor kitchen and storage supplies this w&lt; 

in operation without additional space, except the fitting 

n operation without additional space, except th&lt;- fitting u| 

a class room in the industrial building and the construct 

class room in The industrial building and The const 

purchase of an oven larsre en.muli for bakimr our own In 

m </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
433 

THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

(R 

i 

X3TITI 

L'RINTINt; 

- n.ed of new presses, stone, and type in the printing office 

ipparent and has been brought to your attention before. The 

wspaper sent out by the school is. in some respects, the only 

•tion and acquaintance that the public has with the 
In order that the showing may be equal to the work 

ne tin- material should always be in good order. It is dil 
u-agiiig to teacher and pupils to have a good job of "settiu 

p" spoiled with poor type and press. I would earnestly urgt 

moderation the needs of this department. The 

VI 

of the teacher is hereto appended and his recommenda 
uid requests endorsed as being the only means by which 

»iv results can be produced. 

vlkM'Knt H. K. Dawes: 1 took charge of the printi 

texkext H. E. Dawks: 1 took charge of the printing 

nice at the beginning of the school year, commencing October 

the beginning of the school year, commencing Octo' 
I could find no record of the work accomplished by 

18!t!t. I could find no record of the work accomplished by my 

edecessor. nor anv outline or course of instruction used by 

sor. nor any outline or course of instruction used 

Che first few months were spent in determining how far 

le tirsi few months were spent in determining how 

need the different pupils were in the art of printing aud 

1 the different pupils were in the art of printing ; 

n perfecting an outline for a systematic course of study. Th 

¦tiu&gt;; an outline for a systematic course of study, 

•nditioii of the material in the office is simply deplorable. The 

i of the material in the office is simply deplorable, 

ws tvpe is all verv old. with the face battered and broken. 

pe is all very old, with the face battered and brol 

d filled wiih hardened ink. We have attempted to print a 

d wiih hardened ink. We have attempted to prill 

ich month. The Nebraska Mute Journal, which ha 

inth. The Nebraska Mute Journal, which has a 

on of about tilMi. The first year this paper was prii 

of about ti(Mi. The first year this paper was printed 

ix-coliinui folio on a Prouty news press. The second yeai 

-column folio on a Prouty news press. The second ,\ 

Prouty press tailed us. and so far this year it has beeu 

uty press tailed us. and so far this year it has I 
as an eight and tell page paper on a small 7x11 

printed as an eight and ten page paper on a small 7xH job 

I'i 

oli department is in as poor, if not a worse, condi 

two fonts of type alike, let 

wsi.apei 

alone a full series, in the entire office, with the exception of 

few fonts purchased when I first took chat 

:! 

\ 

u pupils, it being tilt 

trade for the most of them. This veai 

averaging about fourteen years of age. Hesidt </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
434 

AMI CUMMIKKIONEK S UEl'O 


printing the paper, we have printed all circulars, blanks, rej 

cards, luiteheads. letterheads, programs, — in fact all printed mat 

ter used by and at the school. No outside work has been 
solicited. Our efforts have been directed to teaching the relative 

importance of lines to be displayed rather than the amount 

work accomplished 

A\ e are introducing and attempting to follow a 

course of studv. We have made a special effi 

use and meaninj 
and editor's t vim 

rms and the use of proofread* 

The otti 

type. Th 

\\ 

\ 

box." M 

•ttice ai 

beitt 

the otti 

tion tl 

few v&lt; 

1 I 

hul 
just 

beter advantages, onlv to uk'cX w 

Ulllllll 1 

\Y. X. I'axthn. T« 

11 

HOT 

The reciuests of i lie instructor in charge of 

timely and practical. This work is directly a trade school, and 
with from two to live years' instruction these bovs are able to 

ticallv learn 1 1 1* • trade iiiu-v 

Hi'spi-ctt nil v </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
435 

IE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

in any community. The cost of equipment 

what will he made in the manual training 

.lepartnit 

very great and should be provided. The re- 

ort i&gt;f the teacher follows: 
Sri'KKixTK.viiKXT H. E. Dawes : &lt;)c 

H. E. Dawks: October 15th marks the he- 

inning of i lit- fuurtii year of this dr\ 

year of this department, which has been 

i my charge since the opening. Woi 

arge since the opening. Work has been taught as far 

&lt; tools and material would permit. 

would permit. We should have a good 

¦wing machine, a good stock of leathi 

•d stock (if leather, a few dies and cutting 

wn 

mis. We could then turn out new ! 

Hd then turn out new shoes for the pupils at a 

ist of about si' in- &gt;f^.lT) that would &lt; 

that would outwear anv $5 shoe that 

mild Ik- purchased; at The same time 

1: at the same time we could take the uppers 

t' old shoes and reconstruct a new si 

onstruct a new shoe for about $1.25. This 

mild save money for the pupils and al 

pils and at the same time give much 

oik t&lt;n- i hi- ¦ hiss in shoeiuakinjr and 

making and allow me to increase the 

umber 'it pupils and irive rlie oldei 

dents just the work 

ie\ sIhuiIi! now lit- doinii. I Mli-inji the 

w In- doing, huring I he past year, boys who have 

ci u in i his depart incut for about iwe 

department for about twentv-two months, and who 

ave iii-vci 1 before received any insirin 

uring. or 

lakinj;'. turned out as jrood work in t 

tod work in the repairing line as could 

c tumid in i he lit \ . Three boys fron 

iss found employ 

i'-ni at iliis trade iluiin^ vacation. 
\\iili .1 larger anioimi of money a 

il.i 

u.\ our jeailier and shoe findings 

coi!omi/.( in expenditures. All nieni 

the class can do&gt; 

iu;!;.'on ;¦ i^iirini: and three can do e 
¦| airing tor i!ie officers and ]iu|&gt;ils 

hree can do extra tine work. All shoe 

pils has been done here: also 

arness mi ndiuj;. foot and base ball 

pairing, l'upils have 

een saved at least $125 during the 

&lt;l'2o during the past eighteen months on 

heir shoe repairing bills, as they ha 

have been charged onlv for 

ie matt rial used. Since the last re 

•port there have been 475 

airs of shoes repaired, also two cor 

rk soles shoes were made 

w 

&gt;r a cripple. One of these shoes, if 1 

if turned out by a city shoe- 

taker, would cost between *o and *T. 

S..i 

ing the winter the manual training depart- 

ii t t-xpects to make ten new single oak benches with locks 

inri drawers: then I hope to inaugurate a new and up-to-date </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
436 

A 

system of caring for tools. This fall all the names of diffe 

tools and material used have been taught. 

I am doing all that 1 can to teach the boys the business meth 

ods of running a good shop and how to best serve the public, for 

if the pupils I have continue at this trade and open shops in 
small towns they are sure to make a very respectable living 
Following I give a course of study which I have adooted and 

adopted and 

will follow as far as practicable with what tool* 

are now at 

hand. If in the near future the facilities of thi 

are increased, it can be carried 

out in full 

First Tear 

1. Names of tools and their uses 
2. Sharpening knives. 
3. Making wax .-mis. 

4. Harness repairing 
3. Plain cobbling. 

6. Mecliai 

and drawin 

Handle with la 

nd left 

S. General work 

ond Year 

s. 

1. Names of tools and parts of shoe 

Making buttonholes. 
Punching evelet hoi 

i. Setting eyelet studs and hool 
5. Practice on button fastening t 

tening machin 

Continue drawing 

Half-soling, heeling, trimming, and burnishing 

S. Shoe dressing 
0. General work 

Third Year — 

1. Learning uaiu 

?rything used 

\ 

2. Continue drawing 
3. Invisible patching 

4. Neat cobbling 

5. Bottoms, burnishing, I 

uffiing and channe 

work. 

••. Dieing heels 

7. Heel building and shoe dressing 
S. General work. 

department </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
437 

NST1TTTI 

R THE DEAF AXD DUMB. 

ii-th Year — 

Names of tools and I 

kinds of leather. 

itinue drawing. 

Machine practice 

+. Cutting parts of insole, counters, and outsole. 

Hand-sewed turned 
Finishing. 

rk and trimming 

Wl. 

v .Mending and genei 
th Year — 

.il 

work. 

&lt; 'ontinue drawing. 

I se of all machines. 
Foot measuring. 

I. 

Pattern measuring. 
Fitting uppers. 

&lt; fitting and lasting. 

Names of parts of a pattern. 
.Making a complete shoe. 
&lt; leneral work. 

continued sueces 

in this department 

Respectfully submitted. 

L. M. Hunt, Instructor. 

iVIN'G DEPARTMENT 

ist report this department has been organ 

l&gt;ittkult lasting. 

ed and graded; it is now conducted as a school. The course of 

&lt;M 

"inly and the instruction given are planned after the work of 

le Pratt Institute at Brooklyn. This has proven to be a vast im- 

i-oveinent over the old method of instructing by imitation. 

1 believe rliis is the only school in the state where scientific 

istrnction in sewing is given. 

The depaitmeni is well equipped and needs only the usual 

lpply nf niiiterial and findings to continue the work. 

I would also call your attention to an essay by Miss Mary 

mrha. un.- nf rhe pupils in the school of sewing, on the subject 

How 1 Made My Skirt." This will give you an idea of the 

nglish Language required and the kind of practical instruction </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
438 

LAX 

MM I 

NEI 

REI 

given in this department. This pu] 
second grade. 

\ clas 

Hmr I ]f,itl&lt; \h t sk 

I got six yards of cambric 

tnl 

seven yards of lace .-d tf injr. Measure rh,- waist, hip and leng 

The length is forty-five inches for my skirt, hen, two in, 

three tucks one-eighth inch, and one tuck one-fourth inch. Mea 

ure on the paper according 

,..,... ,,....,,,,,,^ ,,, ,,,,. uinip ,„ measurements wh 

mark flu- waist, hip and length, and ,ui out rhe front side a 

mark the waist, hip and length, and ,-ni out the front side ai 

back gores. Tear the selvedge threads off the width of clo 

back gores. Tear the selved"- 

III -i-ai 

lit- width of 

because ir would shrink after washing Fold one width of , 

because it would shrink after washing. Fold om . w id 

\\ 

cloth, pla.ed the front gore pattern nn the fold lai straight 

cloth, placed the front gore pa 

" on the fold lai straigh 

fold 

fore effing it on*. Put tb e side -ore pattern on the edge 

fore cutting it on*. Put 

1^ 

another width 

another width of Hoth. and ,ut it out. then put tl ,,. , n t 

T} ther sili " " f r1 "- "am.- width of doll, and ,-nt on the h f 

the other sid. of rh,- same width of dotli and en 

]s a straight width. Has,,, the sea.us of the front, side and In 

i straight widt 

gor,-s. stit.h then, straight, over.as, both of edges togeth 

HV8. Stit.ll til 

Turned the he,,, two inches on the bottom of the skirt" T. 

Turned the hem two 
eight indies down ii 

eight in.hes down in the ,-enter of the ba.k width pla.k 

turned 1 in,h hem. Make a gusse,. ,,„, „„. ri gh, angle corner 

turned 1 inch hem. Make a gusset. | 
the corner of the nla.kpt ( &gt;v..,l,..., 

the corner of the pJa.ket. Overhand i, half way. turn i, do, 

kel. ( &gt;\ 

on the wrong side and hen,. On,, ai „,. .,,.,„• W1 , ]tll of skjrt 

on the wrong side and hem. &lt;&gt; n ,e and 

allowed for the ruffle. Tear off number of widths required f 

allowed for the ruffle. Tear off numb, 
this measure and stitch them togethei 

thts measure and stit.h then, together. The rule for the u, 

i8 twi.e the width of nirk required plus , he spa.e between . 

is twice the width of nick required pi 

\\ 

t.n-ks. Sewed insertion between .he .lusters of tu.ks in t 

tucks. Sewed insertion between the , lusters of tn 

ruffle overhand stit.h. Divide the la.e edging ruffle into fo 

ruffle overhand stitch. Divide .he lac edging ruffle into f 

quarters before gathering it. 1'u, the gathers of the la.e edgi, 

quarters before gathering it. I'm rh&lt; 

under the one-fourth in.-h tu.k. stit.h i, straight near the ed 

under the one-fourth inch tuck, stitch i, straight near the ed 

of the tuck on the right side. Divide the ,-loth of the ruffle in 

«f the tuck on the right side. Divide the doth of the r.iffl 

four ,,uarters before gathering and stroke verv tine and eve 

Measure ,!„¦ ruffle on ,1,, foundation of ,1,, ski,,, mark the .an 

Measure the ruffle on the founds) 

ion 

measure or pins. Haste one-fourth in.h lu.-k in the foundati. 

measure or pins. Haste one foui 

of the skirt and make three tu.ks one-eighth in.h Pl.n-,,1 ,1 

rnfflo others under the om-founh in.h ,,,,-k of ,!,, foundati. 

skirt. Stit.h it straight near th I.,.. .,&lt; n, i „¦ , , 

\\ </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
439 

V 

EAI 

SI 

Ml 

Tear the hand 

Is. Measure one and one-half ineh wide 

.Measure from 

next seam; 

ski it. on the 

he edije of the band, and 

igain from the first stitching. Stitch it 

ipper fold of the hand. Tinned one and 
tton and buttonhole in the back of band; 

nd with overhand stitch and make bar button 

le skirl. — 1'laced the front yoke pal 

traifjht on warp threads; this makes tht 

s. then cut it out. l'laoed the back yoke 

then cut it out. Placed the back vokt 

e edge iai on the \var|&gt; threads; this makes the hip 

i on the \var|&gt; threads: this makes the hij 

as. Four of these pieces were cut out 

Four of these pieces were cut out 

n file hip and front seams and turned on« 

hip and front seams and turned one 

11 tin- ends of yoke in rhe back, then tn 
seam one-fourth inch above the waist in 

ends of yoke in the back, then try 

-am one-fourth inch above the waist in 

i arc titled. Sometimes it is best to tak» 

are tiffed. Sometimes it is best to take 

I' the front seam. When through with tin 

the front seam. When through with the 

is. baste it a^ain. stitch them, crease fht 

baste it a^ain. stitch them, crease the 

¦ upper and under yokes together with the 
Four pieces, one inch by one and one-half 

upper and under yokes together with tin 

'our pieces, one inch by one and one-hal 

I lie tipper and under yoke for buttonholes 

he upper and under yoke for buttonholes 

kness enough for buttonholes: measure two and 

enough for buttonholes: measure two an&lt; 
I he front seam and two inches for thi 

mi the front seam and two indies for the 

bar buttonholes: they are always used in the 

r buttonholes: they are always used in th 

nd.'! wear. There were three thicknesses left for buttonholes 

ere three thicknesses left for buttonhole 
Stitch one fourth inch of the upper c.urv 

e turned in on the bottom of yoke, as w 

he skirt we made. 

MEN 

II. K. Dawks: Number of pupils enrolled. :'&gt;0 

&lt;e of study in domestic art. ten trii 
lied the first ei";ht lessons. 

\ccordii </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
440 

AMI CUMM1SSIONKR 

RKl'OKT. 

Twenty-tlnc- have finished the first grade and passed good ex 
animations. 

, Twenty have finished tlie first grade and the first nine lesson 
of the second grade, or first garment, with the same r.-sults. 

Four girls have finished the second grade and are ready foi 
the third grade work. The English and examinations are carried 

along with the work. (See course of studv.) 

Aside from the class work of two hours daily the last or third 
hour .s devoted to institution work, such as making towels table 
linen, curtains, bed linen, mending, etc. Of such work we have 
l.n.shed 458 pieces; also the mending of stockings for the 
children. 

Court* of Study in hmneiitic Art 

The hrst grade comprises instructions in all the different 
st.tches used in hand sewing including patching and darnin- 
Practice ,s given in all the various stitches upon small pieces of 
suitable material furnished by the school, also model book in 
winch these models are pasted, with a description and diagram 
of the same, which contains twenty-seven model exercises the 
pnpil receiving the model book when finished. In the remaining 
three grades the pupils are required to record in note books 

te b 

the instruction given in each lesson. 
Draughting on geometrical principl 
After the student lias satisfactorily 

sewing she is fitted to begin dressmal 

Contents of First Grade 

Methods of threading needle, making knot and u 

himbl 

Position of body and care of the eyes while sewin 
Even and uneven basting, running stitch, back s 

&gt;ack stitch, stit 

ng, combination and blanket stitch. 
Overhanding stitch on striped mat 
Method, of weaving explained. 
Turning hems by measure and hen 
Making work bag. 

French hem on damask. 
Felling. </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
T1TUTE FOB THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

441 

alk on manufacture and history of ueedle work and thimble, 
athering, stroking gathers, putting in a gusset and sewing 
bands. 

Making an apron for doll. 

Sewing on tapes, hooks and eves, and making eyelets 
Making buttonholes, blind loops, sewing buttons. 
Talk on manufacture of pins. 

Patchin 

Herrinj; bone stitch on flannel with silk. 
Talk on nature of emery and steel. 
Draughting and making flannel skirt for doll 
Hemstitching, fringing and whipping raffle. 
Square and mitered corners. 

Chain stitch and feather stitchin 
Darning on stockmet. 

Talk on cotton. 

Darning on cashmere flannel. 
Machine stitching. 

Draughting of drawers for child eight vears old. 

Material for the remaining three grades are furni 
lpils as The garments are made for themselves. 

hed 

by the 

Sewing by machim 
Exercise in tuckinu 

ion. embroidery 

ing. sewing, in 

and 

titch- 

band 

Practii 

ing drawers, skirt 

ski 

t-voke. 

rade. 

Pra. 

leasurt 

Draught, cut. and lit. and mak 
»'ut and make from pattern a &lt;•] 

¦ a niglit-dre: 
ild's dress. 

and make from pattern 

shirt-w 
Grade. 

Fourth 

The fourth grade is devoted t 

tine hand and machine 

ewing. 

(•ml Grade 

Draughting, ciittiiifr. and mal 
ml undciwaist. 

Third &lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
442 

LAND COMMISSIONEF 

REP 

i 

Cut and make from pattern a dressing sacque of striped w 
material in which stripes are matched and seams bound. 

Draught, cut. fit. and make a dress of valuable material w 
out lining. 

Draught, cut. fit. and make bv hand a baby drt 
Color lessons. ,. ... 

Minnie L. P 

DRAWING AM" VISK AH 

The work in drawing and art continues to j 

factory manner. The softening and refining influen 
study of nature and art is noticeable in tin- pupils in th 

del p 

of the work done bv the classes in the art department an&lt; 

schoolrooms for two vears. Last vear I taug 

the morning from 111 to TJ::'.(l. This vear I teach sev&lt; 

everv other dav. Monday. Wednesday, and Frid 

12:30. in freehand drawing, using small comm 

jects. and from the pictures drawn on the large slates. Whe 

certain pupil shows any talent for drawin 

given a trial in the art room 

The art class is in session Mondav. Tuesday. W 

! 

Thursday. Friday afternoons and Saturday mornings. 
The classes of last vear contained twentv-seven pin 

these were boys. The class 
Ihese are boys. Seven pupil 
class is divided into section 
the other at work in some 
next day they change about. 

f this year contains lit! 
are new beginners thi 

I 

( hie is in the room M&lt; 

i 

There are five different hi 
crayon, pen and ink. water &lt;• 
up work in charcoal first an 

ii 

Tlicr industrial rteiia 

follow up with iM*a&gt; 

ment. To make this influence as far-reaching as possible 

pictures made in the art room are hung in the buildings, \v 

they are always in view, always giving out their sik-nt inflii 

for all that is good and pure in life. The report of the instrn 

is hereto attached. 

Superintendent H. K. Hawks: 1 hand vmi herewith a re 

EN 

li 

\ c &lt; 

.Mi 

w </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
443 

ITI'TE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

w 

drawn from the 

\v ; 

&gt; 

work at the state 
to The fair for an 

I'm 

The pieces of finished 

lave more Than met our exp 
¦vork turned out of tliis depar 

uenr are equal to tlie work dune 
in the state. Boys are not only 

n any manual training school in i 
earning hand skill and how to in; 
knowledge and skill acquired giv 

make different articles, but the 

in greater self-respect 

work in their other class 

.1., 

1" 

vent in 

ike. with his own 

lands, some 1 

le of 

lit me. He begins to emerge 
&gt; one of independence just in 
in his ability to make things. 

u 

tndition of dependen 

The report of the teacher in th 

lepartment will show more of 
died and The needs for future 

he details of The work accompli 

levelopment 

l'he appropriation made by the 
tment To equip itself with enre 
also enabled To purchase a 

irely new work benches. We we 
ew of The new Tools urgently need 
The wood-working room has b&lt; 

¦d 

n rearranged and placed in 
forward the work of the de- 

years we have been relieved 

partment. During the past tw 

ibout The insTitutc 

ter i 

The wisdom of this change is m&lt; 

de manifest by The rapid ad 

vancemeni madt 

work on exhibition and in use 

our expeetati 
liis department 

oportion in wliicli li»&gt; profit 

ERIXTEXKBXT H. V.. DaWES: ' 
gislatui-e enabled rliis depar 

much better condition for carrvii 

hirli is shown in th€ </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
444 

LAND COMMISSIONER 

REPORT. 

» 'lasses in manual training should as much as possible be kept 

it all times will enthuse them. 

on new work, something that 
will appeal to their pride and 
this wav, and in this way only. 

ax their skill to the utmost. In 
¦an best results be obtained. 

This year we have added English to our technical work, and 
each day the class devotes one hour to the study of names and 
the use of tools and to the technical terms usually employed in 
the branches of industry taught. It is universally admitted that 
no branch of study taught in our school system is of more practical 
benefit to the young men of this country than that of manual 
training, and I would add that this is especially trw of the 
deaf boy, who. being deprived of the sense of hearing, must 
naturally learn so much from observation, imitation, and from 
practical personal experience. 

The deaf boy shut out from the greater number of avocations 
open to his hearing and speaking brother must depend largely 
upon what he can do. Manual training being a school of doing 
and making things, should be brought to the front. The depart 
nient should be equipped with more and better machinery. 
While we have more and better tools and benches than we had 
two years ago. yet there are many tools very much needed at 
this rime. 1 Miring the past year we have been handicapped for 

the want of suitable material to cany forward the work and at 
times have been obliged to resort to second-hand lumber and 
old boxes. This should not be. A large per cent of all the material 
purchased for this department is made by the class into 
furniture and equipment for the school and becomes the property 
of the state. It is. therefore, short-sighted policy on the part 
of the state to stint the appropriations for supplies for this departmenr. 
I would recommend that sufficient appropriations 
be made to purchase sixteen sets of drawing instruments, one 
band sawing machine, one combination rip and cutting-oft" sawing 
machine, the upper attachments of a scroll saw (the machine 
we have), a steam glue kettle, and sufficient bench tools to equip 
each bench. I would also recommend rhat a room be set aside 
for moulding; that sand flasks and a few moulder's tools be procured, 
and that the principles of this branch of industry be </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

445 

in 

i 

1 

I 

I 

u 

A 

i 

I 

\v 

i 


i 

u 

I 

wa 

ghr. Sufficient material of all kinds should be on hand to 
perlv carry forward the work to prornre the greatest amount 

to pi-omit- the greatest amount 

rood 

pupil and to tin 

tate. 

S. S. Videtto, Teacher. 

AlNllKV DEPARTMENT 

riic change in our laundry department is marked and beneal. 
From a place where labor alone was accomplished it is 
ehool where instruction is given in the ironing and cleansing 

otlies. There is room for vet greater improvements, but we 

ve we are progressing in the right direction and that we 

eventually have this work as thoroughly and well organized 

my other department of the school. Your attention is called 
he report of the instructor, as showing the progress made and 
work being done. 

i'pekixtexdext H. K. Oawes: Tlie enrollment for 1809 was 

nty-one. On Monday. Wednesday and Friday, five girls and 
boy. and on Tuesday. Thursday, and Saturday, seven girls 

I one boy. who ironed from - to "» p. m.; I also had a class of 
en girls, who ironed from 4 to 5 r. m. The attendance was 
leially good. The boys run the mangle and the girls did all 
hand work. 

Phe tirst work done in the ironing room after the opening of 
iooI this fall was on September 12, 1900. I have two classes 
o iron every alternate day. The enrollment at present is 

n ty six. On Monday. Wednesday, and Friday, five girls and 
boy. and on Tuesday. Thursday, and Saturday, ten girls and 
bov: I also have a class of nine girls, who iron from 4 to 5 

st. every day. The first hour, from 2 to ?&gt; r. m., is spent in 

truction in English, and from 3 to 5 p. m. the girls iron. So 
most of the instruction given has been upon the equipment 
a laundry and to teach the children to become familiar with 
¦ Knglish name and to give a good definition for everything 

d in a laundry. Very nearly all the children know the sign. 
not the name for such things as clothes horse, a bosom board, 
shboard. clothes pins. etc. This is only the first step of organ- </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
446 

LAM 

MM1 

TONE* 

l;i 

1 

izing the work into school form, but in a short time I think we 
will be able to take up something a little more difficult, such as 
the preparation of the wash, method of washing, and the general 
rules as to how it should be properly done. Next comes the work 
on stains, for example: 

First— The character of the stain— Mildew. 

Third — The method of removing — "Put on the lemon juice and 
let it stand in the direct sunlight." 

up this subject: 

We will do much 

i 

when wi 

ve all the different 

stains. Then comes rlie proper 
removing of stains, washing, h 
injr. and next the body linen: i 

ire of table and bed linen, thf 

liny: 

11 

]i 

waist, collars and &lt;• 
laces, and finish by 
undved silks. Whe 

inbroid 

,Vl 

posed to understani 
stains from any garn 
dress or piece of tabl 

Besides having 

clothing and linen 
This rear a record 

d ha 

bv hand. als 

!•¦ 

her 24 to I &gt;eceinl 

mangle. We have had 

teniber 12. We have two new 
been a ureat help. The work 

\t help. The w 

desire that it shall continue To 

HOKT 

DEPARTMENT 

i: 

The horticultural department, organized and established in the 

Hadkinson in charge, grew and 

prospered as well as could b&lt; 

Mr. Hadkinson left us at the end of the year to accept a position 

Second — The reagent — Lemon juii 

it is useful knowled" 

» improve. 
Marhahkt H. Mihi'hy. TVju-Im 

bpring of 18JW) with Mr. J. H 

xperted of a new department. </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
447 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

li a larger salary than we were able to pay. To facilitate 
work of this* department a small greenhouse was constructed 
he fall of 18!&gt;9. While this is a great convenience it is not 

e enough for our needs, and the plans for it should be carried 
until we have ar least three times as much space as we now 

cupy. This line of work is one in which our boys can make a 
ceess and in which the handicap of deafness is not so serious 
in some other occupations. Many of the boys enjoy this and 
ve promise of becoming expert horticulturists, florists, and 

¦s. 1 believe that this department is worthy of careful 
ration and development. A large ]»er cent of our boys 

1 some form of agricultural pursuits. For these this 
hi gives the most practical instruction that they can 
We are endeavoring to encourage and develop this 
hat when our bovs have finished their course of instruc- 

hings that they can be taught is the planting, care, and growth 
if all kinds of plants; when and how to plant different seeds, 
mlbs, and trees; trimming and pruning of grapevines and apple 
rees; grafting and budding of fruit trees; planting and transplanting 
of all kinds of shrubs; propagation of flowers and 

i-t* they will desire to go to t 

rlie Start- I'nivei-sity aud com- 

leir agricultural education. 

The professor in charge of 

iiiiitinciit. in the University, 

lias agreed to interest himself 

work. and. if possible, to so plan his course of instruction 

deaf boy seeking admission may be admitted and bene- 

I have liojies for much good for our boys in this direction 

work is properly encouraged by a legislative appropria- 

I would call your attention to the report of the instructor 

rjre and ask for it most careful consideration. 

i:i:intk\[&gt;k\t H. E. Hawks: The results secured in this de- 

eiit are ample warrant for its establishment and eontin- 

XYliile we are laboring under many difficulties, incident 

e\\ school, we are making satisfactory progress. Our boys 

gular in attendance and enthusiastic in their efforts. Ne- 

i is au agricultural state. A majority of our young men 

teconie farmers. One of the most important and useful </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
448 

LANI 

MM I 

IOXEF 

REPOF 

arrangement on the lawn: landscape gardening and care of 
lawns. These are exceedingly practical lessons and are much 
enjoyed by the class. In order to get the best results we should 
have a larger greenhouse. Our class now has eight members 
and is gradually increasing. More room is required and can be 
profitably used. Flowers for the sick and for use in the school 
and living rooms are furnished from this department. 

A small library of books bearing directly upon the physiology 

of plants, elementary botany, 
of our greatest needs. We sh 

Etnd other subjects taught is om 
nld also be supplied with paper* 

and magazines published in th 

interest of this line of worl 

The gi'oss value of productlawn 
for the past year is *&lt;&gt;7&lt;i 
slight additional expenses. fo 

from farm, garden, orchard, am 
is. This could be increased wifl 

greenhouse and supplies. B 
bled it would vet be the sun 

though it were doubled ai 

item in the estimate. The valuable product is the 1 
and the citizen. 

Thanking von for voiir constant assistance and enconraj: 

nient. 1 submit this rep&lt; 

K. X. Key 

A 

would call your attention to the report of tl 

nd ask for it most careful consideration. His recommend 

re practical and his requests should be granted 

In addition to the fire protection which la- ask* for we slioiib 

have some additional outside escapes from the main building 

The old chapel on the upper floor of this building has bee: 

arranged for living rooms for the young ladies of the institution 

Should a fire occur and cut off escape by the stairway, ther 

would be no other means of salvation except with ladders raise 

to the windows. 

I would recommend the placing of adequate fire escapes in thi 

building and also the purchase of at least two sets of exiensio 

ladders to be kept in the rare of the engineer and always read 

for 'ise i:i case of einergencv. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
449 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND Dl'JIB. 

I 

Report of the Chief Entjiiicir. 

Superintendent H. E. Dawes: Having charge of the steam 
plant you will please allow me to respectfully submit the followin 
g report: 

I consider that we have one of the most convenient, as well as 
substantial, engine and boiler rooms in the state. The heating 
plant consists of three boilers sixty inches by eighteen feet. 
Numbers 1 and '1 are equipped with the American stoker; they 
are the most complete smoke consumers I have ever seen in connection 
with a steam boiler, and they are a great fuel saver, as 
they burn all the combustible matter and leave very little ash, 
mostly slaj; or solid clinkers. Forced draft is used in connection 
with the stoker, a Buffalo fan and small upright engine supply- 

it. Number :'. lias the common stationary grate. I would 

nit a stoker be put in under this boiler also. One of 

ii- 

boilers that came out of the old boiler room was placed in 

lie battery connected to the standpipe mid used for a heater to 
supply the institution with hot water. In the engine room we 
iave four pumps: One Dean automatic pump and receiver, which 
Kindles tlie condensation from the entire system ami returns 

the boilers. ( &gt;ne small Marsh pump that is used for pump 

the rain water out of the cisterns into the laundry and sup- 

ying the boilers if necessary, 
id an old duplex that is used for 

The others, a Marsh 111x0x12. 
pumping the well water out of 
They have a capacity sufficient 
at any time. One thirty-five 
r very good service. A &lt; 'rocker- 
YV.. or font 1 hundred liglit ma- 

reservoir into the standpipe. 

&lt;&gt; supply the demand for water 
I. F. l'hiHiiix engine that is givim 
V heeler dvnamo. twentv-four K. 

liine, that is up-to-date in evejry respect. A marble switchboard 
ivith the latest electrical appliances and switches for controlling 

its in various department 

and buildings. This dynamo 
that pulls the line shaft that 
and lathes in carpenter shop, 
mo that was used for lights in 
o The increase in the demand 
the dynamo is used for power, 

supplies current for a motor 
the washer, wringer, mangle 
motor is the old Edison dvn; 

engine room, but owing 

o small. A </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
450 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S 

REPORT. 

f 

I would recommend that electric irons lit* pur in the ironinj 
room. It would be a saving of fuel and would be much mort 
pjeasant for The students that are employed in that department 
on account of the extreme heat from the stoves. The exliausi 

steam is used for heating the buildings, and is sufficient to 1 
them warm except in very cold weather. We carry eij, 

&gt;ld weather. We carry eighty 

pounds boiler pressure, and by 

use of reducing valves the pres 

sure is reduced to from four t&lt; 

lit pounds on heating system 

that being all that is required 

most of the svsteni. The lai 

from the old engine boiler room 

ind were verv income 

it 

weighing. They were moved up 

he«d&lt; 

window 

boiler room, which makes it 

\ 

liven 

The 

located that a" load can !&gt;&lt;¦ dii\ 

\*ei 

and the coal dropped tin 
The coal is then right in 

\\ ii 

the times. Tin 

1 1 in 

din 

A 

thorough] v overhauled. A 

main \v 

radiator 

in a mechanical manner. X&lt; 

n 

radiator 

ceilings, etc \\ 

steam piessiin 

Tin 

as not 

w 

Xe\ 

lso put in 

The heating 

ml 

side walls and pipe run 

a t horouu: 

Ph. 

closet in this building is in verv bad condition, owing to its 

long use. The fixtures have h 

¦oine decaved and are in a 

verv 

bad sanitary condition. I would suggest that this be t hoi- 

ujirb.lv 

renovated and a new automatii 
closet is also too small to a&lt; 
which have to use it. There ii 

flush and range be put in. This 
onimodate the number of boys 
a room on the second floor that 

£et a good circulation throngli 
lies were located some distance 

fireman. Ipmi the v. 

I would su&lt;; </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
451 

N 

ITVTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

is intended for a closer, and I would suggest that it be fitted up 
with fixtures and allow pan of the boys to use it. 
Last fall and winter a new school building was put up, which 

dit to the state and institution as well. The steam heat- 

tern and electrical appliances are perfect, giving entire 

itislaciioi 

well pmnps that are located some distance 
i. One well is :51I) feet deep, with a 12x30, 
Cook pump over it and is getting a good 

We ha 

« i 

ivarer. The other is a shallow well with an old 

Kuowles pump over it ( that has seen its best days). If the 

Id give out the little pump would not supply 

e demand for water. I would suggest that this old casing 

w and a larger casing be put down. The 
ild then be depended upon at any and all 

ltstitutiou has not enough tire protection, 
&gt;t reach of city protection. This should not 

protect as well as valuable prop 

institution put in its own 

r would be about #2.500. 

nnected with the downspouts 

ttiiient lo supply tl 

ind Th 

n 

wails. Th 

t hold 

as it would sa 

ml a 

us have a connection with tht 

is 

limp and could be kept full 

V 

if thev would hold it. A large reser 

•ar that was used for well water exclusively 

von 

i 

The plant as a whole is in verv good condition, but is like all 

nature, there is more or less repairing to be done 

1 would ask for a good appropriation for repairs so that tht 
plant may be kept in its present excellent condition. 

Chas. Sexton, Chief Engineer. 

rln- waterworks company extend the main 
un and j&gt;la&lt;-e ir in The protection of the 

the use of so much soaj </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
! 

1 

452 

LAND ( 

MMISSIONBK S RETORT. 

REPORT FROM THE LITERARY SCHOOLS 

The following reports from the different grades and class- 

in the literary department will give you a detailed account 

the work done by the several teachers. I would particularly 

all your attention to the advantages of a complete organization 

a well arranged course of study, good equipment, and a corpi 

of teachers working together in harmony with the superin 

tendent and each other to accomplish all that can be done ft 

our children. Harmony in ett 

it is one of the essenti 

il 

satisfactory results 

Report &lt;&gt;f the Work /&gt; 

n the Oral Department 
nth Grade. 

1 of the S'&lt; 

There are eighty five pupils in 

well in line with the 

great improvement 

Beginning w 

w 

kindergarten thorough, pains 

ng oral work is being dout 

i 

each of the eight oral class 

The oral pupils are carefu 

graded from one class to anotlu 
cises as a music pupil does witli 

r and proceed with their ex&lt; 

x 

In this, the highest oral class 

lie Nebraska State &lt; 

£tudy i adopted two years ag 

(I 

v follow 

i 

advantages of this course. I thii 
At our state exposition two ]i 

are incalculal 


zes were \v 

grade. One upon a map of the I 

nited States and the other up. 

a paraphrase, the later showii 

understanding of the langua 

great work in every study. \\ 

th time, patience, and 

we can and will equip our dt 

mils to go forth from the sch 

prepared to cope with anyone. 
Most respectfully submitted 

;tith of November. 1000 

Head of the Oral Departi 

1 Teacher of the Seventh Grad( 

l- oral instruct ion 

The improvement in the oral w&lt; 

marked adrancemen 

Hie teaching of languag 

Miss Jame M. W'ashin </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
453 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Report of the Fifth Grade 

11. E. Dawbs 

-. 

\ 

Daily Pi 

'iratn. 

Picture work. 
Language. 

New words and idioms 

Recess. 

Self-culture 

Geography. 

Articulation 

Language and 

ramniar 

Physiology and hygiene. 

Copying work 

this program the State Course of Study is followed 

In using 

as possible. This course, however, must be slightly 

closely 

altered to meet the deficiencies of each particular class. The 
child must not be trimmed or stretched to fit the bed, but the 

ted must he shortened or lengthened to suit the child. 

leaf acquire knowledge through sight only, those 

Vs tin 

ethods of instruction are sought which appeal most directly 

Objects can be studied only to a limited 

;ll 

degree in the tifth grade; hence pictures afford the best results. 

n of _\00&lt;&gt; stereoscopic photographs, the 

\\ 

i\ 

property 

)graphs reproduce scenes with all the reality of nature and 

hot 

afford the only real substitute for travel. The pupil is made 
to see what he is studying and he more readily comprehends the 

ideas and masters the language describing it. Besides these there 
is a large assortment of copies from the most famous niaster- 

f art, and choice sketches of the greatest educational 

value. We use pictures and flowers to take the place of music 

lucing a softening and refining effect upon the character 

n p 

of our pupils. Often the children are required to illustrate their 

t &gt;pening exercises 
Newspaper work. 
Arithmetic. 

Underwood &amp; Underwood of New York. These </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
454 

LAND COMMISSIONER 

KEI'OHT 

language. This not only tests the accuracy of their expression 
but demands clear and exact thinking. 

The education of the deaf is a slow and difficult process. It 
requires energy, patience, and thoroughness alike from teachei 
and pupil. The teacher delighis in removing obstacles, clearing 
the path, and helping the pupils surmount difticultites, not foi 
the pleasure of overcoming obstacles, bur because they like the 

pupils. We are closer to our children, have more influence ovei 
them, and are more appreciated by them than is the common 

bv them than is the common 

of language) as shown in the State Course of Study. I think 

we follow trli.it course verv well, and in a few veat 

we have been improving, our fourth grade will d 

grade work in language. The language work that I hand in U 
the pupil's own thought and ideas that the picture and sentenc* 
represents. Mr. , a gentleinean from Lincoln, says: "Thest 
'pictured" ideas were better than one could expect from th&lt; 
country school of this grade. " The words underlined were givei 
to the children to write a sentence about, then they were re 
quired to draw the object or objects spoken of. 

I feel that this is to be a victorious year with a long term, new 
buildings and apparatus enabling us to carry out our motto: 

irrv out our motto 

public school teacher. . ., ., ,„ . 
F Alvin E. Pope, Teacher. 

Ill 

Report of Fourth Crude in Oral Department. 

Superintendent H. E. Dawes: During the two years ending 

November 30, 1900, we have had over 300 visitors. 

I believe with a full nine months' school our pupils can tinisl 

the same 'work done bv hearing children (with the exceptioi 

'Vigorous, Practical, and Progressive." 

Miss Ekith Hank, Teacher. 

It is to be regretted that it is impossible to reproduce the 

cssons and pictures spoken of by Miss Kand. They are splendid 

examples of illustrated language lessons. 

Report of Third Grade in Oral Department. 

Sii'ERixTEXDEXT 11. E. Dawks: The enrollment for 1899 aud 

L900 was nine ifive bovs. four ijiilsi miiil March 15. when one bov </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
455 

XSTITVTE FOB THE DEAF AND DIME. 

i 

\ 

i 

I 

St;\ 

11 

1 

I 

1 

n 

N. 

I 

I 

n were passed to rhe fourth grade and two 

1 in rhe third grade. The present enrollment is ten; 

x hovs and four girls. Seven were promoted from the second 

uto school for the first time. This class is an 

le. one 

Two boys hear all that is said, but have 
speech: two other boys hear when spoken 

ultv \v 

mv loudly: two girls hear some but not enough to receive 
action through the ears. Two boys and two girls do not 

VII the children are good lip readers and the instruction 

lven or; 

he work in the third grade is carried out according to th« 

Course of Study. Every lesson is made a language les 

ut the language lesson proper is the study of pictures, 

nt and animal life, life and customs of different nationalities, 

1 interesting events that happen in the children's lives. The 

use of nouns, pronouns, verbs, adverbs, etc.. is taught. 

hildren are encouraged to do independent thinking and as 

possible correct their own mistakes 

metic written examples are placed upon the black 

ml and the children think for themselves and decide how the 

xani] 

ubic notation, dry and liquid 'measure, linear measure, and 
nev are taught. 

n geography our object is to give primary ideas concerning 

he earth. Definitions of hills, mountains, lakes, rivers, etc 

night. The study of maps, and especially the study of 

braska and the Inited States, is taken up the latter part of 

veai 

In physiology little talks are given concerning the care of the 
dy. teeth, hair, and nails. The parts of the body and uses of 

lementaiy sounds are taught, and short 

In art 

lies that are used every day are taught, such .as "How 
iu-do." "Please give me a pencil." etc. 

he worked. Addition, substruction, division, 

Cora M. Jack. Teacher. </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
456 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S RETORT. 

Report of Second Grade in Oral Department 

Sufebixtexdext H. E. IIawes: The rapid progress of this 
grade shows what can be done when a set course or system is 
followed. The introduction of the State Course of Study was 
a most wise move. At the beginning of the 1899 school jear 
the second grade pupils had a mixed knowledge of a great many 
things; in some branches they were ahead of the course of 
study; in others they were far behind. Their training was such, 
however, — particularly that of those who were not new to the 
school, — that it did not take them long to acquire what was 
new to them, or to rapidly advance in that of which they had 
had but a smattering. Several of the new pupils, however, 
confined chiefly to those who could not hear, were far behind 
the others at the start, and so for months made the class one 
of many divisions; but because of their hearing, they were able 
to progress more rapidly than the others, and, at the end of the 
school year, were quite up to the average of the majority and 
were promoted. The class was made up of nine boys and three 
girls. The oldest of the boys "was fifteen, the average of the 

others eleven. On*' of the girls was eightc 

wi 

eleven each. The two younger girls were the brigl 
of the class. The average hearing &lt;&gt;f the class wa 

per cent. 

The class of this year. 19OO-'O1, numbers thirteen: six boys, 
seven girls. The oldest, a girl, is nineteen; the youngesr is a 
boy of nine, who is the best in the class. An agreeable feature 
is the pupils' comparative evenness. "While some are slower 
than others, no divisions are necessary, a fact that makes the 
work lighter and the results far more satisfactory. The average 
hearing this year I should place at barely *per cent. With last 
year's experience to aid. this year began more systematically, 
with better machinery and more oil to the wheels. This, combined 
wirii their excellent instruction while in the first grade, 
enabled them to start immediately with the work as outlined 
by the course of study. We have followed this carefully.— in 
some cases have even gone more rapidly than warranted by the </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
457 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

¦suggestions" in said course, — and I am confident that by the 

be thoroughly equipped to pass 

nd of the vear the class will 

&gt;nd t;rad« 

examination. 

ublit- srl 

Gorman Shreve, Teacher. 

Class, Oral Department. 

First Gruih 

1 

xtendext H. E. Uawes: The work of the present year 

s that of the first grade in Oral Department. This class conists 
of twelve pupils, ten of which formed part of the kinder- 

garten of last year. The branches studied are articulation, 
language, lip-reading, notation and numeration. The class is 
bright and capable of doing excellent work, if their energies are 
properly directed. Five of the class hear enough to assist them 
in becoming excellent lip-readers and do encouraging work in 
articulation. In language, my object is to make-the very atmosphere 
of the schoolroom written and spoken English. Quantity 

placed on an equal with quality and both are advanced as 

ipidly as possible. The five-slate method is used with success. 

My experience is that the fewer signs used, the better the 

mprehension of English, and I aim to make this the motto of 

wort 

Lena B. McNamab, Teacher. 

First Grade, Oral Department. 

ent H. E. Dawes: In this grade particular stress 

been laid on articulation and lip-reading. At the same time, 
ever, language has had quite as important a place, for, 

owt 

the deaf child must be»led step by step from the 

simple 

\nd constant repetition they become a very part of him. What 
a hearing child obtains bv ear a deaf child must gain by sight. 

First — Articulation. 

This branch consists of work on the elementary sounds, which 
e drilled upon until the pupil can recognize and produce 

them quickly, and then the work passes on to lessons on 
syllables and combining them into words and finally to sentences. 
The sentences were simple and comprised thoughts 

omplex forms of language, until by drill </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
458 

commissioner's report. 

LAXI 

with which the pupils were familiar, and the words eonsiste 
of objects about the school. The lip-reading in connection wit 
this was made up of simple commands and questions, words 
proper names, and anything from the language work that coul 
be used profitably, as. answering simple questions by readin 

the questions from the lipi 

The five-slate systems was used in the language wot 

ukI b 

this method, nouns, verbs, adjectives, pronouns, and 

prepos 

tions were taught. The nouns used were headed 
1. Things in the schoolroom. 

Parts of the body 
Things to eat. 

4. Clothing worn by boy or : 
5. Furniture in different part 

i 

6. Names of a few wild and domestic anini; 

flowers 

7. Proper namt 

8. Days of the week and mouths of the yea 
The Sunday school work was carried on w 

mote the moral welfare of the fluid and give him son 

(1 

spiritual things 

The nature work was not very extensive, and \v 

on in connection with the langua 

Third— Number Work 

1. Writing numbers to»one hundred 
2. Numbers and names to fifty. 
3. Roman numbers to fifteen. 

4. Addition and simple subt 

action 

Simple problem 

Six pupils were recommended to second grade in June. 1S91 

Eight pupils were recommended to second grade in -Time. 100( 

ax B 

Second — Lancua </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
459 

riTTTTE FOR THE DEAF AND DIME. 

t 

' the Work Done in thv Kindergarten 
During the Past Tiro Vans. 

nt H. E. Dawes: The average age of the kiuderght 
years. As is the ease iu most classes, there 
hildi-en whose mental capacity is more developed 

Thus we have children who are past the kinder- 

irtcn. in years, but not past in development of the mind. The 
ght-vear old deaf child is as young as the five-year-old hearing 

hild. so far as mental development is concerned 

The principles and methods which have been handed down 
us bv the great educator Froebel serve as the foundation 

&gt;ur "Kindergarten." When the deaf child comes to us its 
it need is the names of objects, which is preparatory to the 

inguage work which follows in the tirst grade. The different 

he year are taken up in their order. The messages 
ivhich each (season) brings us are given to the 

lildren: thus important lessons are impressed upon their 
mug minds. At opportune times names of the different 
bjects and articles are given the children, by means of the 
lanual alphabet and writing them on the wall slates. In circle 

ind occupation work, commands are given in writing and speak 
ng. The written command is given first without the name 

the child, then, after the attention of the children has been 
cured, the name of one child is written, i. e.. "Find the flower, 

'onrad. 

been given to the articulation 
are two classes, one of which 
other has been slower. It is 

This term special attention ha: 
work. At the present time there 
has made marked progress. The 

hoped that by means of this division there will more ambitious 
work 1..- doin- by this second division. The general outline of 
the year's work is as follows: During the winter season special 

made for the holidays— Thanksgiving. Christ 

prepara 

mas. New Year's, and Washington's birthday. Spring— This is, 
as main have said, one of the most important and delightful 

to the little children. The seeds which they have carefully 
laid away are brought out and planted. The nature work is the </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
460 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

most important during tliii 
birds, butterflies, flowers. et&lt; 
the medium of observation. 

season. Stories, lessons, of tl» 
are given to the children througl 

Clara B. Andrews. Teache 

MANIAL DEPARTMENT. 

Report of the Work Done % the Pupils of the First (node 
for the Past Two Years. 
Superintendent H. E. Dawes: Language being the most 
difficult for the deaf, more time has been spent with it than 
anything else. Practically all lessons, except number work 
.using characters, are language lessons to the deaf child When 
new names are given the child tries to decide in his own mind 
where they belong according to the five-slate system. Vll nameare 
given first by script and followed by the manual alphabet" 
Objects and pictures were used for illustrating the new words! 
Barnes of classmates; articles of the schoolroom; parts of the 
clothing; familiar animals: things to eat; parts of the body 

Frequent drills in finger-spelling 

were given and required; als 

arn the names 

of trees, birds, and other object 
brought to the schoolroom for le: 

vnimals and objects we 

¦ssons 

family names; superintendent, steward, matron, teachers and 
other persons whom they meet frequently; names of colors; a 
few adjectives, pronouns, prepositions: the use of and: davs of 
the week; names of the months; the rooms of a house and some 
of the furniture and other things connected with the home life 
of the child. This is a brief outline of the vocabulary gained 
by the child in this grade, excepting the action words/ A very 
nice list of verbs was given by action-work, which is the basis 
for sentence-making. Toys were used and found very valuable 
rhe use of the singular, plural and possessive nouns were easilv 
™ ders&lt; l tlom lessons and applied with the items 
M nting short stories from pictures was found quite profitable. 

.pelled or written forms of sentences when asking for ol 

n tlie schoolroom. 

The nature work consisted of excursions to learn the- i </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
461 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

\ 

I 

I 

i 

ine number work consisted o 
undred. combining with objects 
nd one-third of numbers to twelve: 
allies and numbers to thirty; a 
nd simple subtraction. Some of 
ubtraetion, multiply and divide 
hree and four. 

of writing numbers to one 
s to twenty; finding one-half 
? ; the Roman letters ro fifteen ; 
i few short written problems 
f the pupils could borrow in 
small number* bv two and 

\t the close of the year 1898 six pupils were promoted to the 
•ond grade, and in 1899 seven were promoted. 

Report of the Second and Third Grades 

Second Grade Language Work 

Superintendent H. E. Dawes: For text -books we used 
•Lights to Literature No. 1." Most of our lessons were taken 
Tom action-work. Class had a vocabulary of about two himlied 
nouns and one hundred verbs. Letter writing: questions 
tnd answers; taught the pronouns I, my. me. he. his. him. she, 

&gt;u. we. and us; commercial journal writing. 

Numbers 

Written problems iu addition and subtraction. Roman numer- 

fifrv. Numbers and their names to one hundred 

Third Grade Language. 

Letter writing. Continued journal writing. Description and 
iction lessons. Have used the sequence method this year and 
find I get a great deal better results than from "any other method 

'. ever used. By this method anything that happens can be put 
uto English by the deaf child. Taught the pronouns your. our. 

Their, they, them. Story writing from memory and pictures. 
Commands that are used in the schoolroom. 

Number 

Multiplication tables. Roman numerals to one hundred. 
Problems in addition, subtraction, multiplication, long and 
short division. Taught the fractions of one-half, one-third, and 

irth. Used the tov monev 

. Taught them to count, make 
"se of the ruler and difference 

change and point off money. I 
between inches, feet, and vards. 

Most of the number work was 

Ora Vivian. Teacher. 


mmissk&gt;ni:k's report. </seg>

            <seg id="p052">462 

LAND C 

given in a language form, using no figures but the names instead, 
the pupils being required to write them in figures. In 
this work thev did not go above one hundred. 

Taught i he pupils home towns, counties, and state in which 
they live. Did not go outside the state of Nebraska. 1 Erection, 
climate, season*, surface of the country. Drew map of the 
state and located capital, largest cities and rivers. Did not give 
very much time ro geography, as I paid special attention to 
language work. If a child understands English he can easily 
grasp ideas of geography. The language and geography work 
has all been copied in note books and kept to be taken home 

by the pupil at the close of the term 

Differenr parts of the body 
Breathing exercises. 

Effects of stimulant 

Care of the body and prop 
&gt;ating. 

in 

All of 

j'ear all except one boy who had b&lt; 

months. 

th mill Fifth ( 

SlTPERIN 

report of tin- fourth and fifth 
for the two years eliding Nov 

jrradt 

This month will end mv 

jnd as I look back over the work done I feed satisfied wi 

what has been accomplished. The only drawback I have en 

countered was the removing from school of some pupils in th« 

middle of the term and by others coming in late in the fall. I 

do not believe all the parents understand what benefit their 

childwn are receiving here or what harm they are doing by 

removing them. The work of teaching the deaf is very hard 

and parents should render all assistance they can. Being deaf 

&lt; Geography. 

Phvsiologv 

Kt port of the Foi 

II. E. Dawks: I herew 

mber :!&lt;!. l!&gt;0&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
463 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

lyself I have always taken a great interest in this class of 
leople, and I have not found so much pleasure from the money 

for my labor as I have found in the labor itself. Since 
into the new school building my task has been much 

lied. Pupils have taken more interest in work. New and 
surroundings, with an abundance of light and fresh air. 

made both pupils and teacher stronger mentally and phy 
v. The parents, friends of the deaf, and the pupils thein- 

cal 

we much to you, the board, and the last legislature for 
in behalf of their education. The adoption of a course 

nt ire fifth grade was promoted last spring, so the pupils 

T 

are now in the fifth are all new to that grade. Following 

win 

is the average in different studies for the class for this term: 
Geography, 85^; language. 7!H; composition. 83^; arithmetic, 
MK; physiology, 7(W; health. 97&lt;£; deportment. 96,^. 

¦ study and the grading of the classes was another good step 

i the light direction. While it has been in operation only a 

¦w years, iis good results are already plainly visible. One 

F the rules of the institution, "to teach by example as well as 

recept." is a good one. and I have tried to carry it out at all 

nic.s. I find by associating freely with the pupils, joining their 

aincs. clubs, sports, etc.. I can win their good will, confidence, 

nd friendship to a larger extent than any other way. So I 

ave spent much of my time, outside of school hours, asso- 

iating with them. In the fourth and fifth grades I have fol- 

&gt;wed the course of study as closely as practicable, and have 

dded such suggestions as were made from time to time by the 

Uperintendent. 

Pupils have been promoted each spring after they have 

assed a satisfactory examination. I have inquired, quite often, 

bmit pupils who have been promoted from my class, and have 

leen t,,ld that tiny were doing nicely. I fee* that the work 

hey did in the grade that I have charge of properly prepared 

hem for the grade to which they were promoted. The average 

landing of the fourth grade in different studies is as follows: 

Teography. 77'/: arithmetic. SI-,; language. "Sv: composition. 

¦&lt;K: deportment. !»"'&lt;: health. 98#. </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
464 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

There is a total of twenty-two in these two classes. The 
average attendance for this term is as follows: Total number 
of days of school, 57; total number of days all pupils attended. 
September 13 to date. 1,04;$: total number of half days absent, 15. 
Average membership entire school year. 18 3l!-57ths. Average attendance 
entire school. 18 19-57ths. On no occasion have I 
found it necessary to use corporal punishment, and at all times 
have had perfect control of my pupils. I shall in the future, 
as in the past, try to carry out the motto of the school, "Vigorous, 
Practical, and Progressive." I wish to thank you, the 
board, and all who have given me help, advice, and encourage 
nient in mv work. 

Respectfully submitted 

L. M. Hint. Tea 

RriHjrt of tin- si.rtfi and Seventh Grad&lt; 

Superintendent H. K. Dawes: — At the begin 

iliool 1 was reassigned to the charge of the sixth and seven 
rades of the manual department. As soon as the classes wt 

•rganized. I pushed the work required by the course of study 

iml followed the outline as far as possible according to 
•onrse. I have the sixth class consisting of three bovs and 

seventh consisting of eight bovs and two girls. The per &lt; 

of attendance from the opening of the school to date is nin 
seven and the per cent of punctuality ninety-nine and one-li 

] will give the following brief resume of the work done sii 

the opening of the school: In language work, they are r 

i 

to construct sentences, either on wall slates or on pap 

containing words or phrases in common use. I think they 

have made satisfactory progress in this direction. They 
are required to copy all the words or phrases given in note 

books, for future reference and review. In history work, not 

lasses take the sa 

It would 

son 

have them take up different woi 

on aecoun 

re being tw 

lasses and a Tin 

The following is a general outline of the history wor 

npossililo t&lt; 

inie possible to be devoted t&lt;i this bra </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
465 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

I 

1 

General causes of the Revolution. 
Writs of Assistance. 

The Stamp Apt and its repeal. 

The tax on tea and the Boston Port bill 
Congress called in 1774. 

The war began. 

Uattles about New York and in New Jersey 
Burgoyne's Campaign. 

The war about Philadelphia. 

I tat ties in Georgia and South Carolina. 
Arnold's Treason and Andrew's death. 
&lt; Ireen in the south. 

n arithmetic work, the seventh grade has made a special 
dy of long, square, and cubic measures. The sixth grade has 
oted their time to the study of fractions and square and long 
iisure. In grammar, the sixth grade study the parts of speech 

•I simple and compound sentences. The seventh class, tbe 
mplex sentences with, whom. who. and which, and diagrams 

the sentences. They are required to write compositions ou 
idavs. I recommend both classes should take up geography. 

should be furnished with reading book 

When 1 was assigned to the charge of the library, I found 
ere were 1.454 volumes on the shelves, and all the books were 

Since the opening of the school, sixty-ont 

Ided to the library. Four hundred and 

I 

iiiv eight volumes and one hundred fifty-nine magazines have 
¦en used, or are in circulation. Some of the books are in poor 
.ndition and need rebinding. I recommend all the books should 

labeled, numbered and catalogued. I recommend the library 

1 have an addition of one hundred juvenile books and 

&gt;f reference for reading worl 

Waldo H. Rothert, Teacher 

f the librarian for additional reading matter are 
s exceedinelv modest in his wishes, and if wt 

d. IT 

ney to do so. more than double the amount asked for 
purchased. All the magazines, picture papers, ami 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
466 

AXI&gt; COMMISSIONER'S BEPOR1 

juvenile literature published should be on our shelves for tlw 
nse of tlie children. It is absolutely essential thai the deal 
child form the "reading habit." Ir cannot beacquired nnles f 
the proper facilities are provided. 

Rr/tort of the Hh/htli 'Irml 

SrPEHiVTEXDEXT H. K. Dawks: The class of 1S!I!I graduated 
five members, our of whom has since entered (iallaudet College 

sun 

I'.er w 

who was graduated ii 
"!»!• arc intelligent, si-ll' 

.ens — &lt;\ 

married durii 

times hajip 

puj ils 

environuieiit 

Ex 

veai 

\\ lia 

leu 

rel 

.Most of the recitations are conducted in writinu. 1 

by this method that our children's 

Washington, I&gt;. ( 

another alu 

TWO Ulcllllli 

...uir..-* ,,, IM fins. r oiiiswinji I lie .\ehrask;; ( ourse of Sn 

comiiicnial arithmetic is &lt;-&lt;.;iiii]\i l ..l in tin- : 1 1 . i &gt; 1 i &lt; -&lt; I miinii 

¦ ' '"iiiuiiiii in i ill- il|&gt;|MMM| | M I |l&lt; I | 

of percentage, and language work receives daily and most ,-; 

ful attention. Tin- latter work is condu-ted analvti&lt;-ally a&lt;&lt;&lt; 

i 

iiif. r t&lt;i Ki-aiiiiuarical forms — not for grammar's sake, but in or 

to strengthen Hie pupils" analytical powers; and svnllw 

i&lt; 

language work is constantly continued in the form of essays 

subjects horli optional and assigned, which are composed. &lt; 

i 

rected and reviewed from &lt;la\ to dav. </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
467 

T1TITE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

onducted in future years, and school life must be. above all else, 
tractically preparatory. Class-work in j;eoijraphy is preserved 

nibers' own future reference, and in this con 

liiber lias in course of preparation his own 

&lt;r 

lescrintion of his- home town, of the state of 

l&gt;la 

\ 

uious regions of our vast country, the prodcoinmerce. 
which is to lie extended to the 

if the earth and their dependencies. As in 
inds and qualities of mind are bound to vary: 
is ro afford each pupil :i just and equal share 

in! encouragement. Not individuals but efforts. 

ilities are in favor, or the 

f praise" is rendered without conscious 

Kt.ftOO 00 

SIM) 00 

1M.200 00 

S.000 i M I 

S.000 00 

17.000 00 

Hoard and clothing </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
468 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S KEPOET. 

Supplies for industries jo 000 00 

Furniture and bedding 2 000 00 

Books and stationery 

1.000 00 

Telephone and telegraph y00 00 

Repairs and improvements 

I'.IMMI 00 

Water supply and connections 1,200 00 

Typewriters 5(K , ,,„ 

Incidentals 

500 in. 

Paints, oils, and glas 

500 00 

Drugs and medicines' 

:&lt;OO 00 

Horses, wagon, feed, liarnes 

SI 10 00 

Fittings for hospita 

200 0o 

Fire protection D.O(U) 00 

&lt;"old storage plant 

000 110 

Oreenhoust 

200 00 

Fruit, ornamental trees and shrubs loo oo 

Postage and expi 

the illness in the institution for The past year was 

than the previous year. We had tin 

matic fever which were very persistent in character and 

some seven weeks or more. Lung fever attacked eight 

small boys, and, while nioderati 
Eight cases of tonsilitis which v 
Ty-two rases of chicken-pox: one 
&lt;&gt;f sore throat; seventy-one eai 
caused from indigeslion. Two 
lingers, which in each case causi 

lv severe, all recovered readi 

in from three to ten da vs. Fif 

acure case of erysipelas; twenty 
&gt;es of headache, in most cases 
sprained wrists; four infected 
¦d the loss of the nail. Six verv 

had cuts: one case of poison from rusty nail; two very severe 
burns; thirty-live cases of earache; forty-four cases of toothache: 
four of sore eyes; six of eczema. In each of the above named 

ases the child was kept in the hospital from two to ten days 

Sidewalks 
Gymnasium and equiimieii 

SrPERixTEXUKXT H. K. Pawes: li is cratifviuK </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
469 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

h 

ii 

I 

¦xcept in lever cases, which required mtfeh longer time and 
he treatment advised bv the doctor. The illness this vear has 

een much less than last. 

An improvement over last year is the small cottage which was 
paired during the summer and fitted up for a hospital. We 

ccupy the second floor, which can be well ventilated and i 
ght. sunny, and cheerful. 

Fifteen cases of tonsilitis which were very light, fourteen of 
leadache and indigestion, two cold on the lungs, one of bronhitis. 
one of la grippe, and five boils were given the usual treatuent. 
In addition to this had numerous calls for medicine and 

dress cuts, sprains, burns, etc. Lulu Hall, Nurse. 

HEADING CLUE 

A leading club has been organized during the ls*st year and 
proving of great benefit and help in forming the "'reading 

labit." The books read by the club are those of the Nebraska 
mpils" reading circle, supplemented by selections demanded by 

H 

U'oused bv the reading in the regular coursf 

I.ITKKARY SOCIKTY 

Phe Literary Society continues to be a source of much interest 
&lt;1 valuable instruction to its members. Nearly all of the pupils 

tlic fourth grade are members of this society. The work 
jilislicd will compare favorably with the work of like 

rades in i lie schools for the hearing. The debates, which takt 
lace diniug the winter, between this and similar organizations 

he Iowa School for the Deaf have been very entertainin 

much encouragement to the members. 

HRISTIAN ENDEAVOR SOCIETY 

This society meets regularly every Sunday evening during the 
hool sessions. The services are conducted in the same manner 

hat this organization has adopted for the churches. All the 
&gt;lder pupils attend and receive much comfort and eneourage- 

uent in their efforts to improve and perfect their moral con- 

duct. 

.1 </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
470 

LA NT 

MM 

IONF 

REPOIST 

All tliree of these organizations are officered and ma 

by the pupils themselves, the officers being selected l&gt;y se&lt; 

ballot 

Some of the teachers are always prt 

to otter suggestive help when needed. The in 

inna th* 

¦onducT of the business are such as usually control deliberative 

bodi 

\ft 

ireful in 

I 

rabbit. 1 was 

would 

prise for the state to 1 
last I purchased a doc 

1 w 

bits doing well and ii 

w 

were made in behalf of these 1 

nals. Not con 

or the waste food, that lliev 

an be produced f 

I .1 

\|. 

poi 

of this kind of n 

providt 

In addition t 

familv with a delicacv that they would not o 

to secure. The rabbit is much in 

easier to raise, safer to handle, moi 
desirable as a domestic pet or foo 

l-produ&lt; 

NAMF 

The name of this institution should b&lt; 

describe i1s object and work. Its present 

tute for the Deaf and Dumb."' This should be changed to "Th 

Nebraska School for the Deaf." As now 

ve as intended from 

v 

ltrht al 

dditi 

I would therefore r&lt; 
the subject of the ch 

I &lt;lo eXl 

the attention of our pcop </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
471 

riTt'TE FOE THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

he State of Nebraska 

the Institute for the Deaf and 

name for 

Omaha, in the conntv of Douglas, state of Ne 

v. changed to the Nebraska School for 

1&gt;. 

ml all acts and parts of acts in conflict with this 

lied 

hereby rep 

ASH FIN 

he cash funds 

For mam .wars the question of the disposal of the easii tunus 

•ism;; in the various institutions lias been one of considerable 

ditical contention. In order that this may cease, and in order 

.(intention. In older that this may cease, and in order 

iai the superintendent of this school may be directed as to the 

•n/lent of this school may be directed as to the 
rsh that may from time to time come into his 

isposal of the cash that may from time to time come into his 

i.ss.-ssioii. I would ask for the following legislation on rliis sub- 

uld ask for the following legislation on rhis sub 

•cl : 

!e ii Enacted l»v the Legislature of the Slate of Nebraska: 
Section 1. That the superintendent of the School for the Deal 

ire of the Si 

Xebrask 

¦ndent of the School for the Deaf 

iperint 

&lt; hereby directed to send all cash that may come into his pos 

ish that may come into his pos 

n 

ession from the sale of articles from the industrial departments 

lie of articles from the industrial departments, 
luce from the garden, and from any and all 

ale of ashes, produce from the garden, and from any and al 

ources. to the state treasurer and to notify the state auditoi 

nd to notify the state auditor 

ism 

f the amount and when sent to the state treasurer. The state 

t and when sent to the state treasurer. The stat€ 

reasurer is hereby directed to keep said cash fund, known ai 

urer is hereby directed to keep said cash fund, known as 
("ash fund of the School for the Deaf." and to disburse the 

he -fash fund of the School for the Deaf." and to disburse th&lt; 

anie as hereinafter directed. 

Section 2. The superintendent may use the cash thus accn- 

uulated for the support and maintenance of the various depart 

uents of the said school only upon vouchers prepared and item- 

ed as required by law. for the disbursement of the appropriai,n 
for tin- maintenance of the said school. 

hereby authorized to draw 

he st 

aid fund upon the presentation of a warrant 

ale auditor in the form and manner provided by law 

the disbursement of the other funds belon&lt;;inji to the state </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
472 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

1 

Section 4. The state auditor shall not draw a warrant again* 
the said cash fund unless there is sufficient money in the fun&lt; 
drawn upon to pay said warrant. 

Section 5. The state treasurer shall not draw his chec 
against The said fund unless he actually has the cash belongin 
to such fund in his possession. 

Section 6. That acts and parts of acts in conflict with this a 
be and the same are hereby repealed. 

Section 7. Whereas an emergency exists, this act shall be ii 
fnll force and effect on and after its passage. 

In the following roll will be found the name, age, residence 
nativity, and date of admission of former and present studentto 
the institution, together with the present location of the grad 
uates, and whether or not self-sustaining: </seg>

            <seg id="p063">
473 

XSTITLTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

taiutei 

t 

ai a 

dG 

1O1 

imps f S g 
JO 8JB&lt;1 rmrmt 

i 

z 

&lt; 

[\VYl 

«n 3£ 2 2 

V 

¦c 

y. 

Z 

e 

• : SS e : S :8 S : : : : :8 :3 : : 
::::::: :&gt;&lt;&gt;&lt;z .&gt;&gt; ¦ &gt;•&gt;&lt; • ;¦_¦¦&gt; ¦.&gt;*:: 

'¦¦'.'•'.'¦ ja ; 
: : u '¦ ¦ '¦ "" '.'¦'.'.'.'¦¦'¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ ¦ '¦ ¦ 
lit ;lli!lllli!!l?I!!l3IJa 

¦XXXCDQOXXXJDODXXXXXXXXOOaOXQOaCXX 

: a a ¦ = = = = = = = = = = = = = = = = = ¦ S ¦ = 
; .1J : :.§.§J.§.i.§J.§JJ.IJJ.sJ.i-i -1 :| 
¦So ¦ ¦v»oSS«as«e«v«oo«o -5 -e 
= = : : = = 2 = = = 53 = = = = = H = a2 " = : I 
¦ •&lt; &lt; • •&lt; &lt;&lt;•&lt;&lt;;•&lt;&lt;&lt;! ¦&lt; &lt;i &lt;!&lt;¦&lt; -^ •&lt; : &lt; : ¦* 

•xxxxooxaoxxocxaoaoajooooxxxaoogtEoooox 

: : : : : jii-4 j :^ j j i^ !te :^ :f i ; ti 
fflflllJllll HlJij Hiili 
II fit liiliil iii| oil s^IhsI 

: o j : : : . : : j« : : 9 ; : : g : : : : : J : : 
Jt&amp;j&amp;JjUfiiljijiilii 
iillililiiiiililifiliiJii! </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
474 

LAND COMMISSIONER S REPORT. 

naiamj :•=:::: 
• XOS 
iW&gt; :&gt;.s 
pne 
-npcjo 

:::¦=: : : : : : : : : 
d . V- T. . . 1. '/¦ 7! BOW 
::::;z;:::q :&gt;&lt;:&gt;&lt;::&gt;&lt;::&gt;-:* ::&gt;.2;:» 
::::::::::::::: 5 ::::::::::: 
:::::::::::::::&gt;*::::::::::::: 

|w;v 

-npBJO 

¦ §¦ M ; i i M i M,i M M M M i i i M i ; i M 
1 \\\.\ ¦¦ \^\\\\\ ¦¦¦. :¦&amp;: ;;;;;;;;;; 
•- J : ;j3-; -8- ¦ : : s ¦ u L j 8 _¦:¦;:•¦.;: S 
• £5 :.5= :sfss i r .S 5 S g g ff3 :5 : :|3| : :| 
» l&amp;S I of 11 if :5t i-sll !¥¦»•= ¦= ¥o ««•£ 
" i £ * w v 5? — ™ * w ¦¦ S E S E *"* a " S ™ ' S 5^i*~'""_tt 
-sirapB S££E£££££££feS5SS£SS££££££S££S££ 
. ...... :; ......-.._ ........... 
•£¦ ce . cs c e e ss=s=e-.«. a -s;afc3=!;.es- 

r. 

J. 

X. 

a H.X 

U 

i 

• 8«f 

- ¦— i, — — wc*- 

.-JcgysilMW^y -yo -KOS&amp;.OX 

n0 F 8 o»'M?»o*'N?icc««co«r3'*r:Tr^»^f'^'^J t^»^"^«'^''T-^"icii3io 


simpe Sfe£E£££££££feS5SS£SS££££££SS£S££ 

jo o»«a 

y-: ? w 53c u HSsiH**H-§-3i-2— •«¦ 

1- S C m b b h h ' " " ' ' "S *C 1m *C " " *C " fl * 'C *U "C *E " "C 

g S5 s s = = S = : : : : : : = = = s : : s : £ : 2 a s a : £ : 

X &lt; x &lt;¦&lt;&lt;;&amp;amp;lt; &lt;&lt;¦&lt;•&lt; ¦ ¦&lt; -3 •¦&lt;&lt;•«;•&lt; •&lt; 

H ! : ¦ • • • •_ ¦ ¦ _: ¦ 

I 1 

00 ' jo aiBrr x»xxocz&gt;xaDx&gt;aoooi.&lt;Exxaca&gt;acxxr x ¦ x x x x x 

O ¦ ¦ -~. • : • • ;¦;;¦¦•;;: T~ :::.:'..:: 

j &gt;&gt; ::::&gt;&gt;::::::::: : 

| ii! !ti i^^if • iifi ; i it it : • Mi. 
I . |! f l!!| 1 |l ft! 
ll!l!Slll«ll!illl||l III fill! 

I . |! f l!!| 1 |l ft! 
ii!l!Slli«liriiii||iliif!i!l 

s J 

H 

-/: 

li^filiP-giirss^iiK 

u. 

XZ 

J«iSii**J*«tS* 

&lt; 

K a 

%"'!"" 

is" i = j i i i M \i i i M i i ;= i iiis ; i ij 

5 I S : 5 I E : : : ; : | : g&gt; J : : : &gt;.| = '• 3 1 f ¦ : : I 

z liilN&amp;s.ilsllislSjii'aiJggliJll 

tl 

e^a^SS^zlcSSSJ^^S^^o* </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
475 

INSTITUTE FOE THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

* I I 

I 

3, 

r- 1 xn 

x 

&lt; &lt; 

i 

*s 

*1 

v 

ii-sii jilii '¦¦¦sell : lil : s.lj§-= \ii i3|*iJ 
iilllifill if HI ; lit III 111, II Ifjll 
Jllllllll! ill!! illilinlilRiliQ 

lliililliggjlllllllliillllliltlltll 

ic- ¦ : c ' a c .sees . . c « = e a . .g . . . • g = -32 
ill il \H 1 i 111 Miilil | M i:ii ijj 

=11111111 -I i||H illllliiillliilliii 

8 tfii!f^,:^ :if^l«uiti|f|l!J1 
I | | Hill 
IitPli!!lI1|ilillliiIiIiIf!i1i!ii 

: i : i i : : : : : : jsj j j \ \ \ \ j ! jj ! ! ! ! \ : : : : 
i if JH^y i iiiif. %u till i»f | in ii! </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

476 

T 


b s ¦ ¦ a 

r 

&gt;¦ 

P»l« 

i 

-npeao 

I 

': 

¦ % S : : : e " • S : J ; : ' • _' : : : g 

0. 

? sir, 

* Hi IfflBWSflBIi 

-Kimp« ££E£xxx££xExociQDxxxxxxxooxocxiaox 

?&gt; "aoa'^ao""''nnD.p.o.a.3...ae 
x I I -SSJ I :J»g : : ijll j| J ;| || j j j| \Z 

z 5 .§§8--8§S.--apa-a-a£B.:S. 

¦ 

• 1« • •; 

a 

a 

JO »VK1 — — — • — — ~*r*r- — — — — r- — — ¦ 

0 

&gt;. 

3 

ss^Um^zmumiiHi 

c 

s i § I 

4, 

B 6 

X I 

» — C - * -* 

A -r m ,- &lt;e . — O 5 

&amp;!!ffi*-H«i1 

&lt; 

* £ :iss : :aas : : :aea :a : s £ s :a 
w •&lt;-&lt;¦&lt; ¦ -&lt;&lt;o ; : ;&amp;lt;-&gt;;&amp;amp;lt; :&lt; ;&amp;lt;x&lt; ;&amp;lt; 

If iliS 1 1 ii ili 

|p!i!!l:iii.lll||jl,i3- &amp; ii </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
477 

INSTITUTE FOE THE DEAF AND DUMB 


&gt; 

£ 

t 

i 

* 

&amp;0 *¦ '¦'¦'¦'¦¦'•'¦'¦'• a '¦•¦¦ 
a ¦? ' 3t «; . ....2 ... 

llllllillllilllllii^l! ;! ! mlml 

1C 

isiiiiisisill iislilliisl illiliilllll 

7 

5§ 

Miltilieiijl ill iiniiiijl \\\\\\\\\\ 

=c 

&lt; 

llslliiillilllii jiilil )\ j§ I jiliHIli 
M ; U i; i ; i^i i : : U; i i#: i ! i ! • I i ! i i ; I ! ! 

-.-, 

¦--. 

&gt;, 


»¦ a 

ii P iftllplf! iiifyfilt !l! ! 
fi|i%!l!l iiMliiiliiiliHllliili 

iliflJifiiff Illiyiiltlliili 


¦ «j 

13i« 

lll1^lf^4Kil^i 

ail ilH-sfMiMi 111 II Hji ill II sllsiIU 

¦Iillil^l!llll!iill|l 4 111i|!1!l!1lil 

X 

S w - ° 

i" : : I :::::::: ; : : '¦ '¦ * &amp; : • : • •' • • •¦ ••¦•:::::: 

IIS^J ; isiii il 

Si 2 

a: 

? t 


&gt;&gt;t- S 

a- 

|f|Sl35ag 

T 

?1?= 1 1 = 1 «¦=! siifj'Si? ilgM*. Ill i lili fill 

u: </seg>


            <seg id="p068">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

478 

-s'ns-j[8S 

I 

t«ie 

-upwo 

c 

r 


S2"^ 

aoi£ 

„„.„,, x x x i; x x x i r t' V -ir cc / X! x x x 66 x x x x x x x • ac 
-sirapb xxxxxxxtxxxxxxuooxxiodxxxxxxxx x 
jo ajcn — — — — — — . — — — — „„_ — — — — — — — — — — • — 

7, Z 

-/ 

r_ 

r 


7 

S J&lt; _- o £ -3 

¦r -M 

&gt;, j g -e -3 m 5 

D0Qint-i~UO&lt;5iJOa5t-Z?aSCJSi5OOO8SSSOWE-iC 


&lt;s :.s^i;.«.j :.:.:t;.5 : S -j js : £ i ¦ ¦« •* | 

M.= •= = 5 = =S = a!-«= : •= = : ¥ ?- 

h qww » -2 £ S 
&lt;E JO 31«a S 2. - i 

I sUfjiiJ iiliii=|-=ii!|liir^i^r 
1=1 « §l; ai itilli 11=1 if si al^sl^ </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
479 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DVMB. 

i. - - 

tc 

i. 

lilillliiiiiiliiiiiilililiiilliilii 

s'lsisictlSisiliSssssssfeississsi 

a 



£ &lt; 

— a _- 

oizc 

r 

If' 

! 

I 

9 

:i 



JC 

jl^^^s.^^ilSi* 

ll|ilS5l|il|JlIll|l|l||!l||h| 

111 
— o ja 

lllliillltlliiiJifif </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
480 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

S SB 

P»»« 

? 

£ I 

-npjwo :::::£ 

I 

t 


Hi'lliig Til 111 1 1 jil II i 1 1 

u 

w 

aois 

T£ai IllllllllllflllllllllllllllH 

smawi „•::: :::-g :::::: -o :: :ts 
-gns-jiag 5 : : : • S 8 S ¦ • • • I • • • I 
&gt;....&gt;&lt;:xq::::::q;;;~. 

NT « """ 'Si'" "~ "~ *T* w ¦— *¦•«?•" S 1 ! "^ 


&gt;* o « 

~c x *¦¦ </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
481 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

/. 

MM '\\\\\\ MMMiM;; \\jj\^\\\\^} 
' i^ ''''.'.'. \ '.'.'...'• 
¦ ¦ ¦ ;::;;«: 
! ; M i is i i i i i i i i hi \i U- i i i i ; ?jS ; ; ;i : • 
FIHliilitilif Illlit jlliIItsSfjiHO 

iiiiiiiii!!l!i!l!ii!!!!!!!!!!!!jlllll 

; c s ' o . a ::.... 
sa.e-08 ;¦ 
• 2 .2 • ¦- • ¦- :.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'¦'¦'¦'¦¦•¦• 
e » ¦.•'.•!•¦¦¦¦¦•••••• ¦ ' • -¦••••••••••-; 
¦&lt;¦&lt;:¦&lt;:¦&lt;::::::::: : : : : : _: J_^_' : : : : • : : " : '¦ 

III llii iiiilliliiiiiiliiiliilii illili 

»i&gt;»»^ &gt;&gt;?'&gt;•&gt;.= :^-i'^: i^iSgi ;5 : ; - : l^ k :^S^P 
iliilif II l! 1 1 islift M \mil 
lililililisllllillliliiiiiilililliiii 

¦= ¦¦;'::::::::'::-^-?=:='' : = : 
« ¦ • * ; • ; ; ; ; ., g - c ¦ - * 3 • 
l!lllllil3l!illllllll!l2llillllllllli </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
482 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 

I- 

-sns-j[8g :::::: t •: 1 :::::•• 

X 
a. 

s •: s 

p8}B 

1 

? 

-npsjo ; 

u 

i 

I 

a. 

t 

HOIS 

jeeosaaoooooaoocos ¦ -cocoooc 
IXIXXXIQOXfEXOOXSXCXX ¦ -XXXX30X3C 

-KHH|ii: 

B 

I 5 

t 

&lt;: 

e: 1 !+ a JH -£-i^xxt*f^aoxf-xxr^t^ • -^^ xjt^i't^j^ -r^r^t&gt;» 
jo ai«a xxxxxxxxxxxxx • xx aoxxSx xxx 
&amp;. : "" "" ~~ : :"~ : :~" — 

r. Ji 

- J£ 

V 

i 

zz 


c 

5ftixOOWOC5aiJO^OSfflQ3uwOii&amp;iIx2iMO 

L 

i 

5 ll^tllll 

a; 

i 

0; 

Jsiiii&amp;jiiiSjiKjji 

Ilililliilliiillllllllllllil 

::___. u s — _: 5 •= s •::,.•••¦¦¦¦¦¦ 

ft! HP!! </seg>


            <seg id="p073">
483 

INSTITUTE FOE THE DEAF AND DUMB. 


£ 

5 X • X 

X -XX) ¦ X 

a — 

— S3, 3«-s, ;* i,— 
=*&gt; &gt;. iagg&lt;2 Si ¦*&gt; &gt;&gt; 

s — 

5 ¦•= 5 .5 «, - 
= ae"3 - •= m 
o = i; I. r = 

3C • 00 OD QD 00 

Islllislilsiilalsrflllisila 

:::;;=::=:;:: j J \ j j = j j j \&amp; j j j : j j 
. :j= ::::: :.n :::::::::::: :.a ::::: 
. . . ac • .-a ¦ • ¦ an a« 
... s ¦¦¦¦•¦ P s 
- . . © . • ¦ . . g S - • - • 
I !? '-hH gill : - S-gl i i ll 1 1 jll ¦ 1 i '¦¦!&amp; 
ll is jli!lf»dsIssilsllfKh ill 

CO CO * QD OP GD HO GO GD 00 30 GD QC TO 00 GO GO 00 GO 3D OD 00 00 00 00 CD 

0Lt^O;|^(--J^^CCC QD "DOOOOCO'X 1 "XXX l^" 3D 00 t^QDQOCDQCdDQDGO t^* 
GO 00 OC QC QU GO 3C GO GO GO QC 00 3C 3D • 3L GO QD QC 00 GO GD 3D QU 00 00 JD QD X! 

::::t:"::-S &gt; ::::i&gt;::: : =: : : ::::::: 
U ;1 :|^ il*'»ii&gt;ii ii^i"! : S :: i* ::-:: 
• a ¦ =H = s ' — c = = = S -suo«&gt;. &gt;&gt;— Ss— &gt;&gt;^t: 
: -"35= £ a _"°O - - - = ¦?* - -- r &lt;""-;x o"aJ t - -~ 
:| &lt; El|s2|fl^lnpS|Sj|i3l||I|H^R 

ll»|g|illliil|iifiiliiiliiMli 
i siti*5 B *S?«*i*3aa i :a«"K»«g*j2|| </seg>

            <seg id="p074">
484 

LAXD COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

SJaiQpu 

»¦&gt; 

c 

l s lll 

K SJ « 

¦5 eDCJ'-ocSIoi^-'S* 
5 ¦s&amp;g5§?l?'M|"g£5 

tlil y if im </seg>

            <seg id="p075">
485 

INSTITUTE FOR THH DEAF AND DUMB. 

M j M 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ! |g 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 

: u : ::::::,::::::::::: :::::::::: g :::: 
sl33ssg|33 :|| :3 8.33ig3|3 :«ig gig : 1 : l : i*_ 
S^-S'SJJ I o' a '3'5 gJS'S 8'3.S-"5"3.2-l'3 ""S : Slots' :g :- "¦ o o-g 
liffilllllltlllilllilllissiliiliiisil 

iiiiiililllillllliiiillliliililliiiis 

x oc x ao x oc S S x 3D oo ao oo x x 3d x od x ao oo oo oo x x ¦ x x x x x x oo ;2£i 

¦'::: i'i'^ 1 : : : : : : ' ' : ¦ • '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ '¦ 
iilfl tt iiWfjff if !f!f f i f t f f 1 !lt! 
i !pll lIiMllM SiSlfl t 1 ! 
ii|l1llii|lllfi|iliillfllrffl|^lilfl 
iiiiiiiiiiiiiliiliiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiil 

ii!ii!iiliiliipii!!iiiiiiiiii 
iiiiiSiiiiiiiiliiiiii </seg>

            <seg id="p076">
486 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 

X 

Saimei 

p»»« 

-njway 

I 

i 

M 


sias? 

M 

7 

si|-siJ :S 

c 

IfMIBlflHfilff III 

a 

aotG 

¦simp, ssissssisslisliiisiilsifilil 
jo aj^j »-« — -, — — -. — _,_«„„__„„„„ .„_„, , 

&gt;-. 

DC 

5 s 

iTmVi llSllsSiiilSiililll iiisliiiil 
b. I -"-i-"-""-i~-"«-i — — -&lt;-«~~&gt;«x.«_ .„„„„„„, 
O . i —r : 

- -. - 

|ill||||||||||||l||||ilIM 

S5 

« 3 

jj o *; M ~ - -c-^-»* 

««s 

5 

i 

r 

soaiaoSi. 

S.3d*3&lt;5::s&lt;3 = S35E:3.5« :£;55 :&amp; 

***£ 

II I ill' lit l^iliif :*8&gt;U£ 8 i 
I ajij hfliiji IsiJfliiyi I 

= 

= Z£ «¦£*» 

a &lt; x 5 us c -5 z i &lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p077">
487 

NSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

r 

8. ae 

| 

m. 

3 

&lt;. 

X 

V 4&gt; 

:C 

ac-S naaca 

ZOO 

XO 

xXxxoiouxxxt: rx 

I. -I 

iiaxxao ¦ x x x x rxooacaoxx 
-aoacxxa 

c 

SSI 

S s §8» 

a 

¦ 

I (&gt;&lt;&gt;.« I U 

&gt; 

f ?• 


;ju 

t£ 

cans 

C 


*c 

¦f. 

£ 

. a . r • • •»». ¦ « _ ¦ • ¦ — — -— • ¦ _ — • « 
5 «5|J : : = .? s J s =.?^ s a o = a B -g = a^.3 
£io£^ : : £ co'as ss £ &lt;5 £ z oj"&lt;5 w 3 3 -; ;s t5 6 z tn* 

» CC X&gt; CO CO ir~ t"~ !"*• t^* f^ I*" t"~ 1^* t"" I s " l^~ IS t^» ("• (*• l^» QC QD CD OD QO 
~. C. ~ * Cd C^ 3t 33 CI ~ » ~ ~ -. « ~. C: * « S 3) O X ?: 3*. 
XXXiXDXXXIIOOIIXXlXllIXXXCDa) 

sasa = = = = = = = = = = = = = = cc 
« w « 2 « .« g » - — " -- 2 "3 .2 .s •- ¦- •- -2 
"u 'C "C •— *E '^ 'u "C *C "Z "Z'Z."C £ *C "E "C E *i- "t, 
' ¦ ¦ * ¦ QQ rtj 1j 
: : : : : :as=j2S2 = = = g3=-S = £ = = aa 

xc:o?&gt;
487 

NSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

r 

8. ae 

| 

m. 

3 

&lt;. 

X 

V 4&gt; 

:C 

ac-S naaca 

ZOO 

XO 

xXxxoiouxxxt: rx 

I. -I 

iiaxxao ¦ x x x x rxooacaoxx 
-aoacxxa 

c 

SSI 

S s §8» 

a 

¦ 

I (&gt;&lt;&gt;.« I U 

&gt; 

f ?• 


;ju 

t£ 

cans 

C 


*c 

¦f. 

£ 

. a . r • • •»». ¦ « _ ¦ • ¦ — — -— • ¦ _ — • « 
5 «5|J : : = .? s J s =.?^ s a o = a B -g = a^.3 
£io£^ : : £ co'as ss £ &lt;5 £ z oj"&lt;5 w 3 3 -; ;s t5 6 z tn* 

» CC X&gt; CO CO ir~ t"~ !"*• t^* f^ I*" t"~ 1^* t"" I s " l^~ IS t^» ("• (*• l^» QC QD CD OD QO 
~. C. ~ * Cd C^ 3t 33 CI ~ » ~ ~ -. « ~. C: * « S 3) O X ?: 3*. 
XXXiXDXXXIIOOIIXXlXllIXXXCDa) 

sasa = = = = = = = = = = = = = = cc 
« w « 2 « .« g » - — " -- 2 "3 .2 .s •- ¦- •- -2 
"u 'C "C •— *E '^ 'u "C *C "Z "Z'Z."C £ *C "E "C E *i- "t, 
' ¦ ¦ * ¦ QQ rtj 1j 
: : : : : :as=j2S2 = = = g3=-S = £ = = aa 

xc:o?&gt;^&gt; -ti — fti.ixaohhfttrsiNOhNMWifl * 
h t 1 3! h C! '313500 QO QD 00 fl&amp; QD OD QC -C CC 35 {"» 3C OD 35 31 t^ 
QD QD QD QD 00 ¦ QD OD QD OD QO 00 CC 3C QO QD QD 3C QD QD 3D QD OU "JC QD • 
::::::::£•:::: :i&gt; :::::: ic :':: 
• x= o • .^...r. 
_ — «••••«»¦• O*-* 
Ifflf ft iffffiJiii^flf 
mil t?ifflHi!i 
!;yi lifiiiiiUiiiyiliii 

;...— ..^&gt;... .^« 
id : ijiiilij j ; ;ii|i gt; -ti — fti.ixaohhfttrsiNOhNMWifl * 
h t 1 3! h C! '313500 QO QD 00 fl&amp; QD OD QC -C CC 35 {"» 3C OD 35 31 t^ 
QD QD QD QD 00 ¦ QD OD QD OD QO 00 CC 3C QO QD QD 3C QD QD 3D QD OU "JC QD • 
::::::::£•:::: :i&gt; :::::: ic :':: 
• x= o • .^...r. 
_ — «••••«»¦• O*-* 
Ifflf ft iffffiJiii^flf 
mil t?ifflHi!i 
!;yi lifiiiiiUiiiyiliii 

;...— ..
487 

NSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB 

r 

8. ae 

| 

m. 

3 

&lt;. 

X 

V 4&gt; 

:C 

ac-S naaca 

ZOO 

XO 

xXxxoiouxxxt: rx 

I. -I 

iiaxxao ¦ x x x x rxooacaoxx 
-aoacxxa 

c 

SSI 

S s §8» 

a 

¦ 

I (&gt;&lt;&gt;.« I U 

&gt; 

f ?• 


;ju 

t£ 

cans 

C 


*c 

¦f. 

£ 

. a . r • • •»». ¦ « _ ¦ • ¦ — — -— • ¦ _ — • « 
5 «5|J : : = .? s J s =.?^ s a o = a B -g = a^.3 
£io£^ : : £ co'as ss £ &lt;5 £ z oj"&lt;5 w 3 3 -; ;s t5 6 z tn* 

» CC X&gt; CO CO ir~ t"~ !"*• t^* f^ I*" t"~ 1^* t"" I s " l^~ IS t^» ("• (*• l^» QC QD CD OD QO 
~. C. ~ * Cd C^ 3t 33 CI ~ » ~ ~ -. « ~. C: * « S 3) O X ?: 3*. 
XXXiXDXXXIIOOIIXXlXllIXXXCDa) 

sasa = = = = = = = = = = = = = = cc 
« w « 2 « .« g » - — " -- 2 "3 .2 .s •- ¦- •- -2 
"u 'C "C •— *E '^ 'u "C *C "Z "Z'Z."C £ *C "E "C E *i- "t, 
' ¦ ¦ * ¦ QQ rtj 1j 
: : : : : :as=j2S2 = = = g3=-S = £ = = aa 

xc:o?&gt;^&gt; -ti — fti.ixaohhfttrsiNOhNMWifl * 
h t 1 3! h C! '313500 QO QD 00 fl&amp; QD OD QC -C CC 35 {"» 3C OD 35 31 t^ 
QD QD QD QD 00 ¦ QD OD QD OD QO 00 CC 3C QO QD QD 3C QD QD 3D QD OU "JC QD • 
::::::::£•:::: :i&gt; :::::: ic :':: 
• x= o • .^...r. 
_ — «••••«»¦• O*-* 
Ifflf ft iffffiJiii^flf 
mil t?ifflHi!i 
!;yi lifiiiiiUiiiyiliii 

;...— ..^&gt;... .^« 
id : ijiiilij j ; ;ii|i gt;... .^« 
id : ijiiilij j ; ;ii|i </seg>

            <seg id="p078">
488 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

8niniB} 

£ 

pajc 

-npwo 


¦ 

. • . to w . . (m »•.... 
£ : : : ll5 : |-s2-- :«|s ' : 33 :3 33 

X 

3&gt; : « S "5 8 

V « O ' W ft) -c 
1 1 g :!| - ff-g 
oj (c S - a! z; uz 

s.-Sb'ss's&amp;a :&amp; ;aE 
ig«S!;S§§ : § • § g 

-simp^ liliilliliillllllllllllllllll 

aacaaacfloscsascoa ' c 

J.I .1.1 sj ssssississsglgsi 
*¦ *- S- fc« *u *E "C *»- 't. 'E 'C 'b 'tl *C *C "C "E "C 'C *C "C 
S|££_=SES|2 = = h| = = S = = = S = 

JO *1U(2 »ooi»ao»ijjxocoeaDxxx3DtCDxx» • -ccaooDacSocx 

t( 

X 

f-iifiosH'ffS ?i oil ssli 5^ s" I s « * •5'S 


S««-5^ 

x 5 

y. 

o o f 
H3 J 


S 

&gt;&gt; 
P 
P ~~7~ 

&gt;&gt; &amp;-&gt; &gt;¦. 

Ipllfllllfiilflfillfiil- 

&lt; E o . ¦ "S : : S ¦- ; : : «, : £ g : : : : * : * • .• * _ ; s 

"2T- </seg>


            <seg id="p079">
489 

INSTITUTE FOE THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

•- 

£ 

¦ 

¦ 

a : . ¦ • . : "s 

V • 

x 

* S n t - : : : t : : : : w : j : : : : : :s : : • • 1 • • i 
Hii Uliilii^iiiiilliiM 1 

* ¦ o 

1) 

ii i-iflil I! 

-&gt; »; 

o a S a — X ¦» .ir a *a 

i* 

iilllll] iinMnu is i II IJiiJ H 

i. 

&gt; 


iilifiiiliipiiiipiiii! ill illlll ill! 

x 

|- :^| :jj«j :|i" isi-siti'iSai'lN 

3-2 a 

a o a o a s o 


s 

5«o 


5C 

ilH^s 


u£«c 

a. 

s © -r 

£i.i,^3ia-35aaaoK.2o3!ziO 

r 

-&lt; 

Si : -s : is :J 

&gt;-.- 

i-a:;i3;.i|i2| B «| 

x 

Ililililiislliiill2lll5gai5g5 


~ ¦ S : * = 

=£ 

&gt;= =» . * 

1**1111 iii i?=i:-r nit m mi p 

O x^ Qao30^54.0-«:0*'J 

1 1 iijll iillJUfP ii isill i </seg>

            <seg id="p080">
490 

LAND COMMISSIONER 

S REPORT 

a 

hi 

5 

i 

Snouts} 
-gns-j[3g 

PSJB 

-ninuo 

e 

¥ 

5^ 

ao O! S6 32 * cc 

aois 

O o 

-simps 

¦*-, 

S5 

JO 81B&lt;T QDXXXXXXCDX 

&gt;. 

&gt;. 

O i" S " 3 

1 a!*-25*isll 

ss»» 

M 


irf«53g 

lilllii 


a ?£ M # 

3- 

5 : : :a ; ;3 
*i ! :"&amp; ! !"» 

o &gt; £ 
¦a =£ S </seg>

            <seg id="p081">
491 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

The fol 

iwing table will show enrollment by counties: 

9 Howard 

o 

\dams 

. . . . 2 Jefferson 8 

Antelop' 

14 Johnson 8 

1 

ioone 

Buffalo 10- Kearney 6 

. . . . 10 Knox 6 

1 

iuri 

9 Lancaster 32 

1 

in! 

Box Butte 2 Lincoln 2 

w 

3 Madison 4 

Bovd 

(Jass 12 Merrick 4 

'edai 

9 &gt;*ance 3 

&lt; 

Hiase 1 Xemaha 15 

•&gt; 

Oherrv 2 Nnckolls Z 

; 

Chevenne 10 Otoe 17 

5 Pawnee 6 

f'lav 

7 Perkins 1 

olfax 

d Phelps 

0 

4 Pierce 3 

1 &gt;ak( 

8 Platte 7 

2 Polk 11 

1 &gt;awe 

Dawsnn 8 Bed Willow 4 

1 &gt;eue 

1 Richardson 21 

1 &gt;ixon 6 Rock 1 

Dodge 12 Saline 19 

Douglas 109 Sarpy 

Douglas 

109 Sarpy 8 

109 Sarpy 

8 

Fill more 2 Saunders . . 

2 Saunders 15 

15 

Fillmore 2 Saunders 

Franklin 1 Seward 

Franklii 

1 Seward S 

1 Seward 3 

Furnas 8 Sheridan . . 

Furnas 

S Sheridan 5 

8 Sheridan 5 

ft Sherman 1 

Gage !) Sherman . . 

Oae 

9 Sherman 1 

(rosper 4 stanton . . . 

(rosp&lt; 

1 Stanton 2 

4 Stanton 

¦-&gt; 

Greeley 3 Thurston . . 

(1 reeli 

3 Thurston 1' 

3 Thurston 1 

Hall 10 Thayer . .. 

Hall 

10 Thaver 6 

10 Thayer 6 

Hamilton 6 Valley 

6 Valley . " 

r » Vallev . 7 

HainilT&lt; 

- Washington ft 

Harlan - Washington 

Washington 

9 

Hayes '¦' Wayne . . . 

'¦' Wayne 1 

Wavnt 

1 

Hitchcock 3 Webster .. 

. Webster 5 

?&gt; Webster 5 

Hitcl 

Holt »* York 5 </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
492 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

The following as "cause of deafness" will show what 

diseas 

most seriously effect the hearing 

Congenital ISO 

Brain fever 

Scarlet fever 52 

Whooping-cough 
Earache 

u 
L2 

Typhoid fever 15 Earache 12 

Fever, kind unknown IT Fall in infancy S 

Fall in infancy 
( 'old 

Scrofula 7 &lt; 'old 7 

Measles Hi Lung fever 4 

Measles 1 •! 

Lung fever 
Fits 

t 

Cholera infantum 3 Fits ." 

Cholera infantum 

Catarrh 5 Inflammation of the brain, i 

Catarrh 

Inflammation of 

the 1 

I 

rain 

Abscess in ears 4 Paralysis '2 

Abscess in ears 4 

Paralvsi 

Pneumonia '2 Worms 1 

Pneumonia 

Worm 

1 

Yellow fever 1 Malaria 1 

Yellow fever 1 

Malaria 

Quinsy 1 I Mphtheria 5 

Quinsy 1 

Diphtheria 

Intermittent fever 1 1 &gt;ysentery 1 

Dropsy of brain 1 Bronchitis 2 

Congestion 1 La grippe VA 

La grippe 
Unknown 

Cramps 1 Unknown IM1 

'ii » 

Spinal meningitis IUI 
In concluding this report permit me to express my apprecia- 

Spinal meningitis 

In concluding this report pern 

it me to express niv apprf 

tion of The earnest painstaking attention to duty on the parr of 

tion of The earnest painstaking a 
each and everv one employed al 

tention to dutv 

pai 

each and every one employed about the school. This has been 

the scho 

very helpful, and has aided in producing that harmony so essen 

very helpful, and has aid* 
tial to the success of the 

1 

tial to the success of the various departments. T desire, also. To 

partments. I 

i. 

IS 

thank you as a board, and as individuals, for your ever ready 

thank you as a board 

divid 

hi 

assistance by suggestive words of counsel and encouragement. 

assistance by suggestive w&lt; 
This perfect harmonv of as: 

n 

i&lt; 

This perfect harmony of association, a unity of purpose on Th* 1 

as 

part of The Governor, the Board of Trustees, and rlie superin- 

part of the Governor, the Board 
tendent has had a beneficial effpi 

ti 

l 

supt 

'ect on all our people, 
almighty God for His 1 
that is good for our de 
his. the twelfth bienni 

With a prayer of thanks to 
in The past and asking for all 
future. I respectfully submit 

ind 

n 

il repf 

of the Nebraska Institute for the !&gt;&lt;&gt;af and Dumb fo 

1899 and 1900. 

H. E. Dawes, Superi </seg>

            <seg id="p083">
493 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Pi 

i 

n 

n 

in 

l,i 

I 

i 


I 

f 

i 

I 

GENERAL I NFORM ATION. 

The Nebraska School for the Deaf, established iu 1809, occu- 

is six large and commodious brick buildings and three small 
une ones, situated upon twenty-three acres of ground in the 
uthwestern portion of the city of Omaha. Of the buildings 
rntioned, two were constructed last year; engine, boiler, pump 
ill coal house at a cost of f 7.700. and a three-story pressed 
irk and stone, with slate roof, school building costing f25.000. 
There are twenty-one teachers employed to give instruction 
the manual and oral (.speech in lip-reading) departments of 

literary school, the kindergarten, manual training, schools 

sewing, laundry work, printing, typewriting, tine art, shoe 
ndiiiK. and horticulture and floriculture. There are also em- 

nved four supervisors to look after the children and care for 

r clothing, fourteen officers and helpers, a physician and two 

Indoor and outdoor amusements are provided, such as foot-11, 
baseball, and lawn tennis in season, bowling, swings. 

mil other sjwrts 

nee the establishment of the school there has been enrolled 

pupils, of which seventeen have graduated, of these eight 
¦ graduated in the last three years i numbers as shown by the 

¦&lt;-ord&gt;. Tliere arc thirty who claim to have been graduated, 
wo of our graduates are attending Gallandet College at Washitrton. 
P. C. 

There lias been appropriated by the legislature of Nebraska 
i the education of the deaf of the state three quarters of a 

llion dollars (estimated^. This amount has been expended in 
• erection of buildings, repairs of the same, and the main- 

nance of the school 

tool is a part of the public school system of the state. 

urse of study, anil carrying instruction up to 

he ninth grade. The tuition is free to residents of the state. 
Mipils outside of the state are charged S200 per year for in- 

ruction and care. </seg>

            <seg id="p084">
494 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

It is sometimes very difficult to get information in reference 
to deaf children that ought to be in school. Any person reading 
these lines and having knowledge of a child too deaf to acquire 
an education in the common public schools would be doing a 
kindly act by writing to the superintendent, giving such information 
as he may have in reference to said child. 

All persons interested in the education of the deaf are cordially 
and earnestly invited to visit the school and see what is 
being accomplished. 

• The following extract from the law appears at the head of 
our application blanks, a copy of which follows. It, is our custom 
to regard deaf and dumb as two separate classifications, and 
to receive them both whon of suitable age and capacity and of 
good moral character: 

Section 15, chapter 2ti, General Laws of Nebraska. 1897. provides 
that "all the deaf and dumb residents of this state, and 
those deaf to such an extent that they cannot acquire an education 
in the common schools of the state, of suitable age and 
capacity and of good moral character, shall be entitled to an 
education in the institute for the deaf and dumb without 
charge." 

Section 16, same chapter, provides that the parents or guard 
ians of pupils admitted to the school shall furnish suitable 
clothing, pay transportation expenses to and from school, nut 
support said pupil during the summer vacation. 

Section 12. same chapter, provides that the superintendent's 
report shall contain certain information in regard to the deaf 
of the state, and it is also desirable that as much as possible 
of the family history of the pupil be known in order that an 
intelligent understanding may be had of the condition of the 
child. 

That this information may be had. the parent or guardian is 
asked to answer the following questions when making applica 
tion on this form for the admission of pupils: </seg>

            <seg id="p085">
495 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

d 

1 

APPLICATION FOR ADMISSION 

1. "What is the full name of the child? 

In what year, month, and day was the child born? 
Where was the child born? 

4. Give full name of father and mother? 

5. If either or both parents are dead please give cause of 
eath? 

(&gt;. What is the occupation or profession of the father? 
7. What is the nationality of the father? * 
8. What are the names and ages of the applicant's brothers, 

isters in order commencing with the oldest? 

!•. Are any of the brothers or sisters deaf, dumb, or blind or 
jartially so? IMease give condition and cause in each case. 

10. Has the applicant any deaf, blind, or dumb relatives? If 
please give name, age, address, relationship, and occupation. 
11. Was there any blood relation between the parents before 

iiarriage. If so, what? 

ll\ What is the cause of the applicant's deafness? 
13. At what age did deafness occur? 

14. If born deaf, can you assign any cause? 
15. Can the applicant hear any? If so. what sound 

lfi. Has the applicant ever been in school? If so. when, 
where, and how long? 

17. Is the applicant of sound mind, in good health, free from 
dilv deformity, immoral habits, and contagious diseases? 
18. Has the applicant been vaccinated, had the smallpox, the 

isles, mumps, or whooping-cough? 

\ 

19. Are von a citizen of Nebraska? 

20. Give name, address, post office, county, and township of 
parent or guardian with whom we shall correspond in regard 
to the child. 

21. If the post office is not at a railroad station, give the name 
of the railroad and station nearest the home of the child. 
This application dated this .... day of 19. .. 

Vddress your correspondence in regard to the' child to the 

Superintendent of the School for the Deaf. 

Omaha. Nebr. 


• </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>