<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Experiment Station Circular 27</title>
               <date value="1925">1925</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Lincoln, Nebraska EXPERIMENT STATION CIRCULAR 27 List of Available Publications, July 1, 1925 Publications of the Agricultural Experiment Station and the Agri - cultural Extension Service are sent free to all persons requesting them. Because of the cost of publication no regular mailing list to which all bulletins are sent can be maintained. Individuals should request the specific bulletins in which they are interested. Firms or individuals desiring to distribute large quantities of bulletins ■will be supplied with them at the cost of publication, but the printing of any personal advertising matter on such bulletins is prohibited. New Bulletins The following are brief synopses of new bulletins issued by the College of Agriculture from January 1, 1925, to July 1, 1925. EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETINS Bulletin 206. — Annual Forage Crops. The early and medium late varieties of sweet sorghum together with Sudan grass and Common and German millet comprise the most important annual forage crops suitable for hay in this state. In a comparative 4-year test of 24 varieties of annual forage crops at the Nebraska Experimental Station, the sweet sorghums proved most productive of cured forage. Complete details of the experiments with all Nebraska forage crops are contained in this bulletin. Bulletin 207. — The Spindle-Tuber Disease. The spindle-tuber disease is one of the most prevalent potato diseases occurring in all parts of Nebraska. It does much damage to the crop in that it reduces the yield and injures the market quality. Recommendations for con - trol are (a) selection of a good strain of seed potatoes as free as possible from this and other diseases, (b) selection of the best type tubers for planting in a seed plat, (c) isolating this seed plat from all other potato fields by a distance of at least 300 feet, (d) roguing this plat severely, early, and frequently, removing all suspicious looking plants, (e) selection of tubers of best type produced in tiiis plat for use in the seed plat the following year and using the remainder of the potatoes for the commercial planting. Bulletin 208. — Hog Prices. The more important forces affecting hog prices are described in this bulletin — supply and demand, cost of production, market strategy, monopoly, the quantity of money in cir - culation and the rapidity with which it circulates, credit, transportation costs, commercial costs, and import duties. Corn and hog ratios are discussed. The bulletin also takes up the monthly and yearly variations in hog receipts and hog prices, pork exports, and cycles in hog pro - duction. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Circular 25. — Tuberculosis of Swine. A popular discussion of the entire matter with special reference to extensive investigations carried on by the University of Nebraska. Evidence has been furnished to show that in some sections avian infection may be a more prolific cause of tuberculosis among hogs than bovine infection. Preventive meas - ures are discussed. Circular 27. — List of Available Publications EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETINS Research Bulletin 29. — Further Studies on the Effect of Environ - ment on Potato Degeneration Diseases. A scientific publication. Readers interested in popular bulletins on potato diseases should order Experiment Station Bulletin 207 and Extension Circular 1256. Research Bulletin 30. — An Inquiry Into the Cause of the Increase of Tuberculosis of Swine. A detailed report of the investigations at the University of Nebraska. Readers interested in a popular dis - cussion of the subject should order Experiment Station Circular 25. EXTENSION CIRCULARS Circular 126. — Cereal Smuts and Their Control. Describes the smuts of small grains, their occurrence and distribution. Outlines the formaldehyde treatment for smuts of oats, barley, and sorghums, and the copper carbonate treatment for stinking smut of wheat and the loose smut of barley and wheat. Circular 127. — Seed Corn Testing. Outlines the rag doll and indi - vidual ear test methods. Gives suggestions for picking seed ears and for shipping seed corn. Circular 128. — Barberry Eradication in Nebraska. Gives the re - sults obtained by the first complete survey of Nebraska and other wheat producing states in barberry eradication. Outlines the relation of the barberry to wheat rust and the reasons why this bush should be destroyed. Circular 228. — Farm Slaughter of Hogs. Gives directions for farm butchering, handling, and curing of pork. Illustrates each important step of butchering with a clear-cut picture. Gives directions for can - ning, salting, and smoking meats, and for making sausages and soaps. Circular 229. — Feedometer. A set of two circular disks fastened together in such a way as to give the farmer all the boiled down, prac - tical suggestions he can use about feeding every farm animal. Can be hung with one nail on any door or in a 9 x 9 inch space on the wall. Circular 1256. — Two Important Groups of Nebraska Potato Dis- eases. Describes (1) potato wilt and tuber rots and (2) "run-out" potatoes caused by degeneration diseases. Suggestions for control of diseases. Circular 1257. — Grape Growing in Nebraska. Deals particularly with the care and pruning of young vineyards but also discusses in detail the varieties adaptable to Nebraska, the planting of a young vine - yard, and the marketing of grapes. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Circular 1258. — Cane and Busk Fruits for Nebraska. Recom- rants that produce best in Nebraska and discusses how to plant and care for each of them. Circular 1418. — The Poultry Industry in Nebraska. Emphasizes the marketing phase of the poultry industry after it tells thru graphs and figures that Nebraska ranks as one of the loading- poultry producing states in the country. Gives reasons why the poultry industry should pay a larger profit in Nebraska than in many other states. MIMEOGRAPHED CIRCULARS Circular 228. — Farm Slaughter of Hogs. Circular 518. — Program for Town or Rural Community. Circular 520. — February Program. Circular 521. — Arbor Day Program. Circular 1427. — Suggestions for a Grading System for the Pro- Circular 1504. — Life History and Control of Army Cutworm. Circular 1 600. — Improving Farm News. Circular 1601. — Project Story Examples. Circular 1602. — Writing That First Sentence of a News Item. MISCELLANEOUS PUBLICATIONS Thirty-Eighth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Sta- tion. Presented to the Governor February 2, 1925. Outlines the ex - perimental work being carried on at the station. Book of Views of the College of Agriculture of the University of Nebraska. Contains sixteen full-page pictures of the campus and activities of the institution. Annual Catalog of the College of Agriculture. Describes the course and requirements of the College of Agriculture, including work in home economics Annual Catalog of the School of Agriculture. Describes the sec ndary or high school agricultural and home economics courses. Illustrated Folder describing the activities of the School of Agri - culture. Just Over the Hill. A folder describing the new poultry course of the School of Agriculture. Home Economics at the University of Nebraska. An illustrated circular describing the work of that department. Available Bulletins The bulletins listed below are publications issued before January 1, 1925, and still available for distribution. Mimeographed extension circulars are also included here. For the convenience of the reader publications are here classified according to subjects. ducer of Market Eggs. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Circular 2 Pump Irrigation in Nebraska Circular 14 Hog Houses for Nebraska Circular 13 Nebraska Tractor Law and Bulletin 200 Results of Tractor Tusts Rules for Official Testa EXTENSION CIRCULARS 701 Price List of Stock Blue Prints 708 South Facing Colony Hog House 709 The Sanitary Privy 70S Sewage Disposal for Farm Homes 705 The " Midwest " Four-Horse Sweep and Stacker 710 North and South Colony Hog House 720 Pit. Semi-Pit, and Bank Silos 700 The "Midwest" Branding and De - horning Chute 721 Dairy Barns 1248 Preservative Treatment of Fence 707 Suggested Manual-Training Exercises in Forge Work ana Carpentry Posts AGRONOMY EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Bulletin 179 Winter Wheat in Western gation Nebraska Bulletin 193 Grain Production at North Bulletin 188 Productive Seed Corn Platte Bulletin 190 Crop Rotations Under Irri- Bulletin 201 Spring Small Grains EXTENSION CIRCULARS 101 Seeding Meadows and Pastures 102 Pasture Crops — What to Plant 103 Judging Oats 114 Nebraska Weeds 120 Wheat in Nebraska 121 Soy Beans in Nebraska 122 Sweet Clover in Nebraska 123 Soil Washing 104 Judging Wheat 105 Judging Barley 109 Black Stem Rust 124 Use Copper Carbonate Dust for Stink- 110 Cereal Smuts and Their Control 112 Milling Qualities of Kanred Wheat inK Smut in Wheat ANIMAL HUSBANDRY EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Circular 14 Hog Houses in Nebraska Circular 17 Common Intestinal Round- Bulletin 174 Beef Production Bulletin 175 Hog Feeding worm of Swine Bulletin 194 Lamb Feeding Experiments in Circular 21 The Abortion Problem in Farm Livestock Western Nebraska Bulletin 197 Winter Lamb Feeding Bulletin 204 Fattening Western Lambs Circular 23 Bovine Tuberculosis Bulletin 173 Supplementary Feeds in Fat- tening Lambs EXTENSION CIRCULARS 5 Disinfection and Disinfectants 201 The Ewe at Lambing Time 202 The Sow at Farrowing Time 203 The Sow and Her Litter 214 Judging Fat Steers 215 The Lamb in the Farm Flock 217 A System of Eradicating Intestinal Worms in Pigs 204 Pigs on Pasture 206 Handling Wool 207 Market Ewes 221 Prevention of Swine Diseases 222 Sanitation in Hog-Raising 223 Prevention of Hog Cholera 224 Synopsis of the Diseases of Swine 225 Bull-Nose in Pigs 208 Judging Mutton Breeding Sheep 209 Judging Beef Breeding Cattle 210 Judging Breeding Hogs 226 More About Hog-Lot Sanitation 227 A Flock of Sheep on the Farm 228 Farm Slaughtering of Hogs 211 Judging Draft Horses 212 Judging Mutton Sheep 213 Judging Fat Hogs </seg>
            <seg id="p005">EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Circular 22 Ice Cream Ingredients Circular 24 Better Sires — Better Stock Bulletin 181 Growth Studies of Dairy- Bulletin 184 Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers II Bulletin 20$ Ice Cream Formulas and Heifers I Standardization EXTENSION CIRCULARS 5 Disinfection and Disinfectants 7 Nebraska Tuberculosis Law — 1923 603 Cheese in Nebraska 604 Feeding Dairy Cows Under Nebraska 45 Handling the SilaKe 601 Judging Dairy Cows Conditions 620 Board and Boom 602 Cow Testing Associations ENTOMOLOGY (Insects, Birds, Rodents) EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS 183 Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers EXTENSION CIRCULARS 1106 Control of Household Pests 1501 Destroying Pocket Gophers 1502 Directions for Poisoning Prairie Doss 1503 Directions for Poisoning Rats FARM MANAGEMENT — MARKETING — COUNTRY LIFE (Rural Economics and Rural Sociology) Farm Management EXTENSION CIRCULARS 800 Analyzing the Farm Business 802 Labor Requirements for Nebraska 803 Share-Cash Farm Lease 804 Stock-Share Lease Crops Marketing EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Bulletin 187 Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains EXTENSION CIRCULARS 64 Cooperative Elevators 1303 Articles and By-Laws for a Co - operative Livestock Shipping Asso - ciation 1302 Articles and By-Laws for a Co- operative Cream Company Country Life EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS Bulletin 202 Landlords of Nebraska Farms EXTENSION CIRCULARS 501 General Picnic Suggestions 502 Old Settlers' Program 593 Rural School Play Day 504 Better Livestock Program 505 The Five-Day Chautauqua in One 506 Trial of a Soil Robber </seg>
            <seg id="p006">HOME ECONOMICS PUBLICATIONS Foods and Nutrition EXTENSION CIRCULARS SOS Mineral Contents of Vegetables MS Meats 961 Food and Its Relation to Health 1)62 Banquets — Management and Service 963 Breakfast Menus 906 Cereals 907 Beverages !)64 Hot Lunches for Rural School: '". -I Childhood Malnutrition »0» Milk and Milk Products 910 Eggs 966 Correction and Prevention of Mal - nutrition ■.ill Honey Dishes 9U Homemade Cheesi 967 Caloric Estimates for the Growing Child 968 Food for Children from Nine Month: to Fourteen Years 915 Delicious Poultry Recipe; HIS Hominy Recipes HIT Emergency Meal MC Christmas Cake.; and Candies 92K Salads and Salad Dressing 934 Doughnuts. Pies, and Cookies 91ft Woman's Part in Home Butchering 860 Meals for All Occasions !&gt;70 Weight-Height-Ago Tables for Schci Age 1171 Symonds Table for Heights and Weights for Women Preserving Eggs % Jelly Making 961 Making the Most of the Meal Ho 954 Kuffet Luncheon Questions and An: ( 955 Cookery for the Sick &lt;H4 Pickles and Relishes -21-2 Canning Vegetable '-26-2 Canning Meats 957 Mineral Nutrients in Foods 968 Precautions with Canned G&lt; Clothing EXTENSION CIRCULARS Kbrics — How to Know Them .brics How to Buy Them .brics — How to Care for Them teration of Patterns 117 Dressing Stout and Slender Worn 41!i Clothes for High School Gradua «1 Millinery— Frame C 432 Hat Selection 4"- Color in Clothing M Renovation of Hat Mater 4:14 Hat Trimmings 409 Planning an Economical Wardrobe 411 Economy in Buying ISfi How to Make and I Dress-Fora 4-14-2 Remaking Cl.ithiiu 412 Healthful Footwear 415 Selection of Clothing 416 Making Sewing Easiei Home Management EXTENSION CIRCULARS 579 A Comfortable Home— What Is It ". 1101 Budgets and Household Accounts 1102 Family Food Account Book 1103 Family Clothing Account Book 1106 Control of Household Pests 1137 Homemade Fly Trap 1140 Taking Drudgery Ou 1151 Floor CoverinK&gt; 1154 Refinishing Furni 1155 Stenciling and Block Print 1 !."-.; Interior Decoration and Hi 1108 Homemaking — A Profession 1109 Business Side of Housekeeping 1110 Marketing Furnishings 1157 Color in House Furnishings 1 158 Arrangement of Furniture 1160 Facts and Stories About Chir 1182 The House ■ Music. Reading and Pictures Time and Labor Saving Device; 1117 Soapmaking 1118 What Women Should Know About 1183 House Constructk Business Affairs 1184 Rooms and Their Arrangem. 1185 Lighting 1119 Notebook Habit by Farmers' Wi 1131 Homemade Fireless Cooker 1186 Heating and Ventilation 1240 Planting the Home Grounds 113S Homemade Cheese Pret Health EXTENSION CIRCULARS 1002 Mother and Baby 1003 Home Sanitation 1007 Home Care in Emergencies 1008 Facts About Prevention of Di* 1009 Appreciating Good Health 1004 Health Habits for Home Folks 1006 Home Care of the Sick Miscellaneous EXTENSION CIRCULARS 2 Suggestions for Picnics 51 Business Side of a Club, Part I 3 Judging Household Exhibits at Fairs 52 Business Side of a Club. Part II 50 Home Demonstration Work in Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p007">( 1 7 HORTICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS circular 11 Strawberries in Nebraska bulletin 14*j Home Mulched vs. Northern Bulletin 182 Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska Seed Potatoes for Eastern Bulletin 199 Relation of Low Temperatures Nebraska- to Root Injury of the Apple bulletin lfil Methods of Controlling Blister Nebraska EXTENSION CIRCULARS POULTRY HUSBANDRY EXPERIMENT STATION PUBLICATIONS The Mori' Important Poultry Disease EXTENSION CIRCULARS RESEARCH OR SCIENTIFIC BULLETINS EXPERIMENT STATION Colloidal Swelling of Wheat Gluten in 27 Potato Wilt and Stem-End Rot Caused by Fusarium Eumartii. 1924 28 Control Equipment for Study of Rela - tion of Environment to Disease. 1924 Relation to Milling and Baking. 1916 24 Seed Potato Investigations. 1923 Address Requests for Publications to AGRICULTURE COLLEGE OF LINCOLN, NEBRASKA i»0 Honu- Vt-iietable Gardening 201 Farm Potato Storage in Western Nebraska 202 Potato Seed Improvement by Hill Selection 203 Handling Nebraska Potatoes to Con- trol Dry Rot 204 Potato Seed Treatment 205 Potato Seed Considerations 206 Plan for a Back Yard Garden 207 Plan for a Vacant Lot Garden 20k The Home Garden Hotbed 209 Plan for a Farm Garden 210 Selection and Preparation of Potatoes for Exhibition 211 Planting Table for Garden 212 Scotts HlufT County Seed Potatoes 220 Grafting 221 Spraying Apples, Cherries, and Plums 222 Pruning Grapes TMt Establishing the Home Orchard 231 Maintaining the Home On-hard Ml 1240 Planting the Home Grounds 1241-5 Ornamental and Forest Planting Material Suitable for Various Parts of Nebraska I Please indicate the tonnty in which you live 1246 Roses for Nebraska 1247 Planting Evergreen Trees in Nebraska 1248 Preservative Treatment of Fence Posts 1249 Fall Planting of Bulbs for Spring Bloom 1251-5 Perennials Suitable for Various Parts of Nebraska. (Please indicate the county in which you live » i MM .*&gt; Disinfection and Disinfectants 4!l A Dozen Hens in the Hack Yard 4»1 Baby Chicks — Their Care and Feed 403 Incubation Pointers 404 Preserve Eggs for Home Use 405 Confine the Cockerel 406 Poultry Disease Problems 407 Dry Mash Rations 409 Appearance of Eggs on Candling 410 Feed Dry Mash 411 Graded Ekes Bring Better Prices 412 Fowl Cholera 14i:i Essentials of Poultry Hygiene 1414 Finishing Poultry on the Farm 1415 Tuberculosis in Poultry 1416 How to Select the Good Layers 1417 How to Pedigree Chicks 1421 Judging S. C. White Leghorns 1422 Judging White Plymouth Rocks 1423 Judging White Wyandottes 1424 Judging Buff Orpingtons 1425 Judging Barred Plymouth Rocks 1426 Judging S. C. Rhode Island Reds 1427 Grading System for Nebraska E| </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>