<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00019">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00019</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH AT BEATRICE TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS.  DECEMBER 1, 1900.</title>
			            <date value="1901">1901</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-29</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-24</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>

			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

OF THE 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTION 

FOR 

FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH 

AT 

BEATRICE 

TO THE 

MfSIIOR AID THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AMD BUILDINGS. 

DECEMBER 1, 19OO. 

LINCOLN, NEB. 

STATE JOURNAL COMPANY, PRINTER 

MM </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
Hon. Win. A. Poynter Governor 

For the Term Ending January 1, 1901. 

Hon. Chas. H. Dietrich Governor 

For the Term Ending January 1, 1903. 

BO 

ARD OP PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

Foil Term Ending January 1, 1903. 

Hon. -I. V 

Wolfe. Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings 

President 

Hon. W. F. Porter. Secretary of State Secretary 

Hon. J. B. Meserve State Treasurer 

Hon. C. J. Smyth Vttornev General 

For Term Ending January 1, 1908. 

Gr. 1). Follmer. Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings 

1). Follmer. Commissioner Pnblie Lands and Buildings 

President 

President 

R. \Y. Marsh. Secretary of State Secretary 

W. Marsh. Secretary of State Secretary 

SV. Stuefer State Treasurer 

Hon. Fiank P. Piout Utornev General </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
RESIDENT OFFICERS. 

\V. H. Dealing, M. 1.) Superintendent 

Mrs. Mary Thomas Matron 

O. W. Stewart Steward 

SCHOOL DEPARTMENT. 

Miss Virginia Laraen Principal 

TEACHEF 

Miss Agnes Brady 
Miss Anna Stewart 

Mrs. Evalyn Culbertson 

Oeneral Supervisor 

J. \V. Culbertson . 
Miss Louisa Frk-k 

Supervisor Boys" Department 
.Supervisor, Armstrong Hall 

In charge of Farm Department 
In charge of Sewing Room. . . . 

Win. Pollock 

.Emily Rurup 

In charge of Laundry 

N. E. Tmax 

Mrs. Edith Callawa.v 
Miss Nellie Blakeslev 


i 

1 

* 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p005">REPORT. 

&gt;n. Win. A. Poynter, Governor of the State of Nebraska, and 

the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings: 

In accordance with the laws of the state of Nebraska I here 
th submit the eighth biennial report of the Institution for 
¦eble-Minded Youth for the period ending November 30, 1900. 
th such recommendations for the future conduct of the institu»n 
as appear to me to be necessary in the premises. 

Appointed to the superintendence of this institution in a 
ii-inv period of its existence, and being officially installed as 
executive head on the. 21st of September. 1900, I found one of 

first duties to be to write this, the eighth biennial report. I 

ve no apologies to make for any imperfections it may contain, 
lave striven, under adverse circumstances, to make such a reit 
as would best acquaint you with the condition of an instition 
which has passed through much trouble and many annoy- 

•; circumstances during the past bicnnium. From such records 
are at my command I will give in detail such facts and figures 
icerning the financial and statistical condition of the institnl! 
as is possible. 

Vt the close of the last biennial period there were present in 

is institution 212 pupils, about equally divided among the 
xes. which population has been subject to the following 

•hanges: 

N'nmber of pupils November :.&lt;•. 1898. . . 

212 

Niunber received since — 

Females 

. 34 

Males 

. . 41 

" 78 

r«»t:ll 

200 </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
514 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S 

REPORT. 

Discharged during biennium 20 

Died during bieiinium 

28 

At home on vacation or visit 14 

Eloped 1 

&lt;;: 

Present November 30, 1900 

_ i 

This population of 227 actually present should have been increased 
by at least fifty had it been possible to occupy the boys" 
new cottage and the hospital prior to December 1. During the 
mouth of December, the boys' cottage will be occupied, and this 
will relieve the pressure for admission for a time and enable the 
superintendent to more properly classify the children. The new 
hospital will furnish room for detention for the pupils when first 
admitted, as well as a lovclv home for them when ttaev are ill. 

As will be observed from the table of the movement of th&lt; 

take up their guardianship and prepare a custodial home for 
them where they can have a permanent home and suitable care 
and control. The most highly trained and best educated of these 
children cannot compete in any way with the normal man or 
woman. Perpetual occupation in an industrial institution, where 
they can have the comforts of a home and the protection of the 
law, is the only remedy. 

The number of deaths during the biennium was twenty-eigh 

population, the per rent of discharged pupils is very low, and that 

covers, no doubt, a number who went home on a vacation and did 

not return. 

The custodial feature of an institution of this nature, there 

fore, is emphasised in every word, every line, and every sentence 

of every report ever written descriptive of its annual or biennial 

results. 

What can we say of those discharged? Nothing very favor 

able. They are not able to cope with the world in a business 01 

social way. or are too restless and unmanageable to be kepr at 

home. There are exceptions to this result, but they are so few 

and far-fetched as to hardly deserve a mention herein. These 

children will be children ahvavs. The state must sooner or latei </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
515 

n 

i IK 

II 

IKEBI.E MINDED YOUTH. 

giving an annual death-rate upon a population of 220 or &lt;«.t»35 
per cent per annum. 

A list of the various causes of death ranuot be included in this 
report. I am sorry t&lt;» say, because of there being no record kept 
thereof. The causes of death in a few instances could be obtained 
from the secretary of the board of health of Beatrice, but 
as many bodies were transferred to different parts of the state for 
interment, the list of causes would be incomplete and unreliable. 

The institution has been fortunate to pass a biennial period 
withoul the appearance of any serious epidemic of diseases, considering 
that diphtheria, scarlet fever, smallpox, and measles 
have been prevalent in many parts of our state. 

No casualty of a serious nature has occurred among the popu 
lation during the past two years. 

The total number of epileptic children now in the institution 
reach the total of sixty-six, and the ratio increases as the population 
enlarges. In tnother part of this report I have dealt at 
some length with this class of cases. I append a summary of 
epileptic seizures for the past year only, which I do to call your 
attention to the importance of finding the epileptic a home by 
himself. 

When the number of seizures above are taken into consideration, 
it can be realized what a constant source of anxiety such 
children are to the superintendent and what subjects of distress 
they are to their parents and the public. These children, with 
th&lt;- can- of skilled attendants ever near, suffer falls, bruises, and 

Slllll 

lejitit- 

&lt; 'nnt'itlxiiiH*, i/ear &lt; ii'lim/ November -JO, 19&lt;)&lt;&gt;. 

— . . . . 

_£ &gt;% 

! t : * ! i i &gt;. t ;! I ! Total - 
S &lt; £ -i *i &lt; x 5 i ss 

Boys. . 
Jirls. . . 

.. li- Hi." 

.'i in. 

• M i-2 i:iv ;.o via :n 12:; 99, io»| um 
Jl.". :uil 159 lei? 107 13:! V86; 594| 240: 2798 

Total 

r, ::ti 

:t5: :w» -2iii ".-&gt;&gt;; 930 170 413 :»:{' 4r&gt;i| 4us&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
516 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

injuries of all degrees, often bringing down the wrath of the 
potent, guardian or friend upon the heads of those in charge because 
of accidents that no one can foresee or prevent. That more 
Kf folia mishaps and accidents do not occur upon epileptic ward*, 
is the wonder and surprise of those who come in daily contact 
with them. 

Applications for admission of the prohibitive classes far exceed 
those who are admissible. I regret to say that the boys" cottage 
and the hospital completed during the present year will not 
long supply the demand for room. It is true they will relieve 
the temporary congestion, and makf happy many children and 
many parents, but within the next two years more room must be 
provided. It is a sad duty a superintendent lias to i&gt;erforni when 
he turns away worthy applicants upon a technicality or for want 
of more room, thus barring the light from the mind of the child 
and deepening the shadows across the threshold of the home. 

The legislature in lX!&gt;!t appropriated the sum of #4S.50n for the 
erection of four new buildings. From this fund was elected a 
cottage for boys that will accommodate about fifty children. A 
hospital building was also erected that will bouse twenty more 
children. This building, while far from being modern in its appointments. 
will serve a good purpose, and add much to the com 
fort and physifcil well-being of the population of the institution. 

The building erected for a laundry, a bakery, kitchen, brush 
shop, sewing room, and storeroom, serves partly only the purposes 
named in the law. It makes a good bakery, a good laundry. 
and sewing room. There is no space for the kitchen, and the 
brush shop had to be transferred to other quarters. 

Many new improvements have been made about the barn and 
feed yards. 

The ice house has been removed to a more suitable local ion and 
&lt;»nlarged. 

The building formerly used for a laundrv ha 

another portion of the premises, built over, and is now the car 
penter and brash shop. 

Many minor improvements have been added that time and 
space forbids mention of. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
517 

INSTITT'TION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

nETEXTIOX. 

All children who are admitted now are. required to pass two 
weeks in the detention department of the hospital. This is done 

to prevent any outbreak of an epidemic of whatever nature that 
might he brought to the institution by those pupils just being 
admitted. All children when taken ill in the cottages are at once 
taken to the hospital, where, under the direction of the superintendent, 
competent nurses care for them during their illness. 
During the quarantine period, which extends over two weeks, we 
take the opportunity of a minute examination of each child admitted. 
The degree of mental defect, the amount of physical infirmity, 
and from these conditions are deducted the department 
which the child will be assigned when it goes out of quarantine 
and takes its place among the other pupils. Its line of school 
work, literary and industrial, will be also planned from the information 
thus obtained. You must place a child among his 
equals in the institution life where a feeling akin to comradeship 
and mental interests arouse him, until exertion, mental anil 
physical, accomplish something useful. The first evidence of a 
change is in the physical condition of the child, the healthier 
appearance, the happy countenance, the increased intelligence. 

taring testimony of the ]M»tent influence of changed but su-U- 

surroundings, 

l/i Assistant Superintendent 

This institution has reached the age and contains the population 
which makes it absolutely necessary that there should he 
added to the staff of officers an assistant superintendent, who 
should be a well qualified physician and surgeon. The numerous 
duties which devolve upon the superintendent not only take all 
of his time when he is present, but in the discharge of his official 
duties it is necessary that he shonld frequently absent himself 
from the institution, tlius leaving the school without the ever 
necessary present physician. In the past it has been necessary 
and customary to enlist the services of physicians from the city 

RECOMMEXDATIl &gt;NS. </seg>


            <seg id="p010">518 

LAND COMMISSIONER S REPORT 

of Beatrice, who. while always willing to assume the duties, frequently 
sacrifice time and loss of business as a matter of accommodation 
to a brother practitioner. 1 trust that the legislature 
during this session will take notice of this very important matter, 
and make the necessary appropriation in accordance with my 
recommendation. 

the training and physical development of the pupils. Again 

since the majority of the people of our state are engaged in 

farming, the pupils should he taught that which they will \ 

able to follow under the direction of their parents, if returned 

to their homes. 

"Land in Nebraska is probably cheaper now than it will ever 

be in the future, and should be purchased while it can be had 
adjoining the present site, instead of being compelled later on, 
as in some other states, to go two or three miles from the insti- 

tution, a matter of great inconvenience, besides removing it 
where it cannot be under direct supervision. Many of the in- 

mates are not able to work a whole dav. and if the farm is near bv 

they can derive some benefit from it. preventing idleness and re 

quiring less care, and their labor being at the same time productive. 
We have been obliged to lease several acres of land for 
the past two years, by reason of the last legislature failing to 
make the provision asked for. The leased ground has been 

attended without additional help 

I want to endorse his appeal. I have asked the legislature ai 
this session to appropriate f 10.000 to purchase additional land. 
The state can always afford to own the land necessary to employ 
all who can labor upon the farm. It is a business proposition, it 
Is a sensible one. and should meet with the approval of all. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">Additional IaiihI. 

All the superintendents of this institution who have written a 

siennial report have begged the legislature to purchase more 

iand for its use. I quote from Dr. .1. T. Armstrong's report in 

L89&lt;&gt;. wherein be said: 

"I am still of the opinion, expressed in my first report, that 

larj;e tracts of land are not only a matter of economy, the farm 
jredncta largely the institution, thus greatly lessen- 

ng the cost of maintenance, but are also of greal usefulness in 


most important remedy and should be most promptly and effectually 
applied. It is a well-known fact that there is no difference, 
whether the age be one year or fifty years — they are all children 
in the eye of the law, and should be cared for as such. 

An Epileptic Colony. 

There are, in the three insane hospitals of the state, 135 patients 
who are afflicted with epilepsy, while, scattered through other 
state and county institutions, there are probably at this time no 
less than 400 epileptic children and adults. The institutions are 
totally unable to accomodate all who apply for admission. The 
presence of epileptics is a menace to the mental and physical 
health of the other children. Their frequent seizures in the 
presence of those who are thud afflicted has a very injurious effect 
on the latter. The result of experience proves, beyond a doubt, 
the feasibility of epileptic colonies. The increase in the popula- 

INSTITTTIuN roK I KKHI.E MINDED YUV/TH. 510 

Additional Water Supply. 

The water supply at this institution, at the bent, has always 

been defective. &lt; &gt;ur present water supply, except drinking water 

which is taken from a well, is secured from Bear creek and 

pumped into the standpipe. This water is unfit for drinking or 

cooking purposes. The supply is liable to fail at any time. I 

have recommended the appropriation of $.".000. for the purpose of 

increasing the quantity and quality of, the water. A large insti- 

tution like this must have pure water for all purposes, or be 

liable at any time to an epidemic of the many diseases whose 

cause is found to lie in impure water. 

Changing the Title or \nme. 

The word "Youth" should be stricken from the name of the 

institution, which would leave the title of the institution to be 

known as the ''Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded," and I 

think probably it would be well to go further and strike out the 

word "Institution"' and substitute the word "School," making the 

name finally read. "The Nebraska School for Feeble Minded." 

That title would then cover all the cases of whatsoever age in the 

state, leaving all of them free to apply for admission. This is a </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
LAM) COMMISSIONER'S KEl'OUT. 

520 

t 

f 

tion of this class of people should urge the state to its best en 

deavor without delay, for the state must care for these 

fortunate defectives in some manner, and it is the duty of Hi 

state to so care for them that they may receive the greatest -rood 

possible from such care. The colony plan is the cheapest in 

most advantageous in result, most humane in administrate 

most pleasant and healthy to the individual, and. therefore 

most relief to society. Nebraska can well afford to be one of t 

pioneers in this humane work. She can afford to mark out 

line and blaze a way for other states to follow 

Remove the Age Harriet 

The age limit should be removed entirely from the restriction? 
of applicants. The younger the child admitted the better tlu 
opportunity for improvement. These children are invariably tli&lt; 
"spoiled child" at home. They are ]&gt;etted and allowed to do a» 
they please at home, and fhe older they are at the time of admin 
sion the more difficult do they find it to drop their old habits am 
form new ideas of conduct. The vices of children are earl 3 
acquired, and when once acquired hard to control. If admitti 1 

when small, they have the advantage of the can- of train*** 
attendants, nurses, and teachers, who find ii much more easy h 
influence and direct them in the way they should p&gt;. Again 
the person over eighteen years of age of feeble mind is only ph\ 
sically larger than the infant. Mentally he is just as irrespoi 
slble. but society demands his care in an institution, and rightl, 
too, for his presence at large in a community is nor for the publi 
good. Take down the -age barrier; it will prove a blessing 1 

many, many people who are worthy of 

I Superintendent's Cottay 

With the ever-increasing population adding to t be dut ies of 1 hi 
superintendent, justice demands, and common sense suggests 
that there should be erected on the institution grounds a cottag* 
suitable for a residence for the superintendent. In order to ex 
press more fully and forcibly the importance of this fact. I wan 
to quote from Judge L. G. Kinne. chairman of the Iowa Hoard 0 </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
521 

INBTI 

TION FOR TEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

( 

'ontrol, who, in bis recommendations to the Iowa legislature 

aking of institutions for feeble minded, and for insane taos- 

tid: "The strain upon The head of state institutions is 

very great. The temptation, if residing in the administration 
bnilding, to continue to labor at unreasonable hours, to seek no 
relaxation from exacting cares and duties, is great. And the fact 
that the superintendent is so handy, results in his being called 
often at night when an under-officer could answer such purposes. 
The result of such an institution residence is that the superin- 

ndent has no home at all. I am fully convinced that snch life 

is detrimental to the accomplishment of the best results. An 
officer who has relaxation from exacting duties will be a 
healthier and better man and render better service to the state if 
he can get out and stay out of the institution a portion of his 
time." Thus speaks a man of broad experience, who only voices 
the sentiments of every man who has had experience in the management 
of such institutions. I have asked for an appropriation 
of $5,000 for this purpose, which amount invested in this direc- 

tion will release for other purposes space that cost the state 
main thousands of dollars. 

The law provides that the most improvable cases, and those 
•tween the aires of tive and eighteen, shall be iriven 

&gt;f five and eighteen, shall be given preference 

admission. I have asked that the age barrier be broken and 
it applicants be admitted in turn; for the present law provides 

pless and deserving of those demanding the 

he state be the last to re&lt;-eive its benefit 

Other Xeeds. 

I have asked for an appropriation of $1,000 for the purpose of 
reeling a horse barn. If this appropriation is secured it will en- 

able the present horse barn to be made into a dairy barn that 
will answer splendidly for that purpose. The products of a good 
dairy about an institution greatly reduces the running- expenses 
and adds almost more than money can buy to the comfort and 
health of the children. At present only seven cows are being 
kept, where at least twenty-five cows would not be too manv. 

Improvable Canes, </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
KEI'Oin 

522 

LAND COMMISSIONED 

Deficiency. 

Prior to September 22, 1900. which date I assumed the du 

of superintendent, several of the funds appropriated by the la 

legislature had been exhausted. Consequently in some funds 

will occur a deficiency for which I have estimated and asked f 

tion has been for so many years, there has been a lack of att&lt; 
tion to the grounds that amounts almost to neglect. Th&lt; 
should be decisive steps taken to remedy the present condition 
the landscape about the buildings and the farm. 

an appropriation of $3,000 to liquidate. 

Fire Escapes. 

The state cannot afford to take the risk of loss of life that 

would be reasonably sure to occur should a fire break out in any 

of the cottages. While every precaution possible is taken to pre 

vent such an occurrence, it would be a wise provision to be pre 

pared for it if it did occur. There should be fire escapes upon all 

three cottages and the hospital, and there should be no delay in 

the matter of having the improvement made. 

Improvement of Grounds. 

Notwithstanding the length of the existence of the institu 

ESTIMATE OF FUNDS NECESSARY TO CONDUCT THE INSTITUTION' FOR 

(I 

FEEBLE-MINDBD YOUTH. 

April 1, 1901, to April 1. 1903. 

Officers" salaries ¦ f 11,000 00 

Teachers' and employees' wages 35,000 06 

Current expenses '. &lt;52.fiOO 00 

Additional repairs 5.100 Oft 

Industrial department 9&lt;W 00 

Deficiencies 300 ° 00 

¦¦COMMENDATIONS FOB APPROPRIATIONS FOR EERMANENT IM- 

PROVEMENTS. 

For the purchase of additional lands $10,000 00 

Improving water supply 5.0&lt;\0 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
523 

IN 

TJ 

IN 

IB 

"EEBI.E MINDED 

YOUTH. 

oniplete and furn 

New cottage for superintendent 

95,006 (Ml 
1.000 00 

i crib, and granai 

Hors 

&lt;-s 

300 00 
1.300 00 

Silo 

walks 

Mom 

The schools have an averagt 

endanee at present of 134 pu- 

it 

me to the advancement of the 

devote their 

iry aiid industr 

&lt;1 

rk. New improvement! in 

ire to be added. 

New lines of industrial work are 

department is to be broadened 

the'kindergarte 

1 made a leading feature. N&lt; 

inimock, and lace weaving is 

plan of the school work. Noth- 

t in the futui 

the school reach and retain a 

f the plan to ma 

gh standard among the school 

of its kind. 

ABLE OF SCHOOL ATTAINMENTS 

Speech. 

Speak a few words only 10 

Speak indistinctly 12 

Speak distinctly 14 

Speak fairly 26 

Speak well 62 

Reading. 

Know no words 16 

Know a few words 5 

Read on chart 9 

Read in first reader 25 

Read in second reader 12 

Read in third reader 4 

Read in fourth reader 14 

Read in fifth reader 10 

rv&gt; 

Vble to read books for amusement 

Writing. 

Make no attempt 18 

Nothing but scribble 14 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S UErORT. 

524 

Form a few or most of the letters 6 

Write easy words 

i; 

Write from dictation 42 

Write from printing 

Irithmetic. 

Have no idea of nuinbei 
Count to five 

ir, 

Count to ten . 
Count to thirty 
Count to fifty 

1 

Count indefinitely 

Mi 

Combine numbers to ftvt 

t; 

Combine numbers to ten or more 
Work in addition 

Work in subtraction . 
Work in multiplication 
Work in division 

1 

t 

Work in fractious 
Work in interest 

7 

// 

Know neither hours nor miuut 
Know some of the hours 

Can tell time to the minute 

(iron 

¦a phi/ 

Know something of location . . 
Know something of geography 
Know something of general ge&lt; 

I't 

Hi 
17 

graphy 

Languagi 

Know use of capital letters 

•"&gt;,: 

Know use of punctuation marks 

:',ii 

Know name of words 2!&gt; 

Know action words 

Know simple sentenct 

••&gt;i 

Know singular and plural forms 24 

Know use of ajmstrophe 17 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
525 

INSTITl'TION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

Know initial letters 22 

Know abbreviations 32 

Write letters with assistance 16 

Write letters without assistance 33 

Drawing. 

1 (raw simple forms 65 

Map drawing 19 

Freehand and era von work 13 

'olor. 

&lt; 

Know one or two colors 29 

Know the primary colors 26 

Know the secondary colors 15 

&lt;";in match compound shades, but not always name them. ... 79 

Value of Money. 

Know a few coins 54 

Know all coins 12 

Know value of monev to 25 cents 15 

Know value of money to f 1 15 

Know value of money to $5 8 

Music. 

Seem to have no interest in musical sounds 6 

in musical i 

Pay some attention to musical sounds 110 

lieal sounds 

Siiifi simple tunes by ear 60 

Sin;-; by note 25 

a v in the band 8 

Gymnastics 

Have no idea of drill 2 

Stand attention 16 

March onlv 18 

Execute simple calisthenic movements with apparatus. ... 40 

Execute difficult movements with apparatus 50 

Kindergarten Work 

i perforate and sew 93 

.ldivir 62 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
526 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Paper weaving 75 

Paper ratting 46 

Paper pasting 85 

Alternate with more than two forms 87 

UBe the peg-boards methodically .'. 32 

&gt;_ 

]»o work with blocks and tablets 40 

We at the present time have an entertainment every evening. 

They arc not -only important as a means of pleasure and recre- 

ation liut are a great aid in developing and quickening the 

senses. These programs vary nightly, and the children con- 

tribute with the officers and teachers their share of the program. 

Dancing is indulged in on Tuesday and Friday evenings. The 

children thoroughly enjoy the musi 

Thanksgiving and the holidays are thoroughly enjoyed by 

all. Christmas is an especially happy time among the children 

and no pains is spared to make all happy. Christmas trees ait 

generously supplied by parents and friends with presents. Th 

pleasure which the children derive from the occasion amply re 

pay officer, teacher, and attendant for the labor and expense of 

weeks of preparation. 

I include our Thanksgiving program in order to acquaint you 

with the interest surrounding lit 

tsions in this in 

ii 

Tli a ii kxy iri &gt;i 1/ Pi o&lt;/m in. 

Vssciablv Hall. 11:40 a. m. to 12:40 j 
Thursday, November 2!». liMK). 

Motto: "The full, the true Thanksgiving, comes from tin- H&lt;-ai 

Band. 

Reading of Thanksgiving Proclamation 

Recitation — "Bertie's Thanksgivii 

Song— "I Will Praise Thee" Churns Hass 

Mandolin Club. 

Concert Recitation — "Thanksgiving."' 

Recitation— Selected Miss Stewart 

Song— "We Praise Thee. Oh Father" Chorus Class 

Recitation — ''Pumpkin" Chas. W. 

Chorus — "Call for Reapers'' School 

Lord's Prayer in Concert. 

Band. 

Grand March to Dining-Room </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
527 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

Tluink.fi/iri hi/ Mm U. 

Children's Dining Hall. Dinner, 1 p. m. 

Roast Turkey. 
Cranberry Sauce. 
Dressing, with Brown Gravy 

Pomatoes. Mashed Potatoes. 

Bread and Butter. 
Pickles. Celery. Cheese. 

Doughnuts. 

Pumpkin Pie. 

Coffee. 
\pples. Candy. 

¦iftemooii Exercises 

Armstrong Hall. 3:30. 

Music Mandolin Club 

Music Band 

Son" Chorus Class 

Boys" Cottage. 4:15 p. m. 

. r &lt;- 

Music Band 

Music Mandolin Club 

Sim": Chorus Class 

Hospital 

I 

40 p. in. 

Mandolin Club 

Mus 

Assembly Hall. 7:15 p. m. to 8:45 p. in 
(Irand Ball for the Children. 

During the summer and fall season outdoor games are indulged 
everv afternoon or evening. In the winter-time outdoor exer- 

iiid games are indulged in so far as the weather will permit. 

In company with teachers and attendants they take long walks, 

turning to the schoolroom or playroom with renewed vigor and 

ngth of body, with a sluggish mind accelerated and maybe a 

w ray of mental sunshine gathered by the way. 

IXKI'STRIAL CLASS WOKK DONE BY HAND 

Hrtmiiitui 

Towels 532 

Sheets 9 

Xapkins 56 

Pillowcases 97 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 

528 

Hemstitch hit). 

Doilies ¦ 10 

Towels 47 

Carvers 1? 

Dresser scarfs 

Table c-overs 

Pillowcases 

&lt; 'enter pieces 1 

I) mini Work. 

Doilies 

o 

Tray covers . . 
Centerpieces . 
1 &gt;r.'sser scarfs 
Splashers . . . . 

! 

1 

i 

Skirts 
Aprons 

o 

Hi 

th. 

There has been 

i great deal of fancy needle work don 

in 

industrial department of the schools of which my predc 

•em 

tors 

have made no record, and I only 
the articles known to have been 

include in the foregoin 
produced. 

ible 

i 

W. l'MMI 

XOVEMHI 

It 

II. 

HIS 

Farn 

2O.2SS 

Engine room 
Sewing 

18.£0&gt;0 

14.40(1 

&lt; Jenterpieees 

HorHS OF EMPLOYMENT OK ITI'ILS FOB THE BIENNIAL I'KUIOD ENDIM </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
529 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE WINDED YOUTH. 

Mending 20,740 

Ward 112.572 

Laundry 54,377 

Kitchen , 65,427 

Brush department 12.273 

Miscellaneous 48,720 

Total for bienninm .* 267,651 

FINANCIAL BIENNIAL REPORT. 

Balance 

bai isy; . 

.•S- * Total. Exiled. »*# 

Officers' salaries... . $|f«K).O2 $7600.00' $9*10.02 17498. 40j $1701.62 

10 .02 $7600.00' $9*10.02 t7498.40J $1701.62 

Officers' salarie 
Employes' was 
Fuel and Hglits 

Employes' wages 95t»7 1UOO0.0OJ Ui9M).OO IH741.W 32IK99 

95t»7 KiOOO.OOi Hi9")0.00 IS741.W 32O-&lt;.99 

Fael and lights. . 755.89 1 15(10. Ouj 12225.89 96H9.HN HMB 

H9 115«0.0U I2225.89 96II9.HK V556.23 

Board and clothing, main- j ¦ 
tenancc 9iHS).*'&gt; 25000. 0O 1 :!4989.85 -27110.16 7879.69 

Board and rlothiii" main 

9ySit.H.-, 25O0O.0O 1 :i4!)89.H5 37110.18 7879.69 

Music and amusements. .. 1Y7.27 2(10.00 357. 27 : 271.47 85.80 

Music and amusements... 1Y7.27 200.00 357 27 271.47 Mo.80 

Repairs and improvemeots. 11.14 VI.OO.OC 21)11.14 13S4.29 64H.I8 

Repairs and improvements. 11.14 2MI0.0O SUII.Hj i:Wi-2.-J9 648.^8 

Furniture and bedding 4&gt;.2i (i(H).OOi 6J5.2"' 496.4:{ ; 148 77 

oroitBre and bedding. ... 4&gt;.2i (i(H).(X)i 615.2"'; 496.4:{ ; 148 

Incidental expenses 20.7"&gt; 300. 00| 220.75 13-J.OS 88.72 

F;\rm implements and supplier 
219.50 lOO.OOi 319.50 258 2. 61.30 

School apparatus 12162 2U0.00&lt; :«:J 6: 191.93, 131.69 

lcho.il apparatus 123.62 2U0.00! :«:J 6: 191.93, 131.69 

Library and periodicals. .? 9-i.OO 100.001 l!»5.00 116:t=&gt;| 7«.«5 

Medicine and snrgic.il instruments 
. 259.96 400 00 69 9f. 659.96 '.. 

Medicine and surgic.il in 
strutuents 

59.96 400 001 6 9 9h 659.9H 

Tools I Hi.Hi ] 8ili 8il« 

Laundry apparatus 60(1.00 600.00 St80 546.20 

Coking apr.arams :!7.H0 :{00.()0l :«7 00 H7.00 30000 

Paint and oils 200.01' 200 00 2&lt;&gt;0.0t&gt; 

Improvement, grounds 43.45 250.00 293.45 277 T, 15.08 

43.45 250.00 293.45 277 .37! 15.08 

Improvement, amunds 
1 Radiator snard^ 

liadiator gnardi 84.00 84.00 8100 

84.00 H4.00I 8100 

Teachers' salaries 1455.5:! 5600.00 7055 53 4276.14 2779. 36 

1455. 51! 5600.00 7055 53| 4276.141 2779. :«i 

Teachers' salaries 

Farm supplies and feed for 
stock :S00.O0 300 00 300.00 

Far 

and leed for 

:iOO.no 3oo oo 300.00] 
300.0 300.00 3C000 

stock 

Office supplies 300.0 300.00 3C0.00 

Office sup 

Telegraph and telephone 200.00 200 00 1;!".16 64.24 

200.00 200.00 l:t*.16i 64.24 

Telegriiph anil telephone. . 
Material and tools for car- 

Material and tools for carpenter 
and brush shops 5011.00 500 00 6.05 493. 95 

penter and brush shops. . 5011.00 500 00 6.05; 493. 95 

Four new hui!din«s 4B500 0d 48 '.( 0.00 4:054.10; 1445 90 

4R500 00 48"il-0.00 47054.10; 1445 90 

Four new bui'din 

Deeciencies 32V2.88 3 '52 69 2983.58] 270.10 

;«V.».6» 3 '52 69 2932.59 270.10 

Deficiencies 

Addition to ice house 200.00 200.00 14.85 185.75 

Addition to ice house 

Totals $15931. 1 o' $ ' 24 1 01. 69 $140033.79 $1 '7*48.57' $&gt;2785. 22 

$1 17,248. 'i7 total expenditure for bieunium 

L?ss 1,129.85 of 1897 — appropriation which lapsed 
$116,118.92 net expenditure. 
34 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
530 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Recapitulation. 

Total amount expended December 1, 1898, to Decem 

ber 1, 1900 f Uti.118 92 

Per capita cost 220 pupils for all expenditures . . 250 70 
I Which includes $47,054.10 for new buildings.) 

Per capita cost for 220 pupils 
expenditures 

less extraordinary 

Io3 82 

Per capita cost for 220 pupils 
value of farm products 

less the estimated 

150 40 

'KRSONAI 

REMARK 

To his Excellency. Governor W. A. Pointer, and to the Board 
of Public Lands and Buildings I desire to extent my thanks for 
the many courtesies and acts of kindness which they have all ex 
tended me. 

To Mrs. Mary Thomas, the matron and ranking officer. I shall 
be ever grateful for her faithful, careful, and conscientious discharge 
of public duty. 

To Chas. W. Stewart, the steward of the institution is due a 
reat deal of the credit for what has been accomplished. The 

state never had a more faithful, honest, garefnl, capable, hardworking 
man in its employ than he. '"He is. indeed, a servant 
worthy of his hire." 

To those employees, skilled in their calling, the teachers in 
the schoolroom, the attendants upon the ward workshop or farm 
I extend my grateful thanks for their assistance and devotion to 
dutv. 

W. H. Hearing. M. T).. Superintendent 

INFORMATION. 

This institution was established by the state of Nebraska for 
the benefit of feeble-minded children between the ages of five 
and eighteen years, who are, by reason of their affliction, denied 
the educational advantages of our public schools, and who likewise, 
because of their physical weakness, are necessarily dependent. </seg>


            <seg id="p023">
INSTITUTION KOK l'EEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

531 

"Besides shelter and protection, the prime object of said institution 
shall be to provide special means of improvement for 
the unfortunate portion of the community who were born, or 
by disease have become, imbecile or feeble-minded, and by a well 
adapted course of instruction reclaim them from their helpless 
condition, and, through the development of their intellectual 
faculties, tit them as far as possible for usefulness in society. 
To this end there shall be furnished them such agricultural and 
mechanical education as they are capable of receiving." (Section 
2. chapter 52, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1885.) 

The education of this class includes not only the simple elements 
of instruction taught in our public schools and in the 
kindergarten, where that is practicable, but embraces a course 
of training in the more practical matters of every-day life. — 
the cultivation of habits of cleanliness, propriety, and self-reliance, 
as well as to develop and enlarge their capacity for useful 
occupation. Children of this class are often feeble in body 

as well as in mind. Their gait and voluntary movements are 
generally imperfect and slow, and their special senses inactive 
and undeveloped. Physical training and development, therefore, 

are essential in order that their mental improvement may be 
made permanent; hence the importance of gymnastic and calis- 

henic exercises in connection with our school work. The very 

feeble power of attention must be cultivated and increased by 
the most attractive means. The special senses must be trained 
mikI educated, vicious habits corrected, and the idea of obedience 
and moral obligation must be instilled and nourished. Some 
who are only backward and undeveloped from being misunderstood 
and abused can be improved and reclaimed by special 
means. Others can be made orderly and obedient, docile and 
industrious, and all can be improved in their general conditions 
and habits. In order to secure these blessings, this class of 
afflicted persons must have special care, treatment, and instruction, 
which cannot be obtained in the family at home, or in the 
private medical practice, or by any of the ordinary methods of 
instruction; and it is only in some institutions well arranged 
and directed for the accomplishment of these special objects 
that thev can receive such benefits. Each individual case must </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
532 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

be studied from a physiological point of view, and treated a» 
its peculiarities may demand. 

Children, residents of Nebraska, who are feeble minded, and 
those who have such marked peculiarities or eccentricities of 
intellect, or those who, by reason of their being backward, are 
nnable to receive the benefits of the common schools and ordinary 
methods of instruction are entitled to care and training free 
of charge, except the expense of necessary clothing and transportation 
to and from their homes. 

THE LAW GOVERNING ADMISSIONS. 

(Session Laws, 1895, Chapter 35.) 

Section. 1. That sections three thousand three hundred sixty 
four (3364) and three thousand three hundred and sixty-five [3365 
of chapter forty-three (43t of the Consolidated Statutes of Ne 
braska, 1891, be amended to read as follows: 

Sec. :53(&gt;4. All imbecile and feeble-minded children and youth, 
between the ages of live (5) and eighteen (18) years, who have 
been residents of the state for the one year that preceded an 
application for admission, and who are incapable of receiving 

instruction in common schools, shall be entitled to I 

ived 

into the institution, maintained and educated at the expense 
of the state, if in the judgment of the superintendent the appli 
cant is a suitable person to receive its benefits. Persons of 
greater age, and those not residents of the state, may be ad 
mitted if the capacity of the institution will permit, but for all 
non-residents, and those not residents for the required time, a 
fair rate of compensation shall be paid, to be fixed by the 
board. No persons, however, shall be received into the institu 
tion, or retained, to the exclusion or detriment of those for whom 
it is especially founded. The board of public lands and buildings 
is hereby directed and empowered to make such rules and requirements 
governing the admission and discharge of inmates as 
they may deem just and expedient. 

Sec. 3365. Parents, guardians, or those having legal control, 
who now have children or wards in the institution, and those who </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
533 

INSTITUTION FOE FEBBLB MINDED YOUTH. 

may hereafter send children or wards to the institution, will be 
required to provide suitable clothing and necessary expenses of 
transportation and necessary expenses in case of death, also all 
other incidental expenses, such as dental work, repairs of cloth- 

ing, etc., unless financially unable to do so, in which case the parent, 
guardian, or next friend of such children, or any officer of the 
county or precinct where such children reside, may make application 
to the county court, and upon a decision by such court 
that such children are unable to procure suitable clothing or 
furnish transportation or other expenses as herein provided, and 
that they are proper subjects for admission into the institution, 
an order shall be passed to that effect. The judge of the county 
court shall thereupon certify the same to the county supervisors 
or commissioners, and to the superintendent of the institution, 
\vh&lt;» shall, if the person can be admitted, notify the county board, 
and they shall at once provide clothing and transportation, and 
on or before admission, pay to the superintendent, in current 
funds, the sum of forty dollars ($40) for each person so admitted, 
which money shall be used only for the expenses mentioned in 
I his section. 

The sujKM-intendent shall report to the county board on the 
first day of December of each year, giving an itemized statement 
of the expenditures made and showing the balance on hand. 
The county board shall, at their first meeting thereafter, pay to 
the superintendent such sum of money as added to the balance 
in his hand shall equal the sum of forty dollars (f40) for each 
indigent inmate from such county. 

If any county board shall fail to comply with the provisions 
of this section, the district court in the county shall, on application, 
compel the same by mandamus. 

Persons who are able to pay the expenses mentioned in this 
section shall give bond to the state of Nebraska in the penal 
sum of seventy-five dollars (f75), payable to the superintendent 
of the institution, conditioned on providing for the above mentioned 
expenses, or that they will pay, or cause to be paid, to the 
superintendent on his statement of expenditure, such sums of 
money as may be necessary for such purpose. Such bond shall be </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
534 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

approved by the -county judge in the county where such persons 
reside. In we parents refuse to pay such expenses the countv 

board shall pay the same, and collect from the parents or 
guardian, the bondsmen being equally holden to the state and 
countv. 

NOTE. 

On another page of this report is given a short notice of the 
life and death of the first superintendent of this institution Dr 
James T. Armstrong, who died in Beatrice. Xeb.. on Januarv 14 
1899. </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
INSTITUTION FOR FKEBLB MINDED YOUTH. 

535 

IX MEMOKIAM. 

I&gt;r. James T. Armstrong was born in Columbian county, O., 
but ar an early age moved with his parents to Fairfleld, la., 
where he received his collegiate education at Parsons college. 
I 'pon graduating from the college he chose the profession of 
medicine and studied with I&gt;r. O. \Y. Archibald at Glen wood, 
la. He entered the Medical Department of the State University, 
at Iowa City, from which he graduated with high honors in 
1878, and afterwards took a special course in eye and .ear, and 
the care, training, and treatment of the feeble minded, epileptics, 
and allied conditions. He began the practice of medicine at 
Silver City. la., where he remained four years, removing to 
Omaha to engage in his special work. Had he remained in the 
direct practice of medicine he would have undoubtedly ranked 
high in his chosen profession, but he was called to a higher 
work. 

He was appointed assistant superintendent of the Hospital for 
the Insane at Jamestown, X. L&gt;., but in a year resigned his position, 
to return to Nebraska to assist in the enactment of a 
law establishing an institution for the feeble minded. This bill 
was passed during the winter of 1885-'86, and in August of the 
latter year Dr. Armstrong was appointed superintendent. Work 
was begun at once on the buildings for the admission of inmates. 
He remained superintendent until February 2, 1897. 

He was a member of the Gage County Medical Association, 
Nebraska State Medical Society, Association of the Medical 
Officers of American Institutions for Feeble-Minded Youth, 
American Medical Association, and the Nebraska Academy of 
Sciences. 

He was successful in his work, every detail of which was at all 
limes under his direct supervision. He studied the individual 
necessities and requirements of each inmate so closely and was 
so uniformly kind in his treatment of them that they learned 
to love him as a father. His life was devoted to a study of how 
best to provide comfort and permanent help for the unfortunate 
ones committed to his charge. </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
536 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S EEPOBT. 

X 

j He died January 14, 1899. In beautiful Evergreen Cemetery 
in sight of the institution he planned, builded, and loved so well 
sleep the ashes of one whose every heart -beat was for the unfor 
tunate. His grave is the Mecca of the children of the institution 
who gather about it at every opportunity, strewing flowers, sing 
ing songs of praise, thus by their acts paying their homage to tht 
memory of ;i man who gave his life that they might have a 
home and a brighter future. No greater monument could bf 
erected to his memory. He built it himself, while he lived; ht 
built it iy the hearts of the children; he built it in the hearts 
of all. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>