<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1911-1912 VOLUME II</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1911—1912 Volume II </seg>
            <seg id="p002">t:_ in PUBLIC LIBRARY 5123031) AIM, UWI AMD </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1 l ■\ © 4 e-5 I. 10. II II v. 13. 1M2 l y 1 1, 1912 CONTENTS Volume II Librarian. Biennial report. 1911-1912 Library Commission, Biennial report, v. 6, 1912 Labor and Industrial Statistics, Bureau of, Biennial report Board of Irrigation, Biennial report, v. 9. 1912 Banking Board, Annual reports, v. 20, 21. 1911. 1912 Building and Loan Associations, Annual reports, r, 19. M, Board of Health. Bulletins Nos. 1. 2 Inspector of Oils, Annual reports, 1911, 1912 Game and Fish Commission, Biennial report. 1911-1912 State Veterinarian. Biennial report, 1911-1912 Charities and Corrections, Biennial report, v. 6. If State Prison Board, Biennial report, v. 1 </seg>
           
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE STATE LIBRARIAN FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 3O 1912 • </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Librarian « H. C. Lindsay Deputy Librarian Mary Katherine Ray : stant Librarian Elizabeth L. Mallalieu ~tant Librarian and Supreme Court Bailiff. .Evan T. Roberts </seg>
            <seg id="p006">OFFICE OF STATE LIBRARIAN, Lincoln, Neb., Dec. 12, 1912. To the Honorable CHESTER H. ALDRICH, Governor of Nebraska : Ei required by law I herewith submit my report as librarian Nebraska state library for the biennium ending December Ethe end of the last biennium there were 62,348 regularly Dned volumes in the library. Since that time 1,322 vol - lave been added by purchase and 2,201 volumes added by donation and exchange, making a total of 65,871 volumes now contained in the library proper. This, however, does not include 26,154 volumes of Nebraska supreme court reports, nor the thousands of volumes of session laws, departmental reports, house and senate journals, etc., which are on hand for distribu- At its last session, the legislature made provision for an assistant librarian and this extra help has enabled us to take up the long deferred work of card cataloguing the library and also preparing a separate author's index to the text-books contained in the law division. The index has been finished ; the cataloguing i^ well in hand, and within the next two years we hope to have it completed. The first 3,500 volumes of the documents issued by congress known as the "congressional set," have been sepa - rately numbered and labelled to correspond with the government indices, thus making the information contained in that interest - ing and valuable collection much more available to the patrons of that branch of the library. Out of the appropriation of $3,000 for general office expenses, since April 1, 1911, we have ex - pended about $1,375 for binding and rebinding some 1,800 vol - umes of periodicals, public documents and law books. All bind - ing has been furnished in durable buckram at an average cost of 76 cents per volume, and we feel that the money has been well expended. It is to be hoped that the legislature of 1913 will treat the library liberally in its appropriation for office expenses </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE 4 anil allow the work oi rebinding to go on, as we have from 3,000 i&lt;&gt; 4.IJ00 valuable volumes on the shelves that should be rebound at the earliest opportunity. In previous reports made to your Excellency's predeo 1 have directed attention to the overcrowded condition of the library, to its continuous growth, to its great value and import - ance to the state and to the possibility of its destruction by fire. Thert is not much more to be said upon the subject. Nebraska's great library, worth nearly half a million dollars, and the loss of which would be irreparable, is still kept in quarters that are ad - mittedly unsafe and a daily menace to its very existence. Two years ago while the legislature was successfully evading the consideration of the question of providing commodious and lire-proof quarters for the library, the magnificent library of the state of New York was destroyed by fire. That state is now erecting a $4,000,000 building for its education department and library. Four years ago Missouri lost her library by fire.- Iowa and Wisconsin have, within the past few years, had the same experience. All these states have learned the lesson of false economy, and all of them have since built, or are now building, -uli-tantial fire-proof buildings in which to house their libraries. There is no real necessity that Nebraska should wait until her library is destroyed. We should attend to the matter before it "&gt; late. For some time there has been a growing sentiment that Nebraska should have a new capitol building, and one is certain to be built in the not far distant future. If the time for such building has arrived it would seem to be proper for the incoming legislature to provide for the making and acceptance of plans and specifications for a new capitol building and at the &gt;ame time make an appropriation sufficient to build one wing (for the library, supreme court, etc.) at once. The other wings can be built from time to time as circumstances require and permit, and, when all is finished, Nebraska will have a capitol that will be architectural! v harmonious and a credit to the state. tas been suggested that a fire-proof addition, the style eh should conform to the present capitol, be made to the wing. If it i&gt; assumed that we are never to have a new building or that if we do it will be built to look like the : now have, this plan might be all right. I am of the opinion that the question can be best handled by providing for the immediate construction of a strictly modern. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">5 marble or granite faced fire-proof building on the half block of ground just east of the capitol grounds, for the joint use of the state library, supreme court, historical society, library commis - sion and such other departments as may be thought best. I am advised that the historical society will deed this half block to the state, provided an appropriation for such a building is made. The building should be a good one — such a building as our ter states have erected for like purposes — one that will be a credit to our state. A levy of three-fourths of a mill for two years would raise about $660,000. This amount would build and equip the kind of a structure needed and also permit the present capitol building to be put into such condition that it Cunfd be used for years to come. The people of Nebraska would scarcely notice the added levy of three-fourth , &gt;f a mill. It would cost a man owning property worth $5,000 the sum of 75 cents a year for two years. 1 believe that our property o\\ ucri will cheerfully pay that amount for such a purpose. P'he foregoing suggestions as to a new building are submitted .dur Excellency in the hope that you will, in your message. te a recommendation to the legislature that some provision made for the protection and better care of the library. Attached to this report is a statement of the condition of the library and supreme court funds, a detailed statement of the re - ceipt and disposition of supreme court reports and an appendix &gt;h&lt;.vving the additions U) the state library, alphabetically ar- Very respectfully. H. C. LINDSAY, State Librarian. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SUPREME COURT APPROPRIATIONS December 1. 1910. to November 30, 1912. Books, Blanks, Stationery, Express, Postage, Telegraph, etc Amount unexpended Dec. 1.1910 $ 146.12 Deficiency Appropriation 400.00 Appropriation for 191 1-12 5,000.00 Amount expended $5,040.08 Amount lapsed 2.06 Balance on hand November 30, 1912 503.98 $5,546.12 $5,546.12 STATE LIBRARY APPROPRIATIONS Purchase of Books Amount unexpended Dec. 1, 1910 $ 936.06 Appropriations for 1911-12 _ 6,000.00 Amount expended $6,406.15 Amount lapsed 1.43 Balance on hand Nuvembei 30. 1912 528.48 $6.&lt;136.O6 $6,936.06 Books, Blanks, Stationery, Express, Postage, Telegraph, etc, Amount unexpended Dec. 1, 1910 $ 509.17 Appropriation for 1911-12 3,000.00 Amount expended $2,710.74 Amount lapsed 1.53 Balance &lt;»n hand November 30, 1912 796.90 $3,509.17 $3,509.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">7 The number of volumes in the State Library December 1, 1910, together with the number of accessions from that date to November 30, 1 ( '12, will appear from the following table: Number of volumes December 1, 1910 62,348 Number of volumes purchased 1,322 Number of volumes received by donation and exchange. . 2.201 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 REPORT OF THE December 1, 1910 to November 30, 1912. On hand Vol. Dec. 1. Del'd Sold Ann. 1910 Free Rec'd On hand Nov. 30, 1912 1 30 1 *) 1 3 171 2 11 $22.00 4 ?2i 2 26 52.00 5 530 2 24 48.00 6 500 2 26 52.00 7 471 2 26 52.00 ! 8 487 2 27 54.00 45S 9 206 2 2 4.00 202 10 224 2 3 6.00 2.9 11 256 2 1 2.00 12 302 2 2 4.00 2» 13 4«)X 2 1 2.00 495 14 498 2 2 4.00 494 IS 81 2 4 8.00 75 16 134 2 3 6.00 129 17 189 2 3 6.00 184 18 23? 2 4 8.00 2&gt;) 19 240 2 3 6.00 235 20 304 2 5 10.00 21 3~? 1 ) 2. 3 6.00 22 163 2 4 8.00 297 354 157 23 188 2 3 6.00 24 203 2 3 6.00 183 198 2:^ 175 2 3 6.00 170 26 ~?23 2 3 6.00 518 27 540 1 4 8.00 535 74 1 4 8.00 69 29 80 1 5 10.00 74 30 &lt;# 1 6 12.00 31 1 7 14.00' 61 70 32 91 1 6 12.00 84 33 98 1 6 12.00 34 122 1 7 14.00 135 1 8 16.00 91 114 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 On hand Dec. 1, Del'd Sold Amt. Nov. 30 1910 Free Reed 139 1 7 14.00 S 149 1 7 14.00 143 1 7 14.00 117 1 6 12.00 I 149 1 14.00 / 160 1 6 12.00 184 1 (&gt; 12.00 174 1 6 12.00 12.00 161 1 6 168 1 12.00 6 173 1 6 12.00 l'O 1 7 14.00 206 1 14.00 / 203 1 7 14.00 s 198 1 10.00 3 I 126 1 6 12.00 s 221 1 5 10.00 212 1 1O.(X) 3 215 1 / 14.00 208 1 7 14.00 1 ( »7 1 8 K..00 1XS 1 6 12.00 200 1 / 14.00 213 1 6 12.00 215 1 6 12.00 239 1 7 14.00 11 22.00 12 24.00 14 28.00 13 26.00 15 30.00 211 1 2V&gt; 2 241 2 256 2 S 279 .1 30.00 307 3 18 36.00 18 36.00 306 3 318 3 20 40.00 3 24 48.00 4 24 48.00 4 26 52.00 4 27 54.00 4 27 54.00 370 i 382 387 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 On hand On band Vol. Dec. 1, Del'd Sold Free Ann. Not. 30, 1910 76 405 4 31 77 411 4 31 78 416 4 33 424 4 36 80 428 4 39 81 437 4 44 82 446 4 48 83 451 4 4« 84 463 5 50 100.00 408 98.00 411 85 465 5 4'» 86 +')2 5 02 124.00 425 ived 87 1,000 209 350 208 340 208 331 207 318 700.00 441 " m 1,000 680.00 452 89 1,000 662.00 461 90 1.000 636.00 475 20.00 584 24.00 621 22.00 605 26.00 616 26.00 613 •• cial 1 594 10 -&gt; 633 12 3 616 11 4 629 13 5 626 13 Damaged Books 364 364 30.058 1,003 2,537 .75 1 Scmicm Laws, 75c IM Session Laws, 50c 9.50 226.80 • &gt;n Laws, 60c Paid State Treasurer Lec'd 62.00 370 62.00 376 66.00 379 72.00 78.00 88.00 96.00 384 385 389 394 96.00 399 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 RECAPITULATION. Reports on hand Dec. 1. 1910 26,058 Received volume 87 1,000 Received volume 88 1,000 Received volume 89 1,000 Received volume 90 1,000 Di&gt;trihuted free 1,003 Sold 2,537 Damaged books on hand 364 Reports cm hand Not. 30. 1912 26.154 30,058 30,058 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 REPORT OF THE Library Fund for the Purchase of Books. Amount appropriated 1909 Unexpended $ ''36.06 Amount appropriated 1911 6.000.00 1911 To Whom Paid Warrant No. Amount Jan. 7 D. A. Hollowell 1775 $ 2.90 11 F. A. Harrison 17/6 207.65 American Ass'n lor Labor Legisla tion 1777 5.00 Lincoln City Directory Co 1778 5.00 K. I.. Polk &amp; Co 177' 6.00 21 T. &amp;. J. \Y. Johnson Co 17*1 5.50 Callaghan &amp; Co 1782 43.28 The Cars well Co 1783 50.45 West Publishing Co 1784 The Banks Law Publishing Co. ...1785 43.53 The Boston Book Co 178f&gt; 14&lt;&gt;.31 Feb. 3 The Frank Shepard Co 1787 32.00 Bancroft-W hitnev Co 1788 25.50 21 Matthew Bender &amp; Co 178V 23.00 Bohhs-Merrill 'to 1790 7.50 Cromarty Law Book Co 1791 38.00 American Publishing Co 1792 5.00 The Hubbell Publishing Co 1793 5.35 The American Economic Ass'n. . . .1794 4.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 1795 1.39 Chas. R. Lauriat 1796 7.50 Lawyers Co-Operative Publishing Co 17'»7 61.00 H. \V. Wilson Co 1798 12.75 Jacob North &amp; Co 17'* 1 ! 5.00 March 4 O .lumbia Law Review 1800 2.50 (,. M. Porter 1801 7.80 6 T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1802 78.15 The Citator Publishing Co 1803 3.00 April 27 Edward Thompson Co 1804 17.50 The Michie Co 1805 • 4.50 The Keefe-Davidson Co 1806 12.00 Mav 17 The American Law Book Co 1807 13.20 The Frank Shepard Co 1808 30.50 Callaghan &amp; Co 1809 142.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 13 1911 To Whom Paid Warrant No. Amount The Cars well Co 1810 65.90 24 C mmartv Law Book Co 1811 3.00 II. C. Carbaugh 1812 3.00 The Rough Notes Co 1813 3.50 The Boston Book C. 1814 253.22 West Publishing Co 1815 62.60 The Banks Law Publishing Co 18W&gt; 18.80 Eugene F . Ware 1817 2.00 June _' Vale University Press 1818 14.68 7 C. R. Stasenka 181V 2.00 July 26 American Ass'n for Labor Legisla- tion 1820 5.00 Lawyers Co-Operative Publishing Co 1821 53.50 Canada Law Book Co 1822 11.65 The Boston Book Co 1823 159.46 The Carswell Co 1X24 21.10 The Banks Law Publishing Co 1825 20.30 I )o&lt;ld-Mead Co 1826 18.90 H. \V. Wilson Co 1827 6.00 T. &amp; J. W. Johnson Co 1828 5.50 I lyacinthe Ringrose 182«&gt; 2.50 X. \V. Aver &amp; Son 1830 5.60 The Michie Co 1831 9.00 WOrld Publishing Co 1832 5.00 J. S. Beem 1833 10.00 Bobbs-Merrill Co 1834 37.50 31 Illinois Law Review 1835 3.00 E. P. Dutton &amp; Co 1836 6.76 Poors Railroad Manual Co 1837 16.00 ■ Bancroft-Whitney Co 1838 12.00 7 Frank Harrison 1839 10.00 1 1 West Publishing Co 1840 65.70 Sept. 28 Callaghan &amp; Co 1841 243.80 Matthew Bender &amp; Co 1842 27.00 State Journal Co 1843 25.00 Keefe- Davidson Co 1844 12.00 Oct. 13 Lawyers Co-Operative Publishing Co 1845 43.50 The Carswell Co 1846 131.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 REPORT OF THE 1 r 1 1 i w in/ uuui i itiu n» ciri dii \ *^u. aujv um T. &amp; J. W. Johnson Co 1847 5.50 T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1848 130.50 Shepard Book Co 1849 2.80 27 West Publishing Co 1850 70.20 The Frank Shepard Co 1851 27.00 Vernon Law Book Co 1852 22.5C A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 1853 7.68 Dec. 1 1 The Boston Book Co 1854 174.57 The C. A. Nichols Co 1855 6.00 American Ass'n of Law Libraries. .1856 5.00 Mrs. F. A. Harrison 1857 206.80 Jan. 12 The H. W. Wilson Co 1858 53.50 Callaghan &amp; Co 1859 107.60 Lincoln City Directory Co 1860 5.00 State Journal Co 1861 7.50 Scientific American Compiling Dept 1862 76.00 Feb. 8 The Carswell Co. 1863 55.00 The Banks Law Publishing Co 1864 34 2:5 The Bee Publishing Co 1865 7 JO West Publishing Co 1866 62 8? 13 W. H. Schmidt 1867 1.00 Bancroft-Whitney Co 1868 12 CO Jacob North &amp; Co 1869 i.OO 20 Edward Thompson Co 1870 15 00 T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1871 69.75 The Hubbell Publishing Co 1872 5.35 The Michie Co 1873 9.00 Cromarty Law Book Co 1874 3.00 The American Publishing Co 1875 5.00 Lawyers Co-Operative Publishing Co 1876 78.50 The Century Co 1877 49.50 The American Law Book Co 1878 7.60 March 8 Keefe- Davidson Co 1879 12.00 American Economic Ass'n 1880 4 00 28 State Journal Co 1881 7.50 Columbia Law Review 1882 2. 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 15 1 y 1 2 To Whom Paid Warrant No. Amount The American Ass'n for Labor Leg- islation 1883 5.00 April 13 The Citator Publishing Co 1884 25.00 Yale University Press 1885 1.32 Canada Law Book Co 1886 7.50 The Carswell Co 1887 47.50 The Boston Book Co 1888 193.40 The Frank Shepard Co 1889 59.00 May 14 West Publishing Co 18 l X) 68.70 The Banks Law Publishing Co. ... 1891 28.50 The Bobbs-Merrill Co IS 1 :.' 81.00 Callaghan &amp; Co 1893 292.60 American Ass'n of Law Libraries. .1894 5.00 28 A. A. Ciearheart 1895 1.95 Journal Criminal Law and Crimi- nology 1896 3.00 June 24 The Boston Book Co 1897 229.82 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 1898 5.42 The Rough Notes Co 1899 3.50 The Carswell Co 1900 44.15 The F. H. Thomas Law Book Co. .1901 ■ 12.00 The Michie Co 1902 4.50 Dodd-Mead Co 11Co 5.67 July 18 T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1&lt;XH 21.50 The Banks Law Publishing Co.. . . l°05 19.85 Cambridge University Press l'O^ 145.00 C. Martin 1907 1.70 27 Lawyers Co-Operative Publishing Co 1908 63.00 Bancroft-Whitney Co 1909 11.00 Aug. 5 The Banking Law Journal Co 1910 3.00 Illinois Law Review 101 1 3.00 Poor's Railroad Manual Co 1912 16.00 Sept. 7 Edward Thompson Co 1913 17.00 Canada Law Book Co 1914 5.30 27 The Carswell Co 1915 53.70 The Boston Book Co 1916 217.46 A. C. McClurg 1917 20.76 West Publishing Co 1918 74.70 T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1919 43.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 REPORT OF THE lviz low noiii i&amp;iq w&amp;rr&amp;ot Amount Callaghan &amp; Co 1920 55.75 The Frank Shepard Co 1921 29.00 The Banks Law Publishing Co.... 1922 21.30 18 F. A. Harrison 1923 197.00 21 Matthew Bender &amp; Co 1925 12.00 The Boston Book Co 1926 120.07 West Publishing Co 1927 103.35 Lawyers Oo-Opentive Publishing Co l«'2K 47.00 T. &amp; J. \\ . Johnson Co 1929 11.00 The Carswell Co 1930 24.65 Illinois Book Exchange 1931 48.50 The Frank Shepard Co 1932 30.00 Amount Lapsed 1.43 Amount Unexpended Nov. 30, 1912 528.48 Appropriation^ $6,936.06 $6,936.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">APPENDIX </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 KKPORT OK THk. ADDITIONS TO THE STATE LIBRARY For the TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912. A Abbott, Austin i.ivil jury trials; 3d ed., 1912. Abbott &amp; Abbott. Clerk's and conveyancers' assistant; 3d ed. Birdseyc, 1912. Adams, George Burton. Origin of the English constitution, 191-' Alabama. Appellate court reports; v. 1-3, - Archives, Dep't of. Official register. 1"-*! 1 . • .eneral acts. 1901, 1907, 1911. Supreme court reports, v. 163-171 Shepard's citations, 2d ed., 1907 Alaska. Reports ; v. 2. 3. Alberta. Supreme court reports; v. 1, 2. American annotated cases; 1912A. 1912B. W12C American and English annotated cases; v. 17-21. Digest, v. 1-20. ■ ricaii and Knglish encyclopedia •&gt;! law and practice; v. 5. 2 copies American and Kngli&gt;li railroad cases; v. 59-O5. American association for labor legislation. Publications Legislative review International labor bulletin \mcrican bankruptcy reports; v. 24-27. American bar association. Proceedings: \_. M&gt;. 1911. American decisions, Notes on ; v. 8-20. \merican digest, Decennial edition; v. 21-24 Rev-number series; v. 9-12. Descriptive word index. 1912 American economic association quarterly, 3d series; v. 11 American economic review; v. 1, 1911. Ban historical review; v. 3. 15, 16. an journal international law; v. 4, 5. an journal of sociology ; v. 16, 17. an law review ; v. 44, 45. American lawyer; v. 6, 16. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE MBKAKIAN. 1911-1912 19 Aiiieru-an nui/k/mc v 7(&gt;-7S • i lil* 1 IV- Alt IKuC Ou 1 ll\^ y T ■ # \^ w \J • American negligence reports; v. 21. Digest, 1910. American newspaper annual and directory (Ayersj, 1911 \inerican pharmaceutical association; v. 58, 1910. American state reports; v. 134 140. Digest, by E. S. (jreen; v. 5. lericana iTbe), 22 v., 1911. nals of the American academy of political and social sciem- v. is-m. Vrchlxild, John Frederick. Criminal pleading; 24th ed. t W10 Arena; v. 22. Izona. Const hutiuiial convention minutes. 1910. Journal ol tin- legislative assemblies. 1912. Session laws. 1909, 1912. Supreme court reports; v. 11-13. Arkansas. Acts, 1905, VO7, 1909, 1911. Supplement to Kirbv's Higest ol tin statutes, 1911 Supreme court reports; v. 85-*V. E antic monthly ; v. 106-109. antic reporter; \. 77-83. 1 )ij^est ; v . 3, Atwell, \\ illiani H. Fedcrml riiniiual law, 1911. Australia. ( oTnniotiv. -ealth law reports: \. ')-12. B Babbitt. Charles J. Motor vehicles, 1911. Bailey, William 1-rancis. I'ersonal injuries; 2d ed.. .1 v., 1912. Baldwin, Willis. Personal injuries; 2d. ed., 1909. IJallard. Mmerson E. Real property ; v. 13, 1911. Banker's magazine ; v. 80-83. Hanking law journal : v. 27, 2X. E— Digest, Jan.. 1900-Jury. 1912. los. 1-aw reports; v. 1, 2. ger &amp; Adams. Mines and mining; v. 2. 1911. ■ &amp; Schultz. Documents on the initiative, referendum an 1 recall, 1912. Keainhanip. I. |. lurisi&gt;rudetue ot the priv'v council (Canada) ; v. 2, 1909. Biblical and theological studies, 1911. (Princeton Seminary). Bigelow, Melville Madison. Fraudulent conveyances. 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 REPORT OP THE xjlucM- Jicnrv Campbell. Lew dictionary ; ed., 191U. Blakemore &amp; Bancroft. Inheritance tax law, 1912. Bloom, Solomon. Mechanic's liens, 1910. Bolles, Albert S. National bank act ; 4th ed., 1910. Bookman, v. 31-34. Bookwalter, John \Y. Rural versus urban, 1911. Booth, Henry Judson. Street railways; 2d ed., 1911. Brady, John Edson. Bank deposits, 1912. rnnan, Joseph Doddridge. Negotiable instruments ; 2d ed., 1911. British Columbia. Law reports, v. 15, 16. Sessional papers, 12th Parl., 1st sess. 1910; 2d sess. 1911. Statutes, 1911, 1912. Broom, Herbert. Common law of England; 10th ed., 2v., 1911. Broom, Herbert. Legal maxims; 8th ed., 1911. Bulletin of bibliography; v. 6, 1909-1912. Burge. William. Commentaries on colonial and foreign laws; New ed. v. 3, 1910. Eterwiirtb'&gt; workmen'! compensation cases (English); v. 1-4, 1909. C Cabell, James Branch. Branch of Abingdon. 1911. California. Appellate court reports; v. 13-17. AaaeMbty journal. 38th sess. (extra) 1910; 39th sess. (extra) 1911. C&lt;»les ( Kerrj ; 4 v. 1905; General laws (Hennings) ; v. 5, 1905; Supplements (Kerr). 1906-1909, 1911. Constitution of U. S. and California and other docu ments, 1912. Examiners, Board of. Report, 1 • ' 1 1 Senate journal, 38th sess. (extra) 1910; 39th sess (extra) 1912. Statutes, 1911; extra sess., 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 157-161 Shepard's citations, 1912. Treasurer, Biennial report, 1912. Campbell, William S. Forms of code pleading for Nebraska. Kansas and ( )klahoma ; 2 v. 1912. Canada. Eastern law reporter; v. 8-10. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 21 Exchequer court reports ; v. 13. Mines department. Annual report, 1910. Parliament. 11th Parl., 1st sess. Appendix to house journals 1907-08, v. 43 pts. 1, 2; v. 44. 11th Parl., 2d sess. House journal 1910, v. 45, pts. 1, 2, 3. Appendix. 11th Pad 2d sess. Sessional papers, v. 11th Parl 3d sess. House of commons journal, 1910-11, v. 46, appendix. Senate journal. 1910-11, v. 46. 11th Parl., 3d sess. Sessional papers, v. 45, nos. 1-8, 10-13. 12th Parl. 1st sess. Journals of house of commons, v. 47, 1911-12 and appendix. Revue de jurisprudence ; v. 16, 17. Revue legale; v. 16,17. Royal society proceedings and transactions; 3d s-:itrs, 1910-1911. Statutes. 1910, 1911, 1912. Supreme court reports; v. 42-45. Territories law reports; v. 7. Canada law journal ; v. 46. 47. Canadian annual digest (case law), 1910, 1911. Canadian criminal cases; v. 15-18. Canadian law times; v. 30, 31. Canadian railway cases; v. 10-13. Catholic encyclopedia ; v. 10-14. Catholic world ; v. 69-94. Central law journal ; v. 70-73. Index-digest; v. 55-72. Century dictionary and cyclopedia; 12 v. 1911. Century magazine ; v. 80-83. Chamberlayne, Charles Frederic. Evidence; v. 1-3, 1911. Chautauquan ; v. 26, 59-66. Chicago legal news; v. 42, 43. Kurch, William Smithers. Legal and business forms, 1911. urch, William Smithers. New Probate law and practice ; 2 v. 1909. Bl, Eugene. Union label laws, 1911. s weekly ; v. 45-48. 44 pts. 1, 4, 9, 15-19. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">22 hns, V arnuru Lansing. Continental Congress at Princeton. tana E. Histoncal and natural history society, Biennial re - port, 1910. Irrigation statutes. 1908. Laws, extra sess., 1910, 1911. Revised statutes, 1908. Supreme court reports, v. 48-51 Columbia law review, v. 10, 11. Commercial laws of the world; v. 1, Argentine Republic v. 2. Colombia. v. 7, United States of Americ*. v. 8, United States of America. v. 15, British dominions and protectorates. v. 18. Australia. New Zealand &amp; Pacific islands. v. 21, France &amp; Monaco v. 32. Spain. Confederate memorial literary society, Year book, 1912. Connecticut. Agriculture experiment station. Annual report, 1911, pts 1-6. Bulletins. Bank commissioners, Annual report, 1911 Comptroller, Report, 1911. Factory inspector, Biennial report. 1910 Fish and game laws, 1911. Forest fire manual, 1912. Geological and natur.il history survey, Bulletins Hartford municipal art society, Bulletins. Highway commissioner, Digest of work, 1910. Historical society, Annual report, 1911, 1912. Collections ; v. 13. List of family genealogies, 1911 House journal, 1911. Insurance commissioner, Annual report, 1912. Directory of insurance com panies, 1912. Labor statistics, Bureau of. Bulletins, 1911. Report: v. 24. 1910. Laws concerning dogs, 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">.-»TATK LIBRAKIAN. 1»11-1»12 23 Laws concerning insurance, 1911. Laws concerning taxation and taxing officials, 1912. Laws for improvement of public roads, 1911. Laws relating to banks, saving banks and trust com - panies, 1911. Laws relating to health, 1911. Laws relating to railroads and railways, 1911. Laws relating to shell-fisheries, 1912. Legislative history and souvenir; v. 8, 1912. List of bills for public and private acts pending be - fore committees of the general assembly. Feb. 1911. Police department. Biennial report, 1910. Prison association, Annual report; v. 33, 34, 1910, 1911. Report concerning the operation of the probation law. 1910. Public acts, 1911. Public documents, 190V, 1910. Railroad commissioners, Annual report, 1911 Reformatory, Report, 1911. Register and manual, 1911. 1V12. Rivers and harbors commission, Report, 1910. Secretary of state. List of registered motor vehicles 1912. Senate journal, 1911. Special acts and resolutions, 1911. Supreme court reports ; v. 83, 84. Treasurer, Annual report. 1911. School fund report, 1910 Contemporary review ; v. 75-82, 98-100. Cosmopolitan magazine ; v. 49-52. Cram's modern new census atlas. 1911 Current law; v. 14-16, 2 copies each. Cyclopedia of law and procedure ; v. 37-40. Annotations, 1911, 1912. D Davids, Berkeley Motor vehicles, 1911. Dean, Maurice B. Municipal bonds held void, 191 1 Delaware. Archives ; v. 1,2. House journal. 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 REPORT OF THE T awe- v 7f\ 1Q1 1 Pennewill's Delaware reports; v. 6, 7 Public schools report, 1910. Senate journal, 1911. rvlin, Robert Thomas. Real property and deeds ; 3d ed., 3 v. 1911. Dial; v. 49-51. Dillon, John F. Municipal corporations; 5th ed., 5 v., 1911. District of Columbia. Appeal cases ; v. 35-38. Doherty, Philip J. Liability of railroads to interstate employees' 1911. Drinker, Henry S. Interstate commerce act ; v. 3, 1910. Dryden, John Fairfield. In memoriam, 1912. Dunn, Charles Wesley. Pure food and drug legal manual; v. 1 1912. E Edinburgh review; v. 212-215. Educational review; v, 39-43. Elliott &amp; Elliott. Roads and streets; 3d ed., 2 v., 1911. Elliott, Charles Burke. Private corporations; 4th ed., 1911 Emerson, R. L. Legal medicine and toxicology, 1909. Encyclopedia Britannica; 11th ed., 29 v., 1912. Engineering news ; v. 63-67. I. British ruling cases ; v. 1, 2. Chitty's statutes; 6th ed., v. 1-8, 1911. Criminal appeal reports ; v. 5-7. Halsbury, Laws of England; v. 13-23; supp. to v, 1-12. Kant's index of cases judicially noticed, 1904-1910. Law journal ; v. 42-46. Law journal reports, 1910, 1911. Law reports, Appeal cases, 1910, 1911. Chancery division; 2 v., 1910; 2 v., 1911 Kings' bench division ; 2 v., 1910 ; 2 v., 191 1 Probate division, 1910, 1911. Law times ; v. 129-132. Law times reports; v. 102-105. Manson's bankruptcy and winding up cases ; v. 17, 18. Mew's annual digest, 1911. O'Mally &amp; Hardcastle election reports; v. 1-6. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 25 Railway and canal traffic cases ; v. 14. Reports (reprints); v. 110-128. Revised reports; v. 117-132. — Solicitors journal and weekly reporter; v. 54, 55. — Spink's prize cases; 1854-1856. Statutes, 1909. — Statutory rules and orders, 1910. — Times law reports ; v. 26, 27. — Weekly notes and current index. 1909, 1910. body's magazine; v. 23-25. F Farrand, Max. Records of the Federal convention of 1787; 3 v., 1911. Faxon, Frederick Winthrop. Annual magazine subject-index. 1911. Federal reporter; v. 180-197. Digest; v. 8. — Shepard's citations; 4th ed., 1911 Field museum of natural history, Annual report, 1912. Fletcher, William Meade. Incorporation and management of corporations in Illinois, 1910. Florida. House Journal, 1911. Laws, 1911. Secretary of state, Report, 1910. Senate journal, 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 59-61. Fortnightly review; v. 88-91. Forum ; v. 7, 44-47. Frost, Thomas Gold. Federal corporation tax law, 1911 G Georgia. Appeals reports; v. 8-10. Attorney General, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Bar association, Annual report ; v. 27, 28. Colonial records; v. 18, 19, 21. ( &lt;miptroller general, Annual report. 1910, 1911. Education department, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Geological survey, Bulletins. Handbook of mineral re- sources, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Governor, Messages, 1912. House journal, 1910, 1911. Insurance department, Report, 1910, 1911 Laws, 1910, 1911, 1912. Librarian, Annual report, 191 i Pensioner commissioner, Annual report, 1911. Prison commission, Annual report, 1912. Railroad commission, Annual report, 1910, 1911 Secretary of state, Annual report. 1911. Senate journal, 1910. 1911. 1912 Statutes : 2 v., 1910. — Supreme court reports; v. 134-13/"" Encyclopedic digest, 16 v Treasurer. Annual report. 1910. 1911. Green Bag; v. 22, 23. Z^regg, F. M. Handbook of parliamentary law. 1910 H dagar &amp; Alexander. Forms, rules and general orders in bank - ruptcy, 1910. 4al«ey, Francis W Grati epochs in American history; 10 v. 1911. •lardy, Carlos S. Fraternal societies, 1910 Harper's magazine : v. 121-124. Harris. \ irgil M Ancient, curious and famous wills. 1911 Hartford seminary record ; v. 20. Harvard law review ; v. 24, 25. Harvard university, Catalogue, 1910-11, 1911-12. Official register. 1909-10, 1910-11 Hawaii, Laws, 1911. Organic an 4 rh&lt; territory of Hawaii as amended July, 1911. Supreme coun reports ; v. 20. - U. S. District court reports; v. 3. Paynes, James B. History of the Trans-Mississippi and inter national exposition, 1898. Homiletic review: v. 58, 60-63. Hopkins, James Love. Judicial code, 1911 Hopkins, James Love. Patents ; 2 v., 191 1 Hubbell's legal directory. 1911. 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATK LIBRARIAN. 1»11-1»12 27 Hunt, William Holman. Pre-Raphaelitism and the Pre-Raphael - ite brotherhood; 2 v., 1905. I Idaho. Land commissioners, Board of. Carey act 1912 Land and irrigation laws, 191 1. Session laws, 1911. Statutes, Revised codes; 2 t., 1908. Supreme court reports; v. 18-20. University of, Bulletin. Illinois. Appellate court reports; v. 152-166. Charities commission. Annual report, 1910. Problems of state institutions which medical men may help to solve, 1912. Civil service commission. Annual report, 1910. Coal report, 1910, 1911. Historical library. Collections; v. 6. Report of trustees, 1908-10 Historical society. Collections ; v. 7. Transactions, 1909, 1910. Labor statistics, Bureau of. Free employment offices. Industrial accidents, 1911. Labor legislation, 47th general assembly. 1911. Workmen's compensation act 1912 Laws. 1911; special sess. 1911-12. Public charities, Biennial report, 1909. Institution quarterly ; v. 3. Report on the taxation and revenue system of, by J. A. Fairlie, 1910. Revised statutes, 1911 Supreme court reports ; v. 245-254. Notes on: v. 1-14 University of. Bulletins Illinois law review ; v. 5, 6. Independent; v. 68-71. Tndia. Law reports Appeal casts; v. 37, 38. Allahabad series; v. 32, 1910 Bombay series; v. 34, 1910. Calcutta series; v. 37. 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 REPORT OF THE Madras series ; v. 33, 1910. Indiana. Academy of science, Proceedings, 1909, 1910. Acts, 1911. Adjutant General, Report, 1910. Appellate court reports ; v. 45-47. Attorney General, Biennial report, 1910. Auditor, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Bar association. Report, 1911. Blind, School for the, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Boy's school, Annual report, 1910. Charities, Board of, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Charities and correction, Bulletins, 1910, 1911. Constitution (proposed), 1911. Dairy association, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Deaf, School for. Annual report; 1910, 1911. Documentary journal reports ; 1909 2 v. ; 1910 2 v. Education. Board of. Manual of instructions or school authorities and school physicians, 1911. Election laws, 1909. Entomologist, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Epileptics, Village for. Annual report, 1909, 1910. Farmer's institutes, Report, 1909-1910. Feeble-minded youth. School for, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Fisheries and game commissioner, Annual report, 1910. Forestry, Board of, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Geology and natural resources, Annual report, 1909, 1910. Girl's school. Report, 1910, 1911. Governor, Biennial message, 1911. Health, Board of, Annual report, 1909, 1910. Div. of bacteriology and pa - thology, Annual report, 1910. History of 3d Indiana cavalry. 1906. Horticultural society. Proceedings, 1910. House journal, 1911. Indiana at Antietam, Report of the Antietam monu - ment commission, 1911. Indiana at Vicksburg, 1910. Insane, Central hospital for, Report, 1910, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 29 Eastern hospital for, Report, 1910, 1911. Northern hospital for, Report, 1910, 1911. Southeastern hospital for. Report, 1910, 1911 Southern hospital for, Report, 1910, 1911. Inspection department, Annual report, 1910. Labor commission, Biennial report, 1910. Laws, 1801-06. Legislative committee report on state educational, benevolent and correctional institutions and public buildings, 1911. Librarian. Biennial report, 1910. Medical registration and examination, Board of, An - nual report, 1909, 1910. Normal school, Bulletins. Report, 1910, 1911 Prison, state, Annual report, 1910. 1911. Woman's. Annual report, 1910, 1911. Public instruction, Dep't of, Biennial report, 1910. Public library commission. Biennial report, 1910. Public printing. Board of, Biennial report, 1910. Purdue University, Bulletins, 1910, 1911, 1912. Railway commission. Report, 1910. Reformatory. Report. 1910, 1911. Secretary of state, Biennial report, 1910. Senate journal, 1911. Soldiers' home. Report, 1910, 1911. Soldiers' and sailors' orphans' home, Report, 1910, 1911. State superintendent. School laws. 1911. State manual and uniform course of study for the Elementary schools, 1911-1912. Uniform course of study for the commissioned, certified and accredited high schools, 1911-1912. Statistics department. Biennial report, 1910. Statutes, Burns' annotated ; 4 v., 1908. Supreme court reports; v. 173-175. Digest ; 12 v., 1910. Treasurer. Report, 1910, 1911. University. Bulletins. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">RKPOKT OK THK 30 insurance digest, v 23, 24, 1910, I91L Insurance law journal ; v. 39, 40. Iowa. Bar association, Proceedings, 1910. E Control, Board of. Biennial report, 1910. Labor statistics, Bateau of, Biennial report, 190y Laws, 1911. Legislative documents, o v., 1911 — Masonic library, Bulletins. — Official register. 1911-1912. Register of the sons of the revolution. 1912. State drainage, waterways and conservation commis - sion, Biennial report. 1911. — Supreme court reports; v. 143-152. Digest; v. 5. 1912 Ireland. Irish land reports, v. 15, In. Irish law times; v. 44, 45. — Irish reports; 2 v. 1910; 2 v. 1911 — Reserved cases, 1860-1864. Weekly law reports; v. 1-8, 1895-1^02. I Man. Adv. .rate's note l*&gt;ok, by J. C. Bluett. 1847. Ancient ordinances and statute laws. Mills. 1821 Ancient ordinances and statute laws from the earliest times to 1836. Mills. Geneste, Jeffcott. Jurisprudence. Johnson, 1811. Legislation by three of the Thirteen Stanleys, Kings of Man acts 1417-1430: Acts 1627-1647; Acts 1703 — Lex scripta, 1819. — Statutes and ordinances now in force, alphabetical! . arranged by T. Stowell, 1792. — Statute laws passed since the year 1821. Geneste. 1832. Statute laws promulgated since the year 1836; Gell. 1836-1848. Statute laws promulgated since the year 1848; Bur- Statute laws, 1853-1861, inclusive; Lamothe, 1862 — Statute laws, 1860-1865. J Jamaica. Law reports, 1905. 1906 pt. 1. Jarman. Thoaas, Wills; &lt;&gt;th ed.. 2 \ .. W10. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">.STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 31 lohns Hopkins university. Studies in historical and politic* science ; v. 28, 29. Pes, Leonard Augustus. Collateral securities and pledges; 6c ed. 1912. • )urnal of American history; t. 3-5. Eof criminal law and criminology ; v. 1, 2 of the Franklin institute ; v. 170-173. of political economy ; v. 18, 19. Joyce, Joseph Asbury. Monopolies and unlawful combinations 1911. Judson, Frederick N. Interstate rr—mr rrf . 2d ed., 1912. Juridical review: v. 22. 23. K is aii»as. Agriculture, Board of, Report, 1912 Laws, 1911. t- — — Supreme court reports; v.82-86. tucky. Acts, 1912. House journal, 1910. Library, Report and Miipplomental catalogue, lylJ ' Official manual, 1912. Opinions; v. 6-9. Public documents ; .? v.. 1908-09. Senate journal, 1910. — Supreme court reports; v. 138-146. cky law reporter; v. 26-32. Kerr, James II. Mining and water cases annotated; v. 1. 1912. Kinney, Clessoii Selwyne, Irrigation; 2d ed., v. 1, 2, 1912. Knocker, Douglas. Accidents in their medico-legal aspect, 1911. K i mkle. Burton Aha. Life and speeches of Thomas Williams 1806-1872. 2 v. L Lake Mohonk conference of friends &lt;&gt;t the Indians and other de- pendent peoples, 1911. Lake Mohonk conference on international arbitration, 1912. Lamed, J. N. History for ready reference; v. 7. Law notes ; v. 11-15. Law quarterly review ; v. 26, 27, Lawyer's reports annotated; v. 28-38 n. s, 4 copies each. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">32 REPORT OP THE Library journal ; v. 35, 36. Lippincott's magazine ; v. 86-89. Literary digest ; v. 40-43. Littell's living age; v. 264-273. Ina. Constitution and revised laws. (Wolff) 3 v.. 1904 - 1908. - Engineers, Board of, Biennial report, 1912. - House journal, 1910. - Public documents; 3 v., 1908-1910. - Senate journal, 1910. iipreme court reports; v. 129. Loveland, Franklin Olds. Appellate jurisdiction of the federal courts, 1910. Loveland, Franklin Olds. Bankruptcy ; 4th ed., 2v., 1912. M McAdam David. Landlord and tenant ; 4th ed., 3 v., 1910. McClure's magazine ; v. 35-38. McQuillan, Eugene. Municipal corporations; v. 1-3, 1911. Maine. Historical society, Collections; v. 15, 16. Piscataquis county ; v. 1. House documents; 3 v., 1911. House journal, 1911; special session, 1912. Laws, 1911. Legislative record. 1911; special session, 1912. Public documents; 5 v., 1910; 4 v., 1911. Register and legislative manual, 1911-12; 1912-13 Senate documents, 1911. Senate journal. 1911; special session, 1912. Supreme court reports; v. 106-108. Vital records. Pittston to 1892. — Randolph to 1892. York deeds ; v. 18. Manitoba. Law reports ; v. 19-21 Statutes. 1911, 1912. Maryland. Annotated code; 2 v.. 1911 Archives. Proceedings of the council, 1753-1761, v. 31 ; 1761-1770, v. 32. British statutes in force in Maryland (Alexander) ; </seg>
            <seg id="p036">33 Court of appeals reports; v. 113-116. House and senate documents, 1912. House journal, V&gt;\2. Laws, 1912. Senate journal, 1912. Massachusetts. Acts and resolves, 1911. 1912. Acts ;md resolves of the Province of Massachusetts Bay; v. 17. 1761-1764. Agriculture, Board of. ( iaxne birds, wild-fowl* and shore birds (Forbosh), 1912. Bunker Mill monument association. Proceedings, 1911, 1912. History of the 2d Mass. battery i .Vims' battery), 1861 - 1865. Ilistorx of the 5th Mass. vol. inf. 1864. History of the 17th Mass, volunteers in the Civil war. Labor statistics. Annual report, 1909. La\v&gt; of foreign countries in the state library. 1911. Library, Annual report, 1910. Hand-list of American statute law, 1912. New Lngland association of plumbing inspectors, Handbook, 1911-1912. Public documents; v. 1-12, 1909; v. 1-10, 1910. Statistics bureau. Annual report, l'H&gt;». Labor bulletins. Report on strikes and lockouts, l'Ml. Supreme court reports; v. 2O&gt;-210. Vital records. Andover, 2 v. Chester. Fo\ borough 1 lansen. llaverhill, v. 2. Ipswich, 2 v. Leonminster. Newbur) . 2 v Newburyport, v. 1. Pembroke. West P.oylston. Wrentham. v. 2. » </seg>
            <seg id="p037">34 Mav flower descendants. 12. U. Medico-legal juurnal; v. 2t&gt;-28. Mendelsohn, Solomon. Criminal jurisprudence of the ancient Hebrews. 1891. -Metropolitan ; v. 29. 31-34. Michigan. Academy of science. Report; v. 12,13. Acts, 1911. Acts, Public. 1911. Agriculture, Board of, Annual report. 19KL Attorney general. Annual report, 1910. Auditor's, Board of. Annual Report, 1910. Auditor general, Annual report., 1909, l'»10, 1911. Hanking department. Annual report, 1910. — Blind. Employment institution for. Biennial report, 1910. Building and loan associations. Report on, 1' '10. Dairymen's association. Annual report. 1910. Deaf. Scho.,1 for. Biennial report, 1909-1910. Education. Board of. Report. 1910. Geological survey, Board of. Report. 1908. Geological and biological survey. Publications. Governor, Message. Jan. 5, 1911. G. A. R. Annual encampment journal, 1910. Health. Hoard of. Bulletins. Report. 190 1 *. Highway commissioner. Biennial report, 1910. Horticultural society. Report, l ( *09. Insane. Eastern Michigan asylum. Report, 1910. Northern asylum. Report. 1910. Insurance department. Annual report, V&gt;\0, 1911. Labor. Dep*l of. Report, 1910. 1911. Legislative manual, 1911. Librarian. Report, 1910. Mineral statistics. Dep't of. Report. 1909. Railroad commission. Report. l'*09. 1910. Registration report, 1908, 1909. Senate journal. 1911. Soldier's home. Report, I'©*'. State, department of. Crop report. May, 1910-Jan. 1911. State superintendent, Report, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">35 oLiJjrcliit.' i * til 1 1 rcpOr TS j \ . 1 Dj*~ loy. Digest; v. 149-168. 1912. Tax commission, and board of assessors. R«. 1910. Treasurer. Report, 1910. Michigan law review ; v. 9, 10. Iesota. Drainage commission. Report to legislature, Water resources investigation, l'&gt;09-1910. Executive documents ; 5 v.. 1910. Laws, 1911. Legislative manual. 1911. t Minneapolis, History of the municipal building. 1909. Employes' compensation commission. Report to legislature. 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 110-116. Digest; 3 v. l'»l(). Minton-Senhouse. R. H. Workmen's compensation cases; 9 v. in 2, 1908. -~ippi. Supreme court reports: v. 95, 96. McWillie &amp; Thomp- m's digest : v. 74-'&gt;3. Mississippi Valley historical association. Proceedings. 1010-11. tiri. Adjutant general. Biennial report, 1910. Agriculture. Board of. Annual report. 1900, 1910, 1911. Appeal reports; v. 144-164. Auditor. Biennial report, 1910. - Banking department. Biennial report on examina - tion-, of state banks and trust companies. 1010. liar association, Proceedings; v. 28. 29. Building and loan bureau. Annual report, 1**10. 1911. Horticulture. Board of. Annual report. 1 ( &gt;09.1910. - House journal. 1911 and appendix. - Insurance department. Annual report, 190*), 1910, 1911. Labor statistics. Bureau of. Red book, 1910, 1911. - Laws, 1911. Mines, mining and mine inspection. Bureau of. An - nual report, 1909. - Official manual. 1911-1 Public schools. Report. 1909.1910. Tax commission. Biennial report, l'UO. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">36 Revised school laws, l'l* 1 '. Railroad and warehouse commission. Annual r&gt; l"0". 1910. 1911. Senate journal. 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 227-2AH.). Treasurer, Biennial report, 1910. Montana. Agriculture, Labor and Industry, Bureau of, Biennial report, 1910. Attorney general. Biennial report, 1910. Auditor. Biennial and annual reports, l'O9-10. Boiler inspector, Annual report, 1910. Coal mines inspector, Biennial report. 1910. Governor, Message, 1911. Health, Board of. Biennial report. 1910; House journal. 1911. Labor bureau. Report. 1910. Laws, 1911. Library. Biennial report, 1910. Livestock sanitary hoard and veterinarian. Re - 1910. .Mines. Inspector of, Biennial report, 1 ''10. Railroad commissioners. Report. l ( '10. 1911. ■ Secretan of ~tau-. Biennial report. 1910. Senate journal. 1911. State lands. Register of, Report. 1909-1910. State superintendent, Biennial report, l')10. Supreme court reports; v. 41-45. Treasurer, Biennial report. 1910. re, Dewitt Clinton. Interstate commerce, l'MO. Morris. Martin Ferdinand. History of the development of law. 1911. N Nation; v. y0-«H. National conference i&gt;f charities and corrections, Proceed! i U85, 1893. National corporation reporter: v. 39-43. National prison association. Proceedings. 1889, 1905. Nebraska. Adjutant general. Biennial report. 1910. Agriculture. Board of, Annual report. 1910. A. F. &amp; A. M. Proceedings of the grand lodge, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">37 Auditor, Biennial report. 1910. Banking board, Annual report. 1910, 1911. — — Building and loan associations, An - nual report, 1910. 1911, 1912 Blue book, l'*)l-1902. Brief's. Opinions filed in Supreme court ; 52 v. Dairymen's association. Annual report. 1910, 1911. House journal. 1911, 2 copies. House mils. 32d session, l'»ll. Knights Templar grand commandery, Proceedings. 1911, 1912 Laws (Judges room "). 1870-71, 1875, 1879-1909. Laws. 1911, 10 copies (Judges' rooms and library). Legislative year hook. 1911. Lincoln city directory. 2 copies 1**11 : 2 copies 1912. Lincoln. City library of. Annual report, \')\2. .Nebraska state gazetteer and business directory. 1911. Nebraska state journal. July 1909- June 1912. Omaha daily bee. July 1909-Jtne 1912. Public documents; 4 v. 1910. Public lands and buildings, Commissioner of, Bien - nial report. 1910. Relief commission report. l'O.V Royal arch masons. Grand chapter. Proceedings. 1910, 1911. Russian famine, by W. C. Kdgar. 1893. Senate files, 32d session. 1911. Senate journal. 1911. 2 copies. South Omaha public library. Annual report, 1912. State superintendent. Biennial report, 1910. Statutes. 1885. 1893. 1897. 189&lt;&gt;. l&lt;)05 Cobhey's supple - ment. Cobbey's annotated. 1911. 10 copies. Wheeler's compiled. 1911. 10 copies. Revised. 1866. (Judges room '») 1873. 1881. 1883. 188". 1901. 1903 Cobbey; 1905 Compiled: 1905 Cobbey'-; supplement. Supreme court reports: v. 8". 88. 7 copies each : v. 89, </seg>
            <seg id="p041">38 KKPORT OP THK ■AJ, o copies t«ic n. (Judges ri h .in 9) v. 1-88. University, Nebraska cornhusker. 1911, 1912. Agriculture experiment station, Report 1912. Elh-. Andrew |. Street railroads; 2&lt;1 ed., 2 v.. 1911. vada. Assembly journal. 1911, and appendix. led Imwi; 2 v.. 1912. Secretary of state, Biennial report, 1910. Senate ji nirnal. l ( 'l 1. Statutes, 1911. Supreme court report*; v. 32. 33. Digest; v. 1-32. 1912 New Brunswick. Statutes, 1910, 1911, l'M2. B— — supreme court reports; v. 39. ngland magazine ; v. 42-44. ampshirc. Annual reports; 2 v.. l'XW; 5 v.. 1*' 10. Charities and corrections. Hoard of, Biennial : 1910. First hundred yean of the New Hampshire bibl ciety. Laws, 1911. Senate and house journals. 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 7?. Bnternational year book, 1907, 1909. 1910, 1911. ersey. Assembly minutes. 1911, T'12. Compiled statutes; 5 v.. 1910. Equity reports: v. 7^-7'K History of the 1st brigade N. J. volunteers 18«V. amille Baquet. l'HO. Laws. 1911. 1912. Legislative documents; 6 v., 1909; 6 v., 1910. Legislative manual; 1911, 1912. Librarian. Annual report, 1910. ftfoMom, Rep..rt. W09, l&lt;'10. Public library commission. Annual report, 1910 Senate journal. 1910. 1911, 1912. Supreme court. Law reports; v. 7 New Jersey law journal ; v. 33, 34. Secretary's report. 1909-1910, and legislative man - ual. 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE LIBRARIAN. Ill 11-1912 39 K Supreme court reports; v. 15, 16. South Wales. State reports; v. 9-11. York. Abbott's annual digest. 1910. 1911. Annotated cases; \. 20. Assembly documents. 131st sess. v. 11-14. VXM: 132d v. 1-20, 22-43, 1909; 133d sess. v. 2-4. 10-1 35, 1910. Assembly journal; 4 v., l'UO. Charities, Hoard of, Annual report; 3 v. 1909; sta- tistical appendix, 1909; 3 v. and appendix, 1910. nil procedure reports; v. 40; v. 2 n. s. Court of appeals reports; v. I'*'- 205. Criminal reports ; v. 24-2&lt;&gt;. Education department. Annual report, 1910, 1911. State museum. Annual report; 4 v., 1909. Governor, Public papers. 1 * K&gt;" ' (Hughes). Hudson- Fulton celebration: 2 \ .. 1 Law-; 3 \.. 1911; 2 v., 1912 — Library, Annual report, l'WN. 1«O). 1910. — Miscellaneous reports; v. 1)6-75. New York supplement; v. 124-136. Public service commission. Dual system of rapid transit for New York city, 1912 ( ias pressure condi- tions in Manhattan. New York city, 1912. Report for the first district: 3 v. I'*)": 4 v. 1910; v. 1., l'Ml. Report for tl ond district. 1W-M11 Senate documents, 132d sess. v. 1-24. l'K&gt;9; 133.! v. 1-27. 1910. Senate journal; 2 v.. 1910. State water supply commission, Annual report. Statutes. Birdseye. (Turning &amp; Gilbert's supplements to consolidated statutes; v. 7-9, 1910-1912. Consolidated laws.; v. 8, 9. Supreme court reports. Appellate division; v. 137-148. Surrogates' courts. Mills reports: v. 1-6. UnconsoHdated laws. 1778-1911, 2 v. Yearl 'cgislation. 1008. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">40 New Y«&gt;rk Chy. Qmeetu Borough paMic library, Report, 1911. New /caland. Law reports; v. 2*'. 30. — Vear book. 1900-1903, 1907-1910. loundland. Acts. 1911-1912 Nineteenth century: v. 68-71. North American review: v. 192-195. North Carolina. Labor and printing- department, Annual report. l ( &gt;10. Laws. Private. l'Ul. Laws. Public. 1911. Statutes, Collection of the statutes of the parliament of England in force in North Carolina. 17' '2. — Supreme court reports : v. 153-158. — Treasurer, Biennial report. 1910. N..nh Dakota. Mouse journal. 1909, 1*&gt;1 1 . Journal of the impeachment of lohn F. Cowaa; 2 v.. 1911. Public document- ; 4 v.. l'XIS:4 v.. 1010. Senate journal. 1909, 1911, Session laws. 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 18-21 Digest. (Hill): v. 2. 1911. Northeastern reporter: v. ( .»2-9S. Digest ; v. d. Northwestern reporter; v. 127-130. 3 copies each. Digest; v. 8. v. 116-130. No^t Scotia. Statutes 1910. 1911. 1912. — Supreme court reports; v. 44. 45. O B Adjutant General. Annual report, l l i00. Agriculture. Hoard of. Annual report. 1908. Report on commercial fertiliz- ers. 1909. Auditor. Annual report. 190 1 '. Comparative statistics of counties. 1907. Bank* and banking. Annual report. 1909. Boys' industrial school. Riennial report. l'XX-l'W. Common schools, commissioner of. Annual report. 1909. Blind. Sch.M&gt;l for. Report. 1907-1&lt;&gt;0 &lt; ). </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATK LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 41 Dairy and food commissioner, Annual report. 1 ( JO9. Deaf. School for. Biennial report. l'*09. Dental board. Report. 1909. Education department. Arbor day manual, 1910. Epileptics. Hospital for. Biennial report, l'W. Fanners' institute proceedings. l'X&gt;&gt;. Federal, state and county officers. List of, l'UO. Feeble-minded, Institution for, Report. 1909. Geological survey. Bulletin. liirls' industrial home. Annual report. l'W. Health. Hoard of, Annual report. 1' House journal. 1909, l u 10. Insurance department. Annual report. 1910. Labor statistics. Bureau of, Annual report. 1909 Law&gt;. l'MO. Legislative practice. Manual of, l'OM'ilO. Library. Library laws. 1910. Library commissioners. Annual report. l'C. Live stock commissioners. Board of, Annual report. 190 1 ). Memorial day and peace day manual. May. l ( '10. Miami University. Annual report. VKfK Mines inspector. Annual report. 1908. 190*'. Public printing. Supervisor of. Annual report, 1**00. Public works. Hoard of, Annual report. 1 ( X&gt;&gt;. Railroad commission. Report. 190"). Secretary of state Annual report. 1*X&gt;&gt;. Senate journal. 190&lt;&gt;. l&lt;&gt;10. Soldiers' and sailors" home, liiennial report. 1909. Soldiers" claims. Commissioner, Report. l ( X)7-l ( &gt;09. State hospital, Athens. Report. 1909. — Cleveland, Report. 1909. — Columbus. Report. 1909. — Dayton. Report, 1909. — Massillon. Report. 1909. Statutes. General code: 4 v.. l ( &gt;10: Annotations, v. 5. 1911. Supreme court reports: v. S2. Toledo library. Biennial report. 1909. Township and municipal officers. List of, 1910. Treasurer. Annual report. \'X¥&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">42 Ohio law bulletin ; v. Oklahoma. Charities and corrections. Commissioner of. Report, 1911. Corporation commission. Annual report. 1909, 1910. Criminal court of appeals reports; v. 4. 5, 6. House journal. 1909, 1'UO; Extra session, 1"K.' Red book. 1912. Senate journal. [907-1908, 1909; extra session, 1910. Session laws, 1910-1911. Supreme court reports; \. 2r-2 l K Ontario. Law reports; v. 22-24. Statutes. 1911, 1912. Ontario weekly reporter; v. 12. 15-19, 21. goo. Adjutant General, Biennial report, 1910. Agricultural college. Annual report, 1909-19! Hanking laws. 1911. Blue book. 1911. Conservation association. Wood-using Industrie-. 111. Corporation laws, 1911. — Desert land board, Biennial report, 1912. Elections. Statutes relating to, 1911. Engineer. Bulletin, Oregon system of water title. Ftth and game laws, 1911. Fisheries. Department of. Biennial report. 19 Forest nre laws, 1911. Forester, Annual report, 1911. Forestry department. Lesson in forestry taught by the forest fires of 1910. Health. Board of. Annual report. 1910; Biennial re - port. 1011. - Health. Statutes relating to. 1911. Horticulture. Board of. Biennial report, 1910. Horticultural society. Proceedings, 1911. House journal, 1911. Insurance commissioner. Annual report, 1910. Insurance companies and fraternal societies, Statutes relating to. 1911. Labor statistics and inspector of factories and work - shop-. Bureau of. Annual report. 1911. Land board. Biennial report. 1910, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 43 Land department. Annual report, 1911. Laws, 1911. Mini's and mining laws. 1911. Motor vehicle law, 1911. Public documents; 2 \.. l'WM'nO. Public instruction, department of. Arbor and bird day manual, 1 ( '12. Railroad commission. Annual report, 1910-1911. Railroads, common carriers by rail and public util- ities. Laws relating to. 1911. Roads, highways, bridges and ferries, Statutes relat - ing to. 1911. Secretary of state. Biennial report, 1909-1910. Senate journal. 1911. Stallion registration board, Annual report, 1912. State land. Statutes relating to sale and dispositi i 1911. State superintendent. Course of &gt;tudv of the elemen - tary schools. 1911. School laws. 1911. Supreme court reports ; v. 55-59. Tax commissioners. Biennial report, 1910-1911. 1 11- &lt;J 1912. Water laws. l'Ul. Oswald, James Francis. Contempt of court; 3d ed., 1911. Outing; v. 56-5 ( &gt;. Outlook; v. 5663, "'5-100. P Pacific reporter; v. 110-123. Digest; v. 6, 96- 110; v. 7, 111-120. Pall Mall; v. 45-47. 49. Parker, John S. Corporation manual; 17th ed.. 1912. EJohn S. New Jersey corporations; 2 v., 1911. James. Fine art collection of Glasgow, 1906. lvania. Agriculture, Board of, Annual meeting, 1912. Agriculture. Departmeat-of, Annual report. 1910. ulletins. "eau of chemistry, Bulletin-- Food and dairy division. Bulle- tins. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">44 REPORT OF THE jl*1_HJ1 t^«£ • U 1 • 1^1* '11, IillllClJIl^. Allegheny county law library, Catalogue of, 1912. Appropriation acts, 1911. Archives, v. 1-8. 1664-1781. Attorney General. Report and official opinions, l l »10. Banking. Commissioner of. Annual report, part 1, 1911. Charities. Hoard of. Annual report, 1910. Laws relating to. 1911. l J reliminar\ report. 1911-1912. Chestnut tree Might commission. Bulletin. 1 ( '12. Colonial records: v. 1-16, WW-1790. O lunty court reports ; v. 37-38. Daopkia county reports; \. 13-14. Delaware county reports; v. 11. District court reports; v. l''-20. Factory inspector, Annual report. 1911. Farmers normal institute. Annual meeting, 1 (| 1_ Fisheries, Department of. Report, 1911. Game commissioners. Annual report. 1911. G. A. K. r.^ter. l'&lt;12. Health. Department of. Laws relative to, 1911. Rules and regulations. l'»12. Health Bulletins. Iliston of the 17th regiment volunteer cavalry. l'Ml History 22d cavalry and Kinggold battalion. 1**11 History at the 45th regiment Penn. volunteer infantry 1912. History of the 52d regiment 1'enn. volunteer infantrv 1911. History of the 61st regiment I'enn. volunteers. l'Ml. History of the 93d regiment Penn. veteran volunteers l'Ml. Itwirance department. Annual report; part 1, 1911 List of insurance brokers. l'»12. Internal affairs. Sec. of. Annual report; parts 1. 2. 4 1911. I . i _ ■ . . y— -y^&gt; Conference, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">45 1912. Legislative journal: 3 v., 1911. Legislative reference bureau, Hill drafting. 1912. Constitution of Penn. 1912. Special legislation. 1912. Lehigh county law journal ; v. 4. Librarian, Report. l'XH 1911. Library commission, Handbook, 1912. Livestock sanitary board, C ircular. Live stock sanitary laws. Mines, Department of, Report; part 2, 1911. Montgomery comt) law reporter; \. 2&lt;&gt;, 27. Northhamptoa county reports; v. 12. Pennsylvania at Salisbury. \. C. Ceremonies, 19 Prison society, Journal of prison discipline ami phil - anthropy. 1912. Public instruction. Superintendent of, Annual r&lt; 1911. Public buildings and grounds, Hoard of. Laws per - taining to. Public instruction. Department of, Coarse oi stttd elementary schools, id ed., 1912. &lt; Outline of ag ture for elementary schools. 1912. Railroad commission, Annual report, 1911. Sinking fund. Commissioners of, Report, 1911. Soldiers' orphan schools, Commission of. Annual re - port, 1911. State college, Annual report, 1911. Stewart &amp; Pardon's digest of statute law: 13th ed.. 5 v., 1903-1910. Superior court reports; \. 42 -kS. Supreme court report-: v. 228-231 Topographic and geologic survey commission, Re - port. 1908-1910. Treasurer. Annual report. 1911. L'niver»it\ of. Law rex iew : v. 56, ; Vale's digest of all court reports: v. 6-9. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">46 Philippine Islands. Commission. Journal 2d legislature, 1st 1010. Public instruction. Department of, Annual report. 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 15-20. •hie times : v. 42. 4.v ■ ence quarterly ; v. 25, 2(&gt;. manual of industrials; v. 2. 3. manual of railroads; v. +4. 4?. Rut. Robert P. IJangers of municipal trading. 1907 ace Edward Island. Statutes, 1910, 1911. aceton University. Catalogue, 1010-1911. Q Brh journal of economics; \. 25. Practice reports; v. 11. 12 - Statute-. Revi-ed: v. 3, 4, 1909. Statutes, 1011. V&gt;\2. .id. State reports. l ( «0. 1910 R Readers guide to periodical literature, 1900-1904 1005-1909. Remington. Harold. Bankruptcy law; v. 3. 1910. Review of re\iew&gt;; v. 42-4 ; Revnolds. William. Trial evidence; Pocket ed.. 1911. Rhode Island. Acts and resolves. 1910, 1911. Adjutant General, Annual report. l'OO, 1010. 1911. Advisorv 1&gt;oar&lt;l of visitors to institutions where women are imprisoned. Annual report, 1912. Agriculture. Hoard of. Annual report, 1000. l'»10. Some suggestions lor R. I apple growers. Auditor. Annual report, 1011. l'&gt;12. Bank commissioner. Annual report, 1 ' '10, 1011. Birds. Commissioner of, Annual report, 1912. [adisou C. Justice to the Jews, VW. Probate report! an nutated, v. 14 I ual bulletin ; v. 7. .jieal review; v. 17. 18. Public libraries : v. 15. lo. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATK LIBRARIAN, 47 C hantit*&gt; .'i in I corrections 1910, 1911. Laws relating to, 1911. Control, lizard of, Annual report, l*&gt;10, 1911. Deaf, Institute for. Report. 1910. Education department, Arbor day manual, 1911, 1* ' 1 _? Laws relating to education l'MO. Library bulletins. Program for the anniversary of Rhode Island independence day, 1911, 1912. Factory inspection. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Forestry. Commissioner. Annual report, 1911, 1912. General assembly reports; 2 w, 1910, 1911. Governor, Messages, 1911, 1912. Grand Army flag day, 1911. 1912. Harbor commissioners. Hoard of. Annual report. I 1 '12. Harbor improvement commission Report. 1012. Health. Hoard of. Annual reports. 1902-l&lt;X)5. Industrial statistics, Bureau of. Municipal finances. 1911. Tenement house conditions in five Rhode Island cities. Commissioner of. Annual re- port. 1&lt;MO. loll. Inland fisheries. Commission of, Annual report. 1911. Insurance commission. Annual report; 2v., 1909. 1910. Legislative reference bureau. Bulletins. Legislature, Report of commission on hospital advanced cases of tuberculosis. 1911. Report of the Col. 1 1. H. Young monument commission, 1912. 2d &amp; 3d reports of the joint special commit - tee on the taxation laws. 101 1, 1012. Librarian. Annual report, 1910, 1911 Library, Handbook, 1911. Manual. 1910. 1911. Manual with rules and orders. 1911, 1912. Operation and maintenance, Commissionor of, Annual report. 1910. Pharmacy. Board of. Annual report. I'M 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">' 48 RKPORT OF THE Law-. Public, l'W-10. 1912. Public roads. Board erf, Annual report, l'UO, 1911. Laws and rules relating to, 1910. Railroad commissioner, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Record commissioner, Annual report, 1912. Registration report. 1908, I'*) 1 '. Shell fisheries. Commissioners of, Annual n 1911, 1912. Soldiers' relief. Hoard of. Annual report, 1912. State house commission, Annual report, 1911. State sanatorium. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Supreme court reports; \. 29-13. Tax commissioners, Board of, lax act of 1912. Treasurer, Annual report. 1911. Vital records; \. 19-21, 1630-1850. Ringrose. Hyacinthe. Marriage and divorce laws of the world. 1911. Rockefeller sanitary commission. Publications, Hookworm in - fection in foreign countries. 1911. s, Peter V. Inheritance taxation. 1912. to. Alfred Henry. Employer!! liability act 1H80 and work - men- compensation act. 1 S Ehewan. Legislative assembly. 4th session, Journals. 1911 - Revised statutes. 1909. 1910-1911. 1912. tine American: v. 102-104. Supplement ; v. S9-71 •.ml. Justiciary cases; v. 3-5. Private legislation reports: v. 10. Public general statutes. 1909, 1910. Scots law times reports; 2 \.. 1910, 1911. — News and -tatutes. l&lt;»10. 1911. Scottish law reporter: v. 47, 4S. Scottish law review and sheriff courts repor: as, 27. Session case&lt;. 1910, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 49 Sedgwick, Theodore. Measure of damages; 9th ed., 4 v., 1912. Simkins, William Stewart. Federal equity suit; 2d ed., 1911. Singer, B. Patent and trade mark laws of the world, 1911. Singleton, Esther. Famous sculpture as seen and described by great writers. 1910. Smurr, Tom W. Law of farm drainage, 1909. Smvthe, R. M. Obsolete American securities and corporations. v 2., 1911. Encer, Edward W. Domestic relations, 1911. th Australia. Acts of parliament, 1910, 1911. th Carolina. Acts, 1911. 1912. House journal, 1911, 1912. Reports and resolutions; 5 v., 1911. Senate journal, 1911. 1912. Supreme court reports ; v. 84-89. South Dakota. House journal, 1911. Laws, 1911. Legislative manual, 1911 Public documents; 4 v., 1910. Senate journal, 1911. Supreme court reports; v. 24-26. Digest (Hill) ; v. 2., 1903-1911. utheastern reporter ; v. 68-74. Southern reporter ; v. 53-58. Digest, v. 41-55 ; v. 4. Southwestern reporter; v. 130-148. Standard encyclopedia of procedure ; v. 1-5. Statesman's yearbook. 1911, 1^12. Stimson, Frederick Jesup. Concise law dictionary; rev. ed., by H. C. Vorhees, 1911. Storey, Moorfield. Reform of legal procedure, 1911. Street railway reports ; v. 7. T Tasmania. Acts of the parliament 1910, 1911. Law reports; v. 6, 1910. Tennessee. Acts, Private. 1911. Public, 1911. House journal, 1911. Mining department. Annual report, 1909. Senate journal, 1911. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">50 REPORT OF THE Supreme court reports; v. 119, 123. Digest (Webb and Meigsi: v. 4, supp. Texas. Civil appeals reports; v. 51-57. Criminal reports; v. 58-62. House journal, called session 1910; regular and called sessions, 1911. Laws. General and special, 3d &amp; 4th called sessions, 1910; regular and 1st called session, 1912. Senate journal. 3d &amp; 4th called sessions, 1910 ; regular and 1st called session, 1911. Statutes. Revised civil. 1911. Revised criminal, 1911. Supplement to Sayles annotated civil stat - utes (Herron), 1908-1910. Supreme court reports ; v. 103. Krnton. William Wheeler. Pure food and drugs, 1912. mpson, Seymour Dwight. Law of trials; 2d ed.. 4 v., 1912. mpson. Slason. Railway library a collection of addresses and papers, 1910, 1911. Eany, Francis Buchanan. Banks and banking, 1012. it. Payson Jackson. National land system, 1785-1820; 1910. ker &amp; Blood. Federal penal code in force Jan. 1. 1910. ;ntieth century magazine: v. 1-5. U United States. AGRICULTURE DEPARTMENT Secretary. Annual report, 1910, 1911. General publications Cooperative laboratory at Reno, Nev., for examina- tion of potash bearing materials, 1912. Yearbook, 1909, 1910, 1911. Circulars, nos. 21. 4th &amp; 5th rev. ; 33-41. Farmers' bulletins. 104 rev.. 410, 414. 415 rev., 420-505, 510. Animal Industry Bureau. Annual report, 1909, 1910. General publications: Notice of quarantine no. 2. Reports, nos. 92, 94. 95, 96. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE LIBRARIAN. 1911-1912 51 I N1TED STATES, Continued. Directory of bureau of animal industry, Jan., April, 1912. State sanitary requirements governing admission of live stock, 1910, 1911. Animals imported for breeding purposes. Cattle, Horses. 1911. Bulletins, nos. 30 (pU. 33-36), 110 pt. 2, 126-147, 14'' - 154. Circulars. MM, 31 rev., 150A. 164-204. Biological Survey Bureau. General publications: Directions for field work of assistants of Biological survey, 1912. Bulletins, nos. 34, 35 rev., 36-42, 44. Circulars, nos. 76-85, 88, 89. North American fauna, nos. 32, 33, 34. Chemistry Bureau. Bulletins, nos. 133-151. 153, 155, 158. Circulars, nos. 16 rev., 41 2d rev., 62, 63, 65-101. Entomology Bureau. Bulletins nos. 58. 64. 64 pt. 10; 75, 80 pts. 6, 7, 7 rev., 8 ; 82 pts. 6, 7 ; 85 pts. 4 rev. ; 90 pts. 1-3 ; 91-93 ; 94 pt. 1 . 95 pts. 1-6; % pts. 1-5; 97 pts. 1-7; 98, 99 pt. 1; 100. 101, 103-105, 107, 109 pts. 1-5; 112, 115 pt. 1 ; 116 pt. 1. Circulars, nos. 122, 125-154, 156-159. Experiment Stations Office. Annual report, 1910, 1911. General publications: List of station publications received during Oct., 1910-July, 1912. Recent irrigation legislation, reprint April, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 229; 230 pts. 1. 2; 231, 233-236, 236 rev., 237-250. Circulars, nos. 94 rev., 97 rev., 99-101, 103-117. Experiment station record, vols. 23, pts. 5-8; v. 24, pts. 1-8; v. 25, pts. 1-10; v. 26, pts. 1-8. Experiment station work. vol. 3, no. 20; v. 4, nos. 1-10. Technical series, nos. 16 pt. 4; 19 pts. 3-5; 20 pts. 1-5; 21, 22, 23 pts. 1, 2; 24, 25, pt. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">52 REPORT OP THE I'XITED STATES. Continued. Farmers' institute lecture, nos. 2, addenda; 12, 13, 14. Alaska agricultural experiment stations, Annual re - port, 1910. Hawaii agriculture experiment station, Annual re - port. 1910, 1911. Bulletins nos. 23-28. Porto Rico agriculture experiment station, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 10, 11. Forest Service General publications: Forest products laboratory series, Experiments with jack pine and hemlock for mechanical pulp. 1912. Information regarding employment on national for - ests; 5th rev.. 1911. Instructions for building and maintenance of tele - phone lines on national forests. Instructions for making forest surveys and maps; rev., 1912. National forest fire protection plans, 1911. National forest manuals; claims, settlements, ad - ministrative sites, 1912 ; forest plans, forest exten - sion, forest investigations, libraries, cooperation, dendrology. 191 1 ; general administration ; grazing. 1911; special uses, 1911; timber sales, etc.. 1911; trespass, 1911. Record of wholesale prices of lumber, 1911, 1912. Standard classification of activities and procedure in forest service accounting, 1912. Suggestions for collection of range plant specimens on national forests. May 1911. Tree distribution under Kinkaid act, 1911. Use book: Water power, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 36 rev.. 75, 80, 83-111. Circulars. ' nos. 23 rev.. 89 rev., 173, 175, 177, 179, 184-192, 194-207. Silvical leaflets. Nos. 45, 51, 52. 53. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 53 I'NITED STATES, Continued. E— Monthly bulletins, Jan., 1911-June, 1912. t Industry Bureau. General publications : Boys' demonstration work: Corn clubs., rev. ed., 1912. Burning quality of tobacco, Nov. 19, 1910. Control of cotton wilt and root-knot, 1911. Cooperative distribution of new Smyrna figs and caprifigs; 2d rev., 1912. Corn crop in southern states, Mar. 28, 1912. Crops for southern farms, 1910. Distribution of cotton seed, 1911, 1912. Effective method of preventing erosion of hill lands. 1911. Emergency crops for overflowed lands in Missis- sippi Valley, 1912. Farm fertilizers, 1911. Field instructions for farmers' cooperative demon- stration work ; 4th rev.. 1912. Have you more productive corn than lst-genera- tion cross no. 182? 1911. Memorandum of information concerning official cotton grades, 1912. Production of cotton under boll-weevil condition-; rev. ed. Relation of handling to decay in California navel oranges, season of 1910-11. Result of boys' demonstration work in corn clubs in 1910. 1911. Selection of cotton and corn seed on southern farms. 1912. Suggestions on growing Egyptian cotton in south- west, 1912. Bulletins, nos. 186-190. 192-208. 210. 213-243, 245 255. Circulars, nos. 68, 69, 71-97, 99-101. Public Roads Office. Bulletins, nos. 36-44, 46. Circulars, nos. 93-97. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">54 REPORT OF THE Publications Division. General publications Farmers' bulletins available for distribution. Aug. 28. 1912. Farmers' bulletins of interest to persons in cities and tuwns, 1912. Circulars, nos. 1 rev , 3 rev., 7-18. Monthly lists. Oct., 1910-Aug., 1912. Soils Bureau. General publications Descriptions of soil types established and changes in classification since publication of bulletin 78, 1911. Field operations of bureau of Soils, 1908. 1909, text and maps. List of soil surveys, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 61, 68, 71, 73-84, 86 Circulars. Nos. 22, 71. Solicitor of Department of Agriculture. General publications : Supplement to 28 hour law annotated, 1911 Circulars, nos. 42. 44-65. Statistics Bureau General publications : Dates of sowing and harvesting, l'Hl Bulletins, nos. 81. 83-85, 88-91. Circulars, nos. 17 rev., 19-33, 35-39. Crop reporter, vol. 12, nos. 11, 12; v. 13, nos. l-!2; v. 14 nos. 1-9. Weather Bureau Annual report. 1909-10. 1910-11. General publications : Daily river stages; pt. 10, 1909-10 Instructions to special river and rainfall observers of Weather bureau, 1912. Instructions to storm-warning displaymen of Weather bureau, 1912. Bulletins, nos. 39-41, Letter T. Instrument division. Circular F, 4th ed. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">STATE LIBRARIAN. 1911-1912 55 IN1TED STATES, Continued. AMERICAN REPUBLICS BUREAU Monthly bulletins; v. *&gt;. nos. 1-3, 4-6; v. 30, nos. 1-3, 4-6! (English.) CIVIL SERVICE COMMISSION. Annual report, 1910, 1911. (ieneral publications: Civil service act, rules, and executive orders. W12. Information for applicants for examination: Railway mail clerk examinations, rev. to Jan., 1912. Stenographer and typewriter examinations ; rev. to July. 1912 Information for boards of examiners concerning: Ap - plications, examinations, and appointments, 1911, 1912; removals, Feb., 1912; transfers, Sept., 1912. Instructions to applicants; for all civil service dis - tricts. 1911. 1912; for mechanical trades and other non-educational positions. Pel)., 1 U 12: lor rural ear - lier, Mar., 1912. Instructions to Engineer department at large, July, 1912 Manual of examinations, 1911, 1912. COMMERCE AND LABOR DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office. Annual report 1910, 1911. Decisions, nos. 120. Census Bureau. General publications List of publications of 10th. 11th, and 12th cen - suses and permanent Census bureau, 1911. Mortality statistics. 1909. Official register (blue book), 1911. Report on cotton ginning, 1910, 1911. Uniform accounts as basis for standard forms for reporting financial and other statistics of health de - partments, 1912. Uniform accounts for systems of water supply, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 109-114. Agricultural bulletins. 13th census: </seg>
            <seg id="p059">56 V -^ 1 i IjI' D 1 1 E^o, v OflllLlUtrOl United States, abstract, farms and farm property, by states. United States, abstract, general farm crops by states. United States, abstract, live stock on farms and elsewhere. Bulletins by states. Forest products, nos. 1-10 (series 1909) ; 1-3, 5-9 (se ries 1910). Irrigation bulletins, 13th census, by states Manufacturers' bulletins, 13th census, by states and Hawaii and Porto Rico. Population bulletins, 13th census: Bv states. Hawaii and Porto Rico. Center of population and median lines, continental U. S. Population by counties, and minor civil divisions, 1910, 1900, 1890. Population. United States, cities and suburbs. Population. United States, population of cities Population, United States, total population and area, by states and territories. United States, abstract of statistics of number and distribution of inhabitants. United States, population of incorporated places. Special reports : Fisheries of United States, 1908. Statistics of cities having- population of over 30.000. 1908 Telephones. 1907 Coast and Geodetic Survey. Annual report. 1910, 1911 General publications : Alaska, supplement to coast pilot notes on Bering Sea and Arctic Ocean, Feb.. 1911. Arctic tides. 1911. Atlantic coast, coast pilot, pts. 1-3. Catalogue of charts, coast pilots, and tide tables. 1911, 1912. O *R&lt;-t pilot n&lt;»tes on Hawaiian Isluncis. 1 *)1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 57 I'NITED STATES, Continued. Directions for magnetic measurements, 1911. Inland waterway, Atlantic coast, Dec 1911. Results of observations made at Coast and Geodetic survey magnetic observatory at : Baldwin, Kansas, 1907-09. — Cheltenham, Md., 1907-08, 1909-10. — Hon.. lulu. Hawaii, 1907-08, 1909-10. — Sitka, Alaska. 1907-08. Vieques, P. R.. 1907-08, 1909-10. Survey of oysters bars. Baltimore county, Md., Charles county, Md., Kent county, Md., Queen Annes county. Md.. St. Mary's county, Md., 1911. 1912. Tables for poly conic projection of maps based upon Clarke's reference spheroid of 1886; 3d ed. 1910. Special publications, nos. 8-10, 12. Tide tables. 1912, 1913. United States coast pilot. Atlantic coast. 1911, 1912. United States coast pilot. Pacific coast, 1911, 1912. Corporations Bureau. General publications: Cotton tare, Sept., 1912. Report of commissioner of corporations on : steel industry, pts. 1-2; tobacco industry, pt. 2. capitali - zation, investment, and earnings, Sept., 1911 ; trans - portation by water in U. S.. pt. 3. water termnials. 1910. Taxation of corporations, pt. 3, Eastern central states, 1911. Fisheries Bureau. General publications : Condition and extent of natural oyster beds of Dela- ware. 1911. Distribution of fish and fish eggs, 1910. Dredging and hydrographic records of U. S. fish - eries steamer Albatross during Philippine expedi- tion, 1907-10. Effects of explosive sounds upon fishes, 1911. Fisheries of Alaska. 1910. Fur-seal fisheries of Alaska, 1909, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">58 . REPORT OF THE List of publications of bureau of Fisheries avail- able for distribution, Nov., 1911. Marine isopods collected in Philippines, 1907-06. Mussel fauna of Kankakee basin, 191?; Maumee river. 1912. Mussels of Big Buffalo Fork of White river, Ark., 1912. Preliminary examination of halibut fishing grounds of Pacific coast. 1912. Salmon fisheries of Pacific coast, 1911. Special investigation of Alaska fur-seal rookeries. 1910. Bulletin, vol. 29, 1909. Economic circulars, nos. 1, 2. Immigration and Naturalization Bureau. Agricultural opportunities, nos. 1-5. General publications : Distribution of admitted aliens and other residents. 1912. Immigration laws and regulations of July 1. 1907. Immigration laws, rules of Nov. 15, 1911. Naturalization laws and regulations, 1911. Treaty, laws and regulations governing admission of Chinese: regulations approved Apr. 18, 1910; edi- tions 1911, 1912. Immigration bulletin, Sept, 1910-July, 1912 Labor Bureau. Annual report, 1909, 1910. General publications : Compensation to injured government employees, 1912. Bulletins, vols. 19-22. Lighthouses 3ureau. General publications: Medical handbook. 1912. Regulations for lighthouse service, etc., Sept.. 1911. Lighthouse service bulletin, Jan. -April, 1912. Manufactures Bureau. Commercial relations, 1909. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 59 UNITED STATES, Continued. Daily consular and trade reports., nos. 114-152 (series 1910); 1-305 (series 1911); 1-230 (series 1912). Foreign tariff notes., nos. 1-7. Miscellaneous series., nos.. 5, 6, 6a, 7. Monthly consular and trade reports., nos. 346-357. Special agent series, nos. 31-57, 59, 60. Special consular reports, nos. 43, pt. 3; 44-53. Tariff series, nos. 7 rev.. 14I&gt;, 15b, 17c, 17d, 27, 27a.. Navigation Bureau. Annual report, 1910, 1911. General publications: Amendments to navigation laws of 1907, 3d sup- plement, 1910. Merchant vessels, annual lists, 1910. 1911 Navigation laws of United States, 1911. Publications available for distribution, July, 1912. Standards Bureau. General publications: National bureau of standards, 1911 Report tu international committee on electrical units and standards, 1912. State and national laws concerning weights and measures of U. S., 2d ed., 1912. Weights and measures, (report of) 5th &amp; 6th an - nual conference held at bureau. Washington, D. C. Feb., 1910, Feb., 1911. Bulletins, v. 6. no. 4; v. 7. nos. 1-4; v. 8, nos. 1-2. Circulars, nos. 2. 4th ed. ; 5, 2d ed. ; 6, 3d ed. ;8, 2d ed. ; 9. 5th ed. ; 10, 2d ed. ; 11; 13, 5th ed. ; 14, 2d ed. ; 15, 3d ed. ; 16. 2d ed/; 17. 2d ed. ; 18, 2d ed. ; 19, 2d ed. ; 24. id and 3d ed ; 25. 3d ed ; 26, 2d ed ; 27-36, 38. Technologic papers, nos. 1-5, 7-10. Statistics Bureau. General publications: Foreign commerce and navigation of United States, 1910, 1911. Monthly summary of commerce and finance of United States, nos. 1-9, series 1909-10, 1910-11. Schedule A, classification of imports and exports of foreign commodities, 1911, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">60 REPORT OF THE Schedule B, classification of commodities, 1911, 1912. Schedule C, classification of foreign countries and dependencies, June, 1912. Schedule E, classification of merchandise, 1911, 1912. Statistical abstract of United States, 1910, 1911. Bulletins, tins. 4-12. series 1910-11; 1-12. series 1911 - 12; 1. 2, series 1^12-13. Steamboat-Inspection Service. General publications: General rules and regulations, 1912. List of officers of merchant steam, motor, and sail vessels licensed, 1910, 1911. CONGRESS. 59th Congress 1st Session. House documents; v. 62. 61st Congress, 1st Session. House documents; v. 7. Senate documents; v. 8, 9. 61st Congress, 1st &amp; 2d Sessions. House reports; Public v. 1. Index to reports and documents; v. 16. Senate reports ; v. 1. 61st Congress, 2d Session House documents: v. 3. 26-32. 71. 72, 74. 114, 126-133 House reports ; v. 2, 3. Memorial addresses. Francis W. Cushman, 1910. Senate documents; v.' 1, 5-7. 12. 15 pt. 2, 18, 26-41 43, 44. 46-55. 57-97. 100-102. Senate reports v. 1-5. 61st Congress, 3d Session. Congressional directory: 1st &amp; 2d ed. Congressional record: v. 46. pts. 1-5. Document index ; v. 17. H.iuse documents; v. 3. 16. 20. 21. 78. 83. KS, I 1 4. l_'i 128. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 61 L'NITED STATES, Continued Senate documents; v. 1-3, 7-11. 14-19, 21, 22, 25, 28 - 59, 61-81, 83-86. Senate journal, 1910-1911 Senate reports; v. 1-3. 62d Congress, 1st Session. Congressional directory, May, 1911; Dec, 1911; Jan.. 1912, Apr.. 1912. Congressional record ; v. 47, pts. 1-5 House documents; v. 1, 3-9. House journal, 1911. House reports; v. 1. Senate documents; v. 2-11, 13, 16-19, 22-30. Senate journal, 1911. Senate reports ; v. 1 62d Congress, 2d Session. Congressional record ;v. 48, pts. 1-3 Senate journal. 1911-1912. COURT OF CLAIMS General publications: Cases decided at term of 1909-10; v. 45; 1910-11. v. 46. COURT OF CUSTOMS APPEALS. General publications : Rules as amended and adopted. Apr. 24, 1911 DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA. Annual report; v. 4, 1909; v. 1-4, 1910; v. 1-5, 1911. GEOGRAPHIC BOARD Decisions July, 1910-Aug., 1911. GOVERNMENT PRINTING OFFICE. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Public Documents Division. General publications Check list of United States public documents, 1789- 1909; v. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">62 REPORT OF THE UNITED STATES, Continued Index to rejHjrts and documents of 61st Congress. 1st, 2d and 3d sessions. Preliminary schedule of volumes of reports and documents of 61st Congress, 1st, 2d and 3d ses- sions: 62d Congress, 1st session. Leaflets; nos. 10, 5th ed. ; 41. Price lists of government documents. INTKRJOR DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office Annual Report, 1910, 1911 Administrative reports. General publications : Analyses of waters of Hot Springs of Arkan^a-. 1912. General information regarding Crater Lake National Park, 1912; department of Interior, 1911; Glacier National Park, 1912; Hot Springs of Arkansas, 1912; Mesa Verde National Park, 1912; Mount Rainier National Park, 1912; Sequoia and General Grant National Parks, 1912; Yellowstone National Park, 1912; Yosemite National Park, 1912. Geological history of Crater Lake, Crater Lake Na- tional Park. 1912; Yellowstone National Park. 1912. Geysers. 1912. Proceedings of national park conference, Yellow- stone National Park, Sept., 1911. Report on Platt and Wind Cave National Parks, 1911. Sketch of Yosemite National Park and account of origin of Yosemite and Hetch Hetchy Valleys, 1912. Some lakes of Glacier National Park, 1912. Education Bureau. Annual reports, 1910, 1911 General publications : Abridged title of bulletins of bureau of Education, 1912. Classification of universities and colleges with refer - ence to bachelor's degrees, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 63 I'NITED STATES, Continued. Federal laws, regulations, and rulings affecting land grant colleges of agriculture and mechanic arts, 1911. Report of education of natives of Alaska and rein- deer service, 1911. Bulletins, nos. 4-6. 1910; 1-19, 1911; 1-20, 1912. Library circulars ; nos. 1-6. Geological Survey General publications : Mineral resources of the United States, 1909, 1910. Publications of Geological survey, not including topographic maps, 1911, 1912. Bulletins, nos. 381, 398-470, 472-491. Geologic atlas of United States, nos. 172, 174-183. List of new publications ; nos. 42-58. Monographs; vol. 51, pt. 2; 52. Professional papers ; nos. 68. 70, 72, 73, 75. Water supply papers; nos. 235-256, 261-278. Government Hospital for Insane. Bulletin, no 2. Indian Affairs Office. General publications : Farm and home mechanics, 1911. Indian lands for sale under government supervision. 1911. Outline lessons in housekeeping, 1911. Regulations approved Oct. 27, 1911, as amended February 21, 1912, governing placing of and ac - counting for moneys of Five Civilized* Tribes, 1912. Regulations for applications for Osage funds. 1912. Regulations governing leasing restricted alloted In- dian lands for mining purposes, 1912. Rules and regulations relating to issuance of pat- ents in fee, etc., 1910. Some things that girls should know how to do, 1**11. Synopsis of course in sewing, 1911. Trachoma, management and treatment among In- dians, 1911 Bulletin ; no 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">64 REPORT OF THE Land Office, General. General publications Bakersfield Fuel and Oil Co. (decision of Interior dep't regarding patent), 1911 Decisions relating to public lands. June, 1910- Mar., 1911. Ephemeris of the sun and polaris and tables of azi- Historical sketch of Louisiana and Louisiana pur- chase, 1912. Openings and sales of Indian lands, 1911. Rules of practice in cases before District Land of - fices, General Land office and department of In- terior, 1910. Statutes and regulations governing entries and proof under desert-land laws, 1911. Suggestions to homesteaders and persons desiring to make homestead entries, 1910. Circulars; nos. 8, 10, 32. 42, 50, 69, 71, 72, 85, 102, 103. 105, 116. 117, 119. 120. 150, 151. Mines Bureau Annual report. 1911. General publications : Preliminary statement on coal mine accidents in United States, 1910, 1911, 1912. Publications of bureau of Mines. Dec. 1910-May, 1912. Bulletins, nos. 1 rev., 14 rev.. 1-21, 23-37, 39-41. 43, 44, 47, 49. Miners' circulars, nos. 2-6. Technical papers, nos. 1-13, 16-26. Patent Office Annual report, 1910, 1911 General publications : Decisions of commissioner of patents in patent and trademark and copyright cases, 1910, 1911. Definition of revised classes and subclasses of sub - jects of invention in Patent office, arranged in nu - merical order, 1912. tnuths of polaris (calendar year), 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 65 I'NITED STATES, Continued. Manual of classification of subjects of invention of patent office, 1912. Official gazette, Jan., 1901-Aug.. 1911. Patent laws, with annotations, 1911. Price list of publications of Patent office with sched- ule of fees of office, 1912. Rules of practice. Specifications and drawings of patents, July, 1909- June, 1911. United States statutes concerning registration of prints and labels. 1912. Classification bulletins; nos. 25-27. Pension Bureau. General publications: Information relating to army and navy pensions and bounty-land warrants ,1912. Laws of United States governing granting of army and navy pensions, 1912. Laws of United States governing granting of boun- Btv-land warrants, 1911. amation Service. Annual report, 1910, 1911 INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION. - Annual reports, 1910, 1911. - General publications: Act to regulate commerce as amended, and acts sup - plementary thereto., rev., to July, 1911. Classification of revenues and expenses of sleeping car operations, effective July 1, 1912. National association of railway commissioners, Pro - ceedings, 1910, 1911. Preliminary abstract of statistics of common car - riers, year ended June 30, 1911. Regulations for transportation of explosives, etc., effective Mar. 31, 1912. Rules of practice to regulate commerce, rev., amended and adopted, Jan. 14, 1911. United States safety-appliance standards Mch. 13, 1911. 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">66 REPORT OF THE United States safety-appliance standards, order of commission. ( )ct. 13, 1910. Accident bulletins. Xo. ,V&gt;-43. Orders : In matter of advances in rates of cotton linters ; for lumber; and on various commodities. 1912. In matter of alteration in method and form of month y reporis of hours of service of employees on railroads subject to act of Mar. 4, 1907. In matter of application of proviso of sec. 2 of In matter of destruction of records of express com - panies, effective May 15, 1912; of records of sleep - ing car companies. 1910 ; of records of steam roads, effective Dec. 1, 1910; of records of telegraph com- panies. 1911; of telegraph companies and cable companies. 1912. In matter of express rates (Adams Express Com - pany). 1911; (United States Express Company) 1911. In matter of investigation and suspension of ad - vances in rates by carriers for transportation of bar - ley ; of certain commodities between certain stations located in Texas common point territory ; of cot - ton seed; of furniture; of hops; of knitting factory products ; of lumber ; of sash, doors, and blinds ; of stock cattle and sheep: of tin plate and sheet metal, 1912. In matter of investigation and suspension of cer - tain new rules and regulations restricting dimen- sions of trunks, 1912. In matter of investigation and suspension of cer - tain regulations and practices with regard to pre- cooling and preicing, 1912. In matter of investigation and suspension of sched - ules canceling through rates with certain tap-line connections, 1912. In matter of investigation and suspension of south- ern classification; bo. 99, 1912. h&lt;&gt;urs-of-serviee-act of trainmen, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">STATE LIBRARIAN. 1911-1912 67 1'NITED STATES, Continued. In matter of investigation of alleged irregularities and discrepancies in weighing of freight by car- riers, subject to act to regulate commerce, 1912. In matter of pipe lines, 1912. In matter of preparation, approval, and establish - ment of rules and instructions for inspection and testing of locomotive boilers and their appurte- nances, 1912. In matter of rates, practices, rules, and regulations governing transportation of anthracite coal, 1912; cement, iron ore, iron and steel and their products, 1912. In matter of publication in tariffs of marked capaci- ties, lengths, and dimensions, etc., 1912. In matter of regulations for transportation of ex- plosives, 1912. In matter of regulations to govern issuing and re- cording of passes of steam roads, 1912. In matter of substitution- of tonnage at transit points, 1912. In matter of suspension of western classification Block Signal and Train Control Board. Annual report, 1910. 1911. General publication* : Block signals on railroads of United States, 1911. Block signals on railroads of United States, and table showing use of telegraph and telephone for E transmission of train orders, tistics and Accounts Bureau. Bulletin of revenues and expenses of steam roads; nos. 18-42. Accounting bulletin ; nos. 7, 8. Statistics of express companies. Annual report, 1910. Statistics of railways, Annual report, 1909, 1910. no. 51. I. C. C. no. 9, 1912. Fourth section orders ; nos. 465. 488, 839. Reports; v. 19-22. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">68 REPORT OF THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT. Attorney General. Annual report, 1910, 1911. General publications : Register of Department of Justice, 19th &amp; 20th editions. Rules and regulations for government and discipline of penitentiary, Atlanta, Ga., 1911; McNeil Island, Rules and regulations governing paroling of pris - oners from penitentiaries. 1910. Sherman anti-trust law with amendments July 1, 1911; Nov. 1, 1911; July 1, 1912. LIBRARY OF CONGRESS. I r-ioriin3n Annual report, 1910, 1911. General publications: Classification, class A, general works, polygraphy, 1911 ; class -H. 1910; class L, education, 1911; class S, agriculture, plant and animal industry, 1911. Supplementary list of publications of Library issued in 1911. Bibliography Division, General publications: Additional references relating to mercantile marine subsidies, 1911; to popular election of senators, 1 ( »11 ; to reciprocity with Canada, 1911 ; to taxation of incomes, 1911. List of references on reciprocity, 2d ed. 1910. Select list of references on boycotts and injunctions in labor disputes, 1911; on capital punishment, 1912; on employers' liability and workmen's com - pensation, 1911; on initiative, referendum and re - call, 1912; on parcels post, 1911; on wool with special reference to tariff, 1911. Catalogue Division. General publications : American and English genealogies in Library of Congress, 1910. Wash.. 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 69 r sited STATES, Continued. Copyright Office. Catalogue of copyright entries, new series, Dec, 1910- Dec. 1912. Law Library. General publications : Guide to law and legal literature of Germany, 1912. Index analysis of federal statutes, general and per- manent law; 1789-1873. Tentative headings and cross-references for subject catalogue of American and English law, 1911. Manuscripts Division. General publications: Calendar of papers of Martin Van Buren, 1910. Maps and Charts Division. General publications: Lowery collection : Descriptive list of maps of Spanish possessions within present limits of U. S., 1502-1820. Music Division. General publications Orchestral music, class M, 1000-1268, catalogue scores, 1912. NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES Memoirs ; v. 10. NAVY DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office. Annual report. 1910, 1911 General publications : Hague and Geneva conventions, 1911. International radiotelegraph convention of Berlin, 1906. Publications for instruction of naval militia; no. 7. Register of commissioned and warrant officers of naval militia, 1911. Ships' data. United States naval vessels, 1911. Transactions of Naval militia association of U. S., Washington, Dec, 1909 ; Dec, 1910. Unveiling of statue of John Paul Jones. Apr. 17, 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">70 REPORT OF THE Hydrographic Office. General uublicatiuns Addenda to (navigation of Gulf of Mexico and Car - ibbean Sea., v. 1, 6th ed.), publication 86, ed. of 1905, 1911; to (navigation of Gulf of Mexico and Caribbean Sea) publication (&gt;4, edition of 1907; to (West coast of Mexico and Central America from United States to Panama) publication 84, edition of 1902; to (West coast of South America) publi- cation 89. edition of 1905. Catalogue of charts and plans issued to vessels on Atlantic station. 1912. Lake supplement, revised. Nos. 108 A-D, 1911 List of lights; v. 1. v. 2, v. 3, corrected to Apr.. 1912. Sun's declination and equation of time, 1911. Sun's declination and equation of time (calendar year) 19J2 (and) table of sunset and sunrise for Great Lakes, 1912. Supplement (to) Coast of British Columbia. 2d ed., publication 96. edition of 1907, 1911; to (publica- tion) 89, West coast of South America, (edition) of 1905. 1912. Useful tables from American practical navigator. 1911. Library and Naval War Records. General unifications: ( )fh'cial records of Union and Confederate navies in Manual of paymaster's department, marine corps. 1912. Pott exchange regulations, 1912. Medicine and Surgery Bureau. U. S. naval medical bulletin ; vol. 5, nos. 1-4 ; v. 6. nos. 1-3. Nautical Almanac Office American cphemeris and nautical almanac, 1913. 1914. American nautical almanac, 1913, 1914. war of rebellion ; series 1. v. 24. l f &gt;ll Marine Corps. ( ieneral publication ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p074">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 71 I'MTED STATES, Continued. Naval Academy, Annapolis. Annual register, 1910-11; 1911-12. General publications: Regulations governing admission of candidates as midshipmen. 191 1. Regulations of Naval academy, 1911. Naval Intelligence Office. ( jeneral publications : Information concerning some of the principal navies ■ of the world, 1911. Militia Office. General publications: Register of commissioned and warrant officers, 1912. Naval Observatory. General publications Publications, 1911 ; 2d series, vols. 6, 7, Naval War College, Newport. General publications (ieneral index to international law situations; v. 1-10. International law situations, with solutions and notes, 1910, 1911. Navigation Bureau. General publications Correction to p. 2*&gt;3-3?2 of landing force and small arms instructions. Navy, 1907; 1910. Register of commissioned and warrant officers of navy and marine corps. 1911, 1912. Regulations for naval auxiliary service, corrected to July 1, 1911. Steam Engineering Bureau. General publications : Wireless-telegraph stations of the world, Jan., 1912. PAN AMERICAN UNION. Monthly bulletins; v. 31. 32. POST OFFICE DEPARTMENT Postmaster General's Office. Annual report. 1910, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">72 REPORT OF THE General publications Instructions for guidance of navy mail clerks and asMstant navy mail clerks, 1912. Postal laws and regulations pertaining to 2d class of mail matter, 1912. PRESIDENT OF UNITED STATES. Messages. 61st Congress, 3d session; 62d Congress, 2d session. SMITHSc &gt;NIAN INSTITUTION Annual report. 1910, 1911 American Historical Association. Annual report. 1908, 1909. Ethnology Bureau. Annual report, 1906. Bulletins ; nos. 37. 38, 40, pt. 1 ; 43-45, 47-52. National Museum. Annual report 1910, 1911 Bulletins ; nos. 39, pt. N ; 50, pt. 5 ;71, pt. 2; 73, 75-78. Contributions from national herbarium ; vol. 13. pts. 6-12: v. 14. pts. 2, 3; v. 15. v. 16, pts. 1-3. Proceedings ; vol. 37-40. STATE DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office General publications : Declaration of Independence, 1776. 1911. Statutes at large; v. 36, pts. 1, 2. Statutes passed at 3d session of 61st Congress pts. 1, 2. Statutes passed at 1st session of 62d congress, 1911 Foreign relations, 1908. SUPREME COURT. General publications : Rules of Supreme court promulgated Dec. 22. 1911 TREASURY DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office Annual report. 1910, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 73 UNITED STATES, Continued. General publications: Accounting system of United States, 1789-1910. Appraisers. Annual report, 1911. Atchitect, Supervising. Annual report, 1911. Auditor for Interior Department. Annual report, 1911, 1912. Auditor for Navy Department. Annual report, 1911, 1912. Auditor for Post Office Department. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Auditor for State and other Departments. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Auditor for Treasury Department. Annual report. 1911. 1912. Auditor for War Department. Annual report, 1911. Comptroller of Currency. Annual report, 1910, 1911 General publications : Digest of national bank decisions, 1912. Instructions relative to organization, etc., of na- tional banks, 1911 National-bank act as amended and other laws re- lating to national banks. 1911 Comptroller of Treasury. Annual report, 1911 Engraving and Printing Bureau. Annual report, 1911. Internal Revenue Commissioner. Annual report. 1910. 1911. General publications : Bulletin relative to production of distilled spirits, 1912. (iuagers' weighing manual, 1911. Internal revenue laws in force Mar. 4, 1911. Regulations and instructions relating to manufac- ture, sale and use of denatured alcohol, 1911. Regulations, no. 16, revised, July 1, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">74 REPORT OF THE UNITED HTA I KS, Continued. Life-Saving Service. Annual report. 1910, 1911. General publications : ( )rganization and methods of live-saving service. 1912. Loans and Currency Division. General publications : Information respecting money in circulation (July, I860;, July. 1910. Regulations of Treasury department in relation to United States bonds, 1912. Mint Bureau. Annual report. 1910, 1911 General publications : Catalogue of coins, tokens and medals in numis- matic collection of mint, Philadelphia, Pa., 1912. Monetary system of principal countries of the world, 1912. Report upon production of precious metals. 1909, 1910. Supplement to laws of United States relating to coinage, 1912 . Assay commission. Proceedings, 1911, 1912. Printing and Stationery Division. General publications : Publications of Treasury department. 1912. Public Health and Marine Hospital Service. General publications: Publications &lt;&gt;f Public Health and Marine Hospital service. Jan.. 1911, Jan.. 1912. May, 1912. Quarantine laws and regulations of United States, rev. ed., 1910. Hygienic laboratory bulletins; nos. 54, 55, 57, 59-62, 64^78. 84. Public health bulletins; nos. 40-53, 55 Register of Treasury. Annual report. 1911. 1912. Public health reports ; v. 25, nos. 43-52 ; v. 26, nos. 1-52; v. 27, nos. 1-39. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">STATE LIBRARIAN. 1911-1912 75 INITED STATES, Continued. Secret Service Division. Annual report, 1911. of Treasury. (jeneral publications: Digest of opinions and briefs, Jan., 1880- Dec, 1910. Treasurer of United States. Annual report, 1911. 34th &amp; 35th annual reports on sinking fund and-fund - ed debt of District of Columbia. 1911, 1912. WAR DEPARTMENT. Secretary's Office. Annual report. 1910. 1911 (ieneral publications: Regulations for army, 1910 Adjutant General's Department. (ieneral publications: Extract! from reports by regular and militia offi- cers. l ( &gt;10. — Official army register. 1911, 1912. Engineer Department. Annual report. 1910. 1911. Bulletin. No. 3. Professional papers. Xo. i2. Inspector General's Department. General publications : (iuide for use of officers. 1911. International Waterways Commission. (ieneral publications : 7th progress report. 1911. Isthmian Canal Commission. Annual report, 1910; l'»10, maps and diagrams, 1911; l ( 'll, maps and diagrams. General publications: Manual of information concerning employments for service on Isthmus of Panama ; rev. 1910. Sanitation department. Annual report. 1910, 1911. Judge-Advocate-General's Department, Army. General publications : </seg>
            <seg id="p079">76 REPORT OF THE Digest of opinions of judge advocates general, army, 1912. Manual for courts-martial ; rev. ed. 1908 ; corrected to Aug. 1910. Military laws of United States; 4th ed. with supple- ment, 1911. Medical Department. General publications: Circular of information concerning army nurse corps, and regulations governing admission to same; rev. 1911. Corrections and additions to manual for medical department, army, 1911. Index-catalogue of library of Surgeon-General's offi- ce; 2d series; v. 16, 1911 Manual. 1911. Military Academy, West Point. General publications: Information relative to appointment and admission of cadets. 1911. Regulations. 1911. Military Information Division. General publications Military notes on Cuba, 1909. (publication, new series) 15. Militia Affairs Division. General publications Extracts from reports by regular and militia officers on joint army and militia coast-defense exercises. 1911. Regulations for organized militia under constitution and laws of United States, 1910. Ordnance Department. General publications : Report of test of metals, 1909. 1910, 1911 Quartermaster's Department. General publications : Regulations for government of national cemeteries. 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 77 UNITED STATES, Continued. Specifications for uniform of army, Jan. 1912. Circulars, Nos. 4, 19, 23. Signal Office. General publications: Drill regulations for field companies of signal corps, provisional, ed. of Mar. 1911. Manual, No. 3 ; rev. 1910. Professional paper: Multiplex telephony and telegraphy by means of elec - tric waves guided by wires, 1911. Staff Corps, General. General publications: Appendix to infantry drill regulations, 1911. Cavalry notes, 1911. Chaplain's duties and how best to accomplish his work, 1912. Drill regulations for cavalry, amended 1909, cor- rected 1911. Drill regulations for field artillery, provisional, 1908, with changes to 1911. Drill regulations for field artillery, horse and light. army, provisional, 1911. Drill regulations for machine-gun organizations. cavalry, 1910. Gunnery and explosives for field artillery officers. 1911. Infantry drill regulations, army, 1911. Laws, regulations, orders, and memoranda relating to organization and duties of general staff corps. 1912. Regulations for uniform of army, 1912. Regulations prescribing standard for field firing and proficiency test, army. 1911. Report on organization of land forces of U. S. 1912. Soldier's Home, District of Columbia. Annual report, 1911. Subsistence Department. General publications: Manual for army cooks, 1910; errata for manual </seg>
            <seg id="p081">78 War College Division. General publications Classification and index of library, 1912. Bulletins, new series, no. 17. United States Circuit Court. I )aveis' reports. 1839-1849. (2 Ware) Circuit court of appeals reports; v. 102-114. Encyclopedia of supreme court reports; v. 11. Federal statutes annotated. 1912 supplement: 2\ Statutes citer-digest, 1910. Supreme court reporter; v. 31. Supreme court reports; v. 218-224. — Lawyer's edition ; v. 54-56, Utah. House journal. 1911. Laws, 1911. Public documents; 2v. 1907-1908. Senate journal, 1911. — i Supreme court reports ; v. 36-38. — Digest. 1912. V Vermont. Acts and resolves. 1910. Adjutant and inspector general. Biennial report, 1910. Agriculture. Commissioner of. Annual report, 1910, 1911. Attorney General, Biennial report. 1910. Bank commissioner. Annual report, 1910, 1911. Cattle commissioner, Report. 1910. Education. Board of. Report, 1910. Education. Superintendent of. School report, 1910. Geologist. State. Report, 1908-1910. Fish and game commission, Biennial report, 1910. Governor, Messages, 1910. Health, Board of, Report. 1909. Highway commissioner, Biennial report, 1910. House of correction, Biennial report. 1910. House journal, 1910. Insane hospital at Waterbury, Report, 1910. Insane. Supervisors of. Report, 1910. Insurance commissioners. Report, 1910, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 79 Insurance department. Directory of insurance com - panies and agents, 1911. Summary of business, 1912. Laws relating to corporations, 1911 ; to saving institu - tions. 1911. Legislative directory, 1910. Legislature. Commission to investigate certain cor - poration laws. Report, 1909. Library. Finding list of the legislative reference de - partment, 1012. Library commissioners, Board of, Biennial report. 1910. Medical registration. Board of, Biennial report, 1910. Permanent school fund. Report of trustees, 1910. Prison. Biennial report, 1910. Public documents, 1909-1910. Public printing. Commissioner of. Biennial report, 1910. Public service commission. Biennial report, 1910. Senate journal, 1910. Soldiers' home. Report. 1910. Supreme court reports, v. 83. 84. Digest (Roberts) ; 2v. 1910. Tax commissioner. Biennial report, 1910. Treasurer, Biennial report, 1910. Victorian law reports, 1910, 1°-11. B William Freeman. Selected addresses and orations, 1912. ia. Acts. 1912. Annual reports of officers, boards and institutions. 1910. 1911. Bar association, Reports, 1910, 1911. Code, Pollard's supplement ; v. 3, 1910. Corporation commission. Annual report, 1909. 1910. House journal and documents, 1912. Index to enrolled bills, 1776-1910. Journal of the House of Burgesses, 1712-1740. Presentation by the people of Virginia of a copy of Houdon's statue of George Washington to the people of the Republic of France, Report of Commissioners, 1912. 51230311 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">80 REPORT OP THE Secretary of commonwealth, Annual report, 1910, 1911. Senate journal and documents, 1912. Supreme court of appeals ; v. 3 Munford. Supreme court reports; v. Ill, 112. Tax commission, Report, 1911. Virginia law register; v. 12-16. W Ware, Eugene F. From court to court ; 4th ed. 1906. Washington. Attorney General, Biennial report, 1910. Auditor, Biennial report, 1910. Barber examiners, Board of, Biennial report, 1910. Control. Board of, Biennial report, 1910. Equalization, Board of, Minutes and proceedings. 1910. Governor, Message, 1911. Highway commissioner. Biennial report, 1910. Highway department, Special investigating commis - sion, Report, 1910. House journal, 1911. Inspection, Bureau of, Comparative statistics and con - dition of school districts, 1910. Labor statistics and factory inspection, Bureau of, Biennial report, 1910. Laws. 1911. Legislature, Commission to investigate industrial ac - cidents, Report, 1911. Library, Biennial report, 1910. Public lands. Commissioner of. Biennial report, 1910. Railroad commission, Annual report, 1910. Secretary of state. Biennial report, 1910. Senate journal, 1911. Statistics and immigration, Bureau of, Irrigated lands. 1910. Supreme court reports; v. 58-67. Tax commissioners, Biennial report, 1910. Veterinarian, Biennial report, 1910. Washington law reporter, v. 31, 32, 38, 39. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">STATE LIBRARIAN, 1911-1912 81 West Australia. Law reports; v. 12, 13. West Virginia. Acts, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1911. Archives and history. Biennial report; v. 3 l'»10. Control, Board of, Biennial report. 1910. Governor, Message, 1911. House journal, 1911. Public documents. 4v. 1909-10. Senate journal, 1911. Senate and house journal, extra session, 1011. Supreme court reports, v. 67-69. Westminster renew; v. 173-176. Wharton, Francis. Criminal evidence; 10th ed. by Hilton; 2v. 1912 Wharton, John Jane Smith. Law lexicon; 11th ed. by Aggs. 1911. White. Edward I. Commentaries on the law in Shakespeare. 1911. Who's who. 1912. Who's who in America. 1910-1911, 1912-1913. ■ Samuel C. Water rights in the western states ; 3d ed. 2v. 1911. Williams. Thomas Cyprian. Vendor and purchaser; 2d ed., 2 v., 1911. Willoughby, Westel Woodbury. Constitutional law of the United States. 2 v.. 1910. Windward Islands. Appeal cases. 1905 Wisconsin. Assembly journal, 1911. Blue book, 1911. Historical society, Collections; v. 19, 1910. Proceedings, 1910. 1911. History commission. Bibliography of Wisconsin in the civil war. 1911. Chattanooga campaign. Fitch, 1911. Wisconsin women in the war. Hum, 1911. Laws, 1911; special session, 1912. Legislature, Index to the journal, 1911. Public documents; 7 v.. 1909-10. Railroad commission. Annual report, 1909, 1910. Opinions and decisions, v. 4-6. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">- 82 REPORT OF THE ad di Secretary of state. Constitution and history erf mission to the union, 1 *&gt;1 1 . -mate journal. 191 1. Supreme court reports, v. 143-14''. Citations, Miller. Supplement to Simmon gest, Glasier, 1908-1911. Witthaus &amp; Becker. Medical jurisprudence; 2d ed.. v. 4. World almanac. 1910, 1911, V)\2. World's work; v. L6-23. Wyman, Bruce. Public service corporations, 2 v., 1911. Wvomingf. Public lands, Commissioner of, Biennial report 1910. Laws. 1911. Supreme court reports, v. 18. Y </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>