<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Farm Types in Nebraska, as Determinded by Climatic, Soil, and Economic Factors</title>
               <date value="1919-03-15">1919-03-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">RESEARCH BULLETIN NO. 15 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA FARM TYPES IN NEBRASKA, AS DETERMINED BY CLIMATIC, SOIL, AND ECONOMIC FACTORS R. R. Spafford Distributed March 15, 1919 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Honorable E. P. Bbown, President, Davey. Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln. Honorable Frank D. Judson, Omaha. Honorable John R. Webster, Omaha. Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Honorable Harry D. Landis, Seward THE STATION OFFICEB8 Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Director. W. H. BROKAW, Director of Extension Service. J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. G. A. Lewis, B. Sc, Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. Kiesselbach, A M., Agronomy. H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene. H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Animal Pathology. J. H. FRANDSEN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. SWENK, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Rural Economics. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. LOVELAND, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc, Poultry. W. P. SNYDER, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. •L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. *R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Rural Economics. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart - ment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Resigned. I </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Contents Introduction 5 The outlines of agricultural regions in the northern hemisphere 6 The effect of heat upon the acreage of crops treated as annuals 11 A classification of field crops, 11. The six principal types of an' nual cropping, 15. Table of six principal types of annual crop - ping, 16. Month-degrees above freezing, 21. Boundary lines de- termined largely by heat, 22. The effect of factors other than heat, 26. Size of farm in relation to rainfall and other factors in the Great Plains 28 Definition of the term "farm," 28. Table of the size of the farm calculated from Nebraska farm management surveys compared with census figures, 30. Table of the size of farm as affected by the number of farms within a given area, 32. Method of map - ping the data, 34. The western edge of 160-acre farming, 35. Two-section farming, 35. Size of farm in relation to rainfall and heat, 36. Size of farm in relation to soil, 37. Size of farm in relation to rainfall and economic conditions, 37. Size of farm in relation to plant growth, 38. farm types in Nebraska 58 Boundaries of type areas, 58. 'Ihe determination of farm types, 59. Table of the number of all farms compared with the number reporting domestic animals, 61. Farm types grouped for the purpose of study, 62. The principal uses of farm land, 63. The acreage and yield of crops, 63. Table of corn per farm in 1909, 64. Table of coarse forage (large corn and "cane") in 1909, 65. Table of wheat per farm in 1909, 65. Table of oats per farm in 1909, 66. Table of rye per farm in 1909, 66. Table of barley per farm in 1909, 67. Table of potatoes per farm in 1909, 67. Table of millet per farm in 1909, 68. Table of alfalfa per farm in 1909, 68. Table of timothy and clover per farm in 1909, 69. Table of wild hay per farm in 1909, 69. Table of apple trees per farm and also the per cent of all land covered with woods, 70. The harvest value of crops, 70. Table of the harvest value of all crops grown on cultivated lands in 1909, 71. Table of the esti- mated harvest value of pasture per farm in 1909, 71. Table of the value of crop and pasture growth per farm in 1909, 72. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">i Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 4 Crop indexes. Table of the calculation of Hitchcock crop indexes using the Cass type of farm as a basis, 74. Table of what were approximately equivalent acreages in 1909, 75. Table of crop indexes in 1909, 75. Live stock, 76. Table of the cows on hand April 15, 1910, and the production of milk and butter for the calendar year 1909, 76. Table of cattle other than cows on hand April 15, 1910, 76. Table of the total number and value of cattle on hand April 15, 1910, and the numbe sold or slaughtered during the calendar year 1909, 77. Table of the total number of horses and mules on hand April 15, 1910, 77. Table of the total number and value of work animals, 78. Table of hogs and corn per farm, 78. Table of poultry raised and eggs produced in 1909, 79. Table of the approximate number of productive animal units per farm, 79. Table of the approximate total number of animal units per farm in 1909, 80. Table of the approximate division of live-tsock capital between productive stock and work animals, 80. Table of the receipts from live stock in 1909, 81. Labor and capital, 81. Table of labor hired in 1909, 81. Table of a calculation of the value per acre of such land as was not reported in the census, 82. Table of the approximate value of land per farm in 1910, 82. Table of capital in live stock, mach- inery, buildings, and land, 83. The approximate amount of cap - ital per farm in 1910, 83. Farm operators, 84. Table of the nativity of farm operators, 84. Table of the degree of ownership, 84. Table of the forms of tenancy, 85. The average distance to market, 85. Table of a calculation of the average distance from farm to town, 85. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Farm Types in Nebraska, as Determined by Climatic, Soil, and Economic Factors by R. R. Spaf f ord INTRODUCTION This bulletin treats chiefly of Nebraska agricultural areas as determined by climatic, soil, and economic factors. Most of the subject matter centers about the kind of farm crops grown and their yields. Cultural practices applied to crops are only incidentally considered. Most of the data used are from the Thirteenth Census of the United States and cover the crop year 1909. The small amount of data not derived from this source comes largely from field studies in this State and is used merely to support certain methods of treat - ing census data. To make the basis of the analysis of Nebraska agricul - tural areas more stable, it has been necessary to follow thru - out the northern hemisphere some of the very general prin - ciples in regard to climate, soil, plants, and people. Further - more, it has been necessary to place the crop groups (based on the classification of annual crops) of Nebraska in line with those of the United States as a whole and to extend the size - of-farm study thruout the Great Plains region. Crop-group belts are determined largely by the quantity of heat received and in general extend from east to west. The size of farm in the Great Plains is determined largely by rain - fall and serves as a good index to the quantity of field crop and pasture growth. The general trend of any given size-of-farm belt in this region is from north to south. The fact that crop - group belts and size-of-farm belts in Nebraska tend to run at right angles to one another makes it a relatively simple matter to block out areas that have a fairly uniform type of farming. In determining the boundaries of type areas, soils are not ignored. Extreme conditions of texture and topography de- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 6 termine certain types and subtypes. The Sand Hill and Level Loess areas in this State serve as illustrations. For each type area the type of farm, as it existed in 1909, has been calculated. The facts concerning the various farm types have The principal object of this work is to correlate in a measured way a number of important facts concerning farm types. The work, it will be seen, is by no means final. The material prepared during short intervals in the past two years is published here simply as a progress report. THE OUTLINE OF AGRICULTURAL REGIONS IN THE NORTHERN HEMISPHERE North America has two large agricultural regions. One of these regions centers in Washington, Oregon, and Cali - fornia, and the other in the eastern part of the United States and southern Canada. Eurasia also has two such regions similarly located. One is occupied in part by Great Britian, France, Germany, Austria, and east-central Russia, and the other in part by China Proper, Manchuria, and Japan. The climate of each of these regions is to a large extent deter - mined by the westerly winds.* Land located along western coasts receives the westerlies fresh from the ocean while that located along eastern coasts receives these winds only after they have crossed more or less of the interior of the land mass. Climate within the belt of the westerlies ranges from oceanic to continental. Naturally the truest types of oceanic climate in this belt of winds are found on western coasts. •The climate of southeastern North America and Eurasia is to an extent affected by the trade winds. leen grouped about as foil 1. Size of farm. Hows : •A. Live stock. 2. Use of land. Kinds. Crop groups. Total yields. Productive stock. Work animals. Yields per acre. Live-stock returns. Value of plant 4. Labor. growth. 5. Capital. Crop indexes. 6. Classes of operators. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farm Types in Nebraska 7 Eastern coasts have what may be classed as an oceanic cli - mate, but it is not as equable as that of western coasts. The extreme continental climate is common to the interior of North America and Eurasia. In contrast with an oceanic climate, a continental climate is variable. Temperature changes are more sudden and extreme. Rainfall is comparatively lighter and when it comes it is apt to be torrential rather than steady. Also when snow falls the ground is seldom covered with a uni - form blanket. In general it can be stated that the climates found on similar sides of North America and Eurasia are more comparable than those found on adjacent sides. This is to a less extent true of points in the interior. The boundaries of the four great agricultural regions in the northern hemisphere are determined by low temperature, low rainfall, and coast lines. In southern Canada, Norway, Sweden, and Finland, and in northern Russia, Manchuria and Japan, agriculture is limited by low temperature. The principal agricultural boundaries determined by low rainfall in North America are found (1) in the states of the Great Plains and (2) in the states of the Pacific coast region. In Eurasia the principal agricultural boundaries determined by low rainfall are found (1) in southeastern Russia and (2) in western China Proper and Manchuria. Figures 1, 2, and 3 indicate in a diagrammatic way these agricultural boundaries. The small circles mark temperature limits, and the dashes rainfall limits. The northern parts of the two agricultural regions in both land masses are connected by a strip of marginal agri - cultural country lying between a cold adverse region to the north and a dry adverse region to the south. This is roughly indicated in the figures by a line made up of both circles and dashes. It is possible that these strips of country are deter - mined by the fact that to the south higher temperature makes droughts very destructive while to the north the lack of heat during the growing season soon comes to act as an absolute limit to ordinary agriculture. Soil has but little visible effect upon the boundaries of these agricultural regions. Considered on any large geo- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Fig. 1. — The principal bouuaaries oi me Hgni'iiuurai region* of &gt;orth America. The small circles mark temperature limits and the dashes rainfall limits. graphical scale, soil effects are often submerged by climate. The reverse, however, is true within any comparatively small area of agricultural land. Here variations in soil often have sufficient range to outweigh the relatively small range of climatic variations. The location of the favorable agricultural lands with ref - erence to the distribution of native vegetation is striking. The low temperature boundaries are closely marked by the southern limits of the northern coniferous forests while the low rainfall boundaries are marked by a sparse vegetation </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Farm Types in Nebraska ■&gt; Fig. 2.— The principal boundaries of the agricultural region of Europe. Th« ■mall circles mark temperature limits and the dashes rainfall limits. characteristic of semidesert regions. Within the favorable region one finds most of the broad-leaved forests and good growths of temperate grasses. Figures 4, 5, and 6 illustrate the relative importance of soil, rainfall, and heat in various parts of any great agri - cultural region. The curved surface of a figure represents the great divisions of substance and the plane surface a few of the greater forces that are important to plants. Man, of course, is actively concerned with only such factors as happen to fall low enough to hinder him in maintaining his </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 10 Fig. 3. — Tlie principal boundaries of tbe agricultural region of Asia. The ■mall circles mark temperature limits and the dashes rainfall limits. bodily comfort. These figures indicate why it is that farmers living well within favorable regions give a great deal of attention to soil problems, while those in the northern border areas are more interested in cold evasive and cold resistant crops; and again in dry border areas interest turns to prob - lems of irrigation, drought evasion and drought resistance. Of the people living in North America and Eurasia, 90 to 95 per cent are located within the favorable regions. To the north scarcity of food and the difficulty of maintaining a comfortable bodily temperature act as checks to immigra - tion. Along low rainfall boundaries the principal check is the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Farm Types in Nebraska 11 Fig. 4. — Soil the limitiiiK factor within favorable agricultural region the difficulty of obtaining food. It may be added in con - nection with these statements that our inability to control bodily temperature is one of the chief hindrances to a suc - cessful intensive tropical agriculture. From the foregoing discussion it can easily be seen that Nebraska data will bear heavily upon moisture problems such as are common to areas near the center of the Great Plains. Altitude in the extreme western part of the State adds to what would otherwise be a short scale in heat differ - ences. As concerns soil, there is almost a complete scale in both texture and topography. THE EFFECT OF HEAT UPON THE ACREAGE OF CROPS TREATED AS ANNUALS* A CLASSIFICATION OF FIELD (HOI'S Most field crops can be classified as either annuals, bien - nials, or perennials. In field practice biennial crops have no •For a number of the ideas presented in thix division of the bulletin the author {!» indebted to Professor E. Hopt. formerly in charee of Field Crops instruction in the College of Agriculture. 1'nlverBitjr of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 12 Fig. 5. — Water tbe limiting factor in border regions determined by rainfall well-defined place of their own. In some cases they are treated as annuals and in other cases as perennials. This being the case, one is justified in saying that, in general, there are but two large divisions of field crops, one division treated as annuals and the other as perennials. Crops treated as annuals divide into three groups com - monly spoken of as fall or winter annuals, spring annuals, and summer annuals. Winter annuals are usually seeded in the fall, live thru the winter, bear fruit and die the following summer. Spring annuals are seeded either in the late winter or during the spring and are harvested in the summer or early fall. Summer annuals are planted either in the late spring or early summer and are harvested during the fall and early winter. This part of the bulletin deals principally with the acre - age of the various field crops listed in the census that are treated as cultivated annuals. It appears that the variation in the acreage of the three groups of crops belonging to this division affords one of the best possible measures of the effect </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Farm Types in Nebraska 13 Fig. 6. — Heat the limiting factor In border regions determined by low tem perature. of heat upon farming. The crops treated as annuals are pres - ent in nearly every county in the United States and usually occupy the greater part of the cultivated land. These points are very essential where large-scale measurements are to be made. While it is true that the acreage of cultivated crops treated as perennials is affected by heat it is also true that the effect of heat upon the acreage of perennials is often out - weighed by rainfall, soil, and economic conditions. This to - gether with the fact that cultivated perennials are scarcely represented in a large number of counties in the United States makes them almost useless in the measurement of what are more purely heat effects. The census makes no attempt to keep winter, spring, and summer annuals separated from one another. This grouping of crops in the census made it necessary in some cases to use estimates, and in other cases supplementary data. The fol - lowing outline will give an idea of how the census material was treated before beginning the study of heat in its relation </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 14 to farming. There may be a number of serious and valid ob - jections to the classification of certain crops in the spring and summer annual groups. The outline simply shows the order in which the census material was organized for this particular study. A. Cultivated crops treated as annuals. 1. Winter annuals. (Cold tolerant but heat sensitive.) a. Winter wheat (supplementary data used). b. Rye. (The acreage of rye given in the census was treated as winter rather than spring. This of course causes error in counties growing spring rye, but this error is seldom sufficient to affect ma- terially any broad classification of farming re - gions.) 2. Spring annuals, together with such summer an - nuals as are favored by cool weather and have a rel - atively short growing season. (Cold tolerant but heat sensitive.) a. Spring wheat (supplementary data used). b. Oats. (The acreage of oats given in the census was treated as spring. If the 1909 acreage of winter oats per county had been available, the southern border of the summer-winter type of an- nual cropping could have been mapped more ac - curately. See page 18.) c. Barley. (The acreage of barley given in the cen - sus was treated as spring.) d. Emmer and speltz. e. Flax. f. Potatoes. g. Grains cut green. (This acreage could not be used, as it contained both winter and spring grains.) h. Peas. (The acreage in the Northern States was classed here . In the Middle States, where the acre - age is very small, peas were omitted.) i. Buckwheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Farm Types in Nebraska 15 3. Summer annuals such as are favored by warm or hot summers. (Length of season required had con - siderable weight in placing a few of the crops in this group.) a. Corn. b. Kafir corn and milo. c. Sujrar cane. d. Sorghum cane. e. Broom corn. f. Millet and Hungarian grasses. g. Coarse forage. (The acreage of coarse forage ac- cording to the census schedule is made up almost wholly of summer annuals.) h. Cotton. i. Tobacco, j. Rice. k. Beans. 1. Peas. (The acreage given in the more southern states was classed as summer.) m. Peanuts, n. Hemp. o. Sweet potatoes and yams. B. Crops treated as perennials. (This division is not used in studying the effect of heat upon farming.) 1. Cultivated crops. a. Clover alone. b. Timothy alone. c. Timothy and clover mixed d. Alfalfa. e. Other tame and cultivated grasses. f. Hop. (This acreage was used only in cases where the cultivated area was desired.) 2. Crops not cultivated. a. Wild, salt, and prairie grasses. THE SIX PRINCIPAL TYPKS OF ANNIAI. &lt; HOPPING Three things, mathematically speaking, have but six pos - sible arrangements ; so it is with the three groups of field crops </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 classed under the head of "cultivated crops treated as an - nuals." In certain regions conditions are such that winter annuals occupy the greatest part of the acreage given to an - nuals. In other regions the acreage of spring annuals or the acreage of summer annuals may occupy first place. Each of the regions thus determined can again be subdivided. For example, in a region where the acreage of winter annuals stands first, it may be that in some parts summer annuals stand second and in other parts spring annuals occupy that place. Thus from the six possible arrangements we derive the six types of cropping. The subdivision of these six principal types could be carried even further by determining the relative standing of particular crops within their respective groups. In this bulletin, however, very little use is made of the minute divisions that are possible. Table 1. — The six principal types of annual cropping. Place Spring- Spring- Summer- i Summer- Winter- Winter - according summer winter spring winter spring summer to acreage type type type type type type 1st I Spring I Spring I Summerl Summer) Winter I Winter 2nd Summer Winter Spring Winter Spring Summer 3rd | Winter | Summer| Winter | Spring | Summer! Spring Table 1 describes and names the six principal types of annual cropping. It will be observed that the name of a type is determined by the relative standing of its two most important groups of annuals. A sample problem will serve to explain the method of determining and mapping these types. According to the Thirteenth Census of the United States the 1909 acreage of various crops treated as annuals in Fillmore county, Nebraska, was as follows: Crops Acres Corn 119,007 Oats 36,443 Wheat 85,893 Emmer and Speltz 344 Barley 88 Buckwheat 2 Rye 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Farm Types in Nebraska 17 Kafir corn and milo maize 12 Dry edible beans 0 Flax 10 Millet and Hungarian grasses 222 Grains cut green 27 Coarse forage 309 Potatoes 957 Sugar beets 0 Cane, sorghum 7 These acreages were treated and grouped as follow : WINTER SPRING SUMMER Winter wheat 85,739 Spring wheat .... *154 Corn 119,007 Rye 40 Oats 36,443 Kafir 12 Emmer and Millet 222 speltz 344 Coarse forage... 309 Barley 88 Cane 7 Flax 10 Potatoes 957 Buckwheat 2 Winter Spring Summer acreage 85,779 acreage 37,998 acreage 119,557 Winter acreage Spring acreage Summer acreage 85,779 or 35.2% 37,998 or 15.6% 119,557 or 49.2% 243,334 or 100.0% Since the summer group stands first and the winter group second in order of importance, the annual cropping system of Fillmore county, Nebraska, in 1909 belonged to the sum - mer-winter type. CROP BOUNDARIES The map on page 18 (Fig. 7) shows the approximate boundaries of the six types of annual cropping as they existed in the crop year 1909. The heart of the Corn Belt is made up of the summer-spring and summer-winter types. To the north of the Corn Belt and along the Pacific coast the domi - nant type is spring-summer. Most of the Rocky Mountain region and some of the cooler parts of the Great Lakes region belong to the spring-winter type. The two remaining types •The acreage of spring wheat was taken from the Nebraska Agricultural year book (crop year 1906) and subtracted from tbe total acreage of wbeat reported In the census The remaining acreage was classed as winter wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Dul. l~&gt; &lt;r- . m S \ -, 5i H R3 £ 1: s 3 Wk i§a Pr SS !•&gt; ■■ F I 'v i .-:v •2 • tl. B ~ s % * 1 ; • *^ •:&lt; r-. p ?w3 ':■ H : E tKiJR 2H v-' -,-i Fi '-:i PF - ;-l -- ra \ * * I f - ( Dt/P^] a . -4J^J. . &gt;^ f - // r - i i I tr ,' n / h± k«\ t Er~i Sw / * 1 '/.; • B&amp;d E CffTJ /r- ■ . /t-w- «¥ V- ¥ u OH zSM li seSSs? illlli #© + •• i - O£?7^ WiM&amp; i -d /-'. •7 ■ '£ Fig. 7. — The approximate boundaries of the six prlnoipnl types of aim -opping in the United States. (Crop year, 1SX».) </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Farm Types in Nebraska 19 occupy relatively small areas within those already mentioned. The winter-summer type develops at certain points within the summer-winter areas. The largest developments of this type are in western Kansas and southeastern Pennsylvania. The winter-spring type may develop in either the spring-winter or the winter-summer areas. Its most accurately defined area covers a part of southeastern Washington and north-central Oregon. This type is also indicated on the map as occurring in Idaho, Utah, Montana, Colorado, Michigan, Ohio, and Pennsylvania. In as far as was possible to determine, the southern states belong largely in the summer-spring type of cropping. Tho the name of the southern type of annual cropping is the same as that applied to the cropping in the northern part of the Corn Belt, the two regions are very different when one comes to compare the per cent of annuals falling in the summer group. In the southern states the sum - mer group commonly occupies from 85 to 90 per cent of the acreage of land given to crops treated as annuals, while in the northern part of the Corn Belt this group occupies only 50 to 60 per cent of such acreage. If the above measurements are true the cropping in the northern half of the Corn Belt and the cropping in the southern states may be looked upon as examples of two divisions of the summer-spring sype. CROSS-SKCT1ONAI, V1KWS OF VARIOUS TYPES OK ANNUAL CROPPING The cross-sectional views (Figs. 8 and 9) drawn from data entering into the map on page 18 make it possible to study the relationship of one type to another. Figure 8 is a cross-sectional view along a line extending from southern Arkansas to the extreme northern part of Michigan. The per cent of the acreage of annuals given to the winter group is extremely low along the line in Arkansas; but by the time one reaches St. Louis County in Missouri, the winter group has come to occupy over 50 per cent of the land in annuals. To the north of this county, winter annuals drop out rapidly. If the acreage of spring rye does not have too great an in - fluence, one can say that there is a tendency for winter an- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 nuals to increase slightly while crossing Wisconsin and north - ern Michigan. Beginning at the southern end of the line in Arkansas the summer group of annuals stands over 85 per cent as far north as Ripley County in Missouri. North of this point sum - mer annuals drop out rapidly until they finally stand at almost zero in Kewaunee County, Michigan. It will be observed that along this line, from southern Arkansas to northern Mich - igan, it is the summer rather than the spring annual group that gives way to winter annuals. The most striking thing to be observed concerning the spring annual group is that its rate of increase to the north is comparatively steady. In all cross-sectional studies thus far made, the rate of change for the spring annual group has been more uniform than that of the other groups. The vertical crayon-like lines in the graph (Fig. 8) mark the boundaries between types. These occur wherever two heavy solid lines cross one another. Named in order from south to north the types are as follows : summer-spring, sum - mer-winter, winter-summer, summer-winter, summer-spring, spring-summer, and spring-winter. The cross-sectional view of types in southeastern Wash - ington and north-central Oregon (Fig. 9) gives the relation existing between the spring-summer, spring-winter, and winter-spring types. At the southern end of the line, which is in Baker County, Oregon, winter annuals stand at about 16 per cent. In north-central Oregon, some eighty miles to the northwest along this line, winter annuals come to occupy over 80 per cent of the acreage. Continuing northwest, winter annuals drop out rapidly until they reach almost zero in Snohomish County, Washington. Spring annuals, it will be seen, vary inversely as the winter annuals, for the summer annual group thruout this cross-section stands so low that it has almost no effect This is particularly true where winter annuals occupy first place. The broken lines crossing the graphs (Figs. 8 and 9) serve as an index to the quantity of heat above freezing that is nor- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Farm Types in Nebraska 21 Fig. f. — A crosR-xertional view of annual cropping alnng a line extending from southern Arkansas to tbe extreme northern part of Michigan. (See key map placed on tbe right-hand Bide of the t'raph.i mally received during the year. To reduce the quantity of heat from degrees to per cent, 450 month-degrees above freez - ing was used as a base. This quantity of heat is found in only the warmest parts of the United States. MONTH -1&gt;K«.KKKS ABOVK IKKKZIM. Figure 11 will show where this quantity of heat (450 month-degrees above freezing) is found in southern Texas. To calculate a similar figure for any given Weather Bureau station, it is only necessary to determine the total of the normal mean temperature of the months above freezing and subtract from the sum as many thirty-twos as there are months having a normal mean temperature above freezing.* This gives what is spoken of here as month-degrees above freezing or, in brief, simply month-degrees. Thirty-two de - grees is used as the lower limit because it marks a point belaw 'Sample problem : — 4'talculation of tbe month-degrees at the University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. Normal mean temperature: Jan.. 24.8; Feb., 26.3; March. 41.6; April, 52.T; May, 62.3; June. 71.1; July, 76.0; August, 75.0; Sept., 6*7.4; Oct., 9&amp;0; Nov. 40.8; Dec.. 28.1. "&lt;41.«H-52.7 +62.3+71.1 + 76.0+75.O+«7.4 +56.0+40.6) — (0x32) = -J53.7 month-decrees above freezinK. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 puanT Kig. 8.— A cros8-8ectl»usl view of : iinral cropping alone » line extending f 'i m northeastern Oregon to northwest - i-rn Washington. (See key map placed in the upper right-hand corner of the ?raph.) Fife. 10. — A diagram of the oi-cur - renre of tbe winter-spring t.vpe of :in - ■ iii.-i I cropping within tbe winter - summer and summer-winter types. which the growth of agricultural plants almost ceases. Some persons prefer 36° F. or even 40° F. as a lower limit. There can, however, be no good reason for choosing an arbitrary point so long as 32 ° F. is less questionable and better known. BOINDABY LINES DETERMINED LARGELY BY HEAT The lines separating one type of annual cropping from another (Fig. 7) are to a large extent determined by heat. The boundary between the spring-summer and summer-spring types east of the Rockies follows in general the line of 200 month-degrees. (See Figs. 7 and 12.) West of the Rockies the boundary between these two types of cropping could not be accurately determined. The boundary line that is shown on the map (Fig. 7) appears to bear no relation to the line of </seg>
            <seg id="p023">farm Types in Nebraska 23 Fig. 11. — Month-degrees above freezing. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">21 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Fig. 12. — The line of 200 month-degrees above freezing marks very closely the boundary between the spring-summer and summer-spring types of annual cropping east of the Rookies. 200 month-degrees west of the Rockies. Question marks ap - pear on the map at points where the classification was most difficult and inaccurate. To classify this part of the United States one would need in some cases to use township or pre - cinct data in the place of county data. Furthermore the acre - age of winter annuals would need to be more carefully sepa - rated from the acreage of spring annuals. The boundaries of the summer-winter and winter-spring types are in close harmony with certain quantities of winter wheat The center of the summer-winter and winter-spring types are usually found close to the line where winter heat measures zero month-degrees. (See Fig. 13.) Each of the winter-annual areas in 1909 occupied areas where the winter heat measured not less than — 25 month-degrees. While the northern limit was closely marked by — 25, the southern limit was almost as closely marked by +25 month-degrees of winter heat (It will be observed that crop boundaries and heat lines are again found to be most at variance with one an - other in the southwestern part of the United States.) Since in the summer-winter and winter-spring regions winter annuals are more or less active from September 1st to </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Fig. IS. — Month-degree* above freezing received during December, January, and February. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 July 1st the quantity of heat above freezing has also been determined for this period. Figure 14 defines the boundaries of a belt of country in the United States which receives from 150 to 230 month-degrees above freezing between September 1st and July 1st. The small circles placed to the north of this belt mark certain points that receive during the winter an - nual season not less than 138 month-degrees. Only a few winter annual areas will be found to the north of these points. THE EFFECT OF FACTORS OTHEK THAN HEAT Tho heat has the greatest effect upon the boundaries of crop types, rainfall, soil, and economic conditions can have a marked influence. A few examples will suffice to illustrate how heat alone will not fully account for the position of cer - tain crop boundaries. Thus the area of winter-summer crop - ping in western Kansas is determined to a large extent by July and August droughts that are accompanied by extreme heat. Winter wheat in this area escapes the hot droughty period more often than corn and other summer annuals. If it were not for this fact this area would without much doubt drop back to the summer-winter type. The factors just men - tioned also influenced the development of the small island of winter-summer cropping in south-central Nebraska, but here extremely level land was also a factor. This type would, in all probability, not have appeared at this point in 1909 had the land been hilly. The position of boundary lines in a given year throws some light on the economic question of profits derived from certain crops. As an illustration, the boundary line drawn around the winter-summer type in western Kansas must define an area within which, according to the experience of farmers, an acre of winter annuals had been paying better than an acre of summer annuals. When one stops to consider that in this area winter wheat is about the only winter annual and corn is the leading summer annual, it is not far wrong to assume that here an acre of winter wheat previous to 1909 had been paying </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Farm Types in Nebraska 27 ? g '1 »« K? % ' ■£m y ,1 j m m I- i; Q-; 1 S I J - ' -a i \ A — -■-■.":'.■•■•-'}- : -r 1 -^ " Hit. i i ; Li i ■■ '-n it . : . - I CCT-M L -I L Y-1_J L/l T\^r-LHJ +* Oo&gt; * • fe ». «i ►T tS J i jx: o o o o p ■y I \ — &lt; r Fie. 14. — Month -decrees above freezing received between September 1st at ulv 1st Tlie small i mles mark points that receive iluring tills perioil not le: han 13S montl^-ilffirefs above freezing. The barred part of the belt on tl •aciflc coast indicates very cool summers, i.e., summers measuring less than li aonth-degrees above freezing. id </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 28 better than an acre of corn. If it were not for the fact that an acreage of one group of annuals sometimes of necessity carries with it a certain acreage of another group, this line of reason - ing could, without much modification, be applied to all type boundary lines. For example, it would be only approximately correct to state that in changing from a corn and oat region to a corn and wheat region the boundary line between the two marked the point at which the profits from an acre of winter wheat began to exceed those from an acre of oats. It would be more nearly correct to say that the boundary line marked the point at which the profits from a given acreage of corn and wheat began to exceed the profits from a given acreage of corn and oats. SIZE OF FARM IN RELATION TO RAINFALL AND OTHER FACTORS IN THE GREAT PLAINS DEFINITION OF THE TERM FARM A farm, generally speaking, is the area of land from which a family derives a living thru such operations as culti - vating crops, cutting wild hay, pasturing native grasses, and feeding live stock. Broadly construed, this definition makes it possible for a single farm to include owned land, leased land, and "free range." If the area of free range were to be excluded, the use of the term farm in this bulletin would be similar to its use in the Thirteenth Census. Two extracts from the instructions for the general agri - cultural schedule (1910) will serve to illustrate the census use of the word farm. Farm. A "farm," for census purposes — that is, for which a general farm schedule should be obtained — is all the land which is directly farmed by a single person, managing and conducting agricultural operations, either by his own labor alone or with the assistance of members of his household or of hired employees. The term "agri - cultural operations" is here used as a general term re - ferring to the work of growing crops, producing other agricultural products, and raising animals, fowls, and bees. A farm as thus defined may consist of a single tract of land or a number of separate and distinct tracts </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Farm Types in Nebraska 29 situated in the same or in different enumeration dis - tricts, and may be held under different tenures, as where one tract is owned by the farmer and another tract leased by him. For example, if A B operates or cultivates under his personal management one tract of 60 acres in one place and another tract of 30 acres in another place, these two separate tracts constitute one farm of 90 acres. But if A B owns 90 acres of land in one tract but culti - vates under his personal management only 60 acres of such tract and leases the other 30 acres to another person, C D, the farm of A B consists of but 60 acres — that is, the number of acres actually farmed or operated by him, the remaining 30 acres constituting the farm, or part of the farm, of C D. Or, again, if A B owns 90 acres of land which he ordinarily considers as "his farm," but leases 30 acres from C D, then the farm of A B consists of 120 acres — that is, the total number of acres actually farmed by him. Ranches using public lands. The farm of ranchmen using the public domain includes only the land which he owns or leases. If he leases public land or any other land, such land is a part of his farm. But his farm does not include any public land for which he pays no rental or upon which live stock are grazed at a fixed charge per head. Across the head of schedules for farms and ranches using public lands for grazing live stock write RANGE in large letters. In cases where cattle are grazed wholly upon the public domain and the owner of the ani - mals does not own or lease any land, fill out a schedule for the owner the same as for anv ordinary farm operator, omitting answers, however, to Inquiries 10 to 15 and writ - ing in answer to Inquiry 6 the words "No land owned or leased." When we include from a farm public land for which a farmer "pays no rental or upon which live stock are grazed at a fixed charge per head" we decrease, to that extent, the area of land from which he derives a living and his farm cannot be directly compared with one having no free range. METHOD OF CMA TI.ATING THE SIZE OF FARM IN THE i.REAT PLAINS REGION For western Nebraska the Thirteenth Census reports that less than two-thirds of the total area of land was oc- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 30 cupied by farms. Field studies at many points in that part of the State lead one to believe that the people living there in 1909 would have been seriously handicapped in making a living had even the poorest one-third of the total land area been wholly excluded from agricultural use. A farm manage - ment survey made in Kimball County in 1915 indicated that the size of farm in the county was nearer two sections of land than one section as reported in the census. In all probability the number of farms in Kimball County had increased since 1909, and so it can hardly be true that a farm at that time consisted of only one section of land. It was also observed during this survey that the area of pasture land not grazed over at some time during the year was almost negligible. Table 2 compares the average size of farms taken at random in Farm Management surveys with census figures. In most cases the average size of farm secured thru surveys (1914-1916) is more in harmony with the result obtained by dividing the total land area of the county by the number of farms it contained in 1909, than with the size of farm given in the census. If the survey figures can be relied upon, it is safe to state that practically the entire area of land is made to contribute in one way or another to the living of farmers located upon it. It is a commonly known fact that nearly every western area had, at some time previous to the last census, Table 2. — The size of farm calculated from Nebraska Farm Management surveys compared with census figures. I'arni Maiiiiiieuieiit »urvt- \ &gt; Cfitsus ti^'irew County In wliirh records were t«ke:i ■I Xnmlier of records Crop year Averajft size o' la mi - taken a; random In field surveys ; Total nreu of tbe I'ounty divided bv tlie number 1 1'MH&gt;&gt; Size of farm as Kiv'ii in tBC ITlhUS I 11H») Western counties Kimhall Box Butte DaweB Thomas Eastern counties Ptaelpg Seward Thurston Madison 36 5.1 67 a m 50 62 1!&gt;16 1914 IMS IMS MI IMS 1915 lften a !»67 1143 r:ir.i 24\ 216 22&lt;&gt; 23S 14-11 A 1171 114N 172:f 644 A 931 (SIS 77v ■s.v:, n;.i as? 207 Hi.-, v»7 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Farm Types in Nebraska 31 seen ranchers strongly opposed to increasing the number of farms. Even in those times they must have felt that, to make a living under such economic conditions as they were experi - encing, it was necessary to use practically all of the land. The first calculations of the size of farm per county in this State were based upon the assumption that only a very small part of a county was not being used by the people farm - ing there. An attempt was made to eliminate from the total acreage of each county ( 1 ) the area occupied by the very small farms reported in the census and (2) the area occupied by town lots and railroads. It was soon found (1) that the very small farms could not consistently be separated from the largest farms and (2) that the area of land occupied by towns and railroads combined did not as a rule amount to one per - cent of the area of the county. Further studies brought out the fact that the relation between the number of very small farms and the area of land occupied by towns and railroads was such that one always tended to offset the effect of the other when the total area of the county was divided by the total number of farms. Figures bearing upon the size of farm in the vicinity of Omaha will illustrate this tendency of very small farms to offset even a large area of land in town lots and railroads. According to the order followed in the first method of study, it was estimated that Douglas county, in which Omaha is located, had 29,560 acres of land occupied by towns, railroads, and very small farms. The remaining area of Douglas county was then divided by the number of larger farms. This gave 168 acres per farm. Following the order of the second method the total area of the county was simply divided by the total number of farms. This gave 12:' acres per farm. As a check on these figures a field study (1917) was made in Papillion precinct in Sarpy county some seven miles southwest of the South Omaha market. Thp area covered was 18,880 acres. The average size of farm here proved to be 126 acres. Judging from this studv and also from field observations in practically all nrecincts in Douorlas county, the second method of calculating the size of farm gives </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 32 a more accurate idea of open farming country than the first. Another very important point in favor of the second method is its freedom from any arbitrary rulings concerning very small farms. When the total area of the county is used, it gives a stable basis from which to measure any change in the aver- age size of farm brought about thru either an increase or a decrease in the number of farms. Table 3 illustrates the im- portance of this fact. In the first column of the table are found the names of the type areas in Nebraska and also the Table 3. — The size of farm as affected by the number of farms within a given area. Nebraska type areas. ' Number j Numbei I Total ares Siie of farm The figures Indicate of all of all divided by total given in census the total acreage of farms in farms Ii number of farms counties chosen to 19U0 191" represent a type area. 1900 i litir 1U00 I 1910 (1) (2) ,3) (4) (5) (6) (7) 2,314,240 acres used 14,520 I 13 52 1 159 171 I 155 164 Cass type area — -f Thayer — -j- + 5.959,680 34,657 j 32.323 172 184 169 178 Wayne + — — 4,747,987 20,254 20,743 234 229 232 213 4,747,987 20,254 20,743 234 229 232 213 Buffalo + — — 2,542,720 9,083 j 9,777 280 260 263 240 Harlan — + + 5,521,280 20,361 19,831 271 278 250 264 Custer -|- — — 2,829,440 6,939 8,194 408 345 32] 316 Boyd + — + 2,369,920 3,764 4,007 629 591 320 549 Hitchcock + — + 3,091,840 3,619 4,588 855 674 514 531 Chase + — + 4.231,040 2,545 5,093 1,662 831 473 502 E. Sand Hills + — + E. Sand Hills + — + 2.994,560 2,016 3,486 1,486 859 439 629 2.994,560 2,016 3,486 1,486 859 439 629 High Plains + — 4- High Plains + — + 4.753.280 2,654 4.203 1,789 1,129 709 746 W. Sand Hills + — + 5,818,240 1,334 3,266 4.359 1,781 661 859 total area of the counties used in determining the average size of farm. The second column contains the number of all farms in 1900 that were located within the area of land indicated </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Farm Types in Nebraska 33 in the first column of the table. The third shows the number of all farms within this same area of land in 1910. Columns 4 and 5 of the table give the calculated average size of farm for 1900 and 1910 respectively, while columns 6 and 7 give the average size of farm as recorded in the census. It will be ob - served that where the number of farms in 1910 shows an in - crease over 1900, the average size of farm recorded in the census decreases in eastern areas and increases in western areas. For example, in 1900 some five million acres of land in the western Sand Hills held 1,334 farms. Ten years later the number of farms on this area of land had increased to 3,266. The total area of land divided by the number of farms gives 4,359 acres per farm in 1900 and 1,781 acres in 1910. From the standpoint of the average area of land required to make a family living in those years, the figures are not far out of line with the experience of thrifty ranchers and farmers living there. Regardless of the fact that the number of farms in the western Sand Hills more than doubled between 1900 and 1910, the census records a 30 per cent increase in the size of farm. This increase in size would not appear if all land grazed had been included in farm. It is seldom that large areas of grass land in the Great Plains are so completely withheld from farm use as to reduce agricultural practices to zero. Where land is partly withheld farmers and ranchers simply practice more extensive methods of farming than the other factors in the region would actually reauire. What is here said of grass lands will not apply to the timber lands found in northern Minnesota and Wisconsin. In this area, part of the land is used by lumber companies and cannot be classed as land in farms. The fact that much of this heavy timber must be cleared before the land can have any farm use makes it relatively easy to hold large tracts of timber from agricultural use. From these facts it can readily be inferred that in a timber region the area of a county di - vided by the number of farms contained cannot give a true index to the average size of farm. Tho size-of-farm lines, so determined, have been drawn across northern Minnesota and Wisconsin, they are of value only when compared with the </seg>
            <seg id="p034">11 1 o4 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 acres per person. A study of figures 24, 25, 26, and 27 in comparison with figures 28, 29, 30, and 31 will brinar out the fact that the land in northern Minnesota and Wisconsin fur - nishesa living for more than is indicated by the size-of-farm lines. It will be observed that ordinarily in a grass-covered region the 1280-acre lines are found very close to the lines in - dicating 200 acres per person (total population). The 1280 - acre lines drawn across the timber region would probably cross about as far north as the lines indicating 200 acres per person if it were possible to reduce lumbering to a farm basis. A summary of the above discussion will bring out more clearly the chief considerations that led to basing size-of-farm studies in the Great Plains on simply the area of a county divided by the number of farms contained. ( 1 ) When a farm is defined as the area of land from which a family derives a living thru such operations as cultivating crops, cutting wild hay, pasturing native grasses, and feeding live stock, nearly all of the land in the Great Plains can be looked upon as farm land. (2) The area occupied by town lots and rail - roads tends to be offset by the number of very small farms. (3) The total area of the county gives a stable basis from which to measure any changes in the average size of farm dur to a chance in the number of fanv.s. SKTHi u of m \r ■ ■ 7i::; i».»ta From county data contains, i.i i:m» census the size of farm has been determined for each cunty 'ounties in Oklahoma excepted*) in the Great Pis' "&gt; region and certain bordering areas to the east. The _ mcludes census reports as far back as 1880. Maps drawn \A r " the plan of those commonly &gt;ised by the Weather Ruread ~? here used to summarize the size-of-farm data. This method of mapping makes it a simple matter to compare the trend of any given size-of-farm line with the trend of precipitation lines. •Since Oklahoma did not develop in harmony with tlu&gt; other states in this region, it is here omitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Farm Types in Nebraska 35 TUB HKSTIKX KIM;*: OF KiC-A&lt; KK I AHMIMi In 1880 the 160-acre farm was common as far west as - northwestern Missouri, central Iowa, and southwestern Wis - consin. A study of figure 19 will show that the 160-acre lines remained almost stationary in Kansas, Nebraska, and Iowa for a period of thirty years. The great expansion during the period between 1880 and 1910 took place to the west, north, and south of this strip of country. Barring soil effects, the western edge of quarter-section farming follows very closely a normal annual precipitation of from 31 to 32 inches. (See Fig. 18.) In eastern Kansas the 160-acre lines are usually found in counties having from 35 to 40 inches of rainfall. Jt is here that the "flint hill section" holds the 160-acre lines to the east. In Texas the 160-acre farm advanced much farther south than west. The westward advance against a decreasing rainfall was scarcely greater than that taking place in the states to the north. TWO-CKCTION KAKMINC. The principal factors affecting the size of farm in the drier parts of the Great Plains can best be introduced thru a study of the 1,280-acre lines. (See Fig. 23 and also Figs. 24, 25, 26, and 27.) Between 1880 and 1910, two-section farming in South Dakota moved from a country having 24 inches of rainfall to one having but 16 inches. In central Texas during the same period this size of farm occupied the strip of country lying between the 21 and the 26 inch rain - fall lines. While 1,280-acre farming in South Dakota ad - vanced thru approximately an 8-inch decrease in rainfall, it advanced thru only about 5 inches in central Texas. The slower advance against rainfall in the south can be attributed largely to two factors, namely, greater evaporation and some - what slower development of country. Of the factors men - tioned, evaporation appears to have the greater influence. In North Dakota and Texas the 1,280-acre lines make a fairly regular advance during each ten-year interval fol - lowing 1880. In contrast with these regular movements, </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 the lines at many points in South Dakota, Nebraska, and Kan - sas show a number of reactions. This is particularly true of the lines marking the western edge of two-section farming in 1890 and 1900. One of the outstanding features of the 1,280-acre line in 1890 is its marked westward bend into northeastern Colorado. Within this bend homesteading reached one of its highest points. In the late eighties and early nineties, people here occupied a country developed more out of harmony with rainfall and heat than could be found at any point either to the north or to the south. The line drawn for the year 1900 gives at least a partial view of the reaction that followed.* It was most severe in southwestern Nebraska and northwestern Kansas. To the north and south of these areas the reactionary movement gradually disappears. NIZE OF FARM IN RELATION TO RAINFALL AND HEAT The size of farm in 1880 and 1910 was probably more uni - formly adjusted to rainfall and heat than it was in either 1890 or 1900. (See Figs. 24, 25, 26, and 27.) Nevertheless, each map in the series just referred to shows a tendency for its lines to converge to the south more rapidly than rainfall. (See Fig. 18.) This convergence is more readily seen when the lines in the eastern quarter of Texas are covered. Figure 15 is a diagram on which the 1910 size-of-farm lines are plotted according to inches of rainfall used as degrees of longitude and month-degrees used as degrees of latitude. The 320-acre line and the lines to the east of it follow approxi - mately the same quantity of rainfall regardless of an increase or decrease in the quantity of heat. To the west of the 320 - acre line the section and two-section size of farm veer rapidly into higher rainfall to the east as the quantity of heat in - creases to the south. As was mentioned in the introductory discussion of the 1,280-acre lines, a small part of this variation may be due to a slower development of western farming in the south. •It mult be borne in mind thnt pome nctions nnd reactions were so sharp that measurements made nt ten-year intervals could not fully record them. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Farm Types in Nebraska ■■u SlZK OF I AKM IN KKLATION TO SOIL From the preceding discussion one might be led to infer that the position of size-of-farm lines in the Great Plains is seldom affected by soil. The series of maps last referred to (Figs. 24, 25, 26, and 27) can also be used to illustrate cer - tain soil effects. The "Flint Hill" section in Kansas was men - tioned during a discussion of 160-acre lines. In 1880 this sec - tion stood out as an island of half -section farming in eastern Kansas. In 1890, 1900, and 1910 the size of farm is seen to be somewhat reduced but it still stands out as an area oc - cupied by relatively large farms. The Sand Hill region in north-central Nebraska has even a more marked effect upon the size of farm. On the map of 1880 (Fig. 24) the two-sec - tion and one-section lines in northeastern Nebraska bend sharply to the east in order to avoid the Sand Hills and border - ing areas of more or less sandy land. In 1890 these lines enter the eastern Sand Hills. In 1900 they recede to the eastern edge, where they almost meet the half-section line which has moved a little to the west and is just beginning to bend east - ward in order to avoid sandy land. By 1910 the two-section line has passed beyond the Sand Hills, leaving behind it an island of very large farms to occupy the western part. While section farming has again entered the eastern Sand Hills, half-section farming in 1910 still skirts the edge. SIZK OK FA KM IN KKI.ATION TO RAINFALL AND ECONOMIC CONDITIONS A cross-sectional measurement of size of farm in the Great Plains region will bring out certain facts concerning rainfall and economic conditions more clearly than can be pointed out from maps. Figure 16 is a cross-sectional meas - urement following approximately the line of 240 month-de - grees from Iowa across southeastern Nebraska and north - western Kansas into Colorado. The purpose of following a given quantity of heat is to eliminate in as far as possible the effect of heat upon the size of farm. The choice of this par - ticular quantity of heat was influenced by the fact that it crosses the Great Plains at a point where soil variations are </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 slight. It is even possible that the western soils, being a little more open and more level than the eastern soils, give a slight advantage to the western farms. With effective vari - ation in both heat and soil largely eliminated, the study along this line can be more positively centered upon the size of farm in relation to rainfall and economic conditions. In the graph (Fig. 16), rainfall tends to give similarity to the shape of the curves while economic conditions are largely responsible for their position relative to one another. Each of these curves shows that as soon as rainfall is decreased below a certain point the size of farm increases rapidly. This point in rainfall is sometimes designated as critical rainfall. Along the line of the graph, critical rainfall varies with economic conditions. Thus in 1880, 1890, 1900, and 1910, critical rainfall stood at approximately 25.0, 19.5, 22, and 21 inches respectively. It is a rather striking fact that between 1880 and 1910 the critical point in rainfall along this line had been lowered only about 4 inches. When cross-sectional studies of this kind are made across the northern part of the Great Plains, the curves reach into lower rainfall and are less sharp. On the other hand, cross-sectional studies to the south of the 240 - month-degrees line give very sharp curves that do not reach into extremely low rainfall. SIZE OF FARM IX KKLAT1ON TO PLANT GROHTH The connecting link between size of farm and moisture conditions in the Great Plains is plant growth. It stands to reason that where rainfall is normally low and as a result crop yields are low and pasture growth is short, a farm must of necessity occupy enough land to bring the total annual growth of usable plants to a level that will insure the average farm family a living. Figure 17 gives a view of the size of farm in relation to the total annual growth of crops and pasture. As shown by the key map accompanying the figure, the heat and soil conditions in the areas chosen are much the same as those described in the preceding cross-sectional study. In the accompanying diagram the blocks placed adjoining one </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Farm Types in Nebraska 39 another illustrate how a farm in the Great Plains adjusts its area to overcome the effects of low crop yields and short pas - ture growth. The base-length of a block represents the total farm area. (Note here Table 3, columns 1 and 5.) The divi - sion of the farm area between crop and pasture land is brought out by shading. The height of one block relative to another (the height above the shading) is in harmony with the crop index of one farm type relative to another. The crop index of each of these farm types was calculated from the census and applies only to the crop year 1909. When the crop and pasture growth in the Thayer area was assumed to be 100 per cent, the Harlan and Hitchcock types measured 60.2 and 32.0 per cent respectively. Tho these measurements are based on only the crop year 1909, they serve very well as an index to normal conditions. According to the results obtained, 100 acres of the Harlan type of farm were equivalent, in 1909, to 60.2 acres of the Thayer type of farm. Comparing the Hitch - cock type of farm with the Thayer type in this year, 100 acres of the former were about equivalent to 32 acres of the latter. This principle of adjusting the size of farm to the quan - tity and value of plant growth is as old as dry land farming. It is practiced in all of the dry border regions of the world. Field studies in Nebraska lead one to conclude that until this principle is complied with the would-be dry farmer is barred from success. MONTH-DiamlC diagram which uses hi nf latitude. Fitr. 15. — The size-of farm lint's for 1910 plotted on rainfall as degrees of lonKitniie and month-degrees a* dc </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bid. 15 •MSPHtfMM C010WD0 IOWJ Fie. 1C — A iTiiss-scition iiK'.iMiri'ini-iit nf ulae-ef-farm following approxi mately the line of L'-H' innntli-ilonro's from Iowa inti&gt; Colorailu. Fan mu macau immuvtiau imwiiums Fig. 17.— The relation of the size of farm to the total annual growth of crops and pasture. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Farm Types in Nebraska 41 Vig lS.-ATerage annual precipitation In inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 42 Fig. 19. — The movement of the lflO-urre lint's. The dotted line indicates I he western margin of 160-ac-re farming in l£*0, and tlie solid line the western marKin In 1910. ,*, i* </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Farm Types in Nebraska 43 Fig. 20. — The movement of 210-aere lines. The "lotted line stands for 1880 and the solid line for 1010. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 * F . l £ 21 iY^ T M e "S^ilEl! 1 — 33&lt;li " 11 ' "n* 8 - 'llie O«tte.l line stnnds for 1S*J and the solid line for 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Farm Types in Nebraska 45 Fig. 22— The movement of 040-ncre lines. The dotted line stands for 1S80 and the solid line for 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 * Fl f- S3 -^ Ih f moTem&lt;&gt;n t of 1280 acre lines. The dotted line stand! for 1880 and the solid line for 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Farm Types in Nebraska 47 Fig 24. — The position of various size-of-farm line* in I860. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bid. 15 Fig. 26.— The position of various sire of farm lines in 1800. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Farm Types in Nebraska 49 KIk I'fi— The position of various size-of farm lines in l'.MK). </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 *"•»• 27.— The position of various size-of-farm lines in 1010. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Farm Types in Nebraska 51 Fig. 26.— Acres per persuii (total population I In 1S8U </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 V\g 2*1.— Acres per person (total population) in 1890. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Farm Types in Nebraska 53 Fig. 30.— Acres per person (total po[&gt;ul:ition i in l!K)0. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 V\K. .11.— Acres per person itotal population) In 1810. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Farm Types in Nebraska 55 Fiff. S2.~ The value i»er nrre of such Innr] as was reported to l»e In farms In 1890. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Fig. 33. —The Milne |irr .uie &lt;if k.i.Ii land ax vms re|ioiteil til tic in farms in 1900. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Farm Types in Nebraska 57 Kic. SM. — The whir imt new of sin h I. mil ;is «ns rrporlcil tn '»' in f:irms In 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 58 Fig. 35.— The nvernse Miiminl precipitation and month deirree in Nebraska FARM TYPES IN NEBRASKA The boundaries of type areas in Nebraska are to a large extent determined by heat, rainfall, and soil. To map the principal areas of the State having a fairly uniform type of farming, crop lines are used to register heat effects as slightly modified by rainfall and other factors, while size-of-farm lines are used to register rainfall effects as slightly modified by heat and other factors. In one case, that of the Sand Hills, soil is used independently to determine the outer boundaries of two types. A key to all boundary lines is shown in figure 36. It will be observed that in general the northern and southern boundaries of type areas are determined by the type of annual cropping, and the eastern and western boundaries by the size of farm. The data used in determining these lines were se cured from the Thirteenth Census. The Fourteenth Census Itol Mi wtlh - OF TVPE AREAS </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Farm Types in Nebraska 59 l"iir. :W&gt;.- Tin- key to the boundaries uf type areas in -NenrasKa as ueivi-uiiiiec for the yenr 1906. ii no doubt will show the need of redrawing nearly all lines aside from those determined by the Sand Hills. For example, it would not be surprising to find that the small island of winter - summer cropping in south-central Nebraska had grown larger, that the summer-winter type was covering more of the south - eastern counties, and that certain size-of-farm lines had moved a little farther west. For the crop year 1909 Nebraska has been divided into twelve type areas. The three northwestern areas are named according to the regions they occupy. All other areas bear county names. (See Fig. 37.) To one who is familiar with the State, county names serve to characterize and locate an area almost as well as regional names. If it had been possible, however, regional names would have been given to all areas. INK HI I 1 KMI\ \ 1 IUN OF FARM TYPES The average type of farm for each type area was calcu - lated from the county agricultural data of the census. Since </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 the organization of the census data would not permit the use of the entire area of land within a given set of boundary lines, it was necessary to choose a representative group of counties to serve as a basis for farm types.* To determine farm types, each item of county agricultural data was tabu - lated according to the representative groups of counties and then totaled and reduced to an average farm basis. While the total area of land was reduced to an average farm basis by using the number of all farms as a divisor, the total number of live stock and similar items were reduced by using the num - ber of farms reporting domestic animals. This avoided at least a part of the error that would result from distributing field crops, live stock, and other items to very small farms not belonging to the general type. Table 4 brings out the fact that in most cases the difference between the number of all farms and the number of farms reporting domestic animals is relatively small. The relative standing of winter, spring, and summer annuals indicated by the crop boundaries of type areas is very accurately shown by the average figures derived from the rep - resentative groups of counties. (See Figs. 36 and 37.) Both the boundary lines and the figures indicate that the High Plains area belongs to the spring-summer type of annual cropping, that the Western Sand Hills, Eastern Sand Hills, •Boyd Area — Boyd, Holt, and Kayapaha Counties. Buffalo Area — Buffalo. Pnwsun. Howard. Merrlck, Nance, and Sherman Counties. Pass Aren — Pass, Dodge, Johnson, Otoe, Pawnee. S;tunders. nnd Washington Counties. Chase Area— Chase, Dundy, and Hayes Counties, in Nebrnsku; Phillips and Yuma Counties in Colorado; Chevenne County in Kansas. IKl &lt; iruilllT^ 1U V oil, 1 .1111, . \.UCICUUr VUUJJl.l Ml ntlllBtin. Custer Area — Boone, Custer. Oreeley. and Vallev Counties. Eastern Sand Hill Area — Blaine. Brown. Garfleld. Lonp, Rock, and Wheeler Counties. Harlan Area — Harlan. Franklin. Frontier. Furnas. Gosper. Kearney, and Phelps Counties in Nebraska : Graham, Mitchell, Norton. Phillips and Smith Counties in Kansas. High Plains Area — Banner, Box Butte. Cheyenne. Pawes, Kimbnll and Sioux Counties. Hicheoek Area — Hitchcock County In Nebraska; Logan, Rawlins. Sheridan and Thomas Counties In Kansas. Thaver Area — Clay, Butler. Fillmore. Hamilton. Jefferson. Niirkolls. Polk, Saline. Seward. Tnnyer. nnd Vork Counties In Nebraska : Clny. Marshall. Republic, and Washington Counties in Kansas. Wayne Area — Cedar, Dakota. Dtxon. Pumlnir. Knox. Madison. Tierce. Stanton. and Wayne Counties in Nebraska: Plymouth County In Iowa; Clay, Union and Yankton Counties In South Dakota. Western Sand Hill Area — Cherry. Hooker. McPherson, and Thomas Counties </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Farm Types in Nebraska 61 Table 4. — The number of all farms compared ivith the numbf reporting domestic animals. Boyd, Chase, Custer, Wayne, and Cass areas belong to the summer-spring type; that the Buffalo, Harlan, and Thayer areas belong to the summer-winter type; and the Hitchcock area to the winter-summer type. The key to boundary lines (Fig. 36) shows that the Wayne area is separated from the Custer area by a line following 5 per cent winter annuals. The figures determined from county groups indicate 2 per cent winter annuals in the Wayne area and 10 per cent winter an - nuals in the Custer area. The relation that exists between the size-of-farm bound - aries and the average size of farm determined for county groups can be seen on comparing figure 36 with figure 38. The average size of farm determined for a group of counties in no case exactly agrees with the average indicated by the size-of - farm lines. This is in part due to the fact that the size of farm does not change at a uniform rate from one line to an - other. Each type area outlined holds a wide range of farm con - ditions. This is particularly true of western areas. For ex - ample, there is not a great deal of difference between lowland and upland farms in the eastern part of the State, but in western areas lowland farms that are either naturally or artificially irrigated resemble in many ways eastern farms Type area Approximate acreage of the I'OUlltte* ilmst'll to represent an urea Number of all farms (1910) in the counties chosen Number of farms (1910) reporting domestic animals Boyd _ i Buffalo ! Cass + Chase Custer E. Sand Hills ... 2,369,920 2,542,720 2,314,240 4,231,040 2,829,440 2,994,560 4,007 9,777 13,521 5,093 8,194 3,486 3,955 9,588 13,297 4,915 8,097 3,382 Harlan High Plains Hitchcock Thayer Wayne W. Sand Hills... 5,521,280 4,753,280 3,091,840 5,959,680 4,747,987 5,818,240 19,839 4,203 4,588 32,323 20,743 3,266 19,331 3,988 4,410 31,833 20,435 2,993 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Fig. 37. — The relative importance of winter, iprinc, iinil suiiini t uuuuals in the various type areas of Nebraska. tlWX&gt;) more closely than they do dry upland western farms. These and similar irregularities make it impossible to describe a type of farm that will fit all conditions within a given area. The numerical descriptions of farm types which follow apply more to farming on nonirrigated upland than they do to farm - ing on bottom land and irrigated upland. I AKM TYPES (.KOI l-h.lt FOB THE PIBI'OSE OF BTUI&gt;Y The effects of heat upon the twelve farm types can be most accurately studied when the High Plains, Western Sand Hills, Eastern Sand Hills, and Boyd types are looked upon as northern, the Chase, Buffalo, Custer, and Wayne types as central, and the Hitchcock, Harlan, Thayer, and Cass types as southern. Rainfall effects can be most accurately studied by comparing the Boyd, Wayne, and Cass types with the High Plains, Chase, and Hitchcock types respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Farm Types in Nebraska 63 Fig. .'!.*•. Tlie iiverafte size of farm In tlie various type areas of Nebraska (1!K*M I III- PRINCIPAL VSES OF FARM LAND Nearly all of the land in a farm can be classed as either cultivated land, wild hay land, or pasture and waste. In this study the cultivated land together with the wild hay land will be spoken of as the crop area. The difference between the total farm area and the crop area is assumed to be the area occupied by the farmstead, pasture, roads, and waste. Since the land occupied by lots, roads, and waste is often used more as pasture than as crop land it will not be far wrong to treat all of the farm area aside from crop land as simply pasture. THK \&lt; KK \i.l AND \ II I n OF CHOPS The acreage of the various crops grown on a given type of farm varies less from year to year than either the yield per acre or the total yield per farm. While yields per acre in any given area vary greatly from season to season, there is a tend - ency for the yields in all areas to vary in harmony with one </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15- 64 another. This is in part explained by the fact that effective changes in weather during the crop season often affect areas as large or even larger than the State. The last column in the following group of tables usually expresses the yield per acre in terms of percentage. Wher- ever this is done, the yield per acre on the Cass type of farm is used as a base, or 100 per cent. These percentage figures picture the normal standing of one area relative to another only in so far as yields in 1909 had the same percentage vari- ation from normal. TABLE 5. — Corn per farm in 1909. Acres Bushels Knshels Index to Type area per per per yields farm acre farm CasB = 100% Northwest to North Central High Plains 11.3 15.9 180 58 Western Sand Hills 23.4 15.6 364 57 Eastern Sand Hills 35.9 22.8 818 83 Boyd 50.6 24.0 1,215 87 Southwest to Northeast Chase 64.5 12.7 819 46 Buffalo 61.0 22.6 1,378 82 Custer 68.8 25.4 1,748 92 Wayne 68.0 36.8 2,500 133 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 48.7 9.6 468 35 Harlan ; 66.4 12.3 816 45 Thayer 59.3 18.2 1,079 66 Cass 59.8 I 27.6 1,652 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Farm Types in Nebraska 65 Table 6. — Coarse forage (largely corn and "cane") in 1909. Acres , Tons Tuns Index U Type area per per per .yields. farm acre farm Cas.t = 100CI Northwest to North Central High Plains High Plains .90 1.64 1.48 61 Western Sand Hills .51 1.76 .90 66 Eastern Sand Hills .35 2.51 .88 94 Boyd .53 2.58 1.37 97 Southwest to Northeast Chase 7.89 1.60 12.62 60 Buffalo 1.13 1.99 2.25 75 Custer .52 2.48 1.29 93 Wayne .22 3.00 .66 112 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 12.82 1.52 19.52 57 Harlan 3.68 1.77 6.51 66 Thayer .45 2.51 1.13 94 Cass .18 2.67 .48 100 Table 7. — Wheat per farm in 1909. Notice that on "hard land" the production of wheat per farm is great- est where the yields are lowest. Acres of Acres of Bushels of Bushels of Index to winter spring all wheat all wheat yields. Type ares wheat per wheat per per acre i&gt;er farm Cass — farm I farm 100&lt;* Northwest to High Plains 1.2 14.5 10.9 172 North Central W. Sand Hills ... .3 1.7 8.0 16 43 E. Sand Hills 1.6 1.3 13.4 39 71 Boyd 1.7 4.2 10.5 62 56 Southwest to Northeast Chase 12.7 15.5 11.4 320 61 Buffalo 24.4 .8 18.3 462 97 Custer 10.6 1.0 19.3 224 103 Wayne , 1.9 5.7 14.2 108 76 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 99.2 4.9 6.4 667 34 Harlan 45.6 .4 10.9 501 58 Thayer 30.2 .3 15.7 480 84 Case 13.2 3.4 18.8 312 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bid. 15 Table 8. — Oats per farm in 1909. At ret) Basket* Bushels Index t Type MM per uer per yields f.irni acre farm Cass = 1 ( 1(W lire Northwest to North Central vest to North Central High Plains 12.6 20.2 255 83 i Plains 12.6 20.2 255 83 ;ern Sand Hills 5.9 15.4 91 63 Western Sand Hills 5.9 15.4 91 63 Eastern Sand Hills 10.4 20.4 212 84 era Sand Hills 10.4 20.4 212 84 Boyd 21.3 20.0 427 82 I 21.3 20.0 427 82 Southwest to Northeast rest to Northeast Chase 3.7 20.5 76 84 :e 3.7 20.5 76 84 Buffalo 16.1 17.0 274 70 ilo 16.1 17.0 274 70 Custer 21.5 16.3 351 67 er 21.5 16.3 351 67 Wayne 35.1 25.1 880 103 ne 35.1 25.1 880 103 Southwest to Southeast rest to Southeast Hitchcock 4.2 18.6 78 7t&gt; icock 42 18.6 78 76 Harlan 8.0 20.8 166 85 an 8.0 20.8 166 85 Thayer 15.3 24.0 368 98 rer 15.3 24.0 368 98 Cass 20.7 24.4 506 100 20.7 24.4 506 100 Table 9. — Rye per farm in 1909. Table 9. — Rye per farm in 1909. Acres Itushrls Bnthela Index t. Acres Hushels KhkIicIs Iudex t Type area n«r ner per yields, Type area n«r ner per yields, farm acre farm Cass = Northwest to North Central High Plains 1.97 11.7 23 82 Western Sand Hills .82 9.8 8 69 Eastern Sand Hills 2.45 9.8 24 69 Boyd 2.31 - 9.5 22 67 Southwest to Northeast Chase .85 9.4 8 66 Buffalo .36 11.1 4 78 Custer .47 10.6 5 75 Wayne .22 10.9 ?. 77 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock .48 7.5 4 53 Harlan .22 9.1 2 64 Thayer i .04 11.0 ' 4 77 Cass 07 14.2 1 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Farm Types in Nebraska 67 x t Ida X t ■ :.u Table 10. — Barley per farm in 1909. Acres ppr BuaheU Bufbela luile Tvp. &gt;l farm re farm 1MI Northwest to North Central High Plains 1.25 17.6 22 83 Western Sand Hills .17 15.2 3 72 Eastern Sand Hills .24 14^9 4 70 .24 14.9 4 70 _ Boyd • 47 18.4 9 87 Southwest to Northeast Table 11. — Potatoes per farm in 1909. \ v. Hunlii'l? Inde ■J'yiM pt y farm re farm ( ll«l Northwest to Ncrth Centra! High Plains 3.5 54 Western Sand Hills Eastern Sand Hills Bovd 1.4 50 1.3 7-1 liit 50 62 72 79 " *~j *~— Southwest to Southeast Hitchccck .■so Harlan Thayer Case .. 50 7K ss 188 61 70 57 96 84 47 78 Southwest to Northeast Cha=e .6 Buffalo * .6 Custer .6 Wayne .7 30 57 37 70 43 82 55 90 25 57 30 57 39 80 53 100 .6 .6 .5 .6 Chase Buffalo Custer Wayne louthwest to Southeast Hitchcock Harlan Thayer Cass 8.07 .22 .85 2.07 19.00 .30 .10 .17 17.6 15.6 14.1 18.8 13.7 13.1 20.4 21.2 142 :i 12 :« 260 4 2 4 «:i 74 66 Kit 65 •52 96 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 TABLE 12. — Millet per farm in 1909. Acres Tons Tons Index to Type area _per per per yields, farm acre farm (.'ass — 100% Northwest to North Central High Plains „... 1.90 1.16 2.20 59 Western Sand Hills .49 1.22 .60 62 Eastern Sand Hills .62 1.61 1.00 82 High Plains .62 1.61 1.00 82 Boyd ...^ _.._ Southwest to Northeast _- _— .77 1.64 1.26 84 Chase 3.70 1.18 4.36 60 Buffalo _ .72 1.63 1.17 83 Custer _ .94 1.65 1.55 84 Wayne .55 2.18 1.20 111 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 2.56 1.29 3.31 66 Hartan _ 1.97 1.50 2.96 77 Thayer _ .65 1.85 1.20 94 Cass | .25 1.96 .49 100 Table 13. — Alfalfa per farm in 1909. Acres Tons Tons i Index to Type area Type area per per ' per yields, farm acre farm Cass = 100% Northwest to North Central orthwest to North Central High Plains 4.30 2.07 8.90 73 High Plains &lt; 4.30 2.07 8.90 73 Western Sand Hills 1.15 2.06 2.37 73 Western Sand Hilte 1.15 2.06 2.37 73 Eastern Sand Hills 2.05 1.91 3.91 67 Eastern Sand Hills 2.05 1.91 3.91 67 Boyd _ 3.50 1.47 5.16 52 Southwest to Northeast Chase 1.75 2.05 3.58 72 Buffalo 11.64 2.19 25.50 77 Custer 12.30 1.87 23.00 66 Wayne ! 2.00 I 2.65 5.30 93 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 5.05 2.02 10.18 71 Harlan ... 10.15 1.69 17.06 60 Thayer I 6.18 2.36 14.61 83 Cass 1.59 2.84 4.52 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Farm Types in Nebraska 69 Table 14. — Timothy and clover per farm in 1909. Acres Tons Tons Index to Type area per per per yields, per farm farm acre f»rm Cass = j 100% Northwest to North Central Hig-h Plains .03 2.00 .06 130 .03 2.00 .06 130 Western Sand Hills .35 1.69 .59 110 .35 1.69 .59 110 Eastern Sand Hills 98 1.30 1.27 84 .98 1.30 1.27 84 Boyd 2.27 1.33 3.03 86 2.27 1.33 3.03 86 Southwest to Northeast Chase 749 1.31 "64 S5 .54 1.31 .71 85 Buffalo .49 1.31 .64 S'&gt; Custer .54 1.31 .71 S5 Wayne 6.03 1.65 9.98 107 6.03 1.65 9.98 107 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock ' !b2 TOO ".02 65 '&lt;"" 2.49 1.33 3.30 86 Harlan 02 1.00 .02 65 Thayer 2.49 1.33 3.30 86 Cass 5.27 1.54 8.12 100 5.27 1.54 8.12 100 Table 15. — Wild hay per farm in 1909. hay per farm in 1909. Acres ' Tons Tons Index to Icres Tons Tons Index t per per per yields Type area per per per yields, farm acre farm Cass = 1W&amp; Northwest to North Central High Plains 40.7 .65 26.4 42 Western Sand Hills 145.0 .82 119.0 54 Eastern Sand Hills ' 88.4 .88 77.5 58 Boyd | 86.1 1.03 88.5 67 Southwest to Northeast Chase I 10.9 .82 8.9 54 Buffalo 19.4 1.15 22.3 75 Custer 24.5 .92 22.5 60 Wayne 16.2 1.48 23.9 97 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 4.7 .98 , 4.6 64 Harlan 9.9 .88 8.7 58 Thayer 7.2 1.17 8.4 76 Cass 8.8 1.53 13.5 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Table 16. — Apple trees per farm and also the approximate per cent of all land covered with woods (1909). ■ X a S Type area X x z. THE HARVEST VALl'K OF CROPS The census reports the value of crops grown on crop land, but does not report the value of pasture growth. If the value of plant growth on one type of farm is to be compared with the value of plant growth on another type of farm, pas - ture must be included. Furthermore, the value assigned to pasture growth must be comparable with the value assigned to crop growth. Since the census gives to crops what might be termed a harvest value (Table 17), it will be necessary to compute a similar value for pasture (Table 18). In com - puting the so-called harvest value of pasture it was assumed that the acreage of pasture per farm multiplied by the average value of all land would give a fair index to the total value of pasture land, and that 5 per cent of the total would not be far from the actual harvest value of pasture per farm. If it had been possible, however, the average value of pas - ture land would have been used in the place of the average value of all land and T% per cent (three times what is approxi - mately the actual rent) would have been used in the place of 5 per cent. I &lt; £-5 * Northwest to North Centra] High Plains Western Sand Hills Eastern Sand Hills Boyd Southwest to Northeast Chase Buffalo Custer Wayne Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock Harlan Thayer Cass 42 1.08 5.64 9.76 1.27 9.55 11.40 14.70 1.90 9.60 35.40 55.30 .40 .03 .51 .94 .21 .96 .59 1.53 .20 .45 .77 1.40 .17 .03 2.88 9.16 .27 9.20 6.70 22.50 .38 4.33 27.40 77.40 1.90 .40 1.07 2.92 .31 1.68 m 2.35 .49 1.34 2.68 4.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Farm Types in Nebraska 71 Table 17. — The harvest value per farm of all crops grown f &gt;n crop land in 1909. X — 9 hi £"SiE u Type area Z. " S r / tl U.^ Northwest to North Central High Plains $744 61 39 $7.45 54 W. Sand Hills .. 732 44 56 3.95 29 E. Sand Hills .... 911 68 32 6.00 43 Boyd 1,185 71 29 6.50 47 Southwest to Northeast Chase 1,004 86 14 7.50 54 Buffalo 1,582 81 19 11.45 83 Custer 1,544 82 18 10.65 77 Wayne 1,939 87 13 13.70 99 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 1,261 86 14 6.15 45 Harlan 1,199 83 17 8.05 58 Thayer 1,718 88 12 13.80 100 Cass 1,612 88 12 13.80 100 TABLE 18. — The estimated harvest value of pasture per farm in 1909. siu hi 'I'M* rf Northwest to (1) (2) (3) (4) North Central High Plains $9.89 1029 $10,180 $509 W. Sand Hills 4.66 1596 • 7,437 372 E. Sand Hills 10.10 707 7,141 357 Boyd 22.73 409 9,297 465 ■Southwest to Northwest Chase ' 11.06 698 7,720 386 Buffalo 49.10 122 5,990 300 Custer ' 34.83 200 6,966 348 Wayne 69.50 87 6,046 302 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock I 15.67 469 7,349 368 Harlan ..........._ 35.40 130 4,602 230 Thayer ".". 74.60 60 4,476 224 Cass 86.90 54 4,639 232 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 72 Table 19. — Value of crop and pasture growth per farm, in 1909 u &amp;H L* 5% 9 •" CO «- x i ~ «vi *j w »_ O OP &gt; „, O a l. u Co U Type area P( HI Northwest to North Central nigh Plains... $509 $ .49 $1253 $1.11 11 W. Sand Hills E. Sand Hills.. Boyd 372 .23 .62 13 1.48 15 2.79 12 357 .50 465 1.14 Southwest to Northeast Chase Buffalo Cuateir Wayne Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock Harlan ... Thayer Cass .. CROP INDEXES In 1909 the Hitchcock type of farm produced on 48.70 acres as many bushels of corn as the Cass type of farm pro - duced on 16.94 acres.* According to this ratio 100 acres of corn in the Hitchcock area would have produced as much as 34.77 acres in the Cass area. In Farm Management this statement would commonly read — the crop index of corn land in the Hitchcock area is 34.77 per cent of that in the Cass area. Table 20 illustrates the method of determining the crop index of the cultivated land, the crop land, and the farm as a whole. It will be observed that according to this calculation 'Representative counties in tbe Cass area — Cass, Dodge. Johnson, Otoe. Paw - nee. Saunders. and Washington Counties produced 21,977,553 bushels of corn on 795.719 acres. Acres per farm reporting domestic animals, 59.82. Bushels per farm. 1,662. Tield per acre, 27.02 bushels. (1906) Representative oonnttes in Hitchcock area — Hitchcock county in Nebraska and Logan, Rawlins, Sheridan, and Thomas Counties in Kansas produced 2,082.805 bushels of corn on 214.529 acres. Acres per farm reporting domestic animals, 46.70. Bushels per farm, MB. Yield per acre, 9.61 bushels. (1908) 386 .55 300 2.46 348 1.74 302 3.51 1.67 15 7.24 15 5.48 16 9.79 14 368 .78 1629 2.42 15 230 1.77 1429 5.13 ; 14 224 3.73 1942 10.55 14 232 4.30 1844 10.78 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Farm Types in Nebraska 73 200.12 acres of cultivated land in the Hitchcock area were about equivalent in 1909 to 83.19 acres of cultivated land in the Cass area. It is readily seen that this is a ratio of 100 acres to 41.6 acres, and that the crop index of the Hitchcock culti - vated land must therefore be 41.6 per cent. Wild hay occupies such a small acreage on the Hitchcock type of farm that there is little difference between the area of cultivated land and the area of crop land. This being true, it is not surprising to find that the crop index of crop land measures very nearly the same as the crop index of the culti - vated land. The value of land is here assumed to be in harmony with the normal yield of native pasture grasses. (Field studies in many parts of the State indicate that this is in general true.) If the inventory of live stock and the use of pasture in one area could have been directly compared with the in - ventory of live stock and the use of pasture in another area, the carrying capacity of the land rather than its value would have been used as an index to pasture yields. When pasture land is added to crop land the index to yields is decidedly lowered. This is especially true of western areas where the greatest difference exists between the quantity of plant growth on the land selected for crops and the quantity of plant growth on the land left for pasture. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">Bye *0.4£ A 4 bu. 14.22 bu. I 0.28 A Winter wheat ».2O A (All wheat) (All wheat) (All wheat) Spring wheat 4.86 A 687 bu. 18.81 bu. 35.45 A Oats — 4.16 A 78 bu. 24.43 bu. 3.19 A Barley lft.OO A 200 bu. 21.23 bu. 12.25 A Emmer _ 1.09 A 21 bu. W.83 hu. 1.25 A 1.0B A 21 bu. W.83 hu. 1.2S A Grains cut green_ 0.19 A 0.18 T 1.37 T ' .13 A Potatoes 0.50 A 25 bu. 88.00 bu. .28 A Corn _ 48.70 A 468 bu 27«2 bu. 16.94 A 48.70 A 468 bu 27«2 bu. 16.94 A Millet 2.56 A 3.31 T 1.96 T 1j8B A Kafir 0.8T A 8.80 bu. Jfl.17 bu. .64, A Cane 0.21 A 0.28 T 3.45 T .08 T Coarse Forage _ 12.82 A 19.25 T Timothy _ „ 2.67 T 7.32 A 1.52 T Timothy and clover 1.54 T Clocer 0.20 A 0.20 T 1.49 T .IS A Alfalfa 5.05 A 10.1H T 2.S4 T 3.58 A Other tame grasses 0.11 A 0.11 T 1.47 T .08 A •The acreage of pasture in the Hitchcock type of farm (469.00A) is to be equivalent acreage of pasture in the Cass type of farm (85.50A) as the price of land in the Cass area ($85.90) is to the price of land in the Hitchcock area (S15.67.) 4 Nebraskc Expent nent Stan )« Research Bui. 15 'ABLE 20. — Th ? calculm he Cass i ion of Hii ype of far chcock crop indexes using n as a basis. (1) (f) (3) (4) T « ij e ■ -= C d 5* II. 2!« (5) (« ! I* n £ = £ -- a II ii!3 "3 c - I Iff in a 'ru Total 20(1.12 A 83.19 A cultivated land Index 41.6% Wild hay ... 4.66 A 4.6 T 1.53 T 2.99 A Total 21H.78 A 86.18 A Crop land index 42.1% Pasture . 46U.00 A 85.50 A* Total . 873.78 A 171.6R A | Crop and pasture land Index 26.5 % </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Farm Types in Nebraska 75 Table 21. — What were approximately equivalent acreages in 1909. Cultivated land Crop l»n&lt;l Crop! mil pasture Type nrea !| Hi! ; || mi II |{j| X ■ *-• &lt;a Higb Plains Jigb Plains... _ SO 40.4 100 :,7.7 112!l KPTi High Plains. _ 5© 40.4 W. Sand Hills 40 23.8 E. Sand Hills 63 51.0 V. Sand Hlllg 40 23.8 1*5 I 101.5 1781 1SK.2 :. Sand Hills 63 51.0 152 102.0 850 1HM loyd &lt;»0 T.s.'i 1S2 13C.J ."^H 244.5 Koyil Southwest to Northeast itliwest to Northeast Chase hase 122 h7.!&gt; 133 7:i&gt; 831 1«3 5 122 f.T.'.' 133 -:;&gt; 831 It8 5 tuffalo .. 1111 !ts&gt; 138 113.1 260 1S1.0 HufTalo mi !is&gt; ("lister •uster 121 102.9 145 117.1 34T» 1!KO 121 MK.8 Wayne \ayne 126 118.0 142 183.5 229 23S.5 126 I »S.O *» JIVIIC Southwest to Southeast ithwest to Southeast Hitchcock IJtclK-uck 200 S3.2 205 S6.2 674 171.7 Hiirlnn Inrlan 13S 74.1 14* 79.9 278 133.9 rhayer 117 W.8 124 95.1 184 147.0 Thayer Casg (the base) :a»g (the bane) 1(» 108.0 117 117.0 171 171.0 •The value of land cnnnot be judged from such equivalent acreages as appt •The value of land cnnnot be judged from such equivalent acreages as appear in this table. In some cases the lo-called equivalent acreage of 4'itss land is made up largely of pasture anil wild hay nnd in other cases it contains a large share of cultivated land. For example, the 17sl-acre farm in the Western Sand Hills appears to lie equivalent to lf-h acres of iivntp lam! in the t'ass area. This is li acres greater than the average Cam* farm. When one stops to consider, how - ever, that the equivalent acreage of (ass land (1W ncresi is made &gt;ip uf Zi acres of good cultivated land in the Cags area. 7n acres of Cass wild hay laud, ami acres of Cass pasture land, It is readily seen that it is not equivalent to an equal acreage of average land in the Cass area. Furthermore, in studying the equivalent acreages given above it must be borne in mind that it is more ex - pensive to harvest a given quantity of a crop where yields are low than where yields are high and also that where farms are large the distance to market i* greatly increased. this table. In some cases the lo-called equivalent acreage of ('ass land is ml largely of pasture anil wild hay nnd in other cases It contains a large sbi cultivated land. For example, the 17sl-acre farm in the Western Sand Hi |&gt;ears to lie equivalent tn IS** acres of avmgr land in the C.iss area. This acres greater than the average Cam* farm. When one stops to consider, ho ■r. that the equivalent acreage of lass land (IN** acres* is maile &gt;ip of 23 acre* od cultivated land in the Cass area. 78 acres of Cass wild hay land, ami res of ('ass pasture land, it is readily seen that it is not equivalent to jul acreage of average land in the ("ass area. Furthermore, in studying i uivalent acreages given above it must be borne in mind that it is more &lt; nslve to harvest a given quantity of a crop where yields are low than wh. &gt;lds are high and also that where farms are large the distance to market eatly Increased. Table 22. — Crop indexes in 1909* TABLE 22. — Crop indexes in 1909* Crop index of Crop index of Crop index of cultivated land, crop land. the farm area. Cass = l!)0', Cas« = 100% Cass = 100% Crop index of Crop Index of t'rop index Type area Type area cultivated land, crop land. the farm arei Cass = 100'; i».&lt; = liii'; 0888 = 100% Northwest to North Centra' High Plains rthwest to North Centra' High Plains 68.5% 57.7&lt;7r 15.0tt Western Sand Hills 59.5 54.8 10.6 Western Sand Hills 59.5 54.8 10.6 Eastern Sand Hills 80.9 67.1 21.5 Eastern Sand Hills 80.9 67.1 21.5 Boyd 82.2 75.0 41.4 Boyd 82.2 75.0 41.4 Southwest to Northeast mthwest to Northeast Chase 55.6 55.4 19.7 Chase 55.6 55.4 19.7 Buffalo 83.0 82.0 70.4 Buffalo 83.0 82.0 70.4 Custer 86.0 80.8 57.4 Custer 86.0 80.8 57.4 Wayne 117.4 115.0 102.0 Wayne 117.4 115.0 102.0 Southwest to Southeast rathwest to Southeast Hitchcock 41.6 42.1 25.5 Hitchcock 41.6 42.1 25.5 Harlan 53.7 54.0 48.2 Thayer 76.7 76.7 79.9 Cass 100.0 100.0 100.0 •The equivalent acreage divided by the actual acreage. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 76 Table 23. — Cows on hand April 15, 1910, and the production of milk and butter for the calendar year 1909 ! M — u i e n id a« w£ Type area t- t. * I I *— eg, S£ as. &lt;9« r3 a §1 ii i • 55 -? Northwest to North Central High Plains 3.7 12.7 ! 837 145 Western Sand Hills 3.7 27.3 789 140 Eastern Sand Hills 5.6 8.2 1113 150 Boyd 6.7 9.2 1423 190 Southwest to Northeast Chase ..._ 3.8 5.7 ! 725 137 Buffalo 5.5 4,8 1660 184 Cnster _ 5.1 6.6 1270 191 Wayne I 5.7 4.9 11440 246 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 4.8 2.7 1014 142 Harlan 4.7 3.3 1160 192 Thayer 4.3 2.2 1149 184 Cass I 4.7 3.2 1337 I 241 •"Milk produced represents all the milk produced during tbe year (ex cept that fed directly, without being skimmed, to calves, pigs, etc., on the farm) even tho a portion or all of such milk is converted into butter or cheese and re ported under these items." Table 24. — Cattle other than cows on hand April 15, 1910. Yearling Spring Yearling I Other Type area heifers calves steers steers per per per and farm farm farm bulls per farm Northwest to North Central High Plains ' 4.2 3.7 3.9 8.4 Western Sand HiHe 8.0 6.9 8.1 16.4 Eastern Sand Hill* 3.6 4.0 4.0 6.0 Boyd I 4.6 5.3 6.0 9.3 Southwest to Northeast Chase _ \ 2.4 2.4 2.4 4.1 Buffalo 3.0 3.1 2.8 4.0 Custer &gt; 3.3 3.4 3.5 4.4 Wayne 3.1 3.1 3.0 4.8 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 2.0 2.3 1.8 2.4 Harlan 2.3 2.5 2.1 1.9 Thayer i 1.8 2.0 1.6 1.8 Cass I 2.3 2.3 2.0 2.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Farm Types in Nebraska 77 Table 25. — Total number and value of cattle on hand April 15, 1910, and the number sold or slaughtered during the calendar year 1909. Total number Value of Number of Type area of cattle cattle per cattle sold per farm farm or slaughtered Northwest to North Central High Plains 36.6 $939 14.8 Western Sand Hilte 70.4 1910 24.3 Eastern Sand Hills 31.4 756 11.3 Boyd 41.1 1000 15.4 Southwest to Northeast Chase 20.8 475 8.6 Buffalo 23.2 584 11.6 Custer 26.3 647 12.3 Wayne _ 24.6 623 11.5 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock I 16.0 351 6.0 Harlan 16.8 393 7.8 Thayer 13.7 337 6.5 Cass , I 16.5 407 7.5 Table 26. — Horses and mules on hand April 15, 1910. Mature Yearling Mature | Yearling Type area horses per i horses per mules per mules per farm farm farm farm — h Northwest to North Central High Plains 9.6 1.7 0.2 0.1 Western Sand Hills 10.8 1.7 0.3 0.1 Eastern Sand Hills 6.6 0.8 0.4 0.1 Boyd _ 7.6 0.9 0.5 0.1 Southwest to Northeast Chase 7.9 1.0 0.7 0.2 Buffalo 6.9 0.8... 0.4 0.1 Custer 7.7 1.0 0.4 I 0.1 Wayne 6.8 0.6 ft 2 0.0 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 7.6 1.0 0.7 0.2 Harten 6.6 0.8 I 0.8 0.2 Thayer 5.8 0.6 0.7 0.1 Cass 5.8 0.5 0.6 0.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Table 27. — The total number and value of horses and mules and also the approximate number and value of tvork animals (1910). Type area -o|8 •- i. ' &lt;&gt;£.= Northwest to North Central High Plains 11.6 $1022 8.0 $760 Western Sand Hills 12.9 1058 9.3 809 Eastern Sand Hills 7.9 723 6.1 586 Boyd 9.1 940 7.1 767 Southwest to Northeast Chase 9.8 971 7.4 770 Buffalo 8.2 993 6.4 742 Custer 9.2 971 7.0 777 777 Wayne 7.7 923 6.5 795 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 9.5 942 7.1 738 Harlan 8.4 895 6.4 710 Thayer 7.2 846 5.8 650 Cass 7.0 807 5.8 677 •The total number of horses and mules minus twice tlie mnulier of yearling horses ami mules leaves approximately the numiier of work animals. tThe total value of horses and mules divided )&gt;y the total number of horse units and mule units (one mature animal or two yearlinjjsi irivi-s approximately the value of one work ■■!— I This value per head multiplied by the number of work animals gives the approximate value of all work animals. Table 28. — Hogs and corn per farm. Mature Hogs gold ' Itushels Hushels Type area lions per or slaush- of corn of corn farm. tered during raised per per hog April 15. 1910 year 1900 farm WOO unit* ■f Northwest to North Central Hiph Plains I 2.5 3.9 180 202 Western Sand Hills ! 3.2 8.1 364 251 Eastern Sand Hills 7.3 10.2 818 330 Boyd 14.4 17.5 1215 262 Southwest to Northeast Chase I 9.9 12.5 819 253 Buffalo 18.9 26.7 1378 214 Custer 22.6 29.4 1748 231 Wayne 25.9 28.8 2500 310 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 6.4 11.2 468 195 Harlan 13.9 23.5 816 159 Thayer 13.6 21.8 1079 220 Cass 15.4 21.8 1652 316 •Mature hoes on hand April 15, 1910. plus one-half of the hogs sold or slaughtered during the year 19(10 and this sum divided by five gives the approxi- mate number of hog units. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Farm Types in Nebraska 79 Table 29. — Poultry raised and eggs produced in 1909. Number Ktrgs , Approxi- Approxl - of poultry produced EjruR mate mate raised per farm I Bold numlicrof number of Table 30. — Approximate number of productive animal units per farm.* Cuttle Hog Sheep Poultry I'ro - uuits units unit* unii- ductlre Type area per farm per farm per farm per farm horse units per farm Northwest to North Central High Plains 28.85 0.89 1.60 0.53 2.70 Western Sand Hills.. 55.45 1.45 0.60 0.54 2.70 Eastern Sand Hills. 23.60 2.48 0.19 0.66 1.35 Boyd 30.50 4.63 0.10 0.88 1.50 Southwest to Northeast Chase 16.00 3.23 0.06 0.78 1.80 Buffalo 17.20 6L45 0.60 1.11 1.35 19.50 7.56 0.19 0.95 1.65 Custer Wayne ; 18.45 8.06 0.19 1.13 0.96 Southwest to Southeast mthwest to Southeast Hitchcock ■ 11.80 2.40 0.30 0.97 1.80 Hitchcock ! 11.80 2.40 0.30 0.97 1.80 Harlan 12.10 5.13 0.10 1.30 1.50 Harlan 12.10 5.13 0.10 1.30 1.50 Thayer ! 10.00 4.90 0.10 1.42 1.05 Cass i 12.05 5.22 0.11 1.31 0.87 *.\M live stock aside from work iiuimals arc here classed as productive. In calculating the number of animal units, the number of sprint; ciilves. spring colts spring pigs, etc., are omitted. * if other jinin»:iN, one cow, two yearling heifers. one horse, two yearling colts, five ho^s, seven sheep, or one hundred head of poultry, are uxed as one animal unit. Type im ype hthii per farm Dozen t'irus used eggs used in seitiiii.'* in the home Dozen Dozen Dozen Northwest to North Central High Plains Western Sand Hills.. Eastern Sand Hills... Boyd Southwest to 53 54 66 88 238 137 163 252 131 9 98 43 9 85 73 11 79 138 15 99 Chase 78 283 175 Buffalo Ill 357 211 Custer 95 275 136 Wayne 113 409 261 louthwest to Southeast Hitchcock 97 332 220 Harlan 130 439 303 Thayer 142 434 285 Cass 131 387 234 13 IK 16 19 16 21 23 22 95 128 123 129 96 115 12S 131 'Two pgfi Allowed f»»r etirh hrail &lt;&gt;f poultry mist'* I. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Table 31. — The approximate total number of animal units per farm in 1909. Productive Units of Total number Type area animal work I of animal unlti stock units Northwest to North Central High Plains 34.6 8.0 42.6 Western Sand Hilto. 60.7 9.3 70.0 Eastern Sand Hflls. 28.3 6.1 34.4 Boyd _ i 37.6 7.1 44.7 Southwest to Northeast Cham _ _ 21.8 7.4 29.3 Buffalo _ 26.7 6.4 33.1 Custer ..._ 29.8 7.0 36.8 Wayne 28.8 &amp;5 35.3 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock _ 17.3 7.1 24.4 Harlan ..._ - , 20.1 fl.4 26.5 Thayer 17.5 5.8 23.3 Cass I 19.6 5.8 25.4 Table 32. — The approximate division of live-stock capital productive between stock and work animals. =a Jo j£ a &gt;5 = 5 ! «* te fill Type area Narthwest to North Central High Plains $2084 $760 $1324 ! 64*&gt; Western Sand Hill* 3090 809 2281 74 Eastern Sand Hills. 1624 586 1038 64 Boyd I 2188 767 1421 65 Southwest to Northeast Chase ' 1616 770 846 52 Buffalo j 1849 742 1107 60 CtMter I 1998 777 1221 61 Wayne ' 1984 795 1189 60 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock I 1429 738 691 48 Harlan I 1543 710 824 54 Thayer I 1440 650 790 ! 55 Caw 1510 ' 677 833 ! 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Farm Types in Nebraska 81 Table 33. — Receipts from live stock in 1909. Receipts' Value i Value Value Value Total from of ')f dairy of of receipts Type area the sale animals pro- poultry wool from of slaught- ducts* and eggs i pro- live animals , ered &lt; produced i duced stock Northwest to North Central High Plains *636 $43 $54 *66 *20 *81P Western Sand Hills.^ . »34 32 48 13 6 1063 Eastern Sand Hills... 900 27 87 50 1 746 Boyd . — _. 80S 3» 92 70 1 1010 Southwest to Northeast Chase „ 442 32 41 . 77 1 593 Buffalo - 997 42 96 102 4 12« Custer _ 1012 3fi 78 79 1 1206 Wayne _.- 1030 49 96 100 1 1294 1 1206 1030 40 96 10B 1 1284 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock _ 4*2 41 «2 86 0 053 Harlan 718 39 74 117 1 048 Thayer 084 42 73 129 1 926 Cas« tea 45 84 129 1 962 1 902 •The census omits here the milk and cream used in the home. Table 34. — Labor hired in 1909* Per cent of, Cash spent Wages farms re- per farms Value of nnd board Type area porting reporting board per farm labor hired labor hired furnished reporting in 1909 labor hired Northwest to North Central High Plains 38.7 $192 $64 $256 Western Sand Hills \ 37.5 319 82 401 Eastern Sand Hilli 38.1 173 46 219 Boyd 43.6 181 54 235 Southwest to Northeast Chase _ - 37.8 162 54 216 Buffalo 47.0 184 59 243 Custer 44.0 179 61 240 Wayne 55.0 202 68 270 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 60.0 182 41 223 Harlan 54.0 215 41 256 Thayer , 54.0 149 47 196 Ca» ! 49.0 180 52 232 •According to field studies the average farm in Nebraska requires about 20 montlis of man Tabor per year. As a rule the operator contributes 12 months, bis boys or other members of his family the equivalent of R months, and hired labor about 3 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Table 35. — A calculation of the value per acre of such land as was not reported in Hi the census. (1909). £ s •* if* Type area f || |«| jf- 1^* &gt;S2 *-&amp; «^g 5&amp;=c Ji|i| &lt;£« Not &gt;e* &lt;tc; „ =.^: i- Northweat to North Central High. Plains 746 66.0 $11.18 383 A $7.38 Western Sand Hills 859 48.0 6.38 922 3.06 Eastern Sand Hills 629 73.0 10.88 230 7.94 Boyd _ 549 77.5 23.10 42 17.90 Southwest to Northeast Chase 502 60.4 13.12 329 7.92 Buffalo 240 92.3 49.40 20 45.60 Custer 316 91.3 35.10 29 32.06 Wayne 213 93.0 69.90 16 65.01 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 531 79.0 16.40 143 12.95 Harlan 264 95.0 35.50 14 33.72 Thayer 178 36.4 74.80 6 72.10 Cass 164 96.0 86.10 7 82.66 'The value of land not reported is here made to hear tin- same relation to the value of land reported as the per cent of land reported bears to 10!) per cent of all laud. Table 36. — Approximate value of land per farm in 1910. Total value Onloulated Approxi- Approxi of tbe land total value mate him tc value Type area reported of the land total per acre of In the not value of nil lallil census reported all land Northwest to North Central High Plains $8,340 $2,826 $11,166 $9 39 Western Sand Hills 5.480 2.821 8,301 4.66 Eastern Sand HUls 6,844 1,826 8,670 10.10 Boyd 12,682 752 13,434 22.73 Southwest to Northeast Chase 6,586 2,606 9,192 11.06 Buffalo 11,856 .912 12,768 49.10 Custer 11,092 .929 12,021 34.83 Wayne 14,889 1,040 15,929 69.50 Southwest to Southeast Harlan 9,372 472 9,844 35.40 Hitchcock 8,708 1,852 10,560 15.67 Thayer 13,314 433 13,747 74.60 Cass 14,120 578 14,698 85.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Farm Types in Nebraska 83 Table 37. — Capital in live stock, machinei-y, buildings, and land (1910). Value of Value of Value of .\pproxi - live (took machinery buildings mute value Type area per farm per firm ; per farm uf land per farm Northwest to North Central Table 38. — The approximate amount of capital per farm in 1910. Total Total rapital capital Type per farm per acre Northwest to North Central High Plains $14,555 $12.90 12,408 7.00 Western Sand Hills Eastern Sand Hills Boyd 7.00 11.447 13.30 17,243 29.20 Southwest to Northeast Qhase 11.987 14.40 Buffalo 16.541 63.60 Custer 15,765 45.60 Wayne 20,318 88.70 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 13.277 19.70 Harlan 12.935 46.50 Thayer _'.'.' 17.136 93.10 Cass "..'.'.......... 18.457 108.00 Higrh Plains Western Sand Hills Eastern Sand Hills Boyd icuthwest to Northwest Chase Buffalo Custer Wayne (Outhwest to Southeast Hitch.-ock Harlan Thayer Cass $2,084 3,090 1,624 2,188 1,616 1,849 1,998 1,984 1,42? 1,534 1,440 1,510 $290 215 235 334 294 366 327 423 350 306 358 362 $1,015 802 918 1,287 885 1,558 1,419 1,982 938 1,251 1,591 1,887 $11,166 8,301 8,670 13,434 9,192 12,768 12,021 15,929 10,560 9.844 13,747 14,698 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bui. 15 Table 39. — The nativity of farm operators. Per cent I'er cent Type area native foreign born Northwest to North Central High Plains 78 22 Western Sand Hills 86 15 Eastern Sand Hills _ 87 13 Boyd I 72 28 Southeast to Northeast Chase 86 14 Buffalo 70 30 Custer 86 15 Wayne _ 61 39 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 81 19 Harian 81 19 Thayer 73 27 OasB 69 31 Table 40. — Degree of ownership. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent of farms I of farm* of farm? of farms Type area operated j operated operated operated bj by by by strictly part tenants managers owners owners Northwest to North Central High Plain* ..._ „ 75 15 9 1 Western Sand Hilta. 83 13 3 1 Eastern Sand Hills 68 19 12 1 Boyd 49 23 27 1 Southwest to Northeast Chase 56 28 17 0 Buffalo _ 45 15 39 1 Carter 45 17 38 1 Wayne _ 44 13 42 1 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 35 38 26 1 Harian 38 22 40 0 Thayer 39 15 45 1 Cam 42 13 44 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Farm Types in Nebraska 85 Table 41. — The forms of tenancy. Per cent Per cent Per cent of tenants classed not Type area classed as at strictly classified share and cash share-cash tenants Northwest to North Central High Plains 48% 27% 25% 24 Western Sand Hills 52 24 Eastern Sand Hills 65 16 19 Boyd 70 23 7 Southwest to Northeast Chase 82 5 Buffalo 80 13 13 7 Custer 77 13 10 Wayne ' 50 45 5 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock _... 85 4 11 Harlan 89 6 6 Thayer 85 11 4 Cass 60 35 5 Table 42. — A calculation of the average distance from farm to town. Average Calculated Calculated number diameter average of sections of trade distance of land terrltoryt to town't per town* I Type area Northwest to North Central Sq. Miles Miles Miles High Plains 825 | 32 11.4 Western Sand Hills 1514 44 15.5 Eastern Sand Hills 1170 39 13.6 Boyd 284 1» 6.7 Southwest to Northeast Chase 444 24 8.4 Buffalo _ _ 120 12 4.4 Custer 201 16 5.6 Wayne 108 12 4.1 Southwest to Southeast Hitchcock 439 I 24 8.3 Harlan - 154 , 14 5.0 Thayer -... 81 10 3.6 Cass _ 59 9 3.1 'Sections of land in the counties chosen to represent a type area divided by the number of towns contained t'l'lic square root of the quantity obtained by dividing- the average number of KCHtions per town by 0.TW5. •tTlie square root of the. quantity obtained by dividing one-balf of the aver- age number of sections per town by 3.1416. [11-13-'18— 3M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>