<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0067.0001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FORTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1928-02-01">1928-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1 927-1 928 VOLUME 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE HEW YORK \ PUBLIC ÜBBARY 70685*7 A ASTOR. LENOX AND TILDEN FOUNDATIONS, . R «3* U </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS VOLUME 5 1. Agricultural Experiment Station, Annual Reports, 1927, 1928. a. •Bulletins, Noa. 214-216, 218, 219, 221-223, 225-227. b. 'Research Bulletins, Nos. 33-37, 39-42. c. Circulars, Nos. 34-36. 2. Fire Commission, Annual Reports, 1927, 1928. 3. Board of Control, Biennial Report, 1926-1927. •Bulletins, Nob. 217, 220, 224, not available tor binding. •Research Bulletins, Nob. 32, 38, not available for binding. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA ■ .-■•■■•■• .- 'i ■ ■■■•■,■■ ■ FORTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1928 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ' U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I.KTTKK OF TRANS.MITTAL TIIK !Nl\l.KSlT\-(iK N'KIiKASKA A&lt;;kli i !.n K\[. K.XI'KKIMKNT STATION' To His h' v, i.'i,,,,/, .\,/,,,r McMiiUm, finrn-iinr &lt;,f S'rhraskd: Silt: In ;n • . iiiaiict with the acl of Congress approved March 2. \M7, ami tlv an of the (^m-ral Assembly of the State ni Ni-ln-itr-kit. apiu-uv.-d Marcli :11. 1887. establishing and rt-jruliit in&gt;r '•xin-rimciii «?aii«ni*. 1 have the honor here - with to Milimj 1 tin Ki.ffv ■'•■&gt;&lt; AiMiuai l\c|Hirt of tlu- Agricul - tural Hxp.riiueiii Sia:ion n|' NelirasKa. W. W. BIRR, Fel)niar\ 1. !'r_&gt; .lr//,,,, Dirtrtnr. UUVKKNOK'S I'KkTIFI('AT.K ST\TK OK XKIiKASKA. XXXi ITIVK IfKi'AKTMKNT Lincoln. Fi'liruary 1. 1928. .I//-. IT. If. /)'//;;■. Aitiiij/ /)■',-, c/nr \, I, mskn Affricidtural h xpi n dii ut Slut mi/ : Sir: I hereliy acknowledge receipt ol the Forty-first An - nual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Ne - braska. Adam McMullen, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA . • THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Members Term Expires Harry DeWitt Landis, Seward, President January, 1929 William P. Warner, Dakota City ; :..... January, 1929 John Robinson Webster, Omaha ; January, 1931 Earl Clinß, Lincoln '. i ~ January, 1931 Stanley D. Long, Cowles '. „..'. January, 1933 Frank J. Taylor, St. Pau1............ 1.... January, 1933 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Acting Chancellor *L. E. Gunderson, Finance Secretary • ■ THE STATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Act nig Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service R. P.. Crawford, M.A., Agricultural Editor W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. ACKERSON, Ph.D., Assistant m Agricultural Chemistry Arthur Anderson, B.Sc, Assistant m Agronomy M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry (Chairman) E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. m E.E., Associate m Agricultural Engineering E. M. Brousb, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Valentine W. W. Burr, B.Sc; Agronomy (Chairman) H. P. Davis, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Associate m Dairy Husbandry H. C. FiLLEY, A.M., Rural Economics (Chairman) R. W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate pi Plant Pathology H. J. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) Greta Gray, Ph.D., Associate m Home Economics I. L. Hathaway, M.Sc, Assistant m Dairy Husbandry Harold Hedges, A.M., Assistant m Rural Economics J. A. Holden, B.Sc.,- Supt. Experimental Substation, Mitchell T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy I -. E. B. Lewis, B.Sc. m A.E;, Assistant m Agriciiltural Engineering W. J. Loeffel, B.Sc, Assistant m Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, B.Sc.' m Agr., Assistant mi Agronomy H. M.. Martin, V.M.D., Ph.D., Assistant m Animal Pathology and Hygiene R. F. Morgan, B.Sc, Assistant m Dairy Husbandry / F. E: Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) J, F. Olney, D.V.M., M.5.,. -Assistant m Animal Pathology G. L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) J. O. Ranki'n, A.M., 'Associate m Rural Economics J. C. Russel, M.Sc.,- Associate m Agronomy Rudolph Sandstedt, M.Sc, Analyst i . . 0. W. SJOGREN, B.Sc. m A.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) EDNA B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant m Home Economics W. P. Snyder, M.S., Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte M; H. Swenk, A.M., Entomology (Chairman) L. VAN Es, M.D., V.S., Animal Pathology aiid Hygiene (Chairman) H. Lew Wallace, M.Sc, Assistant m Agricultural Engineering A. D. Weber, M.Sc, Assistant m Animal Husbandry H. O. Werner, M.Sc, Associate m Horticulture Don B. Whelan, M.Sc, Assistant m Entomofog]/ C. C. Wiggans, Ph.D., Horticulture (Chairman) W. W. YOCUM, A.M., Assistant' in Horticulture ' **L; L. ZoOK, B.Sc, Agronomist, North\Platte ■• By an act of the Lecialnture of the State of Nebraska, approved and m effect February IS, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex oflicio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, .1899. •• Detailed from the Office of Dry Land Agriculture. United States Department of Arriculture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">CONTENTS Page Letter of Tn.nsmittal o Governor's Certificate g The Official Roster nf the StJitimi 3 ('(intents . Introduction - Invextigntionnl Work r Afrricullusal Fnirjneerii..-; : Tractor Testinir Poultry House Ventilation ami Construction S Farm Machinery Survey ; &gt; Study nf Wind-.lriveii Klcitrical Plants for Farm I'se s The I'-e of Klertrintv on Nebraska Farms ;) Animal Di.-ense-: Fowl Cholera Investigation- I Hcniorrhajric Septic-emial 'I An Inquiry into the Part Played hy Avian Tuberculosis Infection m Farm Animal.- and m .Man &lt;, Horse Disease Investigation ](') Current I.alxiratiiry Kxannnat ion- 10 Dairy Husliandry: A Study of Crowth m Dairy Cattli' 10 A Study of rhe Principles of [,c Cream Making 11 Studies of Kilt Soluble A and Other Milk Vitnmilie* Pies,., it m the Milk of the Four I'rimipal Dairy Breeds 1 ] Factors AffiTtinj; the Quality nf Milk as Shown l,y the Fat Test, Sediment Test, and liaiteriaj Count 12 The Control and Keotiomii F.tTeet of Contagious Abortion m the Dairy Herd jo Field Crops and Soils: Corn Breeding j.j Small Cirain . Barley , '., Soil Fertility )3 Fora&lt;;e Crupn Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, and Soil Condition.* to Nitrification of Nebraska Soils ' 1 , Studies m Soil Tilth 15 Restoration of Organic Matter of Scdls 15 Fruit and Vegetable Production: Pruninu- Fruit Tree?, CJrapos, and Small Fruit I"; Fruit Hreedinc jj; Orchard Culture j^ Vegetable Production 16 Fruit-stocks Investigation jy Insect Control: Codling Moth Control j^ Control of Injurious Insects. Mammals, and Birds ]8 r T^R' Orchard - and Greenhouse Stock Inspection 18 Life History of Several Common Cutworms IS Grasshopper Control l 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Page Livestock Feeding.: ■ , . Cattle — • ■'■".-. Effect of Sex upon Rate and Economy of Gain .■ 18 Feeding Rations for Cattle ....-„...■... 19 Factors Affecting the Quality of Meat......... 19 Effect of Length of Feeding Period on Quality of Heifer Carcasses j 19 • Lamb Feeding — Rations for Fattening Lamb 5...,........,'.... ". 20 Hogs- Forage Crops for Growing Pigs.. ;.„.... 21 Rations for Fattening Pigs &#132;.' 21 Home Economics... .-. 22 Milling, and Baking Qualities of Wheat....!.......,. 22 Standardization of Methods of Experimental Baking Procedure.... 22 Nutrition: A Study of the Efficiency of Various Proteins m Poultry Feeding.. 23 Plant Diseases: A Study of Environmental Conditions Influencing the Develop - ment of Stem Rust m the Absence of an Alternate Host 23 A Study of Spindle-tuber and Combinations of Spindle-tuber with Other Degeneration Diseases..... : 24 Control of Seed-borne Diseases of Potatoes 25 Barberry Eradication. L _ 26 The Determination of the Differential Reactions of Strains with - in a Variety of Wheat to Physiologic Forms of Puccinia Graminis Tritici ....:..; ; 26 Potatoes: i Potato Selection for Seed Purposes... ...:; 26 A Study of the Cause of Degeneracy m Potatoes.; 27 Poultry. Inheritance of Egg Pr0ducti0n.:..... ....;;.... .-...'.. ....: 27 Nutrient Requirements for Growing Chicks... 28 Turkey Production '. 29 Rural Economics: j Farm Tenure ; L 29 Cost of Producing Farm Crops 29 Economic Studies m Price, Volume of Production, and Purchas - ing Power of Farm Products 30 Nebraska Farm Land Prices .■'. 30 ■ ' Combine Harvester Studies....' J ..; 30 Market Costs . i 30 Serum Production '. 30 North Platte Substation : 31 Agronomy 32 Pump Irrigation :..... 32 Livestock Production — Beef Cattle ........: : : 33 Dairying : 33 Horses .-.: i : 34 Hops '. 34 Poultry , : : 34 Horticultural Forestry 34 Scottsbluff Substation :J 34 Crop Production 34 Lamb Feeding , '. 35 Dairying i ;.....' 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Hop, Pa f Poultry " 3 &amp; Valentine Substation " Crop Production "*° Dairy Cattle 36 Bepf Cattle Poultry :i &lt;j Additional Land. Buildings, and Equipment 37 N'eecls of the Experiment Station o 7 New LeKislation Changes m Staff ,? Publications dti Acknowledprmt'nt? Financial Statvmont ' ° 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">FORTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT This report covers the investigations, expenditures, and publications of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion during its forty-first year. The work of the Experiment Station is designed to seek out and develop new and helpful information. New problems are constantly arising m the agricultural development of the state, the solution of which requires investigation. The Experiment Station is organized to deal with these problems and to do so much more effectively than could be done thru individual effort. The demand for new information can not always be met by the Experiment Station.. It does not have the resources to undertake promptly the solution of all the problems that come to it. It's efforts are necessarily limited by its resources. As lines of work are completed, ne\y problems are undertaken, but concentration of effort rather than scattering over too many projects is considered advisable. During the past few years there has been an increasing . amount of rather routine work coming to the Station. This service does not contribute to the research program, but on "the other hand detracts from it.. This work consists largely of plant, animal, or other specimens sent m for various pur - poses — identification, analysis, diagnosis, or any kind of gen - eral information. The Station undertakes to take care of these if they have a general community interest, but it is not equipped for general analytical work and whatever effort is expended along that line detracts from the main program of the Station. The amount of this work coming to some de - partments is already so heavy as seriously to handicap their endeavors. The past.year has seen the completion of several projects and satisfactory progress along all lines. The results of a number of lines . of investigation have been made available to the public thru the publications 1 of the past year. INVESTIGATIONAL WORK The work of the Experiment Station is grouped around subject-matter departments. This arrangement makes • for greater efficiency m the solution of the problems undertaken. In the following report the various projects are grouped m corresponding, manner, regardless of the particular class of investigation into which they properly fall. The investigational work of the Experiment Station is supported by both Federal and State funds. In this report </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 8 no attempt is made to classify the investigations according to the different funds. A financial statement is included which shows the expenditures of the various funds allotted to the Experiment Station. In this report only a brief summary of the projects is given. I pon the conclusion of any investigation, the findings are assembled and published. These publications are avail - able to anyone interested m them upon application to the Di - rector of the Experiment Station. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Tractor Texthif,— The work done under this project is m accordance with the Nebraska Tractor Testing Lawv During the past year ten tractors have been tested and the reports of the tests made available to those interested. The results of all - tests to the close of the past year are being summarized for publication. Poultry Hous, Ventilation and Construction —The work on this project was continued as previously planned and re - ported with the addition of a small house-fan m one unit and an exhaust fan m another to afford better ventilation. Neither ot these appliances was effective m increasing egg production. The evidence obtained shows a general falling oft m egg production m all units during extremely cold wea - ther. It shows further only slight increase m egg production where houses are artificially heated. It would appear that there is more opportunity for improvement along lines of construction than there is m attempting to heat poultry houses artificially. The data obtained m this line of work are being assembled for publication. vin?T *y ".«""" S''rr*V— During the past year data pre - viously obtained and new data from farm surveys were stud - ied to determine the life of farm machinery and the actual rates of depreciation. No further field work is contemplated and the project will be closed after the compilation and pub - lication of the data. Study of Wind-driven Electrical Plants for Farm Use.— For this study there is available one commercial plant com - posed of a 60-foot tower with a 10-foot, 2-blade propeller and a 1-kilowatt, 32-volt generator, and a 180-ampere-hour battery. This has been subjected to a load requiring one kilowatt hour daily. This load is assumed as a minimum nec - essary for lights and small electrical accessories on the aver - age farm. In the study the battery was not discharged be - low the point specified as the low limit. During the year 1927 the maximum number of successive days with no current </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Forty-first Annual Report available was 13. There was a total of 55. days during the year under study when no current was available, due either to the lack of wind, movement or to. a discharged battery. During the same year there was a total production of 630V&amp; ■ kilowatt hours. The month of August was the lowest with .16.7 kilowatt hours and May the highest with 87.9 kilowatt hours. The Use. o/ Electricity on Nebraska Farms. — During the last year some work along this line has. been carried on. Studies have been made in the use of electricity in refrigera - tion plants on farms, the loss of energy on rural lines, and the cost per kilowatt hour of electricity produced by small electrical plants on farms. . . ANIMAL DISEASES Fowl Cholera Investigations (Hemorrhagic Septicemia) . — During the past year further work was done on. the immuniz - ing value of certain aggressins. The amount of work along this line was limited by the shortage of animal stock neces - sary for tests. This line of work will be continued. An Inquiry into the Part Played by Avian Tuberculosis In - fection in Farm Animals and in Man. — To date a consid - erable number of tubercular lesions have been examined to determine the origin of the tubercles. The results obtained are shown in the following table. The Distribution of Avian Tuberculosis Infection in Mammals. Progress Report on Results Obtained Prior to July 1, 1927. ~ ' " Uacillary types found in lesions Scries Origin of lesions used 8 '■•'■ c • - number in typing: c £ | 5 ' "2 S 'S B g a ' B &lt; 8 fc &amp; 1 Bovine. Isolated lesions, ■. mostly lymphnodes 72 10 4 34 120 2 Bovine. Skin lesions.....'. .... 38 38 3 Bovine. Hemorrhagic lymph - nodes of no lesion reactors .... 24 24 4 Bovine. Uteri of. no lesion reactors * ' .... 5 5 5 Swine. Mostly isolated lymphnode lesions 11 . 198 14 31 254 6 Swine. Lesions other than' pulmonary 2 38 21 61 7 Sheep. Pulmonary lesions 1 .... 1 8 Horse. Culture .... 1 • 1 9 Avian. Fowls and turkeys 74 1 3 78 Total....... ■ ■•■■: 582 \ ".- • .■■■■„" . ' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 10 The search for avian tuberculosis infection m man is oar icularly warranted because, first, it is important to know if he general distribution and high morbidity of avian tubereu Sin Ihe Sri '* """ nW S ° n l hfa Pr ° ject Until SSriSl^dSr series have been obtained to TOt ,f w W'wfl** 1 Investigation.— The loss of a large number Son Xh ifl aiu - s f tiona of the state led to «57?n523£ tion, which is carried on co-operatively with the State Dp partment of Agriculture. The work has been actively pui - sued during the past year. The pathology of the disease has been care fully studied. The epizilo^icaPfeatuS ofX d£ Older were studied and recorded, and feeding exne Hments w lth p ant, under suspicion were made. The itfratme ™tj subject shows that apparently the disease is similar ?o one occurring m widely distributed areas of the world The ™i - feeT ff'itSi *°*" "** * U W n the h ™ othes ''s that the aisease is of microbic or parasitic origin. Cattle are also found to be subject to it. The disease is marked b? Severe degenerat.ve changes m the liver, which m some easel is a most completely deteriorated as a gland. All changes found he Mvp P °7 an f- are m V' eU L subsidiar y to the elimination of the liver function and the most characteristic symptoms merely express the intoxication arising whenever tn™ S ceases to perform its physiologic function Feeding experiments indicate that the lupines have.no rela - tion to the trouble. The feeding of Senecio species is now m progress but definite results are not yet obtainable.' A carefu" survey of the flora m the region of greatest susceptibility has been made and also post-mortem examinations of manvani ma ls that have died of the disease. The viscera of these an - mals were all examined historically and the results recorded Current Laboratory Examinations.— During the year 6 9&lt;W 0? re sent m by citizens of the state for tfie p»S2 DAIRY HUSBANDRY A Study of Growth m Dairy Cattle.— This project has been under way for a number of years m an attempt to determine the manner and rapid ty of growth. All calves m the herd are weighed at weekly intervals from birth until six months of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-first Annual Keport. 11 age, after which they are .weighed and photographed at the end of definite periods of time; The past year's work has continued this weighing, measuring and photographing. A Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making. — Most of ■the work m this project during the past year has been a study of the cause, method of development, and the prevention of surface crustation of sherbets. Sherbets as made commercially have a tendency to develop a surface crustation of white crys - tals that appear m roseate form. To facilitate the work an experimental freezer was developed containing special gears and controls so arranged that the scraper and beater could be operated independently, at various speeds, and, if desired, m opposite directions. ; By analysis, the crustation has been found to be largely a concenti-ation of sugar crystals. The cause is apparently a concentration of sugar on or near the surface due to evapora - tion and to the tendency of the crystals to aggregate. Crusta - tion may be postponed for long periods and perhaps pre - vented for an indefinite length of time if air is excluded from the container. Complete sealing of the can or the use of parchment circles with or lids is effective for periods up to three months. By comparing various concentrations of sugar m 10, 30, 39, and 50 per cent water solutions, it was found that the higher the sugar concentration, the quicker and the thicker the crustation. Corn sugar or invert sugar, used m quantities amounting to 22 per cent of the sugar, produced sherbets of a low freezing point. There was an apparent retardation of crustation but the sherbets were too soft to be of commercial value. Other possible combinations will be tried later. By comparing various gums for stabilizing sher - bets, it was found that gum tragacanth, gum arabic, and agar all imparted objectionable flavors, while India gum did not. Further studies with various combinations of ingredients and .methods of freezing will be made. Studies of Fat Soluble A and Other Milk Vitamines Present m the Milk of the Four Principal Dairy Breeds. — The major part of the work under this project has dealt with the effect of season on the milk of different breeds. The determination of fat soluble A is made by feeding the fresh milk to rats and noting their rate of gain. The animals are fed and weighed daily, the unused food being checked back. . The results obtained indicate that the effect of seasons, summer and winter, is a greater factor than breed differences. The indications are that it requires slightly more winter milk to produce the same gain as summer milk. In other words, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 12 summer milk is somewhat more potent than winter milk m growth production. Factors Affrctiuu the Quality of Milk OK Shown by the Fat Test, Sediment Test, and Bacterial Count. — This project has been m progress for a number of years and considerable data are now available. A wide variation m quality of milk from different farms at different seasons of the year has been found. The effect of temperature upon the quality of milk is vvvy pronounced, indicating that proper cooling of milk would lie a simple and inexpensive way of improving the qual - ity. EfForts toward improvement arc being made thru weekly reports and farm visits. Tin- ('nut, -ill inul Economic Effect of Contagious Abortion m tlu Dairy Herd.— During the past year data have been collected upon the effect of abortion m the Agricultural Col - lege dairy herd over a period of 30 years. Various: studies of the data are being made, including the effect of milking cows two. three, ami four times daily on their milk and fat yield. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Com Bri-cdiny.—Wovk under this project was continued along lines previously determined. The season of 1926, how - ever, was so dry that complete failure resulted m several lines of work, and continuation necessitated the use of reserve seed supplies. Extensive comparative plantings of varieties secured from a wide range of environmental conditions were made for the purpose of studying the characteristics m which corn differs m relation to the environmental factors to which it has become adapted. Further work was carried on pertaining to the methods of comparative yield testing, especially the comparison of the multiple-row and single-row plats; also, work was done on a means of application of the principles of selection, and on genetic and cytologic studies pertaining to the mode of in - heritance of characters. Three years of work has been completed on the use of cer - tain organic mercury disinfectants. The work was summar - ized and published as Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 218, entitled "Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants." It was found that these compounds have no effect upon the growth or yield of representative farm-selected seed The evidence obtained here indicates that seed-borne diseases aiv not a serious factor under Nebraska conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forty-first Annual Report 13 Small Grain. — Work on this project is under a long-time program and is concerned with both the improvement of small grain by developing better varieties and a study of the cultural practices which tend toward more efficient pro - duction. In addition to a large number of selections of winter wheat and a number of crosses m various generations, approximately 25 varieties of winter wheat were grown m field plats. No commercial strain or variety proved superior to either Ne - braska No. 60 or Kanred. One hundred strains of Burt and Texas Red oats were grown m the nursery and 25 selected' varieties were grown m replicated field plats. Some of these strains show consid - erable promise. Barley. — Considerable work has been done with barley m testing varieties for yield, quality, and convenience m hand - ling. Comfort barley having smooth beards has been found equal to any barley, previously tried under Nebraska condi - tions. The smooth beards are an important factor both m the convenience of handling and m the matter of feeding the straw. ' During the year the data, accumulated during the past five years on seed-bed preparation for winter wheat were assem - bled and published as Station Bulletin. No. 223. In these ex - periments early plowing to a depth of 7 inches together with timely disking proved advantageous. This is accounted for thru the accumulation of available nitrates and moisture m the soil and thru weed control. Disking proved decidedly in - ferior to early plowing only as a method of seed-bed prepara - tion for winter wheat, and. was fully as productive as late plowing. Drilling winter wheat m corn gave little more than half the yield ■ that was obtained on well-prepared stubble land. The depth of plowing was found to be far less impor - tant than the time at which the plowing was done. Soil Fertility. — Six years' data on the new fields where this work is -in progress have now accumulated. Manure has quite consistently increased the yields of wheat and oats. The return per ton of manure Used varies with the rate and fre - quency of application,, being slightly higher for the more frequent and lighter applications. Manure has increasec 1 the yield of corn but very little. Phosphorus m a number, of combinations with nitrogen and potassium has increased the yield of wheat slightly m certain years, but on the average not enough to be profitable. It has generally been without effect on oats and corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 14 Nitrogen m various combinations with phosphorus and potassium has consistently increased the yield of oats m all years hut one, hut on the average not enough to he of interest to farmers. Nitrogen has had no consistent effect on wheat or corn. Potassium has been entirely without effect on all crops m all seasons. Shortage of moisture m the subsoil clue to alfalfa which occupied the field for several years previous to the establish - ment of the experimental plots has so limited the yield of alfalfa m the rotation that results from manurial and fertil - izer treatments have generally been insignificant. Lime, to date, has not proved beneficial on alfalfa, nor on other crops on the Experiment Station Farm. In a number of demonstrational tests on glacial soils m southeastern Ne - braska, lime gave strong evidence of being beneficial, espec - ially with a new seeding of alfalfa. Fomgr Crops.— During the past year ail alfalfa data ob - tained to date were assembled and published m Nebraska Re - search Bulletin No. :',6, and a popular edition. No. 222, was: prepared. In this work winter hardiness of alfalfa was found to he an important factor m alfalfa production m the state. During the past five years there have been two winters m which winterkilling was rather severe. Non-hardy alfalfas of the Peruvian type completely winterkilled. Alfalfas from Argentina, Italy, and from Spain, and also southern-grown domestic common strains were materially injured. Stand es - timates following the fifth winter for Cossack, Grimm, Baltic, and the hardier common strains ranged from 89 to 72 per cent. On a four-year average the various strains ranked m yield as follows: Cossack, Baltic, Grimm, Canadian varie - gated, Nebraska common, Turkestan, and Sand Lucern. The most striking and distinguishing difference observed between common and variegated alfalfa is the flower color. Several other factors studied did not indicate significant differences. A study of other forage crops, both annual and perennial, was continued. Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, and Soil' Conditions to Nitrification of Nebraska Soils.— Additional information was obtained upon several phases of this work, the results cor - relating with those previously reported. Variable tempera - tures and moisture conditions of the soil did not appear either to repress or stimulate nitrification where the ranges of varia - bility did not go beyond the daily variation obtaining under field conditions. A partial report on this phase of the subject has been published m Soil Science, Vol. 19, pp. 381-398 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Forty-first Annual Report 15 Studies m Soil Tilth— Progress -has been made on this pro - ject during the past year along the line of construction of apparatus. A very much refined apparatus for the study of soil friction has been built and some preliminary work on the . effect of moisture on the coefficient of friction of different .soil textures has been done. Restoration of Organic Matter of Soils.-*- Certain investi - gations related to this subject have already been completed and published as follows: "Organic Requirements of Soils under : Various Climatic Conditions", Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 19, May,' 1927; "The Relation of Organic Matter and Nitrogen Content to Soil Series and Type m Virgin Grassland Soil", Soil Science, Vol. 24, December, ' 1927; "The Organic Matter Content and Color of Soils m Central Prairie States", presented at the Seventh Meeting of the International Congress of Soil Science. The point emphasized m the above papers 1 is that virgin • soils of established characteristics carry definite quantities of organic matter and nitrogen, the quantity varying with tex - ture, rainfall, topography, latitude, and perhaps other factors not yet discovered. Other studies made at this ■Station indicate that Nebraska soils have lost as much as 30 per cent of their original organic matter content. At the Agronomy Farm the annual loss is around 1140 pounds of organic matter per acre. Manure at a rate equivalent to two tons per acre per year has maintained the organic content of the soil.' Some work has also been done on the rate of decomposition of various organic materials, these ranging from blood meal with a carbon-nitrogen ratio of 3.68, to cob meal with a carbon-nitrogen ratio. of 152. .The studies have been made m the laboratory under controlled temperature and moisture conditions. Some work on methods for determining organic matter has been done.: The hydrogen-peroxide method, with certain changes, will probably be used m the future m this project. • • FRUIT AND VEGETABLE PRODUCTION Pruning Fruit Trees, Grapes, and Small Fruit.— The work under this project has been carried on for several years to determine the kind and amount of pruning most desirable . The data obtained with grapes confirm previous conclusions that m this climate cane pruning is preferable to spur prun - ing. Under cane pruning the amount of old 1 wood is held to a minimum, just sufficient to maintain the plant. Further - more, under this system the clusters of fruit seem to be larger and more easily harvested. : " </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 16 In the case of apples, trees heavily pruned at transplanting time made almost twice as much shoot-growth and also aver - aged heavier m weight than trees pruned lightly. With older trees just coming into hearing, it is too early to draw reliable conclusions as to the effect of either type or time of pruning upon yield and quality of fruit. Fruit HrrrditH/.— Further observations on a number of strawberry hybrids which have been bred and distributed for observation purposes lead to the final conclusion that none of them is much if any superior to the old standard Dunlap. A tew of the apple seedlings are just coming into fruit - one Genet-Delicious hybrid appears promising. New varieties and species of fruits are being received from other sources, and planted. Several varieties of peaches were set out during the year. Orchard Cult „,■&lt;.— ln a study of different types of ferti - lzers on apple trees at Lincoln, blight has been discovered to be a serious factor where commercial nitrogen is applied. The data obtained, however, emphasize the necessity of a good supply of nitrogen, even with young trees, if maximum growth and fruiting are to be secured. In a study of the mulching of grapes, the results were very similar to those of a year ago. Where the plats were mulched there was distinct evidence of nitrogen starvation early m the spring but vigorous growth later. Vegetable Production. — Several phases of this project were carried on during the past year. In the study of the control of onion thrips it was found that nicotine sulphate 1 to 500 reduced the number of thrips 75 per cent, as compared with 54 per cent m the case of a l-to-1000 solution. While "the onion thrips can be controlled with nicotine sulphate, it was not possible to do so completely with the outfits now on the market. However, the yield was 18 per cent greater where control was attempted. The addition of 6V 2 inches of irrigation water thru an overhead system, supplementing the rainfall of 13.2 inches, between June 1 and September 23, resulted m greatly in - creased yields of tomatoes, sweet and Irish potatoes, wax beans, and egg plants. In a study of cultivation methods, straw-mulched plats made higher yields than cultivated ones. Tests with acid phosphate and manure, either alone or m com - bination, did not increase either the earliness or the yield of tomatoes. Large asparagus crowns planted m 1926 made greater early growth than did the smaller crowns. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-first Annual Report 17 Fruit-stocks Investigation. — In a study of germination, con - siderable difficulty was encountered m securing good germina - tion of seed of various fruits, marked variation occurring even with the same fruits. In the work with vegetative prop - agation very great differences m vigor, growth, rooting habits, and ability to grow from root cuttings were evident. Plums propagated from root cuttings much more readily than apples. Two thousand French crab seedlings were graded according to weight and grafted by different methods m order to deter - mine (1) the seedling size which give's the greatest percentage of No. 1 trees, and (2) the. grafting method which produces the smoothest or least galled trees. The results will be de - termined after two years' growth. Grafts made m the var - ious ways m 1925 showed a year later that scion-rooted grafts were nearly always smaller than those having no scion roots. INSECT CONTROL Codling Moth Control. — Observations on the codling moth during the season of 1926 indicated that emergence and con - ditions favorable for egg-laying and hatching were early. The first and second broods overlapped, the peak emergence being about the middle of July. In attempting to determine the best and most satisfactory spray schedule, from 6 to 11 sprays were applied to the var - ious plats. These varied from one application per brood to an application every two weeks (m addition to the "pink" and "petal fall" sprays). Final results are given below: Per cent No. apples codling moth " Per cent Per cent Schedule counted injury '. stings live worms Two weeks 13,381 9.1 -, ; 7.6 1.5 C Three weeks 9,504 12.0 1010 . 2.02 Four weeks 8,240 11.3 815 2.91 One per br00d.... 8,809 1C.4 12.1 4.34 Two per br00d.... 9,369 5.6 • 4.5 1.06 Unsprayed : 1,620 54.2 1715 36.70 . These data indicate that the "two per brood" and "three weeks" schedules of cover sprays were practical for the con - ditions of season and infestation occurring m 1926. In av - erage years four so-called "coyer spray" applications would be required. The cost of making "■ these applications was about $3.25 per acre, per application. In a study of the kind and amount of materials used, it was found that heavy dosages, double spraying, etc., made little appreciable difference m either first-brood or final counts, but did increase the cost. Ordinary lead arsenate, IV-&gt; pounds to 50 gallons of water, was the cheapest and most practical dosage found. ■ .... </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska. Agricultural Experiment Station 18 " Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. — During the past year the Hessian fly was not present m large num - bers m Nebraska; and field stations maintained for the past several years to determine safe dates for planting wheat were not continued. Considerable work was done m assembling the data which had already been obtained on the Hessian fly. Further studies were made and data obtained on the stalk borer, alfalfa pests, and birds. Some time was spent m obser - vations of the progress made m eastern Wyoming by the al - falfa weevil. Nursery, Orchard, and Gre.enhousp Stock Inspection. — The work under this project, which has been carried m accordance with the Nebraska Horticultural Inspection Law, closed with the past fiscal year. The last Legislature repealed the old law, and the new law places the work m the office of the Secre - tary of Agriculture of the State. Life History of Several Common Cutworms. — The work on this project during the past year was largely from the taxo - nomic side, m an effort to obtain suitable descriptions of the various species of cutworms. The data so far obtained will be offered for publication m the near future. Grasshopper Control. — A large portion of the work under this project was designed to ascertain the best poisoned-mash bait to use under Nebraska conditions for grasshopper con - trol. A portion of this work had previously been published as Station Bulletin No. 183, and during the past year the re - mainder was published as Research Bulletin No. 41. No fur - ther work is contemplated on this phase of the project. LIVESTOCK FEEDING CATTLE Effect of Sex upon Rate and Economy of Gain. — For this study several lots of high-grade Hereford calves were used. These calves had been raised under ranch conditions. They were on feed from November 23 to April 17. The calves were carefully graded at the beginning and at the close of the experiment. The basic ration was shelled corn and alfalfa, but one lot each of steers and heifers received, m addition to the above, cottonseed cake. On a ration of corn and alfalfa hay, steer calves gained 23 pounds more than heifer calves, and the gains were $1.04 per hundredweight cheaper. The profit on the steers was $3.96 per head more than on the heifers, but m dressing weight the heifers excelled the steers by 1 per cent. Where </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-first Annual Report 19 cottonseed cake was added the steers gained at a greater rate than the heifers, as quoted above, the steers making 58 cents per hundredweight cheaper gains and outselling the heifers 30 cents per hundred. The heifers again excelled m dressing weight by l ] /i per cent, but made $2.08 less profit per head than the steers. . : Feeding Rations for Cattle.— -The additional work done with this project during the past year consisted m the feeding of several lots of range calves. The basic ration was corn and alfalfa. It was found that the addition of cottonseed cake at prices obtaining during the past year was profitable. With both steers and heifer calves it increased the rate and cost of gain, the selling price, the dressing 1 - percentage, and the profit. The addition of a molasses feed and cottonseed cake to a corn and alfalfa ration for heifer calves increased the rate of gain but also increased the cost of gain to a point where it reduced the profit per calf, . . Factors Affecting the Quality of Afeat.— ln a study of the effect of sex on carcass quality ,- 18 steers and 20 heifers, aver - aging 7 months of age and 270 pounds m weight, were pur - chased. These were uniform m breeding and quality. Three of each were slaughtered at the beginning of the trial and de - tailed carcass studies were made. The remainder were fed a full ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay for 145 days, when they were shipped to market. After slaughtering, detailed carcass studies were made. During the fattening period the steers gained. 2.41 pounds per day, requiring 460 pounds of corn and 182 pounds of hay per 100 pounds of gain. The heifers gained 2.25 pounds a day, requiring 506 pounds of corn and 244 pounds of hay per hundredweight of gain. The heifers dressed out higher than the steers, both at the begin - ning and at the close of the trial, and at both times carried more external and internal fat than the steers. At the close of the feeding period the muscular development of the steers was greater than that of the heifers. ; Effect of Length of Feeding Period on Quality of Heifer Carcasses.— ln a study of the effect of the length of feeding period on the quality of heifer carcasses, 40 uniform heifer calves were used. They averaged 7 months of age and 395 pounds m weight at the beginning of the experiment. Three average heifers were slaughtered at the beginning of the ex - periment and 3 at each interval of 28 days, running thru a feeding period of 224 days. Numerous studies were made to determine the quality of carcass, and certain portions were sent to the Bureau, of Animal Industry for similar studies. While the project is not yet complete, some interesting data ..■"/" •'• </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 20 have been obtained. During the first 168 days of the feeding the average weight of the cattle increased from 390 to 695 Si«n n carcass weight more than doubled, increasing lon 190 to 4ZO pounds. With the increasing finish of the cattle the average dressing percentage consistently increased IITJI ;•». Pei " {*!*■■ DurWg the same time the omentum noumN Z\ Z . rUP n ' increasin « lrom 4 -»5 pounds to 17.38 pounds per Head. Ihe mesentery or ruffle fat likewise quad - rupled. U hile the meat was improved by the fattening pro - cess the cuts became more wasty. This conclusion is borne out by the fact that the kidney fat from the short loin more than quadrupled, increasing from 1.46 pounds to 6.75 pounds per loin. LAMB FEEDING ««'•«"* /'" Fnttvuhiu La whs.— During the past year m this test. 8 lots til 25 lambs each were fed from October 25 to December 11. White-faced Wyoming lambs, of medium to fine wool type, were used. They were carefully selected for uniformity as to quality, wight, and condition.' The rations used were as follows; Lot 1. — Shelled corn and alfalfa hay. • L&lt;&gt;t ~~- sht ' lll ' (l l ' ( »'»- linseed meal, alfalfa hay. , ! : ;~~ S ! U ' 1 , 1 , ( ' (I t "" rn - Hnseecl meal, and alfalfa meal Lot J. — Shelled corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal ('so', beet). Lot s.— Cracked corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal (SO 1 ; beet). Lot 6.— Cracked corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal (20', beet). Lot 7.— Cracked corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal (-10'; beet). Lot B.— Cracked corn, linseed meal, alfalfa molasses meal (HO'; cane) . The results indicated that where alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal was fed, more corn was consumed and the average daily gain was greater than where alfalfa hay was ted. The replacement value of 100 pounds of linseed meal amounted to 71.2 pounds of corn and 78.5 pounds of alfalfa Grinding alfalfa hay resulted m a saving of 13C pounds of hay m the feed required for 100 pounds of gain The substitution of alfalfa molasses meal for alfalfa meal L»J*th T't lin ? eed - m f a } a »&lt;&gt; alfalfa-meal ration in - creased the cos of gains and decreased the profit per lamb. The heaviest death loss was m the corn and alfalfa lots The </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-first Annual Report lambs in all lots were fed heavy rations and it was difficult to keep"Lots.l and 2 on feed. Possibly the mixing of the corn with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal results in a more equal distribution of both grain and roughage among the lambs. • ... HOGS . . . • Forage Crops for Growing Pigs. — Under this test 6 lots : of 10 pigs each, with an initial weight of 58 pounds, were put on feed June 15th. All were fed in dry lots for 30 days, after which. 2 lots were turned on Sudan grass pasture for 75 clays. All concentrated feeds were self-fed. The pigs which were on pasture and fed corn and tankage gained 1.34 pounds a day, as compared with 1.23 pounds a day for pigs fed sim - ilarly in dry lot. The pasture effected a saving of corn and tankage sufficient to reduce the cost of producing 100 pounds of pork from $6.86 to $6.27, after allowing 15 cents per pig per month for pasture. Meat and bone meal proved to be a supplement superior to tankage, increasing the feed consumption and the rate of gain, and effecting a slight saving in cost. The pigs receiving meat and bone meal gained 1.59 pounds a day at a cost of $6.06 per 100 pounds of gain, while tankage-fed pigs gained 1.34 pounds at a cost of $6.27 per 100 pounds; Pigs fed cracklings, with corn, made more rapid gains than those receiving corn and tankage, but, because of the • high cost of cracklings, the gain was less profitable. Both linseed meal and cottonseed meal, when fed with tank - age, were effective in increasing feed consumption and rate of gain. The Unseed meal lot gained 1.45 pounds a day and the cottonseed meal lot 1.53 pounds, as compared with 1.34 pounds per day for the check lot. The use of the auxiliary supplement resulted in more expensive gains, the cost being $6.33, $6.57, and $6.27 per hundredweight j for the three lots respectively. Rations for Fattening Pigs.— In a feeding test with pigs in a dry lot, 80 head were fed for a period of 85 days, begin - ning January 22. A comparison was made of three grades of tankage, differing only in the amount of dried blood added, the amounts representing 45, 60, and 70 per cent, respectively, of the tankage. As the percentage of dried blood increased, the palatability of the tankage and of the entire ration apparently decreased. The amount of feed Tequired to produce 100 pounds of gain decreased consistently from 363 pounds of corn and 58 pounds of tankage, with 45 per cent protein, to 325 pounds of corn and 37 pounds of tankage, with 70 per cent . ' " i </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station protein. The rate of gain was "not widely different among the three lots. The inclusion of alfalfa hay in a corn-aml-tankage ration increased the daily average gain from 1.22 pounds to 1.58 pounds, ami reduced the cost of 100 pounds of gain from $6.45 to $5.!)2. . v The mixture of equal parts of tankage and cottonseed meal as a protein supplement proved superior to- straight tankage, increasing the daily gain from 1.22 to 1.43 pounds. It also reduced the cost per 10(1 pounds of gain from $6.45 to $6.13. HOME ECONOMICS Several projects are now under way in a study of rural home conditions. These projects deal largely with phases of household convenience and labor requirements. Most of the data are being obtained thru the survey method and during the past year additional records were obtained. Work is also under wav in a comparison of different types' of kerosene cooking stoves. The efficiency of the stove and its fuel con - sumption are being carefully measured l&gt;v standard methods/ MILLING AND BAKING QUALITIES. OF WHEAT A study &lt;it the relation of certain chemical and physical characteristics of Nebraska wheat to its milling and baking qualities was continued. During the past year the develop - ment of more scientific methods of conducting and interpret - ing the laboratory baking tests was stressed. A number of cereals were retested, using a fixed type of procedure which takes into consideration the tolerance of wheat toward oxidiz - ing agents, such as are uniformly used in commercial practice. Standardization ( ,f Method* of Experimental Baking Pm - cedurc—Concentrated effort has been made on 'this project during the past year. Heretofore there ha.s been little if any standardization of methods. The person in charge of this work has been commissioned by the Association of Agricul - tural Chemists as leader in this project for the year. A com - mittee has endeavored to work out standard methods. The attempt to establish a standardized method of proce - dure is for the purpose of eliminating, as far as possible all variables, excepting that of the flour itself. This will make possible a better comparison of the work of the cereal chem - ists of various stations. Efforts were also devoted to a more precise ascertainment of factors which must be taken into account in the practical interpretation of laboratory baking tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-first Annual, Report During the past year three technical papers were published on this subject, as follows : "A Rational Basis for the Stand - ardization of Experimental Baking Tests", Cereal Chemistry, Vol. 4, No. 2 ;■ "The Factors Affecting Interpretation of Ex - perimental Baking Tests", .Cereal Chemistry, Vol. 4, No. 4; "The Report of the Committee on Standardization of Baking Tests", Cereal Chemistry, Vol. 4. No. 4. NUTRITION ' A Study of the' Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding.— In 37 trials with 19 hens an average biological value of. 68 was secured for the nitrogenous matter of yellow corn. The details of this work were reported in Poultry Scicnce,.Ya\ 5. In a previous report it was concluded that the feeding of very small amounts of pure cystine daily to molting hens on a nitrogen-free diet exerted a protein-sparing action out of proportion to the nitrogen content of th$ diet. This raised - the question of whether or not the addition' of pure cystine would enhance the value of a ration fed to molting hens. To test this theory the cystine requirement; of molting hens was studied from August 2 to December 16. ; It was found that the daily addition of small amounts of cystine to the feed. ration of 21 Single Comb White Leghorn hens produced no beneficial nor detrimental results, when compared with a check lot of 20 similar hens on the same basic ration. This was evidenced by the egg record, body weight, and the shed - ding and growth of the primary flight feathers. It is con - cluded as unlikely that the addition of cystine above the min - imal requirements of hens could hasten the completion of the molt. Further work will be necessary to explain the failure of cystine to produce a beneficial effect in a practical way and to account for the protein-sparing action of cystine when added to a nitrogen-free diet. Since the progress of the wing molt was observed thruout the above experiment, it was possible to prepare a series of 13 charts portraying the average progress of the wing molt of 41 hens from week to week during the molting period. These charts will serve to estimate accurately the length of time a hen has been humolt. . PLANT DISEASES A Study of Environmental Conditions Influencing the De - velopment of Stem-Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. — During the past year further work wasl done on this project in co-operation with Mr. Thiel, barberry eradication leader in Nebraska. A total of 213 specimens of stem rust were col- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lected from 55 counties. Among these, six physiologic forms of stem rust were found. One form designated as No. 18 was dominant and was found to be most widely distributed. A new form was found. A manuscript summarizing the results obtained under this project to date has been prepared and sub - mitted to the station as a research bulletin. Among the con - clusions drawn are the following: 1. Barberries have been found rusted at one time or another thruout the state. The degree of infection varies with seas - onal and weather conditions, influencing the viability of the teliospores and the maturation of the barberry leaves at the time sporidia are infectious. 2. During the normal seasons, pycnia appear on the bar - berry between April 20 and April 26, aecia with mature spores between May 6 and May 10, and uredinia on grasses and grains near infected barberries about May 20 to May 25. 3. The tritici and seralis forms of Puccinia, graminis have been the most common ones observed spreading from infected barberries. No clear, convincing case of the arenae form has been observed spreading from barberries in this state. 4. The first uredinia not traceable to barberries are norm - ally found in southeastern Nebraska the first week in June. Within a week they appear in northern Nebraska, and in the western part of the state in about two weeks. This early in - fection of rust is found scattered in very small amounts over a wide territory as compared with a heavier local infection' on grasses and grains near barberries. A Study of Spindle-tuber and Combinations of Spindle-tu - ber with Other Degeneration Diseases. — Several phases of this work wera carried on during the past year. Previously, spindle-tuber and unmottled curly dwarf have been considered under the same name. The results of the past year would in - dicate that a considerable amount of what was formerly con - sidered severe spindle-tuber is due to unmottled curly dwarf, a more serious disease than spindle-tuber. The symptoms are somewhat similar and for practical purposes in advising growers, may be classed together. In inoculation studies the two diseases appear quite different, unmottled curly dwarf being much more easily transmitted artificially than spindle - tuber. Greenhouse tests show that there is a relation between the length of rest period of the seed and the symptoms of unmottled curly dwarf plants, but not with spindle-tuber. A study of other diseases of unknown cause has been made. One appears as a mild form of Mosaic, hard to detect under Nebraska conditions, but evident when the seed is planted and grown in the South. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-first Annual Report : Another disease being studied is more severe in that the plant is either killed or so weakened that tubers are not pro - duced. It is possible, that this disease is similar to one de - scribed by Schultz and Fotsom under the name of Yellow Top. Some histqlogical -and micro-chemical studies have been started but to date no significant findings In a study of the infectious principle;? of 'these etiacaoco one results indicate a biological rather than a chemical factor • causing the disease. It. was found that in cores of tissue from infected tubers the causal factor could be killed in a water bath, at temperatures above £0- degrees Centigrade.^ Further work on the transmission of the disease by cutting - knife confirmed the fact that considerable infection might ocdir in this way. In a study of the transmission of the dis - ease by insects, infection was repeatedly obtained by using grasshoppers, as the transmitting agent: Further work will be done along this line. Control of Seed-borne Diseases of Potatoes.— During the past year experiments were conducted with Irish Cobblers, Bliss Triumphs, and Early Ohios at several points in the state, to determine the effectiveness of a number of seed treat - ments in the control of scab and Rhizoctonia. In the control of Rhizoctonia, various organic mercury compounds failed to produce a significant increase in yield over the bichloride of mercury treatment. On the basis of Rhizoctpnia-infected potatoes produced, the organic mercury compounds did not give as good control as bichloride of mer - cury. The best control was obtained with bichloride of mer - cury when the potatoes were presprinkled and kept moist for 24 hours before treating. The only effective control of scab was with the hot formaldehyde treatment. Neither bichloride of mercury, sulphur, nor any of the four organic mercury treatments gave effective control of scab. None of the treat - ments increased the total yield. . . In a study of relative susceptibility, Irish Cobblers were found more susceptible to Fusarium Wilt than Bliss Triumphs, indicating that Irish Cobblers should not be planted on wilt - infected soil in western Nebraska. Treating the cut seed^with organic mercury compounds to prevent possible seed-piece infection by Fusar-iam from the^ soil reduced the infection approximately 5 per cent for both Cobblers and Triumphs, but did not prevent the disease. Either the treatments are not effective against this organism or the disease enters chiefly thru the roots. Previous work has indicated that the latter may be true. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Barberry Eradication.-^-This work is carried on by the U S A^f^ ent .°r^ griCUlt^ re •'" co -°P era tion with the Nebraska Agricultural College. Durmg the year 1927 six additional counties in the northeastern section of the state, were covered in the farm-to-farm survey for the common barberry. In these counties 714 barberry bushes were found and destroyed on 69 properties. • rds ? nd other agencies have scattered the barberrv seerte in the panted and native woods. It is very difficult to find the seedlings and bushes which have grown from these scat - tered seeds. During the summer 438 such escaped barberrv ; bushes and 2,322 seedlings were found and destroyed Jthfr, De \f r^ tio { n jl Differential Reactions of Strains S2SS, %?7 ° f r WheC i! t0 Ph vr l °W Forms ofPuccinia urammis Tntin.— Greenhouse work on this project has been completed and published as Research Bulletin 39 The date indicate that there may be a decided variation in the differed tial reaction of wheat strains within a commercial variety of various physiologic forms of stem rust. Field work on thfo project is being continued. • * POTATOES Potato Selection for Seed Purposes.— Further work verified the conclusions that (1) good seed potatoes can be produced in all parts of the state when disease is not present as a dfs - turbing factor and (2) spindle-tuber is more detr men al thin o e n aS Hrv n , T m &lt; T 9t Z n Nebraska - (« «nder irrigation SSi V and 'u (c) under ? ultiv ation than with straw mulch and (d) with early planting and late harvesting than with late planting and early harvesting •mind! 18 ? 1 !!* cor , relation was fou "d between the length of time spindle-tuber plants remained in seed-potato fields and the Th P vttf 6 ffS SGVe ? ty ° f . s P indle -t"ber in the ensuing crop Ihe yield of the next crop is similarly affected Continuing the tuber index work with disease-free Triumph strains, it was found that the Mosaic content of some pre vious y lndeX ed ota was less than 0.2 per cent as compared with the original lot, which showed as high as 38 2 per cent Sir *« 3 ? K nU l UaI m °u led condition of the I"* wa P s found, apparently tuber-borne, but not yet diagnosed In eastern and central Nebraska, spraying with Bordeaux during the season of 1926 had no beneficial effects *° rdeaUX Hollow heart was found to be most prevalent on plants with few stems, in large tubers, in spindle tubers, and in tubers showing second growth or growth cracks. The planting of large seed pieces, so as to increase the number of stem? or </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-first Annual Report the use of a substance (thiourea) to induce the growth of . mbre stems per seed piece,; may prove beneficial, but 1926 results were not conclusive. In co-operation with the Boyce Thompson Institute and the Bermuda Department of Agriculture, some studies are being carried on concerning methods of breaking the rest period of seed potatoes so as to permit the planting of northern seed potatoes in subtropical regions in October and November. s A Study of the Cause of Degeneracy in Potatoes. — Further work was carried on during the past year to determine more definitely the effect of environmental factors on seed potatoes when disease is not present as a disturbing factor. Under control conditions, healthy potatoes grown under different soil temperatures and in different amounts of soil moisture did not reveal any significant differences in seed value. In a study of the maturity of potatoes in relation to seed value, distinctly immature tubers made less vigorous growth ' than more mature lots. In lots exposed to disease the per - centage of spindle-tuber in the crop was in direct ratio to the length of time the parent plants were in the field. Pota - toes planted early and harvested late gave the most inferior seed stock. Those planted, late were the most productive. These results were obtained on irrigated land. On dry land the results this year did not show how much difference in seed value is caused by different planting, dates. In eastern Nebraska cultivation, irrigation and- straw mulch made little variation in the seed value of the potatoes when disease was absent. When spindle-tuber was present, cultiva - tion and irrigation seemed to favor the increase of the disease. . A bulletin is being published which gives some of the results \ obtained in the work with seed potatoes. . POULTRY, . . Inheritance of Egg Production. — The work under this pro - ject has been carried on for a number of years in an effort to produce birds of greater laying ability. During the past year a progeny test was made of the breed - ing influence of six different Single Comb White Leghorn males, mated with hens of equal laying and breeding ability. The percentage of good laying daughters sired by these birds ranged f rota ,11.1 to 54.3. In a similar test with 5 Rhode 1 Island- Red males -.the percentage * of good laying daughters ranged from 33.3 to 56.2. Work is being done in selecting breeding birds on the basis of size, quality, and numbers of eggs. In this work the size of hen and the rate of maturity, as well as the size of egg, </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station have been studied in a flock of Single Comb White Leghorns. Nutrient Requirements for Growing Chicks. — During the ' past year several phases of this project were continued. In one experiment excessive amounts of calcium and phosphorus were added to a basal ration which had given good results without; the mineral additions. The basal ration, complete for essential vitamines and proteins, was made of yellow cornmeal 45 parts, ground wheat 22 parts, yeast 3 parts, cod liver oil 2 parts, meat meal 20 parts, and cornstarch 8 parts. As min - eral elements were added to the basal ration, an equivalent amount of starch was withdrawn, thus retaining the same vitamine and protein plane in all lots. The addition of cal - cium carbonate materially changed the calcium-phosphorus ratio of the original basic ration. The addition of 4 per cent of calcium carbonate very appreciably checked the growth rate, and an addition of 8 per cent of calcium carbonate was quite disastrous. It does not appear, however, that the disturb - ance of tlv calcium-phosphorus ratio was in itself the dis - turbing factoi', since subsequent experiments in which the calcium-phosphorus ratio was markedly changed by the addi - tion of sodium phosphate did not similarly inhibit the growth rate or cause rickets. The addition of" 8 parts of raw bone-meal to the basal ration increased the total calcium and phosphorus content of the ration with but a slight change of the calcium-phosphorus ratio. Eighty-eight per cent of the chicks on this ration de - veloped typical cases of rickets. The results indicate that the common opinion that excess mineral elements make for safety in chick nutrition and. at most, can do no harm, seems ill-founded. A study of bone deterioration in crate-fed poultry was made with four crates of 1.9 pound cockerels, fed under close con - finement and without direct sunlight, for 29 clays. The feed - ing ration was 60 parts yellow cornmeal and 40 parts whits shorts moistened with buttermilk. Three crates received ad - ditional mineral and irradiated cornmeal. Average gains of 64 per cent were obtained. Bone-breaking tests and X-ray photographs showed no evidence of bone deterioration, either in the check lots or those receiving additional minerals or ir - radiated corn oil. The addition of 3 per cent of a mineral mixture of raw bone (60), calcium carbonate (20), common salt (20), was, with respect to our basal ration, entirely su - perfluous, tho apparently not harmful in the quantity used. A study of the vitamine content of germinated oats indi - cated that germination increased the vitamine B content but not the vitamine A content. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">■;■',"-■' Forty-first Annual Report In a comparison of a simple chick-mash mixture with a more complex mixture, both fed at the same protein plane, no advantage was found for the complex mixture. Turkey Production.— A study of the weight loss of turkfey eggs under different conditions of incubation showed that the average weight loss from the first to the 24th day was 12.7 per cent of the initial weight. This approximates the loss in hen eggs for the first. 18 days of incubation. When artificial methods of hatching are used the moisture problem requires special attention under our conditions., Sand tray moisture pans proved satisfactory for this purpose. When hatching conditions were optimum, the poults during the past year averaged 66 per cent as much weight as the eggs from which they were hatched. Previous work indicates that blackhead in turkeys can be controlled by sanitation. Special attention given this point this year shows more progress in this direction. RURAL ECONOMICS Farm Tenure. — The work under this project has been con - tinued under a narrowed study called "Cost and Standards of Living on Nebraska Farms". During the past year one manu - script on "The Cost of Feeding the Nebraska Farm Family" was presented and published as Nebraska Bulletin No. 219. This bulletin takes into account the different kinds of food consumed on the farm, as well as the dollar cost of same. Some data are also being obtained on the cost of housing the Nebraska farm family. Cost of Producing Farni Crops. — Under this project record books are furnished to the farmers for keeping labor and other costs in connection with the production of crops. Farm - ers have taken keen interest in the work of keeping the re - cords and during the past year there have been completed 128 records for corn, 26 for oats, 10 for wheat, and 26 on the use of tractors. Data from these are being assembled and an - alyzed. In connection with this study there is also being carried a study of farm organization in relation to net returns. This phase of the study takes into consideration different systems of farm organization as well as different lines of farming. During the past year a co-operative arrangement with the Dairy Development Society has been entered into whereby the society is to obtain records in certain sections of the state which will permit special study on dairy farms. • - ■"• ■■ ■: ■■■'■■. . ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production and Pur - chasing Power of Farm Products.— -Concerning these projects, several bulletins have already been issued, numbers 187, 198 and 208. Very little work was clone during the past year, lne tabular matter accumulated from beef cattle prices has been brought up to date and some work done in assembling it in manuscript form. Nebraska Farm Land Prices.— Under this project the con - sideration involved in nearly every farm transfer by warranty deed has been secured from nine Nebraska counties and some additional data from two other counties. The data obtained make it possible to determine for each year of the historv of the county studied the number of farm land transfers "the total and average acreage, the total and the acre value and the relation of size of farm to the acre value. The data ob - tained are being analyzed and prepared for publication. Cnmhhu Harre»tvr Sfwrf/V«._Thru the co-operation of the Agricultural Engineering Department and the U. S Depart - ment ot Agriculture, some work has been done on the use of combines in harvesting wheat in Nebraska. The preliminary studies have been assembled and published as a U. S. Bulletin entitled Harvesting Wheat in Nebraska with a Combine Harvester Thresher . n c M l rh V f«»'*---L'nder this project a study has been made ' ot the trend of the prices of farm products together with their production and movement. From the analysis of these data is prepared a mimeographed circular, "The Nebraska Economic Situation", which is issued monthly "thru the Ex - tension Service. A study of the shrinkage of corn in cribs has been under way during the past year, but no data are yet available Fur - ther work was done on the study of protein as a wheat market factor The data obtained along this line have been assembled tor publication. SERUM PRODUCTION During the past year there was no general epidemic of hog cholera in the state. Several localized outbreaks were re - ported in different sections but these were evidently- confined to comparatively small areas thru immediate vaccination. ™Vt e hr U u O u d t iUyr 6 ""^ ilTe * Ular demand f ° r Sel " Um and The State Serum Plant carried a liberal reserve of serum in storage during the year and all orders coming to it were filled promptly. The policy of purchasing serum subject to </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forty-first Annual Report retesf was continued. The virus was manufactured in the state plant. The retail price of blood serum from March 1st to the close of the year was 75 cents per 100 c.c. The price of concen - trated clear serum was $1.00 per 100 c.c, and of virus, $1.50 per 100 c.c. The following is a complete record of the activities during the past year: .. Cubic centimeters Serum on hand January 1, 1927 , J . 3,630,200 Serum purchased during 1927 14,517,525 Total serum handled for year .' 18,147,725 Serum and virus sold by months: , Serum Virus c.c c.c. January ..........:.X.. .....j. 181,100 10,280 February L I 127,700 7,890 March . 158,030 7,650 April '. 1 180,175 9,250 May : 956,300 66,315 June :.2,544,675 165,215 July 1.1,693,800 107,365 August 2,129.325 127,235 September 1,539*,675 83,500 October : 1,134,950 61,635 November ....: 569,575 35,205 December . ,.. 389,380 28,258 11,604,685 709,798 Used by plant..... 100,200 11,530 11,704,885 721,328 Serum on hand January 1, 1928 ....„ 6,442,840 c.c. Total gross sales from all sources $100,518.01 Money collected and .receipted lor 101,480.43 Cash balance January 1, 1928, according to re - port of bursar ■■ £47,384.03 Value stock invoice January 1, 1928... . 45,099.88 Accounts payable January 1, 1928, with Farm Bureaus ....: | ;..■....• . . 2,250.37 Number of pigs used at plant for testing serum and making virus :....'. '.&gt; .... 768 Number of orders for year. , 1 .'...2,873 NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Following the very dry year of 1926 in which crop yields were low, very ..little reserve soil moisture was carried . over. There was, however, sufficient surface moisture to give good germination, to fall-seeded grain and good winter sur - vival. Early spring rains were satisfactory, but dry condi - tions in May were severe for small grafn. This set-back was </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station largely overcome in June and fair yields of all crops were ob - . LTotthe^fX 0^.^ made P ° SSi " le giV " AGRONOMY tii? UCh tK Of tv the n agr ? nOn J 1^ VOrk of this station is in co-opera - tior with the Dry Land Office and Office of Cereal Crops In - vestigations of the U. S. Department of Agriculture; some of it now having been in operation for 21 years The most pronounced difference in tillage practices for the year was between early and late fall plowing. On late fall Plowmg poor stands of winter wheat were secured and 8 plats so treated gave an average yield of 7.6 bushels per acre A vZ a lAT7 °h f , ear ' y fall -P» owed Pl«t« gave'an average &gt;ield of 18./ bushels per acre. The difference was less for SSr^ll^Sf m a " -^ S ™ obtained importance than the method by which it is secured On dfskej corn stubble the yields of winter wheat were °5 bShel. greater than where it was seeded in stubble without disking In the study of the effect of previous crops on small Brain production it was found that the yields o ? f a crop were higher following a cultivated crop than where they followed small gram. This is in accordance with results obtaSed at Irowfn °th thl ' U PaSt yearS - CrOps on land oontSSSsS growing the same crop for 21 years gave less vields than where they were in rotation. This difference shoS up' in corn yields as well as in yields of small grain Variety yield tests were continued with 22 varieties of win ter wheat, 14 of spring wheat, 19 barleys 15 varieties of oats and 16 of corn. The 8 higher yielding varietS of corn were within V ., bushels of the same yield Among these were 3 out of 6 inbred crosses, one of which unde^i rigation has held first place at the station for two consecutive Ws Pnnp Irrigation.— The work of crop production under irri - gation has been increased. From this work it is attempted to deternune the cost of pumping and spreading the Tater as P e e ctecl S C ° Ver th&lt;&gt; inCreaSe in yiekl Wh^ h may be 'ex! _ During the current crop year 37 L, acres of corn under irrigation averaged 63 bushels per acre. Without irrigation water and under comparable conditions, the corn vie I was 42 bushels per acre The maximum yiekl of corn was on alfalfa sod with one fall and three summer irrigations, totaling a P </seg>
            <seg id="p037">• Forty-first Annual Report &gt; ■&gt; ■ • . ■ . ■ proximately 19 inches 6f water and yielding 102.4 bushels per acre. Ensilage corn gave an average of 15.7 tons per acre with irrigation as compared with 5.5 tons without, and 4.5 acres of potatoes under irrigation averaged 312.5 bushels. LIVESTOCK PRODUCTION Beef Cattle. — Two purebred herds of beef cattle are main - tained — one each of Hereford and Shorthorn cattle. Up to the present time these have served largely for demonstra - tional purposes and as a source of purebred stock for this community. During the fiscal year a beef cattle barn was built for experimental and breeding purposes. Sheds to this barn with feed lots . are contemplated in the near future. These will permit some experimental feeding. Dairying. — The dairy herd at the station has continued to make splendid progress. The entire herd is Holstein and has been developed from a few females purchased 13 years ago. Among the 26 cows of special record there is only one not sired by a University of Nebraska bred bull. The following is a brief account of this herd, recently published in the Holstein World. "On September 15, 1927, there, were in the University of Nebraska North Platte Substation Holstein herd 26 females on which the Holstein-Friesian Advanced Registry Associa - tion had reported semi-official 365-day records. The only other females in the herd are the old 15-year-old foundation ■ cow . Topsy', 6 heifers in their first lactation periods, and younger heifers. 'Topsy' was never on yearly test. No fe - males have been sold from the herd during the past year, and no female has been purchased since the purchase of the orig - inal foundation cows about 13 years ago. "The average of the highest milk records of each of the 26 equals 20,000 pounds. The average of the highest 365-day butter records of 16 "exceeds 1000. pounds. The average of the highest 7-day butter records . of 21 exceeds 30 pounds. There are ten in the herd each of which has a 365-day butter record in excess of 1000 pounds. One of these is a heifer still on test. A conservative estimate of her production for the year gives an average for the 10 of 1127 pounds. Two more heifers will join the thousand pound group before January 1, 1928, barring accident. "The average of the highest butter records of the 26, 6 being made as full age cows, 7 as 4-year-olds, 3 as 3-year-olds, 4 as heifers, still on test, is 959 pounds." During the development of this herd most of the better </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station male offspring and many young heifers have been sold to far - mers within the state. Horses. — No special work is being done at the substation with horses, except in a co-operative study with the Depart - ment of Animal Pathology (Project No. 137). Under this study a number of horses have been fed various supposedly poisonous plants in the hopes of solving a so-called horse dis - ease quite common to certain sections of western Nebraska. Hogs. — The work on hogs at this station has been carried for many years, the hogs being grown both for experimental purposes and for sale to farmers of the locality for founda - tion stock. During the past year 10 lots of 20 pigs each were carried in dry lot and alfalfa pasture studies. In both cases these lots received rations varying from corn on the alfalfa pasture to the inclusion in the rations of different amounts of tankage and cottonseed meal. The results are not yet available. Poultry. — A poultry plant, taking care of both chickens and turkeys, is maintained. The work with the flocks is for demonstrational purposes and to provide foundation stocks for the locality. No experimental work has been undertaken up to the present time. HORTICULTURAL FORESTRY Considerable effort at the station is being devoted to the growing of vegetables, flowers, shrubs, and trees, mainly from a demonstrational standpoint. A considerable number of both Austrian and Scotch pines have been grown from seed and will be used for forest plantings on the rougher lands on the station farm. SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION The work at this station deals with irrigation farming and is carried on in co-operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. During the past season work was continued along lines previously determined. In the spring of 1926 ad - ditional work in crop rotation and manuring was inaugurated. This new work involves 28 plats of one-fourth acre each, and 10 cropping systems. Crop Production.— The spring of 1926 was dry until the second week of May, after which liberal amounts of moisture were obtained and crops made good progress. On June 15th a severe hail storm, accompanied by a heavy downpour of rain, did extensive damage to the crops at the station and considerable to crops in the surrounding territory. This storm was followed in a few days by heavy winds," and ad - ditional damage was don« by blowing, necessitating the re- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-first Annual. Report seeding of some beets and the substitution of corn or potatoes where beets could not be replanted. The rest of the season was favorable for crop production until a severe freeze came on September 23 to 25. This materially reduced the yield of sugar beets and potatoes. The yield of all crops was compar - atively low. The average yields on the station were : potatoes 275.9 bushels, sugar beets 13.53 tons, corn 24 bushels, oats 34.5 bushels, wheat 8.1 bushels. The comparatively low yields of corn and small grain were largely the result of the spring storm. In a test to determine the best time for planting and for digging potatoes, the yields decreased with successive planting dates from May 12 to July 1. Planting after June 11th gave very low yields. In the time-of-digging test, the lowest yields of marketable tubers were obtained on the first harvesting date, August 3, the marketable tubers increasing from 32 bushels on that date to 365 on September 22, for Triumphs, and from 111 bushels to 460 bushels for Cobblers. Lamb Feeding. — During the year 13 lots of 25 lambs each ' were fed different rations. The lamb-feeding work has been carried on for several years. The data obtained during the past year are not available at the present time. The results of all lamb-feeding work will probably be assembled for pub - lication during the coming year. Dairying. — The station dairy herd consists of 12 cows with a yearly average production of 383 pounds of butterfat. These cows are kept. under farm conditions, the primary pur - poses being as a demonstration of good farm practice and the furnishing to the community of purebred dairy stock. About half of the cows are purebred and the bulls from the better cows are loaned to the farmers in the vicinity when they be - come of serviceable age. Hogs. — Between 15 and 20 brood sows are kept on the farm. Both spring and fall farrowing are practiced. The pigs are used for experimental purposes in pasturing and fat - tening rations, .the object being to find out the most profitable method of handling both spring and fall farrowed pigs. Sev - eral tests were made during the past year, including both dry lot and pasture feeding. An interesting feature in one test was relative to the cost of gains on pigs from mature sows compared with the cost of gains on the progeny of gilts. The cost per 100 pounds of gain was materially higher with the pigs from the young sows than with those from older sows. Poultry. — The poultry work at the station consists of both </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station chicken and turkey raising for demonstrational purposes. The chicken flock consists of approximately 200 hens, and about 10 turkey hens are carried for breeding stock. This work has proved very popular with the farmers in the vicinity. VALENTINE SUBSTATION During the past year weather conditions were quite un - favorable for crop production. 'The growing season of 1926 was very dry and the soil went into the winter with almost no available moisture in it. During the following March and April there was an excess of rainfall; then the season turned dry. Crop Production. — Experimental work with crops has been carried on as previously outlined. As is generally recognized, the soils of the station farm are not well adapted to the pro - duction of crops. Some work is done in co-operation with the farmers on the harder land just north of the station. In a variety test of various crops, Kanred and Nebraska 60 were the high yielding winter wheats, Rosen Rye among the ryes, Nebraska 21 and White Burt among the oats, and two barbless varieties of barley gave promising results. In a test of forage crops, ordinary amber cane gave the highest tonnage, millet the lowest, and Sudan grass intermed - iate. The yields of all were low on account of weather condi - tions, and those drilled on the land rather than planted in rows and cultivated were practically failures. The work in meadow improvement has been continued. Disking the sod again proved beneficial in obtaining a stand. The inclusion of red and alsike clover in the native meadows gave an increase of 65 per cent in total hay yield. During the current year this station co-operated in some further studies on native hay production in the Elkhorn river valley. Dairy Cattle.— The herd at this station is handled as a farm herd, being milked only twice a day. Thirteen daugh - ters of Varsity Derby Allen 256012, completing two-year-old records, show an increase over their dams' two-year-old re - cords of 40 per cent in milk and 42 per cent in fat The average production for the entire herd for the year was 415 pounds of fat. The project comparing production and cost of ten Holsteins with seven grade Shorthorns showed an additional profit above cost of feed of $34.89 per head in favor of the Holsteins. Beef Cattle.— A project inaugurated during the past year on the wintering of beef calves is providing one of the most popular projects ever carried on at this station. For this test four wintering lots were prepared with shelter </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Forty-first Annual Report sheds, a windbreak, and open 1 feed-bunks. The calves were fed as follows: Lot 1, prairie hay Lot 2, prairie hay and 1 lb. cottonseed cake Lot 3, prairie hay and V/» tons per head of cottonseed cake Lot 4, mixed native hay The winter gain per calf for the 150 days on feed was: For Lot 1, 25.4 pounds For Lot 2, 174.4 pounds For Lot 3, 190.9 pounds • For Lot 4, 155.5 pounds The daily hay consumption per head fed, ad lib., was 9.1, 12.1, 11.3; and 12.6 pounds for the four lots respectively. After wintering, the calves from these four lots were turned : into a uniform pasture, to determine the summer gain. It is expected, after summer pasturage closes, to weigh them and then ship to the main station for further observation as to whether or not the calves in Lot 1 will overcome the handicap placed upon them by the poor ration of prairie hay alone. The results obtained in Lot 4 indicate the importance of seed - ing clover into the native meadows wherever advisable. Poultry, — The poultry work at this station consists of a demonstration flock of turkeys, the larger portion of which are hatched and brooded artificially. Incubator hatches var - ied from 50 to 75 per cent hatches, early hatches turning out the best. A 6 per cent loss occurred thru blackhead, most of . the loss coming at the time the poults were 8 to 10 weeks old and again at fattening time. " . ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT During the last fiscal year there have been completed the following buildings: A seed house at the North Platte Station, at a cost of $2500. A bdef cattle barn at the North Platte Station, at a cost of ?7500.. A second beef cattle barn at the Experimental Farms near Lincoln, costing $4800. NEEDS OF THE EXPERIMENT STATION Plans are being made for three new greenhouse units at the main station and a herdsman's cottage at the Experi - mental Farms near Lincoln. Among the most urgent needs in the physical plant of the Experiment Station are sheep barns and sheds at the main . station, a new well, additional lots and hog houses at the Ex - perimental Farms near Lincoln, and an experimental feeding shed and new corral fences at North Platte. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station new legislation Several bills were passed during the last legislature which have some relationship to, and effect upon, the work of the Agricultural Experiment Station The Nebraska Nursery Bill, House Roll 538, places the in - spection and certification work in the State Department of Agriculture, thus relieving the Experiment Station of per - forming this service. A quarantine bill. Senate File 138, places within the De - partment of Agriculture and other state offices the power to make quarantines. In the placing of quarantines the Station is not involved beyond its advisory capacity A serum bill House Roll 624, supplied a fund of $30,000 tor he use ot the regents in supplying storage facilities for handling serum, any balance of the fund to be placed in the hog cholera serum revolving fund An emergency bill, House Roll 549, appropriated $25,000 to be used by the State Department of Agriculture in meeting fnto the state mei " genCy &amp; * the * dvent ° f the corn ' b ° re * CHANGES IN STAFF Resignations: F ' ?L Coe ' Assifi tant in Horticulture, effective September 1, Appointments: W 'ber"l Y S27 ' Assistant '" Horticult "'-e. effective Septem- PUBLICATIONS Statin? 6 Vari ° US pub » ications ai ' e iss "ed by the Experiment ohfl «!rf a " noun f ceme "t 1S ™&lt; e to the public and they mav be obtained free of cost by writing to the Director of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station, at Lincoln. In addition to, the publications put out by the Experiment Station, numerous articles, generally of a technical nature, SEdTvSJS iZ bers of the station staff and v»b - those named in the RESEARCH BULLETINS «J?°~ i n'n^ lfalfa InV f U S at ' ons - T. A. Kiesaelbach and Arthur Ander - 1926. C0P ' eS ' ePt6d f ° r publication Ju^. 1926. December, </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Forty-first Annual Report . No 37, Studies on the Ascaris Lumbricoides.. H. M. Martin. 5,000 copies. Accepted for publication June, 1926. December, 1926. No. 38, Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. F. E. Mussehl. 5,000 copies. December, 1926. ■ „ . . . No. 39, The Differential Reaction of Strains Within a Variety of Wheat to Physiologic Forms of Puccinia Graminis Triticu T. A. Kies - selbach and George L. Peltier. 6,000 copies. December, 1926. No. 40, The Pine Tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest. M. H. Swenk. 3,000 copies. April, 1927. . No. 41, Further Experiments with Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers. M. H. Swenk. 3,000 copies. May, 1927. No. 42, Stem Rust in Nebraska. Part I, General Survey of Sources; Part II, Identification of the Physiologic Forms of Puccinia Granwus from Various Sources. George L. Peltier and A. F. Thiel. 5,000 copies. July, 1927. BULLETINS No. 214, Pork Production at the North Platte Substation. W. P. Snyder. 8,000 copies. November, 1926. No. 215, A Survey of the Cattle Industry in the Nebraska Sand Hills. Harold Hedges. 5,000 copies. October, 192G. No. 216, Lamb Feeding Experiments in the Sugar Beet Growing Dis - tricts. James A. Holden. 5,000 copies. November, 1926. No. 217, Cottage Cheese Manufacture in Dairy Plants. E. L. Reichart and H. 'P. Davis. 5,000 copies. January, 1927. No. 218, Field Experiments with. Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants. T. A. Kiesselbach.- 7,000 copies. May, 1927. No.- 219, The Cost of Feeding the Nebraska Farm Family. A Com - parison of Costs and Standards of Food Consumption of Owners, Part - owners, and Tenants. J. 0. Rankin. 5,000 copies. June, 1927. ■ No. 220, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-26. Rules for Official Tractor Testing and the Nebraska Tractor Law. Board of Tractor Test Engi - neers: Oscar W. Sjogren, E. E. Brackett, C. W. Smith; Engineer in Charge of Tests, H. L. Wallace; Assistant in.Tractor Tests, F. N. Laub. 5,000 copies. June, 1927. No. 221, Protein as a Wheat Price Factor. Harold Hedges. 3,000 copies. July, 1927. . , . , No. 222, Alfalfa in Nebraska. T. A. Kiesselbach and Arthur Ander - son. 10,000 copies. July, 1927. . EXPERIMENT STATION CIRCULARS / No. 34, Turkey Production. F. E. Mussehl. 10,000 copies. July, 1926 ■ ' • ' * No. 35, Babcock Testing — Principles and Uses. L. K. Crowe and H. P. Davis. 10,000 copies. April, 1927. TECHNICAL PAPERS No. 26, The Robinson Method for. the Determination of Clay. E. B. Engle, D. R. Yoder. American Society of Agronomy. July 16, 1926. No. 27, The Farm Crops Laboratory. F. D. Keim. American Society ' of Agronomy. November 8, 1926. No. 28, The Relation of Root Development and Time of Seeding to - Winter Survival of Fall Seeded Grasses and Legumes. F. D. Keim. G. W, Beadle. Ecology. November 8, 1926. No. 29, Curing Alfalfa Hay. T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson. Journal American Society of Agronomy. November 9, 1926. 706857 A ■ . . . : . ■ • • . . . ■ . . . '..... </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station M N J°; rL/r 0 r^'hh^H (&lt;f Gluten in Wheat Flour. 30 l»2fi "• "• Platcnlus - Cereal Chemistry. November B.k"AK Teit^M.' jI'bW" 'rl.,-^ S A and ? r t dizati S, n ° f th « Experimental V ip I- V. .' ' "■ "• ' llial &lt; hemistry. February 2 1&lt;I27 t|: :!^. rHsa art &amp;::,« js% Sc™^ Flr \V'T S X ( ; t \ ; niliryinE - "• R Davis ' Jou «-nal of Dairy Socfetv'RTpo'rr"^ '" HiZ6 - F - M ' r ""' Nebraska S^te Horticultural c. T c he &amp; ;rK£r a Ho^c A u ?^ fl r&amp;r raska AppIe Grew - ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly newsnaners especially those papers located within the state have sho^ &amp;Kaf ™ ° f /V° rk ° f the Ex P e n^ent Static™ giving libeial space to the experimental work reDortpr? nnW knoSe^ faCi ' itating the eXtensi °" of -eful'Scultu^l </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Forty-first Annual Report THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal yeav ended June 30, 1927, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total j .' $15,000.00 ■ • &gt; . Expenditures For salaries '. ..... $15,000.00 Total : 515,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the .State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1927, under act of Congress approved March 16, 1900. Total..: , $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries. I. .-. $15,000.00 Total.. , :.... , $15,000.00 PURNELL FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who' is also the treasurer ' of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1927, under act of Congress approved ' February 24, 1925. Total. $30,000.00 Expenditures Salaries ,." $20,480.01 Supplies Office supplies ....,.§ 275.44 Laboratory supplies 547.75 Educational supplies. 34.37 Janitor and barn supplies ; 3.35 Feeding stuffs , .....' 2,842.55 Agricultural supplies .... .::....... 55.72 Total ..\ $ 3,759.18 Expense' Postage, telegraph, and telephone: $ 73.00 Freight, express, and drayage 17.52 Heat, light, and power 2.94 Public printing, advertising, and photo supplies , '. .'.". 332.40 Traveling expense........... 1,066.35 Special and temporary services 2,298.34 Miscellajie.ous ...:. ' 1.51 Total.......' : $ 3,792.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT— (Continued) Repairs Equipment $ 92.63 Total 5 92.63 Equipment Furniture and fixtures .... $ 265.63 Apparatus 1,457.13 Livestock 05.00 Machinery 86.16 Books, magazines, and maps 2.20 Total $ 1,876.12 Grand Total $30,000 00 L. E. GUNDERSON, . f T ■ , ., , , Finance Secretary. At Lincoln, .Nebraska, January 20, 1928. FINANCIAL STATEMENT— (Continued) Expenditures for Agricultural Experiment Station for the year ended June 30, 1927 (exclusive of Federal funds). SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees $100,991.84 Temporary employees 1,536.55 ?102,528.39 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 788.09 Laboratory supplies 7,066.53 £ ue \ 1,446.18 Food stuff 1,741.09 Educational and recreational . 230.84 Janitor and barn 235 20 Feeding stuffs 31,940 52 Agricultural supplies 7,179.91 Total $ 50,634.36. EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ 1,090.08 Freight, express, and drayage 1,647.36 Water, heat, light, and power 3,526.39 Public printing, adv., and photo 4,675.94 Traveling expense 3 191 14 Rentals "'" ' 46i66 Special and temporary services 25,375.31 Miscellaneous 729.83 Total 40,282.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">. Forty-first Annual Report l "•'• ' REPAIRS Buildings .........? 3,154.66 Lands : ..:. :... 546.28 Equipment ...:.: .'. ...:.:....... 3,947.68 Total ■;, ...:. .....:..,..,....... "" ' 7,648.62 EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures ... § 1,248.17 Apparatus (labor and equipment)..: 3,844.41 Livestock :... 14,104.54 Machinery, tools. -..: 3,248.92 Books, magazines, maps = 393.50 Educational specimens.... , 8.00 Total... , ;".• ■ 22,847.54 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land- improvement ■. .-..? 1,018.41 Orig-inal construction 688.20 , •'■-■. Total 1,700.61 GRAND TOTAL ,. $225,648.23 This includes expenditures for the central station at the Agricultural Campus, and the substations at Scottsbluff, North Platte, and Valentine. L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. At Lincoln, Nebraska, January 20, 1928. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>