<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH BULLETIN Published quarterly at the office of the Secretary of the Board, Seward, Nebraska. Entered as second class matter, February 6th, 1914, at tbe Post - office, Seward, Nebraska, under the act of July 16th, 1894. VOLUME 2 OCTOBER, 1J15 NO. 4 This Bulletin will be sent free to any person within the State upon request C. T. BURCHARD, M. D.. President, Falls City E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Vice-President, Lincoln L. STARK, M. D., Treasurer, Hartlngton H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Secretary, Seward BOARD OF HEALTH JOHN H. MOREHEAD, Governor WILLIS E. REED, Atty. General. A. O. THOMAS, Supt. Pub. Instr. J. D. CASE, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln WM. F. WILD, M. D., Director Bacteriological Laboratory, Lincoln Most of the trouble in the world is caused by germs, and human beings. SECRETARIES </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">BIRTH REGISTRATION TEST IN NEBRASKA This paper will open with that which may seem to be the ex - pression of a most unpatriotic sentiment, and yet before its close, the writer hopes and expects, to be credited with impulses of an exactly opposite nature. Quoting from the Bureau of Census, "The era of modern sanitary civilization may be marked by the dates upon which various countries began to record infant mor - tality. Some countries — China, Turkey and the United States, even yet possess no records of infant mortality. Unless the American people wake up China and Turkey will have satisfac - tory data long before the United States." Let me ask you to carry in mind this association of our own wonderful country with the land of the unspeakable Turk, and the wide wasted do - main of pest-ridden China. Let the comparison rankle and bite. Let the bare thought of such association rankle in our souls, let the disgrace of such people forging ahead of us in the mere mat - ter of vital statistics bite into our conscience until we as a people come to our senses and demand that our government make laws which will push us ahead out of the delinquent zone, becau.se they are enforced. Assuming now, that the old-time, worn out fire-cracker patriot - ism we regard as belonging to July fourth and no other day in the year, may rationally give way to a very personal sense of civic responsibility. We stand where we can advocate, perhaps demand that children be given their rights as potential citizens. It is with this laudable purpose in view that the birth registra - tion test has been undertaken in Nebraska under the guidance of Miss Julia Lathrop, Chief of the Children's Bureau of the U. S. government ; which work is to be carried on by a number of Nebraska women who stand for that higher patriotism which in turn stands for state pride and a conviction that justice must be done — even to the least of these — the little ones. Ever since the world went to housekeeping attempts have been made by progressive nations to keep vital statistics; the Egyptians, Greeks and Romans made census enumeration and notably the Romans required registration of births and deaths, perhaps the first of the great nations to do this bookkeeping of humanity, as it has been called. During the last century and a half, and particularly the last fifty years, the treatment of vital statistics has been undergoing a rapid change. In September of 1912 there met in the city of Washington the International Con - gress of Hygiene and Demography (or vital statistics) whose first meeting was held in Brussels in 1852. To this Congress, Ne - braska sent six delegates to mingle with the students of this sub- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OP HEALTH ject from all over the world, among whom were numbered a con - siderable group of club women. Let me quote Dr. Wolcott of Massachusetts in his welcome address as President of this Con - gress: "The discoveries in the astronomical observatory have no more certain application to navigation, nor chemical research to manufacture, than have the statistics of life and death to the protection of the human race." In 1903, a joint resolution in Congress approved the enactment of uniform registration laws in every state in the Union with the idea in view that our country would not fall back or rather stay back abreast of China and Turkey. Along these lines in 1912, at the San Francisco Biennial of the General Federation of Woman's Clubs was the resolution passed as follow*: "Whereas, accurate registration of births and deaths is the essential basis for intelligent efforts to conserve infant life, to secure the education of all children and to protect their working life and legal rights, therefore be it resolved that the General Federation of Woman's Clubs requests the Chil - dren's Bureau to prepare in brief form for popular distribution such material as may be available concerning the present degree of registration of births and deaths in this country and the best method of securing complete returns." Here then is the excuse which club women and others have for undertaking to put our bookkeeping for humanity on a business-like foundation. Now, for some of the reasons why it is desirable, necessary and urgent, first let us hear from Miss Lathrop. "Most of us are very much shocked," she says, "to find that in the ten years between 1900 and 1910, there came into the world at least two and one - half million children who died before they were one year old. slipping into life and slipping out again, unknown and unnum - bered in any public way." Did it every occur to you that every operation but one in our lives is conducted by the civil and religious authorities com - bined T And that single exception is birth. When we die the church and the state bid us Godspeed with a passport to the great beyond in the form of a death certificate and a burial permit. For your own satisfaction, look over a standard death certificate and note all the questions to be answered regarding that which has gone, which is no more. These items are neces - sary, of course, for no civilized country can afford to be without statistical information as to the cause of deaths ; but by the same reasoning how can any civilized country afford to be without statistics of birth t How can any parent, how can any child af - ford to be without some record of his appearance on earth? To the writer, it seems almost ludicrous that the operation of birth should be unnoticed by the civil authorities and only noted by those religious organizations whose church laws demand a record </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 5 of baptisms. Thanks be that there existed some churches with some such laws, notably those of England where registration dates back to 1538 when Thomas Cromwell, Vicar-General to Henry VIII issued an injunction to all parishes in England and Wales requiring the clergy to enter on Sunday, records of bap - tisms, marriages and deaths of the preceding week and fixing a penalty of three shillings three pence in default of observance. Take the operation of marriage — here we must qualify and re - ceive permission from the State before we join together as man and wife, and we may dispense with church sanction if we wish ; but State sanction we must have. Hence our state knows who marries and who does not ; but the natural issue of marriage, the child, comes among us unnoticed except among the very few whd understand the importance of registering the arrival for record purposes. The dead receive their passports, those con - templating matrimony are licensed as if about to embark on a business enterprise ; but the little helpless newcomer — with his whole life ahead of him — and the whole world to conquer — does anyone give him clearance papers against the time when his little bark shall leave the mother port to sail forth on un - known seas? Dr. John Fulton, a noted physician of Baltimore says, "the private interest of the citizen in registration of births is superior to his interest in registration of deaths, for a greater proportion of his privileges, immunities, rights and duties, turn - ing upon the question of his age and parentage, are definitely conserved by the registration of his birth." It is said of the south the first question asked a newcomer is "'Who was your grandfather!" While in the west, "Who are yon?" Now, the writer maintains that the question of the south is a perfectly proper question, for without information on that score how is one to answer the question of the West "Who are you?" Well, who are you anyway? Does anybody know but your parents and are they alive today so they can tell you who you are? Did they duly set it down in the family Bible, and did the house burn down with the Bible, or did an older brother wanting to keep you out of your father's money as long as he could, tear out that particular page from the Bible! This hap - pened in Indiana — though the girl knew she was eighteen, but she must prove it in court and could not. The unwritten book of humanity is overflowing with instances like this where the inheritance went astray all for lack of a few penstrokes on a standard birth certificate. Lost! one perfectly good steed from the stable for lack of a padlock, is an item to* be found down all the ages since the world went to housekeeping. But this Indiana case was finally justified, and how? Because an old person happened to recall that a blooded cow had a calf the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH 6 same day the girl was born whose estates were in dispute and perhaps the farm books would show the calf's birthday. They did. The girl received her patrimony. Now, don't laugh. This is serious business. Maybe we never could sell that calf unless we recorded its birth and calves cost money you know. Its dif - ferent when a daughter is born; we can get a daughter for nothing, but a pedigreed calf! Calls to mind a story about the governor of a southern state, who was inquisitive about the neces - sity of enforcing the registration of births and deaths, but who seemed convinced that there was some slight degree of reason for the enforcement when it was delicately put to him that the state had enforced registration law for stallions and hogs. The writer is tompted to quote a newspaper telegram of March 24th, from Lincoln as follows: "The thoroughbred hog with a pedigree and the unregistered poor man without a pedigree fought it out on the floor of the house today and both won. The hog won first when an appropriation for $80,000 was up for the building of a hog barn at the state fair grounds and the appropriation won. The poor man without a pedigree and a slim pocket - book won in the second round but it was a close call and a bitter fight. The matter was up on an appro - priation of $150,000 for the erection of a public hos - pital in Omaha, and charges were made that the friends of the hog and the friends of the poor man had tied up for mutual benefits." ■ Now. let the friends of the hog and the friends of the poor man tie up for the benefit of the babes unborn in Nebraska, so that when we shall have entered into that last real estate trans - action of ours, we will accept our passports into the unknown country with the knowledge that Nebraska childhood has not been mortgaged because of our shortsightedness — that no handi - cap, whether it be disease, heredity or environment shall have held a lien on that portion of our citizenship which at one and the same time is the most promising and the most helpless. And we will have plenty of help: no need to go it alone for the peo - ple who think are on our side: listen to the roster; social work - ers, health officers, labor leaders, employers of labor, business men, insurance men. school authorities, factory inspectors, pub - lic officials, lawyers and the great organizations to which these people belong, all urge accurate birth registration as essential to intelligent government and sound conduct of the people's business. Do you want your child kept out of school because yon cannot prove he is old enough to attend 1 Or do you want </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 7 him kept in school when he is old enough to be released in case you need his help as a bread winner f Are you satisfied to see child labor flourish when a birth certificate would settle the dispute and keep the child in school ? As a laborer yourself do you want to lose your job because child labor is cheaper than yours and no one can prove the child who took your place should be in school T Are you interested that prosecutions dealing with the age of consent should be settled by record and not by con - jecture? Would it concern you that litigation over matters of inheritance as in the Indiana case could be simplified by recorded data as to the ages of litigants? If you are a foreigner, are you anxious for your American born children to have indisputable evidence of American birth, which will protect them from en - forced military service wheD visiting the old countries? Did you ever hear of blindness in a new born babe going unchecked with fatal results because' of mid-wife attendance and no registering of the birth? You and I pay taxes to support a state institution for the blind, most of whom would have kept their eyesight if medical care had been given within one week of birth. Do you know that mothers and babes lives might be saved among the very poor if every birth were registered? It would mean some - thing for the nation's citizenship if the sad procession of the little white hearses could be interrupted. Do you realize that death registration without birth registration is like noting your expenditures without recording your income? Rather a poor way to do the bookkeeping for humanity? And do you under - stand the reasons for the very existence of the Children's Bureau of the United States government? Do you know that it was founded and that it exists so that the nation's greatest asset — the child — may continue to be an asset instead of becoming a liability, and that the millions of dollars from public and private resources dedicated to the protection of infants and the welfare of the young and through these to the development of the whole race, may be wisely spent and intelligently employed. Let us face for one moment the eugenic side of that great conflict in Europe. If you are the outcome of sturdy emigrants to this country, are you willing to say that those who will come to us twenty years hence will be of the same calibre and char - acter as you are yourself? No, you cannot say that in truth. But this is the melting pot. Here we assimilate even the Orien - tal; and when we are called upon to assimilate twenty years hence the product of the present inhuman carnage would we not better be prepared with laws which are honored in the observ - ance? You think it a far cry perhaps, between the war and this subject of birth registration, but it is not so, for a due observance today of all laws regarding vital statistics will help us to enact </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH protective laws against this war product invasion twenty years hence, as well as serve to educate us in regard to these vital matters. Twenty years is not so far ahead ; it only means that your children or your grandchildren must be protected against a very definite menace in the shape of defective individuals; that we. must not wait supinely until that menace is upon us, but that we must act today, now in order to have the law abiding habit so very firmly fixed upon us that nothing can shake us loose from that habit; in this way we will stand in a position to force others to become law abiding. Nebraska has almost a model registration law, the Children's Bureau tells us. Why is it not enforced in its every provision? Don't blame the doctors — they have plenty of burdens to carry without doing your bookkeeping. What is the matter with you, yourself, you who are an intelligent and responsible citizen, why don't you put Nebraska up in the front row among the good children in the national family? It's a large family — forty-eight children and only eight of them good enough in this matter of birth registration to sit in the front row. You know we Ameri - can born or American trained people are the very best people ex - tant, but we are not half as good as we could be if we lived up to our opportunities. In this crucial moment of the world's history, we Americans have an almost exclusive opportunity to make good, so that when the hideous war product come to us. twenty years hence, we can safely assimilate it without political indigestion. Now, let's redeem ourselves; let's put Nebraska in the front rank in the matter of birth registration as she is in so many other ways. Let's be quoted far and wide as the state which kept its books for humanity in due order with debit and credit balanced; let's never give the vote to the microbe that under - mines childhood, whether the women ever get the vote or not. Why, you have no idea how fine a feeling it is to be quoted be - cause you have been good. Once the writer reported the baby death statistics of Omaha to the New York Milk Committee, and when the survey was printed, it was an immense satisfaction to find Omaha way up front, and this was clinched a year later when the dairymen met in Milwaukee and gave Omaha milk a high rating. A wonderful satisfaction comes with the feeling that all is well when it has been worked out and proved so, and who knows but when the year is over and the Nebraska birth registration test a completed fact, that the Children's Bureau will give us a clean bill of health. Wouldn't it be glorious to find out that we belonged in the front row, but just had not been smart enough to prove it long ago. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 9 Remember, that where all births are recorded and an efficient child labor law maintains— as in Nebraska — a shiftless parent cannot force his children to do the work he should perform. Remember, that occupational diseases cannot take away a child's right to be healthy and strong where births are registered according to law. Remember, that where state wide birth registration is observed a farmer has equal advantages with a city man. Remember, that a registered birth may save a real estate title from being clouded ; that no one has legal proof of his identity or legitimacy, or that the name he bears is his own unless he can point to his birth certificate. Remember, that no one can enter the navy or army unless he can produce this certified information about himself. Remember, that many corporations refuse employment unless applicants can give proper evidence of date of birth. Remember again, that a law is a law and that there is such a thing as the sanctity of the law ; that where a law is not uni - formly and effectively executed, it is a menace to that respect which legal enactments deserve and hence far worse than no law at all. Remember too. that where non-observance exists in respect to such a law as birth registration, there also exists a very definite invitation to the criminally inclined to take advantage of the laxity of enforcement. We cannot permit Nebraska to invite such crime. And finally, remember that such law contemplates only justice to an individual newly come to an unthinking world, incapable of protecting its future interests and liable to have its most valuable rights and privilege* placed in jeopardy if not entirely lost, unless some one sensing the responsibility acts for the new - comer. The fact that this is a necessary service to which every one of us should be committed is shown by the statement that in one year alone in New York City, three thousand inquiries for birth data came to the registrar. That means 3,000 people for different reasons fell back on an enforced state law to give them evidence of their birth, for lack of which evidence they might suffer some irrevocable loss. One more plea for Nebraska activity in perfecting birth regis - tration. While the United States began early enough in colonial life. 1632 in Virginia, and 1639 in Massachusetts — to have ad - vanced as other nations have, it can only be said, somewhat shamefacedly on the part of the writer, that our country as a whole is not represented in international vital statistics. Even </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Mexico, even Argentina, even Japan, are ahead of us. After a century and a third of existence, and after public health legisla - tion lias been agitated for 45 years, we have but the aforesaid eight well-behaved states whose birth statistics are dependable. Now, suppose, we consider this as a sort of National Debt which is owing to humanity, not in the abstract but in the concrete be - cause it is our own humanity, and let us as Nebraskans, whether native or transplanted but loyal either way, assume our just proportion of this particular national debt. Just one-fortieth of what the nation owes its citizenship in laws to be enacted or en - forced as the case may be, Nebraska owes itself as a state. Now, let us help Nebraska pay this before the interest mounts up in neglected childhood which may be translated in terms of in - efficiency as citizens, due to handicap in any of its many forms whicli we, you and I, might have prevented. Government Special Agent. A WORD OF CAUTION. The large place given in our lay press to the deficiencies of our children ; the constant agitation in social clubs and medical societies, reports of which find their way into the daily press, occasion in the minds of many people some serious questions. Are we raising a generation of children, if not actually degen - erate, at least alarmingly imperfect? Were children of thirty years ago more or less afflicted than today? If so, how did they manage to eke out an existence, and many of them actually develop to full stature and count for something in life? One cannot altogether blame the parent, unenlightened on these matters, from looking askance at the intrusion of the state into what has always been considered, the sacred sphere of the home. The parent naturally thinks that his or her solicitude on behalf of the child must, in the very nature of things, be the most sincere, and only slowly can arrive at the conclusion, that the state through its competent inspectors and its improving methods is able to do for the child what the parent unaided can not hope to do. Many factors have helped create a spirit of suspicion if not real hostility on the part of some parents, when cooperation of MRS. K. R. J. EDHOLM. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 11 all is so essential to success. Nothing has done so much, how - ever, as the fear, whether well grounded or false, in the minds of these parents that the defects of their children will be ex - ploited by unscrupulous members of the medical profession, and in the case of children suffering from visual defects, by opticians as well. Most parents are loth to believe that their children are defec - tive, a few are over-solicitous. If these parents could believe that an absolutely unbiased opinion devoid of mercenary or selfish motives would be rendered, when directed by the state to con - sult a physician, much of the antagonism would be overcome. It is too much to hope, however, that this happy condition will ever arrive. For this very reason we shall find supervision of the health of the children ever widening in scope, becoming more thorough in its detail, and why not? Why concern ourselves so greatly over the development of the intellect at state expense, and so little over the development of the body ? Perhaps this is too socialistic to be approved by many at present, but if it ever does come as a good many believe it may, the exploitation of the infirmities of those coming under our care, will be one of the determining factors. For example, why not tell the parent that every child has adenoids and ton - sils ; that it is normal tissue, not a foreign growth, belongs in the throat and doubtless performs some function of childhood, and that it is the abnormal development, either as to size or position or pathological condition, etc., that calls for interference on our part. Again with eyes; why not tell them that the large pro - portion of the children go through the school years wholly un - conscious of defects of a certain degree and character, and not every child that consults the doctor is doomed to wear glasses. Let it be known that it is well that every child be tested, as to eyesight, but only those suffering from serious deficiency of vision or reflex disturbances will be subjected to the incon - venience of glasses, and the confidence of the parents and their cooperation with the state in its efforts to protect their children will be greatly advanced. Having fairly entered upon an age of state inspection of the human animal as well as, of livestock, it is well that we weigh seriously the responsibility placed upon us by these forced con - sultations, for a failure on our part to properly discharge this responsibility will certainly bring about far more radical and thorough state control. JOHN P. WILLIAMS. M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OP HEALTH QUARANTINE RULES AND REGULATIONS TO BE SUBMITTED FOR ADOPTION. As there seems to be a question among physicians and local boards of health, pertaining to the powers and duties of the state and local boards of health, and so many inquiries having been received at this office regarding same, and the law having been very materially changed giving the state board of health more authority and extending its duties since the last issue of our rules mid regulations, I deem it advisable to publish the laws governing the same. Also the law governing county hoards of health in all territory of the county excepting incorporated cities and villages. The county board should recognize the fact that when the county board of health has not been organized that the county commissioners become or are the official county board of health and are responsible for the enforcement of the rules and regulations governing sanitation and quarantine. Article IV. Section 28 and Section 2!l of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska. 1913: Section 28. Counties — Quarantine — Board of Health. That the county board of supervisors or commissioners of the several counties shall make and enforce regulations to prevent the in - tioduction anil spread of contagious, infectious or malignant dis - eases in their respective counties: and to that end shall make ami enforce quarantine rules, and shall establish, in each county a board of health, one member of which shall be a legally regis - tered physician, which board shall have jurisdiction throughout all the territory comprising said county, except incorporated cities and villages having the power to establish boards of health and quarantine regulations. When quarantine rules and regu - lations have not been made and a board has not been appointed as above specified and provided for, then the county board of supervisors or commissioners are hereby charged with and it shall be their duty to enforce the quarantine rules and regula - tions of the state board of health. Section 29. State Board of Health: Rules, Quarantine. The state board of health shall have supervision and control of all matters relating to sanitation and quarantine necessary to the protection of the people of this state from disease arising from unsanitary conditions and from contagious, infectious, and epi - demic diseases: and it shall be the duty of said state board of health to formulate, adopt and publish such proper and reason - able general rules and regulations as will best serve to promote sanitation throughout the state, and prevent the introduction or </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 13 spread of disease. In addition to such general and standing rules and regulations, in cases of emergency wherein the health of the people of the entire state or any locality therein shall be menaced by or exposed to any such contagious, infectious or epidemic disease or diseases arising from unsanitary conditions, or when a local board of health having jurisdiction of a particu - lar locality shall fail or refuse to act with sufficient promptitude and efficiency in any such emergency ; or in localities wherein no local hoard of health shall have been established as provided by law it shall lie the duty of the board to adopt and enforce such .special i|uarantine and sanitary regulations as the occasion and the proper protection of the public health may require; and all necessary expenses incurred in the enforcement of such rules and regulations shall be paid by the city, village or county, for and within which the same shall have been incurred. It shall be the iluty of all local, municipal, and county boards of health, health authorities and officials, officers of state institutions, police officers, sheriffs, constables, and all other officers and employes of the state, or of any county, city, village or township thereof, and every person to obey and enforce such quarantine and sani - tary rules and regulations as may he adopted by the state board of health and each and every person or officer specified in this section, who. shall fail, neglect or refuse, to obey or enforce such rules or regulations shall upon conviction for each and every such offense, be subject to a fine of not less than fifteen ($15.00) nor more than one hundred ($100.00) dollars. RULES AND REGULATIONS GOVERNING TUBERCULOSIS IN PUBLIC SCHOOLS. Numerous inquiries from boards of education, teachers, super - intendent of schools and others have come to this office regarding tuberculosis and asking what to do in case of a tubercular child attending school and also whether children should be admitted to school from families where tuberculosis exist. The old quarantine rules and regulations being exhausted and we will probably not be able to issue the new set before the first of the year I am publishing in this volume rules and regulations governing this matter, which will be submitted to the board of health for their adoption when they will then become effective if approved. These rules are some of the rules and regula - tions that have become a law in other states and we feel that if </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH these rules are followed out and the precaution therein taken there will be no danger of disseminating the disease. There is nothing in the rules and regulations that work a hard - ship on the patient or family and every precaution is taken to avoid publicity as far as it is possible to do so and yet protect the people. TUBERCULOSIS Reports of Tuberculosis by Physicians and Others. Rule 38. Tuberculosis is hereby declared to be an infectious and communicable disease, dangerous to the public health. It shall be the duty of every physician in the State of Nebraska, to report by telephone or in person or in writing on a form to be furnished as hereinafter provided, the name and address, of every person known by said physician to have tuberculosis, to the health officer of the city, town or village in which said person resides or may be, within twenty-four hours after such fact comes to the knowledge of said physicians. It shall also be the duty of the chief officer having charge for the time being of any hospital, dispensary, asylum or other similar private or public institution to report the name, age, sex, color, occupa - tion, place where last employed if known, the previous address of every patient having tuberculosis who comes into his care or under his observation, within twenty-four hours thereafter to the health officer of the city, town or village in which said institution is located and also to the health officer of the city, town or village from which said patient came. Any physician, nurse, employer, teacher, head of a family, landlord, or other person may report in writing the name and ad - dress of any person coming under his observation who appears to be suffering from tuberculosis to the health officer of the city, town or village in which such person is, and the health officer shall thereupon take such step as may be prescribed by the rules and regulations, provided the person making such report signs his own name and address thereon. Each registrar of vital statistics shall promptly report to the health officer the name and address of every person reported to him as having died from tuberculosis. The health officer shall ascertain whether such person has been previously reported as having tuberculosis by the physician signing the death certifi - cate, and if it appears that such physician has not so reported </seg>
            <seg id="p015">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 15 / such person, the health officer shall call the attention of such physician to the provisions of this section. In case of repeated violations of the provisions of this section by any physician the health officer shall report such repeated violations to the board of health or other local health authorities, who shall cause such steps to be taken as may be necessary to enforce the penalty provided for such violation. Rule 39. Examination of Sputum. It shall be the duty of every health officer of a city, town or village, when so requested by any physician, or by authorities of any hospital or dispens - ary, to make or cause to be made a microscopical examination of the sputum forwarded to him as that of a person having symptoms of tuberculosis which shall be forwarded to such officer accompanied by a blank giving name, age, sex, color, oc - cupation, place where last employed if known and address of the person whose sputum it is. It shall be the duty of said health officer promptly to make a report of the results of such examination free of charge, to the physician or person upon whose application the same is made. Rule 40. Protection of Records. It shall be the duty of every health officer of a city, town or village to cause all re - ports made in accordance with the provisions of Rule 38, and also all results of examinations, showing the presence of the bacilli of tuberculosis, made in accordance with the provisions of Rule 39 to be recorded in a register, of which he shall be the custodian. Such register shall not be open to inspection by any person other than the health authorities of the state and of the said city, town or village, and said health authorities shall not permit any such report or record to be divulged so as to dis - close the identity of the person to whom it relates, except as may be authorized in the rules and regulations. Rule 41. Disinfection of Premises. In case of the vacation of any apartment or premises by the death or removal there - from of a person having tuberculosis, it shall be the duty of the attending physician, or if there be no such physician, or if such physician be absent, of the owner, lessee, occupant, or other person having charge of the said apartments or premises, to notify the health officer of said city, town or village, of said death or removal within twenty-four hours thereafter, and such apartments or premises so vacated shall not again be occupied until duly disinfected, cleansed or renovated as hereinafter pro - vided. Rule 42. Health Officer to Direct Disinfection, Cleansing or Renovation. When notified of the vacation of any apartments or premises as provided in rule 41 thereof, the local health offi- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH eer or one of his assistants or deputies, shall within twenty-four hours thereafter visit said apartments or premises and shall order and direct that, except for purposes of cleansing or dis - infection, no infected article shall be removed therefrom until properly and suitably cleansed or disinfected, and all apart - ments or premises shall be disinfected, cleansed or renovated in order that they may be rendered safe and suitable for occu - pancy, as prescribed by the rules and regulations. If the health authorities determine that disinfection is sufficient to render them safe and suitable for occupancy, such apartments or prem - ises together with all infected articles therein, shall immediately be disinfected by the health authorities at public expense, or provided, however, that in any locality which in the judgment of the state board of health may be considered a resort for per - sons having tuberculosis such disinfection may in the discretion of the health authorities be done by such health authorities at the expense of the owner of the premises. Should the health authorities determine that such apartments or premises are in need of thorough cleansing and renovation, a notice in writing to this effect shall be served upon the owner or agent of said apartments or premises, and said owner or agent shall there - upon proceed to the cleansing or renovating of such apartments up premises in accordance with the instructions of the health authorities, and such cleansing and renovation shall be done at the expense of said owner or agent. Rule 4.J. Prohibiting Occupancy Until Order of Health Officer is Complied With. In case the orders or directions of the local health officer requiring the disinfection, cleansing or renovation of any apartments or premises or any articles therein as hereinbefore provided, shall not be complied with within forty-eight hours after such orders or directions shall be given, the health officer may cause a placard in words and form substantially as follows to be placed upon the door of the infected apartments or premises: ""Tuberculosis is a communicable disease. These apartments have been occupied by a consumptive and may be infected. They must not be occupied until the order of the health, officer directing their disinfection or renovation has been complied with. This notice must not be removed under penalty of the law except by the health officer or other duly authorized of - ficial." Rule 44. Prohibiting Carelessness of a Person Having Tuber- culosis. Any person having tuberculosis who shall dispose of his sputum, saliva or other bodily secretion or excretion so as to cause offense or danger to any person or persons occupying </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 the same room or apartment house, or part of the house, shall on complaint of any person or persons subjected to such offense or danger, be deemed guilty of a nuisance and any persons sub - jected to such a nuisance may make complaint in person or writing to the health officer of any city, town or village where the nuisance complained of is committed. And it shall be the duty of the local health officer receiving such complaint to in - vestigate and if it appears that the nuisance complained of is such as to cause offense or danger to any person occupying the same room, apartment, house or part of a house, he shall serve a notice upon the person so complained of, reciting the alleged cause of offense or danger and requiring him to dispose of his sputum, saliva or other bodily secretion or excretion in such a manner a,s to remove all reasonable cause of offense or danger. Any person failing or refusing to comply with orders or regu - lations of the local health officer of any city, town or village, requiring him to cease to commit such nuisance, shall be deemed guilty of a. misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be fined not more than ten dollars. Rule 45. Protection of Patient's Family. It shall be the duty of a physician attending a patient having tuberculosis to take all proper precautions and to give proper instructions to provide for the safety of all individuals occupying the same house or apartment, and if no physician be attending such patient this duty shall devolve upon the local health officer, and all duties imposed upon physicians by any rules of this act shall be performed by the local health officer in all cases of tuber - culosis not attended by a physician, or when the physician fails to perform the duties herein specified, and shall so report. Rule 46. Providing That Physicians Shall Make a Complete Statement of Procedure and Precautions on a Blank to be Fur - nished by the Health Officer. It shall be the duty of the local health officer to transmit to a physician reporting a case of tuberculosis as provided in rule 38, a printed statement and re - port, in a form approved by the state board of health, naming such procedure and precautions as in the opinion of the said com - missioner are necessary or desirable to be taken on the premises of a tuberculosis patient. The state board of health shall print an ample supply of such statements and reports and furnish the same in sufficient numbers to health officers # for all physicians. .Upon receipt of such statement the report of the physician shall either carry into effect all such procedure and precautions as are therein prescribed, and shall thereupon sign and date the same and return it to the local health officer without delay, or. if such attending physician be unwilling or unable to carry into </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH effect the procedures and precautions specified, he shall so state upon this report and immediately return the same to the local health officer and the duties therein prescribed shall thereupou devolve upon said local health officer who shall receive the fee hereinafter provided as payment of the services of the physician if he comply with the duties herein prescribed. Upon the receipt of this statement and report the local health officer shall care - fully examine the same, and if satisfied that the attending phy - sician has taken all necessary and desirable precautions to in - sure the safety of all persons living in the apartments or premises occupied by the persons having tuberculosis, the said local health officer shall issue an order upon the treasurer of the city, town or village in favor of the attending physician, ex - cept where such physician is employed by and receives a salary from the State of Nebraska, or is employed by and receives a salary from a hospital, sanatorium, or other similar private or public institution in the State of Nebraska, for the sum of one dollar thereupon to be paid out of a fund which shall be pro - vided by said city, town or village. But no such payment shall be made to any physician for reporting cases of tuberculosis elsewhere than in the city, town or village where such patient resides. If the precaution taken or instructions given by the at - tending physician are, in the opinion of the local health officer, not such as will remove all reasonable danger or probability of danger to the persons occupying the said house or apartments or premises, the local health officer shall return to the attending physician the report with a letter specifying the additional pre - cautions or instructions which the health officer shall require him to take or give: and the said attending physician shall immediately take the additional precautions and give the addi - tional instructions specified and shall record and return the same on the orginal report to the local health officer. Rule 47. Penalty for Failure of Physician to Perform Duties or for Making False Reports. Any physician or person prac - ticing as a physician who shall wilfully make any false statement concerning the name, age, sex, color, occupation, place where last employed if known, or address of any person reported as affected with tuberculosis, or who shall certify falsely as to any of the precautions taken to prevent the spread of infection, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof shall be subject to a fine of not more than one hundrd dollars. Rule 48. Reporting Recovery of Patient. Upon the recovery of any person having tuberculosis, it shall be the duty of the at - tending physician to make a report of this fact to the local health officer, who shall record the same in the records of his </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 19 office, and shall relieve said person from further liability to any requirements imposed by this article. Rule 49. General Penalty. Any person violating any of the provisions of rules 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47 and 48. of this article, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction • thereof shall be punished, except as in this article otherwise provided, by a fine of not less than five dollars nor more than fifty dollars. STATE HEALTH OFFICERS TO MEET IN OMAHA At a meeting of the board of secretaries of the state board of health in Lincoln, September 8th, invitations having been received from the Omaha Commercial Club, commissioner of health of Omaha and other prominent physicians asking that the next conference of local and state boards of health be held in that city. The question was taken up and on motion the board decided to accept their invitation and hold their next meeting in Omaha. The board feels very grateful to the Commercial Club of Omaha and to the profession for the interest they are taking in these matters and for their kindly offer to assist in any way to make it a success. This will be our third annual conference and we feel that the work that was begun by the board three years ago has resulted in much good and we feel that a greater interest has been taken in sanitation and public health and a better understanding of the necessity of this work has been accomplished. The object of these meetings is to become more acquainted with the local health officers and city officials and procure from them their opinions as to the requirements and the best means of obtain - ing a higher degree of sanitation in this state. It is more or less a school of sanitation and some of the most able and ex - perienced men in this and other states will be present to read papers and to instruct in the matter of sanitation and disease prevention. We have the assurance of several that will prepare papers for this meeting and all matter pertaining to the subject will be taken up and thoroughly discussed. We are very anxious to have every health officer in the state attend this meeting for through them we will be able to ascertain the conditions as they exist in the different parts of the state and that information is invaluable to the health officer as well as to the state board of health. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH The board is well convinced that a proper degree of sanitation will never be obtained in this state until the people of the state are educated to the importance and responsibility of their local health officer. The question and advisability of a state sanitary survey will be taken up and considered and an effort will be made to ascer - tain and locate the unsanitary places in the state and the local - ities needing attention. Nebraska was among the first states to adopt this plan and we are pleased to know that a majority of them are now holding these meetings and that a number of states have passed laws compelling the municipalities to pay the expenses of a represen - tative upon the presentation of a certificate given by the board of health setting forth the fact that they have attended the meet - ings. Wt earnestly request the different towns, villages and county boards of health to send a representative paying their expenses and that they require the representative to report to the local board the proceedings and recommendations of the conference. These meetings are not only for the members of local boards &lt;&gt;f health and health officers but for educators and we are espe - cially desirous of having county superintendents and superin - tendents of schools to participate in the discussions and read papers as we believe through them a great work can he accom - plished and an interest generated along the line of sanitation and better living. The date and place for this conference has not been definitely decided but it will be held the latter part of January. HEALTH CONDITIONS IN NEBRASKA Health inspection made in Nebraska since the induction into the office of the present health inspector, impels one to the con - clusion ; that greater appreciation of the importance of proper sanitary precautions necessarily resulting in the checking of disease, and marked improvement in the general public health, should be indicated by increased activities on the part of local health authorities in the several municipalities of the state. As the general average of health conditions in a local community, rises and falls, just so certainly one can determine the activity or non-activity of health officers. There is, however, a duty resting upon such officers to perform efficient service which will </seg>
            <seg id="p021">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 21 n-sult in a higher degree of health conditions in each community and thus redound to the credit of efficient active health officials. In connection with local sanitation, I particularly wish to call attention to the special source of danger existing because of stagnant ponds or pools of water which I have found in or near several villages and cities of the state. I am of the opinion that stagnant water constitutes one of the really dangerous sources of disease. The particular wet and cold summer just past, has been one peculiarly inimical to public health in general, and such con - ditions should attract the close attention of local health officers throughout the entire state. Cold damp weather is particularly conducive to smallpox as is shown by the prevalence and spread of that disease during the summer months of the present year. I therefore call upon all the health officers of the state and urge their constant cooperation in checking the spread of this dread disease and in checking all contagious and infectious diseases now prevalent in the entire state. In giving out this word of warning to health officials of the state, I do not want to be understood as urging the co-operation of health officials only, but wish to call to the aid and assistance of the local health officers, and to the state board of health, the medical profession of the State of Nebraska, who because of their special training and medical intelligence, are able to exert and give a tremendous impetus to better health and sanitary con - ditions if they will but lend their aid to local health officers. The physicians of the state should carefully and fully report the vital statistics and all infectious and contagious diseases. Finally I call upon the body of the people of the whole state to study health matters and their local sanitary conditions, and the water supply, and call their health officer's attention to any con - dition which may be dangerous and a menace to the public health. J. D. CASE, M. D. Health Inspector. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH HEALTH RULES Formulated and adopted by the Association for the Prevention of Tuberculosis, Washington, D. C. 1. Good air. Avoid badly ventilated, badly lighted, dusty, dirty, overheated, or crowded rooms. 2. Avoid house dust. Breathing dust, notably house dust, often causes disease. Have no tacked down carpets and mat - tings. Have loose pieces of rugs, and clean them frequently out - doors. Keep lower sashes closed while sweeping or dusting. Open upper sashes. Never sweep rooms with a broom that raises dust. 3. Pure water. Drink pure water. Avoid water from shallow and unprotected wells, and from ponds and streams. If in doubt boil the water. Some corner pumps are dangerous. Filtered river water is safe to drink. Avoid public drinking cups. 4. Safe milk and cream. Tuberculosis, typhoid fever, and other diseases are often caused by drinking dirty raw milk and raw cream. Investigate your dairyman. Patronize the dealer with clean, up-to-date methods. 5. Keep clean. Take a bath or sponge daily, and a warm bath, followed by a cold splash, plunge or shower, once or twice a week or oftener. Use soap freely. Wash your hands before handling food. Don't put fingers, money, paper or pencils in your mouth. Don't bite your finger nails. Clean your teeth morning and evening. ■ 6. Food. Don't eat raw food that was exposed to flies or dust or touched by unclean hands. Fruits or vegetables so exposed should first be rinsed or washed thoroughly. Chew your food well. Tea, coffee, and alcohol are stimulants, not foods. 7. Sleep. Get enough sleep. Sleep with windows open, or bet ter still, outdoors. 8. Head up. Sit and stand erect. Practice deep breathing, Breathe through your nose. 9. Exercise. Take plenty of outdoor exercise, but avoid excess in athletics. It may cause heart trouble. Don't eat or drink when overheated by exercise. 10. Liquor and tobacco. Avoid tobacco and liquors. They are especially injurious to the young. Alcohol is a preservative, but not of the health. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">ANNUAL BULLETIN NO. 4 23 11. Don't neglect colds. Don't neglect coughs or colds. If you do not get well soon, go to a doctor or dispensary for treat - ment. Never cough, sneeze, or breathe into another person's face. Don't spit on floors, sidewalks, or street cars. 12. Sunshine. Admit plenty of sunshine into your houses and into your lives. Cultivate cheerfulness and kindliness; it will help you to resist disease. Your mind acts on your body. NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH AN ACTIVE BUNCH. The following is taken from the Elm Creek Beacon, Geo. F. Keenan, publisher, which is very much appreciated by the editor of the bulletin. We are very glad to know that the press is taking greater interest in matters of sanitation and disease prevention. We wish to make mention of the fact of the way in which the state board of health are dealing with the affairs that necessarily follow along the line of our public schools. We want to give them a "hunch" or as much as to tell them they are on the right trail, and hope to see the present faculty bend their best efforts for the furtherance of the good work begun. Many a newspaper man over the state is watching every move these fellows take, who would not hesitate to "call" them for some crooked move as they do in penning a good word for them. However, we're pleased to note in looking' through a recently issued bulletin, published at Seward, Nebraska, that the present board believe in doing good, as is specifically emphasized and outlined in the new bulletin, and the people should be made to read the same, specially our school teachers. Those of you who are interested will call at the Beacon office for a copy of the same. Read what A. 0. Thomas, superinten - dent public instruction, has to say along this line. There was published in the July bulletins an article entitled "Medical Legislation." This paper was read at the Conference of local and state boards of health held in Lincoln, February, 1915, by Dr. F. L. Wilmeth, of Lincoln, Nebraska. The doctor </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH failed to sign same when handed in and through an oversight he was not credited for the same. After four years of experience as Food and Dairy Commis - sioner, Clarence E. Harmon, has become convinced of the need of a publication to inform the people along the line of food and dairy products. The result is a very creditable publication en - titled "Nebraska Food and Dairy Journal" issued monthly under the auspices of Mr. Harmon. We must congratulate our colleague in health work on his neat and attractive Journal. Ed. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>