<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  EXPERIMENTS IN ORCHARD CULTURE.</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN P I HE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Vol. XV, Article V. EXPERIMENTS IN ORCHARD CULTURE, By R. A. Emerson. DlSTBIBUTED MARCH 30, 1908. OLN, NEBRASKA, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (tM «M««T« Or T«I UKlVIMITt) GBO. F. KENOWER, President. Wtaner E. v. FORELL. Kearney EDSON C. RICH, Omah» JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln E. G. CALKINS. Kearney C. J. ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS ■ BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman LTON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF A. T. PETERS, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Besset, Ph. D., Botanist S. Avert, Ph D., Chemist KHaecker. B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman ence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist r H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist B Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist P. STOUT, C. E., Irrigation Engineer SWEZEY, M. A., Meteorologist t Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist Perln, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm </seg>
            <seg id="p003">EXPERIMENTS IN ORCHARD CULTURE. BY B. A. EMEBSON. INTRODUCTION. I)rchabd cultivation often neglected. — While it would difficult to suggest a method of orchard culture not on il in Nebraska, yet in many cases little or no cultivation any sort is practiced. In some instances the orchards ad in a close sod of blue grass, pastured by young stock, in a sod of timothy and clover regularly mowed for hay. nparatively few orchards in the state are maintained ler clean cultivation. It certainly seems reasonable to ect our deep, rich prairie soil to be able not only to sup - t an orchard almost indefinitely, but also to furnisl same time, such additional plant food as may be re - red by whatever grass or grain can find room to grow ween the trees. Clean cultivation, a question of moistube. — The lead - ing fruit growers of Nebraska, however, learned long ago that the conservation of moisture is our main orchard prob - lem, and that in our rich prairie soils the question of plant food is of secondary importance. In eastern Nebraska, whore abundant rains usually fall in early summer, fair Its have been secured by maintaining old orchard sod. Farther west in the state this method is out of the • luestion. Even in eastern Nebraska the best orchards were given thorough cultivation while young, and are by n&lt;&gt; ■mum neglected after having come into bearing. The one idea that has been most clearly and forcibly brought out at almost every session of the Nebraska State Horticultural Society is that careful cultivation for the conservation of soil moisture is an essential part of orchard treatment. A few dry summers are enough to convince most fruit grow - that trees need more moisture than they are likely to </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Experiments in Orchard Culture. Cultivation versus neglect — injury during winter. — The unusually severe winter of 1898-99, which resulted in the destruction of so many orchard and nursery trees throughout the northwest, led many western fruit growers to question whether the accepted ideas of orchard culture did not need revising. From many parts of Nebraska and adjoining states, accounts came of neglected orchards that had almost entirely escaped injury, while neighboring or - chards that were carefully cultivated were badly damaged by the severe cold. In some cases the freedom of neglected orchards from winter injury was ascribed to the protection afforded the tree roots by the mulch of grass and weeds. In other cases it was attributed to the early maturity of trees in the dry soils of uncultivated orchards. The fact that winter injury was more pronounced in cultivated or - chards than in neglected ones led some orchardists to ques - tion the advisability of cultivating their trees at all. Tests at thb Nebraska experiment station. — To help in the solution of questions of this sort, a number of experi - ments have been undertaken by the Agricultural Experi - ment Station. These tests have been in progress for the past three years, and it is believed that enough information of real value has been obtained from them to warrant pub - lication at this time, although of course the experiments are only fairly under way and should be continued for some years to come. 1 ICKNOWLEDGMENTS. — In carrying out the experiments i described, the writer has been materially assisted by C. G. Marshall, who has made many of the records and d in computing the results. The Departments of Chem - y and Agriculture have kindly made most of the deter - ations of the soil moisture of the various orchard plats, writer also wishes to acknowledge his indebtedness to officers and members of the Nebraska State Horticul - lI Society, who have added much to the value of the jriments here reported by their friendly suggestions and cisms. •A test of the relative effect of cultivation and sod in an old orchard was con - ducted at this Experiment Station during 1894-95, and reported in Bulletin 39, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Experiments in Orchard Culture. Experiment I r:T OF VARIOUS METHODS OF CULTURE ON MOISTURE CONTENT OF ORCHARD SOILS AND ON THE GROWTH OF YOUNG ORCHARD TREES. PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT. The ouchaud site AND plats. — This experiment was be - gun in 1901. In the spring of that year an orchard of about six acres was set at the Experiment Station. It cone of eight plats, each twenty-one rods long east and west by six rods wide north and south. These lie side by side, mak - ing the orchard forty -eight rods long north and south by twenty-one rods wide east and west. The soil of all the plats is a fairly uniform upland loam. The land slopes gently to the northeast, except in the case of the south plat. one end of which slopes slightly to the southwest. The north plats are, therefore, on slightly lower land than the south ones, and appear to have a slight natural advantage over the latter in regard to the rapidity of tree growth. On the whole, the site is sufficiently uniform throughout for purposes of the test The orchard is protected on the west and north by an osage hedge about twelve feet high and about three rods from the nearest orchard trees. Varieties of trees planted. — All plats contain the same number and kinds of trees, arranged in the same order. The varieties of trees planted and the number of each variety in each plat are: Apples — 12 Ben Davis, 6 Oldenburg, 6 Jonathan, 6 Wag- rherries — 1 Early Richmond, 4 Montmorency, 4 Windsor, eaches — 4 Russell, 3 Wright, 3 Wager. Pears — 4 Keiffer, 3 Bartlett, 3 Flemish Beauty. Klums — 4 Wild Goose, 4 Forest Harden, 3 Abundam i bard. Kf the 608 trees in the orchard, there are, therefore, 240 les, 96 cherries, 80 peaches, 80 pears, and 112 plums, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Experiments in Orchard Culture . plat containing 1 1&gt; trees. A. 1 1 1 1 1 m l •* - 1* of trees died the ar and were replaced in the spring of 1902. EEATMENT OF THE VARIOUS PLATS. — During the tWO i that the experiment has been in progress the various have been treated as follows, the plats being numbered north to smith : Plat 1. This plat was cropped with watermelons in 1901 ami with bush beans and turnips in 1902. These crops i :i very thorough cultivation and occasionally hoed, no Is being allowed to grow during the growin n of ■ndary crops. The ground was not plowed in the spring of 1902, being merely stirred deeply with a disk as soon as thawed. B_\ This plat was treated exactly like Plat 1, pole beans were grown instead of bush beans in YMY1. 13. A crop of corn was grown in this plat both \. The distance between the corn and tree rows same a.s between the corn rows. The corn was given n cultivation during the usual season. The stalks i iding during winter to catch the snow. Soon after frost was out of the ground in the spring of 1901, the ks were broken down and cut up by a disk, followed i common harrow, which also stirred the surface soil and ►ed conserve soil moisture. After the second cultiva - , the ground was plowed six to eight inches deep, most he stalks being turned under. The plat was then difl harrowed frequently until corn-planting time. Plat 4. The trees here were given thorough, clean cultiva - tion with disk and harrow throughout the summers of 1901 and 1902. During the very dry season of 1901, the ground was disked at least once every two weeks from the time the trees were planted until well into October. The surface soil stirred a.s soon as possible after every rain, to break the Bt. Scarcely a weed was allowed to show above the sur - at any time during the season. In 1902 the disk and harrow were started about the middle of March and run the ground at frequent intervals until about the middle of October. Cultivation was not so regular as in 1901, owing to the very wet weather. We nally became quite troublesome, but were never permitted to get beyond control </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 with disk and barrow. Daring fall scarcely ■ weed could niid m the whole plat. Hat ."). The plat was cropped with &lt;&gt;ats botl The mi at the usual time in spring with I brill, run as close as possible to the n saving u strips only a few feet wide in tree rows. In 1901, the ground about each tree was hoed once or twice. In 1902, the mi sown strips were cultivated a few times with a one-hi cultivator. The oats were mowed and removed from the field when ripe. In the fall of l!)02 rains prevented liar and caused a heavy second growth. The stubble was left ding daring fall and winter of both seasons and the nd plowed in the spring of l'jou, like the corn ground in Plat 3, and worked down with disk and harrow befoi ilat &lt;;. The |i i cultivated exactly like Plat 4 daring early part of both summers. Cultivation was dit ed about the middle of July and a cover crop 1 of millet n. No further treatment was given during either fall. cover-crop was left standing daring winter to hold the w. In the spring of 1902, cultivation was begun at the e time as in other plats. The (-overcrop - iked ■ the soil with a disk, the ground not being plow- flat 7. The treatment given this plat w. , given Plat &lt;&gt;, except that oat wn for ) and that the cover was plowed under in the sprin 1, being found loo heavy to he worked into the soil with isk. Ilat 8. The treatment of this plat was identical with ; given Plats ♦&gt; and 7 during the early part ;. Cultivation was discontinn tuple of than in the latter plats, and a cover-crop of weeds al - id to &lt;jrow. The wet weather of l'.MH' caused such is weed growth that the cover-crop was mowed earl ;ust, making little further &lt;{rowtli. In the spring of I the lover crop was disked into the soil, as in Pit Ke term "cover-crop" isoften misunderstood. A " crop " is usually^ that yields a return on being harvested. An orchard "cover-cr &gt;p," how- K solely for the benefit of the trees. Some o\ which derive benefit from cover-crops are brought out later in this bul- Iso Nebr. State Hort. Soc. Rept., 1900, pp. 131-138; 1901, pp. 130- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 M Orchard Ci. 1 lat J. I&gt; Iip eight orchard plats already described, a ninth pla&gt; »ting of only a few square rods of ground and containing no trees, adjoined the orchard on the south - east. This was sown to rye early in the fall of 1900. The rye was allowed to grow to maturity in 1901 in order to allow the effect on soil moisture to be noted. Ikos. — The percentages of soil moisture at the depth o nine inches in the different plats were determined ;ral times each season. All the trees were measured i after setting, and also after the close of each - vth. The measurement* Included, in all cases, the diam - s of the trunks, and in some cases the height of I spread of brandies. Records have also been kept of depth of snow in the various plats, the depth of fi of the ground, the relative amount of washing from s or melted snow, and, in short, of everything that it deemed might lie of use in determining the relative its of the different methods of culture. RESULTS OF THE EXPERIMENT. Soil moisture. — To avoid confusion, the results from the two vegetable plats, Noa. 1 and 2, have been averaged, which will in no way detract from the value of the results, since two plats have received practically the same treatment and have given almost identical results. Of the three cover crop plats, No. 7, millet, has been chosen as representing the best type of cover-crop. The differences observed between and the other two cover-crop plats will be presented in iter bulletin on cover-crops. The percentages of moisture found in these five plats at various times during the two years are shown graphically in the accompanying chart (fig. 1), which also shows the rainfall when it equaled or exceeded one fourth inch. I he vegetables dried the soil but little more than clean ivation. In neither case did the per cent of moisture be - e dangerously low, even during the protracted drought of I, when only a little over seven inches of rain fell during four months from May to August inclusive. The crop of dried the ground much more than any other method of </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Fig. 1. — Per cents of soil moisture in orchard plats and inches of rainfall dur - ing summers of 1901 and 1902. The dots show dates of making moisture deter - minations and exact per cents of moisture found, the curved lines indicating probable fluctuations in moisture between these dates. The vertical bars show dates and amounts of rainfall "••r^V flP * 1 *- ► M * Y JUNE ; JULY t AU«U5T ; •CPTCHKIt; OCrOIK I -• i i --: H ; Wk ~» :^ . ; : : »lwJfc\f/ : : 1 1 i . —^**^ &gt; *&lt;. • .... ; : =Rf :..... V^5^ \ i \ ! \ x -- H % i '?&gt;-^/ B ♦s^ a: 1/ ;^x v "?■ « \; jv? s* v «• i ;•■ ' -V— -:/ h - ,r^; p lT I Anil HAI ■i-J I U- **Hr k. Li i ! : ; I : "- vJlri Lllilli, ill ili; i, r ■ -•-i 2 L- £^J SS2 H •V- lit -^ - fjtr" ■ ■&gt;! </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Experiments in Orchard Culture. culture tried. Not only was the rye ground somewhat drier, Imt it became dry earlier, and moreover, since no rain - curred to thoroughly moisten the ground after it had once •me dry, the rye plat remained dry "nearly a month louder than any of the other plats. Next to rye, the oat p dried the soil most seriously during the dl u of 1901, though it did not make the soil much drier than corn or cover-crop*. Its effect, however, was noticeable much :«&gt;r in rammer and lasted much longer. By the middle of July, when the corn plat was becoming dry, many t have completed their greatest length growth and do not need so large a supply of moisture as they do earlier in the son. Furthermore, the ground of all plats was thoroughly moistened by the unusually heavy rains of late September and early October. The corn plat was very dry, therefore only about half as long as the oats plat. The important difference between the cover-crop and the corn, just as be - tween the corn and the oats, is that the soil in the Cover-crop plat did not become dry for a week or two after the corn ground had become dry. Iihe great difference, as regards soil moisture, between clean cultivation on the one hand and the rye and oats the other is fully appreciated only when it is remembered t many plants established in common loam soil often t, or even die, when the soil still contains 8 per cent or per cent of moisture; or, in other words, that only the isture in excess of 8 per cent or 10 per cent is available plants. In June, 1901, the clean cultivation plat con - led only a little over one half more absolute moisture n the oats plat, Of the moisture available to tender nts, however, there was from two to three times as much he clean cultivation plat as in the oats plat. In 1902, the plats did not vary greatly as regards soil moisture. Naturally, no method of culture dried the ground msly at any time during this very wet season, when over twenty-eight inches of rain fell during the four months from May to August inclusive, or about four times as much as fell during the same months of the preceding year. During midsummer all the plats contained from 22 per cent to 24 per cent of soil moisture. Late in September, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Experiments in Orchard Culture. 11 after about three weeks of dry weather, the corn plat had about 18 per cent of moisture, and the oats, vegetables, and r-crop plats somewhat less than 19 per cent. The el cultivation plat at no time after April had much less than 21 per cent of soil moisture. Au important difference between the plats with respect tu the absorption of water in heavy rains is shown in the chart for 1902. Just after periods of heavy rainfall the r-crop and oats plats were almost invariably wetter than the others. The vegetation of these plats apparently held the water until it had time to soak into the soil, while there little to prevent rapid surface drainage in the well - cultivated vegetables, corn, ami clean cultivation pi far as average conditions are concerned, however, the greater ability of the oats and cover-crop plats to al water during heavy rains was counterbalanced by their more rapid loss of water during periods of little or no rain. The chief value of these crops, in rainy seasons, lies in their venting too rapid surface drainage with the erosion which usually accompanies it in all but level The ground of the clean cultivation plat was eroded considerably the rammer, in spite of the fact that it was rarely culti - d in the direction of the greatest slope. In the corn and vegetable plats, erosion, though less troublesome than in the cultivated plat, was still quite noticeable. In the and cover-crop plats almost no washing away of soil was ■een during the time that they were covered with vegetation. I'kkes KILLED by dkought. — The great differences in soil isture just described were not without correspond hi - ts on the young trees growing in the various plats. The lowing table shows the number of trees of each kind set each plat, the number that died during the summer of H, and the per cent of dead trees: </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Experiments in Orchard Culture. Tablk I.— Effect of various methods of culture on drought-killing of O PLATS land 2. t. 2. — The shaded parts of the horizontal bars indicate the number of live and the unshaded parts the number of dead trees in the different orchard at the end of the first year. The clean record of the cultivation plat certainly shows the value of thorough cultivation in keeping newly set trees alive during very dry seasons. The excellent results ob - tained are to be ascribed to nothing but the effect of re - peated thorough cultivation in keeping the soil moist throughout the summer. The vegetable plats were some- young rees. I I ! App trei 4c Cl tl ien tl each Pear Plum ■ees trees trees LS ces i b Method of *j J culture. -: g| Z Z (2 Z termelon crop 30 2 Watermelon crop 30 2 7 12 Corn crop 30 2 7 12 Clean cultivation 30 1 312 Oats crop 30 14 47 12 Cover-crop — millet ... 30 4 13 12 Cover-crop — oats 30 4 13 12 Cover-crop— weeds ... 30 7 23 12 Method of culture. si S B a a z z I s z 1 2 1 0 G 2 4 8 I Sz 9! 10 17.d 9 1" Oio SOW 1710 33io 50 i&lt;J •s • ■s « i/ c a* f c u i si I si /, S5 (£ Z 0 010 0 OH o oio 2 201-* -2O 10 -0214 0 0 10 1 1014 b 8 ■" ' GO '4 1 1 10 2 2014 o io i ion o io o o W li — ' 1- k. «J V S JJ j S, c 0 0 76 '2| Ofi 5 36 7^51.3 0 0 16 9lj .8 The total number of treei planted on each p »lat and the total number killed by droug; it are shown in the accompany- ing chart. (Fig. 2.) </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experiments in Orchard Culture. 13 what less favored than the clean cultivation plat, M might have been predicted from the moisture chart. That the records of the cover-crop and corn p] quite so good as the rleau cultivation plat is not - remembering how greatly these crops dried the soil. extremely high percentage of dead trees in tli plat is to be accounted for by the early and long-contin! ness of the soil of that plat rather than by the degre dryness. It is very probable that no such disastrous re - would have followed if the season of 1901 had been leas dry or if the trees had i&gt; ir before and •me better established before the ?ery di Had rye been used instead of oats in the orchard p the chances are that all the trees instead of half of 0 would have been replaced the next spring. Even old, fairly rous trees are sometimes killed by being cropped with rye. In Lincoln near the Experiment Station are man\ apple trees. Since the land was divided into building t he individual owners or renters have given a great d of treatment to the remaining trees. Jn one case the trees on a few lots were fairly uniform in health and \ up to the spring of 1901. That summer a crop of allowed to mature on about half of this ground, while i lie remainder a crop of cane was grown. The early and long-continued dryness of the soil where the rye grew hurt the trees badly, but none, or at least only a few of ti died that summer. The cane, of com dried the ground upon which it grew, but the drought was felt I and was of shorter duration. The early spring of 1902 was very dry. This, combined with the early drying effei the rye crop, was more than the trees could stand. The abundant rains of June came too late to save the trees, which consequently presented the peculiar spectacle of dying from drought during one of the wettest seasons on record. (See fig. 3.) The adjoining trees on the cane ground, while dam - aged more or less by drought, are still alive. |)isasters as great as those just described may not occur tin for several -years as the result of growing oats or rye orchards in eastern Nebraska. On the other hand, the istrations given show well what might occur almost any </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Experiments in Orchard Culture Ir. No one can tell at planting time whether the summer be wet or dry, and yet almost every spring orchard s, and other kinds of trees as well, are set by hopeful uninformed men, who later wonder why their trees die le the small grain is growing so well on the same ground, v usually come to the conclusion that this state is not pted to fruit growing or that the nurseryman sold them r trees. It would be quite ;is reasonable to blame the Isman for selling them the seed oats or rye that killed the Fig. 3. — Old apple trees dying from drought during one of the wettest sea sons on record — the result of continuous cropping with rye. Tbee gbowth in the various plats. — After the comple - tion of growth in both 1901 and 1902, the trunk diameters of all the trees were measured. The average sizes of the tree trunks in all plats for each kind of tree after the first and again after the second year's growth are given in the table below. In a few cases where a relatively large proportion of the rapidly growing kinds survived the drought of 1901, averages obtained from the surviving trees are la </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Ii they would have been had all varieties lived. In other s, where the slowest growing varieties alone survived, averages were likewise lower than they would otherwise i been. The averages in these cases have, therefore, been ected to make them comparable with the plats in which or no trees died, tin- correct ion factor being obtained by ing the relative rapidity of growth of the various sorts rees in the plats where few died. Table II. — Diameters of tree trunks in sixteenths of an inch for various orchard plats. Method Apple. Cherry. Peach. Pear. Plum. Average. of I culture. 19 ui ; l8 o2 l 1901 1902 1901 19OI -I 190lll90l egetabie c: 29.9 9.9 10. « 11.2 l'J J 10 2 19 3 egetable ci 10 2 19 5 am crop. 9.1 16.5 lean cults' L6.2 9.520.6 l 10.8l29. 9 9. 7116.0 9.9 19.4 tjon . At the end of the second year in the orchard the height of all trees and the breadths of their tops weir determined. These records, corrected as in t the diameter records, are summarised in the following table: Table III. — Height and breadth of trees of orchard plats, in feet. i'ats crop ove r-crop — millet over -crop- oats over-crop — weeds 13.7 8.H l 8.7 15. 9.3 15.6 9.-J l».3 9.5 17 9.5 15.4 8.018..", 10.926.9 9.0 13.7 10.817.5 9.7 17 9.6 15.3 8.819.1 10.1 25&gt; 110.318.4 9.717. 1 . l_. l_ . I _ I _ Apple. Cherry. Peach. Pear. Plum. At ch. Pear. Plum. Aver. I Method of culture. ~ | ~ 3 - | 5 3 3 . Vegetables "5.9 Vegetables!!!.!.!'.'.!!!!'.'.'.. p-«g-' - J "' 6!i Corn p. 5{2 . - ' . 4 3 . 815. 912. 215. 0- Clean cultivation 6.a5.O6.1 1.96.83O5,* Oats 4.S1.83&gt; »5.1 1.35.62*4,6 CoTer-crop— millet 5. 12. 44. 7B. 66. 94. 85. 72.1 6.02.7 5.4 Cover-crop-oats 5.O2.33.9 2.3 6.0U.6W.9 1.66.03.O|S.i Cover-crop-weeds 5.S».34.7p.6^.oU.3p.S1.6^.52.^5.S 3 - — </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Experiments in Orchard Culture. The average diameters of all trees in each plat are shown in fig. 4, and the heights and breadths of the trees in fig. 5. It is worthy of note that the oats plat makes the poorest ving in regard to height, spread of branches, and diam - &lt;&gt;f trunks. The effect of the oats in retarding growth, PLATS I and 2 fj. 4. — Diameters of tree trunks, in sixteenths of an inch, at the end of the year, indicated by shaded parts of horizontal bars, and at end of second by full length of bars. Fig. 5. — Height of trees, in feet, indicated by full length of bars, and spread of branches by shaded parts of bars. Egh very noticeable, is not so great as its effect on the of the tm^s the first vear after planting (see fig. 2). corn plat is next poorest as regards size of tree trunks le end of both the first and second years, the cover-crop I haying noticeably larger trunks. In breadth of top, </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 however, the trees of the cover-crop plat exceed only slightly • in (inn, and in height the trees of the corn plat are slightly ahead of the cover crop trees. The shade of the cornstalks may cause the trees to grow in height at the ex - pense of breadth of top and trunk diameter. This tend* so far as it goes, is certainly bad, since low. stocky treea are best suited to our climatic conditions. If the corn i had been kept farther away from the tree rows, so that the tall stalks would not have shaded the tree tops, the observed effect on tree growth would probably not have been noticed. The vegetable and clean cultivation plats are ahead of all others in regard to size of trees. In size of trunks at the end of the first year the vegetable plat was slight! of the clean cultivation plat, but at the end of the se&lt; fear there was no difference between the plats. The trees in vegetable plats are slightly taller than those given clean cultivation and have noticeably broader tops. This slight difference may be due to the fact of the land sloping slightly to the north, the vegetable plats being, therefore, lower than the clean cultivation plat. nsidering all these things — drought killing, hci_ idth of top, and diameter of trunk — the vegetable clean cultivation plats rank first, the former being slightly ahead of the latter. The next in rank are the cover-crop and corn plats, the former being very slightly ahead of the latter. The oats plat naturally ranks lowest, much lower than the corn and cover crop plats. 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Ex p. r. meats in Orchard Culture. Experiment II. rCT OF COVER-CROPS ON FALL DEVELOPMENT AND WINTER INJURY OF YOUNG PEACH TREES. PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT. Situation of the trees. — In the spring of 1901, 48 peach trees, all of the Wager variety, were set to test the effect of •r-crops on winterkilling of the trees. One half the a were set on moderately rich upland loam, sloping slightly toward the north, protected by a windbreak on the south and east — on the whole a good site for a peach or - chard. The other half of the trees was let on rich, well - drained bottom land, protected on all sides by windbreaks. This situation would certainly never be chosen by well-in - formed peach growers as a proper site for a peach orchard, since peach trees in this region often winterkill on low ground. The two sites were selected with the idea that if following winters should prove mild, the different meth - ods of treatment to be used might give results on the low land, and if the winters should prove extremely severe, kill - itll the trees on the bottom land, those on the upland might still show differences in winter injury due to differ - - in treatment. IUUTMKNT of the plats in 1.901. — Both blocks of trees l given clean cultivation from the time the trees were until midsummer. Notwithstanding the fact that the on was unusually dry, the thorough cultivation kept the moist and the trees in good condition. Those on the land made fair growth, though of course not so good a rth as would have been expected in a more favorable :&gt;n. The trees on the low land grew vigorously, no more rously, however, than trees on upland situations usually r during seasons of abundant moisture. All the trees in block were quite uniform in size and vigor. On July 13, both the lowland and upland blocks of trees were divided into three plats of eight trees each. In one plat </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Experiments in Orchard Culture. 19 of each block oats was sown as a cover-crop and in a second plat millet was similarly sown. At the time of sowing these cover-crops, the surface soil was very dry, but being sown with a press drill, which penetrated the dust blanket to the moist ground below, they began growth with fair prompt - ness. Their growth throughout the fall was good, consider - ing the unusual drought prevailing at the time. In the re - maining plat of each block of trees, cultivation was con - tinued throughout the summer, the last cultivation being given in October. RESULTS OF THE TEST OF 1901. Kipening OF the summer's gbowth. — The trees in upland block stopped growing early in fall, and their « matured well before cold weather. No great difference was noticed between the trees that were cultivated and tho&gt; the cover-crop plats. In the block of trees on the bottom land, however, striking differences were seen between the different plats. The trees in the cover-crop plats practically stopped growing by the middle of August, only a month after the cover-crops were sown, and began to mature their wood. The trees in the plat given late cultivation contin growth much later. The cultivated trees had matured their wood and formed their terminal buds no more perfectly by the middle of October than the cover-crop trees had by the middle of August. Unfortunately, no photographs were se - cured showing this difference. Similar differences were - in the fall of 1902, however, and are illustrated in if \\\ the first or middle of November, 1901, little differ' could be seen between the trees of the cultivated plat those in the cover-crops, so far as maturity of the - growth of wood was concerned. The wood of all trees seemed well ripened and ready for winter. The trees of the cultivated plat were considerably larger, as a whole, than those of the oats and millet plats. IVinterkilling. — At the time growth started in the spring 1902 the differences between the trees of the various plats the low ground were even more striking than they were late August and through September of the previous fall. March 14 it was noticed that the previous year's growth </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 of many of the trees of the bottom land block was winter injured. The inner bark and wood of the twigs were badly discolored, being quite brown, even where there was little outward sign of injury. The discoloration seemed at that Pig. 6. — Winter-injured peach tree*. No. 1, best tree, and No. 2, poorest tree, on millet coyer-crop plat; No. 3, beat tree, and No. 4, poorest tree, on dean - attrition pl»i. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Experiments in Orchard Culture. 21 |.e somewhat greater in case of the trees that had been tivuted late in fall than in case of those in the cover-crop ts. Considerable discoloration, however, was found in gs of all trees. On April 21, when the trees were &gt; leaf, it was found that one half of the trees on the late tivation plat were apparently dead and the remaining f badly injured, while in the cover crop plats about half trees were badly injured and the other half were p illy unhurt, not a single tree being dead. On May 17. ?r the trees had made considerable growth, two re tative trees of the late cultivation "plat and two from the let plat were photographed, the least and worst inj ■ being selected in both cases. These photographs are roduced in fig. ti. The number of uninjured, badly ured, and dead trees in the different plats is shown in Fig. 7. — Relation of cover-crops to winterkilling of young peach trees Kber of d 1 bars, \ hori- Hghtly shaded parts, and &lt;t No. 1) t uninjured t I he injured trees in all pi • primed back to live d and given clean cultivation until midsummer. All the s in the cover-crop plats recovered, mad vth, are now (February, 1003) alive with the exception trees that were killed accidentally late in summer after ng made a vigorous growth. Of the five trees in the late ivation plat that came through the winter alive only e are now living, the other two having died in the sum - , apparently from winter injuries. These three trees e a fair growth, but are not so large now as the trees le cover-crop plats. So much for the trees on the bottom </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Experiments in Orchard Culture. &gt;ne of the trees of either plat on the poorer upland soil were seriously injured by the winter's cold. Some twigs were killed back a few inches from the tips, but the great majority of them were not hurt enough to kill even the ten - der tips. The winter was a comparatively mild one and practically no peach trees on upland soil in this part of the state were injured. An examination of the trees in the up - land block made early in spring, however, showed that the different plats might have presented as great difference - did the plats on the bottom land had the winter been more severe. On March 14 the trees of the three plats of the up - land block were carefully examined. In the cover-crop plats there was almost no indication of discoloration beneath the bark, the twigs presenting a fresh, bright appearance when cat across. In the plat that received late cultivation, how - . nearly all the twigs showed considerable brown colora - tion beneath the bark. They were plainly injured, though oualy enough to prevent normal growth the follow summer. Had the winter been as severe as many win - in this section, the superiority of the cover-crop cultivation would doubtless have been as pronoui on the upland as it was on the low land. REPETITION OF THE TEST IN 1902. Iuring the early summer of 1902, all plats of the peach s were again given careful cultivation. On July 16, et was again sown in the plats where it was grown •r-crop the year before. All other plats, both those that 5 in oats and those that were cultivated late the preced - . were given clean cultivation until late in fall. The on of 1902 was as excessively wet as the preceding one dry. The cover-crop did not, therefore, show as pro need an effect in inducing early ripening of the new i t did in 1901. Considerable difference was seen between plats, however, especially in the upland block. About middle of September, 1902, two twigs were taken from i tree in the millet plat and two from each tree that had ived late cultivation both years. These twigs were se - jd to represent the average condition of the trees as to </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Experiments in Orchard Culture. Pin case most of the young growth of the tree are, two immature twigs were chosen, and, simi - nearly all the wood was well matured, two ma - were taken. Where a tree presented a condition ay between the two extremes just noted, one ma - le immature twig were selected. These twigs, 16 Fig. 8. — Peach twigs. Nos. 1-14 fromiate cultivation, and Nos. li&gt; cover-crop plat. Note maturity of latter and immaturity of former. from the cover-crop and 14 from the late cultivation \ were photographed after taring most of their leu to better show their maturity or immaturity when crow together. The photographs are reproduced in tiji. s. The twigs shown in the lower row, Nos. 15 to 30, were taken f the millet cover-crop plat, and those shown in the upper </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Is. 1 to 14, from the late cultivation plat. It will W n that of the 1G twigl from the cover-crop plat, el. s. 16 to 25, are fairly mature, and five, Nos. 2C&gt; to 30, are uature, while of the 14 twigs from the late cultivation t only three, Nos. 1 to 3, are mature, and eleven, Nos. 4 14, are immature. The difference between mature and nature twigs is perhaps better seen in fig. 9, where a ture twig and an immature one are shown with le act Fig. 9. — Mature peach twig on left, immature one on right. APPLICATION OF RESULTS. Young peach trees are especially inclined to grow too late in fall, and, as the result, to be winter injured. The same tendency is often noticed in Japan plums. Some of the American plums, like the Chickasaws and some varieties of apples, like Jonathan, Winesap, and even Ben Davis, would be hardier if they ripened their wood earlier. In any local - ity, then, where these trees are not entirely hardy, growing a cover-crop to hasten their maturity in fall would certainly </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 On the other hand, our common native plums stop gr ing long before the Japan plums and peaches. The i varieties of sour cherries ripen their wood very early and d&lt;&gt; not usually start growth again until the n&lt; though the fall may be wet. Such varieties of apple a&gt; denburg and Wealthy and the Whitney crab also get re for winter early in fall. It is noteworthy that the - ties are hardy, probably on account of their habit of early ripening. With inch fruits it would seem useless to | cover-crops to hasten maturii. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 EXI'KRIMENT III. ROOT-KILLING OF APPLE AND CHERRY STOCKS IN RELATION TO SOIL MOISTURE AND SOIL COVERS. PLAN OF THE TEST. A preliminary test of the effect of a soil cover and of various amounts of soil moisture on winterkilling of tender roots was made the past winter. Seven boxes, two feet are and eighteen inches deep, were tilled with common loam soil of varied water content, the soil in every case being thoroughly mixed, to insure uniform distribution of the soil moisture. In each of these seven boxes of soil, 25 one apple seedlings and 10 two-year Mahaleb cherry seedlings were planted. About the middle of December, 1902, six of the boxes of seedlings were placed on the ground out doors in an unprotected situation. The spaces between the li were filled with hay, packed down and covered with soil, ami hay and soil were also banked up around the outside of the group of boxes. A little later, the seventh box was put in a cool, dry cave. One box of soil was covered with a mulch of straw four inches deep. A second box was pro - &lt;1 by about four inches of snow whenever snow fell, the iction remaining until the snow melted. The other s were left without covering of any sort, the snow even Inking swept off from them after each storm. The boxes were left in place until about the middle of February, when they were taken into a moderately warm room to allow the soil to thaw. The weather was so mild during the two months of the test that very serious injury to the roots was not to be expected. The severe weather of February occurred just after the boxes were taken in doors. The moisture content of the soil of the various boxes was determined before the test was begun. The box of soil covered with snow increased considerably in moisture during the test from the melting of the snow. The mulched soil also became somewhat moister. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Experiments in Orchard Culture. Ifter the boxes had bwu taken indoors and when the entirely thawed, the Medlingl were taken out and ex - ned. It was then noted that some of the apple seed! been injured more than others, some of the olored, while others were bright and apparently uuin - ■d. In general, the roots from the drier soils slm e discoloration than those from the inoi- B. The ■ protected by the straw mulch were least injured of all :pting those kept in the cave, which showed no injui inewhat similar differences were noticed in case of cherry roots, but they went not so pronounced. In I none of these roots were very severely hurt, the poor showing nothing worse than a brown discoloration when cut across. After the preliminary examination, all the seedlings m heeled-in in moist sand in a greenhouse where they remained for about a week before being reexaniined. It was then found that none of the cherry roots had been injured enough to ent their growing, and practically no difference could be detected between the roots from the different 1" With the apple seedlings, on the other hand, the iujun much more apparent than when the roots were rirst exam hied. In the warm, moist sand the uninjured seedlii lieginning to grow, the white tips of new roots could be seen ■plainly and the old roots presented a bright appears The leaf buds also were beginning to ezpaad. On the ol hand, where roots had been badly injured they «■ quite brown and beginning to decay. None of the ro. entirely dead, the tips of all being bright and for the part unhurt, apparently capable of growth independently of the top. The line of demarcation between the dead the live parts of a root was usually well denned, the br decaying part giving place abruptly to the bright, li In a few cases the dead part of the roots extended no more than an inch below the soil surface, but in most cases it ran down from two to four inches, and some roots were dead for as much as seven inches. In some cases, where s. were injured, but not seriously enough to kill them, the RESULTS OF THK T </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 roots were starting feebly into growth. In external appear - ance such roots were like uninjured ones, except that they were a little less bright. When cut into, very considerable discoloration was still seen. It was thought that these roots would probably live and that they might in time recover from the injury. They were classed as merely "injured," the others being either "uninjured," when no injury could be detected, or "dead," when any considerable part of the root was dead, though the root tips were alive. In but verv r Fig. 10 — Apple seedlings. Nos. 1 and 2, root-killed from surface of ground to a depth of 6 inches, tops barely alive, root tips unhurt, sprouting; No. 3, uninjured. I cases were the tops of the seedlings dead. Even where or seven inches of the root immediately below the soil ace was brown and decaying, the top was usually green apparently uninjured. In most respects the injury to e apple seedlings was much like that which occurred the </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Eer before to apple seedlings standing in the Experiment ion nursery. A photograph of the latter is reprodn g. 10. Kll. — Relation of soil moisture and soil cover to root-killing of apple lgs. Number of dead roots indicated by unshaded parts of horizontal injured roots by lightly shaded parts, and uninjured roots by hca 1 parts. The number of dead, injured, and uninjured apple r from the various boxes is given in the table below, which also indicates the treatment that each box of seedlings re - i tived and shows the per cent of water in the soil at the be - ginning of the test. The results are perhaps more clearly indicated in the chart (fig. 11). Table IV. — Root-killing of apple seedlings. — I umber of roots. Where kept. Soil cover. Per cent of soil moisture. In test. Unin- jured. In- jured. (doors None doors None doors None doors None doors Straw mulch .... doors Snow occasionally 1, dry cave . . . None 10.4 15.2 19.8 25.6 16.0 15.8 10.0 2.") as 28 SB IS i; 1 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 the dryness alone, bat to dr.\ and cold combined, is evident from the fact that the n ■ lely unlmrt in eqoallj dry soil kept in a cool, dry cave The nme conclusion is indicated by the fact that lower ends of the roots were never injured, i Feral indies of the upper part of the same roots were i. though the soil in the bottom of the boxes was as dry l». That dryness alone was not. responsible injury is further shown by the comparatively slight in - jury to roots in rather dry soil which was protected I inch mulch of straw, while roots in bare soil of all inn- moisture content were very badly hurt. Just win freezing should injure roots worse in Iry than in moist soil is not shown by the id above. On further investigation it may be found that mply unable to withstand severe freezing or to \er from it unless surrounded by an abundance of i Be this as it may, it is quite probable that one . of the great injury in rather dry soil is alternate freezing and thawing. That freezing and thawing alternately is mncfa more pronounced in rather dry than in moist soil is well known. A test carried out in the winter of 1900 01 showed that this is true, and further indicated that, the more i- a soil contains the less subject it is to frequent alter - ing and thawing. The fact that the apple seedlings were much less seriously injured where protected by a mulch of straw than they were in bare ground is to be explained by thi of mul&lt; on freezing and thawing of the ground. The latter was (1 during the winter of 11(01 02. The mulch pi ■oil not only against severe freezing during cold ni_ i against alternate freezing and thawing. The tern - tture changi on February 2. 3. and 4. 1902 cold jK'iiod — ■ cially interesting. The surface of ound thawed during the middle of the day ami verely each night. Two inches lower, however, the soil did not thaw out during this very cold weather, though the temperature changes between day and night wcr perature of the mulched ground, both at the surface </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 point and, m varied but little during the A cover-crop that mats down on the arrival of cold weather •ects the soil in just the same way that a mulch of straw I, both of them tending to prevent deep freezing and al - ate freezing and thawing. Cover crops that stand ei Fig. 12. — Depths of frost in bare ground represented by full length of hori - zontal bars, ana depths under cover-crop by shaded part of bars. during winter naturally do not directly protect the ground against severe freezing as thoroughly as those that mat down, though they check alternate freezing and thawing by shad - tbe ground, thus keeping it frozen during bright, Iht. Erect cover-crops, however, li. advan mulch-forming ones. They hold the I drifting winds. A blanket of snow is one of the vtr protections against severe freezing and alternate fret and thawing. Moreover, the increase in soil moisture t </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 E:ng snow tends to lessen alternate freezing. and thaw- Some of the records of the depth of frost in bare ground in ground protected by a millet cover-crop are shown •ammatically in fig. 12. APPLICATION OF RESULTS. Many trees with hardy tops are budded on rather tender roots. The cherry is worked on lfahaleb and the plum on Marianna or Myrobalan stocks. Neither of these roots is as hardy as the hardiest varieties of plums and cherries that are worked upon them and are sometimes killed by winters not severe enough to seriously injure the tops of the trees. The seedlings upon which apples are worked vary greatly in hardiness, the tenderer ones being even less hardy than the stocks upon which plums and cherries are budded. When propagated by piece-root grafting, hardy apples are less lia - ble to root killing, since roots form from the scions, making what is known as own-rooted trees, the seedling root if it persists at all being so far below the ground that it is not likely to be injured. Deep planting may accomplish for budded apples in the orchard what is accomplished in the nursery by piece-root grafting. Unfortunately, it is often impractical to protect the tender roots of plums and cher - ries by deep planting, since the roots which start from the scion sprout very badly. ILny method of culture that leaves the ground perfectly ■e in fall, thus favoring deep freezing and alternate freez - and thawing, is not to be recommended where root kill - is at all common. A cover-crop is one of the best means protecting the roots of trees. Likewise, any method of ture that leaves the ground moist in fall has an advan - ce over methods that leave the ground very dry. In this ard, clean cultivation might be expected to be ahead of er-crops. As a matter of fact, however, during the three irs that cover-crop experiments have been carried on at Experiment Station, the soil under cover-crops that are led by the early frosts has been as moist on the approach cold weather as ground (riven clean cultivation through - i the fall. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Experiments in Orchard Culture. 33 GENERAL CONCLUSIONS. We may fairly say that the tests reported in this bulletin indicate the best all-around method of culture for young orchards to be thorough cultivation in early summer, fol - lowed by a cover-crop in fall, so far as tests covering only a few years can prove any method best A mulch of straw - is known to keep the soil moist during summer and it also protects tender roots in winter, but its use will surely in - crease winter injury to tender tops of trees by prolonging fall growth. Besides, a mulch induces shallow root devel - opment, which may result disastrously in later years, and its use is out of the question in large orchards. Thorough cultivation protects trees against drought as well as mulch - ing, and keeps the roots from forming near the surface of the ground. When cultivation is given in early summer, all that is necessary in order to furnish winter protection I stop cultivating in midsummer, grow a cover-crop (weeds being better than nothing) which will dry the ground in fall, causing the new wood growth to ripen early in prepara - tion for winter and which will, by holding the snow or by matting down to form a mulch, protect tender roots during winter. Good cultivation in early summer can often be given young trees by growing some cultivated crop in the orchard. Tender crops are best since they can not be sown so early as to dry the ground seriously in spring and are killed by fall frosts, thus preventing very late drying. Cropping with corn', for instance, insures fairly thorough early cultivation, and corn is a fair substitute for a cover-crop in fall and </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>