<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWENTIETH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane AT LINCOLN TO THE GOVERNOR For the Period Ending November 30, 1910.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane AT LINCOLN TO THE GOVERNOR For the Period Ending November 30, 1910. The CU0m Printiof Cm. XJmiwnnity Place, NobrMka </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS llnii. K. B. Cowles, (.'ummixx Buihliiu I'nsiil.-Dt Hon. &lt;;&lt;■(). ( '. Junkin Hon. Arthur Mullen Hon. Lawxon (J. Brian Secretary Attorney Genera] State Treasurer RESIDENT OFFICERS Daniel S. Woodard. M. I) Ernest o. Weber, M. I) Halle L Ewing, M. 1) Benjamin F. Williams. M. I) Superintendent First Assistant l'li\ ■ Second Assistant Pin - iuner Public lati&lt;l&gt; and Path,. Horace P. Bishop, Ea Mr«. s. II. Raley </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">SUPERINTENDENTS REPORT Governor of Nebraska Dear Sir Ilt is a pleasure, as well as with to submit a general i nial report, for the two-ye a duty imposed by law. for me itatement, in this, the twentieth ar period ending November 1910, of the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. I am pleased to report the bienninm just past has been one of progress and with marked permanent improvements for the in - stitution. There have been no accidents of a serious nature during the period. The state's most unfortunate wards have been kindly treated and well fed with an abundance of whole - some and nourishing food. The sanitary condition of the in - stitution has been of the best. The employes ha\ rule. been painstaking, faithful and efficient. I December 1. 1908, the hej;inninj: of this biennial period. ■ were five hundred fifty-nine i."&gt;:&gt;!i patients in the hospital. bom two hundred twenty-seven ( 221 were males and three lred thirty-two CM2&gt; females; there were admitted ami re - ed, during the bienninm, eight hundred twelve total ber treated during the biennium one thousand three hundred nty-one (1371); of this number there were discharged, \ and escaped six hundred seventy-nin&lt; ninety » died and one (1 I was transferred to the Hastings Asylum. ing six hundred and one Mini patients in the hospital at close of the biennium, November :{0. 1910. The daily average number of patients present for the bien - nium was five hundred eighty (580), who have been maintained at a per capita cost of three hundred thirty-four and 5-100 dollars i*:m.n."&gt;&gt; or an annual expenditure of on.' hundred sixty - and 2-100 dollars ($167.02), or an average monthly eo«1 thirteen and 92-100 dollars ($13.92). The above tabulation in - cludes inebriates and drup habitues. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Care of Patients. I The bosipta] has been crowded during the biennium. but not lively as to sacrifice the comfort and well-being of the ents. The ward* have been kept clean. They have had good. li'siiinc food in abundance, which the physical appearan. patients will attest. The care of the aped and infirm male patients by female nurses lias been discontinued. This service did not appeal to patients as attested by the numerous complaints offered against its continuance. The general health of the patients, as a rule, has been _ Theer have been no epidemics and very little sickness anong them during the period. There have been but few cases of diph - theria, also a few cases of erysipelas, and but one case of typhoid fever and no infectious diseases, excepting tuberculosis. There are always tubercular cases in institutions of this kind, usually scattered throughout the building on each of the wards. The plan adopted in this hospital a few years ago, of setting apart a ■lormitory in one of the wards in the new building for tubercular %, has never been very satisfactory, for the reason they can be kept separate from other patients. They associate with. more or less and come in contact with, the other patients while in the building and when out walking and in various other way-, making this method of isolation practically worthless, and yet it is the best method that can be adopted under present conditions. The training school for nurses has been discontinued. It lieved this method of training nurses does not fit them to go out and take charge of special c ises. And the time consumed, both by teachers and nurses, employed by the state, should be devoted to the case and comfort of the inmates. During this biennium there have been no calls for nurses to take charge of private cases, thus miking it reasonably conclusive that the serv - if nurses so trained are not in much demand. The training needed for the successful management of the insaii first, a natural intuition possessed by the individual: second, the cultivation of a kind disposition, gentleness, pleas int words. and firmness. These qualifications are the essentials necessary to the successful management of the insane. Medicines, scientific - ally administered when ppuuired. plentv of sunshine, fresh sir. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">383 wholesome food, and regular habits, this is about as far a^ can go in the successful treatment of these eases. Pathological Report I The work in the pathological laboratory during the past l.i.-n i has been thorough and most efficient. It has been the ine to secure a sample of urine from each patient when ail - ed to the hospital. A qualitative analysis has been prep 1 each sample and presented to the physician in charge "' patient, and this report has been made a part of the clinical rd of the case. In specially indicated cases the analyses have 1 made qualitative and complete, and subsequent ana ? been made of samples when desired by the physician in charge of the patient. During the past biennium there have ben five hundred thirty-three i ."&gt;:« . urinalyses. seventy-three 73 sputum exam- nteen (17) throat cultures, eighteei blood inations counts, six (6) analyses of stomach contents. fi\ rial ex - aminations of inflammatory pro 1- Widal I and a number of examinations of purulent discharges from dif - ferent organs. There have been four cases of diphtheria shown by culture during the past biennium. In the analysis sof water it has been the routine pr;i It his department to collect from the reservoir, when ter is kept, a sample of water and to subject this sample to dextrose-broth test for gas and to mak,. a colony count by plating method. It has. also, been the practice t.» tak uple from the general dining room tap to subject to the ilysis. This investigation of the water supply has been carried at intervals of two weeks. At no time have the gas forming ranisms been encountered from the samples, but at one time ■ culture count ran up above the usual number, and by order the superintendent, an investigation was made, with the result it some organic substances were found and removed from tin - rage. The entire volume of water was drained out and the erior washed with copper-sulphate solution. I Since the completion of the new stand-pipe it baa n possible to collect samples from the storage and ins iples hav,&gt; been collected from the tap in the dining room. The Widal reaction for typhoid has been applied in all </seg>
            <seg id="p008">I " 1= T j • i m - i i &lt; 4 ' 1 I [ . i </seg>
            <seg id="p009">385 IAiiiomj.' the permanent improvement! may be Mentioned the tion of .1 new Btandpipe at a cost of three thousand dollars 000); the placing of the two Jonei stokers under the two Izontal boilers at an expense of two thousand one hundred and dollars ($2,150); the installation of a refrigerating | i&lt;-e machine with a capacity for Making 2.."&gt;(M) lh&gt; v. This plant cost the state four thousand dollars - erection of an addition to the grren boo* ft.; the inj: of new concrete walls under the old trreen house; the tion of a new hog house. 26x80 ft., with twenty-two pens it cover, and c -rete floor through the middle. 1(1 ft. wide. nding the entire length of building, this making an el. _ Feed one hundred or more head of ho^s in time of stormy ther; also, there are twenty-two outside pens. Kxlti ft.; the ■x to the main building and all other outside building! hare l painted a uniform color, adding much to the heautv and metry of the whole. The interiors of ill the buildings have i painted, and at the present time are in exceptionally Kitary condition. The grounds have been well kept; the vases, the lawn for decorating purposes, have been painted white when placed in an irtistic manner have given a very pleas - effect throughout the grounds during the summer months. »The state employ* a paint OgBOUl tin- year, who is k decorating inside or outside ■r and decorator by the month pt constantly at work painting the buildings. work about the institution, in garden and dairy, directed by Tlie patients do most of tl t kitchen, on the farm, in th&lt; petent help employed by tht stat. Needs of the Institution. This hospital is very much in need of two additional build intr&gt;. one for male and one for female patients. KThe laundry equipment is inadequate. The machinery ■ and worn out ; at least two new washing machines are needed; a shirt, collar and cuff irooer; and at least twenty 7-pound trie irons. To make our engine room equipement adequate to the needs of the institution there should be installed, at once, two 1 - 1"&gt;(&gt; II. 1'. horizontal, tubular boilers and one 360-ampere dynamo. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">386 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT The wall's paid employe* at this institution are not suf - ficient to secure and retain the services of the most desirable help. In bat ■ few of the subordinate places are the « sufficiently high to attract and retain the services of the must capable and efficient help to be had. At present the state is paying from eighteen ($18) dollars to thirty ($80) dollars per month for female help, and from twenty-two ($22 1 dollars to thirty-five ($35) dollars per month for male help. A uniform of wages for ward help ranging from twenty-five to thirty ($'M) &gt; dollars per month for female employes and from thirty ($30) dollars to thirty-five dollars for male employes would secure better and more efficient help and would no doubt ultimately be of great benefit to the state's most unfort unite. KThe appropriation asked for the period beginning April 1, I. viz: — salaries, wages, maintenance and general repairs unts to two hundred twenty thousand three hundred dollars 0,300.00). The usual statistical tables including the farm, garden and dairy products will be found in another part of this report. tin conclusion. I wish to thank the Governor ami each mem - of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings for their kind - and assistance. I wish to thank the steward and our efficient [keeper and each of the physicians, who compose the medical . also the heads of the several departments and other em - es. who have promptly and efficiently performed their re - tive duties, thereby assisting in the successful management ie institution during the biennium just closed. Respectfully submitted. I). S. WOODARD. M. 1). Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 387 TABLE &gt;O. 1 GENERAL ThEAl.MENT FOR THE FORTY YEARS ENDING VEMBER 30, 1910 (INSANE ONLY.) ■■&gt;■ v. ■-■ »■? X z I « . z I 5 S fi h £ * -: 87 8 1 1 56 49 |« M 87 14 1 1 2 56 2 17 73 15 1 5 46 M 46 : -'0 12 - 61 til 72 IX! 30 1 I 3 I U M 1 13 1878.. '.&lt;'' 83 1 11 1879 ISO 117 837 42 1 14 1880 160 114 . 274 44 1 t ■". IM 1*3 l-'» :il7 17 230 164 ... -I'M 71 1 25 _ 1873 -'(Hi 47!) T-t I S3 M 4H6 74 M . 3«0 360 is". MS si M 3M am 07 i :)74 2O\.' '.70 M 4 4 i 4(M) IIS 619 72 I 2 n 4«r, 7t M . 3«0 160 I8S .VIS el M 1886 391 MO 07 1 :.7O M 4 4 i 4&lt;M) 4(M) SIS fil9 72 I 2 IH I'H SM 72 6 2 19 12 131 309 6 2 19 12 131 309 .«»*» 201 1 32 41 :t&lt;m 201 l :t2 41 :t26 189 4 519 1 H 126 189 4 519 1 27 4 . 346 200 4 590 67 2 2 31 14 l»i _'7:i 242 3 518 92 4 I 21 1 ' 26 317 . 346 200 4 590 67 2 2 31 14 10' 1893... -'7:t 242 3 518 92 4 2 21 1 ' 26 317 317 269 1 587 90 4 2 24 17 :tl7 269 1 587 90 4 2 24 17 .141 25f, 2 598 11") 1 30 61 141 598 118 1 30 61 ::.- 101 I 1 19 34 30 101 3 1 19 34 3d (51 216 n 93 3 1 23 57 t.'.l 216 n 93 I 1 23 57 360 SM ■■»'. 73 .'t I 30 19 107 :s:to 2.V1 6 :&gt;8!) 106 .16 2 J4 309 SM 61'.i 90 I 3 28 18 89 3«3 MS :!. r &gt;8 9 732 80 3 ." 531 476 S 1012 10.-, 7 4 ■ 66 182 J16 530 16 1062 lfifi 4 1 61 17 18&lt;. :&gt;16 530 16 1062 166 4 1 61 17 1M MS VJ4 17 I0.-.4 113 7 » .14 80 \&amp; 513 VJ4 17 10r,4 US 7 I M 80 10' 111 1062 121 10 It 181 559 -..-,9 .t.W l'.t 917 -&gt;7 11 71 77 130 508 M 7:. 6 1 48 13 91 501 :,(H) 107 IS 6*2 37 I 3 40 56 3 .-,11 188 66 1 41 132 1910 " - 1 3 4 46 1 3 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT MOVEMENT OF POPULATION. Insane. Summary 1909 1910 t..r In hospital at beginning of year Admitted Returned from parole Under treatment 294 468 762 315 461 776 408 ' Discharged 33 12 9 21 If. Discharged, not insane Eloped 12 3 1 1 1 4 4 Transferred to Hastings Died 1 1 . 19 41 25 21 46 47 Parolee 66 66 132 62 6'.i 131 128 I Total removed 93 1 1 4 207 1 04 1 02 20fi 1 97 216 41?. Under treatment Discharged Eloped Died ... Paroled Total removed 1M 8 187165 5 170 346 11357 Remaining Novem' 1 27 31 .... 31 31 \ l~ 2 Years M W T M VV T MIW T 17!t:i:i2.-)ll -»01 354 555 179 185 71 59 130 17:i 142 315 13 53 66 43 48 91 56 101 157 Ill hospital at l&gt;eginning of year 48 48 M 1 27 48 M Admitted m 7 145133 4 137 271 11128!! Returned from elopement 21 21 :S7 37 58 -,'07 7 214 106 .-&gt;201.'(77 11388 liti :. 121 &lt;I2 2 01 - 40 49 33 33 82 1 1112 2 1 IS 1 16 38 2 41 -.4 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">HOS1MTAI, FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 389 TABLE. NO. 2 Type of Disease of Patients Admitted. Toxic Psych Alcohol Acute Mania Knic Mania iae-depreanv entia Preeox sis Secondary Dementia Psvi-lio-ncwrost's — Epilepsy Hysteria Organie Diwaw Paraplegia Bl ut ion melancholia litv &gt; 13 Senile Dementia Imliecility S Not Insam 4 . | E Development rum Tremena ■rin Schleripsis 1 1 ■&gt; Total 173 Inebriates and Drug Habitues. Men WOMI 2:.:. Alcohol • &gt; Dnisr Ilaliit in ii </seg>
            <seg id="p014">PATIENTS AT HOSPITAL NOVEMBER 30, 1910. TABLE NO. 3 INKMRIATES AND UHVd Addicts Insane Women Men Women Men Adams •&gt; 9. 1 Antelope 1 1 1 1 Boolle 1 Bux Butte Brown 1 Buffalo :) 1 i i i 1 i !l 15 ST 1 »&gt; •) i l l •) Col fax ( inning ( 'lister Dakota l l l in 1 it DonglM Fillmore Franklin Furnas 52 s •&gt; .&gt; 1 •2 3 Iti 11 ;;:;;•"' i i o i Hamilton Ilarlan 3 4 1 1 Holt" 1 2 6 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 391 IXHBKIATKS AND DRH; Insane Addicts .Men Wniiit'ii Men Wolllrll Johnson •&gt; !) i i B2 Lane Madison M.-rrii-k 4:! .&gt; 1 1 1 1 •&gt; Morrill . NYmaha Xu.kolls 1 .1 4 1 13 i 11 Pawnee IVrkins .&gt; 1 1 1 1 9 .( E Willow ardson M 1 3 11 . 1 1 1 H 1 9 Sarpy 1 SanndiTs Reward 12 1&gt; •&gt; ti Sheridan Sherman 1 1 1 Ktts Bluff tyer ■&gt; 4 Thurston Valley 9 1 1 1 1 KBoington yne 9 K'hstcr rk 1 ■ i 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">392 LAM) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT TABLE NO. 3. INEBRIATES AND DRUG Insane Addicts .Men Women Men Women Adams 11 1 Antelope 2 Blain,. 1 Boom 4 Box Bvtt 1 1 Buffalo r&gt; ,„,„ 4 Itar. 1 •") 12 9 2 ( 'berry 1 SL 2 7 ' Cuauag :{ &lt; 'lister 1 Dakota 1 5 Daw.s !» 2 DUo. 1 !) •) t; l 44 :&lt;:{ 4:5 4 m Fillmore 1 Franklin 2 Frontier 1 Furnas 1 10 ti !» (Jartiel.l 1 l( V 7 !i'.T r 1 9 ' Hamilton 2 Ilarlan 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. LINCOLN 393 INEBRIATES AND DRUG Insane Addicts Total .Men Womi'ii Men Women Johnson Knnx 9 .-, .&gt; 1 12 t; 6 Lancaster M iilisoii Merriek 41 4_&gt; L'ii .) • ) .Murrill Vance Xirnah i Nuckolls s I'iiwni-i 5E 4 Platte Richardson Saline 10 •» 1 S innden Seward 8faermao Sioux Ki 12 : •&gt; 1 i 4 4 1 1 Stanton •) ■ ts Bluff yer 4 4 , Thnraton Valley 1 •&gt; ■ 1 1 Khington •s 4 Wheeler 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">LAND COMM1SSIONKRS REPORT 394 Totals 11 INEBRIATES AND DRUG Insane Addicts Total Men Women Men Wonwa 15 to M 7 5 1 13 2(&gt; to 2.') 12 16 9 2 39 IS to 30 24 18 29 2 7S 30 to 35 lit 21 4d 2 35 to 4(&gt; Ki 21 41 1 79 4o to 4.") 17 17 38 72 4.'. to 50 21 11 :il 1 .,4 50 to •"&gt;•") 15 Id 24 4«l 55 to 60 13 ■"&gt; 15 :« 65 11 9 10 1 :il 85 to 70 4 !l 21 7(1 to 7:. 2 11 4 7.") to 80. 1 1 I B0 to 85 4 2 86 to 90 Tnknown 3 2 2:i 1 29 Totnls 173 142 271 11 597 CONDITION OF FATIENTS ADMITTED. TABLE NO. 5. INEBRIATES AND DRUG Insane Addicts Total Men Women .Men Women .Married 7ti 77 14H 10 .{11 Sinple 7.5 4ti 89 208 Widowed 11 Ki 15 42 Divorced !» 1 1 lit Inknown 4 2 11 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">HOSPITAL FOK INSANK. LINCOLN 395 NATIVITY OF PATIENTS ADMITTED. TABLE NO. 6 INKHKIATKK AM) 1)HI( Insane Addicts Total .Men Women .Men Women Kria 4 mia :j •&gt; I 10 11 .) Belgium Canada • &gt; ■ ) i Denmark •&gt; •) ■ &gt; England &lt; termanv Greece •&gt; .» Hi it; l : Holland i i Ireland Moravia Norway 1'oland Russia s 14 1 1 1 1 •&lt; •) 4 ■) i land I 17 !i . ) United Sttaes 11(1 •Japan mi 1!»4 10 1 1 1 Hungary 1 Inknown 11 t; J4 41 Totals 171 142 271 11 OCCUPATIONS OF PATIENTS ADMITTED. TABLE NO. 7 XKMKIATKS AM) DHVd Insane Addicts Total Men Winner .Men Women Actor •&gt; 1 •) •i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">LAM) COMMISSIONERS REPORT &gt; INEBRIATES AND I&gt;KI"&lt;; Insane Addicts Men Women Men Woini'ii Bartenders 4 • s &lt; Blacksmiths o '.i i ■) :i Barbers i 1 Boilermaker 1 •) Butchers •&gt; 4 12 it; Carpenters 4 ! &lt; 'onductor, St. Car 1 ( n*rks i H r Makers 1 1 •&gt; 1 ( 'ontractor 1 Cook 1 1 •&gt; !l I &gt;oinesties \) 1 Dancing-master_. 1 Dressmakers .s DnifTfrists 1 4 • &gt; •) Electricians 9 Engineers, sta'ry 2 ■&gt; Farmers ~&gt;1 62 Firemen. staVy 1 1 1 •&gt; Harness-maker 1 Housekeepers !l!l il Hotel-keepers :{ Insurance Agents 1 1 Laborers 40 i;&lt;&gt; Iron-moulders •&gt; •&gt; 1 1 Jeweler Lawyers •&gt; •&gt; Liverymen 1 •&gt; 11 l.i Masons .&gt; 4 Merchants 1 ■ &gt; Musicians 1 ; Music Teachers 1 nger Boy Machinists •&gt; 3 1 Minister 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">PITAL FOR [NSANE, LINCOLN 1 1 •&gt; ;:::;:;;; •&gt; 1- i i Kicians ibers 4 1 1 4 • Prostii ■» 1 1 4 ! Real Kst. Ae'ta 1 ! Switchmen Sailor 4 : 1 Shoemak Soldier Students 1 •&gt; i i •&gt; •&gt; 4 Kograpl &lt;men •) 14 Teachers ■&gt; 4 Telegraphf 1 ! Tinner Tailors l 9 Teamsters • &gt; 6 s Veterinary Sur No occupation •&gt; ■&gt; 11 11 T'nknown 12 Totals 142 271 11 CAUSES OF DEATH. TABLE NO. 8. Men W Kte Cardiac Dilatation plexy 1 Bronchiti Chronic Endocarditis 1 Eaustion austion of Acute Maim 4 1 ■&gt; Intestinal Tuberculosis 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Maniac Depressive Organic Brain Disease Pulmonary Thrambris Pulmonary Tnberculosi -is Pneumonia 1'vemia Senility Typhoid Fev Totals Dipsomaniacs. By Degeneration of Herat rium Trcmeiis. 1 1 Pulmonary Tuberculosis •) 1 Totals POPULATION FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1909 Men Women Total Number of inmates present at the b ginning of the fiseal year ■&gt;■)- AA9 559 zz&lt; ■ \.Y£ Number admitted during the y&lt; ir 240 !»(» til 54 115 Number returned during the ye ir 67 Number paroled during the year 8] :S4 Number discharged during the y iar 120 Number Eloped during the year 1 1 1 1!) Number died during the year 2:! Number piBSent at end of h'seal year 227 :i")"&gt; Average daily number inmates present 221 346 Average daily number officers and em- ployea </seg>
            <seg id="p023">I r.. . i * i .\ i 171 j.n POPULATION FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910 Men Women Total ber of inmates preseni at the 1 nniiif.' (it the fiscal year ■&gt;•)- i.). N T umber admitted during th&lt;- year 2&lt;&gt;4 63 b: year .")1 137 ing tin- y&lt; n K»1 71 ! 72 N'umber discharged daring the year 105 13 118 dumber eloped during the year 43 3 Number died daring tin- year 26 22 18 2fi ■)■) *H N'umber transferred to Hastings 1 1 1 Number present at end of fiscal year 242 :{."&gt;!&gt; •age daily number inmates preseni 2:i(i n«l of fiscal year 242 •age daily number inmates preseni 2:i(i Average daily Dumber officers and em - ploye* 39 42 -q \ v n 19 42 81 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS. FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS Corn 6,000 btti 6,000 bus 1,881 bushels z Wheat 1,88] bushels 400 boRDeb Barley and Spelts 300 bushels id Sift Millet Seed 300 bw Straw 10 tons Millet S Oat Straw Wheat Straw 40 t 40 tona 300 tuns 325 tona Prairie Jlav 300 tons Alfalfa Hay Tame Hay Millet Hay (an,. Hay 25 ton 20 tuns 30 tuns 200 ■ Knsila' 3,500 bus 1.317 bu* Asparajru 15 itUshels 290 hllshels Beans, strin Beans, dry s bushels blood turnip </seg>
            <seg id="p024">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 400 !.age 45.000 I, 300 h 500 heads 12 bnshe Cauliflower Cherries _.. Corn. 650 hu&gt;li. Kns. spinach n pepper e radish ice 119 hu Musk melons ... Onions, dry.... Onions, green 160 ;:::::;: 173 in busht-ls luislu'l s bush'ls bushels Pudey Parsnips 9 300 158 Potatoes, sweet Radishes _ 147 82 Rhubarb ifv . 115 2.-. Tobii Tomatoes 125 1.374 wherries Turnips H4 'It 115 Watermelons _ 1 :&gt;,ooo Cattle and Hogs E butchered.... butchered butchered. 319 head 22 head 179 head 172 3 32 Dairy. El number gallons milk thly average gallons milk y average gallons milk y average per cow 65,700 2.738 2.045 Daily average number cows milked 44 Poultry. 4.229 dozens 3 bu 2 bushels 146 bm 23,000 bnshela </seg>
            <seg id="p025">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. LINCOLN 401 Cash Received From Sale of Farm and Garden Produce. Cattle * in Hides 2.01 1 Millet seed Wheat 1.571 Melons and emntelottpe* 512 "4 ■ ape and tomatoes Rasrs and old iron 1 1 ■'■ Tomato, cabbage and sweet potatoe plants 155 rJl*€*flo Total $13,61 CASH FUND $ 1,299 73 h on hand December 1. on deposit with State Treasurer December 1. 1908 1,627 45 2,927 18 Total cash— December 1. 1908 Cash received for care of dipsomaniacs $12,180 71 Cash received from sale of live stock 8,329 15 Cash received from sale of hides 2,016 20 Cash received from sale of bread 396 59 4,540 86 27.463 51 Cash received from all other sources expended from December 1, 1908, to November 30. 19H' *28.134 05 Cadi on deposit with State Treasurer No - inber 30, 1910 591 33 i on hand November 30, 1910 1,665 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">402 L^VND COMMISSIONERS REPORT A&gt; the average Dumber of patients present during the two years was 580, the per capita cost was .+:{:S4.0.'&gt; or $1:5. !t2 per month, not considering the money received from tlie counties for the board and care of inebriates. If we add to this the amount received for the board and care of inebriates, $12,180.71, the total amount expended for maintenance and general repairs would be 1205,929.99, which is $355.05 for the two years, or +14.79 per capita per month. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. LINCOLN £ ?: * V. X /. * Z I y; / &gt;- v^ /- r 7 S3 v. M &gt;: Z z i'. X Z Vr z X X z s OS lHI z i ~. 5 5 8 S — ■ CC — CZ =* — .z. S s - age a "*• *- — ■&lt;r~* r- " - : •• ~- 3 =- ~. '-. S m m e 3S S x *" t- •.* I s s s 1~ M £ r ~ - = ' ~i ''. t~ •" "^ •"* — _• go - 11 5..S till!:--* </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>