<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00085.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA R. L. COCHRAN, GOVERNOR Second Annual Report NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION 1938</title>
               <date value="1939-02-01">1939-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA R. L. COCHRAN, GOVERNOR Second Annual Report NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION 1938 DEPARTMENT OF LABOR NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION STATE HOUSE - - - - LINCOLN February 1,1939 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Office of the Commissioner of Labor Lincoln, Nebraska February 1. 1939 Honorable R. L. Cochran Governor of Nebraska Lincoln, Nebraska Dear Governor: in compliance with Sec. 4S-711 (a), C S.. Supp., X&lt;'\»: 1937, I herewith submit the second annual report of the Unemployment Compensation Division covering the calendar year of 1938. Very truly yours. V. B. KINNEY Commissioner of Labor </seg>
            <seg id="p003">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page State Officials, State Advisory Council, and Advisory Committee on Merit Examinations 1 Foreword 2-4 Cost of Administration 5 Unemployment Compensation Administration Fund Balance Sheet and Statement of Receipts and Encumbrances 6 Administrative Expense for Calendar Quarters During 1938 7 Monthly Expenditures for Personnel Services During 1938 8 Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund 9-10 Balance Sheet, Unemployment Compensation Fund 11 Cash Receipts and Disbursements, Unemployment Compensation Fund 12 Monthly Cash Collections During 1938 Classified by Source and Type of Collection 13-1-1 Quarterly Collections of Contributions and Interest 14-16 Contributions to Employer Reserves Classified by Industry 16-18 Subject Employers. ... 19 Workers' Wage Reports 19 Rules and Regulations 20 Merit Examinations -for Administrative Personnel 21-22 Covered Employment and Payrolls. Total All Industries 23-25 Covered Employment and Payrolls by Industry Groups 26-28 Monthly Employment and Payrolls by Industry, Appendix A 29-33 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATE OFFICIALS R. L. COCHRAN Governor V. B. KINNEY Commissioner of Labor R. T. M ALONE.. Director, Unemployment Compensation Division STATE ADVISORY COUNCIL: Representing Industry: DONALD BRIDGE, Norfolk. Nebraska. Norfolk Cereal and Flour Mill. WILTON VAN SICKLE, Lincoln Nebraska. President of Van Sickle Class &amp; Paint Company. Representing Labor: 6. M. OLSKN. Omaha. Nebraska. Member of Plumbers' Union. Attorney for Omaha Central Labor Union. L. 0. SCHON. Lincoln. Nebraska. Electrical Contractor, member of [brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Representing the Public: HOBART BLACKLEDGE. Chairman. Kearney. Nebraska. Prominent Attorney of Central Nebraska. EARL MARVIN. Editor, Beatrice Sun. Beatrice. Nebraska. DR. FREDERICK W. CLAYTON. Pastor of All Saints Epis - copal Church, Omaha. Nebraska. ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON MERIT EXAMINATIONS. CHARLES C. HELLMERS, Chairman. District Manager of ! lowa-Nebraska Light and Power Company. Lincoln. Ne - ! braska. (Term expires September 15, 1940.) E. W. AUCUSTINE, President, Augustine Company, Grand Island, Nebraska. (Term expires September 15. 1939.) WILLIAM D. LANE. President, Eggerss-O'Flyng Company, Omaha. Nebraska. (Term expires September 15, 1941.) Supervisor of Merit Examinations: DR. E. GLENN CALLEN, Nebraska Wcsleyan University, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FOREWORD The Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Division had as its major objective in 1938 the preparation of a program that would assure the prompt and accurate payment of benefits to eligible claimants after January 1, 1939. The normal function of the Division during the year was tin- collection ofi quarterly contributions from Nebraska em - ployers, subject to the Law, based on wages paid to covered workers. The accurate crediting of individual wage records to each covered worker and the proper accounting of contributions to the individual reserve accounts of each subject employer was the principal work of the Division during 1938. During the year, $133,778.26 was expended for administra - tion, flic entire sum of which was granted to Nebraska from the Social Security Board. Audits of the administrative expense records of the Division are conducted at periodic intervals by the Social Security Board staff. Expenditures and budgets are thus rigidly surveyed. Continuous studies are being made tending toward simpli - fying the administration of the present law, with the aim of facilitating payment of benefits and reducing administrative expense. MERIT EXAMINATIONS Early in the year the Advisory Committee on Personnel th numb its Supervisor of Examinations, Dr. E. Glenn fallen, con - ducted a series otj written and oral examinations. The purpose of these examinations was to establish registers of personnel based mi merit examinations as set forth in the Unemployment Com - pensation Law. Following the written and oral examinations registers of I,7Bl 'applicants were established, and all adminis - trative persons at present employed by the Unemployment Com - pensation Division in permanent or temporary positions, exclu - sive of the Director, have been appointed from the eligible posi - tions on these registers. During December, 1938. the Division had 10 1 employees on its payroll. However, a number of these employees were added temporarily to take care of the peak load of benefit claims which is expected during the first three months of 1939. I EMPLOYERS CO-OPEKATING Nebraska employers in general are to be complimented on the promptness with which they supplied the Division with the 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">necessary quarterly reports of payrolls and contributions. The response was so general, in fact, that the percentage of con - tribution delinquencies of 1.32 approached a very favorable minimum. BENEFIT SECTION About August 1, the Benefit Section began to function. A Chief of Benefits was appointed. Several assistants and neces - sary stenographers carried on the work of this section until December 1, when the skeleton staff was enlarged sufficiently to prepare for the start of benefit payments on January 1, 1939. The principal work of the Benefit Section during the five' months of 1938, following its organization, consisted largely of drafting procedures and forms which would facilitate the hand - ling of claims with dispatch and accuracy. Much valuable in - formation was gathered from other states which had been pay - ing benefits during the early months of 1938. On December 1, a full staff of claims deputies was appointed. These deputies immediately began an 'intensive training period which lasted until Christmas, when they were assigned to duties at the headquarters of the Division in Lincoln, or in the field offices of the Nebraska State Employment Service. Meanwhile, a series of staff conferences was necessary in order to properly coordinate the work of the Unemployment Compensation Division and the Nebraska State Employment Service, which under the Nebraska Law has the responsibility of taking all claims for benefits. These staff meetings were very beneficial and due to the splendid cooperation of the Ne - braska State Employment Service and its Director. Mr. Harry Bane, the work of these two divisions of the Nebraska State Department of Labor was co-ordinated so that claims for benefits could be cared for properly. Since Nebraska's Law contains specific provisions for fur - nishing information regarding benefit payments to public agen - cies concerned with the administration of work relief, the Divi - sion held several conferences with Federal W. P. A. officials am! with the State Assistance Department in order to work out needed procedures. EDUCATIONAL MEETINGS Early in September the Division began a state-wide program of education with the objective of properly informing employers, covered workers, and the general public as to important features of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law. As the 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 month of January was approached, this program was centered upon benefit payment procedures. During the month of December a series of seventeen educa - tional meetings was sponsored by the Unemployment Compen - sation Division in conjunction with the Social Security Board. The Nebraska State Employment Service cooperated in arrange - ments for these meetings which were held in the larger centers of employment within the State. Splendid public response was accorded these meetings, and representatives of key industries in the State together with representatives of labor and of the gen - eral public were in attendance. An educational pamphlet explaining the benefit provisions of the Law and stressing eligibility requirements of claimants and the proper procedure to follow in filing claims for benefits was widely distributed throughout the State. PREPARE FOR BENEFIT PAYMENT The staff of the Division worked strenuously during the closing months of 1938 in order to be ready for the payment of benefits after January 1, 1939. Employees of the Unemploy - ment Compensation Division will be located at some twenty key points over the State wherever local offices of the Nebraska State Employment Service exist. Adequate preparation having been made, the Unemployment Compensation Division was prepared to care for the peak load of benefit claims which will be filed during January, 1939. ADVISORY COUNCIL The Division appreciates the help that was secured during the past year from the State Advisory Council, which is com - posed of representatives of industry, labor, and the public. In the administration of unemployment compensation, questions of policy arise that affect the various groups interested in the operation of the law. The State Advisory Council was very cooperative ami helpful in offering suggestions and recommen - dations to the Division in connection with the formulation of ad - ministrative policy. Respectfully submitted, It. T. Malone, Director UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION </seg>
            <seg id="p008">COST OF ADMINISTRATION During the calendar year 1938. $133,778.26 was expended for administrative purposes. The entire amount of this money was received in the form of grants from the Federal Govern - ment through the Social Security Board in accordance with Title 111 of the Social Security Act. During 1938, $119,774.29 was received from the Social Se - curity Board in the form of grants, and $26,487.54 was received in the form of reallotments. At the close of the calendar year 1938, there remained unencumbered, in" the form of unallotted grants. $12,483.57. The cash on hand in the State Treasury as of Decemher 31, 1938 amounted to $27,839.66. This includes $2,418.40 of warrants outstanding. The amount of the admin - istrative grants that remains unencumbered at the close of an administrative period is reallotted to the. Division to cover ex - penditures for the next administrative period. All grants made to the State from the Social Security Board for Unemployment Compensation administrative expense were made on a quarterly budget basis, and the expenditures were incurred in accordance with the rules and regulations of the State of Nebraska and the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Division. Xo funds from the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation fund .ire used for administrative expense purposes. Section 48-712, C. S. Supp., Nebr. 1937 provides lor a special Unemployment Compensation Administration Fund. All funds with respect to the administration of the law are expended from this fund. As provided in Section 48-712, C. S.. Supp.. Nebr. 1937 all monies with respect to Nebraska State Employment Service activities are maintained in the special Employment Service account of this fund. The report of the funds of the Nebraska State Employment Service account, including funds granted by the Social Security Board to the Employment Service. are not included in this report. The following balance sheet, and receipts and expenditures statement cover the administration of the Unemployment Com - pensation Division. 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION ADMINISTRA - TION FUND (Exclusive of Employment Service Account) BALANCE SHEET As of December 31, 1938 ASSETS EXHIBIT A Federal. Cash December 31. 1938 $25,421.26 Equipment 23,468.98 &lt; lonsumable Supplies on Hand 2,779.90 TOTAL ASSETS .$51,670.14 LIABILITIES Unallotted Grant $12,483.57 Accounts Payable 12,937.69 Equipment and Stores Accountability 26.245.88 ' T&lt; &gt;TA L LIABILITIES .$51,670.14 UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION ADMINISTRA - TION FUND (Exclusive of Employment Service Account) STATEMENT OF RECEIPTS AND ENCUMBRANCES January 1, 1938 Through December 31, 1938 KKC E I I *TS : EXHIBIT B Reallptments $26,435.70 Adjustments to Renllotments 51.84 $ 26.487.54 Federal Fund Grants —154 F . . . TT~ 119,774.29 $146,261.83 ENCUMBRANCES: Personal Services $ 86.682.32 Equipment 14.634.31 Travel 8,588.90 Printing and Binding 7,574.34 Rental o£ Equipment 5,691.37 ( 'onsumable Supplies 4.508.16 Postnge 1.854.00 Repairs and Alterations 1.656.81 Telephone 822.67 Telegraph 143.93 Transportation of Things 646.63 Rental of Premises 97.50 Advertising 45.05 Other 832.27 $133,778.26 Unallotted firant $ 12,483.57 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Reconciliation With State Treasurer's Account No. 15 l-F As of December 31, 19315 SCHEDULE B-l Unallotted Grant December 31, 1938 $12,483.57 Encumbered Accounts Payable 12.'937.Y&gt;9 Outstanding "Warrants 2.418.40 Balance on December 31, 1938, State Treasurer's Report i-&gt;7 kj-jj) (j,; During the calendar year 1938. the Division encumbered $133,778.26 for administrative expense. Although Section 48-720, C. S„ Supp.. Xchr., 1937. appropriates state funds, which could be used temporarily for administrative expense purposes and later refunded, no part of the State appropriation was used during .1938. The accompanying Table 1 shows the amount expended for administration of the Unemployment Compensation Division dur - ing the calendar year 1938. The table shows the total amount of expenditures for the year and for each of the calendar quar - ters' by the type of expenditure. Table 1 Amount and Per Cent of Expenditures for Administra - tion of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Division For the Calendar Yiear 1938 and for Calendar Quarters Total For Year' Amount of Expenditure.- Tyi&gt; e "f Per For Calendar Quarters Ending Expenditure Amount Cent March 31 June 3(1 Sept. 30 De7\~3l~ TOTAL 5133.778.2H 100.00 527.053.1l $25.069.44 534.053.12 $47.570,66 Pers Services 8fi.652.32 64.80 17.813.89 17.831.16 23.069.18 27.967.79 Equip. Purchase ... 14.634.31 10.94 2,010.04 2.153.82 4 319 56 6150 89 Travel Expense 8.388.90 fi.42 1.664.76 154132 " l"l'9'l 1268*11 Prtg. &amp; Binding 7.574.34 5.66 1.976.27 497.80 '626.69 ' 1.474.08 Rentals 5.788.87 4.33 612.21 1.361.73 1.690.90 2 121.0.) Consumable Sup. .. 4.508.16 3.37 1.052.37 600.27 1.079.91 1775 61 Communications 2.820.60 2.11 378.82 629 26 73-80 1 079 7* gep. &amp; Alter 1.656.81 124 1.263.39 158.62 70.70 164*10 Trans, of Things. ... 646.63 .48 153.35 126 14 "33 31 m S'l Advertising 45.05 .03 25.55 " Too is'.-,o Other 832.27 .62 102.49 169.02 138.24 122.52 "Corrected to Februniy, 1939. Approximately 65 per cent of all administrative expendi - tures made during 1938 were incurred for Personal Services. The total expenditures for Personal Services during 1933 amouted to $8(5,682.32. The amount of Personal Services by months during 1938 is shown in Table 2. 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Table 2 Amount of Monthly Expenditures for Personal Services During the Calendar Year 1938 Month Amount Total for .1938 $86,682.32 .January 5,618.79 February 6,071.44 March 6.123.66 April 5,278.12 May 5,932.17 June 6,621.17 July 7,026.97 Au-usl 7,929.24 September 8,112.97 October 8,138.17 November 8,395.22 December 11,434.40 The increase in the administrative cost, especially in the category of Personal Services, was occasioned by adding the function of wage record processing, and by preparing for the payment of benefits beginning with January, 1939. The total number of employees on the staff of the Unemployment Com - pensation Division in December, 1938 was 107, including perma - nent, temporary and probationary employees. This was an in - crease of 69 employees over December, 1937. Included in the 107 employees in December, 1938 are thirteen temporary em - ployees, who were added during the month of December pre - paratory to the payment of benefits in January. 1939. The entire operating staff of the Division, exclusive of the Director, and including the temporary employees, was selected from registers established by merit examinations. Table 3 shows the amount of administrative expense for the year and for the calendar quarters, and the per cent of admin - istrative expense to total collections received. Total collections include contributions received converted to a comparable 2.7 per cent of taxable wages, as well as employer penalty interest and Trust Fund interest. y ■ 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Table 3 Per Cent of Administrative Expenditures to Total Contributions Received During Calendar Year 193J5 Calendar Amount Per Cent 1 Period Administrative Administrative Expense 1938 Expenditures To Total Collections For Year $133,778.26 3.19 First Quarter 27,053.14 2.15 Second Quarter 25.069.44 2.72 Third Quarter 34,085.12 3.47 Fourth Quarter 47.570.56 4.58 ■Contributions for 1937 received during 1938 were converted to an equiv - alent of 2.7 per rent of taxable wages. Administrative expenditures for 1938 amounted to 3.2, per cent of all collections received during 1938. NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND During 1938, $5,104,664.98 was added to the Nebraska Un - employment Compensation Fund, bringing the Fund balance and cumulative collections to $7,041,539.05 as of December 31. 1938. Total collections during 1938 and the Fund balance as of De - cember 31. 1938 include employer contributions, employer pen - alty interest, interest from cumulative balances in the Fund, and a special Congressional appropriation. The collections made during 1938 and the balance as of December 31, 1938 do not include contributions from employers covering wages paid in covered employment during the months of October, November, and December. 1938. The reporting requirements of the Division provide thai employers shall sub - mit their contribution and wage record reports to cover a.calen - dar quarter. The due date for the contribution and wage re - ports is the end of the month following the quarter covered by the report. The contribution and wage reports, and likewise, the contributions for wage payments made during &lt; ictober. No - vember, and December, 1938 were not due. therefore, until the 31st of January, 1939. Inasmuch as all administrative expenses are paid from grants made by the Social Security Board, and benefit payments 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">did not begin until January, 1939, no payments, other than em - ployer refunds, were made from the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund during 1938. Submitted herewith is the Balance Sheet, a chart of collec - tions received, and the Statement of Receipts and Disbursements of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund. Of the total balance in the Trust Fund as of December 31. 1938, $204,680.26 was in the Clearing Account of the Unemployment ( 'ompensation Fund of the State Treasurer, and $6,836,859.69 was deposited in the Nebraska Unemployment Trust Fund. United States Treasury, Washington, D. C. A continuous balance of approximately $200,000.00 is kept in the Clearing Account of the State Treasurer. All remaining collections are forwarded to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, and credited to the Nebraska Unemployment Trust Fund in accord - ance with the provision of Section 48-709(a), C. S„ Supp., Nebr. 1937. It should be noted that the Balance Sheet is designed to show tin; cash position of the Fund inasmuch as the re - ceivable items included under the assets are offset by the ac - count, "Unrealized Contribution.'" The liability section of the Balance Sheet shows the amount of overpayments of contribu - tions and interest by employers and the distribution of the re - maining fund between employer reserves, pool reserves, and re - serve for unallocated appropriation. 'With respect to contributions receivable. Judge Hunger of the Federal District Court in the De Gniw Motor Company Bankruptcy case reversed the referee's finding that claims for unpaid unemployment compensation contribu - tions were allowable as general claims only, and gave the Commissioner of Labor a preferred claim. 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THE UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND Balance Sheet as of December 31, 1938 ASSETS EXHIBIT c Unemployment Compensation Fund Clearing Account S 204,680.26 Unemployment Trust Fund Account in U. S. Treasury 6.836.859.6!) Contributions Receivable 571.355.85 Contributions Receivable in Suspense 1,402.56 Dishonored Checks Receivable 588.50 Total 7573,346.9l LESS — Unrealized Contributions 73,346.91 none TOTAL, ASSETS 77. Jtf^l~s3SK&amp;s LIABILITIES Claims Payable: Overpayments of Contributions $ 3,421.32 Overpayments of Interest 44.28 S 3.465.60 Unemployment Compensation Employers' Reserve: Contributions Paid in Full and Processed . $5,623,618.58 Contributions Held in Suspense Pending Adjustments 426.12 5.624.044.70 Unemployment Compensation Pool Reserves: Interest in U. S. Trust Fund Account. . . .$ 71,723.79 Transfers From Employers' Res. Accts.. 6,353.26 Interest Delinquent Employers' Accts. . . . 5,760.46 Total ."$ 83,837.51 LESS — Interest Earned on Delinquent Accounts Not Collected 643.76 83,193.75 Reserve for Unallocated Appropriation by Congress 1,330,835.90 TOTAL LIABILITIES $7,041.5391)5 UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND MU..ONS CUMULATIVE COLLECTIONS OF 00U.ABS 9 oY. 1 1 0 J A J 0 J A 1937 19 3 8 19 3 9 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND Statement of Cash Receipts and Disbursements For the Year Jan. 1, 1938 Through Dec. 31, 1938 EXHIBIT D Clearing Trust Fund Account Account Total Balance of Cash on Hand 1-1-38.$ 236,874.97 $1,700,000.00 $1,936,874.97 Collections: •: Contributions: First Three Quarters 1937.! 106,589.39 Fourth Quarter 1937 756,878.98 First Quarter 1938 908,691.74 Second Quarter 1938 954,700.19 Third Quarter 1938 984,771.99 $3,711,632.29 Less Decrease in Contribu - tions Held in Suspense..... 11,542.66 Net Contributions $3,700,089.63 3,700,089.03 Interest on U. S. Trust Fund Account 71,723.79 71,723-79 Interest on Delinquent Em - ployers' Accounts 4,734.73 4,734.73 Dishonored Checks Redeposited 8.129.12 8,129.12 Transfers In 3,734,300.00 3,734,300.00 Appropriation by Congress 1,330,835.90 1,330,835.90 Total Cash Collections. .$3,712,953.48 $5,136,859.69 $8,849,813.17 Total to Account for. .$3,949,828.45 $6,836,859.69 $10,786,688.14 Disbursements: Refunds of Contributions .... 2,062.04 2,062.04 Dishonored Checks 8,786.15 8,786.15 Transfers Out 3,734,300.00 3,734,300.00 Total Disbursements ..$3,745,148.19 $3,745,148.19 Bal. of Cash on Hand 12-31-38..$ 204,680.26 $6,836,859.69 $7,041,539.95 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Table 4 Net Cash Collections During Calendar Months from All Sources to the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund October 1, 1937 Through December 31, 1938 Total Employer Employer Trust Fund Congressional Date Collections Contributions Interest Interest Appropriation TOTAL $7,041,539.95 $5,633,819.28 $5,160.98 $71,723.79 $1,330,835.90' 1937 Total 1,936,874.97 1,936,448.72 426.25 October . . . 1,750,046.60 1,750,044.97 1.63 November 155,535.82 155,359.47 176.35 December 31,292.55 31,044.28 248.27 1938 Total 5,104,664.98 3,697,370.56 4,734.73 71,723.79 1.330.835.90 January ... 814,232.33 809.353.46 614.22 4.264.65 February .. 8,788.19 8,233.82 554.37 March 17,677.02 17,297.25 379.77 April 304,651.63 289,654.82 856.89 14,139.92 May 602,974.78 602,799.27 175.51 June 1,340,441.33 9,228.56 376.87 1.330.835.911 July 614,554.21 594,856.04 279.23 19.418.94 August 355,266.59 355,081.27 185.32 September 9,541.93 9,250.08 291.85 October .. . 894,613.40 860,453.19 259.93 33.900.28 November 129,458.96 129,209.80 249.16 December 12,464.61 11,953.00 511.61 The accompanying Table 4 shows the cash collections during 1937 and 1938 by calendar months. It should be noted that the $1,330,835.90 received during the month of. June 1938 in ac - cordance with H. R. 8174, representing the 1936 tax refund, is included in the collections during 1938 but is excluded from the contributions received during 1938. Excluding the refund for 1936 taxes paid under Title IX of the Social Security Ant. total colfections during 1938 amounted to $3,773,829.08. It should be pointed out that all the collections received during 1938 were not based on a 2.7 per cent of taxable payrolls, inasmuch as a part of the collections were for the year 1937, for which the rate was 1.8 per cent of taxable payrolls. ■This represents the amount made available to the Unemployment Compen - sation Fund of Nebraska pursuant to Aet of Congress, Publie No. 353. 75th Con - gress, Chapter 755, Ist Session. 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">During 1938 the individual employer reserves increased from $1^936,448.72 to $5.(&gt;27.466.02, and the pool account from! $426.25 to $83,238.03. All employer contributions are credited to indi - vidual employer reserve accounts; interest from Trust Fund in - vestments and employer penalty interest, together with reserves of terminated business firms, are credited to the pool account. The following table 5 shows the reserve accounts and pool ac - count accumulations by months during which the collections were received. Collections received after December 31. 1938 which were for 1937 or 1938 contributions or interest are not included. Table 5 Monthly Accumulations of Reserve Accounts and Pool Account During 1937 and 1938 by Type of Collection Employer Reserve Accounts Pool Account . Month Monthly Collections and Cumulative Amt. of Cumulative Trust Fd. Empl. Reserve Year Amount Contributions Amount Total Interest Int. Transfers Total 55. 627.466.02' $rv 627.466.02 583.238.03' 583.238.03 $71.723.79 55. 160.98 56.353.26 1937 ~ ~~ ' ''" Total 1.936.448.72 426.25 426.25 Oct. ■ 1,750.044.97 1,750.044.97 1.63 1.63 1.63 Nov. 1.905.404.44 155.359.47 177.98 176.35 176.35 Dec. 1.936,448.72 31,044.28 426.25 248.27 248.27 1938 Total 3,691,017.30 82.811.78 71.723.79 4.734.73 6.353.26 Jan. 2.746,802.18 809.353.46 5.3U5.12 4,878.87 4.264.65 614.22 Feb. 2,754,036.00 8.233.82 5.859.49 554.37 554.37 Mar. 2.771.333.25 17.297.25 6,239.26 379.77 379.77 Apr. 3.0«U.955.07 289.651.82 21,236.07 14.996.81 14.139.92 856.89 Slav 3. 663.787.34 602.799.27 21.411.58 175.51 175.51 June 3.673.015.90 9.228.56 21.788.45 376.87 376.87 July 1.262.958.18 589.942.28 16.400.38 24.611.93 19.418.94 279.23 4.913.76 Aug. 4.618,039.45 355.081.27 46.585.70 185.32 185.32 Sept. 1.627.280.35 9,210.90 -16.886.73 301.03 291.85 9.18 Oct. 5,487.665.53 860.385.18 81.114.95 34,228.22 33.900.28 259.93 68.01 Nov. 5.616.241.29 128.575.76 81.998.15 883.20 249.16 634.04 Dec. 5,627.466.02 11.224.73 83.238.03 1.239.88 511.61 728.27 'Includes 53. 421. 32 contributions overpaid by employers. -Includes 544.28 employer penalty interest overpaid by employers. 11l connection with the accumulation of the individual em - ployer reserves and the pool account, the congressional appro - priation of $1,330,835.90 is not included in either the reserves or the pool. This appropriation is being held in a separate account pending a decision of the Nebraska Legislature with respect to its disposition. 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Table 6 Total Cumulative Collections to the Nebraska Un - employment Compensation Fund from All Sources Classified by Period for Which Payments Were Made' Total Collections Contributions 1 Average Average Amount Calendar Quarterly Quarterly .if Quarter \mount Collection J _ Amount Contributions' Interest TOTAL, ,58. 150.393.03 $1.017.285.21 5JL03J2J176V24 51.007.308.78 5117.416.79 1936 1.330.835.90 998.126 92 1.330.835.90 998.126.92 1937 Total 2.790.715.54 1.046.518.33 2.786.114. 53 1.014.793.06 4,600.71 First 3 Quarters .... 2.033.711.53 1.016.855.76 2,030.019.79 1.015,009.90 3.691.71 4th Quarter 757.004.01 1.135.506.02 756,095.04 1.131.1-12.56 {HIS. 97' 1938 Total 4.028.841.59 1.007.210 40 3.916.025.51 979.006.38 112.816.0S Ist Quarter 936.036.36 936.036.36 917.168.23 917.168.23 18.868.13 2nd Quarter 981.770.88 981.770.88 961.775.56 961.775.56 19.995.32' 3rd Quarter 1.031.079.13 1.031.079 13 997.178.85 997.178.85 33.900.2S 4th Quarter 1.079.955.22 1.079.955.22 1.039.902.87 1.039.902.87 40,052.35 •Tills table reflects cumulative collections, including contributions and in - terest received on the January 31. 1939 due date to cover the fourth calendar quarter of 1938. and to cover earlier quarters. The figures are corrected t., February 15. 1939 and exclude contributions in suspense. S AU collections, including Interest, were converted to an equivalent "f 2.7 per cent (if taxable wages. a For the purpose of this tabic, tne congressional appropriation is classified as contributions. 4 AU contributions were converted to an equivalent of 2.7 per cent of taxable wages. a Figures include interest from investments in the Unemployment Trust Fund. U. S. Treasury, and employer penalty interest. "Includes $168.33 interest collected in January,' 1939 on 1937 delinquent accounts, but not allocated to any quarter. 'Includes $315.89 interest collected In January. 1939 on 1938 delinquent accounts, but not allocated to any quarter. After including substantially all contributions due for 1937 and 1938 and correcting for the difference in contribution rates, the average quarterly contributions collected for 1938 amounted to $979,006 compared to $1.1144.793 for 1937. Total average quarterly collections for 1938, including in - terest, amounted to $1,007,210. While contribution collections during 1938 were on a lower level than 1937. increases were re - corded for each calendar quarter during the year. It should be pointed out, however, that the fourth quarter collections are af - fected by bonuses and special year end payments. Table (i shows the contributions and interest collected for each reporting periotl. Interest received for 1938, including interest on investments and employer penalty interest, amounted to $112,816.08, or a 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">monthly average of $9,401. Interest received for the fourth cal - endar quarter of 1938 averaged $13,351 per month. Interest from the Trust Fund amounted to $107,511.49 during 1938. The average annual interest return on monies in the Trust Fund, exclusive of the Clearing Account balances, was 2.477 per cent. CONTRIBUTIONS TO EMPLOYER RESERVES CLASSIFIED BY INDUSTRY Contributions to individual employer reserves for the year 1938 amounted' to $3,916,025.21. Delinquent payments for the year 1938 made after the January 31. 1939 due date will neces - sarily correct the total collections for the year. The correction because of delinquency, however, will, not materially affect the total contributions. 1 In several industries, however, the contri - bution collections for 1938 will be affected by late payment of contributions. This is true principally in three industry groups — service, including hotels, furnished rooms, etc., transportation other than interstate railroads, and construction. The amount of contributions received during 1938 and dur - ing each calendar quarter of 1938 from each industry subject to the Unemployment Compensation Law is shown in Table 7. The contribution rate during 1938 was 2.7 per cent of all wages subject to the taxing provisions of the law. 'On tite basis of the contributions collected for 1938 and the total estimated contributions payable for 1938. 1.32 per cent of the contributions due were un paid approximately fifteen days after the fourth calendar quarter due date. 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Table 7 Amount of Contributions to Employer Reserves, Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund Received for 1938 and Calendar Quarters of 1938, Classified by Industry Contributions' Received For 1938 Industry* Total ~ Calendar Quarter . Amount Per Cent " ' First Second Third Fourth ""TOTAL ALL INDUSTRIF.S.T WMMS^ 100.00 3917U08.23 &lt;M1.77i.56 8997.178^ .1.039.902.87 „„. nl . 1.(170 .',08.71 27.31 253,603.22 261.UBl.lll) 201.31)0.28 231.454,21 rKAl "'' „.,|) ■■&#132; &#132;, "VhS r, ( , i 47 n56 965.54 56.008.33 60.079.85 Wholesale Distributors 208 OM4O 531 49.792.28 50 20322 51533.18 56,565.74 Wholesale Merchants..... 208 ,09 .( •&gt;. ■ i».«m - 11100.48 39,162.02 52,144.03 Retail General Merchandise »0 .454.13 I.JO Sg'Jjggj 37 456.13 37,301.18 40,026.15 Wholesale and Retail Trade sf'VliMW ''M 20 382 87 22490.35 22,310.73 22.127.21 ReUll Automotive S'gsS'S !H 2 '20284 20138 44 20 239.05 22.072.45 Reta Trade Not Classified m'oos'!s 207 19 687 33 20352.11 10.801.61 21.168,10 RefalrAroarei^:;;:^^;: :::::: ::::::: S'Sw*" i'»- SSS-m ■?.*«•«•■ l3 - 863 ' 25 ,6 ' 369 '" MANUFACTURING 905.718.82 23.13 210.222.10 223.071.35 223.411.00 2.18.113,29 MANUFACTURIWO &#132;.„.,.,-.,. TTln 128 125 55 138.120.86 137.803.83 158.228.10 Food Manufacturing ', r is ™ 3 22 30 876 73 32 106.29 30,002.18 32,406.38 Printing and Publishing ............... 126.18 1.58 3.22 J1&gt;,67«. .1 735153 8273.32 8.030.18 iron and Steel and Their Products. .. . I.'.'".' 1 , ' &#132;, 6546 32 6 728.28 0,505.30 7,022.60 Machinery Other pan Electrical SH.o'aS '„ 5 243 90 6.59083 7 105.69 6.828.62 Stone. Clay and Glass Products 25.7 69.04 .66 6.194.80 6.600.08 6.539.35 Chemicals .;;,'.,,.-n Vl 1806 06 5 130 51 4,007.75 5,763.35 Finished Lumber Products 52'?iS' 7 2 3? ; mI.o" '.814 40 3 490.72 3.671.58 Electrical Machinery .. Wasam 36 00 82 3 368.30 3 419.64 3.866.31 Apparel, Flnisluv Articles. } Vil'l "• «H&gt; 36 3 413 08 3 646.29 3,184.15 '. 3.669.38 Nonferrous Metals. Products 13 .01- .9 1 ..l» 2 767 44 2 883 22 2.005.01 3.404.7.1 Paper and Allied Products J '!'J'!'. %\ 239442 2 577.84 2,506.31 2,798.72 Basic Lumber Products TtS'S 1 "Wis 073.08 1,130.62 1,029.75 Leather and its Manufactures .i'a^m 4S 5 363 14 4.469.10 14.16,10 1.674.26 Miscellaneous Manufacturing 18.012.00 .is &#132;,.»&gt;.&gt;.n INTERSTATE RAILROADS V . \ 812.278.02 Wt., ' 188.251.66 W1.9W.711 21M0040 .213J27 ll 0 UTILITY'S ■-■ 276.571.81 7.06 67.327,10 70.194.08 69,807,74 . , 69,151.72 UTILITIES. ,-,. &#132;..,, &#132;, -7T7J 13 015.57 46,219.44 11.225.68 43.878.73 Communications i,i., .1.1.1.1- *.au &#132;, ,11 it 24711022 25 498 38 25,150.21 Light, Heat, Power Companies ... TO 'H?'?S 2 „J '9995 mil ' 173 68 22.7J other Local Utilities ■ 581.73 .02 00.0., 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">PERSONAL AND BUSINESS SERVICE. . . 256.1.19,14 6.54 66.061,10 Ji^O! 62,700.49 , -^~F ~Pc7s7uT-U Service ~~~... ~6,800.83 1.45 . 13.861.68 11.586.48 IJ-i*|J'J?1 J-i*|J'J? 'o'Sai? i i i mi [i. 1 1 service ■-■■ — ■■. ..,.„- .i, 1 i»e .« «iii 1 1 in nu7 7&lt;i 'l 02.1.81 O.tiJj, 1 &lt; Hotels. Camps. Lodging Places ........ JHtlSo *'2S 'b'lbilo 9 42462 '',0158 10 076.69 Business Service &#132;. 38.561.20 .00 HSM2 i'iiiu', 8 242 37 8 013.08 toting and Drinking Places 33.010.18 .81 ?-g_'sS S'nTOM 783476 7 989 58 Auto Repair Services .11.173,18 .80 '■^15 «?2l"»7 6'530 ; ,7 71.17 2 Motion Pictures 27,026.91 .60 J'™-' 8 . S'iSm 1707 41 2 747 04 Amusement and Recreation 14.174.26 .36 3 -&lt;iH2 iKS', 1 FIMM 127812 Employment Agencies. Schools 1.821.21 .12 J- 2 ??'! 8 'Ss! 1149*77 9 261 Repair Service, and Miscellaneous 4.097.48 .11 1.0 6.40 MMI ''iK'S sou 99 Agricultural and Horticultural Services. . 3,883.56 .10 910.74 1.281,17 sjo..!i, FINANCE ANTJ INSURANCE '.. 258,214.06 6.59 62.866.67 63.694.44 63,963.78 '""%&amp;% -Tn.un.nc, Carrurs •.:.. ~^&gt;|f'| 3 ' 7 | WS tSS Finance Agencies 30.383.60.. .78 5'67693 6012.53 5.945.40 6.716.00 {rstment'^an.ing and Seeurl.y:::::: ! ! | ! || &lt;:&gt;f? 2 ° £«£ 3 : 70 i;§ij S»a'„dTKsfcomlS"^::::::::: f : : : § JgJ« i : §SI2 Miscellaneous Finance. Group 14.476.40 .37 3,277.1n 3.532.62 3,712.13 .1.005.D0 CONSTRUCTION 158,437.39 4.05 25.523.33 36,931.09 50.633.95 i|g£j| -General Contractors Olher Than Building 91.115.19 2.33 »."MJ 2 ??. ii'mss? 10*«266 General Contr:clors Building 38,606.68 .99 *'™H1 All 11 7M1?2 7 35227 Special Trade Contractors 28.625.52 .73 6.567.74 6.893.99 7,811.i2 T.M.1l TRANSPORTATION Other Than Railroads. 148,063.12 3.78 37.648.76 37.874.86 37,860.33 "l'"'-" "Trucking and Warehousing .T~ ■ 39,554.67 ToT 11.015.45 11.228.54 9.012.68 7.308.00 Services Allied to Transportation 32,135.83 .82 f- 2 "-™ I'ml? ?'21116 7438 64 Street, Cltv Railways and Bus Lines.... 20,419.02 .75 .Hills ,AmA 1254793 11975 77 Miscellaneous Transportation 46,953.60 1.20 11,069.74 11,360.16 12,547.93 11.in0.f4 MISCELLANEOUS 30,003.21 .77 5.570.51 8.505.07 8.733.80 . '',103.74 Non-Metallic Mining and Quarrying' . . . . 11,566.89 .30 HiU'S owVn 219802 2'050T0 Medical Services and Law Offices 8,895.08 .23 2 ' 302 ?J anil'l? 165372 152157 Membership Organizations 6.301.97 .16 *"HrH 'mIU 49231 41840 Other Social Service Agencies 2,195.64 .06 665.49 619.44 492.31 41H.4U crude Petroleum and Natural Gas .... 952.73 .02 59/T5 371.89 SOOJJO ftyu &gt; Includes contributions received on the January 31. 1039 due date for the fourth calendar quarter and for earlier quarters. The figures are corrected to February 15, 1039 and exclude contlbutlons In suspense. = The classification Is based on the Social Security Board's Industrial classification, March 15, 1937. J The figures are exclusive of penalty Interest received from employers. 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">SUBJECT EMPLOYERS With respect to the number of employers subject to the Ne - braska Unemployment Compensation Law, 348 were added from January 1 through December 31, 1938. During the same period there was an increase of 457 in the number of accounts main - tained by the Division for reporting purposes. The increase in the number of subject employers is attributed in part to em - ployers electing coverage under the Law. and to the fact that the list of subject employers was gradually completed during the year by field and coverage work.' Table 8 shows the num - ber of employers and accounts added and terminated during 1938. Table 8 Number of Subject Employers and Active Accounts of The Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Division 1938 Number of Employers Number of Accounts ■Changes During Month Ch;n,;:--s During Month Year Active Ter- Active Ter - .inil End of Net Addi- mina- End nf Net Addi- mini, - Month Month Change tions tions Month Change tions lions 1938 Total 348 739 391_ 457 878 421 Jan. 1 . . . 2,989 777 3.180 Jan.-May. . 3,182 193 394 201 3.366 166 396 210 June 3,197 15 48 33 3,379 13 53 40 July 3,223 26 48 22 3,404 25 50 25 Aug 3,231 8 39 31 3,411 7 39 32 Sept 3,260 29 38 9 3,549 138 147 9 Oct 3,281 21 51 30 3,577 28 60 32 Nov 3,305 24 58 34 3,604 27 65 38 Dec 3,337 32 63 31 3,637 33 68 ' 35 WORKER'S WAGE REPORTS On April 30, 1938 the Unemployment Compensation Division received the first workers' wage reports from subject employers. These reports covered the earnings of covered workers during ■Several District Court decisions relating to the determination "f liability under the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law were made during the year. In the case, Interstate Live Stock Commission Co. vs. Kinney, the District Court of Lancaster County held that the provision of the law permitting an employer to be held liable on the basis of employment in the preceding calendar year did not apply to 1936. In Kinney vs. Sanitary Towel Co.. Inc., the District Court of Douglas County refused to declare the controlling interest clause |48-702(g&gt;(4) 1 invalid. 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">the months of January. February, and March, 1938. The Unem - ployment Compensation Law provides that the first base period with respect to payment of benefits shall begin January 1, 1933. In order, therefore, to have available the necessary wage infor - mation at the time of benefit operations, the Division requested wage reports listing the Social Security account number, the name of the worker, quarterly earnings, and wage rate informa - tion for all covered workers. The workers' wage reports received from subject employers for the fourth calendar quarter 1938 included a listing of 147,424 wage items. RULES AND REGULATIONS The Commissioner, after public hearing and publication, promulgated two General Rules during 1938 that related to benefit payments. These rules are designated as a part of Series II of general rules and arc as follows: Rule Title 111 Part-Time Workers IV Charging of Benefits Against Several Employers During 1938, the Commissioner of Labor also issued a series of regulations regarding benefit operations and payments, which were effective January 1, 1939. These regulations, other than Regulation No. 11, are also a part of Series 11. Benefit Regulation No. Title 1 Claims and Registrations for All Individuals Claiming Benefits for Total Unemployment Except Those Covered by Benefit Regulations 2 and 3 2 Claims and Registrations for Individuals Located in Areas Served by Itinerant Service 3 Claims and Registrations for Individuals Affected by a Mass Separation, or by a Strike, Lockout or Other Labor Dispute 4 Forms Prescribed for Recording Claims for Benefits and Registrations for Work for Total Unemployment 5 Separation Notices 6 Payment of Benefits to Multi-State Workers 7 Interested Parties 8 Appeals to Appeal Tribunals 9 Determination of Full-Time Weekly Wage 10 Weeks of Unemployment and Weeks of Disqualification 11 Disqualification for Benefits 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">MERIT EXAMINATIONS FOR ADMINISTRATIVE PERSONNEL In accordance with the regulations for the merit system and personnel administration promulgated by the Commissioner of Labor in October, 1937 and pursuant, to the provisions of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law, written and oral examinations were held during January, February, and March of 1938 to establish registers. From a total of G.055 applications for examination received by the Supervisor of Examinations, 1.781 names' were placed on the registers after passing the pre - scribed examinations. The number of persons appearing on the registers varied from 472 on the Junior Clerk register to two oii the Chief of Research and Statistics register. The official regis - ters and records of the examinations are kept by the Supervisor of Examinations at his office, Wesleyan University, Lincoln Nebraska. The registers were officially established on April 1. 1938 The original registers established at that date, based on the pre - scribed examinations, were as follows: 2 „ Number on br&gt;J»lr,S Original Register Register Clerical Junior Clerk 470 Intermediate Clerk 165 Senior Clerk 1 23 Junior Clerk-Typist .320 Junior Clerk-Stenographer .21 1 Intermediate Clerk-Stenographer 63 Senior Clerk-Stenographer lti Junior Duplicating Machine Operator , 17 Key Punch Operator jo Senior Tabulating Machine Operator . 7 Supervisor of Tabulating Unit .. ... 3 Legal Junior Attorney 1 4 General Counsel '.'.',['„,', 7 g in lSS^ EinSSSiF * y aS S 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Accounting • Intermediate Accounting Clerk 109 Senior Accounting Clerk 79 Junior Accountant 77 Chief Accountant 12 Field Adviser Unemployment Compensation Field Adviser.... 24 Chief, 'Unemployment Compensation Field Advisers 22 Statistical and Research Junior Statistician 7 Intermediate Statistical Clerk 9 Chief of Research and Statistics 2 Informational Assistant Informational Assistant 13 Examinations for Chief of Benefits, Appeals Referee, and Claims Deputy were not included in the original series of exam - inations given during the months of January, February and March. 1938. Upon recommendation of the Advisory Committee on Personnel, the Supervisor of Examinations established regis - ters for the three classifications by using the names of persons on certain original registers.' For purposes of establishing registers for Chief of Benefits, Appeals Referee, and Claims Deputy, the Supervisor of Examinations used original registers of Chief Accountant. General Counsel, Chief Unemployment Compensation Field Adviser, Junior Attorney, Unemployment Compensation Field Adviser, and Junior Accountant. With respect to the merit examinations, establishment of the registers, and the selection of the temporary staff, the Ad - visory Committee on Personnel in its first report to the Com - missioner of Labor set forth the following conclusions: "You are to be commended on the care with which you selected the temporary staff pending the establishment of registers based on merit examinations. A large number of these persons earned very satisfactory grades in the exam - inations, and are being continued in the Division. "The Committee has much evidence for its contention that a substantial and representative type of Nebraska citizen participated in the examinations and secured places on the registers of eligibles. Your Committee is convinced that you may be assured of an efficient personnel for po - sitions in the Division." 1 ■It should be pointed out that this is not the number of different persons appearing on the registers inasmuch as one person may be eligible for atroolm - ment from more than one register. TT^ „ j!.f lrst Semi-Annual Report of the Advisory Committee on Personnel E. Glenn Callen, Supervisor of Examinations. Nebraska Wcsleyan Unlversitv Lincoln, Nebraska. T .*' 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">COVERED EMPLOYMENT AND PAYROLLS The Unemployment Compensation Division requests a quar - terly (calendar) report from all employers in the State of Ne - braska who are subject to the provisions of the Nebraska Unem - ployment Compensation Law. The report is designed to furnish total quarterly wage information for contribution purposes, and detailed quarterly wage information for each worker included on the payroll during the calendar quarter. As a part of the contribution section of the employer report, information is requested for each calendar month. This informa - tion includes the number of covered workers employed in the last pay periods of all types ending within the month, and the amount of wages payable in all pay periods ending in the month. These reports permit practically complete coverage with respect to employment- and payrolls in those industries included under the provisions of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law. Firms in covered industries that are exempt because of the size-of-firm provisions of the Law are not represented in the employment and pay-roll data compiled from these reports'. The total volume of covered employment and -'amount of wages for covered workers based on the calendar quarterly re - ports is shown in Table 9. The chart on the opposite page shows the monthly fluctuations in the volume of covered employment and amount of covered payrolls unadjusted for seasonal variation and using as a base of 100 the average monthly employment and payrolls for the year 1937. It should be noted that employment during 1938 in general was on a lower level than for 1937. but that encouraging gains were made during the latter part of the year. Losses in employment and wages during 1938 were ex - perienced in all industries ; the most severe losses, however, were felt by workers engaged in transportation, manufacturing, and construction. The unusual increase in payrolls for the month of Decem - ber, 1938 was attributed to the payment of year-end bonuses, salaries, and gratuities. This increase in payrolls was recorded in every major industry except interstate railroads. 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">COVERED EMPLOYMENT AND PAYROLLS 4 . IN NEBRASKA II I I l-l l-.-l I .|i||| NII I I 1:1 1-1. J II jjl 1.1 I 11 - -13- • U .- ; . . ■ I ;- .■ f .;. : L .:,_. Id- -- - ■ ■■■■■ ,oo ; .y^TTirN i , i h /_ L I 11 - -80 -r-A — I — . i &#132;^_. _; 70 — . , 6ol — I — I — I — I — LJ — I — I — LJ — I — I — LJ — LJ — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — LJ I I I I I I l_ J A J 0 J A . d ■ 0 J A J 0 1937 19 38 . 1939 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Table 9 Volume of Covered Employment and Amount of Covered Payrolls State of Nebraska, for Montbs of 1937 and 1938 Year and Volume of Employment Amount of Payrolls' Month Volume 1 Index 5 Amount' Index* 1937 January 116,838 92.8 February 114,920 91.3 March 119,781 95 . 1 April 124,267 98.7 May 128,018 101 .7 June 131,524 104 .5 July 130.810 103.9 August 132.416 105.2 September 131,961 104 . 8 October 132,371 105.1 November 127,067 100.9 December 121,009 96.1 Monthly Average 125,915 100.0 $13,066,588 100.0 1938, January 112,632 89.5 $11,454,135 87.7 February 110,379 87.7 11,119,546 85.1 March 112,223 89.1 11,660,873 89.2 April 114,121 90.6 11,916,538 91.2 May ... 116,119 92.2 11,820,244 90.5 June 118.789 94.3 12,317,437 94.3 July 117,751 93.5 12,529,873 95.9 August 119,901 95.2 12,441,655 95.2 September 121,142 96.2 12,483,082 95.5 October 124,403 98.8 12,687,490 97.1 November 120,696 95 . 9 12,282,856 94 . 0 December 119,480 94.9 14,260,259 109.1 Monthly Average 117,303 93.2 $12,247,833 93.7 The monthly fluctuation in covered employment and pay - rolls for eight major industry groups in Nebraska are shown on the charts on the opposite page. The charts are based on Table 10, which shows the indexes of covered employment for 1937 and 1938, and the indexes of covered payrolls for 1938, unadjusted for seasonal variation. , Volume of employment is defined as the number of covered workers em - ployed in the last pay periods of all types ending within each calendar month. 'Monthly average for 1937 equals 100. "Amount of payrolls is defined as the money wages and other remuneration payable in pay periods ending in each month. 'Monthly payroll Information for 1937 is not available. 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">o s ; ; ;ii iiiii i i.-iiiiiii'i ssagsgsss^s ttzss lists &lt;- I—ll——!lr— 1 1 1 1 1 T~T 1.11 I ' * «- .-zdzz^zzjzjzjz -==EES: Ez .^tj: : : * •S"ffig "°~ X Ts=^g °Ez|zzbzzzzzz^ °[: 3 3 If O &gt; '•-:-: -:-t-izjqzp^ "■:- : -zfzztzpjjj ■ I I zzxzzzg -Z-j- - }: t rij, I+zrzzz§ -r^rf/zLizazi zElz=^s ===3== = F=ffi =^==g=rzzzp^ ztzr£zzzt±:g z "zzzzzw .-i — iztjz — — .z=±zznz^ 9 • — + z -V- i - ; F : -f- 1 0° = =rzzE§ ' --— j" zfcz : ==pzlzztz=z§ ; =^ztztffl:§ § pp TOM uaßTi-aJg M#N ... ? 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Table 10 Indexes of Covered Employment for 1937 and 1938 And Payrolls for 1938 in Eight Major Industrial Groups in Nebraska 1 Personal "ear Inter- Other and Con- Public Finance and Mnnufac- state Trans- Business at rue- Util- and In- Month Trade turing Rnllr'ds portatlon Service Hon illes Burance Employment 1937 January ... 95.0 93.8 99.3 107.0 96.6 38.0 96.2 97.2 February .. 94.7 93.7 93.2 103.0 96.1 34.5 95.1 96.9 March 99.5 95.7 96.2 100.1 99.1 52.7 97.0 97.8 April 99.5 98.8 98.1 99.9 103.0 84.3 100.3 99.7 May 100.0 102.0 103.0 99.2 104.6 100.2 102.1 100.6 June 100.0 105.4 108.3 100.5 102.9 120.6 105.0 101.0 July 98.8 103.3 104.3 95.8 99.4 150.5 103.1 102.0 August 99.6 104.1 105.5 98.5 100.4 158.5 102.2 101.5 September . 101.6 103.0 100.6 99.7 102.5 149.7 103.7 100.8 October 103.9 105.4 103.6 101.0 101.2 127.6 100.6 101.0 November .. 102.2 102.6 96.5 98.3 97.1 110.1 98.1 100.9 December .. 105.1 92.0 91.5 97.0 97.0 73.5 96.6 100.5 1938 January ... 95.6 90.9 79.2 97.7 94.7 57.8 92.2 98.1 February .. 94.3 87.7 80.6 92.3 94.2 48.3 91.2 97.5 March 96.0 88.2 77.2 92.4 95.8 67.6 91.7 98.2 April 95.0 90.0 78.4 92.2 96.1 75.7 100.2 98.5 May 93.9 91.1 83.0 91.2 98.1 90.4 94.9 99.1 June 93.9 92.9 85.4 90.7 98.1 111.2 96.8 99.6 July 93.1 90.3 91.1 94.5 93.1 105.9 95.8 99.4 August 93.8 92.2 93.4 96.3 93.9 115.9 95.2 99..-, September . 97.6 91.1 95.9 89.1 96.2 114.0 94.6 97.9 October .... 105.3 96.1 94.5 89.0 96.4 104.9 93.8 97.5 November .. 103.9 96.2 87.6 87.3 93.7 85.0 93.6 96 3 December .. 111.6 91.1 82.8 88.0 93.6 66.0 92.4 97 0 Avg. 1938 .. 97.8 91.5 85.8 91.7 95.3 86.9 94.4 98.2 Payrolls 1938 January .... 89.1 86.3 84.8 94.9 93.9 59.3 96.6 97.8 February .. 86.7 87.0 79.1 92.3 91.0 55.4 93.3 95.4 March 93.3 85.7 82.8 96.5 98.5 71.4 96.0 99 6 A Pril 95.7 91.9 80.1 97.7 98.1 73.7 101.9 98.2 May 90.4 90.7 83.8 94.3 97.4 81.9 97.9 98.1 J une 94.1 94.3 87.6 94.6 98.7 101.9 98.3 100.7 J uly 94.9 92.8 93.7 95.7 97.9 106.2 100.5 103 5 August 90.0 93.3 95.8 100.4 94.7 120.7 98 7 97 3 September . 93.3 90.9 96.8 92.5 98.5 120.2 97 7 975 October .... 94.3 97.9 99.0 85.7 96.3 110.3 97 8 976 November .. 90.9 100.0 92.0 83.8 94.0 93.6 96 4 975 December .. 127.1 110.5 89.0 95.7 107.6 107.9 995 1204 Avg. 1938,. 95,0 93.4 88.7 93.7 97.2 91.9 97.9 100^3 '1937 monthly average = 100. 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">EMPLOYMENT AND PAYROLLS BY INDUSTRY In Appendix A to the report is shown the volume of tmiploy - ment and amount of payrolls for each month of 1938 by indus - trial classification. Table 11 shows the employment each month, and the average for the entire year; Table 12 shows the amount of payrolls for each month, and the average for the year. The classification by industry is based on the classification of the Social Security Board, March 15, 1937 Revision. Included in Appendix A is also a subclassifieation of food manufacturing. Food manufacturing in Nebraska is the largest manufacturing .industry, and includes a number of unrelated manufacturing processes. Table 13 of Appendix A shows the monthly indexes of employment of industries included in the classification "Food Manufacturing" of Table 11. using the monthly average of 1937 as 100. The detailed data for individual industries are presented in this report for the purpose of permitting employers to compare their trend in employment and payrolls with that of the entire industry as well as making available industrial employment and payroll data to those persons interested in the field of unem - ployment compensation and labor. The data presented includes only the employment in the State of Nebraska that is covered by the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law. Firms in a covered industry that are excluded from the Law because of the si/.e-of-firm exclusion, less than eight employees, are not rep - resented in the data. During the coming year, the Division plans to make further subclassifications of industries engaged in manufacturing in Nebraska. 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">APPENDIX A Table 11 Volume of Covered Employment for Eacl, Month of the Calendar Year 1938 — . __^_ Classified by Industry INDUSTRY. M J n ?£, y ' TOTAI Art ,«,r.„, " AveraKe January February MaVch XS TOTAL ALL INDUSTRIES 117 •,„•, &#132;, „,_ TTTZT- — 121i32 ""-379 112.223 in. I -w^MiVDWrtbu'tor,::::;:::: - 3 %?g —Trie? - 3ii - 19 ? 3r, - g " 2 ~^ Wholesale Merchants H 47 R . 7 JI 8.628 6.715 iTT Retail General Merchandise. "I. '! S'J?? ?'§JJ J.«O .',.412 b| Wholesale and Retail Trade " ?™ J-J" T-626 7.939 7.6! Retail Automotive i-H* &lt;&gt;5 M 4.580 4.148 I? Trade Not classified.:.:::;:; |*?5i i- 03 ? 2.919 2:923 Sia Retail Food *•&lt;;» 2 .811 2.782 2.770 -7 Retail Apparel ";,;; 3.301 3.305 3,249 3.318 3.4 MANUFACTURING , ' ° 7 I'9lB1 ' 918 2 .001 2.277 2!' " Food Manufacturing '. '. ." '■ Trim — HMZi 24.762 24.919 2.1.4 f™ t,n 1. and Publlihlng,....:. ; ?'?? 2 I WiZ 14 - 79fi 14.660 10 Iron and Steel and Their Products « 42 HI? 3 - 42 3 3 407 3 4 "finery other Than Electrical.":.::.':: '• 133 SJS sl3 SIB 8 Ch o emica C lL ayandClaMProdu «» " 781 8g SH SI? ! Finished Lumber Producti St 4 550 "HM 575 11 Electrical Machinery 66 ? BSO 664 708 Apparel. Finished Articles...:::; 88 ~JO 394 429 4 Nonferrous Metals. Products... 221 Ji r 'fil 603 r, Paper and Allied Products .' 2,',? 3,5 380 401 4 Base Lumber Products l%\ 298 293 297 2 Leather and Its Manufactures...:: T? 4 , ?J} 277 282 2 Miscellaneous Manufacturing- .... JA? "J 182 183 , INTERSTATE RAILROADS.... ,- ??. ° 3 ! 914 921 UTILITIES Z3~ -~- -^^2 _1i393 . 15.7Q9 1.-,.t Communications ... j4?? ~ 427 7.346 7.382 s,( LiKht. Heat power companies:: :::::: j-sjj %-%«i 4.825 4Tt7B — r.~. Other Local Utilities 2 - 8 ?2 2.532 2.493 2 553 : , : PERSONAL AND BUSINESS smvrrv 12 il2 „ . 2 * • 2S 31 rtr»onal Service " — -4p.£ — "■■"' '2.26Q 12.47U 12.. Hotels, camps. Lodßinß places::::::;: ?■;?: 2 "» -2.419 s^pt — 27 Business Service V™} 3 ' 240 3,261 3 244 3! Eatlns : and Drinkln K Places.:.::: IZB '-J 33 . Ml* 1106 ?'i Auto Repair Services f 08 ? 2.198 2.123 2 095 •&gt;', Motion Pictures I'" 7 1.190 1,153 i"S T. Amusement and Recreation . '. o-i 5 42 931 '940 , i™, 1 ", 01 "?"", AKencles. Schools...::.;'. Ykq i'2i 7n 81" » R '?f' r ,. Ser r lcc " and -Miscellaneous ,JS J?? J°o 178 Agricultural and Horticultural Serviced A, S 4 MM 153 FINANCE AND INSURANCE.... "" . " -If 2 "° 230 Insurance Carriers rrV^r. 2dS£ -'"21 5.768 Finance AKencles 3 -' ou 3 - 09( &gt; 3.084 iTToS" T Real Estate ; « 44 644 636 630 , i n^; tn " nt . Banklnß and security;;.;;;; •■•• %'Z ?38 935 9 56 Insurance AKents and Brokers..... o?? 343 299 303 Bank and Trust Companies fj; 280 273 275 Miscellaneous Finance Croup...: J?g J?5 178 176 CONSTRUCTION r dl ° 319 .314 General Contractors-Other Than' Bui'ldin K " TSF H^T '"'"''" ' 4 - gf ' 3 General Contractors—BulldlnK *"' ' 3, 5f5 !S 71 lISS 2li2T T~ Speclal Trade Contractors.. .... . J - 378 1.2J2 i,045 i,VSo f ] TRANSPORTATION Other Than M^V ]' ' J£ ™ , « |» «» TrucklnK and Warehouse j—jg 1^ -. 4:i89 4 -'396 &#132;. sfwit"™" l^ f.° Tra »»p&lt;&gt;rtation. :::: ::;: '-jj? , 1 « 9 « lsm rvriir — r SKSKi ?ii. y Ra , l ' w "&gt;'s and Bus Lines ?J B 'S 4 ? 8 « 4 830 Miscellaneous Transportation , IJ? ,723 728 723 I MISCELLANEOUS .. , 1 - ,9 ° llf,s I.IBS 1 " Non-Metallic Mlnlnu and Qua'r'ryin B ' ~ 252. —iIiSL ». M„ ed ,hf' ?." v !? ea and Law °"'«s ::::::• ? 7 J 3 j 4 259 3sr -=— ; Membership Organizations ill ZH 398 332 °"»« Soc'al Service AKencles .' ; 318 240 248 245 Crude Petroleum and Natural Ga5...:.;..;; J? 8 1 »&gt;3 K6 2. tortSffi^d. to Hn%i^^ u^? 1 0 f^«&gt;' 1| Bo.rd-. classification. March ,s.'' ,937 ment of subject employers who "fa^dTo^o?, 5 STSi F22Z SSBSSS "Vhe'oSLC </seg>
            <seg id="p033">: MONTHLY VOLUME COVERED EMPLOYMENT* May June July AuKust September October November December 116.119 118.789 117.7 M 119.901 121.142 .124.403 120.696 119.480 35,047 35.030 :14,727 34.981 36.404 39.282 38.752 41.642 6.358 6.380 6.554 6,545 6,648 6,620 6,601 6,315 5.384 5.427 5.543 5,488 5.423 5.458 5,470 5,482 7.695 7.517 7.271 7,529 8,578 11,554 11,184 14.145 1. 426 4.502 4.546 4,538 4.574 4,630 4.625 4.552 2.953 2.992 2.976 2,987 2,923 2.875 2.917 2,961 2.719 2.725 2.657 2.695 2.702 2.658 2.65T 2.779 3,352 3.405 3.265 3,199 3,237 3,304 3,231 3,309 2.160 2.082 1.915 2.000 2,319 2.183 2.067 2,099 25.737 26.235 25.511 26.031 25.718 27.126 27.154 25.715 15,498 18.135 15,735 19,124 15,807 17.358 17,481 16,384 3.396 3.317 3.069 3.080 3.103 3,114 3,113 3,021 793 863 887 917 912 806 799 782 839 820 826 846 829 814 796 798 822 843 913 882 842 817 728 618 596 605 641 626 613 596 583 586 704 698 653 650 664 657 640 628 106 357 374 370 357 374 373 374 610 581 478 571 591 584 566 453 107 389 380 312 328 359 377 391 294 295 291 302 311 307 315 314 290 283 284 298 297 274 284 282 174 179 174 174 171 156 160 158 •' 908 870 806 879 893 912 939 926 16.887 17.359 18.529 19.001 19.497 19.216 17.811 16.828 7.643 7.791 7.713 7.662 7.615 7.549 7.539 7.441 5.014 5.093 5.045 4.928 4.909 4.858 4.865 4.793 2.582 2.652 2.625 2.693 2,660 2,656 2,649 2,627 IT 46 43 41 46 35 25 21 ■ 12.778 12.775 12.123 12.230 12.521 12.550 12.203 12.190 2.522 2.556 2.550 2.509 2,537 2,523 2,460 2 465 3.308 3.377 2.765 2.781 3.064 3.299 3.106 3 101 1.128 1.17.1 1.249 1.405 1,226 1.252 1,271 1 260 2.158 . 2.068 2,016 2.052 2.141 2,097 2,061 1,987 1.207 1.178 1.168 1.164 1,142 1,147 1,136 1,250 916 896 903 882 nil 975 964 947 I.OOS 1.053 981 979 1.021 807 . 768 768 163 165 165 159 174 169 170 160 1.17 135 152 153 166 135 132 137 231 172 174 146 139 146 135 115 5.820 5.847 .1.839 5.835 5,751 5.728 5.659 5.695 3.155 3.145 3.097 3.092 3.067 3.093 3.061 " 3 078 644 672 656 653 642 638 629 640 976 982 923 981 970 947 927 939 281 281 334 302 275 269 261 266 273 274 303 289 280 287 258 260 175 184 184 183 175 177 181 184 316 329 342 335 342 337 342 328 6.222 7.653 7.288 7.910 7.848 7.222 5.854 4.546 3.719 5.001 4.719 5.359 5.502 4.854 3.576 2 490 1.583 1,629 1.633 1.601 1,389 1.406 1,320 l'll4 920 1.023 930 1.012 957 962 9SB 942 1.337 4.316 4.497 4.581 4.239 4.236 4.154 4,189 1.567 1.542 1.563 1.544 1.199 1.136 1.119 17142 825 848 846 874 894 912 868 855 761 767 729 733 732 785 777 741 1.184 1.159 1,359 1.430 1.414 1.403 1,390 1.451 1.648 1.783 1.524 1.600 1,549 1.494 1.570 1,234 657 808 771 858 771 760 676 515 387 386 368 384 375 357 363 357 492 482 252 247 307 302 471 280 89 88 95 76 76 66 59 73 23 19 38 35 20 I) 1 periods of all types ending within each month. The figures Include estimates of employ - of the estimates would affect the comparability of the monthly data for certain industries. 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Table 12 Amount of Covered Payrolls for Each Month of ihe Calendar Year 1938 Classified by Industry 1938 Average INDUSTRY' Monthly January February March April TOTAL ALL INDUSTRIES $ 11.454.135 11.119.546 11.660.873 11.918.f- TRADE 3.343.293 3.135.486 3.051.430 3.284.477 . 3,367.6 Wholesale Distributors 717.269 680,571 880.679 " 733,339 714. C Wholesale Merchants 847.831 620.909 602.708 633.887 837. t Retail General Merchandise 526.915 468.126 447.682 492.927 538.5 Wholesale and Retail Trade 472.762 449.746 441.460 458.034 465.4 Retail Automotive 280.322 259.703 242.654 268.865 288.J Retail Trade Not Classified 261.437 258,902 250.033 257.731 264,4: Retail Food 254.823 235.839 232.047 267.941 252.11 Retail Apparel 182,134 163,890 154.167 171,753 204,1 li MANUFACTURING 2,815.448 2.599.722 2.621.558 2.581.122 2.767.11 Food Manufacturing 1,741.630 1,609.795 1.643.884 1.502.582 1.656.' Printing and Publishing 391.692 376,903 367,073 393,102 421.* Iron and Steel and Their Products 96.269 94.671 87.872 92.808 91.1 Machinery Other Than Electrical 83.495 79.184 74.891 88.956 87.) Stone. Clay and Glass Products 81.027 61.936 59.799 72.487 79,* Chemicals 77.177 67.080 67.963 71.639 76.! Finished Lumber Products 63.632 52.393 57.280 68.329 63. a Electrical Machinery 44,921 45.820 41.156 45,536 52.1 Apparel, Finished Articles 44.168 35,057 42.398 48.464 45.3 Nonferrous Metals. Products 43.029 41,320 40,821 44.270 48. J Paper and Allied Products 37.192 30.882 33.064 38.551 34., Basic Lumber Products 31.720 29.333 28.413 30.930 30.5 Leather and Its Manufactures 12,725 12.642 11.495 12,473 12j Miscellaneous Manufacturing 66.771 62,706 65.449 70.989 dfil INTERSTATE RAILROADS 2,507.036 2.395.256 2.236.467 2.340.561 2, 263,? 9 UTILITIES 853.615 842,489 813.939 837.160 888 (j Communications 544.256 542.214 516.655 534.282 579," Light. Heat. Power Companies 307,564 299.220 296.022 ' 301,493 307* Other Local Utilities 1,795 1,055 1.262 1.385 22 PERSONAL AND BUSINESS SERVICE 857,340 828.598 802.860 868.487 801 Personal Service 182. 23T 164.705 161.526 189.020 185! Hotels, Camps. Lodging Places 164.774 171.838 169.901 171.866 167J Business Service 122.385 117.445 115.957 120.667 12l! Eating and Drinking Places 112.194 116.204 107.511 112.437 lot. Auto Repair Services 100,193 92.422 87.677 96.159 102i Motion Pictures 84.003 81.762 78.035 88.458 87- i Amusement and Recreation 50.755 46.268 43,567 45,382 49, Employment Agencies. Schools 15.609 16.368 15.489 16.653 14i Repair Services and Miscellaneous 13.218 12.695 12.842 13.358 13 Agricultural and Horticultural Services 11,978 8.891 10.355 14.487 IS FINANCE AND INSURANCE 799,534 779.881 760.476 793.687 782'. Insurance Carriers 466.097 454.959 450.262 457.429 463- Finance Agencies 96.123 96.820 90.016 91.189 92 Real Estate 75.420 69.791 68.860 72.245 7i! Investment Banking and Security 53.660 52.110 52.251 74.257 51- Insurance Agents and Brokers 39.665 35,753 35.102 35.678 3(; Bank and Trust Companies 24,369 30,185 23.260 22.501 22- Miscellaneous Finance Group 44.200 40,263 40,725 40.388 4i. CONSTRUCTION 506.043 326.794 305,131 393.278 4 Of. General Contractors — Other Than Building. . 286.053 139.585 126.721 187.088 19J' General Contractors— Building 127,511 99.054 97.096 114.759 12C Special Trade Contractors 92.479 88.155 81.314 91.431 8i- TRANSPORTATION Other Than Railroads. . 470.520 476.521 463.320 484.770 491- Trucking and Warehousing 133,397 143,612 143.033 148,098 15! Services Allied to Transportation 99.780 103,232 98.565 104.992 9:. Street. City Railways and Bus Lines 91,159 92.167 87.157 93.801 9: Miscellaneous Transportation 146,184 137,510 134,565 137,879 14' MISCELLANEOUS 95.003 69.388 64.365 _ 77.331 »' Non-Metallic Mining and Quarrying 36.943 17.556 14.468 25.015 2' Medical Services and Law Offices 27.849 28.347 28.283 28.648 31 Membership Organizations 20.187 13,359 13.792 14.755 1 Other Social Service AKencles 7,284 8,359 7.780 8,510 , Crude Petroleum and Natural Gas 2.940 1,767 42 403 {■ 1. This distribution Is based on the Social Security Board's classification, March 15. 1937. 2. Covered payrolls is defined as the money waKes payable In pay periods ending In each tm for one or more quarters. The omission of the estimates would affect the comparability of 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">MONTHLY AMOUNT COVERED PAYROLLS' May June July August September October November December ! .820.244 12.317.438 12.5iX&gt; 873 12.441.655 12.483.082 12.687.490 12.282.856 14,260.259 M 82.767 3.313.447 3.339.284 3.163.131 3,282.563 3.318.408 3,200,761 4.474.121 699,932 712.939 . 736.670 702.706 689.801 715.766 671.609 868,306 607.788 630.625 661.836 628.536 633,621 643,862 617,607 852.252 482,372 507.827 482.702 452.766 517.854 505,088 519,081 910.054 447.232 476.461 466,588 456.538 464.266 477.864 459.909 609.110 277.849 284.541 301,787 282,971 277,553 273.715 272.273 333.404 249.970 253.453 263.206 248.818 254.460 256.653 244.371 335,240 233.341 ' 271,082 255,408 237.448 261.992 251.174 237.179 321.577 184.283 176.519 - 171.087 159.348 183,016 194.286 178.732 244,178 .733.428 2.842.341 2.796,232 2,812.060 2.737,876 2.951,014 3,012.292 3,330.021 .703,063 1.767.670 1.725.688 1,754,240 1.645,030 1,894,658 1,957,883 2,038,188 376.971 392.327 393.939 370,217 390,222 383.830 368.222 466.103 88.682 93.379 101.755 101,719 104.305 91.764 87.939 118.605 80.301 82.514 80.354 79.901 85.376 78.833 76.440 107.595 79.582 84.924 88.541 87.223 90.791 85,918 74.240 107.285 72.852 79.596 85.358 78.710 83.746 76.326 74.657 91.209 60.019 66.715 58.391 60.328 63.050 60.646 88.961 63.850 47.928 40.402 44.555 44,031 40.698 44.517 41.929 49.537 41,876 41.434 36.849 48.876 45.974 49.359 51,328 45,138 43.448 43.007 45.251 35,731 38.001 40.688 42.310 52.904 33.616 38.991 34.317 38,508 34,768 36,248 37.635 55,552 30.500 34.326 29,692 31,711 31.424 30,550 30.810 42.297 11.280 11.798 11.864 14.434 15.576 12.391 11.761 13.986 j 83.310 65.258 59,678 68,431 68.915 65,286 68.179 77.774 .368.672 2.475.588 2.647.658 2.707 901 2.736.704 2.796.890 2.598.851 2,516.374 853.306 857.569 876.706 860.525 851.575 852.864 840.784 867.525 549.870 545.927 554.780 545,712 537.496 538.920 532.182 554.058 301,198 309,447 319.682 312.570 312.133 311.912 307.360 312,216 2.238 2.195 2.244 2.243 1.946 2,032 1.262 1.253 858.850 870.242 863.167 835.637 868.363 849.185 828.962 949,438 179.119 189.185 185.946 179.013 191.981 182.759 176.132 201.593 170.684 164.172 149.552 149.085 163.730 165.730 163.539 169,582 119.468 115.991 123.670 119.806 121.119 120.119 124,622 147,880 113.031 111.992 111.605 113.088 112,987 114.848 109.946 118,431 100.275 105.347 106.724 100,120 96.048 94.754 89.713 130.720 79.738 84.587 84.130 76,353 82.281 83.272 87.598 94,511 54.130 59.998 59.872 57,930 56,813 47.582 43,260 44,965 13.622 14.051 14.369 15.803 17.298 17.396 14,983 17.245 11.923 13.003 14.564 14.357 15.968 12,703 11.065 12,972 16.860 11.916 12.735 10,104 10,138 10.024 8,104 11,539 781.985 802.773 824.785 775.374 777.334 777.999 777.524 959.777 462.003 459.383 493.429 460.292 458.891 484*447 453.384 515,177 92.998 108.583 93.797 • 87.915 92.548 87,951 95.812 122.944 74.819 75.801 73.293 73.652 74.165 72.096 74.996 102.493 51.131 52.893 52.112 47.499 45,993 49.025 49.033 88,518 36.331 39.280 41,189 39.470 38.578 36.341 35.408 66.806 22.058 22.382 20.668 23.743 22.531 22.657 22.762 30.988 42.645 44.457 44.297 42.803 44.628 45.482 46.129 54,851 450,915 561.286 584.874 664.701 662.225 607.553 515.569 594.434 243.314 319.105 344.111 419.391 411.328 391,216 320,916 331,466 123.688 145.697 142.425 146,974 148.656 124,981 111.203 154.680 83.913 96.484 98.338 98.336 102.241 91,356 83,450 108,288 473.825 474.902 480.789 _ 504.413 464.606 430.517 420.884 480.792 &#132; 143.131 146.549 150.821 ~ ' 144.043 116,845 79.662 86.659 138,973 - 97.283 97.671 96.735 103.925 104,467 103.085 93.863 95,347 91.729 92.882 86.527 93.311 88.691 93,243 92,212 90.050 141.682 137.800 146.706 163.134 154.603 154.527 148.150 156.422 116.496 119.284 116.378 111.906 101.836 103.060 87.229 87.777 42.364 45,949 45.116 52.322 49.176 51.962 - 35.731 34.655 28.683 27,761 28.315 27.785 25.311 25.709 25.251 27,359 33,454 33.313 28.611 17,251 17.753 18.125 19.451 19.180 7.417 7,858 6.999 6,770 6,156 6.722 6.586 6,583 4.578 4.403 7.337 7.778 3.440 542 210 ._^_. ie figures Include estimates of payrolls of subject employers who failed to report ninthly data for certain industries. 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Table 13 Indexes of Employment in the Food Manufacturing Industries of Nebraska, 1937 and 1938 1 Food Manufacturing Industries Year Meat Dairy Bakery Gr. Mill Canning and Prod- Prod- Prod- Prod- Bev- Beet &amp; Pre- Con fee- Month ucts ucts ucts ucts erases Sugar serving tionery 1937 January ... 104.2 89.5 95.0 96.2 76.2 44.1 78.4 98.3 February .. 98.2 87.0 95.7 92.9 76.7 44.9 81.2 99.0 March 97.0 91.3 97.7 93.3 85.9 46.3 81.2 97.5 April 98.0 97.9 97.8 97.4 103.0 49.6 100.0 93.0 May 100.1 106.0 101.8 101.6 106.7 48.5 136.0 93.0 June 101.7 117.0 102.3 99.0 114.4 49.2 142.7 92.2 July 97.2 111.4 101.6 109.9 126.0 53.6 97.5 86.1 August 100.4 109.7 99.5 105.0 125.0 68.3 156.6 92.2 September . 100.8 105.1 98.8 106.2 120.7 79.7 108.0 101.3 October 101.8 96.8 101.9 103.2 96.8 335.9 81.4 114.3 November .. 103.0 93.7 102.8 100.1 89.0 301.8 77.9 115.8 December .. 97.6 94.5 105.1 95.3 79.8 78.0 59.1 117.3 1938 January ... 102.3 83.4 102.6 92.9 83.1 46.3 68.0 87.6 February .. 92.3 82.4 102.2 89.8 84.8 45.2 63.0 82.3 March 88.5 84.3 103.8 87.0 90.4 49.1 61.3 80.8 April 87.3 98.3 104.6 85.7 92.3 47.9 75.0 77.0 May 89.5 101;. 2 103.4 92.1 92.4 49.5 100.3 75.4 June 93.6 107.4 103.4 93.6 102.1 51.8 97.8 73.1 July 90.8 101.2 99.0 97.1 105.2 58.0 88.6 69.3 August 90.3 99.5 99.3 95.3 99.2 77.2 184.7 79.2 September . 91.4 93.7 100.9 95.1 89.1 92.4 114.4 79.2 October 91.8 89.7 102.5 96.0 86.0 329.9 76.2 79.2 November .. 98.2 89.0 102.6 92.9 81.5 303.5 62.3 78.5 December . 102.2 89.1 100.5 93.5 77.5 146.2 35.0 78.5 '100 equal 1937 average monthly volume of covered employment. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>