<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat</title>
               <date value="1930-06">1930-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 246 T June, 1930 Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat L. K. CROWE Department of Dairy Husbandry EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN ■ W. W. Burb, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 246 the author's experience with their use may be briefly indi - cated as follows : Method I. — Reagents : Glacial Acetic Acid and Hydrochloric Acid (1, 5, 6, 10, 11, 12, 25, 27). 3 Five modifications of a procedure involving the use of these reagents were studied. These included the use of a mixture of these two acids varying from 12 to 15 c.c. to "fill the bottle almost to the neck with a mixture of the acids." When using the modifications as suggested, results on the same sample varied as much as 2.0 per cent of fat. Most of the tests with these reagents contained either curd or charred material in the fat column of the finished test and in many cases this material made the tests practically unreadable. Variations in the length of time heated in the water bath, as well as in amounts of reagents used, failed to give satis - tory results. Method II. — Reagents : Glacial Acetic Acid and Sulf uric Acid (2, 3, 4, 6, 10, 11, 12, 15, 16, 19, 20, 21, 22, 25, .26, 27). The use of these reagents appears to be especially popular, for six - teen modifications involving their use have. been reported. Procedures included almost every conceivable variation in the amounts of the two reagents, in the method of adding reagents, and in the treatment of the sample. This method in all of its modifications failed to give entirely satisfactory results, from the standpoint of either clearness of fat column or accuracy of results. The results were greatly improved in both clearness of fat column and accuracy when 10 c.c. of water at a temperature of 180° F. was added to the i test before centrifuging, altho this practice was not sug - gested in the published procedures. This was one of the methods by which accurate results were obtained with a selected group of samples. The use of these reagents according to recommended pro - cedures gave results within reasonable agreement with the Mojonnier results. The ice cream mix used was composed of sweet cream, . condensed skimmilk, skimmilk, sugar, and gelatin and was calculated to contain 14.0 per cent butterfat, 13.0 per cent sugar, 10.0 per cent milk solids not fat, and 0.25 per cent gelatin. Incorporating what appeared to be the good points of each modification as well as those factors found desirable from experience in using these reagents, the follow - ing standard method of procedure was outlined. 1 Numbers refer to references given at end of bulletin. Each reference explains a method slightly different from any other. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 246 Possibly some of the fat was poured off with the whey, or the curd or charred material below the fat column may have con - tained a small amount of fat. Method IV. — Reagents : Hydrochloric Acid and Sulf uric Acid ; (10). A single method of procedure was suggested in which 15 c.c. of concentrated hydrochloric acid and 8 c.c. of concentrated sulfuric acid were used. The use of the recommended procedure produced results in which there was so much charred material in the fat column that the results were rendered inaccurate. Using less than the prescribed amount of sulfuric acid did not remedy the condition. Method V. — Reagents: Sulfuric Acid with Normal Butyl Alcohol, Amyl Alcohol, or Ethyl Alcohol (95 per cent) (3, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 17, 18, 20, 22, 24). The main variations were in the kind of alcohol used and include the use of normal butyl alcohol with two modifications, the use of amyl alcohol, and the use of ethyl alcohol. ■ When normal butyl alcohol was used the fat column was very clear and satisfactory in appearance, but a comparison of the results with Mojonnier results on eleven samples indi - cated that the normal butyl alcohol results were from 1.1 to 4 1 per cent too high. In only one of the eleven samples were the results lower than the Mojonnier results. The use of amyl alcohol in place of the normal butyl alcohol produced approx - imately the same results with high readings. The use of ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) produced a fat column which in all cases was slightly charred and with re - sults that were usually too high. The addition of water at a temperature of 180" F. before the first centrifuging improved results, altho this procedure was not suggested in the ref - erences. Since the use of these two reagents when testing ice cream of the composition outlined under Method II produced results agreeing favorably with the percentage of fat as obtained with the Mojonnier procedure, a method of procedure was outlined incorporating the good features of the modifications studied as well as those factors found by experience to be desirable. „,•■."« c The method as outlined is as follows: Weigh 9 grams of the well-mixed sample into a 10-per cent, 18-gram Babcock milk test bottle. Add 10 c.c. of ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) and mix the contents of the bottle thoroly. Add 9 c.c. of sulfuric acid (specific gravity 1.825) and again thoroly mix </seg>
            <seg id="p007">* Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat the contents. After a few minutes the color changes to dark brown, or almost black, at which time 10 c.c. of water at a temperature of 180° F. is added and the contents are again mixed. Centrifuge the tests at the regular speed for 5 minutes. Add water at a temperature of 180° F. until the fat is raised to within % to % inch of the base of the neck oi the bottle and mix the contents and centrifuge for 3 minutes. Add water at a temperature of 180° F. until the tat is entirely raised into the neck and centrifuge for 1 minute Measure the fat column as in the Babcock milk test atter the bottles have been in a water bath for 5 minutes at a temperature of 135° to 140° F. The reading is multiplied by_two to give the percentage of fat in the ice cream tested. Kesults by this procedure did not prove accurate with a group of samples of varying composition. Table 2.—Sulfuric acid and ethyl alcohol compared with Mojonnier -ES&amp;I Flavor Mojonnier \_, ' alcohol Mojonnier Per cent Per cent Per cent * Vanilla 12.60 12.85 + .25 2 Van; a 11.32 n.65 + .33 ? Vanilla. 13.39 15.15 +1.76 I Van; a 15.22 15.70 + .48 5 Vanilla 941 9 on 'I 2a 6 Vanilla iSios £]&amp; + j» Method VI.— Reagents: Glacial Acetic Acid, Sulfuric Acid and Nitric Acid (6, 13, 14, 22). In the four variations of the procedure involving the use of these reagents the glacial acetic acid and sulfuric acid were added separately or in combination; the nitric acid was added a few drops at a time or in a mixture with the other acids. ' Many of the tests with these reagents were clear, but bubbles arising thru the fat column interfered with the read - ing to such an extent as to make accurate reading impossible. Method VII. — Reagent: Sulfuric Acid (1, 5, 11, 12, 27). Three variations were found regarding the amount of sulfuric acid to be used and the method of adding the acid. No amount, strength, or method of adding sulfuric acid alone proved satisfactory in producing a fat column that did not contain a large amount of either charred material or un - dissolved curd. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin "246 Method VIII. — Reagents: Sulfuric Acid, Nitric Acid, and Formaldehyde. 4 The procedure consisted in using a 4.5-gram sample to which was added 1 c.c. of concentrated nitric acid and the mixture heated to boiling. To this was added 4 c.c. of sulfuric acid and a small amount of formaldehyde, after which, the fat column was raised into the neck of the bottle with a. mixture of equal parts. of sulfuric acid and water. In the hands of an expert this test might be operated with considerable accuracy, but as conducted by the ordinary operator, the material will probably boil out of the bottle. It has the further disadvantage of liberating nitric acid fumes that are very irritating. Method IX. — Reagents : Sulfuric Acid and Ethyl Ether. 6 A procedure was tried in which ether was added to the sample, followed by the addition of sulfuric acid. This test was found unsatisfactory because of the excessive heat which caused the material to boil out of the bottle when the sulfuric acid was mixed with the ether. DISCUSSION OF RESULTS OBTAINED WHEN USING MODIFIED BABCOCK TEST PROCEDURES In many cases, the outlines of procedure given for the operation of the tests were meagre and lacking in essential details so that it was necessary to make several tests before a definite procedure giving even fairly satisfactory results could be established. All of the above tests were tried follow - ing the exact procedure as reported and were compared with results obtained with the Mojonnier used as a standard. If the test in its original form did not give satisfactory results, modifications were made endeavoring to overcome some ob - jectionable features. The factors considered in judging the merits of a test were in main as follows. First— clearness of fat column. A fat column that contained char (black material), curd (light - colored, undissolved material), or other foreign matter was not considered satisfactory because of the elements of un - certainty involved when reading such a test. Often this foreign material was below the fat column when the test was first removed from the centrifuge, but became incorporated with the fat column when the test was placed in the water bath before reading. Second — consistency and accuracy of results. It was considered that duplicate tests should check with each other to within 0.1 per cent, and that the average of the duplicates should check within 0.2 per cent of the average Mojonnier results. Where the recommended pro - * O. Osborne ml at the time that he suggested this test the chemist for the Colorado State Dairy Commission. Nothing has heretofore been published on it. : 'While studying the literature the author decided, to try these reagents. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Testing Ice Cream for Bu'tterfat cedure required a 9-gram, 50-per cent cream test bottle, the test was either discarded or a 10-per cent, 18-gram mi k test bottle was substituted. Since the smallest graduation on the f2Sf b0tUe f iS °, nly + °-l per . cent this would »&lt;* Permit making fn hf ««t ? ? f 7 aIue l° e } ce cream manufacturer. In ordef sulfs Sth »11 J»™ mV £ alsb^ ve e 1 ually Pliable re, tXSh li • ? am P les .' regardless of composition or flavor. Sente f y f° f P rocedur . e ' and availability of reagents. The first two factors were given the most weight. • DESCRIPTION OF THE NEBRASKA TEST ■■'..;•■ EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURES After these studies were completed without finding a satis factory modification of the Babcock test procedirf efforts %mZ S e £°. devise a test th at would give satisfactor? re! the usTof nilri?^ 1 " T m J&gt; l ? s -. ? had bee " observefthlt the use of normal butyl alcohol with commercial sulfuric acid %n \* W P. roduced . a clear fat column, but the results were ft? h in. Practically all cases. They were not propoS tionately high; hence, a correction facto/could not be Ssed After making more than two thousand tests, using various reagents singly and in combination, the following method of procedure was formulated which oVercame the ob?e C tion to the use of normal butyl alcohol as previously described as a'Sb "iw" W a r« d e&amp;nated Tor convenience as A and B Reagent A is a mixture of normal butyl alcohol ySSrfSfi w m ,° n i ium ?Wd««Me, made up as follows y parts of normal butyl alcohol and 1 part of C. P. (chemicallv &amp;tv e m rrr? h 7 dro ? ide A convenient TuS SS ?Jf y made by . mixln fi: 90 c.c. of normal butyl alcohol and- 10 ac. of ammonium hydroxide. This reajrent s stahlP when kept in a tightly stoppered bottle. Sent B is a mixture of equal parts by volume of sulfuric acid fsWifi8 - grayity 1.82 to 1.83) and ethyl alcohol per cent) This mixture, is prepared by pouring the acid Slowly into the alcohol in a glass beaker or other glass container that wil! withstand high temperature. The mixture will becoml^v tremely hot, and will boil, but no trouble need be experienced" «6 P^™n bef T V? 1 "?- ?; ch 8 ™*tur/ofSw ill" </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 246 , In case ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) can not be procured, specially denatured alcohol (Formula Number 30)" can be substituted and in the work herein reported has given as satisfactory results as ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) . When the mixture of specially denatured alcohol and sulfuric acid be - comes light brown in color, it should be discarded and a new supply made. This brown coloration may occur in two or three days in a warm room. If possible, it would be well to make this mixture fresh as used. OPERATION OF THE TEST Preparation of the sample. — Frozen ice cream should be melted in a closed jar at a temperature below 80° F. to pre - vent melting the fat. The sample of ice cream mix or the melted ice cream should be mixed thoroly by pouring from one vessel to another. Care should be taken not to churn the fat in the sample. It is especially easy to churn the fat in samples of melted ice cream. Fruit or nut ice cream should be strained to remove the coarser pieces of these products. Weighing the sample. — By means of the ordinary Torsion Cream Test Balance, weigh 9 grams of ice cream mix, or melted ice cream, into a 10-per cent, 18-gram milk test bottle. 7 Addition of reagents. — Add 5 c.c. of reagent A. Mix the contents of the bottle thoroly by shaking. Add 30 c.c. of reagent B (cooled to room temperature before using). A small variation in the amount of this reagent apparently does not affect the test. Consequently, if the capacity of the base of the bottle is small, 28 or 29 c.c. may be used to prevent the mixture from rising into the neck of the bottle while heating, which makes it difficult to mix the contents of the bottle. If possible, bottles that will hold the regulation 30 c.c. should be selected and retained for this test. After adding reagent B, again mix the contents of the bottle thoroly by shaking and continue mixing until the curd is all dissolved. The contents of the bottle should become clear and free from curd, but will not become dark until heated in the water bath. "Appendix to Regu'ations No. 3 (formerly 61) of the Treasury Department, Bureau of Prohibition, entitled "Formulae for Completely and Specially Denatured Alcohol," revised February, 1928, gives the following directions for Formula No. 30. "To every 100 gallons of ethyl alcohol, add ten callons of pure methy' alcohol of specific ' gravity of not more than 0.810 at 60° F. The denatured alcohol may be recovered for reuse, provided such recovery is accomplished by simple distillation without the use of oxidizing agents ; for example, the common laboratory practice of removing ' by dis - tillation over caustic soda. "Authorized for use in artificial musks; celluloid cement; chemical and physical laboratory purposes : dental gold : digestive ferments and similar glandular "products (provided they contain no alcohol) ; fur dyeing ; hypodermic tablets : oleo resins : photo dry plates ; mercurochrome : vacuum tubes ; manufacturing vegetable oils : varnish and white petroleum oils (conditional) ; mirrors." This alcohol was obtained from the American Alcohol Corporation at Pekin, Illinois. after obtaining a permit from the Prohibition Administrator at Topeka, Kansas. "■ A milk test bottle with a large capacity below the neck is best adapted for this test. The test bottles we have used have been obtained from the Louis F. Nafis Cnm - pany of Chicago. ■ - </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat Heating the tests. — Place the tests in a water bath at a temperature between 175° and 180° F. and heat for 15 minutes. Shake the contents of the bottles at least three times during this heating period. Centrifuging and adding water. — Remove from water bath and centrifuge at the regular speed for 5 minutes. Shake contents of bottle thoroly. If the fat column is not up to the neck of the bottle, add water, at a temperature of not less than 180° F., until the fat column is raised to within about 14 inch of the base of the neck. Centrifuge at the regular speed for three minutes. If any curd is apparent in the mixture at this time, shake the contents of the bottle thoroly. Add water at 180° F. until the fat column is raised so that its extremities will be between the 0 and 10 per cent gradua - tions on the neck of the bottle. Centrifuge at the regular speed for 1 minute. Reading the tests. — Remove from centrifuge and place bottles m a water bath for 5 minutes at a temperature of 135° to 140° F. Add glymol and read the percentage of fat with dividers as in a Babcock cream test. (Measure from bottom of lower meniscus to line between glymol and fat.) Multiply reading by two, to obtain the true percentage of fat in the ice cream sample, since only a 9-gram sample was used in an 18-gram bottle. Duplicate tests should always be made and the reading of these duplicates should check to within 0.1 per cent of each other, making a maximum variation of 0.2 per cent when the reading is doubled. The fat column in the finished tests should be clear and golden yellow in color. A small amount of fluffy brown precipitate may occur below the fat column when testing samples of fruit ice cream. This precipitate has not mixed with the fat in our studies suffic - iently to hinder reading the percentage of fat. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS Table 3 gives results obtained in testing ice cream samples by the above procedure. These samples were collected from different manufacturers in Nebraska and neighboring states and represent a wide range in percentage of fat, percentage of solids, and type of stabilizer. This table also shows a com - parison between the use of ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) and specially denatured alcohol, Formula Number 30, as compared to the Mojonnier results. Each result given is an average of at least two tests. All modified tests were made in a standard 24-bottle steam centrifuge. </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 246 Table 3. — (Concluded) Modified Babcock testa for butterfat Specially denatured Sample Mojonnier Ethyl alcohol (95%) alcohol, Formula No. 30 number Flavor test for . — — butterfat Variation Variation Test from Test from Mojonnier Mojonnier ".At. percent At. per cent Percent At. per cent Percent 129 Strawberry 13 .36 13.4 ' +.05 130 Strawberry 12.55 ..... 12.6 +.05 181 Strawberry 13.81 14.0 +.19 132 Vanilla 14.58 .... 14.7 +.12 133 Vanilla 14.43 14.5 +.07 134 Vanilla 12.76 .... ..... 12 Si +.04 135 Vanilla 13.72 .... 13.7 —.02 136 Strawberry 11.99 12.1 +.11 137 Strawberry 12.53 .... . 12.7 +.17 138 Vanilla 13.87 .... • 14.1 +.23 139 Vanilla.: 13.39 13.1 — .29 140 Strawberry 13.10 .... 13.0 — .10 141 Vanilla 14.40 14.5 +.10 142 Strawberry 12.45 • 12.6 +.15 143 Vanilla 14.28 .... 14.3 +.02 144 Strawberry 12.60 .... 12.5 —.10 'Figure given is an average of at least duplicate and sometimes triplicate tests. 'Blank spaces left in the denatured alcohol results column indicate that the sample was lost before this substitution waa made. 'Indicates results that were obtained with the regular procedure, except that the tests were heated 20 minutes at 180° F. before centrifuging, rather than 15 minutes. This represented the regular procedure prior to the procedure reported in this bulletin. These samples were lost due to souring, churning, or breaking of sample jar before the length of heating period was short - ened. A comparison of results obtained by the 15 and 20 minute heating period, however . showed no variation. The shorter period is advisable because of the time saved. SUMMARY OF RESULTS A. When reagent B was composed of ethyl alcohol (95 per cent) and sulfuric acid. The tabulation below represents results with a total of 101 samples of ice cream of which 50 were vanilla, 29 chocolate, 18 strawberry, and 4 other flavors. 16 samples or 15.84 per cent were 0.01 to 0.1% higher than the Mojonnier 27 samples or 26.73 per cent were 0.01 to 0.1% lower than the Mojonnier 45 samples or 44.65 per cent checked within ±0.1% of the Mojonnier 16 samples or 16.84 per cent were 0.11 to 0.2% higher than the Mojonnier 19 samples or 18.81 per cent were 0.11 to 0.2% lower than the Mojonnier 80 samples or 79.20 per cent checked within ±0.2% of the Mojonnier 9 samples or 8.91 per cent were 0.21 to 0.3% higher than the Mojonnier 7 samples or 6.93 per cent were 0.21 to 0.3% lower than the Mojonnier 96 samples or 95.04 per cent checked within ±0.3% of the Mojonnier 3 samples or 2.97 per cent were 0.31 to 0.4% higher than the Mojonnter 1 sample or .99 per cent was 0.31 to 0.4% lower than the Mojonnier 100 samples or 99.00 per cent checked within ±0.4% of the Mojonnier. The average variation of these results from the per - centage of fat as determined by the Mojonnier procedure was ±0.1337 percent. - j. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat B. When reagent B was composed of specially denatured alcohol (Formula No. 30) and sulfuric acid. The tabulation below represents results with a total of 119 ice cream samples of which 65 were vanilla, 21 chocolate, 27 strawberry, and 6 other flavors. 35 samples or 29.41 per cent were 0.01 to 0.1% hiither than the Mojonnler 35 samples or 29.41 per cent were 0.01 to 0.1% lower than the Mojonnier TO samples or 58.82 per cent checked within ±0.1% of the Mojonnier IT samples or 14.28 per cent were 0.11 to 0.2% higher than the Mojonnier 11 samples or 9.32 per cent were 0.11 to 0.2% lower than the Mojonnier 98 samples or 82.35 per cent checked within ±0.2% of the Mojonnier 5 samples or 4.20 per cent were 0.21 to 0.3% higher than the Mojonnier 13 samples or 10.92 per cent were. 0.21 to 0.3% lower thnn the Mojonnier 116 samples or 97.48 per cent checked within ±0.8% of the Mojonnier 1 sample or .84 per cent was 0.31 to 0.4% higher -than -the 'Mojonnier 2 samples or 1.68 per cent were 0.31 to 0.4% lower than the Mojonnier 119 samples or 100.00 per cent checked within ±0.4% of the Mojonnier The average variation of these results from the per - centage of fat as determined by the Mojonnier procedure was ±0.1093 per cent. Critical studies, trials, and comparisons involving proposed modified Babcock procedures for estimating butterfat in ice cream have indicated that none of the procedures thus far proposed is reliable and satisfactory for all types and flavors of ice cream, when using the approved Mojonnier method as a basis of comparison. A new modified Babcock procedure is herewith proposed whereby the percentage of butterfat in ice cream may be de - termined with a degree of accuracy and reliability that should be satisfactory for almost any commercial purpose. The method is convenient, simple, inexpensive, and applicable to ice cream of all types and flavors. The test is not presented as a replacement of ether extrac - tion methods, but only as a procedure to be used where such methods are not available, or as a test preliminary to such procedure. LITERATURE CITED 1. Baer, A. C. Ice Cream Making:. Univ. of Wisconsin, Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 262, February, 1916. Reprinted June, 1925. 2. . Inquiry Department. Ice Cream Rev., Vol. 3, No. 11, June, 1920. 3. . Preparation and Processing of Ice Cream Mix. Olsen Publishing Co., 1927. 4. Benkendorf, G. H. Simple Method of Determining the Solids in Ice Cream. Ice Cream Rev., Vol. 2, No. 11, June, 1919. 5. . The Babcock Test for Fat in Ice Cream. Ice Cream Trade Jour., Vol. XIII, No. 5, May, 1917. 6. Burke, A. D. Practical Dairy Tests. Olsen Publishing Co., 1926. 7. . Inquiry Department, Milk Denier. Vol. 16, No. 6, March, 1927. 8. De Pew, H. F. Ice Cream Industry Development. Chicago Dairy Prod., April 5, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 246 9. Fisher, R. C, and Walts, C. C. A Comparative Study of Methods for Determining the Percentage of Butterfat in Dairy Products. Jour. Dairy Sci., VoL VIII, No. 1, 1925. 10. . A Comparative Study for Determining the Percentage . of Fat in Dairy Products. Storrs Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 131, August, 1925. 11. — . Report presented at National Dairy Science Association Meeting, Detroit, 1926. 12. Fisk, Walter W. The Book of Ice Cream. The Macmillan Co., 1923. 13. Francis, C. K., and Morgan, D. G. Determination of Fat in Certain Milk Products. Oklahoma A. &amp; M. College, Tech. Bui. 114, April, 1917. 14. —. . The Determination of Fat in Certain Milk Products. Jour. Indus, and Engin. Chem., Vol. DC, No. 9, September, 1917. 15. Friedman; W. G. Testing Samples of Ice Cream. Ice Cream Trade Jour., Vol. 17, No. 7, July, 1921. 16. Lichtenberg, H. F. Jour. Indus, and Engin. Chem., Vol. 5, No. 9, 1913. 17. Moore, H. C, and Morse, P. A. A Babcock-Gerber Method for De - termining the Percentage of Fat in Ice Cream. Jour. Dairy Sci., Vol. 9, No. 3, 1926. 18. , and Ball, G. L Practical Methods of Sampling and Test - ing Milk, Cream, and Ice Cream. New Jersey Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 186, February, 1926. 19. Nans, Louis F. Chicago Scientific Glassware Catalogue. Copy - right, 1928. 20. Newlander, J. A. Testing Dairy Products. Olsen Publishing Co., 1926. 21. Olson. Determination Of Fat in Ice Cream by the Babcock Method. Ice Cream Rev., July, 1919. 22. Reuhe, H. E. Questions and Answers Department, Creamery and Milk Plant Monthly, March, 1928. 23. Rudmick, A. W. Ice Cream as Found in Various Markets in the State of Iowa. Thesis on file at Iowa State College Library, 1910. 24. Sproule, W. H., and Clark, H. P. Ontario Department of Agricul - ture, Ontario Agr. College Bui. 336, May, 1928. 25. Turnbow, Grover D., and Raffetto, Lloyd A. Ice Cream. John Wiley &amp; Sons. 26. Utt, C. A. Jour. Indus, and Engin. Chem., Vol. 7, No. 9, 1915. 27. Van Slyke, Lucius L. Modern Methods of Testing Milk and Milk Products. Orange Judd Company, 1917 and 1927. E5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>