<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products</title>
               <date value="1923-11">1923-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">UNIVIMITY or NEUAio ntH </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products H. C. FILLEY RELATIVE PRICE OF FARM PRODUCTS AND ALL COMMODITIES, 1840-1**1 The prices of farm products have risen very rapidly during* war periods, but have fallen more previpitousJy after a war ended than have the prices of other commodities THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Supply and demand * Cast of production * Market strategy • Monopoly 8 Money 8 Credit 11 Transportation '- 12 Commercial costs IS Import duties 14 Other force. 15 Potato acreage, production and price.. 16 Wheat production and price 18 Corn production and price SI Oats production and price 24 Time of sale of wheat, oats, and corn 24 Price of wheat and time of marketing 28 Price of oats and time of marketing 31 Price of corn and time of marketing 31 World supply and world demand 34 Hog receipts and prices — corn production and prices 35 The application 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products H. C. FILLEY' NEARLY everyone who lives in Nebraska is interested either directly or indirectly in the price which the farmer receives for his products. The farmer and his family are Eested because their purchases are necessarily limited by income. As a matter of course the farmer is also in - ted in the price of the goods that he buys, because the amount of his purchases necessarily depends upon the rela - tionship existing between the price of what he sells and the price of what he buys. If this relationship is satisfactory, that is, if the price of what he sells is relatively high com - pared with the price of what he buys, we say that the farmer is prosperous. Under such conditions he is able to purchase not only the necessities of life but many comforts and possibly some luxuries. Nearly everyone else is interested indirectly, because agri - culture is our greatest source of wealth. If the farmer pro - duces an abundance of corn, wheat, hogs, eggs, butterfat, and other commodities and sells them for a favorable price as compared with the price of goods that he purchases, he will be able to buy more goods of the merchants than if he had but little to sell or exchange values were unfavorable to him. Instead of buying only meager necessities he will be able to buy more and better clothing, invest in new farm equip - ment, and perhaps enlarge or modernize his home, thus furnishing labor to carpenters, plumbers, and other me - chanics. The dollars which come to the farmer in exchange for his products are therefore important not only to him but to many others. In the typical Nebraska community prac - tically everyone — merchant, mechanic, banker, doctor, lawyer, preacher, and teacher — is dependent for his or her income upon the purchasing power of our farm products. It is, therefore, not surprising that not only farmers but many men in other occupations follow crop reports and market quotations, and base their plans upon the probable buying power of the farmer. In estimating this buying power the 'Valued assistance in preparing the graphs and tables used in this bulletin was re - ceived from E. A. Frerichs, Charlotte Hickman, Harold Hedges, and Francis Flood. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 general public follows more closely the price of products sold by the farmer than the price of the commodities that he buys, altho the price of the products sold is relatively no more important. Various explanations have been offered as to why the prices of farm products go up and down, and the power to determine prices has been ascribed to various forces. Very often price changes are attributed to a single force, but accumulated evidence seems to indicate that they are usually the result of a combination of forces. The more important of these forces are supply and demand, cost of production, market strategy, monopoly, the quantity of money in circu - lation and the rapidity with which it circulates, credit, trans - portation costs, commercial costs, and import duties. In this bulletin a brief discussion of each of these forces will be given, following which data will be presented showing how the forces actually have influenced prices in recent years. SUPPLY AND DEMAND Under competitive conditions, the forces which have the greatest influence in determining the price of any product at any given time and place are supply and demand. The supply of a thing as used in the phrase "supply and demand" is the quantity that will be offered for sale at a given price ; the demand is the quantity that will be bought at a given price. If the price of a commodity is lowered, more is pur - iised; if the price is raised, less will be purchased. Sellers, they wish buyers to take more of a commodity, must luce the price; if they raise the price, they will sell less. : us suppose for example that in some locality strawberries : produced in unusual abundance. At the ordinary price ; all the crop can be sold, for strawberries are very perish - e and cannot be held for a higher market. The producers 1, therefore, lower the price, which will increase the quan - tity taken, because when strawberries are cheap nearly every - one will buy them in abundance, not only for immediate use but for canning or preserving. On the other hand, if straw - berries are a short crop, the sellers will raise the price to a point where the demand is just sufficient to move them. If the demand for a product at a given price is increased, as, for example, the demand for pork was increased during the war, the price rises, until some persons necessarily de - crease their consumption, and demand and supply meet at a new and higher level ; on the other hand, if there is a fall- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">§off in demand, as always happens during a period of ness depression, sellers must either lower prices or put on the market. Not only do the quantity supplied and the quantity de - manded influence price, but price influences the quantity sup - plied and demanded. When the price of a product is relatively high, producers increase the supply, until because of this increase the price necessarily drops. For example, hogs were relatively high in 1921 compared with other farm products, and nearly all Corn Belt farmers were anxious to produce more hogs. The increased number of hogs has caused prices to drop so that now (1923) they are relatively low. This low price will cause many farmers to decrease hog production. A decrease in the number of hogs will logically be followed by an increase in price. As a matter of course, demand is influenced by various factors. In Nebraska, the demand for lemons is greater in July than in January and the demand for heavy clothing is greater in December than in June. A rain storm increases the demand for rain coats and rubbers. An increase in general prosperity is always accompanied by a demand for more and better goods, but demand decreases during a period of depression. Advertising is one of the most common means employed for increasing the demand for some particular com - modity. The California citrus growers, for example, have increased the demand for oranges by well planned and well executed advertising campaigns. Advertising such staple products as- wheat and corn would, however, have little effect upon the total consumption of food. If we ate more corn we would doubtless decrease our consumption of wheat or po - tatoes. The manufacturer of a given brand of flour may increase the demand for his flour by advertising but the de - mand for some other brand or brands of flour is decreased by a like amount. The producers of such staples as corn, wheat, and oats are therefore much less interested in adver - tising their products than are the producers of such agricul - tural specialties as oranges, soft shelled walnuts, prunes and raisins. COST OF PRODUCTION The cost of producing any commodity influences price in the long run because no one will continue to produce goods to be sold for less than it costs to produce them, while if the price is well above production costs, other men will be induced </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 to enter that particular field, and production will increase until the goods must be sold for lower prices if all are to be consumed. Cost of production has little if any effect on the price which may be obtained for perishable farm products at any particular time. For example, the 1922 potato crop was so large that few Nebraska growers secured cost of production. If they sold, it had to be at the price set by supply and de - mand. One effect of this low price was to reduce the 1923 po - tato acreage, so that unless the yield per acre is exceptionally high the producers may expect to secure at least their cost of production. If the potato yield in certain sections of the country should be very poor, due to drought, or floods, or other causes, the growers in more favored localities will doubtless secure much more than production costs, because of the decreased supply. Any great improvement in methods of production natur - ally results in lower prices just as soon as it is generally adopted. The men who adopt such methods first are the ones who profit most. Production is increased under the new meth - ods and the price falls until, generally speaking, over a period of years it is just about equal to cost of production. Improved farm machinery, for example, has greatly increased the amount of grain which one man can produce, and prices are therefore lower than would be possible under the old weari - some hand methods. MARKET STRATEGY There are almost always forces at work which seek to fix a somewhat different price than would be established by supply and demand under conditions of absolutely free com - petition. For example, Chicago market reports for March 27, 1922, said that the wheat market had advanced from 1% to 2% cents because of reports stating that "the wheat in several Kansas counties is damaged and not coming up well. Reports of damage by green bugs in Oklahoma and elsewhere were also of considerable effect in turning wheat traders on the bull side of the market during the last part of the day." Two days later wheat prices closed % to 1% cents lower and a market report stated: "Down turns in the price of wheat came chiefly near the end of the day and after a former president of the Kansas State Board of Agriculture was </seg>
            <seg id="p008">quoted aa saying the Kansas wheat crop was entering the growing season with a prospect of a greater production than at any time in the history of the state." Doubtless someone profited because of these price changes, and as a matter of course someone else lost. The green bug did little damage that season. Probably the better known examples of market strategy are the Hutchinson wheat corner of 1888, and the attempted Leiter corner of 1898. Because of the bad effects of such market manipulation, the Chicago Board of Trade has had rules in effect since about 1910 which make the cornering of any commodity upon that market practically impossible. A close scrutiny is also maintained over all reports issued by members of the Board of Trade and others who have the privilege of the floor, and rules concerning the issuing of false reports or rumors are strictly enforced. It has been, as a matter of course, impossible for the grain exchanges to control the issuing of reports by men not in any way con - nected with these organizations. The activities of the Federal Government in collecting and disseminating information con - cerning weather, crops, and markets have also been a handi - cap to certain types of market strategy. The Capper-Tincher law, which has recently (1923) be - come effective, renders even more difficult the manipulation of grain prices. It forbids the dissemination of false or knowingly inaccurate reports on crops or market informa - tion, and also forbids the manipulation of prices or cornering. During the war the Federal Government urged a reduction in the consumption of meat. Since the end of the war the campaign against meat eating has been continued by persons interested in the sale of meat substitutes. This propaganda has doubtless resulted in a permanent change in the food consumption of millions of people. Nearly everyone can recall the use of "market strategy" which has influenced the price of stock at farm sales, or the prices paid by local buyers, or even the terms of a horse trade. It enters constantly into price making, and affects the price of farm products sold locally or irregularly or of manufactured goods sold at retail much more than it does the price of farm products sold by grade in an established market. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 MONOPOLY Monopoly has been defined as "that substantial unity of action on the part of one or more persons engaged in some kind of business which gives exclusive control, more par - ticularly altho not solely, with respect to price." The owner of a copyright has a complete monopoly, since he has control of the price at which material copyrighted is sold. He can fix this price because he controls the supply. As a matter of course if he sets the price too high the sales will be so few that his total profits will be small. On the other hand, he might set the price so low that altho the sales were large the total net profit would be small. He would, therefore, prob - ably set the price at the point somewhere between these two that he believed would give him the greatest net profit. The effect of monopoly upon price is really a supply and demand effect, since the monopolist can fix the price because he controls the supply. Partial monopolies which give control over a considerable portion of the supply, but not over a sufficient portion to give domination, are more common than complete monopolies. Even the copyrighted book must meet the competition of other books published upon the same subject. Nebraska pioneers tell us of an almost complete monopoly among grain buyers a generation ago. The farmers coopera - tive elevator has made such a monopoly impossible today. Even tho there may be but a single buyer in a town, or several buyers working under a definite price agreement, they cannot set prices as definitely as was possible 25 years ago. There is the competition of the elevator in the near-by town, and the ever existing potential competition of the possibility of a farmer owned elevator being built if the grain growers feel that they are not receiving a fair price. There is no question but that monopolies, both complete and partial, have an important influence upon prices, but their influence is much greater on commodities purchased by the farmer than on the products that he sells. MONEY An increase in the amount of money in circulation causes the general price level to rise, while a decrease causes it to fall. In other words, as the supply of money increases the demand for it decreases, and a greater amount of it is re - quired in exchange for other commodities. Without making </seg>
            <seg id="p010">K exhaustive explanation it may be stated that "the value noney, under the simplest conditions, is exactly inverse to quantity." x If the quantity of money in circulation is bled, other conditions remaining the same, prices will be twice as high as before and the value of money will be one - half. It should be remembered that conditions are far from simple and are constantly changing. Changes in the amount of money in circulation have so far been accompanied more or less closely by changes in other forces affecting prices. The following table gives the per capita circulation of money in the United States at different periods from 1800 to 1923: Table 1. — Circulation of money * per capita, July 1 'Taussig: Principles of Economics, Vol. 1, p. 28S 'Include* money held by Federal Reserve Banks. The small amount of money in circulation in the early days of the Republic accounts in part at least for the very low prices of that period or perhaps we should say the large amount of money in circulation today is one reason for the relatively high price level. The price of nearly all com - modities rose during and following the World War, not only because there was a great demand in proportion to the supply, but because the amount of money in circulation increased nearly 67 per cent from July 1, 1914, to July 1, 1920. The most rapid increase in circulating medium came after our entry into the war, and each noticeable increase was followed closely by a rise in the general commodity price level. The close relationship between the two is shown in the following table: Year Dollars 1800 $ 4.99 1840 10.91 1861 13.98 1865 20.58 1877 15.32 1890 22.82 1900 26.93 1910 34.33 1914 34.35 Year 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 1920 1921 1922 1923 55.14 57.35 54.11 49.17 53.31 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 HiArfc-KIMkNT oTATION, £&gt;l LLtilN life Table 2. — Per capita circulation of money and the price index: » 191 U to 1920 Money in Bureau of Labor circulation all commodities per capita- price index July 1, 1914 $34.53 99 July 1, 1915 35.59 99 Dec 1, 1915 38.04 105 Dec. 1, 1916 41.73 146 M June 1, 1917 45.49 181 Jan. 1, 1918 48.76 185 Apr. 1, 1918 49.70 190 Sept. 1, 1918 52.95 207 Dec. 1, 1918 56.23 206 Jan. 1, 1919 55.76 203 Feb. 1, 1919 53.58 197 Apr. 1, 1919 54.56 203 Dec. 1, 1919 55.65 238 Jan. 1, 1920 55.89 248 May 1, 1920 56.44 272 Nov. 1, 1920 59.77 207 Dec. 1, 1921 52.19 150 June 1, 1922 48.78 150 June 1, 1923 _ 52.81 153 'Changes in price levels, that is, in the purchasing power of money, are indicated statistically by the use of index numbers. The average price of a considerable number of commodities during some one rear or for a term of years is taken as a base and is always given the value of 100. If the purchasing power of money de- creases, that is, if the prices go up, the index number will rise above 100, b prices go down the index number will fall below 100. The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Dpartment of Labor undoubtedly assembling more information upon prices than any other uriranization in the United States. Its "all commodities" price index is at present (192S) based on the wholesale price of 404 commodities. In all index numbers used in this bul- letin, average wholesale prices for 1913 are used as a base and given the value of 100. For example, when the price index stood at 272 on May 1, 1920. (see Table 2 the average wholesale prices of commodities averaged 2.72 times the average pr of these same commodities* in 1913 'Includes money held by Federal Reserve Banks During the first year of the World War there was no inflation of our currency, and prices of most commodities re- mained at approximately the pre-war level. As the amount of money in circulation was increased during the later months of 1915, prices rose. This increase in circulating medium, followed by a price increase, continued thruout 1916 and 1917. After the signing of the Armistice, the money in circulation decreased and prices dropped. The inflation of the currency began again early in 1919 and continued until in November, 1920, the per capita circulation was $59.77. The high point in prices came in the spring of 1920, the price index for May 1, being 272. Demand decreased, business con- fidence lessened, and credit was restricted. As a result prices dropped, even tho the amount of money in circulation con- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 11 tinued to increase for about 6 months. In fact one of the purposes of the Federal Reserve System is to provide funds for just such emergencies as occurred in the last half of 1920. The rapidity with which money circulates is also a factor affecting prices. This is because it is the money which is expended that creates the demand for goods. If everyone spends money as quickly as possible after it comes into his possession, as there was a tendency to do in the inflation period following the war, the price of commodities will in - evitably rise. Doubling the work that a dollar does is just as effective as doubling the number of dollars. Decreasing the work done by dollars, that is, keeping them out of circu - lation by being slow to make purchases, lowers prices as does a decrease in the actual number of dollars. CREDIT The immediate effect of credit sales on prices is the same as cash sales, because credit sales constitute a demand for goods. This effect is counterbalanced when the debts in - curred by the purchase of goods are paid, because the money is then used in payment of a past demand instead of being used to satisfy a present demand. It will thus be seen that a very general granting of credit, such as we find in a period of business expansion, tends to raise prices. In 1919 not only could almost anyone get credit, but apparently almost everyone did get credit. Business boomed and prices rose. We were spending the earnings of the future. When creditors began demanding payment there was a sharp decrease in the demand for goods. The money which was being used in payment for debts contracted months before could not be used for new purchases. This necessity for cancelling credit obligations was therefore one of the causes contributing to the price decline which began in the summer of 1920. When credit instruments are used in place of money, as when we make payment by check, the effect is the same as increasing the volume of money. Unquestionably the increase of deposit banking and the extensive use of the bank check, which decreases the amount of money which most people carry, has had an effect on prices. The use of Liberty Bonds in payment for land and other purchases contributed to the post-war boom. We used them as money and therefore the effect was the same as if the volume of money had been in - creased. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">TRANSPORTATION Transportation charges ordinarily increase the margin be - tween the price received by the producer and that paid by the consumer by the amount of the charge- It is, therefore, ob - vious that an increase in transportation costs either decreases the price paid to the producer or increases the price paid by the consumer, or possibly the increased cost is divided be - tween producer and consumer. The increase in freight rates is one reason why farm machinery is so much higher today than in pre-war years. * sight adds very materially to the cost of such raw material iron, coal, and wood and thus increases the cost of the manufactured product. Whether farm machinery is sold f. o. b. factory, as is the prevailing custom, or f. o. b. destina - tion, the freight charge is really paid by the retailer and becomes part of his cost and therefore increases his selling price. Freight is an important item not only in the price of farm machinery, but in the price we pay for many other important articles. Transportation costs have an even greater effect upon the price of most agricultural products than upon the price of manufactured goods, because of their greater bulk in propor - tion to their value. An increase of 5 cents a pound in trans - porting a suit of clothes would increase the cost very little, but an increase of one-half cent a pound in transporting hay to market would add $10 per ton to the difference between the price received by the producer for his hay and that paid by the consumer. In many instances this would prove pro - hibitive. The price paid for wheat at a country elevator is ordinarily the terminal market price less freight and other handling charges. As we go westward across Nebraska a decrease in the wheat price may be noted which corresponds quite closely to the increase in freight charges to Omaha and Kansas City. The price in Omaha is usually lower than the price in Chicago by the cost of freight and handling between these cities, and the Chicago price is in turn lower than the Liverpool price, where our wheat sells in competition with wheat from Can - ada, Argentina, and Australia. The price of surplus farm products decreases as the distance from market increases. This price variation corresponds to the cost of freight and handling charges. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Local demand for wheat for milling or for seed may raise the price above the terminal market price. This is because freight and handling charges must be added to the price of wheat brought in from outside to sell in a wheat deficient area. The price of the home grown product naturally rises to the same level. The increase in freight rates has increased the spread between the price paid locally for many products in Nebraska and the price at the terminal markets. This brings to us the question of modifying our agriculture so that we may either reach markets closer home or ship to the more distant markets those products, such as butter and eggs, which have a relatively high value per pound. COMMERCIAL COSTS Trade costs, such as commission or brokerage, inspection, weighing, insurance, yardage, and feeding costs, affect the price of*farm products much as do transportation charges. They increase the spread between the price received by the producer and that paid by the consumer. In all organized markets such charges are uniform and regulated by rule. The elevator which ships 200 carloads of wheat to a commis - sion firm in Omaha (or any other large market) pays the same selling costs per bushel as the man who ships but a single carload. Altho such charges are a relatively small percentage of the selling price, they do constitute a very definite charge which must be paid. The general public is interested not only in the service being performed for the shipper more economically than he could perform it for himself, but in its being performed with the utmost efficiency. A grain exchange which handles no small part of the grain produced in Nebraska has recently put into effect a rule requiring that all grain sold on the exchange must be weighed in elevators at that terminal market. A "shipper's weight" rule was formerly in force. As a result of this new rule every bushel of grain which passes thru this market will pay an additional charge of one-half cent. Perhaps the ser - vice is worth the cost; if not, it unnecessarily reduces the net price received by the producer for his grain. Farmers' cooperative commission companies are already operating in several of the more important livestock markets. The Capper-Tincher law provides that the representatives of cooperative companies shall be admitted to grain exchanges </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 on the same basis as other applicants, except that as members they may distribute their earnings to their patrons. Since these cooperative firms are owned by the producers them - selves, they should furnish a very satisfactory index as to the efficiency of the service now being rendered. IMPORT DUTIES Emport duties do not affect the price of those products of :h we have an exportable surplus. A tariff on wheat, for example, cannot increase the price of wheat which we export and sell in the world market in competition with the wheat grown in Canada, Argentina, and other countries. A general tariff on wheat probably increases the price paid for certain grades of wheat which are particularly desirable for milling and which we do not produce in quantity sufficient for our own needs. No. 1 Northern spring wheat when scarce commands a premium over other wheats because millers wish it to mix with the softer wheats in making a very high grade of flour. A tariff on wheat might therefore benefit growers of this particular type of wheat and not benefit other growers. Corn, hogs, and cotton are other crops little affected by a tariff because we ordinarily produce an ample supply for our own needs. A tariff on those agricultural products of which we do not have an exportable surplus tends to increase the price paid to the producers. Other conditions remaining the same, wool is undoubtedly higher in price and wool producers more prosperous when there is a tariff on wool than when it is admitted free. Among other farm products the price of which has been influenced by an import duty may be mentioned lemons, raisins, olives, and soft-shelled walnuts. With the single exception of sugar beets the price of the most important farm products of Nebraska, including corn, wheat, oats, cattle, hogs, butter, poultry, and eggs, is ordi - narily influenced but little if any by a tariff. It is true that each of these commodities is imported into the United States to some extent, but the total exports ordi - narily exceed the total imports. So far as Nebraska farmers are concerned the direct effect of a tariff upon their products, sugar excepted, is therefore almost negligible. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 15 OTHER FORCES Other forces which are sometimes mentioned as affecting the price of farm products include speculation, foreign ex - change, and general business conditions. These are all really a part of the forces already discussed and further explanation is not warranted in this brief bulletin. In the remainder of the bulletin, graphs and tables are presented showing the price trends of some of our most important farm products. The explanation of these price changes is not intended to be exhaustive, but merely to assist the reader to see what price fluctuations are due to the price - making forces already discussed. POTATO ACREAGE, PRODUCTION, AND PRICE The annual production of potatoes and the December 1 farm price for the years 1866 to 1922 inclusive are given in Figure 1. The figures used were taken from the Yearbook of the United States Department of Agriculture. In Figure 2 (page 17) the price per month is given for the years 1911 to 1922 inclusive. The acreage and production for each given year are indicated at the end of that year; for example, the vertical line separating the 1911 price quo - tations from the 1912 quotations is used as the base to give the potato production and acreage for 1911. As a matter of course the new crop affects the price several months before the end of the year. The figures indicate clearly the part played by supply and demand in setting the price upon potatoes. Whenever the production is high, the price falls, and when the production is low the price rises. It is also noticeable that the acreage always tends to increase after a year or two of good prices. Doubtless the increase in acreage is actually greater than that given by the Yearbook because if potato prices are high many thousands of village and city gardens will contain a few rows of potatoes which do not enter into the department figures. The lowest prices of course occur in years when the acreage is large and the yield per acre high. The price of potatoes is depressed more by high yields than are the prices of other commodities. One reason is that they are perishable, and can be carried in storage for only a lim - ited time. Old potatoes have little value after new potatoes at a reasonable price come on the market. Another reason is that the demand for potatoes is less elastic than the demand </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 for most fruits and many vegetables that are of an even more perishable nature. Most people will eat about the same amount of potatoes whether they are 50 cents a bushel or 3 times that amount. Let strawberries, peaches, or apples fall to one-half the regular price and the consumption will probably be doubled. I Figure 2 shows the effect of the war upon potato prices, i short crop of 1916 caused prices to rise very high in spring and early summer of 1917. The 1917 acreage and duction were the largest on record up to that time but price remained well above the pre-war level. A decrease production in 1918-1919 was naturally followed by very h prices in the early part of 1920, and a slight increase he acreage planted. In 1921 there was another increase in eage but a reduction in yield per acre 'so that the producer jived very satisfactory prices. This stimulated the plant of potatoes in 1922, which happened to be a very favorable son for potatoes. The result was a production which eeded even the crop of 1917 and a price so low that thou - ds of acres of potatoes were not dug. WHEAT PRODUCTION AND PRICE Probably more interest has centered around the marketing of wheat than of any other product. It is not only one of the most widely grown cereals, but is used more extensively for bread making than any other product. Unlike corn, oats, and barley it is used but little for feeding livestock, so that Kost the entire crop except that used for seed finds its r to market. The United States is one of the great wheat export na - tions. For the 10-year period 1913-1922, we exported an annual average of more than 245 million bushels, which was nearly 30 per cent of our total wheat production. These exports were abnormally large because of the war, but in only one year since 1866 have we exported less than 10 per cent of our wheat crop. In the past half century there have been 7 years when less than 19 per cent of our corn was exported. The wheat which we export is sold in the markets of the world in competition with wheat grown in Canada, Argentina, Australia, and other wheat surplus countries. Generally speaking, the price paid for cash wheat at Chicago is the </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">Liverpool price less cost of transportation and necessary handling charges. World supply and world demand cannot be ignored in any discussion of wheat marketing. f Figure 3 shows the annual production of wheat from 1866 1922, the average farm price of wheat December 1 of each year, and the annual imports and exports of wheat. Wheat production has increased with the development of the country so that not only have we produced enough for our own use but have had each year a surplus for export. The price of wheat declined following the Civil War, the low point being reached in the period of financial depression of the early nineties. Increased efficiency of production has aided in keeping wheat prices low even during the years when, because of the increase in our circulating medium and other factors, the general price level was rising. The price rose during the World War but not as high as it would have risen had not the ordinary price determining forces been over - ridden by government regulation. WORLD WHEAT PRODUCTION AND PRICES Flo. «. — The heavy line represents the world wheat production. 1891 to 1922. inclusive, and the broken line, the average Chicago price for No. 2 Hard Red Winter Data from Yearbook. U. S. Department nf Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 21 I Figure 4 gives the world wheat production and price ■n 1891 to 1922. Without exception a decreased production iccompanied by a price rise, the most marked example ig the years from 1916 to 1920. Whenever Russian pro - tion reaches pre-war level we may expect even lower prices wheat until the acreage of wheat in the United States other countries now shipping wheat to Europe is reduced ause of the crop failing to pay cost of production. We are very evidently entering an era of overproduction of wheat, if we may judge by present consuming demands. A part of the land now used for wheat production will necessarily have to be used for some other purpose or else farmed at a loss. Men who feel that they are receiving for wheat less than the cost of production, or in other words men who are sub - marginal producers, must inevitably revise their system of farming. It is doubtless feasible for producers thru coopera - tion to reduce the handling charges on grain ; it is hoped that an extension of inland waterways and greater efficiency of railway operation will reduce transportation costs; it may even be possible to reduce the cost of wheat production ; gov - ernmental agencies may be induced to place temporary barriers in the way of the free movement of wheat; but ulti - mately, the wheat of the world will sell on the world market and the American farmer may well regulate his course of action in expectation that the price of his product will be determined by world- wide price making forces. CORN PRODUCTION AND PRICE Figure 5 shows our total production of corn and the aver - age farm price for December of each year from 1866 to 1922. Our average annual production of corn has approximately trebled since the Civil War, due of course to the development of the Middle West and the increased demand for corn. Short crop years are almost invariably years of good prices and good crop years are years of low prices. The market price of corn is, however, less of a factor in the profits of the aver - age farm than is the price of the livestock to which the corn is fed. This is because so large a proportion of Corn Belt farmers plan upon feeding the major portion of their crop. Of course upon those farms where either corn is bought fo? feeding or a considerable surplus is sold the price becomes a factor of primary importance. A discussion of some of the relationships existing between pork production and corn prices is given in later pages of this bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">Factors Affecting the Price ok Farm Products 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">OATS PRODUCTION AND PRICE Figure 6 shows that the same general relationship exists between the production and price of oats as for wheat and corn. The farmer who raises oats for sale does not always secure the greatest net returns from his crop in years when his yield is highest because he must take a lower price per bushel. Figure 7 shows that the same relationship holds true for the World as for the United States. OATS— WORLD PRODUCTION AND PRICE Fig. 7. — The heavy line represents the world oatt production. 1895 to 1922. and the broken line, the average Chicago price of No. 2 White Oats. Data from Yearbook U. S. Department of Agriculture. In a considerable portion of Nebraska oats are raised be - cause they are very desirable for feeding and fit well into a rotation with corn and winter wheat. These farms have, therefore, a greater interest in their yield per acre than in the market price per bushel. TIME OF SALE The monthly marketing of wheat, oats, and corn in the United States and the Chicago price per bushel for the con - tract grade for the years 1907 to 1922, inclusive, are shown in Figure 8. The amount of any one of these grains marketed </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 26 in a month varies widely but the time of the year in which the major portion of each crop is marketed shows a remark- I uniformity for the entire 16-year period. In the 5-year od, July, 1917, to June, 1922, about 62 per cent of the at, about 50 per cent of the oats, and about 47 per cent le corn which were sold from the farm where grown were keted in the 4 months following harvest. The heavy keting of wheat is in July, August, September, and Oc - r; of oats August, September, October, and November; of corn, December, January, February, and March. There very noticeable secondary marketing period for corn :h comes in May and early June following corn planting, in the majority of years the marketing of corn increases a brief period in late July and early August. This late keting is largely by farmers who hold their surplus until w crop is practically assured. The price of each kind of grain varies from month to month, with but few exceptions during the years studied, in accordance with the amount which comes to market. The price is lowest when the supply is greatest and highest when the supply is smallest. The seasonal variation in price is, however, much smaller than the seasonal variation in the amount marketed. Evidently there must be some reason why so many producers will each year hurry their wheat and oats to market immediately after threshing and their corn after husking, altho the price at that time is almost invariably lower than it is later in the year; and also there must be some explanation for the wide variations in the amount of grain marketed not causing a much greater variation in price. There are several advantages in hauling wheat or oats from the threshing machine direct to market. The cost of Kage, insurance, and extra handling are saved and loss n shrinkage is eliminated. The sale of grain often permits the farmer to pay loans, thus saving the interest on borrowed capitaj, or permits him to invest in time deposits or other interest-bearing securities. If the net value accruing from these advantages of early marketing equals or approximately equals the value added to the grain by holding, we may expect farmers who live near a market to continue to sell their surplus grain at the earliest opportunity. i Nebraska farmers apparently distribute their grain mar - ng more evenly thruout the year than the farmers in many jr states. The following tables are compiled from records </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 27 kept by the Omaha Grain Exchange. Of course not all of the grain received at Omaha is raised in Nebraska and not all the Nebraska grain which is shipped to market goes to Omaha, but nevertheless the receipts at that market doubtless give a fairly accurate reflection of the time when Nebraskans sell their grain. It will be noticed that less than 52 per cent of the wheat sold at Omaha is received in the 4 months following thresh- ing. Evidently many farmers prefer to put their wheat in a bin and haul it to market when other farm work is not press- ing instead of attempting to deliver to the elevator direct Table 3. — Average number of cars of wheat received in Omaha per month, July, 1904 to June, 1922 Month Average No. Per cent Cumulative cars of total per cent of marketing July 1708 11.8 11.8 August 2427 16.8 28.6 September 1684 11.6 40.2 October 1660 11.5 51.7 November 1222 8.4 60.1 December 1201 8.3 68.4 January 1041 7.2 75.6 February 781 5.4 81.0 March 607 4.2 85.2 April 668 4.6 89.8 May 917 6.3 96.1 June 572 3.9 100.00 Total 14,488 100.0 Table 4. — Average number of cars of oats received in Omaha per month, August, 1906 to July, 1922 Month Average No. Per cent Cumulative cars of total per cent of marketing 755 9.5 9.5 August 755 9.5 9.5 September 959 12.1 21.6 October 1008 12.7 34.3 November 642 8.1 42.4 December 685 8.6 51.0 January 687 8.6 59.6 February 535 6.8 66.4 March 654 8.3 74.7 April 575 7.3 82.0 May ..'...-.. 493 6.2 88.2 June _~ 471 5.9 94.1 July 467 5.9 100.0 Total 7,929 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">from the threshing machine. The relatively small amount sold from March to June inclusive, only 19 per cent, may possibly indicate that most farmers have been compelled to sell in order to pay debts, but more likely it indicates that holding for the spring market is not ordinarily • profitable enough to make it a popular venture. The receipts of oats at the Omaha Grain Exchange are E evenly distributed thru the year than wheat. In the first nths after harvest only 51 per cent of the total number rs for the year had been received. TABLE 5. — Average number of cars of corn received in Omaha per month, December 1906 to November, 1922 Average No. Per cent Cumulative cars of total per cent of marketing The variation in the receipts of corn at Omaha are less I in for wheat and greater than for oats. In all probability ! Nebraska farmer actually sells a much higher percentage his corn in the first 4 months after husking than these fig - ;s indicate, because feeders usually try to buy the major rt of their season's supply as early as possible. These local es are of course not included in this table, but are included Figure 8, which gives all sales for the entire United States. PRICE OF WHEAT AND TIME OF MARKETING Figure 9 shows the average monthly prices paid for cash wheat at Chicago for 42 crop years, July, 1880, to June 30. 1922. The average spread in price was but 10 cents. This is less than the cost of holding wheat for 10 months in a public warehouse. December January 1907 2702 2170 2014 1381 1501 1816 13S2 1549 1125 955 846 9.9 14.0 11.2 10.4 7.1 7.8 9.4 7.1 8.0 5.8 4.9 4.4 9.9 23.9 35.1 45.5 52.6 60.4 69.8 76.9 84.9 90.7 95.6 100.0 ToUl 19,348 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">WHEAT— AVERAGE MONTHLY PRICES. 1880 TO 192* Fig. 8. — The heavy line represent* the average monthly price of No. 2 Hard Red Winter Wheat at Chicago from July, 1880 to June, 1922. Nebraska is particularly interested in the price paid at Omaha. Table 6, compiled from the annual reports of the Omaha Grain Exchange, shows the average monthly prices paid for No. 2 Hard Red Winter wheat from July, 1904, to June 30, 1923. Table &lt;&gt;. — Average price 1 of wheat (No. 2 Hard Red Winter) Yaar July Aug. ; Sept. Oct. Nov. Dae. Jan. Feb. ; Mar. April 19M-06 fO.8C fO.94fl.O3 fl.05 fl.OC fl.(M fl.OS $1.08 $1.06 $0.95 May | June $0.92 $0.98 .80 .78 .76 ■ .73j .75 .77 .76 .68 .68 | .70 | .68 .71 .78 .87 .95 .96 I .94 j .96 .94 .96 .94 .99 .98 1.05 j 1.10 l!aO 1.29 l!t8 1.07 1.08 1.07 : 1.081 1.08 1.02 .94 .91 .94 .87 | .86 .86 .90 .87 .98 1.02 1.01 1.031 1.08 1.10 I 1.08 .82 .86 .86 I .831 .86 .86 I .86 .82 .83 .83 i .86 .86 .88 .81 1.14 1.33 1.50 1.47 1.S8 1.47 I 1.21 1.08 1.19 I 1.14 i 1.04! 1.10 1.07 i 1.00 1.68 I 1.84 I 1.75 1.96. 2.52 3.02 2.64 1918 19 2.23 2.14 2.13 i 2.12 2.131 1919-20 2.32 j 2.15: 2.16 2.20 : 2.36 1920-21 2.52 ! 2.34 2.34 2.05 1.75 1921-22 1.13 1.08 1.10 1.06 1.04 1922-23 1.08 1.02 1.01 1.10 1.14 2.20 2.26 2.28 2.31 2.86 2.57 | 2.40 2.58 2.74 2.44 \ 2.50 2.73 2.86 2.79 1.66 1.69 1.64 1.52 1.30 1.46 1.20 1.10 1.08 I 1.24 I 1.291 1.32 1.40 | 1.14 1.15 1.27 i 1.26 1.26; 1.28 1.24 1.14 Averace '■ $1,196 fl.iei $1,168 81.187 f!.18| $1,203 $1.2561 $1,247 $1.25 $1,314 $1,365 $1,274 'In making the computations, fractional parts of a cent were considered, i r ding they are omitted in the table except for the final average. In order to facilitate t &lt;&gt;,,&lt;, ih&lt;i by months, July. 190+, to June, 1922 m ri w: ..« 908 09 909-10 Silt 11 Sll 12 912 13 ;»l» -M !SJ IS 916 17 m- i a .90 I .72 t .86 .92 1.14 1.00 .85 .97 .82 .79 1.29 ; 1.08 .80 .78 .80 .80 .64 .66 .67 .68 .82 .91 .98 .921 .91 .93 .94 .96 .98 .97 1.04 1.02 .99 .97 .94 .89 .90 .96 1.08 .99 .88 .85 .86 .82 .82 .82 .80 .81 .83 1.03 1.02 1.08 ! 1.28i 1.01 1.02 .99 1.35 1.49 1.70 ! 1.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 30 In only 8 years of the 19 has the price in May been high enough to return a profit for holding wheat from the pre - ceding August after paying commercial storage charges, in - terest on investment, and insurance. In 2 of these years, 1914-1915 and 1916-1917, the World War was in progress, and in 2 other years, 1918-1919 and 1919-1920, the market was influenced by conditions due to the war. The level of average wholesale prices rose from 99 on July 1, 1914, to 243 on June 1, 1920, so that the rise in the price of wheat at that time can be considered only as a part of the general rise in prices. During a part of these years, cotton, furniture, shoes, sugar and many other products rose more rapidly in price than wheat. The rise in prices from August, 1921, to May, 1922, and from August, 1922, to May, 1923, was due in part at least to the general revival of business which followed the acute depression beginning in the autumn of 1920. The price of wheat rose in the spring of 1909 because of the scarcity of milling wheat due to short world crops in 1907 and 1908, and in the spring of 1912 because of the small world surplus and the Turko-Bulgarian War. There was an unusual rise in May and June, 1907, due primarily to the damage caused by the green bug in Texas, Oklahoma, and Kansas. A study of the table shows 2 other years when farm stor - age would have been profitable, provided the producer had bin OATS— AVERAGE MONTHLY PRICES— 1880 TO 1922 Fig. 10. — The heavy line represent* the average monthly price of No. S White Oats at Chicago from August, 1880 to July. 1922 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">r Av X UKb •"\r r r.l 1 1 »\ u X XX £j i KK t ( l r J/ AKM rKUlil I 13 31 room available that would otherwise have been unused. The cheapest place to store grain is on the farm where it is grown, and the man who has storage room already provided can store at much lower cost than the man who must rent storage space. Generally speaking, the storing of any cereal is most apt to prove profitable in those years when the market price is less than the cost of production. PRICE OF OATS AND TIME OF MARKETING Figure 10 shows the average monthly prices paid for cash oats in the Chicago market for 42 crop years, August, 1880, to July 31, 1922. The average spread in price of 5.6 cents does not indicate that there is ordinarily any very great profit in holding oats for the May market. The records of the Omaha Grain Exchange show a close relationship between the prices there and at Chicago. Accord - ing to Table 7, in only 6 years of the last 18 has the May price been enough higher than the August price to make the storage of oats profitable. PRICE OF CORN AND TIME OF MARKETING Figure 11 shows the average monthly price of corn in Chicago from December, 1904 to November, 1922 inclusive. The average monthly variation in price is greater for corn Table 7. — Average price 1 of oats (No. 2 White) at Omaha by mont #. A ugv8t •4 to * .'/• i I i Yaw Auf. Sq*. 1*04-05 $0.36 $0.30 1905-06 M .26, 1906-07 .28 M\ 1M7-08 .46 .46 1*08-09 .48 .48 1M»-1O .31 .38 1910 11 .34 M 1*11-12 .40 .44 1912 13 .33 .81 1*13-14 .40 .41 1*14 15 .40 .4* 1*15-16 .38 .34 1*1(-17 .51 .44 1*17-18 .«* .58 1918-19 .70 .70 1*19-20 .71 .&lt;* 19*0-21 .70 .00 1921-22 .32 .31 Amp $n.447 $0.43 Oct. $0.28 .27 .30 .44 .46 .38 .30 .46 .31 .38 .44 .34 .48 .58 .68 .68 .52 .29 $0,423 Nov. "£ .30 .43 .46 .38 .30 .46 .31 .38 .46 .36 .53 .86 .63 .71 .47 M 90.428 Dec. .31 .48 .48 .42 .80 .46 .31 .88 .46 .40 .52 .75 .70 .80 .46 JO $0.45 Jan. Feb. $0.28 $0.29 .28 .28 .84 .38 .48 .47 .48 .50 .46 .46 M .29 .49 .51 .82 .82 .38 .38 .51 .54 .46 .46 .54 .53 .82 .89 .60 .59 .86 .87 .41 .40 M .36 $0,465 $0,474 Mar. $9.30 .28 .40 .50 .52 .43 .28 .52 .31 .38 .54 .43 .61 .90 .68 .91 .40 .35 $0,483 April $0.30 .30 .40 .50 .52 .40 .30 .55 .32 .38 .54 .43 .70 .85 .70 1.00 .84 .35 $0.49$ May June $0.30 $0.30 .32 .85 .43 .48 .10 .SO .14 .56 .38 .36 .SZ .38 .13 .51 .36 .38 .38 .37 .51 .46 .40 .37 .17 .M .76 .74 .69 .66 l.M , 1.10 .38 .33 .37 .34 ♦0.495 10.488 1 10.. In making the coi ■tading they are omitt mtatioi in the as, fractional table except parts of m cent were considered. For the final average. In order to faciliui </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 32 CORN— AVERAGE MONTHLY PRICES— 1880 TO l»2l Fkj. 11. — The heavy line represents the average monthly price of No. 2 Yellow Corn from December, 1880 to November. 1921 than for either wheat or oats. One reason for this is that corn shrinks more after husking than does either wheat or oats after threshing. The Iowa and Illinois Experiment Sta - tions have found that on the average corn shrinks more than 16 per cent from the time it is cribbed in November until the middle of the following summer. Table 8 gives the aver - age shrinkage by months for 8 years as reported by the low? Experiment Station. Table 8. — Average shrinkage of corn by months, given in percentage Month November December January February March April M.y June July August September October Shrinkage during month 5.2 1.7 .6 .3 1.9 3.1 1.9 1.6 1.0 .5 .4 .0 Total shrinkage 5.2 6.9 7.5 7.8 9.7 12.8 14.7 16.3 17.3 17.8 18.2 18.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 33 For 50 cent corn in November the August price would have to be 59.6 to compensate for shrinkage alone. Because of the high amount of moisture contained in corn at husking time, it does not store well when shelled and placed in bins. It may of course be dried, but this is a somewhat expensive process. It is, therefore, only natural that some price inducement should be offered to the man who will store it in slatted cribs on the farm where it is grown either until it is needed for consumption or until it has dried sufficiently to keep if placed in a bin. 'In making the computation., fractional part* of a cent were considered. In order to facilitate readme they are omitted in the table except for the Anal average . Table 9 shows the average price of No. 3 Mixed Corn at Omaha by months from December, 1904, to November, 1922. From December to August the average spread for the entire 18 years was 17.1 cents, but if 1916-1917 is omitted the average spread was only 11.9 cents per bushel. The farmer who holds corn from December to May is apparently paid for his costs of storage, but he does not ordinarily receive a large profit. A large profit is sometimes made by holding until midsummer, but there is also danger of loss. Appar - ently the probable size of the new crop is the most important factor in determining whether the price of corn will go up or down after August 1. The average price for August has been almost the same as the average price for July on the Omaha market for the past 18 years. ABLE 9.- — Average price 1 of corn (No. 3 Mii months, December, 190b, to Novemb xed ) at Omaha by &gt;er, 19M Yew- Dec. ju. Feb. Mar. April May 1904-05 $0.39 10.39 $0.42 $0.43 $0.42 $0.45 1*05-08 M M .S6 .17 .41 .46 1908-07 M M M M .40 M 1907-08 .60 .62 * .62 .67 .80 .86 906-09 .64 .64 j .58 .61 .66 .70 1909 10 , .60 .80 ' .68 .64 .64 .68 1910-11 .41 .49 ' .38 .40 .44 .48 1911 12 .57 .61 ' .82 .68 .76 .75 1912-13 .42 .48 I .44 .46 .62 .66 1918-14 .64 .6* .69 .62 .86 .68 1914-15 .61 .68 .88 .68 .71 .71 1916-16 .66 .68 .67 .66 .89 .68 916 IT .85 .92 .96 1.07 1.86 1.66 917 18 1.66 1.68 1.6S 1.68 1.64 1.69 1918-19 1.44 1.37 1.28 1.43 1.62 1.69 1919-20 1.44 1.42 : 1.38 1.46 1.61 1.82 920-21 .84 .66 .64 .62 .48 .60 1921-22 .89 .40 .48 .60 .60 .53 kveragr $0,688 $0,691 $0,689 $0,718 $0,772 $0,824 June (0.48 .47 .48 .88 .89 .56 .54 .n .58 .M .69 .88 1.60 1.4T 1.72 1.77 .46 .64 $0.82 July $0.60 .47 .48 .72 .66 .57 .62 .71 .61 .68 .74 .74 1.97 1.59 1.84 1.48 .49 .66 $0,866 Au«. $0.50 .45 .60 .72 .61 .58 .69 .72 .71 .74 .72 .78 1.93 1.88 1.84 1.48 .44 .62 $0,869 aept. $0.48 .42 .66 .74 .62 .60 .62 .89 .71 .72 .66 .80 1.94 1.60 1.52 1.66 .48 .66 Oct. Not. $0.47 $0.48 .40 .40 .57 .62 .68 .60 .57 Ml .45 .44 .66 .66 .61 .48 .68 .68 .68 .68 .59 .61 .90 .92 1.91 1.96 1.41 1.38 1.36 1.46 .84 .72 .36 .39 .62 .68 $0,766 $0.75 $0.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">WORLD SUPPLY AND WORLD DEMAND The figures already discussed show that the amount of wheat, oats, and corn produced in any one year has a much greater influence upon price than the time of the year in which the grain is marketed. In other words, the price is influenced more by yearly world supply and probable demand than by the amount of grain coming to market in any month. The demand for grain is ordinarily greatest during the months when the supply is greatest, and the demand is least during the months when the supply is small. This does not mean that we eat more bread in August and September than in May and June but that millers ordinarily buy heaviest dur - ing the months when the price is lowest. It is good business to secure sufficient of the new crop to serve as a reserve. Foreign demand for wheat is greater in the summer and fall than in winter and spring when wheat from Argentina and Australia is seeking a market. The average exports of wheat by months from July, 1909, to June, 1922, inclusive are as follows: Table 10. — Average monthly exports of wheat 1913 to 1922 Month Amount Month Amount For the months of August, September, and October the average exports are 20,766,000 bushels. The average exports for January, February, and March, when the competition from Argentina is keenest, are but 14,088,000. It is generally conceded that sales for exports are more irregular than are the actual exports. The speculator is always watching the market, ready to take advantage of any drop in price and buy grain that he can sell when the price rises. As evidenced by the statistics already given, there is seldom a large net profit in buying grain in August or September and holding for the May or June market, if we consider average prices. The opportunity for profit comes from being able to buy when the market is temporarily depressed, due to unusually large receipts or other causes, and to sell on the rise, usually within a few days but sometimes not for weeks or even months. uly 16,407,000 August 21,119,000 September 21,614,000 )ctober 19,565,000 November 17,139,000 December 18,151,000 January 14,753,OO&lt; February 12,883,00( March 14,627,00&lt; April 15,059,00( May 15,647,001 June 16,130,001 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 35 The heavy demand for corn comes during the winter months. Nearly 40 per cent of our total corn crop is fed to hogs, and most spring pigs are finished on new corn. Many more cattle are also on feed from November to April than during the warmer months of the year when field work is more pressing. The speculator plays the same part in the corn and oats markets as in the wheat market. HOG RECEIPTS AND PRICES— CORN PRODUCTION AND PRICES Figure 12 is in part a duplication of Figure 5, since it shows the relationship between the production of corn in the United States and the price at Chicago for the years 1903 to 1922 inclusive. The variations in price and production do not appear quite so abrupt in Figure 12 as in Figure 5, for the reason that fewer years are represented and therefore the vertical lines are farther apart. The receipts of hogs are for the 6 principal hog markets — Chicago, Kansas City, Omaha, St. Louis, Indianapolis, and St. Paul. The receipts at these markets are a fair indication of the marketing trend for the entire United States. Chicago hog prices have been taken as a standard because of the size and central location of the market. In nearly every year studied more hogs were marketed in January than in any other one month. Large numbers were also marketed in December and February. These were, as a matter of course, the spring pig crop fattened in major part each year on the new crop of corn. A second high point comes in May or June of each year when the bulk of the fall pig crop goes to market. In 1911 the marketings in May and June were heavier than in January. This was doubtless the result of the high prices of hogs in the spring of 1910, which stimulated the breeding of sows for fall litters. In nearly every year for which statistics are available, the low hog price of the year coincides with the largest marketing of hogs, and the high price coincides with the light marketing. An increase in the supply of any product, unless accompanied by a corresponding increase in the demand, ordinarily results in a fall in prices. The seasonal price range is not as great proportionally as the variation in the number of hogs mar - keted. One reason for this is that pork consumption is naturally heaviest in the winter months. The curing of meat products when marketings are heavy helps equalize the supply for the year. Foreign buyers watch for the seasonal price decline, and their buying strengthens the market. </seg>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 37 I Figure 12 also shows an interesting correlation between n prices and hog production. The country as a whole was sperous during 1905, 1906, and the early months of 1907. s stimulated the consumption of pork, which naturally jlted in a higher price as hog production had not increased. ! price of corn was relatively low during all of 1906 and early months of 1907. Cheap feed and high-priced pork int good profits for the hog producers, and naturally stim - ted production. The 1907 spring pig crop was just ready to come to market at the time of the panic in the autumn of 1907. This practically destroyed the market for livestock and kept hogs from coming to market in November. In January, 1908, more hogs were sold at the principal markets than in any one month up to that time, and the price dropped to the lowest point it had reached since 1899. The price of corn rose during 1908 due to the heavy de - mand caused by the large number of hogs produced. The 1908 spring pig crop which came to market in large numbers in November and December, 1908, and January, February, and March, 1909, was large enough to keep the price of hogs low and of corn high. Because of the increase in hog pro - duction and resultant increase in the demand for corn, the feeding of corn to hogs was less profitable during the later months of 1907 and all of 1908 than was the selling of corn on the market. As a result of the failure of hogs to return a profit during 1908, farmers curtailed production. Receipts at the principal markets were low during the later months of 1909, 1910, and early months of 1911. The average price of hogs at Chicago rose from $5.65 per hundred weight in December, 1908, to $10.55 per hundredweight in March, 1910. The price of corn at Chicago, burdened by the large yield of 1910, dropped from 80 cents in September, 1909, to 47 cents in January, 1911. The men who were fortunate enough to have hogs for sale in 1910 received an excellent profit. As has been already stated, the high price of hogs in the spring of 1910 stimulated breeding for fall litters with the re - sult that a very large number of hogs came to market in May and June, 1911, at a greatly reduced price. Marketings were also very large in the following November, December, January, and February, due to the stimulus of the big profits of 1910. Hog prices were high again in 1913, low in 1915, and, under the spur of war, demands rose very high in 1917, 1918, and 1919. As indicated in Chart 12, corn prices also rose </seg>
            <seg id="p039">{ I I I I 1 4 ■ £ I in I I I I I = t 1 I F I. « K Ill oil z =-= id 8P ■■■ 6« </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Products 39 very high, so that during the major part of the war period the man who sold his corn on the market received a greater net profit than the man who fed the corn to hogs. Losses were particularly heavy in 1920, and as a result hog produc - tion was somewhat reduced. The 1920 corn crop was the largest ever produced and the 1921 corn crop was nearly as large. The price of corn fell precipitately. In December, 111, the prices offered by elevators in Nebraska were the est since February, 1900. European demand kept hogs at air price; the low price of corn made their production y profitable; in consequence hog production increased, re - ing the price in June, 1923, to the lowest point in many ,rs. The price of corn rose with the increased demand for ding, making hog production unprofitable. If we may ge the future by the past, the 1924 spring pig crop will much smaller than in 1923. tTo produce hogs at a profit evidently demands something re than economical production. It certainly requires a iy of probable supply and demand, a curtailing of produc - i during the years when other men are increasing produc - i, and an increase when other men are decreasing the size heir herds because of losses. (Figure 13 shows the relationship between hog prices and k exports. Excepting the period of the World War, which resented a very abnormal condition, the exports were low m prices were high and increased when prices dropped. ! Europeans are evidently careful buyers who watch our ■ket for bargains in pork and pork products. The fact is t millions of people in Europe are too poor to buy meat ept when the price is low. They will doubtless continue to buy our pork when we have a large surplus, but cannot be relied upon to furnish a steady market for a large volume at a high price. THE APPLICATION The price-making factors discussed in the early pages of this bulletin affect the prices of butter, eggs, cattle, rye, barley, and other farm products in much the same way as they do those products for which graphs and statistics are presented. The object has been to discuss and exemplify the factors affecting the price of all farm products rather than to discuss in detail the production and marketing of any particular product. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 198 A knowledge of these price-making forces is essential to an understanding of the causes of the present low prices paid for farm products and to the formulation of any plan for their betterment. Neither legislation to increase prices nor market - ing programs devised by farmers are apt to prove effective if they seek to controvert economic law. [(Ml </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>