<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00025</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  NEBRASKA BOYS AND GIRLS CLUBS.</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN No. 4 Distributed April 10. 1912. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. V. S. A. NEBRASKA BOYS AND GIBXS CLUBS. COOKING AND SEWING By Gertrude N. Rowan I 4 5 « J K J 5 z c i** J . x 5 I - iiii I hi DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. Pugiley, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS. Nebraska Boys and Girls Clulis Introductory -------..._ 4 Doawstk Science I'liriMist- nf I'iMid Orgaaic Pooch u [■orgasac Foods ---------- ;i Composition of the Air - | i i inposition of the Body HI i omposhtoa of Food Materials -.-.... t] Table of Measurements -[- -13 Fruits and Cereals Beverages - - u - - .7 Vegetables m Bread and Rolls Soaps ----- •_&gt;,-, Biscuits and Muffins Salads and Sandwiches ------ -I _. J| Meats and Dumplings --•-... I .. ;si t on Bread, Browa Bread, Steam Pudding and Sauce - - - :;.") Cold Desserts - :jf, Cakes and frosting* t'astry - ;:&gt; cCnfections :jh Canning and Preserving ......... 40 Invalid Cooking and Home Nursing ------- 42 Se«mg ------ ■ . 4: , Running and Overcasting -------- 4."&gt; Basting and Hemming .---•••. 47 Stitching and Backstitching - - -- - - - -49 lluttonhnles and ISuttons ----.-!-. 51 I &gt;orothy Seam on Flannel .-,2 Hooks and Eves :,:; Loop Stitch. Feather Stitch. French Knot 54 Petticoats M Shirt Waists </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 NEBRASKA BOYS AND GIRLS CLUBS. COOKING AND SEWING E' ( )ur organizations had their l&gt;eginning in the spring of 1905, a membership of five hundred Nebraska boys who entered the growing contest. At the first state meeting, December 14- in, we added 'corn cooking' and initiated an equal number of aska girls. "We expect each of our menil)ers to learn to do something worth doing — something the world wants done.' to learn to do it well: to acquire skill with the hands, to combine brain and muscle; to answer as far as possible his own questions by ex]ieriment and by &gt;tudy : each thus to become his own teacher, and to lead himself nit • &gt; an education that will bring the fullest development to the t family, — the hand, the head, the heart." Ex-State Superintendent E. C. Bishop. ( Sept. 20, 1906. ) BThe teaching of cooking and sewing in our public schools is "fail, but a substantial part of the course of study. It should •011 raged by all who are interested in a more progressive, prac - chool. RAYe urge the use of these bulletins, and advise county superin - nts to see that the teachers become familiar with their con - and organize classes in the subjects outlined." STATK Sl'PF.KINTKNDENT JaS. E. Dki.ZKLI. (March 13. kji 2. ) MY CKKTKl'DE N. ROWAN. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">DOMESTIC SCIENCE 4 INTRODUCTORY. Herein is given our individual home work course in domestic science. The outline of lessons was originated and used first by the York High School girls' domestic science club, which held regular meetings once a week under the direction of Miss Rowan, one of the high school teachers. The work was done separately in the homes of the pupils. The results were such that the following year the board of education fitted up a domestic science laboratory, en - gaged a special teacher, and established a regular course of study in domestic science, open to all high school girls. This outline has been successfully used by the domestic science clubs of the York, the Ainsworth, the Nebraska City, and the Beaver City high schools ; the Woman's Club at Rising City, and the Women's Institutes at Harvard, Clarks, Clay Center and other places. When used by women's institutes it is recommended that the girls be invited to participate and that they prepare and serve some of the dishes under the direction of some of the officers or the leader of the meeting. I 'he number of domestic science clubs has so increased, and is such general demand for a course of lessons adapted to the dual home work plan, that this bulletin is issued especially to such needs. I Che Plan. — The plan of organization which has been very ssful, not only in high schools but in other schools, is as fol - : The girls form a club limited in membership to only those are especially interested in the subject and who, without neg - g the regular school work and their home duties, can give a but definite time each week to the work. A president and tary are elected to look after the executive work and to keep </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 the records carefully. A teacher in the school who is interested in the work and in the girls becomes the adviser of the club. fleetings of the club are held once or, in some cases, twice a generally from 20 to 30 minutes in length, and held at a time they will not conflict with the school work. A certain recipe or direction is taken for the work each week and each member tries it at her home. Two, four, or more mem - bers, or in small clubs all the members, are requested to bring results of their efforts to the next meeting for a special report, and all members are called upon to report results and make comparisons. Then a new recipe is taken, or a variation of the old one is tried for the next week. Thus, during the year a definite course of study is Sometimes luncheons for special occasions, Thanksgiving dishes, candies for Christmas time, and other timely variations take the place of the regular lessons from the outline. Such variation is encouraged that the club members may learn to prepare the things in which they are most interested and which are in demand locally at particular times. Ehile it is an advantage to have as director or manager of the teacher who is familiar with the work in domestic science, )t necessary that such be the case. Some of our best work ;n done under the direction of teachers whose contribution success of the work was careful management and a spirit of g. |\fter trying the recipes as given, club members are encour - to vary recipes and directions as their originality may suggest o develop any plan or direction which is different, and good, bers are requested to report any good things learned to the and the club officers are requested to report the same to this rtment, who will give other clubs an opportunity to try them The outline is as well adapted for grammar grades and for older girls in rural schools as for high school students. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 DOMESTIC SCIENCE. |)omestic Science has a definite and proj&gt;er place in curricula e public schools. In the Nebraska Course of Study for the ntary schools, domestic science is outlined not as one of the ssentials, but as one of the general subjects to be interwoven the regular work of the school. As in the teaching of agriculture and manual training, domes - tie science should be correlated with the other subjects taught in the school so as to bring out the science and art of home making. It should show that the language, .the drawing, the physiology, geography, physics, chemistry, and other science taught in the tchool may be best illustrated from the everyday home life of the pupil, and in such a way as to bring not only a good degree of right general education, but so as to stimulate an interest and bring an enjoyment into the particular lines of activity in which the indi - vidual in the home should become interested. I such teaching will interweave the school life with the home will elevate the home, properly dignify the tasks connected with, and will vitalize the work of the school. The intelligent skillful performance of any duty related to the interests of the : is right education at any period of the individual's develop- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">■ S f « L ~ p ! (I p 1 . ri s 4 i r I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 COURSE OF STUDY. COOKING The Purpose of Food. Ethe study of Domestic Science we think first of food, and rpose of that food. Aside from eating because we are , we eat food to make us grow, to repair the waste, and give gy to keep warm and to work. To do all this we need to take into the body a certain amount of various kinds of food which will supply the needs of the bones, muscles, brain, and all parts and organs of the body. Some of this food we take in its natural state just as it grows. Some must be cooked to make it of good flavor and easy of digestion. Some food may be taken either raw or cooked. Under ordinary condi - tions, with the average person, the requirements of the body de - mand seventeen ounces of solid food and five pints of water each Two Great Classes of Food. In the first class are all those foods which possess or have cised life. These are called the organic foods, such as meat, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DOMESTIC SCIENCE 9 potatoes, flour, etc. In the other class are the inorganic foods, or those which do not contain organs of life, as water, salt, etc. I. ORGANIC FOODS. It. Proteids. Animal and vegetable foods which contain albu - in large amounts are called proteids. These are tissue build- White of an egg is the purest albumen in this class. Other pies are milk, cheese, meats, fish, cereals, peas, beans, and B. Carbohydrates. The sugars and starches are called carbo - tes. They furnish the energy and maintain heat. They in - vegetables, fruits, cereals, sugars, and gums. 3. Fats and Oils. These store energy and heat to be used as needed. This class includes butter, cream, fat of meat, fish, cereals, nuts, and olives. II. INORGANIC FOODS. B. Mineral matter furnishes the salts for the bones, the blood, nails, etc. 2. Water makes up about two-thirds of the weight of the The Composition of the Air. Before going to anything as complex as the composition of the body, let us study the air, with which we are more familiar. Kir, which we cannot feel, taste or see, is made up chiefly of ements, oxygen and nitrogen. About one-fifth of it is oxy - id four-fifths nitrogen. There is also a very little ammonia, r gases, watery vapor, and carbon dioxide. Kere are some experiments which may be performed to show nposition of the air. Experiment 1. Drop a piece of ice into a glass of water. ! the moisture collecting on the outside of the glass. From does it come? Edoes not come through the glass. The air around the glass kly cooled and the moisture or watery vapor collects upon ss. The same may be observed when the temperature falls. )isture collects on objects in the form of dew or frost Experiment 2. Insert in the tightly fitted cover of a jelly </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 glass a small lighted torch or wick several inches long. Watch it doady as ii burns and finally goes out. What is the cause? fie oxygen in the air in the jelly glass is entirely used and ■ therefore goes out. Without the oxygen of the air, there be no fire. Without the large proportion of nitrogen, fire hum with a great explosion and too great rapidity. I Experiment ■?. Put a piece of fresh lime alxwt the size of an nto a pitcher and ii]x&gt;n it poor a small teacupful of water. n the lime has crumbled, pour a pint of water into the pitcher, horoughly, let settle. Half fill a glass with the clear liquid. I a straw or other tube, force the breath slowly through the water in the tumbler. ■he clear water becomes turbid, which shows there is carbon e in the air from the lungs. Composition of the Body. Eie-third of water is oxygen. It is united with two parts of en. and the symlx&gt;l or sign representing water is H.,&lt; &gt;. or &gt;lecules of hydrogen and one of oxygen in an atom of water. lust as air and water are made up of certain elements, the body is also coHBOMd of different elements united in certain pro - portions. In the body there are 62'^ per cent of oxygen. 21 '/&gt; per cent of carbon, 10 per cent of hydrogen, and 3 per cent of nitrogen. Three per cent is made up of the following: Calcium, phosphate, potassium, sulphur, chlorine, sodium, magnesium, iron, and flourine. |\fter studying the composition of foods and the composition e body, we can readily see that certain foods are of greater to the body than others, and also that the needs of the body be as well satisfied by the use of inexpensive foods as of the expensive ones if they contain the proper amount of nutri- Tiik Calorie. When we wish to heat a pint of water or keep it warm we kindle a fire under it. If we could arrange a thermometer under the kettle and measure the heat, we could tell just how much heat is required to make the water one degree hotter. This amount of heat in the bodv is called a calorie. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Ehe body must be kept warm. We know there is no fire to t heated, so there must be another method. In the body the s the fuel, and as it is eaten and digested heat is produced, eat of the body i&gt; measured just as the heat of the water was red, by calories. SoflK kinds of food will produce much heat and therefore more calories than others. Bne pound of protein or carbohydrates contains i860 heat or iS&lt;&gt;o calorics; one i&gt;ound of fat, 4220 calories. In other one pound of lean meat is equivalent to one pound of sugar ; than one-half poaad of fat in its energy -giving capacity. Ehe best tissue builders — those which contain large quantities tein — are beef, cheese, beans, mutton, mackerel, codfish, and il. The following table from Atwater shows the composi - t many food materials, excluding the refuse: Composition of Food Material •Page 31. Refer to l&gt;eet animal for differences between round and Emphasize these four essentials: 1. Neatness in personal appearance. 2. Cleanliness of utensils. 3. Economy in the use of materials and fuel. 4. F.xactness in measurements. Foik Essentials in Cooking. NTTKIMENTS. r Total Water Nutri- ments Car- Min- Pro- Fat In &gt;hy- eral tein ilrate Matt'r s •Beet, round M.I :n.8 : •Heef , sirloin 42 . 2 ST.i Mutton, leg 61.8 M.l Cod *2.6 17.4 Oyster «7.2 M.I Milk 87.0 U.« B u tter 10.3 ■•• Cheese :!( &gt;-2 W.I Potatoes »•• W.I Moans H.I Sl.l Rj ce 12.4 IT. I Corn meal !*•• s: - " Oat meal "■■" ■•• Wheat flour 12. 3 "»•• Wheat bread M.3 B7.7 M.I 10.1 1.2 II. J 4:i.T 0.8 18. :i 19.0 0.9 15. S 0.4 1.2 1.1 1.6 4.0 0.9 3.6 4.0 4.7 0.7 1.0 S5.0 0.5 3.0 :!.-&gt;. 5 1.8 4.2 2.1 0.1 17.9 0.1 7.1 0.7 22.0 1.7 7.4 0.4 79.4 0.4 &lt;l.2 S.I 70.6 . 1.4 14.7 7.1 68.4 2.0 11.0 1.1 74.9 0.5 5.5 1.7 56.3 0.9 ;m.7 0.2 1140 t» /■ .1 __r : i r . *r&gt; it D a (.r tn 1i»..-t animal fnr i Hifferem-es between round an </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Directions. With the foregoing as a basis we are ready to begin the cook - ing lessons. Where there are no facilities for cooking in the school, the Individual Home Work Method may be adopted. The teacher meets the class once or twice a week at a convenient time and place. At these meetings the teacher has written upon the board recipes from the following collection or from others she knows to be reliable. The method of combining the recipes is carefully explained, and the recipe and notes on the method are copied by each girl in a little recipe book or note book kept for the purpose. Each recipe copied at a meeting of the class should be tried before the next meeting. All directions should be carefully followed. Where the class is large each recipe should be assigned to four girls who are not only to prepare the dish but to bring the results to the next meeting of the class. This avoids the incon - venience of having more samples on hand than can be carefully examined and compared. The recipes are given under fourteen headings and from one to four lessons may be given to each. Lesson in Measuring — Bancroft School, Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DOMESTIC SCIESCE 13 Table of Measurements. The following table of measurements applies to each of the 3 teaspoons (tsp.) equal 1 tablespoon (tbsp.) 16 tbsp. equal 1 cup (c). 2 c. equal 1 pint (pt.). All measurements level. Level each cup or spoonful with a knife by scraping off all excess material. Recipes quoted are from the Boston Cooking- School Cook Book by Miss Fannie M. Farmer. I. Fruits and Cereals. Table for Cooking Cereals. Ed. Quantity. Water. Time, ooked and rolled oats lc l&gt;4c 30 min. led Avena lc. lj^c 30 min. iker Rolled Oats, H-0 lc l#c 30 min. Rolled Avena Old Grist Mill lc l#c 30 min. Rolled Oats lc lfic 30 min. Steam-cooked and rolled wheat lc lJ4c 20 min. Rolled Oats Old Grist Mill Old Grist Mill lc lJ4c 20 min. Rye Flakes, Pettijohns, etc lc \%c 20 min. ""(steamed) lc [g£- [ « J° „. Indian Meal lc 3 l Ac 3 hrs. Vitos lc 4»4c 30 min. Wheatlet lc 3*ic 30 min. Wheatena lc 3*$c 30 min. Hominy (fine) lc 4 c 1 hr. Table Showing Approximate Composition of Cereals. Mineral Proteid. Fat. Starch. Matter. Water. Oatmeal 15.5 7.5 68 o Corn meal 9 2 7."&gt; 1. Wheat flour (spring) 12 1 75 .1 Wheat flour (winter) 10.5 1 Trt . j Entire wheat flour 14 ■2 71 1. Graham flour 13.5 ■ 70 2. Pearl barley 9. 1. 78 1. 11. Rye meal 7. 1. 79 1. 12.5 Rice 8. .5 79 .5 12.5 n .5 Buckwheat flour 6. 1. 77 1.5 14.5 Macaroni 11.5 1.5 13 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 I. CBEAM OF WHEAT WITH SLICED BANANAS. Kb ,Vm c. Iwiling water, add I tsp. salt. Stir in gradually ream of Wheat. Cook over lire for 5 minutes, stirring oocs - ly to keep fnmi burning. Steam in double lx&gt;iler for 30 es. Serve with cream and sliced bananas. • BAKED APPLES WITH OATMKAI Wash appies. remove core and add sugar. Fill cavity with cooked oatmeal, sweeten and bake until apple is tender. 3. CEREALS WITH FKIIT. K serving oatmeal. Cream of Wheat. I'ettijohn's Breakfast corn meal. etc.. serve with either sliced dates, steamed tigs le fruit, with cream. 4. kkikp mush Slush left over from breakfast may lie packed in greased one king powder tins, and covered, which will prevent crust from ng. The next morning remove from box, slice thinly, dip in and saute. Serve with maple syrup. BOILED BICE. 1 .. tsp. salt 2 c. boiling water K'ash thoroughly, add slowly to boiling salted water, keeping lx)iling rapidly until rice is tender, about ' _&gt; hour. Drain in strainer, return to saucepan in which it was cooked and let on back of range or over low fire until dry. Kernels should tinct. ' j c. grated cheese macaroni 1 c. cream or milk 1 tsp. onion juice 1 tbsp. chopped parsley 3 eggs ■ soft bread crumbs butter i tbsp. red or green pepper Kook the macaroni in boiling salted water until tender. Drain nse in cold water. Scald the cream, add bread crumbs, butter, f&gt;. MACARONI LOAF. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 8 per, salt, grated cheese, parsley, onion juice, the beaten eggs and •aroni. Line a quart baking dish with buttered pa]&gt;er, turn in Hire, set the pan on many folds of paper, in a dish of water, and e in a moderate oven from '.. to ; i of an hour. Serve with tomato or mushroom sauce. ~. tom ATO SAl'CE. 2 tbsp. butter 2 tbsp. flour 1 C. stewed and strained tomatoes '■ _• tsp. salt Slice of onion l /2 tbsp. capers % tsp. pepper Hrown flour and butter separately, then combine and add salt and pepper. Cook tomatoes with slice of onion for a few minutes, then remove onion and add juice gradually to butter and flour. Cook thoroughly, then add capers. 8. MACAKOM ITALIAN STYLE. i ' _&gt; c. scalded milk i c. macaroni 1 tbsp. butter 2 tbsp. flour 2 3 c. grated cheese Salt and paprika y&gt; c. finely chopped cold boiled ham I'reak macaroni into one-inch pieces and cook in boiling salted water, drain, and re-heat in sauce made of butter, flour and milk to which is added cheese. As soon as cheese is melted, season with salt and paprika, turn on serving dish. Sprinkle with ham, garnish with O,. RICE DESSERT. Cook in double boiler until rice is thoroughly cooked. Mound rice on a platter and garnish with preserved pears. II. Bevekacks. E beverage is any drink. The uses are to quench thirst, furnish ter in the blood, regulate the temperature of the body, stimu - e nervous system, and as a medicine. K;e i ' .. c. water salt i ' 2 c. milk sugar </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 DOMESTIC SCIENCE ■he most common prepared beverages are tea, coffee, chocolate, and fruit drinks. TEA. Kea is of little value as a food except for the cream and sugar with it. It contains a stimulant, theine, and an astringent, . If tea is boiled when prepared, tannic acid is developed injures the coating of the stomach. Tea should therefore be. d, but never boiled. IO. TEA. 3 tsp. tea 2 c. boiling water Scald teapot, put in tea, and add the boiling water. Let stand three to five minutes. Strain, serve. Experiment: Boil tea ten minutes. Compare the dark color, bitter flavor, and the dark ring formed on the cup. Topics for supplementary reading and language work : i. The tea plant. t Preparing tea for market. Green tea and black tea. 4. Preparation of tea for the table. Reference: Chamberlain, "How We Are Fed." COFFEE. Eflfee contains caffeine, a principle similar to the theine in tea. s more stimulating than tea, and quickens heart action. Care t&gt;e taken not to boil the coffee, and to avoid using coffee which &gt;d from one meal to another and has been re-heated. ii. Coffee. io tbsp. coffee J4 c. cold water % egg 6 c. boiling water I Scald coffee pot. Put in ground coffee, egg, and cold water, thoroughly with fork. Add boiling water. Bring gradually to Settle with 2 tbsp. cold water. Strain and serve. Topics for supplementary reading and language work : i. The coffee plant. 2. Picking, sorting, and sacking coffee. 3. Roasting coffee. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 COCOA AND CHOCOLATE. Cocoa and chocolate are prepared from the dried and roasted seed of the cocoa bean. Like tea and coffee, they contain a stimu - lant, which is known as theobromine. They contain more nutriment than either tea or coffee. Chocolate differs from cocoa in that it contains more fat. 12. COCOA i tsp. cocoa y 2 c. boiling water i tsp. sugar ]/ 2 c. scalded milk Few grains salt and drop of vanilla Kix cocoa and sugar. Add gradually (while stirring) to boil - uid. Boil one minute. Flavor. Beat with Dover egg-beater inutes to prevent scum. Serve. 13. CHOCOLATE. l}/ 2 squares Baker's chocolate 3 c. milk 4 tbsp. sugar 1 c. boiling water Few grains salt E:ald milk. Melt chocolate in small saucepan placed over hot add sugar, salt and gradually add boiling water; when 1, boil one minute; add to scalded milk, mill (beat to froth), rve in chocolate cups with whipped cream. Topics for supplementary reading and language work: 1. The cocoa tree. 2. Collecting and drying the pods. 3. The manufacture of chocolate. III. Eggs. Eggs resemble milk in that they contain the food elements in nearly correct proportions to support the body. Kventy-three and five-tenths per cent of egg is water, nearly cent proteid which is albumen, over 10 per cent fat found in the yolk and 1 per cent mineral matter. Eggs should be cooked either at a low temperature or for a time. If cooked too long or at too high a temperature they </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 14. BOILED EGGS. IA'ith a spoon, place number of eggs desired in boiling water enough to cover eggs. For "soft boiled," cook three minutes ive to seven minutes for "hard boiled." Plunjje "hard boiled" into cold water when taken from hot water. 15. POACHED EGGS. Bnto a shallow pan two-thirds full of boiling salted water slip eggs one at a time. Water should cover the eggs. When a orms over eggs, carefully remove with skimmer. Eeat eggs slightly with silver fork ; add salt, pepper, and milk, pan, put in butter, and when melted, turn in the mixture, until of creamy consistency, stirring and scraping from bottom pan. 17. PLAIN OMELET. 4 eggs 4 tbsp. water ]/ 2 tsp. salt 1 tbsp. butter Separate yolks from whites. Beat yolks in a bowl with a Dover beater until thick, add salt, pepper and water. Beat whites until stiff, cutting and folding yolks into them until the mixture is blended. Melt butter in omelet pan, and when moderately hot turn in mixture, spread evenly, place on range where it will cook slowly (about 12 minutes). Keep the temperature low until the last minute, when it may be raised to brown the bottom. When well puffed put pan in a moderate oven to cook the top. That is, until omelet is firm to touch. Crease across the top, fold on hot platter. and serve at once. Enelet may be served with White Sauce II to which has been finely chopped cold ham or grated cheese. Omelet may be ed with jelly, parsley, or toast points. fl6. SCRAMBLED EGGS, js y 2 tsp. salt milk ]/ % tsp. pepper 2 tbsp. butter </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 1 8. BOILED CUSTARD. K scalded milk J4 c - sugar ', yolks J-6 tsp. salt . vanilla Iieat eggs slightly, add sugar and salt ; stir constantly while tally adding hot milk. Cook in double boiler, continue stirring mixture thickens and a coating is formed on the spoon, strain ; ind flavor. If cooked too long custard will curdle. Bipress the fact that eggs should be taken from clean sur - ngs. For reference, see Farmers' Bulletins 128, 182, 236, 7. These may be obtained by writing to Secretary of Agri - ■, Washington, D. C. IV. Vegetables. ■Fhe principal constituent of certain vegetables, especially pota - and of cereals, is starch. E Starch is a white, glistening powder which does not dissolve in water. When heated in boiling water the grains swell and : forming a paste. EXPERIMENTS WITH STARCH. A ten-cent bottle of iodine can be purchased at any drug store. A small amount is sufficient for all these experiments. Experiment 4. Stir into a half glass of cold water, one tbsp. starch. Add a few drops iodine. Note change in color. This blue tint shows that starch is present and is known as the iodine test for Experiment 5. Boil together, stirring constantly, one cup \vate r and one tbsp. starch until paste is formed. Add a few drops of iodine, and note the blue tint which indicates presence of starch as in Experiment 4. I Experiment 6. Heat starch over flame or in the oven until 3 n color. Stir in cold water. A paste is formed showing that lew compound called dextrin is unlike starch, being soluble in water. Which do you conclude is more easily digested, raw starch or starch aft^r it is tViorniiP"h1v rdn\cf*t\ \nd whv^ </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 taw starch is indigestible, therefore all foods containing starch be thoroughly cooked. There are several kinds of starch, ling on the source. Corn-starch is made from Indian corn, root is made from the Maranta plant and is the purest form rch. Tapioca is obtained from the roots of the cassava, a American plant. Sago is starch from the sago palm of India. Bxperiment 7. Cut a very thin slice from a raw potato. Test arch with iodine. What do you conclude about the composi - f the potato ? COMPOSITION OF THE POTATO. Starch, 18 per cent. Proteid, 2.1 per cent. Water, 78.9 per cent. Mineral matter, .9 per cent. Fat, .1 per cent fopics for supplementary reading and language work : The manufacture of starch. 2. The starch foods. Keferences: Selecting Potatoes for the Contest, University in, Series XIII, No. II. 19. BOILED POTATOES. B'are, wash, and place in cold water potatoes of uniform size, into boiling salted water and cook until soft to the center when d with a fork. Drain when tender. Rice is cooked as potato, not washed before dropping into the boiling water. 2O. MASHED POTATOES. I dash, or force through ricer, boiled potatoes. To one quart :d potato add three tablespoons butter, one teaspoon salt and Durth cup hot milk. Beat with fork until creamy. Serve, serve as border around steak, shaping pockets of the potatoes lling with green peas well seasoned. 21. POTATO CAKES. ■hape cold mashed potato into round flat cakes. Fry slowly &gt;lenty of butter until light brown on each side — about twenty es. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 22. FRANCONIA POTATOES. | 3 repare as for boiled potatoes, and parboil ten minutes ; drain, &gt;lace in pan in which meat is roasting ; bake until soft, basting fat in pan when basting meat. Time required for baking about minutes. Sweet potatoes may be prepared in same way. 23. CANDIED SWEET POTATOES. K&gt;il until tender 6 medium sized sweet potatoes. Peel, place in th 1 c. sugar and l / 2 c. melted butter over them. Bake slowly urs. 24. GLAZED CARROTS. K'ash, scrape and cut in thin strips. Parboil, drain, place in pan with l / 2 c. butter and x /i c. sugar. Cook slowly until and tender. 25. STUFFED BAKED TOMATOES. Klium sized tomatoes 1 tsp. onion juice ft bread crumbs Salt 4 tbsp. melted butter Pepper Eipe and remove thin slices from stem end of tomatoes. Take ;ds and pulp, drain off liquid. Add seasoned bread crumbs ke in buttered tin from 20 to 30 minutes. 26. CAULIFLOWER POLONNAISE. ■Soak a cauliflower in cold water, head down, 1 hour. Place in ttle with 1 quart boiling water and 1 pint milk. Add 1 tbsp. and boil until tender. Drain and arrange on dish for serving. Sprinkle with yolks of hard-boiled eggs finely chopped, and mixed with 1 tbsp. finely chopped parsley, and fine bread crumbs fried to a light brown in Duller. 27. ONION FARCI. Peel 6 large onions and remove a part of the inside. Cover with boiling water, cook 5 minutes, drain and stuff with chopped meat. Place onions in a baking dish on 6 thin slices salt pork, sur - round with 1 cup stock. Bake slowly until onions are soft. Remove fat from gravy, season with salt, pepper and butter, and pour over </seg>
            <seg id="p022">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 22 28. ASPARAGUS. Cut off tough ends of asparagus. Wash. Cook in boiling salted water twenty to thirty minutes, leaving tips out first ten minutes. Drain. Spread with butter. Serve on milk toast. 29. CREAM OF LIMA BEANS. Soak one cup of dried beans over night, drain, and cook in boiling salted water until soft ; drain, add three-fourths cup cream, butter ai:d salt. 3O. BAKED WINTER SQUASH. Cut squash in pieces two or three inches square. Steam twenty minutes. Place in hot oven to finish cooking, adding butter, salt. and pepper to each piece. Serve on shell. 31. SCALLOPED TOMATOES. Alternate layers of stewed or canned tomatoes with layers of cracker crumbs, salt and pepper, in a buttered baking dish. Cover top with buttered crumbs. Cook in medium oven until brown. alx&gt;ut thirty minutes. Information may be gathered about asparagus, beans, squash. tomatoes, and other vegetables, and compositions written accord- Table Showing Approximate Composition of Vegetables. Carbo- Mineral Proteid. Fat. hydrate. Matter. Water Asparagus 2. .2 3.5 1.0 94 Beans, Lima 7. .7 22. 1.5 68 Beans, String 2. .4 9.5 .5 87 Beets 1.5 .1 9.5 1. Cabbage 2. .4 6. 1.5 91 Carrots 1. .4 9. 1. 88 Cauliflower 1.5 .8 6. .5 90 Celery 1.5 .1 3. 1. 94 Corn (green) 3. 1. 14. .5 81 Cucumber 1. .2 2.5 .5 96 Egg-plant IT .3 5. .5 93 2 2.5 .5 .'6 Lettuce 1.5 .4 3.5 1. 94 Onions 4.5 .6 .5 1. 93 Parsnips 1.5 .6 16. 1.5 80 Peas (green) 4.5 .5 16. 1. 78 Potatoes (sweet) 2. .7 27. 1. 69 Potatoes (white) 2. .1 18. 1. 79 Spinach 2. .5 3. 1.5 92 Squash 1.5 6. 10. 1. 86 Tomatoes 1. .4 4. .5 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 23 V. Bread and Rolls. Experiment 8. Test a piece of bread with iodine for starch. Bread is a perfect food except it lacks fat; we therefore spread with butter. There are two kinds of bread known since the time of Lot as unleavened and leavened. Unleavened bread is a mixture o{ water and flour, baked, resulting in a hard, tough material. Lea\ - ened bread has been made for nearly two thousand years. To the water and flour is added a leaven or ferment to hasten and perfect the rising. There are different ways of procuring this ferment or EXPERIMENTS WITH YEAST. Experiment p. To a quantity of milk add a little salt — enough vent its souring quickly. Place the milk in a warm but not ace. The milk will begin to froth, showing that yeast from • is growing in the milk. This kind of yeast was used to mix with the dough before com - pressed yeast was made. Experiment 10. Fill each of three jelly glasses one-third full n flour and water paste. Dissolve slowly one dry or com - d yeast cake in one-half cup lukewarm water. Add one table - ful to each jelly glass, stirring vigorously until small bubbles To glass I add a piece of ice the size of an egg. Place glass II in a warm place, 65 degrees to 80 degrees F. ■Fill glass* I II with boiling water. Watch results and compare ontents of the three glasses, noting the number of bubbles. Which is the most favorable temperature for the action of yeast, freezing, moderate, or the boiling temperature? What pre - cautions must be taken in the making of bread to get the most active yeast, and therefore the lightest bread? 32. MILK AND WATER BREAD. 1 c. scalded milk 1 yeast cake dissolved in % c. lukewarm water 1 c. boiling water 1 tbsp. lard 6 c. sifted flour or 1 c. white flour and enough entire wheat flour V/ 2 tsp. salt </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">25 i ut lard, sugar, and salt in bowl ; pour on boiling water and milk. When lukewarm, add dissolved yeast cake and 5 c. flour. Stir until thoroughly mixed. Add remaining flour, mix, and turn on a floured board, leaving a clean bowl ; knead until mixture is smooth, elastic to touch, and bubbles may be seen under the surface. Return to bowl, cover with clean cloth, let rise over night in warm place. In morning cut down and allow to rise once more. When light, knead down into loaves, placed into greased pans, filling them about one-half full. Allow to rise until they double in size, and bake in slow oven 1 hour. This recipe may be varied by using one-half graham, rye, or entire wheat flour. 33- EGG ROLLS. To one c. bread mixture (No. 32) after rising add 1 egg, 1 tsp. sugar, 1 tbsp. butter, and flour to thicken. Shape, let rise to double bulk. Bake 30 minutes in moderate oven. 34. COFFEE CAKE ■Roll bread mixture (No. 32) out thin; cover with melted but sugar, and cinnamon. Let rise ; bake 20 minutes. Topics for supplementary reading and language work : </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 DOMESTIC SCIESCE 1. The growing and threshing of winter and spring wheat. 2. The wheat in the flour mills. 3. The making of a loaf of bread. Score Card for Bread. Flavor Taste ( Odor ) 45 Texture of Crumb Lightness ] Doughiness i Color *° Moisture Texture of Crust Color ( Hardness J 10 Size and Form 5 Total 100 Flavor — Good bread has a pleasing taste and no disagreeable Texture of Crumb — Good bread is thoroughly kneaded and K slowly. As a result the air holes are small and uniform. The is evenly white and light to the center of the loaf. The crumb d bread is not so dry as to be impalatable when a couple of days old. Texture of Crust — The crust should be thin, crisp, deep brown color and well done. * Size and Form — This is of least importance. Rectangular loaves, smooth, and evenly raised are preferable. VI. Soups. There are two classes of soups, those with stock and those with- » Soups with stock made from meat will not be considered here. 1 without stock have for their basis white sauces. The smooth- ness of the soup depends upon the white saute. 35. WHITE SAUCE I. 1 tbsp. butter 36. WHITE SAUCE II. 1 tbsp. flour </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DOMESTIC SCIESCE 27 37. WHITE SAUCE III. 1 c. milk 3 tbsp. butter 3 tbsp. flour Rub flour and butter to a smooth paste. Beat gradually into scalding milk. Add seasonings to taste. 38. CELERY SOUP Parboil 1 c. celery cut in inch pieces. Add 2 c. White Sauce I, 1 slice onion, salt and pepper. 39. corn soup. 2 tbsp. butter 1 can corn 1 pint boiling water 2 c. flour 1 pint milk 1 tsp. salt 1 slice onion Few grains pepper Eiop the corn, add water, and simmer twenty minutes; rub h a sieve. Scald milk with onion, remove onion, and add ) corn. Bind with butter and flour cooked together. Add d pepper. VII. Biscuits and Muffins. I ["he leavening in biscuits and muffins is not yeast, as in bread, hemical compounds which act more quickly and under condi - different from yeast. The chemicals are soda, which acts with milk or molasses, and baking powder, acting with sweet milk iter. LEAVENING EXPERIMENTS. Ixperimettt II. Take four jelly glasses. Fill the first half full d water, the second half full of sour milk or buttermilk, the one-fourth full of cold molasses, and the fourth one-fourth f heated molasses. To each glass add one tablespoonful of Stir vigorously. Erhat are your conclusions as to the action of soda? Upon materials does it act best and what temperature gives the st reaction? Blxperiment 12. Take four jelly glasses. Fill the first half full d water, the second half full of cold milk, the third one-fourth f hot milk, and the fourth half full of sour milk. To each add iblespoonful baking powder. Stir vigorously. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Ifhat are your conclusions as to the action of baking powder? what materials does it act best and what temperature gives the st reaction? How many minutes does the reaction last? does this indicate about the handling? Will the best results ained if the dough is not placed in the oven as soon as mixed? 4O. BAKING POWDER BISCUIT. 2 c. flour yi, c. milk 3 tsp. baking powder 1 tsp. salt 2 tbsp. butter Sift dry ingredients together. Work in butter with tips of fingers. Add milk gradually, mixing with knife. Toss on floured board. Roll to one inch in thickness. Shape with biscuit cutter. Bake in hot oven 1 2 to 15 minutes. 41. STRAWBERRY SHORT CAKE. I Bake biscuit dough, recipe 40, in round or square cake tin. and cut in two one box strawberries, add one c. sugar, and let while baking the crust. Spread over biscuit dough. Serve Strawberry Short Cake may be made by adding 2 tbsp. butter tbsp. sugar to the recipe given in 40, and proceeding according directions given. Topics for supplementary reading and language work : 1. Strawberry culture. 2. Climate and soil adapted to strawberries. 42. DUTCH APPLE CAKE. Eiur 2 tbsp. sugar baking powder 1 egg lard 1 c. mik butter IVtix dry ingredients and cut in the shortening. Mix egg and and combine the two mixtures. Place in buttered pan, and small slices of apples half way into the batter, sprinkle liberally sugar and cinnamon and bake slowly. Serve with lemon sauce. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 43- TWIN MOUNTAIN MUFFINS. l /i c. butter i tsp. sugar y 4 c. milk 2 c. flour 3 tsp. baking powder 44. CHINESE MUFFINS. 2J4 C. flour 1 c. milk Yi tsp. salt 1 egg 5 tsp. baking powder £J c. hot cooked rice 2 tbsp. sugar 2 tbsp. melted butter Eix and sift dry ingredients; add one-half milk, egg well the remainder of the milk mixed with rice, and beat thor - ; then add butter. Bake in buttered gem pans about 25 VIII. Salads and Sandwiches. ! j tbsp. salt ]/ 2 tbsp. flour 1 tsp. mustard Yolks 2 eggs i l /2 tbsp. sugar i]/ 2 tbsp. melted butter Few grains cayenne 24 c - m 'lk l /4 c. vinegar Klix dry ingredients, add yolks of eggs slightly beaten, butter, and vinegar very slowly. Cook over boiling water until mix - hickens; strain and cool. 46. POTATO AND CELERY SALAD. Etwo cups boiled potatoes cut in one-half inch cubes add one - finely cut celery and medium sized apple, pared, cut in , then eighths cut in thin slices. Add dressing to moisten, e in a mound, garnish with celery tips and sections of bright les. 47. FRUIT SALAD. Arrange in four separate piles on lettuce leaf small pieces of orange, strawberries, pieces of sliced pineapple, and sliced banana. Sprinkle with lemon juice. Add dressing and garnish with whipped 45- SALAD DRESSING. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 48. MOULDED SALMON SALAD. Remove salmon from can, rinse thoroughly with hot water, and separate in flakes. Mix dry ingredients, add egg yolks, butter, milk, and vinegar. Cook over boiling water, stirring constantly until mix - ture thickens. Add gelatin soaked in cold water. Strain and add to salmon. Mould, chill, serve with cucumber sauce. 49. CUCUMBER SAUCE. Eix 1 cup stiff salad dressing and 1 cup finely chopped sweet ber pickles. If desired, one cup whipped cream may be folded : before serving. 5O. NUT AND CHEESE SANDWICHES Mix equal parts of grated cheese and chopped English walnut meats ; then season with salt and cayenne. Prepare as other sand- I can salmon Yolks 2 eggs l /i tbsp. salt iV£ tbsp. sugar Yi tbsp. flour i tsp. mustard \ l /i tbsp. melted butter 34 c. milk % c. vinegar 24 tbsp. granulated gelatin Few grains cayenne 2 tbsp. cold water </seg>
            <seg id="p031">IX. Meats and Dumplings. Make a Careful Study of the Above Diagram. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Location of the bones in the various cuts of meat. Fig. 10. Location of the bones in the various cuts of meat ■a6, thick or hip sirloin ; a6 to a8, rump piece ; a", where rump is divided op and tail end ; c. d. shoulderblade ; e. e, e, e, cross-rib piece ; f , g, in shoulder of beef; h, sternum; i, head of thighbone; k, socket; 1, ball. It is very important to spend considerable time in study of the two preceding diagrams, carefully fixing in mind the various cuts of meat. Meat contains a large amount of albumen, and should therefore be subjected to long, slow cooking after searing the surface to pre - serve the meat juices. Eie tougher and therefore cheaper cuts of meat are more digested if properly cooked. They are cheaper for two rea- Their first price is lower and there is much less waste. It will erved by looking at the chart that the most tender and finest i meat is cut from muscles which are least used. 51. BOILED I'.EF.F AND DUMPLINGS. E:ason with salt and pepper, dredge in flour, and brown the surface of a four or five pound piece from the rump or round, kettle, add water to half cover meat, cover closely and keep </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DOMESTIC SCIEKCE 33 just below boiling point for four hours. When done, remove meat strain liquid and thicken gravy. 52. DUMPLINGS. K flour 2 tsp. butter . baking powder y 4 c. milk . salt Mix and sift dry ingredients. Work in butter with the tips of fingers, add milk gradually, using a knife for mixing. Toss on a floured board, pat, and roll out to one-half inch in thickness. Shape with biscuit cutter, first dipped in flour. Place closely together in a buttered steamer put over kettle of boiling water, cover closely, and steam twelve minutes. A perforated tin pie plate may be used in place of steamer. 53. ROAST BEEF ■fhe best cuts of beef for roasting are : Tip or middle of sirloin, of rump, or first three ribs. Wipe meat, and dredge meat in pan with flour. Place in hot oven, that the surface may be quickly seared, preventing escape of inner juices. After flour in pan is browned, reduce heat, and baste with fat which has tried out ; if meat is quite lean, it may be neces - sary to put trimmings of fat in pan. Baste every ten minutes; if this rule is followed meat will be found more juicy. When meat is about half done, turn it over and dredge with flour, that skin side may be uppermost for final browning. A five pound roast will re - quire about two hours' roasting. 54. ROAST BEEF GRAVY. I Remove some fat from pan, add three tablespoons flour, and intil well browned. The flour, dredged and browned in pan, d give additional color to gravy. Add gradually, one and one - cups boiling water; cook five minutes; season with salt and :r ; strain. 55. SWISS BEEF STEAK. Eake round steak, cut from one to one and a half inches thick, id pepper and place on bread board. Pour l / 2 c. flour on one id cut this into the meat with the edge of a saucer. Turn meat </seg>
            <seg id="p034">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 34 frying pan and in this brown three slices of onion. Add the floured meat, cover with water and simmer slowly for two hours. 56. BREADED VEAL CUTLETS. Wipe the meat, remove bone and skin, then cut in pieces for serving. Sprinkle with salt and pepper, dip in crumbs. Fry slowly in salt pork fat or butter, keeping covered until well browned. 57. BAKED HEART WITH DRESSING. Wash a calf's heart, remove veins, arteries and clotted blood. Stuff with bread dressing and sew. Sprinkle with salt and pepper, roll in flour, and brown in hot fat. Place in small, deep baking pan, half cover it with boiling water, cover closely, bake slowly two hours, basting every fifteen minutes. It may be necessary to use more water. Remove heart from pan, thicken liquor with flour diluted in water, and serve. 58. DRESSING FOR HEART. ■ cracker crumbs % tsp. salt stale bread crumbs % tsp. pepper melted butter Few drops onion juice hot water Mix ingredients in order given. 5Q. MOCK BIRDS. Use pork tenderloins or boned pork chops. Place one slice of meat on board, salt and with rolling pin mash as thin as possible without breaking. Place a ball of bread dressing in center about the size of an egg. Fold the meat over from right to left and fasten with wooden toothpicks, then fasten in the end the same way. Place in dripping pan with a small amount of water and two strips of bacon. Bake from thirty to forty-five minutes according to size. When done remove meat and thicken the gravy. After spending considerable time studying the charts, draw - ing meat charts, and naming the parts, it is well to visit a meat market or cellar where meat may be examined. The local butcher if requested is very glad to give a meat demonstration. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 ■ Corn Bread; Brown Bread; Steam Pudding and Sauce 60. baked corn bread, or golden corn cake. . c. corn meal }i tsp. salt 1% c. flour 1 c. milk H c. sugar 1 egg 4 tsp. baking powder 1 tbsp. melted butter Mix and sift dry ingredients; add milk, egg well beaten, and butter ; bake in shallow buttered pan in hot oven 20 minutes. The above amount will make a cake about two inches thick, if baked in pan 6x8 inches. 6l. BOSTON BROWN BREAD I rye-meal J4 tsp. soda granulated corn meal 1 tsp. salt graham flour 24 c. molasses sour milk Mix and sift dry ingredients; add molasses and milk, stir until well mixed ; turn into a well-buttered mould, and steam three and one-half hours. The cover should be buttered before placing on mould, and then tied down with string; otherwise bread in rising might force cover. Mould should never be filled more than two-thirds full. 62. GRAHAM PUDDING. % c. butter \)/ 2 c. graham flour ■ molasses milk yi tsp. soda 1 tsp. salt 1 cup raisins, seeded and cut up. K!elt butter, add molasses, milk, egg well beaten, dry ingredi - ixed and sifted, and raisins; turn into buttered mould, cover, earn two and one-half hours. To one-half cup sugar and three tablespoons corn starch add gradually, stirring constantly, one cup boiling water. Boil two minutes. Flavor with salt and vanilla extract. 63. PUDDING SAUCE. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 XI. Cold Desserts. 64. COFFEE SPANISH CREAM. Imilk Yolk 1 egg coffee infusion Few grains salt . granulated gelatin White 1 egg p. sugar % tsp. vanilla t Scald milk, add coffee infusion, and gelatin. As soon as gela - &gt; dissolved, add yolk of egg. beaten slightly, mixed with sugar salt. Cook over hot water, stirring constantly until slightly ened; then add white of egg beaten stiff, and vanilla. Turn individual moulds, first dipped in cold water. Chill, remove 1 moulds, and serve with sugar and cream. 65. CHOCOLATE CREAM. Ic. scalded milk |J4 squares Baker's chocolate tbsp. corn starch 3 tbsp. hot water Ic. sugar Whites 3 eggs tsp. salt - 1 tsp. vanilla c. cold milk I Mix corn starch, sugar, and salt ; dilute with cold milk ; add to ed milk, and cook over hot water ten minutes, stirring con - ly until thickened ; melt chocolate, add hot water, stir until &gt;th, and add to cooked mixture ; add whites of eggs beaten and vanilla. Mould, chill, and serve with cream. Illustration showing placing of china and silver in setting the table. In using silver, use from the outside. 1. Salad fork. 2. Dinner fork. 3. Dinner knife. /i MTTt &gt; ■4. Dessert spool . O | 4(I 5. Coffee spoon. V J !!©if 6. Soup spoon. NAPKIN Edge of table </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 66. GINX.ERCAKE. B molasses I tsp. soda boiling water i)' 2 tsp. ginger 2J4 c. flour y 2 tsp. salt 4 tbsp. melted butter Add water to molasses. Mix and sift dry ingredients, combine mixtures, add butter and beat vigorously. Pour into a buttered pan and bake 25 minutes in a moderate oven. Chicken fat tried out furnishes an excellent shortening, and may be used in place of butter. This may be baked in two thin layers and put together with vellow sauce. 67. YELLOW SAUCE. 1 egg yolk yi c. powdered sugar Yi tsp. vanilla Beat yolk of egg in a bowl until thick, add sugar gradually, and add flavoring. f)X WHITE CAKE. 1 c. butter 3 c. flour 2 c. sugar Whites 4 eggs 1 c. water tsp. baking powder Cream butter and sugar. Add water and sifted dry ingredi - ents alternately, stirring well. Fold in stiftiy-beaten whites. Spread batter evenly in well greased cake tins. Bake in moderate oven fifteen to twenty minutes. 69. BOILED ICINC Stiffly beaten whites two eggs 1 c. sugar 5 marshmallows l /&gt; tsp. vanilla Yi c. boiling water Btoil sugar and water until it spins a fine thread when dropped spoon (about three minutes). Pour slowly over beaten whites, ig constantly with fork ; add the marshmallows cut in small .. Beat until cold. Add flavoring. Spread on cake. XII. Cakes and Frostings. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">DOMESTIC SCIENCE 38 7O. APPLE SAUCE CAKE. K?ream sugar and butter, add spices. In another bowl, dissolve in a little warm water and add to apple sauce. Combine the lixtures and add flour in which raisins have been dredged, and add the egg. Bake slowly in a loaf about 45 minutes. 71. MARGUERITES. Ko boiled icing add Yi c. cocoanut, c. chopped nut meats, i on crackers, bake in very slow oven until delicately browned. XIII. Pastry 72. PIE CRUST. V/2 c. flour Cold water :^p. salt. \'2 tsp. baking powder 1/3 c. lard I Mix flour, salt and baking powder thoroughly. Rub lard in tips of fingers. Moisten sufficiently to roll out. Leave crust le larger than pie tin to allow for shrinkage. Perforate top to allow escape of steam. Bake in quick oven, unless filling nds slow cooking. 73- BANBURY TARTS. 1 c. raisins 1 c. sugar 1 egg, slightly beaten 1 cracker, finely rolled Juice and grated rind 1 lemon PLone and chop raisins, add sugar, egg, cracker, and lemop. istry one-eighth inch thick, and cut pieces three and one-half long by three inches wide. Put two teaspoons of mixture h piece. Moisten edge half way round with cold water, fold press edges together with three-tined fork, first dipped in Bake 20 minutes in slow oven. i c. sugar I tsp. cinnamon 2 c. butter 2 c. flour y 2 tsp. cloves J4 tsp. salt i egg (beaten) i tsp. soda i c. unsweetened ai ile sauce i c. seeded raisins </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 39 XIV. Confections. These recipes may be furnished by the girls, each one who has a good recipe bringing it for the others to try. It may be desirable to have the candy lessons before the holidays, so that the girls may make their own Christmas candy. Bhe teacher should be careful to keep up interest in this way. Iso more economical to buy supplies in season. Bacteria, Yeasts, and Moulds. Kxperiment /j. Partly fill a sauce dish with jelly, carefully ling the top. Expose the jelly to the air of the school-room ng room. In about twenty-four hours various colored specks pots appear. Note the delicate yellows, greens, and blues. Watch the growth of these for several days, noting those which grow tall and feathery, and the others which are shiny, waxy, and low. Note also the dust-like material flying from the tall, feathery plants. We call them plants, for they grow like plants. Like plants they require warmth and moisture, and the dust-like material observed flying from the plants are their seeds. The seeds of these plants are called spores. The plants with which we are familiar all have names, and belong to different classes depending upon their different character - istics. These very small plants in the jelly are also divided into classes and have names. All of the smallest and simplest plants are in the first class and are named Bacteria. Klacteria are so small that a single plant can be seen only by &lt;e of a microscope to magnify it many times. They take their from the air or surrounding material, then give off as waste cts gases or liquids. These waste products may do harm or In the case of ptomaine poisoning we see the harm they do. ier common example of the work of bacteria is the souring of In the second class are found the yeast plants with which we II familiar. We put the yeast in the bread. It grows, and growing throws off alcohol and a gas which is called carbon le. The bubbles of gas cannot break through, so they raise hole mass of dough. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 40 The third class are the moulds which form a velvet-like sub - stance in bread, on meat, leather; and canned goods. Other forms of mould are mildew, ringworm, and moulds on the skin. We performed some experiments which show favorable and unfavorable temperatures for the growth of these plants. Sunlight and draughts of air retard or destroy germ life. We conclude then that the best way to avoid germ life in food is either to keep the food in a refrigerator or very cold place, or else to boil or bake it before using. The best way to avoid the germ life in the vari - ous rooms of the house is to thoroughly air the rooms, admit all the sunlight possible, and keep as free from dust as possible. I Ml that has been said of the house applies to the barns and rooms as well. Attention will be called later to the pure food which are requiring cleanliness in the handling of milk, butter, and all foods. Canning and Preserving. Successful canning and preserving depends first upon the de - struction of all bacteria, yeasts, and moulds, present in the veg - etable or fruit ; and secondly upon perfect sealing so that no new germ is admitted. Great care must be taken in order to prevent the spoiling of any foods kept for winter use. The first precaution is to use earthen or graniteware utensils, and to use silver or wooden spoons only, for stirring. The second precaution is to thoroughly cook the material so that all germ life is thoroughly destroyed. Khe third precaution is to cleanse thoroughly with boiling the glass or can in which the material is to be kept, to fill the :eptacle over full while the material is at boiling temperature, seal the receptacle at once. Kegetables are prepared as for sauce, observing all the pre - is noted above. There are many ways of keeping fruits for winter use. ( I ) Jellies — Cooked fruit juice and sugar in equal amounts. (2) Marmalades — The pulp and juice of fruits with equal amounts of sugar. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 (3) Canning and Preserving — Sterilized fruit sweetened to (4) Pickling — Preserving in salt or acid liquor. RASPBERRIES. 12 quarts raspberries 2 quarts sugar Put 2 quarts of the fruit in the preserving kettle, heat slowly on the stove; crush with a vegetable masher; spread a square of cheesecloth over a bowl, and turn the crushed berries and juice into it. Press out the juice, then turn juice into the preserving kettle. Add the sugar and put on the stove; stir until the sugar is dis - solved. When the sirup begins to boil, add the remaining 10 quarts of berries. Let them heat slowly. Boil ten minutes, counting from the time they begin to bubble. Skim well while boiling. Put in cans and seal as directed. Banners* Bulletin No. 203. This bulletin may be obtained by t from the U. S. Department of Agriculture. CURRANTS. \2 quarts currants 4 quarts sugar Treat the same as raspberries. CHERRIES. Karts cherries l /t pint water arts sugar Ileasure the cherries after the stems have been removed. Stone or not as you please. If you stone them be careful to save : juice. Put the sugar and water in the preserving kettle and ver the fire until the sugar is dissolved. Put in the cherries eat slowly to the boiling point. Boil ten minutes, skimming FROSTED CHERRIES. Dip sweet, ripe cherries which have not been stemmed into stiffiy-beaten egg white. Immediately dip into granulated sugar. Let dry about twenty minutes. Serve as dessert. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 GRAPES. 6 quarts grapes (stemmed) % C. water I quart sugar Bjueeze the pulp of the grapes out of the skin. Cook the ve minutes and then rub through a sieve that is fine enough i back the seeds. Put water, skins, and pulp into the pre - l kettle and heat slowly to the boiling point. Skim the fruit en add the sugar. Boil fifteen minutes. PEACHES. 8 quarts peaches (pared and i quart sugar halved) 3 quarts water Bare the peaches, cut in halves, and remove the stones, unless efer to can the fruit whole. Kut the sugar and water together and stir over the fire until gar is dissolved. When the sirup boils, skim it. Draw the back where the sirup will keep hot but not boil. | 5 ut a layer of the prepared fruit into the preserving kettle and with some of the hot sirup. When the fruit begins to boil, carefully. Boil gently for ten minutes, then put in the jars, eal. If the fruit is not thoroughly ripe it may require a little r time to cook. It should be so tender that it may be pierced with a silver fork. It is best to put only one layer of fruit e preserving kettle. While this is cooking the fruit for the batch may be prepared. INVALID COOKING AND HOME NURSING. Kfwo-thirds of all disease is caused from eating the wrong of food or food improperly cooked. To cure such disease a rted diet is of as great importance as medicine. fis of great importance in caring for the sick or convalescent :ct the cleanest and daintiest of glass, china, silver, and linen arranging the tray. Kis important also to serve easily digested foods. Liquid milk, lemonade, fruit juices, oatmeal water, beef tea, and ;s are among the best. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 The semi-solid foods are the gruels made from corn meal, oat meal. Imperial Granum, flour, starch, crackers, or arrowroot. They are heat producing. Care should be taken not to serve them when there is inflammation of the stomach or intestines. Eeatest care must be exercised in the giving of solid foods, lly during convalescence. The danger is that too much, will •n. Among the best foods are fresh eggs cooked soft, dry Ik toast, chicken cooked until the flesh falls from the bone, Is, ices, and ice creams. High seasonings should be avoided. BASKET LUNCHES. To the subject of lunches a great deal of attention should be given. School lunches may be much more attractive than they often are. Note the value of a clean cloth napkin or a white paper nap - kin. Bread should be thinly sliced, and evenly buttered. If sand - wiches are desired, the cold meat should be evenly sliced, or finely chopped. Hard-boiled egg may be chopped and seasoned. Lettuce sandwiches and a little salad-dressing make the lunch more pal - atable. Some jelly, jam, or sauce may be conveniently carried in a jelly glass. Fruit is easily carried and is more nutritious than a sweet of any kind. HOUSEHOLD PESTS. ■'xperiment 14. Gather all available material on insects, col - l the dry, alcoholic (animal dropped in a small bottle of alco - and live specimens, also pictures of them. The dry specimens 1 be pinned to a thin board by a long, sharp pin. Ehe common insects injurious or disagreeable to persons are itoes, flies, bedbugs, and fleas. Those injurious to food are aches, ants, mice, rats, and others. Insects injurious to g or fabrics are moths, silver-fish, carpet beetles and crickets. ■rhe best ways of getting rid of these pests should be looked up discussed in class. If the subject is carefully handled no se will be given and good results will come. Kfhe importance of cleanliness should be emphasized here. The hat most of these insects breed in damp and filthy places should iphasized and the conclusion drawn that if the back door yard, </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 * l. ~* W1 *■! * i 11 i • 1 1 t minimum of disease and annovance. PURE FOOD. Ewing to the fact that all people must suffer from impurities i, steps have been taken by both the national government and ite government to prevent these impurities as far as possible. In this state there is a Food, Drug, and Dairy Commission to earn- on this work. Their work is to see that no misbranded food, decomposed foods, or foods containing poisonous chemicals are offered for sale. Under the pure food laws it is "unlawful to use or employ in and about the keeping or handling of any milk, cream, or dairy products to be used as food, any pail, can, vessel, churn, separator, or other implement which is in an unclean or unsanitary condi- 1 tion ; or to operate any creamery or factory in the manufacture of any dairy products which is in an unclean condition. I 'It shall be unlawful to knowingly sell or offer for sale any or cream from diseased or unhealthy cows, or from cows kept filthy or unsanitary condition. Milk shall contain not less three per centum of butter fat and cream shall contain not han eighteen per centum of butter fat." In connection with the study of pure food discuss the care of the barns, dairy cows, and poultry. Also emphasize the need of cleanness of all pails, utensils, separators, etc.. used in handling the milk. Keferences: Nebraska State Food Laws; U. S. Dept. of Agri. of Experiment Stations, Standards of Purity for Food Prod- U. S. Dept. of Agri. Bureau of Chemistry, Bulletin No. ioo; X)k of the Department of Agriculture for 1904. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DOMESTIC SCIEXCE 45 SEWING. A course in sewing properly taught begins with the funda - mental stitches. The youngest child in school can learn these stitches and no young woman in any school is so old or so skilled in needle work that she can not profit by reviewing and studying the stitches until each one can be perfectly made. The lessons which are presented in succeeding pages are adapted for work in the school room, at home, or the girls may work in small groups with the teacher or some other interested person after school hours or on Saturday. Kor the work requiring samples, the school may furnish them tie instances, or each child may be asked to bring suitable al from home. Sphere the work is carried on in the school room and during hours it is recommended that one lesson only of thirty to five minutes duration be given each week, and that but little :mpted in each lesson. Do only what can be well done. Where advisable the children may make a second sampler at home, using the first as a guide. Khe pieces of work when finished should be carefully laundered arked with the pupil's name, age, and address. There are eight fundamental stitches which will be studied. Rixxing and Overcasting Materials required : Percale, 6 inches long and 3 inches wide. Thread, No. 60 white cotton. Needle, No. 9. RUNNING. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 tioi n ucin^ idKcn ™~* 'S pssscci o\ cr cucti time. /\DOUt ten stitcncs to an inch is an average size running stitch. Thread the needle, having at least twelve inches of thread, and a very small knot at the end of the thread. Begin at the right side of the cloth at the point marked (i) and take very even, fine stitches to (2). Fasten the end by taking an extra stitch on top of the last stitch. Leave one-half inch of thread. Kepeat, beginning at (3) and sewing to (4) making the second *ter than the first. M ,5, ,2. .1. I. ■ 01 ■ OVERCASTING. I Overcasting is a series of even, loose stitches over a raw edge, ■event ravelling. Take a thread about twenty-four inches in h, tying the small knot at the end of the thread. Begin at point and sew over and over, taking the stitches one-fourth of an down from the edge of the cloth. Take four or five stitches time on the needle before drawing the thread through. At point (6) leave one inch of thread after smoothing the material to see that the thread does not draw. Turn the material around and repeat, beginning at (7) and overcasting to (8). </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 Basting and Hemming Materials required: Piece of crash 6 inches long and 3 inches wide. Thread, No. 50 white cotton. Needle, No. 10. Trim edges of material evenly, and corners square, leaving no frayed edges. Hold material wrong side up. Begin at ( 1 ) and turn the edge in % inch, creasing with the fingernail. Go back to (1) and fold again, creasing firmly. Basting. Basting is sewing to hold materials in place for fitting or final sewing. The stitches are even, and take up as much material as is passed over. Khread a needle with about eighteen inches of thread, tying JtS. ■Begin at (1) leaving one inch of thread, taking stitches J4 long, and straight through the center of the hem. Leave an inch of thread at (2). Do not fasten the basting Kurn material around and repeat, beginning at (3) and finish- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Hemming. I'hread the needle, using about eighteen inches of thread. Tie ot. Begin at (i), hold the needle on a line with the material, up one thread of the cloth and one of the fold. In beginning one inch of thread which is put under edge of hem and sewed Make the stitches as close as possible, slanting and as nearly )le on the right side as possible. After completing, finish side ) (4) in same way. Materials required: Cross-bar muslin, 6 inches long and 4 inches wide. Thread, No. 80 white cotton Xeedle, No. 10. But the cross-bar muslin in two pieces, each 6 inches long and es wide. Trim evenly on all sides, leaving no frayed edges, lat all corners are perfect. Carefully turn, baste, and hem sides (1) to (2), (3) to (4), (5) to (6), and (7) to (8) according to the directions in the last Overhanding is the sewing together of folds or selvedges with small stitches taken over the edges. Kaste together pieces (A) and (B), holding the right sides er with edges (4) to (3) and (5) to (6) together. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 (Thread the needle, tying a very small knot. Begin at the point re (4) and (5) are joined, insert the needle at (4) and straight ugh (5), keeping the needle at right angles with the goods and point toward you. Take up only two threads at a time on each ;. When finished fasten end firmly by taking three stitches, over the other, and cut thread close to work. Open the seam thus made, and press flat with the fingernail. Baste the strip of lace on the side (1) to (2), holding right sides together with the lace toward you. Begin at point (1). Care must be taken to hold the lace loosly enough so the lace will not draw after the overhanding. After basting, the same overhanding on seam (4) to (3) and (5) to (6) is used to sew the lace on the material. Take very fine stitches. Draw out bastings and open the seam, pressing firmly. Stitching and Backstitching. Materials required : Calico, 6 inches long and 3 inches wide. Thread, No. 60 white cotton. Needle, No. 7. Cut material in two pieces, each 6 inches long and \ l / 2 inches wide. Straighten and trim the edges, and square the corners. hi a Ikl a Ill (4) B pieces with right sides together, and baste ft inch from along the sides (1) to (2) and (3) to (4). STITCHING. ■Pitching is a series of long forward stitches and short upper stitches. K Beginning at (1), J4 inch from the edge of the cloth, take a forward under stitch. On the upper side set the needle back alf the length of the first stitch and repeat. Begin at (3) and repeat to (4). Overcast all sides to the depth of l /k inch. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BACKSTITCH! NG. Beginning at (5), take a long forward under stitch. &lt; &gt;n the upper side set the needle hack the full length of the first stitch Begin at (~) and repeat to (8) Felled Seam Materials required : Soft nmslin. (1 inches long and 4 inches wide. Thread. Xo. So white cotton. Needle. No. &lt;j. Cut the muslin in two pieces, each (&gt; inches long and 2 inches wide. Trim evenly on all sides, leaving no frayed edges. See that all corners are square A felled seam is a seam which is hemmed down to conceal the ■ sides together, below the other. Stitch carefully. Trim one of the edges l /i and fold the wider edge over the narrow. Baste the folded seam flat on the material and hem. making the ■ as possible, and as small 1 m the right side stitches as close together </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Buttonholes and Buttons Materials required : Striped gingham. 8 inches wide and 4 inches long Buttons. 3 four-holed pearl. Thread. Xo. 50 white Needle, X&lt;&gt;. 7. Edit the gingham in two pieces, each 4 inches wide and 4 inches trimming edges neatly. Turn in one long side of each piece inch on the wrong side. Turn in again one inch, baste, and with very tine, even stitches. This makes three thicknesse- of for the buttons and buttonholes. |&gt;n one piece mark off three places for buttonholes. Find the 1 of the button, put the ix&gt;ints of the scissors !4 inch from the of the material and cut along a thread the exact size the but - &gt;le is to be. Begin at the edge farthest from the folded edge and overhand the edges of the buttonhole closely, taking the stitches three threads deep. Have no knot. Begin at the same place, put the needle in the material with the point toward you. draw it half way through, take the two threads at the eye of the needle and carry them under the needle from the right. Draw the needle out so the thread is drawn from you to bring the loop thus made to the raw edge. Have the stitches an even distance apart. K'ork around the corner by slanting the stitches so the button - rounding at the end. When the end is finished, work across e to the point opjxjsite where the buttonhole was started. E'his end is finished with a bar. To make the bar. draw the • down through the first loop, then up through the last one, raw the stitch tight to bring the sides of the buttonhole close ler. Take three more stitches in the same place. Work four ihole stitches over these threads, having the loop on the edge buttonhole. Draw the thread through on the wrong side and firmlv. Make the other three buttonholes in the same way. Bl'TTONlIOLF </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 BUTTONS. K locate the buttons, pin the material with the buttonholes on ce to be used for the buttons with the two hems exactly ping. Kith pins indicate the location of the button. The center of ton should come in the circular end of the buttonhole. Kfter the four buttons are located, and it is certain the buttons ttonholes will be opposite when finished, then sew on the first |)ouble the thread and tie a small knot in the end. Put the : through from the right side first, then back through the but - i order to hide the knot. Place a pin across the top of the 1 and sew over it, always keeping the threads straight and rig parallel with the direction of the buttonhole. Sew through pair of holes five times; take the pin out, then bring the i out between material and button and wind the thread around titches underneath the button several times. This prevents Jttonhole wearing the threads through so quickly. Sew the remaining three buttons on in the same way. Button the two pieces together. Dorothy Seam on Flannel Materials required : Flannel, 6 inches long and 4 inches wide Thread, white silk A. White binding ribbon, 6 inches. Needle, No. 10. Cut the flannel in two pieces, each 6 inches long and 2 inches wide. Baste together, matching the figure. Backstitch the seam J4 ' ncn from edge of material. With just a warm iron press the seam open. Lay the binding ribbon on the wrong side of the flannel with the center of the ribbon over the seam. Baste. Hem the edge of the ribbon down to the flannel with very fine stitches. Be careful that the stitches do not show on the right side. Draw out the bast - ings and press again. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 Hooks and Eyes. Materials required : Black percaline, 4 inches long and 8 inches wide. Hooks and eyes, 3 No. 2 black. Thread, No. 50 black cotton. Needle, No. 7. If rim material evenly on all sides and cut in two pieces, each 4 s long and 3 inches wide. Turn in one long side of each piece ich on the wrong side. Turn in again one inch, baste, and hem very fine even stitches. This makes three thicknesses of cloth he hooks and eyes. Draw out the bastings and overcast the three sides of each piece, according to the directions for asting. HOOKS. Thread the needle and tie a very small knot. 11 one piece of the percaline mark off three places for hooks, 1 distance apart. Set the hook in J4 ' ncn from the edge of &gt;ds, hold firmly in place and take one stitch through each the hook and five stitches back of the patent hump to keep d of the hook firmly in place. Then take five stiches through : the loops, fasten the thread well and cut close to work. Sew on the other two hooks in the same way. EYES. II"o locate the eyes, pin the material with the hooks to the piece : used for the eyes with the edges of the two hems exactly ing. Indicate by marking with a pencil the places where the are to be sewed on. Let each eye project just far enough over dge of the material to allow the hook to catch in the eye easily. Efien certain that the eye is in just the right position accord - he cut, catch it in place by taking a stitch through each loop, ike three stitches at each side of the eye on the edge of the These should be very small stitches, but firm to keep the m shifting. Then take five stitches through each loop and thread firmly. Cut thread close to material, and sew the wo eyes on in the same way. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 tLoor Stitch, Fkathkr Stitch. Fhekch Knot. aterials required : ( iray flannel, 4 inches square Kmbroidery silk, light blue. Needle. Trim edges of the material and have the corners square. LOOP STITCH. Biread the needle with the blue embroidery silk, and make a nail knot. Work on the right side from left to right, begin - (I). Take the first stitch % inch from the edge. Hold the in place with the left thumb, and take straight up and down i % inch in length, each time bringing the needle out over ead. Finish the four sides of the flannel with this stitch. FKATHKR STITCH. Thread the needle with the embroidery silk, and following the ■irefully work three rows of the feather stitching from (5) to (9) to ( 10). and (7) to (8). FRENCH KNOTS. Thread the needle with the embroidery silk, and tie a small knot. Then bring the needle through at (4). leaving the knot on </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 Irong side. Work on the right side of the flannel. Take up a short stitch, one thread, keeping it on the needle. Take hold e two threads a short distance from the eye of the needle and them twice around the i&gt;oint of the needle from right to left, the needle through, holding the stitch firmly in place with ft thumb. I'm the needle in at the same point it was brought out. B'ontinue along the four sides of the material, working a h knot in the center of each of the loop stitches. Two holders, one a small square one to be worn at the belt while cooking, the other a long one for handling large kettles and baking dishes, are always useful. I To make the small one, cut a piece of blue denim or bed j ~ inches wide and i8'/&gt; inches long. Turn in l/ &gt; inch on the &gt;ng sides and on one short side. Press firmly. Then fold the three times so there are no raw edges and the piece when I is 6 inches square. 2. Baste '4 inch from edge on all four sides. Overhand. Draw out bastings. 3. To keep the holder firm and in shape stitch in two diagonal rowi from comer to corner, crossing in the center of the holder. 4. Sew a piece of tape ' 4 yard long on one corner of the holder. Fasten to the belt of the apron with a safety pin. 5. To make the long holder, cut a piece of denim or bedtick - ing ' _■ yard long and 1/3 yard wide. Turn in ' i&gt; inch on all sides. Draw out the bastings. HULDKKS. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Sofa Pillow Cover. riere are so many possibilities for pretty and useful sofa covers that if the choice of material, color, design and size to each girl the resulting assortment is very beautiful. Ifo secure uniformity which sometimes seems advisable it is for the instructor to recommend the general points to be ob - d in making the pillows. I\ white pillow, either square or oblong, worked or embroid - in white and finished with a white ruffle or plaiting, a white or left plain, is very dainty and is useful as well. Phese covers should be sewed up on three sides and the raw bound with a narrow bias strip of the material. In case the ial is too heavy it is better to use muslin or cambric for this g. Hem the edges of the open side, and finish with at least buttons and buttonholes. When the top is completed, launder it carefully. Kese pillows make pretty gifts, especially to be used in baby and cribs, and for invalids. </seg>
            <seg id="p057"/>
            <seg id="p058">58 l&gt;cli.r." making the petticoat you will have to take your meas - ure and block out a pattern. Klie petticoat requires &lt;&gt; inches more than twice the length of skirt, and a piece of muslin cut lengthwise for a band. 2V2 wide and 2' _. inches longer than your waist measure. White 1. outing flannel or seersucker may l&gt;e used for making the Have someone take two measurements: The first one the length the skirt is to be when finished, the second your hip measure taken four inches helow the waist line. Table of Measi'dements. Top of liottom of Top of Bottom of 3 '.. 4-I4 7 9'A ::-'_■ ."■ T-'_. 10 i U-4M 4 :,-' , - 10-".^ ■ he pattern in the cut is made for those whose hip measure - is 2(&gt; to 30 inches and who wish the ])etticoat 26 inches long finished. Three-eighths of an inch is allowed for seams. To make the pattern, rule a piece of plain paper in two-inch squares, then copy the pattern from the scale to the ruled sheet. In the table of measurements the tap of the front is measured along the line "bd." which is 4 inches below the waist line. The bottom of the front is measured along the line "ce" and the length of your skirt on "ac" and "gf." The top of the side gore is meas - ured on "km" and the bottom of the side on "lm." If your hip ■Measure is not between 26 and 30 inches, find the correct measure in the table and make your pattern accordingly. If your measure is an odd number of inches, take the next higher number in making your pattern. After cutting the pattern carefully, fold your goods through the center with selvedges together. First cut a straight piece 29 inches long for the back, if the skirt is to be 26 inches long when finished. Xext pin the pattern marked "front"' with the straight edge on the fold of the goods. Cut the cloth 3 inches longer than the pattern to allow for a hem. Directions r&gt;r Making the Petticoat. ■ Front. Frost Side. Side. :; (Ixll 4', (eel 6-U (RM 1 9(In) </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 ■'lace the pattern for the "side" on the remaining goods, allow - inches on the lxittom for hem. Pin carefully and cut out. If you wish the petticoat longer than 26 inches when finished, allow the extra length when making your pattern. to make the skirt, baste the front to the straight edges of the are. Baste the straight back piece on the side pieces, leaving ft side open ten inches to allow the skirt to slip over the lers. Gather the top of the skirt twice. Try the petticoat on, [C most of the gathers in the back with enough over the hips the skirt tit smoothly. Stitch seams and overcast them. Ein to the band. Baste the band on the wrong side first, then n the right side and baste. Stitch. Finish the band with a and buttonhole. Kuril up a 3-inch hem evenly around the bottom. If of flannel y hand, otherwise on the machine &lt;&gt;r by hand. Overcast all Rhe petticoat may be trimmed or not as you desire. Tucks t put in the petticoat or there may be a gathered flounce which mied with ruffles, tucks, insertion, edging or insertion and Shirt Waists. I The girls in some counties have been interested in the making lirt waists. A good way to make a shirt waist is to do the tuck- Mid sewing in of lace or insertion before cutting out. Use a .. well-fitting pattern. Determine on the design and measure naterial on the pattern. Do the tucking first, then by laying kc pattern determine just how long to cut each strip of lace, r sewing in the lace or embroidery, pin the pattern carefully in : and cut out, making all notches and perforations. Match and baste the side and shoulder seams and try on. Fit carefully by making necessary changes at these seams. French seam the waist and sleeves and bind the arm's eye. Adjust the neck band and finish the lower edge with a narrow hem. The fullness at the back should be gathered at the waist, and confined in tapes. The tapes should be stitched across the back and to the side seams. They should be long enough to tie in front. The front of the waist can be pulled in place under them, and a waist finished in this way </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 DOMESTIC SCIENCE is easier to iron than when gathered into a belt. For a stout per - son it is better to adjust the fullness at the waist line and finish with a fitted peplum. Garden Hat Directions for making : I 'he pattern for a garden hat is on the opposite page. On the each square equals two inches. To make the pattern, rule :e of plain paper in two-inch squares, then copy the pattern the scale to the ruled sheet. After making a careful drawing three pieces, cut them out carefully. Khe hat requires i l / 2 yards of 27-inch material, or i*4 yards inch. Pink and white or blue and white checked gingham is mended. White goods or embroidery may be used if desired. Three-eighths of an inch is allowed for seams. In cutting the brim (A) cut an inside and an outside piece, and if the goods is very thin cut an interlining of white muslin. Stitch together the sections for the brim along the outer edges and ends, turn right side out and finish the head edge with a narrow binding ; lap the ends of the brim }i inch and close with buttons and buttonholes. Sew small buttons to upper side of brim at the single eyelets. Line the tabs and work a buttonhole in each at the single eyelet. Work button - holes at the points indicated by eyelets. Hem the ties, and fasten to each side of the brim underneath at the second eyelet from the closing. There are many other things that might be made by the pupils working at home, at school, or in small groups. Kensington bags are dainty and useful and many pretty designs can be worked out. Some of the simplest bags are the prettiest if nicely made. Fancy aprons are always attractive and useful. I Work in patching and darning should be done and the children uraged throughout the year to keep their own clothing in repair, ord from the teacher now and then is enough to restore many rment. ■Practical lessons in the care of clothing are more needed than Y of us have ever thought. </seg>
            <seg id="p061"/>
            <seg id="p062">DOMESTIC SCIENCE I &gt; i. •, </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>