<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Eighth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1925-02-02">1925-02-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 2, 1925 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U- S- A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor here - with to submit the Thirty-eighth Annual Report of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, February 2, 1925. Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Lincoln, February 2, 1925 Mr. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station: Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirty-eighth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Adam McMullen, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY I Hon. George N. SEYMOUR, President, Elgin. ...Term expires January, 1927 Hon. Frank J. Taylor, St. Paul Term expires January! 1927 Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Term expires January, 1929 HON. Wm. P. Warner, V. P., Dakota City Term expires January! 1929 Hon. John R. Webster, Omaha Term expires January, 1931 Hon. Earl M. Cline, Lincoln Term expires January Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor 1931 •L. E. Gunderson, Finance Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. Burnett, D. Sc., Director W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Assistant Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service R. P. Crawford, B. A., Agricultural Editor W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. Ackerson, M. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry Arthur Anderson, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy M. J. BLISH, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry E. E. BRACKETT, B. Sc. IN E. E., Associate in Agricultural Emjn "a E. M. Brouse, B. Sc, Snpt. Experimental Substation, Valentini W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy (Chairman) H. P. DAVIS, M. Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman ) P. A. DOWNS, Ph. D., Associate in Dairy Husbandi it H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Rural Economics (Chairman I H. D. FOX, M. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry R. W. Goss, M. Sc, Associate in Plant Pathology H. J. GRAMLICH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) J. A. Holden, B. Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Miteht T. A. KlESSELBACH, PH. D., Agronomy W. J. LOEFFEL, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry W. E. LYNESS, B. Sc IN Agr., Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V. M. D., A. M., Assistant in Animal Patholog d Hygiene B. I. MASUROVSKY, M. Sc, Graduate Assistant in Dairy Husbandry R. F. MORGAN, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry F. E. MUSSEHL, B. Sc, Poultry Husbandry F. R. NOHAVF.C, B. SC IN A. E., A taint art in Agricultural Eng nny G. L. Peltier, Ph. D., Plant Pathology J. O. RANKIN, A. M., Associate in Rural Economics J. C. RUSSEL, M. Sc, Associate in Agronomy Rudolph Sandstedt. B. Sc, Analyst O. W. SJOGREN, B. Sc. IN A. E., Agricultural Engineering (Ckmirwm W. P. SNYDER, M. S., Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology (Chairman ) L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene (Chairman) H. O. WERNER, M. Sc. Assistant in Horticulture DON B. WHELAN. M. Sc, Assistant in Entomology C. C. WlGGANS, PH. D., Horticulture (Chairman ) **L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte •Bv an act of the Leiriilature of the State of NVI.ra-ka approved and in effect February 15. 1899. the State Treasurer became &lt;x ofiirio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1. 1 «'•'!' ••Detailed from the Office of Dry Land Agriculture. United States Department of Agriculture. Washington. D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS Page Letter of Transmittal 8 Governor's Certificate 8 The Official Roster of the Station 4 Contents 5-6 Investigational Work • Agricultural Engineering: Traitor Testing • Plow Draft Investigations... ; • Poultry House Ventilation and Construction 9 Animal Diseases: Hemorrhagic Septicemia 10 An Inquiry into the Source of Tuberculosis of Swine 10 Current Laboratory Examinations 11 Dairy Husbandry: Roughage for Dairy Cows 11 Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making 11 Study of Weight in Dairy Cattle 12 Field Crops and Soils: Corn Breeding 12 Water Requirements of Crops 13 Small Grains 13 Forage Crops 14 Soil Fertility 14 The Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, and Soil Condi - tion to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils 15 Parallelisms between the Glacial and Loess Soils of South - eastern Nebraska 16 Soil Tilth 16 Effect of Lime on the Physical Properties of the Soil 16 Investigation of the Soils of the Proposed Central Nebraska Supplemental Irrigation Project 16 Relation of the Organic Matter and Nitrogen Content of Prairie Soils to Soil Types 17 Loss of Organic Matter and Nitrogen under Cultivation 17 Fruit Production : Pruning Tree Fruits, Grapes, Small Fruits 17 Orchard Culture _ 18 Vegetable Experimentation 18 Insect Control: Control of Injurious Insects, Animals, and Birds 18 The Life History of Several Common Cutworms 19 Nursery, Orchard, and Greenhouse Stock Inspection 19 Grasshopper Control 19 Livestock Feeding: Cattle — Effect of Age upon Rate and Economy of Gain 18 Baby Beef Production 20 Summer Cattle Feeding 21 Lambs — Fall Lamb Feeding... 22 Spring Lamb Feeding 22 Hogs — Wheat for Fattening Pigs 23 Summer Pig Feeding 23 Summer Hog Feeding 23 White vs. Yellow Corn for Fattening Hogs 24 Simple Mineral Supplements for Fattening Hogs 24 Milling and Baking Quality of Wheat 24 Glutenin Determination 25 Identity of Gluten Proteins from Different Flours 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">CONTENTS (Continued) Page Nutrition : Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks 25 A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding 26 Studies in Fat Soluble A as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds. Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey . 27 Plant Diseases: A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the De - velopment of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host 27 A Study of Fusarium Wilt and Tuber Rot of the Irish Potato in Reference to the Relation of Environmental Conditions to the Infection and Progress of the Disease 2&gt; The Influence of Environmental Conditions on the Transmis - sion of Seed Borne Diseases, Including the Potato 29 Potatoes: Seed Potato Selection 30 A Study in Degeneracy in Potatoes 30 Poultry Production: Inheritance of Egg Production I] Turkey Production ;{1 Rural Economics: Farm Management Survey Farm Tenure Cost of Producing Farm Crops Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and Pur chasing Power of Farm Products The Farm Land Problem Co-operative Agricultural Organizati n&gt; Serum Production North Platte Substation Agronomy Crop Improvements Beef Cattle Dairy Cattle Pork Production Sudan Grass Pasture Union Fruit Farm Scottsbluff Substation Pastures Sweet Clover Hogs Lamb Feeding. Poultry Valentine Substation Dairying Clover Projects . Soy Beans ta Small Grains » Forage Crops 3« Pasture Crops 38 Turkey Project :!s Changes in Station Staff SB Publications .• 39 Technical Articles 41 Accepted for Publication 41 Acknowledgments 41 Financial Statement 42 The Purnell Act 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT During the period covered by this report, every depart - ment of the Experiment Station has made splendid progress. Important information and exact knowledge contributing to the welfare not only of agriculture but of society as a whole have been obtained. A number of investigations have been completed and the results assembled and published. Several new lines of investigation have been undertaken. The demand for exact information along many lines has been increasing rapidly during the past several years. There are probably several factors that contribute to this increas - ing demand for information. The price of farm lands has greatly increased over what it was some years ago. This, together with the general agricultural depression of the last few years, has probably brought more clearly to the attention of the farmer the problems that confront him. Further - more, as the agriculture of a section becomes older there is an increasing number of handicaps to be overcome. The fertility of the soil becomes less, the crop yields are corre - spondingly lower, and the management of the land becomes more difficult. As the animal and plant population increase and are kept within the same area for a longer period of time, the ravages of diseases become greater. Furthermore, the narrow margin of profit under which the farmer operates makes it imperative that he be ever watchful for more pro - ductive strains and varieties of crop plants, better livestock, better methods of production of all farm products, and better means of control for the diseases and insect enemies. The farmer looks to the Agricultural Experiment Station for this knowledge. With his narrow margin of profit he cannot afford to experiment, for experimentation is costly. There must be some agency that will try out the new varieties, work out the new methods, and develop the new means of disease control. The purpose of the Experiment Station is to get this information for the farmer, and to that end it is working to the full extent of its resources. It is not possible for the Experiment Station to investi - gate promptly all of the farmers' problems. Some, which to Acknowledgment is due to Assistant DirecUtr W. W. Burr for the preparation of his Report. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the individual or to the State as a whole may be of great importance, cannot be taken up at once. It is necessary to limit the number of projects under investigation to the resources of the Station. If the resources were greater, a greater amount of investigation could be carried on. However, it is good administration not to undertake more work than can be well done by the personnel and funds avail - able at a given time. It is realized that the effort on some of the problems now under way should be increased and that other important problems should be undertaken. This can only be done thru an increased support of the Experiment Station or thru the release of men and funds by the com - pletion of lines of work now under way. There is a considerable amount of routine work coming to the Experiment Station which seems necessary to be done but which neither falls within the field of research nor con - tributes material to the research program. Such work con - sists largely of plant and insect specimens sent in for identi - fication and general information concerning them; plant and animal disease specimens for diagnosis and suggested control ; seed to be tested for purity and germination ; samples of soils, commercial feed, poisons, grains, and so on, for various analyses. The Experiment Station under - takes to care for such requests as fall within its proper field. It does not, however, undertake to test seed for germination and purity, as the State Agricultural Department maintain* a seed laboratory for that purpose. Where samples for analysis have a community rather than an individual inter - est the Experiment Station undertakes such analytical work, but it does not do general analytical work of a private nature. If there seems to be sufficient reason for doing such work the cost of the analysis is charged to the individual. Fortunately, very few changes in the Experiment Station staff were made during the past year. This is an important matter in the Experiment Station service. The greatest results of research work are generally obtained thru long periods of continuous service of the individual staff member. INVESTIGAT1ONAL WORK The investigational work of the Experiment Station is sup - ported by both Federal and State funds. In this report no attempt is made to distinguish between the investigations receiving their support from different funds. The financial statement showing the expenditure of the various funds </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 9 allotted to the Experiment Station is given later on in this report. The following brief summary shows most of the problems now under investigation at the Experiment Station. With the space possible in a report of this kind details cannot be given. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Tractor Testing. — This work has been continued during the past year, in accordance with the Nebraska Tractor Test - ing law. Ten tractors were tested during the year, and reports of the results have been prepared and are available &gt;r those interested. This work was followed very closely by the farm equipment manufacturing industry, and many important improvements have been noted in tractors since the work was begun. Plow Draft Investigations. — During the year, this work has been continued with the view of determining the effect )il moisture and soil compaction on the draft of a plow; also means of measuring the condition of the soil so that the tilth of the soil can be measured and the draft of the plow be fairly accurately predicted. The earth plat used for this work was successively compacted to varying degrees of compaction. Following this, water was added to the soil, successively in amounts equivalent to one-half inch of rain for each series of tests, thus varying the moisture content from 12 per cent to a little over 20 per cent. The data secured indicate that at low compaction the variation in moisture has very little effect on the draft of a plow. At higher compaction the draft decreased slightly with each increase in moisture up to about 17 per cent. As the moisture increased from this point, the plow draft in - creased slightly. The draft increased uniformly with the increase in the degree of compaction and shows an increase of about 80 per cent from a compaction of 64 pounds per cubic foot of soil to a compaction of 76 pounds per cubic foot. Poultry House Ventilation and Construction. — (Co-oper - ative-Agricultural Engineering and Poultry Husbandry.) Three houses 20 x 20 feet square, each containing 100 hens, were compared for temperature, humidity, and ventilation. Carbon dioxide determinations were made and egg produc - tion was recorded. One house contained a brooder stovi which was used during severe weather in an effort to main - tain even temperatures. One was lined with sheet rock and </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station equipped with storm sash, and closed to cut off all ventilation from 4:00 P. M. to 7:00 A. M. each day. One had no arti - ficial heat or lining and had standard ventilation. Egg production, during a 14-day period, in the heated house exceeded that in the check house, which was unlined and had full ventilation, by 51 eggs from a flock of 100 hens. The increased production exceeded the cost of heating by about $3 for 52 days. The house which was lined but un - heated gave an egg production almost the same as the heated house. Lack of ventilation during the night did not appear to affect production adversely. Since the close of the fiscal year being reported, thesj houses have been removed to a new location. Four of them are having steam heat installed for constant temperature and this study will be enlarged during the next fiscal year. ANIMAL DISEASES Hemorrhagic Septicemia (Fowl Cholera). — Very little progress was made on this project during the past year. The experimental work that has been done led to the trials of a very highly potent anti-serum in actual field outbreaks in order to find out to what extent such a serum may be made useful in actual disease control. In order to reduce the influence of the large factor of error in such work, the department planned to subject not less than 10.000 fowls in actual outbreaks and to have its own staff members do the needed field work. As long as outbreaks occurred within reasonable distance of the Station good progress was made, but when the disease disappeared from our neighborhood pro - gress ceased. Over 3000 fowls in outbreaks have been treated, a number not sufficient to permit of conclusions with any degree of accuracy. No doubt occasion will present itself again to pursue this phase of the work. There are also other phases of the project that must yet receive atten - tion. An Inquiry into the Source of Tuberculosis of Swine. — During the past year a great deal of work was done on this project. It has now been completed, and the final report of the work has already been published. In all, 250 consignments of hogs, originating from 41 dif - ferent counties, were examined. Of these, 31 gave negative results, showing no tuberculosis ; 2 were discarded ; 8 showed tuberculosis of probably avian origin; and 209 permitted of definite conclusions. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 11 From this work it appears that the tuberculous swine from which the material was examined and classified as to infec - tion origin derived the same from the following sources and in the following proportions: Avian sources, 185 cases, or 88.5 per cent Mammalian sources, 11 cases, or 5.2 per cent Mixed sources, 13 cases, or 6.2 per cent Current Laboratory Examinations. — During the past year many animals of various kinds were sent to the laboratory for examination. In all, 1409 laboratory examinations were made for diagnostic purposes. This work is of a general service nature and requires much time which must be taken from the regular investigational work. DAIRY HUSBANDRY RniHjhage for Dairy Cows. — A study of the carrying capacity of sweet clover pasture for milk cows has been made for two years and will be repeated. So far the indi - cations are that between two and three cows per acre can be kept on sweet clover provided a limited quantity of grain fed Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making. — During the past year the experimental work on this project has been as follows : Working out of practical methods for standardizing the ingredients in an ice cream mix. Formulae have been pre - pared and tables calculated that allow the ice cream maker to quickly prepare his mix from the various constituents. In this study it was found that viscosity of the ice cream mix increased with the increase of butterfat, other factors remaining constant. Increased percentages of milk solids not fat increased the viscosity of the mix also. Studies to determine the plasticity of the ice cream mix were started. A comparison of different grades of gelatine was made on the basis of the viscosity of a 1 per cent solution, the chlor - ine content, and the hydrogen-ion concentration. The pro - tective properties of the gelatines were studied in a 5 per cent lactose solution and the crystallization observed: the fewer and smaller the crystals the greater the protective property of the gelatine. The crystals were studied under a micro - scope and photomicrographs were made. It was found that the melting point of the gelatine solution is an indication of jellying strength. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Work was done in comparing score cards for ice cream with reference to the number of points that should be allowed for each characteristic. Preliminary work indicated the need of more accurate in - struments for ice cream experimentation. An orifice was designed which records the rate of brine flow by using differential pressures. Meters were unsatisfactory. All brine lines are now equipped with thermometer wells so that temperatures can be recorded at different places. Study of Weight in Dairy Cattle. — Weights so far taken indicate a distinctly slower growth in weight for Holstein females as compared with Holstein males up to 6 month*. The rate of growth for different breeds appears to vary widely with animals kept under the same conditions. Studies are being made to determine if there is a periodicity of growth as is claimed by some writers. Studies in the gain in weight due to advancing pregnancy indicate a regular pro - gressive increase month by month. Figures so far compiled on the dairy herd indicate that the average length of days carried by the mother is longer for male than female calves. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Corn Breeding. — This project has been carried for a num - ber of years to determine methods for the improvement in the yield and quality of corn and to establish general prin - ciples of corn breeding. The work during the past year was confined largely to the establishment of pure line strains by inbreeding, the hybridization of certain of the pure line strains, and the reassembling of a number of pure lines in an effort to determine whether it is possible to get a corn sufficiently stable so that continued hybridization would not be necessary. The season's work bears out the results of former years in that it indicates the superiority of pure line F, combinations over the original corn, and also that new hybrid seed must be produced each year rather than to select seed from the Fi progeny. A very material reduction in yield has resulted in the case of all generations beyond the first cross. Investigations are under way to determine the possibility of permanently recombining a relatively large number of pure lines, and thereby restoring a productive, superior, open pollinated variety. The work of 1924 suggests this as one practical means of utilizing the pure line strains. Somewhat greater production has resulted from such seed than from seed of the original commercial variety. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 13 Water Requirements of Crops. — This project has been carried for a number of years, the purpose being to study correlation between the use of water by the corn plant and climatic factors, soil fertility, variety, plant char - acteristics, and source of seed. Homozygous inbred strains were also compared with their hybrids. The work on this project was continued along much the same lines during the past year, but not on as large a scale as in former years. The work of the past season bears out the results obtained in former years; the water required has been found to correlate rather closely with the evaporation rate from a free water surface, which in turn varies with seasonal climatic conditions; the amount of water trans - pired per pound of dry matter has decreased somewhat with the application of manure or artificial fertilizer, but the total amount of water used by the corn plant in its growth to maturity has not decreased. This is due to the fact that where there is a greater amount of fertility present larger plants are produced. S»iall Grains. — Work was continued in variety testing, acclimatization, breeding, and cultural studies with various small grains. Bulletin 201 summarizes 18 years' work with spring sown small grains and a manuscript has been pre - pared summarizing all winter wheat investigations. Early oats have given materially higher yields than the late varieties, — Kherson, Texas Red, and Burt averaging 8.7 bushels more than later varieties, such as Swedish Select, American Banner, University No. 6 (Minnesota), and Lin - coln. This work, as carried on at the North Platte Station, showed even a wider margin in favor of early oats, which indicates that earliness is more important as one goes west - ward in the state, except where the oats are grown under irrigation. In an 11-year test, 1913-1923, with Kherson oats planted at the rates of 4, 8, 10, 12, 14, and 16 pecks per acre, the respective grain yields were 51.1, 54.0, 55.9, 56.2, 55.9, 55.4 bushels per acre. Considering the amount of seed sown, 10 to 12 pecks per acre for this section of the state seems best. In a 7-year test on the time of seeding, 1917 to 1923, early, medium, and late seeding of Kherson oats (March 31, April 12, and April 20) yielded 58.2, 49.4, 38.6 bushels per acre respectively. In a corresponding test with Java spring wheat the yields were 15.8, 12.1, and 9.0 bushels per acre respec - tively. Turkey Red winter wheat seeded at the rates of 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 pecks to the acre gave respective yields for 5 years of 28.6, 30.4, 30.5, 31.5, and 30.7 bushels per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station In a 5-year date-of-seeding test of winter wheat, the fol - lowing yields were obtained from the seedings on the differ - ent dates: September 16, 32.1 bushels; September 22, 34.2 bushels; October 1, 32.2 bushels; October 16, 25.1 bushels; October 31, 20.2 bushels; November 25, 16.7 bushels; Feb - ruary 9, 11.8 bushels; March 4, 5.5 bushels; March 25, 0.1 bushel. In a time-of-harvesting test, oats harvested at 4 different stages of maturity, namely, 6, 4, and 2 days before ripe and when ripe, gave 51.1, 52.8, 57.5, 57.0 bushels per acre respectively. Winter wheat harvested in the early dough, medium dough, stiff dough, and at maturity gave yields of 26.2, 31.6, 33.5, and 34.6 bushels per acre respec - tively. A 4-year comparison, calculated on a hull-free basis, of the various small grains gave the following average yields : Kherson oats 1095, Manchurian barley 1212, hulless barley 816, spring emmer 817, spring rye, 1165. Marquis spring wheat 906, Turkey Red winter wheat 1638, and common winter rye 1568 pounds per acre. After many years of study on the relative yields of light and heavy seed, the work at this Station indicates no material gain in grain yields under farm conditions from the prac - tice of grading small grain seed which is reasonably free from trash and inert matter. Forage Crops. — The forage crops work during the past year was carried on as in previous years, with certain additions. With the annual forage crops it consisted largely of varietal studies of the sorghums, millets, and other annual crops adapted to Nebraska conditions, and cultural studies of ordinary amber sorghum and Sudan grass. In addition to the work carried the previous year, studies were inaugurated dealing with the curing of various crops. Root crops, red clover, and the grain sorghums were included in comparison of yields. Investigations were started on the proper height to cut sweet clover in order to avoid the heaw killing which is so common. The past season's work gave additional data on the rate and time of seeding the annual sorghums. The actual figures on yields were changed somewhat, but the relative positions obtained in the first 4 years' work were not changed. Amber sorghum gave the highest yield of any sorghum. German millet gave the highest yield among the foxtail millets. Seed - ing the forage crops relatively early in the growing season gives higher yields than later seeding. Soil Fertility. — This work was continued according to the rather permanent outline. Four years' results are now </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 15 available from the studies at the Agronomy Farm. Appli - cations of commercial fertilizer showed some response in yields for the grain crops, but in no case has the increase in yield been sufficient to pay the extra cost. Applications of manure, lime, and various commercial fertilizers have failed to increase the yields of alfalfa, the indications being that after the alfalfa has been grown on the upland for a period of years it is entirely dependent upon available moisture. The Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, and Soil Condition to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils. — Laboratory investigations on the effect of variations in moisture and temperature on nitrification have been completed. Nitrate production was found to increase at an exponential rate as temperature was increased, up to 35° C. (95° F.). Beyond 35°, nitrification decreased, and at 55° all accumulation of nitrates ceased. At temperatures as low as 5° nitrification was negligible. Nitrate production increased directly with moisture content up to one and one-fourth the field carrying capacity, which was the highest degree of wetness studied. Soils differ in quantity of nitrate production at different temperatures and moisture contents. At optimum water content, typical eastern Nebraska soils produce very little nitrates when the temperature is below 15°, while at the same wetness typical western Nebraska soils produce a sufficiency of nitrates. During the year laboratory work on the effect of drought conditions, — that is, high soil temperatures and low moisture content, — on nitrification has begun. The data so far accumulated indicate that the superior nitrification rates found in western Nebraska soils may be due to the frequency with which these soils are subjected to drought. The third year of field experiments on the response of wheat to nitrates, and to practices encouraging the form - ation of nitrates, bears out the statement made in the Annual Report of 1924, namely, that the proper maintenance of the soil to produce nitrates is of great importance. Wheat made better response to nitrates artificially applied at intervals thruout the spring than when applied all at one time in the fall. There were no indications that the fall application wa3 lost by leaching. Soil treatments designed to increase the nitrification rate of the soil gave yields of wheat comparable with the best tillage methods. Statistical studies of climatic data for Nebraska show that in eastern Nebraska the weather may be a limiting factor in nitrate production in the spring for wheat in about 1 year in 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 16 Parallelisms between the Glacial and Loess Soils of South - eastern Nebraska. — This project has been completed during the year. The glacial soils differ from the loess soils in that the former have a very pronounced clay horizon, differing from the same level in the loess soils, not so much in mechanical analysis and chemical composition as in proper - ties of plasticity, tenacity, cohesion, etc. The soil-forming material, and not climate is responsible for these differences. Soil Tilth. — The various physical properties of the soil determining tilth — like cohesion, adhesion, tenacity, plas - ticity, and shrinkage — are being studied in the laboratory. The apparatus already devised includes a briquet-breaking machine, a shearing-test apparatus, and equipment for study - ing friction. Loss of organic matter seems to be the biggest factor reducing tilth quality. Loss of 30 per cent of the organic matter on 6 Nebraska farms has lowered the scour - ing point of soils from 40 per cent moisture to 30 per cent, and has also increased the stiffness of the soil when wet and hardness when dry. Effect of Lime on fh&lt; Physical Properties of the Soil. — This project was begun February 1. under a fellowship arrange - ment with the National Lime Association. Plot work, with different rates and kinds of lime, laid out on a uniform ilapc shows that the granulating effect and physical improve - ment due to lime is resulting in a small economy in water storage and conservation. However, organic matter in the tt form of manure is somewhat superior to lime. Other phast of the project include tilth studies on several plots laid oi on refractory soils. New apparatus for tilth studies is 1&gt;&lt; ing devised. The project is being continued. Investigation of the Soils of the Proposed Central Nebraska Supplemental Irrigation Project. — At the request of the L. S. Bureau of Public Roads and the organized supporters of irrigation in central Nebraska, considerable study was made concerning the feasibility of supplemental irrigation in Adams, Kearney, and Phelps Counties, from the standpoint of soil adaptability and crop response. A report of the in - vestigations is in publication in the annual report of the State Department of Public Works. The soils were found to be well adapted to supplemental irrigation. The upper 6 feet of soil will carry an average of 12 inches of available water. The soil takes water readily and offers no serious difficulties in cultivation or management under irrigation farming. There is no indication of a possibility of alkali development. Statistical studies of weather records and crop </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 17 yields indicate that on an average 2 bushels increase in yield per acre of wheat and corn can be expected for each inch of irrigation water properly applied. Relation of the Organic Matter and Nitrogen Content of Prairie Soils to Soil Types. — Established upland virgin prairie soil types are found to be homogenous with respect to organic matter and nitrogen. Soil types with destructional topography like bluff lands, and soils of constructional features like ahuvial lands, are not homogenous in organic matter and nitrogen. The organic matter content of the surface foot of virgin prairie soils is found to be close to 20 times the nitrogen con - tent. In established virgin upland prairie soil types the nitrogen content decreases with coarseness of texture and with decrease in rainfall. Lnsn of Organic Matter and Nitrogen Under Cultivation. — Studies on many cultivated farms show that 20 to 50 per cent of the original organic matter and nitrogen in the soil has been lost. Where erosion has occurred the loss in these constituents has reached 70 per cent on many farms. On farms where attention has been paid to soil maintenance by the return of manure and crop residues and the growing of legumes, the decline in organic matter and nitrogen is very ittle FRUIT PRODUCTION I'nniiiiu Tree Fruits, Grapes, Small Fruits. — This study is undertaken to determine the influence of different methods of pruning upon the fruitfulness and growth of the plant. The season's work was carried along the line originally outlined. With apples was included the study of several pruning methods ; also the effect of light and heavy pruning during both the growing and the dormant season. Trunk diameter measurements have been taken on all the trees included in the experiment, but the work has not been carried suffi - ciently long for conclusive results to be shown. In the pruning work with grapes the spur versus cane - pruning work has been continued. The results indicate a higher percentage of productive buds on the cane-pruned plants. Cane-pruned plants produce a slightly larger number of clusters per productive buds; clusters from cane-pruned plants were slightly larger than those from the spur-pruned vines. This means a larger total production on the cane - pruned plants. During the past year the pruning was done so as to leave approximately 60 buds on each plant, no matter whether it was spur or cane-pruned, or had one or two trunks. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 18 Approximately one acre of cherries of Early Richmond, Montmorency, and English Morello were planted at Union Fruit Farm in the spring of 1924 in order to study the effect of pruning on cherry trees. In this work the control leader type will be compared with the more open systems of prun - ing. A good stand of trees was secured and preliminary work will start next season. Orchard Culture. — This work is carried on both at the Union Fruit Farm where cultural studies are being made and at Lincoln where nutrition studies are being made. In the latter study, applications of manure, sodium nitrate, acid phosphate, and ammonium sulphate are compared with clover as a cover and green manure crop, and with clean cultivation. At the present time there seems to be slightly larger growth on the trees where acid phosphate is applied. Blight is more prevalent with sodium nitrate. A few trees were lost. There is also some blight where ammonium sulphate has been applied. Vegetable Experimentation. — During the past season work was started on varieties and cultural tests with a number of the important vegetables of the state. INSECT CONTROL Control of Injurious Insects, Animals, and Bird*. — During the past year most of the work done under this project has been in relation to Hessian fly control. The work was carried on similarly to that reported in the Thirty-seventh Annual Report, except that two stations were established in 192 4 instead of one. One station was near Wahoo in Saunders County and was maintained from August 11 to October 1. The second station was located near Beatrice and main - tained from August 13 to October 6. A great deal of additional information on the behavior of the main fall brood of the Hessian fly was secured, especially in relation to the influence of moisture on emergence. Be - ginning September 3, a series of bulletins was issued, one every few days until the final bulletin (No. 11) on October 7, these tracing the development of the fall brood in detail. These bulletins were given wide publicity, and by means of the information thus secured it was possible to announce dates of safe sowing for each infested Nebraska county a day or two ahead of the actual date. In this work the Station co-operated with 26 Nebraska counties, thru their county agents, as compared with 11 co-operating counties in 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 19 In addition to these counties, 2 counties that had no county agent were co-operated with thru community clubs located in those counties. The 1924 work followed very close.y the work begun in 1923. The accuracy of the announced dates of safe seeding in 1923 were checked up in several counties by experimental sowings and were found to be accurate. The 1923 work was quite fully reported upon on pages 86-98 of the Fifteenth Annual Report of the Nebraska Crop Growers' Association. No published report has been made of the 1924 work. This work was instrumental in saving many thousands of dollars to the wheat growers of the state who awaited the announced dates of safe sowing. Minor observations and life-history studies were made on several other pests. These include the chinch bug, stalk borer, peach borer, and several species of aphids. The Life History of Several Common Cutworms. — Work was continued on this project in an effort to discover satis - factory means of identifying different species in the larval stage. This would obviate the necessity of rearing them to the adult moth stage for identification, which is now the prac - tice. Nursery, Orchard, and Greenhouse Stock Inspection. — As provided in the Nebraska Horticultural Inspection Law, Ne - braska nurseries and greenhouses were inspected and granted certificates by the State Entomologist. This routine work of inspection requires considerable time during the late sum - mer months. Grasshopper Control. — During the past season no field work was done on this project, but considerable time was spent in working over the results that had been secured dur - ing the summer of 1923. A bulletin was prepared on the use of poison baits for grasshoppers. LIVESTOCK FEEDING CATTLE Effect of Age upon Rate and Economy of Gain. — This work has been carried on for 4 years, making 4 tests in all. During the past year, 4 lots of 10 steers each, ranging from 3-year-olds to calves respectively, were fed thru a 200 - day period beginning November 1, 1923, and closing May 19, 1924. A ration of shelled corn and alfalfa was fed to all groups. The results obtained in this test concurred rather closely with the results from the 3 previous tests. The 3 - year-old steers made the greatest gain, the 2-year-olds, year- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lings, and calves gaining about 70 pounds less. The older steers consumed a much greater amount of feed, and con - sequently the amount of gain per given quantity of feed was less. Figuring corn at 70 cents and alfalfa hay at $15, the cost per 100 pounds of gain was — for the 3-year-olds, $13.69 ; for the 2-year-olds, $12.48; for the yearlings, $11.39; and for the calves, $8.69. In terms of gain per bushel of corn con - sumed, the 3-year-olds gained 6.2 pounds, the 2-year-olds 6.7, the yearlings 7.5, and the calves 9.6. An outstanding feature of the 4 trials has been the con - sistency with which big steers gained rapidly during the first 100 days, but gained at a rate of but little more than 50 per cent as much during the second 100 days. The calve&gt; have been found to gain consistently in each trial thruout the entire period. In fact, during the second 100 days ii, several of the trials a slightly greater gain was made than during the first period. We feel that this work has tended to point very closely toward the utilization of younger cattle in the feed lots of Nebraska: first, because they are much more economical: second, because they can be held over a longer period in cas. - adverse markets should make that advisable; third, becaus &gt; the present demand is for light cuts of beef and the pros - pects are that this demand will become even stronger in the future; and fourth, because the initial cost is much less and consequently the capital outlay is much more favorable to the feeding of younger cattle. Baby Beef Production. — Six lots of 20 calves each wen put on feed October 24, 1923, to be fed for 200 days. At the end of that period an adverse market made it advisabl - to hold the entire group an additional 50 days, at which time 10 head of each lot were marketed and the 10 remaining ware held an additional 50 days, making 300 days on feed. Feeding as long as 300 days did not prove profitable. The gain made by the calves during the last 50-day period was unsatisfactory. This unsatisfactory gain may have been due to extremely hot weather and the flies during the last period, but the gain was less than 1 pound per day. Much more corn was consumed per pound of gain than during the previous periods. Furthermore, the market price was not high enough to nearly make up the increased cost of the gains. Briefly, it might be stated that at the end of 200 days. Lot 1, consisting of open heifer calves, had failed to gain as much as the steers, fed a similar ration of shelled corn and alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 21 hay, by 43 pounds per head. They had consumed practi - cally as much feed and consequently showed to be less efficient than steers. The addition of linseed meal to the ration failed to show any big advantage, altho the calves which had received this were somewhat fatter than those receiving only corn and alfalfa. The cost of gain with the linseed meal more than offset the advantage in gain. The use of silage resulted in calves carrying somewhat less finish than those fed upon a straight shelled corn and alfalfa ration. However, the gain was a little cheaper. Ground ear corn showed quite favorably in comparison with shelled corn, altho the added gain was scarcely sufficient to pay for the cost of grinding. Summer Cattle Feeding. — Three groups of 10 steers each were used in this test. The first trial was carried in 1923 and was repeated in the summer of 1924. The first lot in each case was fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay in dry lots. Lot 2 was fed shelled corn on Sudan grass pasture. Lot 3 was fed shelled corn on sweet clover pasture, the purpose being to ascertain the relative values of the two grasses for fattening cattle and at the same time compare feeding on pasture with feeding in dry lot. In the first trial, 1923, the steers in Lot 1 gained one-fifth of a pound daily more than those on pasture, but consumed more corn. The cost of 100 pounds of gain was $10.72 for the dry lot, $9.61 on Sudan grass, and $9.77 on sweet clover. The cattle in the dry lot carried better finish and sold for 25 cents per hundred more than the cattle on Sudan grass and 75 cents more per hundred than those on sweet clover. The tests showed that cattle made good gains and economical utilization of corn when fed during summer months, and that grass did not produce as good a finish as alfalfa hay and shelled corn. The test of 1924 checked very closely with that of 1923, the difference being that the cattle on sweet clover showed more finish this year. This may have been due to the fact that they were fed on the field that was used in 1923 and had second-year sweet clover for pasture. All lots made economical gains. Cattle in the dry lot again made more gain than those on pasture but the gain was a little more expensive. The pigs following the cattle returned a greater gain on Sudan grass than either those in the dry lot or those on sweet clover. An interesting feature of the test is that in both years steers fed in the dry lot made more efficient gains than similar cattle fed on similar feeds during the winter months. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 22 LAMBS Fall Lamb Feeding. — Ten lots of 30 head each of western lambs were put on feed October 10, 1923, and fed for a period of 110 days, the objects being: first, to study the results of adding different quantities of linseed meal to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay; second, to study the results of adding different quantities of alfalfa molasses meal to % ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay; third, to get informa - tion concerning the feeding of oats during the first few weeks of the feeding period; and fourth, to compare alfalfa and prairie hay as roughages for fattening lambs when fed in conjunction with a full feed of shelled corn and a heavy allowance of linseed oil meal. The results show that the addition of linseed oil meal to corn and alfalfa hay rations caused an increase in the rate of gain and a slight increase in the cost of gain. The feed consumed was slightly greater in lots where larger quan - tities of oil meal were fed, and in this test the profit per lamb was increased with the use of oil meal. The addition of alfalfa molasses meal to the corn and alfalfa hay ration increased slightly the gain made. The meal seemed to serve primarily as a substitute for the alfalfa hay. The replacement value of a pound of alfalfa molasses meal decreased as the amount of this feed was increased. Lambs fed oats in addition to shelled corn and hay made less rapid and less economical gains than the lambs that were not fed oats. Furthermore, the lambs that were fed oats made a somewhat lower dressed yield and less profit per head than those not receiving oats. The lambs fed alfalfa hay made considerably larger gains and returned more profit per head than those fed prairie hay. Spring Lamb Feeding. — Six lots of 26 head each of west - ern lambs were put on feed February 10. 1924, for a period of 60 days, the purpose being to secure information concern - ing the shearing of western lambs before marketing and to study the results of adding a medium feeding of linseed oil meal to the ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Two lots of lambs were sheared 10 days after they were started on feed, 2 lots 2 weeks before being marketed, and 2 lots were not shorn. The lambs that were not shorn made the largest and cheap - est gains and returned more profit per head than any of the lambs that were shorn. The lambs fed linseed oil meal made larger gains at slightly greater cost, but returned more profit </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 23 per head than did those which were fed only corn and alfalfa hay. HOGS Wheat for Fattening Pigs. — Because of the low price prevailing for wheat during the summer of 1923, much interest was manifested in the feeding of this grain to hogs. Four lots of ten 92-pound spring pigs were fed for 80 days, beginning August 7, 1923. Lot 1 was self-fed torn and tankage, gaining 1.29 pounds daily and requir - ing 403 pounds of corn and 40 pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds gain. Lot 4, self-fed whole wheat and tankage, gained 1.37 pounds daily and required 393 pounds wheat and 22 pounds tankage to make a similar gain. Lot 3 was self - fed ground wheat and tankage. The hogs in this lot made the largest gains of the series, 1.5 pounds. While some feed was saved by grinding the wheat, the saving was not sufficient to pay for the cost of grinding, which was figured at 6 cents per bushel. Summer Pig Feeding. — The objects of this experiment were : first, to compare dry lot feeding with feeding on Sudan and alfalfa pasture; second, full feeding and limited grain ration, on pasture; third, to determine the advisability of feeding tankage to pigs on pasture; and fourth, to compare Sudan and alfalfa as pasture for pigs. In every case pigs on full feed made greater and more efficient gains than did those on limited rations. Pigs on pasture gained 50 per cent more than those in the dry lot and required less feed to produce 100 pounds of gain. Alfalfa pasture reduced the cost of pork production about $2 for 100 pounds. The addition of tankage to the ration proved advantageous with both full and limited grain rations, on both alfalfa and Sudan grass pastures. The tankage in - creased both the rate of gain and efficiency of feeds, saving approximately $2 per hundred on the cost of 100 pound3 gain. Sudan grass had a higher carrying capacity during the hot weather of this summer than alfalfa. Summer Hog Feeding. — Two lots of hogs were fed for a period of 20 days. Lot 1, self -fed corn and tankage, dry lot, gained 1.25 pounds daily. Lot 2, fed in similar manner and ration but with alfalfa pasture, gained 1.4 pounds per day. Alfalfa effected no appreciable saving of corn, but the tank - age required to produce 100 pounds of gain was cut to one - third of that required in dry lots. Lot 3, self-fed corn alone on alfalfa pasture, gained 0.65 pound per day, — or approx- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station » imately one-half as much as Lot 1 and Lot 2. This shows a decided advantage for supplementing with tankage even on alfalfa pasture. White vs. Yellow Corn for Fattening Hogs. — In a rather comprehensive test, pigs fed yellow corn consumed more and made larger and more economical gains than those that were fed white corn. Mixed corn appeared to be intermediate between white and yellow corn. Where both white and yellow corn were available the pigs consumed more of thu yellow. The difference between white and yellow corn was not found as great when fed to pigs of this weight — namely, 113 pounds — as has been reported for lighter pigs. Simple Mineral Supplements for Fattening Hogs. — In this experiment 8 lots of hogs, averaging 75 pounds, were fed for a period of 120 days. Two basal rations were used, 1 lots being fed corn and tankage and 4 lots corn and alfalfa hay. The mineral supplements used were block salt, steamed bone meal, and a home mixture of 1 bushel cob ashes, 5 pounds salt, and 8 pounds air-slaked lime. With tankage none of the mineral supplements increased either the rate or the efficiency of gain. With alfalfa hay all the min - eral supplements increased the rate of gain. The addition of block salt or steamed bone meal to the corn and alt'all rations reduced the food requirements to produce 100 pounci of pork. The homemade mixture did not effect any savin in corn. MILLING AND BAKING QUALITY OF WHEAT The Nebraska wheat crop of 1924 has been surveyed witi respect to milling and baking qualities and chemical com - position, as were the crops of 1922 and 1923. The 1924 croj averaged slightly lower in protein or gluten content than th.. crops of the 2 years preceding, but averaged slightly highei in baking quality. This indicates that quality in gluten i. - of great importance, as well as quantity. In the 1924 croj the earlier maturing varieties showed higher protein con tent and better baking qualities than the others. Nebraska No. 28 was outstanding in this respect. It is planned to publish the results of the 3 years' survey in one comprehensive report. This work for the past 3 years seems to indicate definitely: (1) That in so far as baking qualities are concerned the wheats of Nebraska vary con - siderably in different localities; (2) that there is apt to be marked variation from one year to another within the same locality; (3) that high protein content frequently failed to </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 25 correlate with high baking quality exhibited by Nebraska wheats, due to differences in gluten quality, or to a factor as yet undiscovered; (5) that there is no correlation between commercial grade and quality; (6) that the higher protein winter wheats from the more arid regions of western Nebraska are frequently of poorer baking quality than the winter wheats of eastern and southern Nebraska; (7) that, generally speaking, Kanred and Turkey wheats are about equal in baking quality; and (8) that in general the baking quality is determined more by soil conditions as influenced by such factors as climate and weather conditions, as well as by cultural practices, than by inherent varietal character - istics. Glut &lt;it in Determination. — Under the same project there have been completed two researches dealing with glutenin, which is now considered to be the special flour protein responsible for differences in the gluten qualities of various flours. One of these researches has resulted in the develop - ment of a simple, accurate, and direct method for the prep - aration and quantitative determination of this important flour constituent. Such a method has heretofore been lacking. A report of this work has been submitted for publication and will appear in an early issue of the technical journal known as Cereal Chemistry. Identity of Gluten Proteins from Different Flours. — The other research disproves a recent announcement by an English chemist to the effect that differences in baking qualities are due to differences in the chemical configurations of one of the principal flour proteins, namely, glutenin. This work involved the preparation, purification, and study of the racemization rates of a number of proteins from wheats of different sources and quality, and shows con - clusively that, while proteins from various wheats may occasionally differ slightly in chemical configuration, these differences are not a determining factor in flour strength. The report of this work was recently published in the Novem - ber, 1924, issue of Cereal Chemistry. NUTRITION Nutrient Requirements of Groiving Chicks. — (Co-operative — Agricultural Chemistry and Poultry Husbandry.) This project was continued during the past year. It was planned to determine the effect of environmental conditions on the prevention and cure of rickets in chicks. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Leg weakness or rickets in chicks is due to improper bone development, associated with faulty calcium and phosphorus metabolism. The particular phase of the work emphasized this past year was a study of the influence of the vitamine content of the ration and the effect of certain light rays on calcium and phosphorus assimilation in the chick. It was found that the quality of light has an especial influence on the calcium and phosphorus assimilation and that light which comes thru common window glass, which filters out the short or ultra violet rays, does not possess the catalytic action which is necessary for calcium and phosphorus absorption. Exposure to direct sunlight for 45 minutes a day makes a difference between success and failure in growing chicks when standard rations are used. In the absence of proper light conditions 2 per cent of cod liver oil added to the rations furnishes the vitamine " D," which has the same influence on calcium and phosphorus absorption that sunlight has. Further calcium and phosphorus studies were made on the blood sera of a considerable number of chicks which had been subjected to various diets and treatments for causing and curing leg weakness. Inorganic phosphorus, calcium content, and bicarbonate carbon dioxide of the blood sera of experimental chicks were determined. The amounts of in - organic phosphorus and calcium were found to be appreciably higher in the blood sera of healthy chicks which had received direct sunlight or cod liver oil than in cases where they re - ceived the same basal rations but no direct sunlight or cod liver oil and were rachitic. The latter group included lots which were treated respectively with rays from a copper arc light, light filtered thru window glass, and the addition of juice pressed from fresh alfalfa. A report of this work will appear in an early issue of the Journal of Biological Chemistry. A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Pro - teins in Poultry Feeding. — (Co-operative — Agricultural Chemistry and Poultry Husbandry.) Thirty-seven trials with 12 mature normal Rhode Island Red hens gave an aver - age figure of 147 mg. of nitrogen (per kilogram of live weight) excreted on a nitrogen-free diet. This figure has been used in calculating the percentage utilization of nitro - gen from yellow corn and from casein in further trials. When this figure was applied in the case of yellow corn, marked disagreement was encountered between the values for molt - ing and non-molting birds. Therefore 14 trials with molt - ing birds were made. A striking increase of 65 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 27 in the endogenous nitrogen was found over that of non-molt - ing birds, which tends to explain the differences in nutritive value under the two conditions. Forty-four trials with non - molting birds gave an average value of 64 per cent utiliz - ation of the nitrogen of yellow corn. Eight trials with molt - ing birds gave a value of 65 per cent with corn when the figures secured in the latter trials on a nitrogen-free diet were used. In like manner, 8 trials with non-melting birds fed casein as the sole source of nitrogen showed a utilization of 64 per cent. Ten molting birds, when the increase in the endogenous nitrogen excretion of molting birds was taken into consider - ation, utilized 69 per cent of the nitrogen fed. The addition of cystine to the casein ration was found to markedly increase the utilization of protein by molting birds, taking the average for 11 molting birds. Further studies on this point are in progress. Studies in Fat Soluble A as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds, Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey. — A study of the records of 68 rats, that have been used so far, indicates that the richer milk tends to be more potent in its effect upon young rats fed a basal diet free from vitamine A. The deficiency symptoms appear between 6 and 8 weeks from the time the young rats are placed on the basal diet. More groups are being run, repeating the work already done, and work has been started feeding definite quantities of butter - fat from the different breeds. The milk is churned and the samples taken from the resulting butter. PLANT DISEASES A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. — During the past year the behavior of a third phys - iologic form (XXI) was tested in the greenhouse upon the differential hosts, under various environmental conditions. In the main the same general results were obtained as have already been reported for two physiologic forms. (Research Bulletin 25.) A series of experiments to determine the period of initial infection for urediniospores was carried out with the follow - ing results: A small percentage of infection was obtained when the inoculated plants were held under optimum incu - bation conditions within 3 hours. When plants were held under these conditions for 12 hours, 15 per cent subsequently </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station became infected, while the percentage of infection when plants were held for 18 and 24 hours in the inoculation chambers was 30 to 90 per cent respectively. When the period of incubation was extended beyond 24 hours, 100 per cent infection and a larger amount of rust developed. The influence of varying intensities of artificial light on initial infection by urediniospores and the subsequent development of rust was determined. In short, it was found that the various light intensities used did not influence infec - tion, but that the best development of the rust occurred at the higher intensities of light. During the past 3 years the viability of the urediniospores of 3 physiologic forms has been determined and a final report on this phase of the stem rust investigation is ready for publication at an early date. The results obtained are similar to those published in Research Bulletin 22. However, at low temperatures and at medium relative humidities the time period for the viability of the spores has been greatly ex - tended. The overwintering phase of the project ha tinued, with negative results. Collections of stem rust from every county in the stat were made during the summer of 1924 in order that the phys iologic forms present in Nebraska could be determined. A these physiologic forms are identified their reaction on th&gt; strains and hybrids of wheat developed by the departmen of agronomy will be tested, in a search for varieties of whea resistant to stem rust. During the past year a bulletin (Research Bulletin 28) has been prepared dealing with the control equipment in the greenhouse used in the various studies of the relation of environment to plant disease. A Study of Fusarium Wilt and Tuber Rot of the Irish Potato in Reference to the Relation of Environ mental Con - ditions to the Infection and Progress of the Disease. — The major portion of this project has been completed and pub - lished (Research Bulletins 23 and 27). Certain phases of the problem have been continued as a minor project. A study of the physiology of the parasitism of several species of Fusaria producing either a wilt or tuber rot or both is being undertaken along the following lines: 1. Determination of the cause of wilting of plants affected with Fusarium wilt: i.e., by plugging of vascular ducts or secretion of toxic substances. Preliminary studies have in- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 29 dicated that different species of Fusaria produce different kinds of toxins and in varying amounts. 2. Determination of the ability of these species to pro - duce an enzyme breaking down the middle lamella of the cell wall of potato tissue. Preliminary determinations indi - cate that the species being studied vary greatly in their abil - ity to produce the enzyme pectinase. 3. It has been found that the different species of Fusaria studied produce different amounts of amylase and that the production of an enzyme capable of breaking down raw starch can be regulated by controlling the source of carbon used in the culture media. The Influence of Environmental Conditions on the Trans - it) imtim of Seed Borne Diseases, Including the Potato. — The results of the previous work on this problem have been pub - lished (Research Bulletin 26). During the past winter this work was continued. A large number of degeneration dis - eases and combinations of diseases were studied under a great number of controlled environmental conditions. The results of this work with the practical applications are being published (Research Bulletin 29). During the past summer, experiments were conducted to determine the rate of spread of several types of mosaic, leaf roll, and spindle tuber under both dry land and irrigated conditions. The progeny are being indexed in the greenhouse and the experiments will be continued during the next sum - mer. Experiments have also been undertaken to determine the insects capable of transmitting these diseases in Nebraska, and a survey of the insects in western Nebraska potato fields has been attempted. Aphids, the recognized carriers of the disease, apparently do not occur in our fields in sufficient numbers to account for all the transmissions. A survey of native solanaceous weeds in western Nebraska has been started and will be continued during the coming summer. All such plants are being tested as carriers of these diseases. Experiments are being conducted in the greenhouse in determining the effect of soil and air temperatures and soil moisture on the tuber symptoms of the spindle-tuber diseases and on the tuber characteristics of healthy plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station POTATOES Seed Potato Selection. — The purpose of this experiment is to improve the seed qualities of potatoes grown in Nebraska. Observations indicate that if seed plats are thoroly rogued and plants affected with various diseases, particularly spindle-tuber and mosaic, are removed at fre - quent intervals, especially early in the season, relatively good seed potatoes can probably be produced in the eastern and central parts of the state and in the irrigation as well as in the dry land regions of western Nebraska. During the past season tuber index work has been carried on. Six thousand Triumph tubers were indexed in the green - house. Of these, 1500 were considered sufficiently healthy and normal to plant in isolated seed plats in western Ne - braska. These plats were carefully rogued of any suspicious plants. It is hoped that a strain of Triumph potatoes that will be almost free from disease can be established by this method. The conduct of the certification trial plats has been part of this project. Two hundred fifty lots of western Nebraska Triumph potatoes, of which more than 100 were certified lots, were planted in western Nebraska for the purpose of secur - ing disease readings from the various strains, the information to be used by the certification committee of the college to check up the quality of the certification work and to secure more cemprehensive data as a guide to establishing future certification standards. A duplicate set of trials were con - ducted at Baton Rouge, Louisiana, in co-operation with the Louisiana Agricultural College and the Nebraska Potato Improvement Association. A Study in Degeneracy in Potatoes. — The disease most conspicuous as causing degeneracy has been identified under the name " spindle-tuber." This disease causes the plant to take on very distinctive symptoms, generally an upright appearance and considerably dwarfed in size, depending on the severity of the disease. The tubers are abnormally elongated and rough, with numerous shallow eyes, and in the case of colored skin varieties the color is very much lighter. This disease is transmitted thru the seed tubers and from plant to plant by insects in much the same way a3 the mosaic disease. Efforts were made during the season to determine to what extent cultural conditions would influence the transmission of the disease. That it is transmissible was proved by means of tuber grafts, and furthermore the disease was obtained </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 31 by leaving plants exposed in the field where protected check plants remained normal. That infection may take place early in the season is proved by the fact that plants caged as early as 10 days after their emergence became infected. Furthermore, various lots of potatoes harvested at different dates all showed infection. The indications are that the disease is not transmitted from plant to plant thru the soil. POULTRY PRODUCTION Inheritance of Egg Production. — As this project has pro - gressed, it has become evident that numbers of eggs should not be the sole basis for measuring improvement in fecund - ity, but that size of eggs and shell quality must also be con - sidered. A study is now being made of the factors that in - fluence egg size. These include breeding, feeding, sunlight, and other seasonal influences. Turkey Production. — During the past year a project was undertaken to study the production of turkeys. For this work 352 eggs were purchased ; 182 or 52 per cent were hatched and 162 birds raised to maturity. Of the birds raised, 35 of the best females and 3 males were kept for future breeding stock. The future work con - templates a study of feed costs and normal rate of growth. The preliminary work this year indicated that the young turkeys were even more sensitive to feed deficiencies than growing chicks. It further demonstrated that artificial brooding of turkeys is possible and that clean feeding and clean yarding are possibly the first essentials to turkey rais - ing. RURAL ECONOMICS Farm Management Survey. — During the year, 52 survey records have been taken; also 20 complete business records. These have been worked up to show a complete financial state - ment for each farm. Farm Tenure. — This work was carried on as a survey in several rural communities. The data obtained from the survey have been carefully tabulated and analyzed and a number of bulletins dealing with various phases of Nebraska farms and farm homes have been published. Cost of Producing Farm Crops. — This work is carried on thru co-operation of farmers in various localities. Record blanks are furnished by the Agricultural College to the farm - ers. The record books are returned to the Agricultural Col - lege and the data compiled leading to the cost of production. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The study is being carried on with wheat, corn, oats, hogs, and other important Nebraska farm products. Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and Purchasing Power of Farm Products. — A bulletin on the factors affecting the price of farm products has already been issued under this project. At the present time data are being assembled relative to the price and purchasing power of beef cattle. The Farm Land Problem. — This project is being carried in co-operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Considerable material has been assembled upon farm mort - gages and taxes paid by farm property. Co-operative Agricultural Organizations. — An intensive study is under way of the co-operative marketing of livestock in Nebraska. A considerable amount of material has been assembled and tabulated for study and will probably be ready for publication in the near future. SERUM PRODUCTION The practice of buying and retesting serum has beer tinued as during the past several years. The deman serum was much less than a year ago. The serum wai at the plant at 70 cents per hundred c. c. With the exception of 5,000 c. c. that was purchased, all virus put out by the State Serum Plant was produced by it. Particular pains have been taken with the virus in order that a pure, fresh, and virulent virus may be sent out, as this is necessary to successful immunization. The following is a complete report of the activities of tr plant for the year beginning January 1 and closing Deeemlw 31, 1924: Annual Report of State Serum Plant for 1 Ce Serum on hand January 1, 1924 1 Serum bought during the year 11 Total serum handled for year 12 Serum and virus sold by months: Virus Serum e.c. c.c. January 12,610 249,8"i(l February 12,270 217,430 March 11,330 180,550 April 14,0«0 230,250 May 39,510 629,250 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 33 Junt July \ugu Septembt October Xovi-nibe 140,020 ,557,630 NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION During the past year progress has been made along all lines of work. The herds of livestock have been improved by the elimination of many of the less desirable animals and by the development of younger animals produced in the herd. More experimental work has been carried on in pork pro - duction, and important lines of work have been added in crop improvement. The physical plant has been kept in fair state of repair &gt;ut no substantial improvements have been made. Agronomy. — Much of the work along this line is con - tinued from year to year on a general plan previously adopted. Some of the work is carried in co-operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Co-operation with the Office of Dry Land Agriculture began in 1906, with 92 tenth-acre plats, used in rotation and tillage studies. This has been increased until there are at the present time 326 plats in use. These investigations are planned to determine the effect of various climatic and soil influences on crop yield and quality ; the interaction of crops upon one another when planted in different sequence; and the effect of tillage and 85,020 91,390 57,870 58,320 32,710 14,620 10,290 1,353,900 1,524,350 1,107,000 1,066,650 614,400 238,600 165,400 Serum and virus used at plant 5,535 115,000 Total used and sold....445,555 7,672,630 Serum on hand January 1, 1925 5,217,675 Total jrross sales from all sources $65,005.55 Money collected and receipted for 67,867.61 Outstanding accts. with County Farm Bur's 1,402.73 Money on hand according to report of Bursar $37 ,981.36 Invoice of stock on hand 37,523.72 Outstanding accounts 1,402.73 Total $76,907.81 Number of pigs used in retesting serum bought 807 Pigs used in making virus 410 Number of orders 2,238 i X </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station various cropping methods upon the conservation and use of moisture and fertility. Thruout the entire period that the Station has been in operation it has been found that climatic factors, particularly the amount and distribution of rainfall, are the most impor - tant ones in determining crop yield. As an average thru a period of years, certain tillage practices are found to be important factors, but in other years, with adverse climatic conditions, the effect of tillage is not nearly as important as climatic conditions. The season of 1924 was favorable for the production of small grains, but not so favorable for the production of corn. The yields of winter wheat and oats were especially large. The wheat was of good quality. Early fall plowing for winter wheat was especially beneficial this year. Under certain conditions of moisture distribution, tillage after harvest may be almost as beneficial as summer tillage. Bulletin 193, Sixteen Years' Grain Production at the North Platte Substation, summarizes much of the work in crop production up to the present time. Crop Improvements. — This work is in co-operation with the Office of Cereal Investigations, the purpose being the pro - duction of grains better adapted to the climatic and soil con - ditions of the region and the development of higher quality and disease resistance. The work is being carried on with corn, winter wheat, barley, and oats. Seventy-two varieties of small grain were included in the test. Beef Cattle. — The Station now has a herd of 20 purebred Hereford cows and a herd of 30 purebred Shorthorn cows. These are carried for demonstrational purposes. Dairy Cattle. — The dairy herd now consists of 52 Holstein- Friesian females and 10 males. The average production of 15 cows and heifers completing 365-day periods was 15,971 pounds of milk and 708 pounds of butter. The de - velopment of the herd is illustrated by the production records of the 10 highest producing cows during the past 3 years. In 1922 the average was 15,016 pounds of milk and 621 pounds of butter; in 1923, 16,110 pounds of milk and 684 pounds of butter; in 1924, 17,788 pounds of milk and 797 pounds of butter. Pork Production. — (Comparison of White and Yellow Corn.) Additional data were secured during the past year on the relative values of white and yellow corn when fed to hogs under usual farm conditions. In this test 8 lots of pigs were fed white corn and 8 lots were fed yellow corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 35 The average daily gain per pig was 1.36 pounds for white corn and 1.37 for yellow corn. The pounds of grain con - sumed per 100 pounds of gain were 336.3 and 355 respec - tively. A study of the results of 3 winters' tests and 1 summer's test when 220 pigs were fattened on rations about like those used by most Nebraska farmers gives no basis for advising the farmer to pay any attention to the color of his corn, so far as its feeding value under ordinary farm conditions is concerned. Where sufficient variety is furnished in the ration and sufficient protein requirement, the gains from yellow corn have not been greater than from white corn. Sudan Grass Pasture. — Three lots of 20 spring pigs were pastured on Sudan grass in comparision with 3 similar lots pastured on alfalfa. The effect of pasture as recorded in the daily gain was about the same for the 2 kinds of pas - ture during the early part of the season when the Sudan grass was abundant and succulent. Later, when dry weather made the Sudan grass less succulent, there was a marked difference in favor of alfalfa. Similar results were obtained from 2 lots of sows that had raised spring litters that were being carried thru the summer without grain. From the 2 years' work that has been done it seems that the best quality of Sudan grass pasture is about equal to alfalfa pasture. While alfalfa continues as an excellent pasture thruout the season, Sudan grass pasture from unfavorable weather conditions and on account of its growth habits is likely to be in the best condition but a comparatively short part of the season. While Sudan grass is an excellent summer forage plant for hogs, it should not be used to the exclusion of alfalfa where the latter is available. UNION FRUIT FARM The work at this plant is primarily for the purpose of demonstrating certain practical phases of fruit production. In the 40-acre apple orchard the trees have not reached the bearing stage. The pruning and culture for the past year have followed the plan previously outlined, except that where corn is grown between the trees 2 rows less of corn was grown this year than in previous years because the trees have attained a larger size. It is now planned to use corn one year more, before beginning the clover treatment. The steeper portions of the orchard were terraced during the past year in order to prevent soil washing. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Approximately an acre is devoted to the production of grapes, the purpose being to allow for pruning and fertiliz - ing demonstrations. These are now 2 years old and during the past season a permanent trellis with steel posts was set. Considerable interest is being shown in this vicinity in the commercial production of cherries, and one acre of cherries was set in the spring of 1924 which not only will serve in pruning demonstrations but will probably answer many other questions that will arise. SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION The work at this Station is in co-operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. It is designated mainly to study the farming problems under irrigation farming. The crop rotation experiments were started in 1912. These con - sist of 97 quarter-acre plats divided into 35 different cropping systems. The cropping systems or rotations vary in length from continuous cropping up to a 7-year rotation. Some of the rotations have alfalfa or sweet clover and some receive applications of manure, while others have neither alfalfa nor sweet clover nor do they receive manure. The most outstanding feature of this work is the increased crop yield from the inclusion of alfalfa or sweet clover in the rotation or the use of barnyard manure. This shows clearly that soil fertility is an important factor in crop production on these soils. In the main the rotations containing alfalfa or sweet clover or receiving manure have been profitable, while those not so treated have been unprofitable. Commer - cial fertilizers have not materially influenced yield, which shows that the problem is not one of mineral plant food but rather one of organic and nitrogen content of the soil. Pastures. — The work with tame grass pastures was con - tinued during the past year. It bears out the results of former years, showing that annual applications of manure materially increase the carrying capacity of the pastures. Sweet Clover. — Studies with sweet clover, both for pas - ture and for soil improvement, were continued. The value of sweet clover for pasture purposes has been clearly demon - strated. Studies now under way indicate that it has the same beneficial effect on the soil as shown in the succeeding crop yields as is found with alfalfa. On a tract of land that had been cultivated for a considerable number of years without any attempt at soil maintenance, sweet clover was seeded with oats and used for pasture in the late fall and the </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 37 following year and then planted to sugar beets. The in - creased yield of beets following this treatment as compared with beets where no sweet clover had been grown was very marked. Hogs. — A number of brood sows are kept at this station and various experiments are carried on in pork production. These deal primarily with different grain rations for hogs on alfalfa pasture, comparison of heavy and light grain rations, and time of finishing hogs for market. Lamb Feeding. — Each winter for the past 4 years western lambs have been purchased on the market and fed various rations. A summarized report of the first 3 years is found in Bulletin 194. The last year's work along this line has not yet been reported. Poultry. — During the past year a poultry plant was added to the Station's equipment. A very satisfactory, prac - tical poultry house was built. Three breeds of chickens, namely. White Leghorn, Rhode Island Red, and Buff Orping - ton, were purchased. While it is hoped that practical and valuable information will be obtained, it is not the purpose to do experimental work with the poultry, but to keep them more as a demonstration as to the value of good stock and proper care. A turkey project was also started at this Station. A satis - factory hatch was obtained and a high per cent of birds grown. Breeding stock is being kept for next year's work. We feel that this entire poultry project will be very beneficial thruout this region, since there is a great deal of interest in poultry. VALENTINE SUBSTATION The climatic conditions during the past growing season were not favorable in this region. Extremely dry weather occurred during parts of the summer that materially reduced yields of grain and certain forages. Dairying. — The dairy herd consisting of Holstein-Friesian cows has been continued as in past years. Improvement in the herd is shown thru the fact that 5 or 6 heifers, sired by the senior herd bull, are now producing. All of these show increased production over their dams. The best one is pro - ducing 90 per cent more butterfat than her mother. During the past year it has cost approximately $2 to produce 100 pounds of milk. This is quite equally divided between feed and labor costs. In this locality the cost of silage is relatively high and the extra returns in milk from feeding it have no more than compensated for the cost. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Clover Projects. — The work of attempting to seed legumes in the subirrigated and wet valleys of the sand hills has been continued. The results correlate rather closely with those of preceding years. The season's work demonstrated again the unprofitableness of seeding clover where the sheet water was more than 3 feet from the surface during the spring. Some of the best clover stands are obtained where the water is not more than 12 to 16 inches below the surface in the spring. An interesting feature of this year's work was the vari - ation in the water table. During the growing season when all vegetation was using water rapidly, the water table low - ered approximately 2 feet. Soy Beans. — Varietal trials with soy beans were continued during the season. The earlier varieties matured and gave grain yields of from 4 to 8 bushels per acre. In these testrf the soy beans were seeded in rows and cultivated. When seeded broadcast they were all failures, due to lack of mois - ture. Small Grains. — Of the winter wheats, Kanred, Nebraska No. 60, and Minturki have proved hardy and ranked very close in yield. Among the spring wheats Prelude, which is much earlier than the common spring wheat, gave the high - est yield. Small grain production has not been satisfactory on the Station farm, due to the light, sandy nature of tho soil. On heavier soils on the table-land north of town, Mar - quis spring wheat gave three bushels per acre more than Prelude, and Nebraska 21 oats gave the highest yield amon&lt;? the various varieties tried. Forage Crops. — Due to unfavorable weather conditions the germination of all the sorghums and millets was very poor, consequently yields were unsatisfactory. During the past 4 years amber cane has given the highest yield of any of the strictly forage sorghums. Sudan grass has not become a very popular feed because of the low yields produced. Pasture Crops. — Neither Sudan nor sweet clover made much pasture during the past season. As above mentioned, the dry weather prevented good germination, and further - more the season continued so dry that neither crop furnished pasture after the middle of July. Turkey Project. — A turkey project was also added at this Station during the past year. Natural methods of incubation and brooding were used. When furnished shade and sour milk there was no tendency to range outside of a small field of alfalfa in which they were placed. The field, </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 39 including a small grove of trees, was enclosed with a 4-foot netting. After the poults were a week or 10 days old the hen was released from her portable coop. No attempt was made to house the poults after this age and the loss was negligible. CHANGES IN STATION STAFF Mr. G. A. Loveland, Meteorologist, resigned July 1, 1924. Mr. R. F. Howard, Chairman of the Department of Horticulture, resigned September 1, 1924. Mr. E. E. Wehr, Assistant in Entomology, resigned September 1, 1924. Mr. Don B. Whelan was appointed Assistant in Entomology Septem - ber 1, 1924. Mr. C. C. Wiggans was made Chairman of the Department of Horti - culture September 1, 1924, upon the resignation of Mr. R. F. Howard. PUBLICATIONS Three classes of publications are issued by the Agricultural Experiment Station giving the results of the various lines of investigation. These are — Station bulletins, Research bulletins, and circulars. A Station bulletin contains a defin - ite report of some particular investigations. The data obtained are presented in a manner readily understood by the average reader. Research bulletins give more detailed reports of investigations, and the information is of more technical nature. Circulars are either popular reports of experimental work or a summary of the best information obtainable on a particular line of work. As the bulletins are published, announcement is made to the public, and they may be obtained free of cost by writing to the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station. In addition to the publications put out by the Experiment Station, numerous articles, generally of a technical nature, have been written by members of the Station staff and pub - lished in technical journals and papers. The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Thirty-seventh Annual Report, by the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station; 2,000 copies. This report deals with the investiga - tional work carried on by the Experiment Station, changes in the Station staff, publications, and a financial statement. Bulletin 199, The Relation of Low Temperatures to Root Injury of the Apple. By R. F. Howard. 5,000 copies. This bulletin is a report of investigations concerning the relative hardiness of eion and stock roots of the apple, extent of injury from the low midwinter temperatures, and the effect of cultural practices on soil temperatures. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 200, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1921, 1922, and 1923. By E. E. Brackett et al. 10,000 copies. This bulletin reports the data obtained in the testing of various tractors sent in for test during the last three years. Bulletin 201, Spring Small Grains. By T. A. Kiesselbach and W. E. Lyness. 5,000 copies. This bulletin covers the experimental work done with all spring sown grains since about 1918. Certain lines of work were reported for longer periods. The principal spring sown small grains are oats, spring wheat, and barley. Varietal tests were reported with all of these crops, date of planting with spring wheat and oats, and cultural practices with oats. A comparison of the yields of various small grains, presented on a hull-free basis in pounds per acre, is given. as well as some practical suggestions for the growing of these crops. Bulletin 202, Landlords of Nebraska Farms. By J. O. Rankin 5,000 copies. This bulletin is a report of this particular phase of th« data obtained in a survey of several Nebraska communities. Bulletin 203, Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization. By H. P Davis, P. A. Downs, and Benjamin Masurovsky. 5,000 copies. This bulletin deals with the standardization of ice cream mixtures, methods for making, formulas for various classes of ice cream, tables termining the butterfat factor of milk and cream, and helpful sugges tions on ice cream manufacture. Bulletin 204, Fattening Western Lambs, 1923-1924. By H. D. F&lt; 5,000 copies. This bulletin summarizes data obtained in feeding difft quantities of linseed meal, different quantities of alfalfa molasst the use of oats during the early feeding period, the relative valut alfalfa and prairie hay, the effect of '-.hearing lambs which together with the cost data on all lambs in the experiment. Research Bulletin 26, Effect of Environment on Potato D« Diseases. By R. W. Goss. 3,000 copies. This is a rep. work and work done in the greenhouse under control conditions. I primarily with the effect of various temperatures, intensity and moisture content of the soil, on the appearance of in potatoes. Research Bulletin 27, Potato Wilt and Stem-End Rot Caused \ Fusarium Eumartii. By R. W. Goss. 4,000 copies. This bulletin dea with the distribution, economic importance, and plant symptorr disease, description of the causal organism, the relatio tors to the progress of the disease, and methods of control. Research Bulletin 28, Control Equipment for the Study of the Re tion of Environment to Disease. By George L. Peltier and R. W. G 3,000 copies. This bulletin gives detailed information concerning equip ment for the accurate control of soil moisture, soil temperatu temperature, and light, under greenhouse conditions. Experiment Station Circular 23, Bovine Tuberculosis. By L. Van Es. 10,000 copies. This circular covers quite completely the subject of bovine tuberculosis, its history, geographical distribution, cause, modes of infection, symptoms, economic importance, and means of control; alst bovine tuberculosis in other animals, including man. Experiment Station Circular 24, Better Sires — Better Stock. Bv H. P. Davis. 20,000 copies. This circular deals with the improvements made by the use of several pure bred dairy sires of the Holstein- Friesian breed. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 41 TECHNICAL ARTICLES The Analysis of Two Years' Tractor Testing. By Oscar W. Sjogren. Society of Automotive Engineers, Vol. 12, No. 6. The Newer Knowledge of the Role of Gelatine in Ice Cream Making. By Benjamin Masurovsky. Ice Cream Trade Journal, Vol. 20, No. 3. The Five Essential Steps in Ice Cream Making. By Benjamin Masurovsky. Ice Cream Review, Vol. 7, No. 11, p. 26. The Relative Effects of Foreign Pollen upon the Kernel Weight of Corn. T. A. Kiesselbach and G. C. Cook. Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 16, No. 1. Relation of Seed Size to the Yield of Small Grain Crops. By T. A. K iesse lbach. Journal of American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 16, No. 10. ACCEPTED FOR PUBLICATION The Chromosome Number of Corn, Zea mays. By T. A. Kiesselbach and N. F. Peterson. Genetics, January, 1925. The Occurrence of .Starch and Erythrodextrin in Corn and Their Segregation in the Pollen of Hybrids. T. A. Kiesselbach and N. F. Peterson. Genetics, January, 1925. The Study of Phosphorus, Calcium, and Alkaline Reserves of the Blood Sera of Normal and Rachitic Chicks. C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl. Journal of Biological Chemistry. Two New Soil Thermometers. J. C. Russel and E. G. Jones. Journal American Society of Agronomy. Studies on the Moisture Equivalent of Soils. J. C. Russel and W. W. Burr, in Soil Science. Progress Report on the Nutritive Requirements of Growing Chicks. F. E. Mussehl and Paul Bancroft. Poultry Science. The Effect of Low Temperatures on the Apparent Fertility and Hatching Power of Eggs. F. E. Mussehl and Paul Bancroft. Poultry Science. Report of Certain Investigations of the Central Nebraska Supple - ental Irrigation Project. W. W. Burr and J. C. Russel. In the Annual Report of Nebraska State Department of Public Works. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly news - papers, especially those papers located within the state, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experimental Station by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of usefu 1 agri - cultural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1924, under act of Conjrress approved March 2, 1887. Total $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries. $15,000.CH Total. ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1924, under act of Conjrress. ap - proved March 16, 1906. Total 115 Expenditures For salaries. $15,000.0 Total. $15,000.00 L. E. GUNDERSOX, At Lincoln, Nebraska, January 21, 1925. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 43 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— (Continued) Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station )f the University of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1924 the y^ar ending June 30, 1924 (exclusive of Federal funds) SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees $70,944.76 Temporary employees 201.18 Agricultural supplies and feed. 26,559.38 I Total. 36,546.92 KXPENSES Office expense, postage, telephone &amp; telegraph Freight, express and drayage $ 468.76 1,260.49 4,071.20 6,615.21 Fuel, light, heat, water, and power Publishing, printing, and advertising. Traveling expense 2,554.25 17,816.24 Miscellaneous Total. * 32,786.15 MATERIALS, PARTS, AND REPAIRS FOR Buildings Grounds Upkeep of property - UPKEEP $ 2,939.00 1,619.88 5,078.02 Total S 9,636.90 EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures. $ 946.81 4,139.76 16,605.72 Laboratory supplies Livestock Machinery 5,263.30 Books and magazines 271.48 Total I 27,227.07 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land Buildings $ 792.19 672.88 Total. $ 1,465.07 Grand total. $178,808.05 This includes expenditures for the central station at the Agricultural Campus and the substations at Scottsbluff, North Platte, and Valentine. L. E. GUNDERSON, At Lincoln, Nebraska, Finance Secretary. January 21, 1925. Total $ &gt; 71, 5.' UPPLIES Office supplies $ 755.99 Laboratory supplies 6,728.09 Food 2,163.35 Educational 232.47 Janitor 107.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 THE PURNELL ACT [Public — No. 458 — 68th Congress] [H. R. 1ST An Act To authorise the more complete endowment of agricultural experi - ment stations, and for other purpose* Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled. That for the more complete endowment and maintenance of agricul - tural experiment stations now established, or which may here - after be established, in accordance with the Act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, there is hereby authorized to be appropriated, in addition to the amounts now received by such agricultural experiment stations, the sum of $20,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1926; $30,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1927 ; $40,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1928; $50,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1929; $60,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1930 ; and $60,000 for each fiscal year thereafter, to be paid to each State and Territory; and the Secretary of Agriculture shall include the additional sums above authorized to be appropriated in the annual estimates of the Department of Agriculture, or in a separate estimate, as he may deem best. The funds appropri - ated pursuant to this Act shall be applied only to paying the necessary expenses of conducting investigations or making ex - periments bearing directly on the production, manufacture, preparation, use, distribution, and marketing of agricultural products and including such scientific researches as have for their purpose the establishment and maintenance of a perma - nent and efficient agricultural industry, and such economic and sociological investigations as have for their purpose the development and improvement of the rural home and rural life, and for printing and disseminating the results of said researches. Sec. 2. That the sums hereby authorized to be appropriated to the States and Territories for the further endowment and support of agricultural experiment stations shall be annually paid in equal quarterly payments on the 1st day of January, April, July, and October of each year by the Secretary of the Treasury upon a warrant of the Secretary of Agriculture out of the Treasury of the United States, to the treasurer or other officer duly appointed by the governing boards of such agri - cultural experiment stations to receive the same and such officers shall be required to report to the Secretary of Agri - culture on or before the 1st day of September of each year a </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Thirty-Eighth Annual Report 45 detailed statement of the amount so received and of its dis - bursement on schedules prescribed by the Secretary of Agri - culture. The grants of money authorized by this Act are made subject to legislative assent of the several States and Territories to the purpose of said grants : Provided, That pay - ment of such installments of the appropriation herein author - ized to be made as shall become due to any State or Territory before the adjournment of the regular session of the legis - lature meeting next after the passage of this Act shall be made upon the assent of the governor thereof duly certified to the Secretary of the Treasury. Sec. 3. That if any portion of the moneys received by the designated officer of any State or Territory for the further and more complete endowment, support, and maintenance of agri - cultural experiment stations as provided in this Act shall by any action or contingency be diminished or lost or be mis - applied, it shall be replaced by said State or Territory to which it belongs, and until so replaced no subsequent appro - priation shall be apportioned or paid to such State or Terri - tory, and no portion of said moneys exceeding 10 per centum of each annual appropriation shall be applied directly or in - directly, under any pretense whatever, to the purchase, erec - tion, preservation, or repair of any building or buildings or to the purchase or rental of land. It shall be the duty of each &lt; ;f the said stations annually, on or before the 1st day of February, to make to the governor of the State or Territory in which it is located a full and detailed report of its opera - tions, including a statement of receipts and expenditures for the fiscal year next preceding, a copy of which report shall !&gt;e sent to each of the said stations and the Secretary of Agri - culture and to the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States. Sec. 4. That on or before the 1st day of July in each year after the passage of this Act the Secretary of Agriculture shall ascertain and certify to the Secretary of the Treasury as to each State and Territory whether it is complying with the provisions of this Act and is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriations for agricultural experiment sta - tions under this Act and the amount which thereupon each is entitled, respectively, to receive. If the Secretary of Agri - culture shall withho'd from any State or Territory a certifi - cate of its appropriation, the facts and reasons therefor shall be reported to the President and the amount involved shall be kept separate in the Treasury until the close of the next Congress in order that the State or Territory may, if it shall </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station so desire, appeal to Congress from the determination of the Secretary of Agriculture. If the next Congress shall not direct such sum to be paid, it shall be covered into the Treas - ury. The Secretary of Agriculture is hereby charged with the proper administration of this law. Sec. 5. That the Secretary of Agriculture shall make an annual report to Congress on the receipts and expenditures and work of the agricultural experiment stations in all of the States and Territories, and also whether the appropria - tion of any State or Territory has been withheld ; and if so, the reason therefor. Sec. 6. That Congress may at any time amend, suspend, or repeal any and all of the provisions of this Act. Approved, February 24, 1925. </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>