<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00024.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00024.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">Fifth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1910 1910 Thb Woodbott Bank Nom Co. Lincoln, N: </seg>
            <seg id="p002">F. L. HALLER, President, Omaha, Nebraska S. AVERY, Chancellor of the University of Nebraska E. C. BISHOP, State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY, State Librarian DR. W. K. JEWETT, Librarian of the University of Nebraska CHARLOTTE TEMPLETON, Secretary GUESS HUMPHREY, Librarian </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL To Hit Excellency, A. C. Shallenberger, Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sir: Complying with the requirement of the law, I herewith present the report of the Public Library Commission for the biennium ending November 30, 1910. This report of our Secretary, which shows the activities of the Commission and the library conditions of Nebraska is commended to your Very respectfully yours, F. L. Hallbr, President. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">J* T-&lt; u \ g • • • • zn K • V. • • • </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Commission Public Libraries 5 NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION During the biennium there have been two changes in the personnel of the Commission. Dr. S. Avery succeeded E. Benjamin Andrews as Chancellor of the University of Nebraska and E. C. Bishop succeeded J. L. McBrien as Superintendent of Public Instruction; Dr. Avery and Mr. Bishop thus becoming ex officio members of the Public Library Commission. During the biennium semi-annual meetings of the Com - mission have been held in April and November of each year, and the usual business transacted. At each annual meeting F. L. Haller has been re-elected president. The Commission was represented at the annual meeting of the American Library Association at Bretton Woods, N. H. in 1909, by the Secretary and Librarian and at the meeting at Mackinac in 1910 by the Secretary, Dr. Jewett and H. C. Lindsay. The Secretary also attended the mid-winter meetings of the League of Library Commissions in Chicago in 1908 and 1909. During the past biennium the towns of Alliance, Alma, Ponca and Schuyler have passed library ordinances, made levies and established public libraries. At Pierce, Friend, Laurel, Clay Center and Gibbon, library associations have been formed which have started libraries free to the public and maintained by the efforts of the association. In Broken Bow an old library club turned over its books and a building to a new library association which is maintaining a free public library open every day of the week. In Aurora, Chadron, Madison, Minden, Norfolk, North Bend and Wayne, libraries which were organized by library associations have been turned over to the towns for support. Kthe sixty-seven libraries reported a year ago four seem ve at present. With thirteen new libraries organized ; the biennium we now have seventy-six active libraries, six of these are supported by tax; seventeen are main - 1 by library associations free to the public; and the re - ig three are what we call subscription libraries; that is, &gt;rrowers pay for the use of the books. I our last biennial report we stated that there were five i having a population of over 2000 which were without ies. The organization of libraries in Alliance and Schuy - is reduced this number to three and there now remain Auburn, North Platte and Wahoo in this class. North e, however has an excellent Y. M. C. A. library which ihes the town with reading. Comparing the number of libraries at the present time with the number previously reported, the figures show that we now </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Traveling Libraries 6 have seventy-six as compared with sixty-seven two years ago, and with twenty-six nine years ago. During the biennium library buildings have. been completed in Fairbury, Lincoln, Norfolk, Superior, and Neligh; and build - ings are under way in Aurora, Chadron, David City, Alliance, Alma and Sutton. All of these, with the exception of the library at David City, have been given by Mr. Carnegie. Twenty-nine libraries are now in buildings of their own. With almost no exception Nebraska libraries have good systems of administration. This is largely due to their new - ness no doubt, since two thirds of them have been organized since the establishment of the Public Library Commission and have availed themselves of the assistance and advice which the Commission stands ready to give. The standards of librarianship are unusually high. We have sixteen librarians who have had regular library school training; fifteen who have taken summer courses and many who have taken the correspondence course offered by the Library Commission. Evidence of their interest in professional advancement is shown in the attendance at the meetings of the State Library Association. At the meeting held in Lin - coln in October of this year there were about seventy-five persons present, representing forty libraries. The Commission has given assistance in organizing to the libraries at Norfolk, Chadron, Alliance, Osceola, Humboldt, Pierce, Ponca, Schuyler, Friend, Laurel, Broken Bow, Clay Center and Gibbon. The secretary visited fifty-one libraries during the biennium and in addition to making personal visits has carried on a large correspondence, giving advice in regard to organizing and administering libraries. During the biennium we have made some changes in our traveling libraries. Originally we made up the fixed groups on the basis of ten books of fiction, ten books of non-fiction and twenty books for children. The proportion of non-fiction seemed large and we decided several years ago to put in eight books of non-fiction to twelve of fiction; at the same time en - deavoring to put in only readable non-fiction. Still libraries came back with some books practically unread and a year ago we made a further change. We took out all non-fiction except such books as Riis's "Making of an American" and Booker Washington's "Up from Slavery" which almost rank with fiction in popularity, leaving a fixed group of thirty-five vol - umes. To each library that we send out we add from five to fifteen volumes, suiting as far as possible the needs and tastes of the community. The books of non-fiction taken out form a reserve collection from which we draw to send books to study clubs, to indi - vidual students, or to fill out a traveling library in a community which expresses a desire for reading along special lines. In </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Women's Clubs and The Commission 7 During the biennium we have sent out 17,932 volumes in in response to 442 requests for general traveling libraries, compared with 17,280 volumes and 432 requests of the last biennium. In our special loan work we have sent out 4,921 volumes in response to 636 requests as compared with 2,789 volumes and 388 requests of two years ago. The total number of volumes sent out was 22,853 and the total number of re - quests 1,078. That the use of the books has been widely dis - tributed over the state will be seen from the map appended. During the bienniam we have sent books to eighty-three counties. The collection of Bohemian books which was barely ready for circulation at the time of our last report has proved popular and twenty-six towns have availed themselves of this oppor - tunity of getting books in the Bohemian language. The twenty-five Bohemian libraries have been out ninety-four times since the spring of 1908. I nee the establishment of the Library Commission, largely ugh the efforts of the Nebraska Federation of Women's 98, there has always existed a close relationship between clubs and the Commission. Two years ago when the ncial needs of the Commission were pressing, the clubs of state undertook to interest the legislature in the work of Commission and the result was an increase of $2,000 in biennial appropriation. This has enabled us to buy a great many books needed for study and to assist the clubs more than ever before. In ad - dition to the books loaned to individuals to aid them in the preparation of special topics we have made up study group libraries to send out to clubs for the whole winter, covering as fully as possible the year's work. This fall we sent out thirty-one such study groups. We have also made suggestions to program committees and have assisted in outlining courses of study for women's clubs. The clubs are working away from the "miscellaneous" pro - gram and we are assisting them, as far as we are able, to take up definite lines of work. iist winter the Art Department of the State Federation some money in its possession and decided to purchase ographs of famous paintings to be used by the art clubs le state. They sought the cooperation of the Library mission and the Commission made up three study libraries 'rench, Dutch, and English painting and the Art Depart - t supplied three portfolios of photographs of the most ble paintings of the various schools, to accompany the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 The Library Commission has cooperated with the university extension department of the State University and has supplied students taking the course on Abraham Lincoln with the neces - sary books for study. For this purpose the Commission bought sixteen sets of the complete works of Abraham Lincoln and seven copies of the "Life of Lincoln," by Tarbell, and thirteen copies of the life by Morse. The constant use of these books has justified their purchase and the Commission may well consider developing this line of work further. Books for University Extension bourses The Schools and the One of the activities of the Commission which is not shown in statistics, is assisting in the selection of books for school libraries. The secretary serves as an advisory member of the Reading Circle Committee which makes up each year suggestive lists of books for school libraries. She also gives a great deal of advice to individual teachers. A count was made of the letters from teachers and school directors for help in book selection which came between September and April of last year and it was found that the Commission had answered 125 such requests. Commission Library I called attention in my last report to the need of amending our library law to provide for some means by which library privileges may be extended to country people. A library extension bill was drawn up and introduced in the last session of the legislature but failed to pass; not, I believe, from op - position, but rather from indifference. Extension According to our present law, only incorporated towns and cities may establish libraries and tax themselves for their maintenance. There certainly should be some provision by which people living outside the corporation limits might, if they so desired, enter into a contract with a town library for the enjoyment of its privileges, or by which they might, if they chose, establish a library of their own. From the rapidly' increasing number of libraries we may complacently consider that we have adequate library facili - ties, but when we come to study figures, we find that we have not reached an ideal condition by any means. While the in - habitants of our large towns are fairly well provided for, in the small towns the book collections are usually pitifully meagre, and there still remains our large rural population practically untouched by the library movement. We have in Nebraska, by the census of 1900, 1,068,539 persons. The towns having libraries have a total population of 308,736. It will be seen that only BS% of our people have access to libraries. The total number of volumes in the public libraries of the state is 203,946. So it will be seen that even the fortunate 28 % have less than a book a piece. To be sure, each library has a few </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Libraries in State Institutions 9 out of town patrons, but the number is so small as to be almost negligible. Let us estimate it at 2% of the total population, and consider that 30% of our people have some sort of library privileges. There still remains 70% unprovided for. The State Traveling Library is doing its best with the limited re - sources at its command but it can reach comparatively few. What we need is a strong system of local libraries, supported by town and country people alike, so that it cannot be said, in this democracy which should mean "an equal opportunity for all" that less than one third of our people have the free use of books. We have made a great to-do over the library movement; we have felt it our duty to see that every one has proper reading; the dwellers in cities and towns through public libraries, the rural population through traveling libraries, but with all this we have ignored a large number of our citizens, a class of citizens who need most the beneficent influence of books, a class who are in no position to know their needs or to clamor for their rights, — the wards of the state, the inmates of our state in - stitutions. We have upwards of 4000 of these unfortunates in Nebraska and so far practically nothing has been done to supply them with reading which is well chosen and adapted to their peculiar needs. I think that it is time that we turned our attention in this direction. All of our institutions are pitifully in need of the right kind of books. Such libraries as there are, are largely the result of indiscriminate generosity. Very little money has been spent and that not always with wisdom. The meagre collections of books which they have are ill-cared for and are not used to the best advantage. I am not criticizing the present ad - ministration; the condition is the result of a wrong system of control of state institutions. One can hardly expect a man who is in charge of a state institution possibly for only two years, who has had no previous training for work which de - mands the most highly specialized education, and who has no money for the work in hand, to build up and wisely use a good collection of books. Insidering the existing system of control in Nebraska, i seemed to the persons moat interested in this subject, the most satisfactory method of doing efficient library in the various institutions, would be to centralize the in the State Library Commission. This Commission ; of politics, it is fairly permanent, and it already has the hinery" for book ordering, cataloging, and library or - ing. A thoroughly qualified librarian should be added e staff of the Commission to take charge of the work; a n who would combine a knowledge of books with a sym - pathy and insight into the needs of the various unfortunates, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 who would divide her time among the different institutions, going over the old libraries, weeding out the undesirable books, organizing the collections into working libraries, getting in touch with the attendants and inspiring them to make the utmost use of these tools at their command. There should be an appropriation for the purchase of new books, to be divided among the various institutions according to their needs. It has been estimated that a biennial appropriation of $7500.00 would make a very creditable beginning for this work; $2500.00 to be used for salaries and supplies and $5000.00 to be used for books. SUMMARY OF STATISTICS, NOVEMBER 30, 1910 Volumes in library, December 1, 1908 7,084 Additions, Nov. 30, 1908-Nov. 30, 1910 By gift 358 By purchase 1,566 Total 1,924 Withdrawn, Nov. 30, 1908-Nov. 30, 1910... 197 Volumes in the library, Nov. 30, 1910 8,811 Number of volumes sent out, 1908-1910 22,853 Number of requests in answer to which books were sent . . 1,078 EXPENDITURES, NOV. 30, 1908-NOV. 30, 1910 Books $1,518.64 Printing 82.50 Office expenses 1,102.79 Librarian 1,633.34 Total $7,735.33 Appropriation for 1909-1911 $8,000.00 Expended from 1909-1911 appropriation 6,900.36 Balance, Nov. 30, 1910 $1,099.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">5 m lirfPld j|s liil H^ m p {i P lm P ?o n x n x r ' "*■ jq ' *"• a: S ' oo -^ .£ ib il t-^&gt; IBS* ■ -W*w4 ■ OO00 ■© ■* 00 91 ■ ■ 00OS &lt;it- ••»«O«O ■ ■ O&lt;-1 ■ 00OO O ■ ■* CT100 M ■ - 00M 5O^_ ■ 00 t^.M ■ tO to ■ ■MO'-i O M ■»!-! CM ©CO «?•» :Mf2°^ ■ ■ ■ looV : .atfoto :co" :© :m"c» :V : : t-^M "■•« .... . . .y-&gt; MM . . . MM II eo«o©©o©© oj©^.-! om &lt;-&gt; ■© M us to ■ .-i^ir- tcoooooo ■ io-*m© -&lt;t- c» ■© ■*- oo -eo ■ -eoM&gt;o «&gt;M «00©^ ■* ©t- -^OO ■* -»Ii ■•* ■«&gt; &lt;C ■ -HMO eo" p* p* I p« ! ! ! ! 'Heo' . . . ... » l_ : :__: ; ocook-icoooo •©©•*» ©Mcnco - oo •t-nO'* Ortosio ©moco^oooo o&gt;ooom ©^"t-to ©&lt;e ioioo&gt;a ©.""l^ 1 e i.°°.O.CM-«D t-COt&gt;M_ t-&gt;o^00_^ • 00O «^eo_«5u^ COCO^t-^ m"&lt;-T i-T i -J'm"-&lt; i-Ti-T ' M"eo"co" ! ' eo* .-^V) •-" ! &gt;o^V a : . ... i oous eo^eo o • ■©© • ■ -oohq © us oois o ■ -^c-io &gt;oio c-coeo © o^ ' ' 1 ~'.' 3i . 0 . °. °. t ~: °. °5 e i'^! t-e» !t~Meo '© !©t~ ! ! .to-^ci .m .t^ .eiei !© ! © - -o ad U300 MtO^ M COCO . .OIC-J CO M &lt;OCO M . :••::: :** :^ : : SS5 ?D 00 :^oo-«ii o M i ©O OVHOO ■ - t~ ■ - Nl-rt O HJ5 M CO •© OOMO ouj oqioaiqq to oiut^ © "« •*"* © »o«oco ojuj locooious ' ; '^ ' ; ;»h©i-&lt; ;© ;i-^ ;«j&gt;d ;© ;nm*» OOCA U3U3&lt;OU3CO O i-icnco "S .i-l .CAt-&gt; .O M99IIO moo ...•"!.. .eoMeo . &lt; .eo .-*t- .1-1 . s « - gg ggggg : : :g : : :SS3 § £ S§ g : :§§§ us© ©Meet-© © ' ' '©©&gt;-« !m !^" !©co :© ' oo© &lt;om&gt;omco oo ' -*mo&gt; .eo . t- .© . .^co-"? &lt;m&gt;-i mm I : ! |S ! ! !iS . ••• .•* ■*» .eo . . o© a ■ i I S3 :gS3 g :ggg : : : SK :t S 5S § : Sgg cooi &lt;ood«d © 'mg&gt;o uid '^ .oj .t--t- © ! mous oot- :t-eo«e :© :t-»-i© : . : mi- .© m «ooo .•* . o»©«&gt; ust- "5. is . . . .^»o .eo .^j_ *i«i .«© . co©^&gt;-" •* ■ com ;"* ; J i^ 6^ : : ' «^*» | I o : iooo ■ ■©■•©© OO oo © © t-o» ■ • ■ m -eo t-f; ■ IONOO °O "^ O "-J • ■ &lt;C 00 com eoeeus© c- t- .© .oo coo . o» 3 •» ; iM'V »5 : jj . ■ e9l 1 . . . eo •* SS SSI : : i~:g§ : : :| 1 :B :■ :2§ :§ : pO HiO (OQQ ' tOQ ' O O O | CO 'COO O ' OiO U3U3 t-OO — &lt; O OJ O O CO 00 -« B«H tot* hnio to n io oj!co.cAo;co;.;ot- • hn • ■ ; ; ;-h ; ; w ■ i-l ■ i-i • • • cm ■-i x l« OOHOOAOOOHHOnOO Olr-OOO ©OO©O©Oi-if-i00O [ liiliiiliiililliili! </seg>
            <seg id="p012">2 1 111 "Si c"^J : s|-g „ Is g c fclliiillig llg:lMiilli S E E E* J l| 2 E E E E E"| |j :| J Sf | E El|i I | &gt;| 5 E E E t-C-J «O O» U5 5O 00 00 © CM -91OO4 t— - CO CO O &amp; ■ T)&lt; O t~ CO © I~- -tt ■ t- 1- •"-&gt; N &lt;o © i-H us©iot- oo t-o&gt;o&gt;e» ■ nocom osco ■^&lt;o '^L e»osooo&gt;_©t^M e»e5u3t-^ © io©eoo^ l ~.'° c^. e ?. &gt;&gt;H 1 oo"©" 't-^ io &lt;e-*io&gt;o&gt;'B &lt;o&lt;d oo" !oT ' evru5"o»eo" ' O9"i-?eo"i-r ;io"»o •h .eo .t- i-i . &lt;e . . . . . i-&lt; . ;S : cm . . : : : if "5 s «DOOOO&gt;t-COO&gt;U30©0000© OMOCnXrtN&lt;D»Hio^^ • 00 ■«» cm eo oo n t- oi i-i oo «o te © t- © ■* © • us -^ © us to t- cm o&gt; us to oo co e- co t-«o oooo«ei&gt;^^'&gt;o^»-"©_u5©eot-eM"i'-i •-i'- 1 1- tM cm ■&gt;* useo t-eoo»-^'CM_ «Ht- »" o" co" h :V t-T eo ; oovpN&lt;D'&lt;i"Ot-oniooKOoooot-^booo*"oioa&gt;o6-»os:« eMt-©00t— t-—l&gt;0©CMt-lOi-l©i-l©tCt-«D©«DOO©lOTjiiOCO©OJTl'©0&gt;^&gt; 1 COlO©tQ-^&lt;M3'^&lt;CO©CCOOiaoOGM©^ l O&gt;lCCO©C0t~CO'^&lt;OOCOlQOOOSi-*CMOO© i^eJ^t^' oo" •&amp;r*r**By-t i-Ti-T eo" &gt;- T^T -^T i-I'i-Tom""-? ob"i-T eo" CM OO I t-»ooe«soo •© • • • •©©©©«&gt;©© ■ us «rHo&lt;o^ t-«e c&gt;i ■ - - o&gt; © 05 io c-j us Tt - to c ?'~ l cmoc o© ©cj c-i» '© ' ' ' ' o&gt; © n »o fH oi c&gt;i ' "e» '&lt;-&lt;eo"sr-e4 'toa» uxoooHt-mt- eo ' .toioiot-'"* us . .^ t-iot-uso tei-i eoeo&gt;-i'4 l t-*»«o »neo»o ih ujHHHt- . eo us &lt;e •** t-T • ! HOOOOI'iOt-O^ -CM ■ OQOOCOO) '(OOOt-^i&lt;n -CMO)^ •CM"'*' ■HOOOONt^^tote -^ ■ ©©»-&lt;eooo •-&lt; © © t-; t-; rf ■«a'eo^i| o»cm ddooisndndt- ! »h ' t^©t^eo«o oiujusoicnoi '»n«eeK 't~e&gt;i cm os © © t- «-i co © io cm .© . .HHioHoo .ooe»eMeo oo .i-iooco ;«oco rteo^-ieo &lt;o«*-eo H .S . .** »rtH —in f .cm eft . m eo • • us • ■ .1 IO OOOoSo-^OO © ©S -COO© dOOOOiSOMOCOOOO ui6(sdc«an«d :© load Itousod :td6o6iete6iat^o6n'd6io &lt;e©'-l©NOi0500CC-* .© .CM«-l .Nt-«O . O&gt; 00 ■* CO &lt;N t- (M ■&gt;* to t- &lt;O Oi t- &gt;o &lt;e cm oj --I o&gt; •» tji eg N .h .»-iej .eo eo . i-ieo f-innNH »-ie4 "* : : :S : ** " I &lt;-i(0©0 &gt;&gt;O314&gt; t- © tOOi 000000 00O9CM OOO ••* • ■© "*c&gt;)oc© -oiosrH oq •© ©oo eooocsj oi©©eo ©o»© •© • to odt^t-^c&gt; odoio oo &gt;d °oi© «5c^eo 't^ooiid "Scot-^ 'V ! - i-^ «ot-en© MtDoi .ej t- .eo© .-ftfee .eooo-«© .oosoo .e&lt;j . .cm ©_©_i/s t- h ,ia . &gt;o . ©_^« . t-^ej oo . e» eo &gt;o . ej_eM . o» . . t- r*r* r-T -of**?-? • • -T+ tO -H '^ • - ■-C CM ■ -J* ■ • ■ i o 5cvio ooujSooo © o© -atoonq -co©© ©o - ■© oco oo't-io id^oooioo 'us Ic^iiN iot~oio °&lt;-&lt;ciod 'ujrn ' n ;«t- «O&lt;O&gt;O . P) &gt;O O) t~ d ' t- C5«O . t- .«"*&lt;-! .©&lt;^ . .*-&gt; .rHCM rHMiMNot- . : s :S m : »n:t- .: &lt;*&gt;.&lt;-&gt; s ooo - oo^ o o ■© ©oo ■ tt o ai toon osiooqo lO ,°, f'od : :-*nc&gt; :© :© :©od :©©« : \ccdt~ :©Nt&gt;.-«.-&lt; :©© —i ■&gt;* t-ioo © .© .©eo .t-^c-c . .Tf©oo .OocootOH .o»© ©eo . t-i^i^i .3 .35 .©cm .onio . coiqcm »ocM-*"*t- .h* t"iOOO9) t O* H 04t v t i &gt;C0^ l 00CfiX ■ t-» ■ 00 00 CO © 91OO • 5| 00 ■ O9)O)0)Ot~OOOO9)OOOO t~ OOOOQOh -©©A - © 00 *Q0 AOOQOOO9&gt;QOO)0}9}C)OOO1O)AO) 00 A A9101OO A -0)0)00 -OS 00 ■ 00 ■ I ::::::::::&amp;: j :::::^ ::::::::::« j :: ::.'■'■■'■'■■ : 5 : • :&gt; 2 '■ '■ '■&amp; '■ '■ ••$ '■,'• '• ■ '■ -H ■ '■ ■ «1 lHlli llS|l|L-3l If ill ililllilll </seg>
            <seg id="p013">S*^^ c w c 5oSSSSSS|Sh t-©T* "t-OO H(J OO 00 CO NtCO ■ t— O m ■ -^ r; o^ ~* ~ — — .- op«o«c OCOU3CO O l-0«50 ©OS«5U5 -HMOS ■M r*00 ©«o -os t-oooosco ©&lt;O ■fl" MOOOONIO O &gt;-&lt; *o id io in a; 6 oc Htc &gt;o t- t-i t~ evi t- o CM &gt;-l rtr&lt;lO ooomooocc-iQO OOOCCOOOOX5OO eoonooooec'- - ©aou9Mtc«&gt;w«riM&lt;a«c CM N i-l U5 flO IO 1O 00 •-" OO ?l 5 qioni-; -w toot-n tD&lt;O(BH rt ?Ii-ic~O3 53 ■*■* si k! So oo ©&lt;e© t-oo &lt;^e&gt;f !t^ '.n ri '.■*■* RO&gt;OOOOOr4&gt;C os os en © &gt;-&gt; u^eo^w t-7 t-T t-i i-4v*iQ OritCO ' C". W •-« &lt;-l ■ .Q — jS a B 5 a, "5 © go o »*»»&lt;_,»&lt; Sj3 c O 00© © C4t-«^O Bc^5«O 35 . to .11 MrtO . ; S,5' "S*r : : ~^ — " k£ I* S'k5"55'S '■'■'■'■■' ' -°^^tt-e-stit ■"•••'■ t. ■ a) 1) O O O « O O C ; ; ; • : : # - • • ? ■ MZc.c.aa.Q,ii liiili" </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATE LIBRARIES NOT ALREADY MENTIONED " TOWN SCHOOL No. of Vols. LIBRARIAN Bellevue* Bethany* College View*..;! p TunKiin Grand Island* Hastings* Kearney Bellevue College Cotner University Dana College Union College Doane College Franklin Academy Baptist College Hastings College State Normal School University of Nebraska Gates Academy Brownell Hall Creighton University State Normal School Wesleyan University Luther Academy Weeping Water Academy.. York College 5,542 2,600 Helen Byram 2^420 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '. 11,000 W. E. Jillson 4,990 7,000 Harriet Craig 6,300 Emma Cadwallader 5,295 Anna V. Jennings 87,007 Dr. W. K. Jewett l!900 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 28,250 17,000 Elva E. Rulon 7,486 : May Ingles 5,280 Aleda C. Johnson 2^400 Blanche Bagg University Place. Wahoo Weeping Water*. •Reports m »t received in 1910. Numbei of volumes rei &gt;rted in 1908. TOWN INSTITUTION %? icoln State Library 62,843 icoln State Historical Society 32,100 icoln Penitentiary 2,650 ASSOCIATION LIBRARIES tPlatte Y. M. C. A y Jefferson County Teachers' Library 3,000 1,600 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>