<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE COMMANDANT OF THE Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkett, Nebraska To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">kt &amp; I k s- I •Y \fS^ "*%■ «&gt;. k. U ■ 82 c &lt; ■ ; ' « \ * -*9J r- *F 2 I &lt; LU i ! M i c ;_ '&lt; I 1 i ■» " "^B -n </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE COMMANDANT OF THE Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914 Burkett, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">162 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I hereby submit to you a detailed report of the condi - tion and the future necessities of this institution. By care - ful study and examination you, I think, will agree with me that this report is very conservative, especially as to the future necessities of this institution. While they may ap - pear at first sight to be large, when you consider the condition the institution was in when I took charge of it, you will no doubt see the necessity of making the improve - ments that I am asking for which are, in my judgment, absolutely necessary for the welfare of the members of the institution as well as the management and a credit to the State of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 163 ESTIMATED EXPENSES FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM, 1915-1917 Officers' Salaries Year Biennium Commandant $1,500 $3,000 Adjutant 90O..._ 1,800 Surgeon _ 1,200 _ 2,400 Matron 500 1,000 Engineer 1,020 2,040 Night Engineer 600. 1.200 Farm Manager 600. ....'.... 1,200 Bookkeeper and Stenographer 600 1,200 $6,920 $13,840 Employees' Wages Serg. Major $ 480 Orderly 480 Commissary 600 Asst. Commissary 120 Driver 480 Florist .'. 480 Butcher 600 Fireman, 4 3720 Farm hands, 5 3000 Dairyman, 2 1200 Teamster (WO Yardman 480 Gardener 400 Laundry help 8600 Cooks 5400 Baker 1200 Hospital Matron 960 Nurses 7680 Table waiters, 11 4200 Dishwashers, 3 1200 Janitors 2520 Night watch" 480 Librarian 120 Sexton : 360 S403fi0 $175,000 Maintenance 67,800 General repairs (consisting of the following) 1 vault for office $1,500 1200 ft tunnel for steam and water mains, in - cluding all complete 7,500 Plumbing, a complete overhauling 9,000 Boiler, 125 H. P. installed 2,500 New engine and generator, 150 H. P., installed 4,000 Ice plant, 5 ton capacity, complete 3,000 Shop machinery, including lathe, drill, pipe thread - ing machine, etc 1,500 Boiler compound and white waste 1,500 Street lights 800 Addition to power house and new roof for the whole building 4,000 1 new pump, deep well 3,000 Electrical supplies 8,000 Re-wiring of the main building 1,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">164 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Elevator 1,500 Repairing: and painting all the buildings on the in - side and outside with the exception of the East Brick Hospital and the inside of the West Hos- pital 25,000 Total appropriation for biennium $287,000 ESTIMATED VALUATION OF FARM PROPERTY ON HAND NOV. 20, 1914 Horses and Mules: Eight head work horses Two driving horses $ 600 250 Four mules Cattle: _ 700 $1550 Thirty-four milch cows ..$2500 Forty-nine stock steers and heifers Two bulls 2000 200 Ten calves Hogs: 150 4850 Eighteen fat hogs. ... Fourteen brood sows Fifteen stock hogs $ M 200 100 625 Carriages and Wagons: One spring wagon One carriage 86 25 One carry-all (pall-bearers wagon) Five wagons 250 150 450 Farm Implements and Tools: Two hay racks One Dane stacker Two sweeps One rake One harrow Two gang plows Two Sterling plows One potato digger One potato planter One McCormick reaper Two McCormick mowers One silo cutter, complete Two one-horse lawn mowers One disc One disc cultivator Two cultivators, walking Two fertilizers One roller One corn binder One corn planter Two post diggers Eight scoop shovels Three picks Seven shovels Three hand rakes Two garden plows Two garden harrows Three lawn mowers :iu 25 ■lit 20 10 50 15 5 HO 51) 60 200 50 25 25 20 60 10 100 40 2 X 3 7 2 10 .50 15 One sickle grinder 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 165 ESTIMATED VALUATION OF FARM PROPERTY ON HAND NOV. 20, 1914— (Continued). One grind stone 2 Curry combs and brushes :i Seven pitch forks 7 Five garden hoes 5 Six sets double harness 120 One set light harness _ 20 Two lap robes _ _ 20 1106 Grand total _ _ - $8581 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCE 1912-1913 1913-1914 Pork 16146 lbs. $1614.60 6449 lbs. $ 644.90 Beef 15890 lbs. 1430.10 Lard 480 lbs. 48.00 Milk 27315 gal. 3277.80 50466 gal. 6055.92 Wheat _ 956 bu. 736.00 1600 bu. 1200.00 Corn 600 bu. 300.00 Oats _ 1000 bu. 400.00 Alfalfa hay 225 ton 1125.00 500 ton 2500.00 Prairie hay 45 ton 225.00 Oat hay 25 ton 80.00 Straw 20 ton 30.00 Silage 125 ton 625.00 150 ton 750.00 Onions 22% bu. 11.25 44 bu. 33.00 Cabbage 1725 hd. 100.00 3000 hd. 75.00 Beets ..._ 38V4 bu. 43.12 50 bu. 33.00 Sweet corn 70 bu. 70.00 330 doz. 50.00 Tomatoes ! 5 bu. 2.60 100 bu. 50.00 Greens 31 bu. 15.50 50 bu. 25.00 Carrots _ - 4 bu. 2.00 20 bu. 10.00 Parsnips 6 bu. 3.00 65 bu. 32.50 Potatoes 275 bu. 137.50 2980 bu. 1490.00 Radishes 17 bu. 8.50 30 bu. 15.00 Lettuce 19 bu. 9.00 40 bu. 20.00 Peas, green 21 bu. 10.50 18 bu. 9.00 Beans, green ' 40 bu. 20.00 Turnips 50 bu. 25.00 Rhubarb ' 10 bu. 5.00 Apples ! 100 bu. 100.00 Sauer Kraut : 5 bbl. 50.00 Calves, 15 170.00 10 150.00 Hogs _ S 15 100.00 $9501.37 14408.32 Total value of products for biennium $23909.69 Balance farm products on hand Nov. 30, 1914 6500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 166 Col. Ferdinand Zimmerer, Commandant, Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Burkett, Nebraska. Dear Sir: The following report of the hospital conditions is sub - mitted herewith : During the last biennium there have been 98 deaths of members (18 more than during the preceeding one) and of these 64 were men and 34 were women. Of this number, 13 men and 9 women died while on furlough. During the first half of this biennium there were 48 deaths — 31 men and 19 women. During the last half there were 50 deaths — 33 men and 17 women of whom 7 men and 4 women died while on furlough. In the first half of this biennium there were 70 men and 36 women admitted to the hospital and in the latter half 60 men and 38 women, most of them brought from other buildings but a large number were new members of the institution. 18 members (10 men and 8 women) have been located elsewhere in the institution. There are now 35 men and 43 women in the hospital and 38 men and 16 women in the two convalescent hospitals. During the twelve months ending Dec. 1, 1914, I have attended to 7200 office calls in the dispensary and have 6600 hospital calls and 3750 calls elsewhere in the institu - tion. I have dispensed $1,000.00 worth of drugs for the year 1913-1914. All beds in the hospital are at present occupied and the total patient capacity increased over that of the first half of the biennium by fitting up two additional rooms for patients' use. The capacity of the West Hospital is taxed now and provision must be made for caring for many more who need the care of the nursing staff. Owing to the in - creasing decrepitude of the members of this Home it will </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 167 be necessary to provide one more ward for men and one more for women with nurses attending. The sanitary surroundings are greatly improved by the building of 5 large skylights and ventilators. The painting of the West Hospital has added greatly to the appearance and healthf ulness of the surroundings. The nurse force has been reorganized with a trained nurse in charge and for the nurses a uniform wage scale established. The two convalescent hospitals are very much in need of repair and painting and, if done, will greatly benefit the well being of the patients housed therein. Two more venti - lators are needed in the West Hospital and the dining rooms and kitchen as well as the second story hall painted. Some noiseless and sanitary floor covering, such as linoleum, is needed on all the hall flooring of the West Hospital. The morgue has been repaired and painted and is in charge of a man experienced in undertaking. The stock of drugs is of the best and an ample supply is kept on hand. Respectfully submitted, Dr. C. P. Fordyce. Burkett, Nebraska, November 30, 191k- STATUS OF MEMBERSHIP OF THE HOME FROM DECEMBER 1, 1912, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1914 Men present November 30, 1912 Men absent November 30, 1912 Admitted from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1913 Discharged from Dec. 1, 191*. to Nov. 30. 1913 Gain for 12 months Women present November 30, 1912 Women absent November 30, 1912 Admitted from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30. 1913 Deaths, Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1913 Discharged from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1913 Gain Deaths, Dec. 1, 1912, Nov. 30, 191S </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 168 STATUS OF MEMBERSHIP OF THE HOME FROM DECEMBER 1, 1912, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1914— (Continued) Daily average present, men 261 Daily average present, women 176 Daily average present, men and women 427 Daily average present and absent, men and women 541 December 1, 1913, to November 30, 1914 Men present Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 278 Men absent Dec. 1, 1913, to November 30, 1914 43 321 Admitted from Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 75 396 Deaths, Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 33 Discharged from Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 49 82 314 Lose _ _ _ _ 7 Women present Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 199 Women absent, Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 38 237 Admitted Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 50 287 Deaths, Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 lit Discharged from Dec. 1, 1913, to Nov. 30, 1914 18 37 250 Gain 13 Daily average present, men 248 Daily average present, women 192 440 Daily average present and absent, men and women 553 Men present Nov. 30, 1912 268 Men absent Nov. 30, 1912 47 315 Admitted from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 142 457 Deaths, Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 &lt;;2 Discharged from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 81 143 314 Women present Nov. 30. 1912 180 Women absent Nov. 30, 1912 40 220 Admitted from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 93 313 Deaths, Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 35 Discharged from Dec. 1, 1912, to Nov. 30, 1914 28 63 250 Men present Nov. 30, 1914 _ , 273 Men absent Nov. 30, 1914 _ _ 41 314 Women present Nov. 30, 1914 _ _ 217 Women absent Nov. 30, 1914 33 250 Loss, men for two years 1 Gain, women for two years. 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">*\ . a: 1 e In a 5 I '1 ► L I *&gt; H </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 169 k c &lt; S S-l||1= I 1«S 3 §1S1S 11= fcg &gt;•= I 111 J S «• i j i J j j i i J • ijjjjjjjjjjj !li i : * : : ; O £ E£ E E £ £ E EEEEEEEEEEE £■££ E - E E £ E E : E o KBC^KaSCKK | gESSSCKKKKaSBSSCKK 2 _|k gKKSWX^ .K ..5 bC .tioc i. . ..« — wwi-sWwwwcooauwwwKWtntnwccwwwi-JOOccOaJKosaJaifcKa: x: ■^i ■&gt;i'm-*eciNec«J-&gt;i'«co-v^i-fl 1 P5Tf m Tf»'vsOTfTfwj^i'weoTf«e&lt;5ececcci^rTf n E - c s ■?; Q c q u C&gt;lt-iinMCC l CC^ l NiM^K)MAMtCXO)$VCCeCHMiaC]Mt-t-HHtO(OH^ 3l Ci Cl wl 3i 3^ Cs O&gt; * J^ * QO * C". 3". OC * A Oi Ci Cl OS C5 31 31 31 Cl 31 31 3! 31 31 31 31 31 c "S-2 x eo^ C&lt;T IO an t&gt; of 00^ i-T eo" CxT cT cT of t^ U3* of t-^ -^ OD &lt;£ ?C&gt; t&gt;" io" tjT *-^ «cT oT cT l/f C*f OS oi IG tC rHMN « IN CM Ni-i « MO N hhhNhM 2 1 e« E IM CM M — MN N HHnCInN &gt;» tj fa .o cj t.' i." _• ti &gt;&gt;&gt;»&gt;&gt;&gt; h e- &gt;?■ """.ii S fci &gt; _o *J &amp;i £" &gt;' e o &gt; '■ &gt; ' o &lt; 423 g ** •fi e. i * iil|.CIii|i|ii|ti|^|li^^si!ii|Il &lt;; cq n co m « dq ca &lt;a a: n o o fc t. o Be s S S !z: ft. w ai w w w re P &gt; p &gt; &gt; a Z &lt; I i I i ! I Hi ! i ! i ! ! i ! i I i i I ! i II • ■ * * * * a ■ an*** ' i ' ' 'i am ■ ■ Qj4ia;CoOOa;OOa*00000004&gt;Oi)ajaJ0 0 i&gt;OOOOOaj4)4)a; ! ; I i ! I ; t t I ! 1 i M • i • : i ijd i !!•!!!!;•! \je ■ ! i &lt; : : ; ; : : :+&gt; : -CH : : : C :::: t :::::: s : :33 : : : </seg>
            <seg id="p012">170 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 5° o &gt;, £ S S JSM If ■- a. x &amp; C S ° if -sij iii *== g iini= 1 1=1 !!=! 5£ Egg ggs ££:£ =gg;§gjg:g g §ge 5,3^ I iii iii iii iiiiiii \ U : titi 2 www www wwoji cc^^oJKoaoa j mc tci^aj i. ta e»j»_ w w w k co w fc. in U C ec k w" w ww'C w^5p«j *"¥ | XC-OC OCt-t- t-t-tS t- tr- X t- » t- 0C «C C-0C5D ™t-»t- catc. Ci^iCi cscia: CiOsoiCtcsosc; as c. *. c. aiasaso; i ■« N _rtf oc-vd ic"«'"—*o*p*iox" os os'io eJ n'« Q §-s^ iii $^ Siiiiii I 11^ luij &lt;Cfc tg &gt;^m&lt; IS ' *-t O '-* •— WM CC Oi CO O CC t- (fi O OS CO 00t-^ tOMNr i— ' •»-* i— . o — O^OOhhQC OOIi-i O &lt;— • " S CiAOS -. C- _. C- * ~ AOiAOiOiAGO Ci CaQOO) Oi Oi Oi o; J5? ©.2 i . — , — .— — _ __ , 8 ! i3 *c" iaoo"t-" Vx^' co* os cc'^ufv-T o co'Vec" t^cooTv-T J, 5 •" ■ 2 " WN « M^ir-flN CO t-t US« f s| Hi HI iii jjjjfife i ill jlii 5 S« lie tit tl |i|tti| t iii «tl •la I=z5||z7:e^=s==^|sI! zzis§ liz^ * I : :~- i i i I ! i j j i i i i i i : i I i i F" : iii iii J I i i I iii s in hi 6 s i i j 1 1 » j j u idJii if Iii !il |ij jfi Bi It; noana mmaa noc Qooc3ix]£Eb o ooo mi </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 171 Iff s§§ I ilii uiiilliil a- a&gt; a) a» ai-a aJ:aJa&gt; ! « v 4) a&gt; * ££S££|SES £ S E E £ o o o o o * o o o k o o o o o SS KBC SKj »^SSK _=« K K SC S j. xx •j.ti.-z ui'^oiui Ek od ai aj co &lt;« =3=3 =3«g a =gTi»a°8 &lt;« •« &lt;0 &lt; w ww uiaio oiSuim Ocri w oi oa oa *J WC*I CiOS^ 1 ■^'00 t- *-H to «c t* IO A ©« t- t-t~ «Dt-t- C-MOCt- *?• t- 00 M t- V 3 Z I ■ — -T 1- OS OS OS O-. O J3 -~- — &lt; — — Q — 'in as »-*»-• Q I"H f"H iM »H 133X3 •» •^t MKn eceoeo-» ersec n C4 ec n c: os os a: os os osososos as os os as as as c-" n"k oTiod eJi^rH'i-r o«" r- 1 oo 1 i^ eo N Si m ii ih coi-i i-i «4 m r-&gt; I II III IIII II I j I s T COCO NCCX &lt;N X iC O *-H O N OS i-H » OlO OOCiOl rH OS O Oi 00 C- Oi * O* Oi Oi 00 00 O) O) Ol 00 OS OS 10 iQia^t oedoiv-T t-"«" ai o" t-" «p* *-. n cc cm i-, n ©j oi w «5 | jl |J| l-5-S^ £g -8 | | | &lt; &lt;!'-, fc75&lt; ajnifc^; fefe fa S3 SS g; T k i ijj i Or &gt;&gt;&gt;»}- : BJ §§£ i g mi §.2 =«&gt;;£ I 1 II III fill fe 1 III n oiih t- «h &lt;H«t- hh co ih o) eo »&lt; j \&lt;*&lt;o &lt;: &lt;a oMfc -&lt;»&lt;;« h« u k &lt;ooas 1 Illl : lea : : : o = ja = «~ o a SBffiKE I j I i i i i i i i • ; i ] I i o i J I I Mil :• : w - I li 111 III! HiU 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">172 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF I a z H 5 d O^a-D SSu O-«(J Q O~O iSfei S t TTXIX T%X * ix?t X wp»wo. a. fc 7. lit a Mx .... I c Ijag- a 41 01 WO CO5-C C, 4. 4- 41 01 4) 41 V § SEES B&gt;-BE£ SEE £ E E E E " SKS« XOECXK XXX X S^SE IS wwtzi'o ajgwajw waj«i oi 'fed cow w E_ mmwO aiwaieooa ajojco oi ijw'edw oa V | (ot-!ct* c- 1- 1- x t- x t- 1- t- x eo t- 1- t^ *M OJ O) 02 O) 93 Oi 93 O) OS C- Ci 9) O3 9) O3 O3 Ci 93 Jill JIHJ III I lljf I w i&gt; oi t- ift ec c: qi i-&lt; oeoo w t-^-ow cj O ?. O ft C •— ■ w C O OhO) »"• O © O i&gt;h C * X * X * Ci CO Cl O)A AO) 9i od oa ©* io W n ** oc ©" ai in »o « i&gt; id V ci a| iiii mam $ m I if It : I Jl if I MS « S £ &lt;£X 41 4&gt; 4, 4&gt;S • 0)J= «J= 41 uocco cl,&gt;S is OOZo a. !i ii«i gi i i nil i o I * ill rt*ii 0. i *iL i I .^i iliii Hi i his i OS aJBSOS wwccaiw Hhh &gt; ££££ &gt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 173 Li - «■§ E «i E S EE«oc&lt;&gt;E&gt;&gt; CbkCt.C - k. Ci - C fc, C o a - O s a tfcSOgetBOdO uo^dnooo (|lf(|JJ| X rt (N »"o» * M f~ A « '.t t&lt;) o; w v'j i^ h ffl a « o « oooooooio aoccooiAa * oi ?. r. r. c: oc a 66oooo«o «»_l © fH »H i^ i—i &lt;"H l^ »^ *-H 3-5 H a c SE M x 5 " s i iiiiiiiit ami mim ■ojj jad uois ooueusooafl o^St-^'o oso-w^-w^^o tut Ijjj il||:li l|il||i ZO-OZZ = 0-£U O = E£&gt;fl. ZOBS0.&amp;.6.O «&gt; U f l&lt; ti;&lt;;asmw'-w«o3&lt;c5;a:mijSfc.c»«fcK i -o 5 iiiiii -a c -o c c c c a-o asosos JE«-«'^ = i5 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 174 &lt; 1 t- O4 M hiiiiSUU llWillll II I — •oft jad uois foeiacoot *-a Ne5«^NrtNN?] !&gt;5 MM IN *E c cCj&gt;-ooaj: *.2&gt;-5=-F*g-S &gt;.2 .* exrioxft-fN-i-T n-sonei-«i imo-. tc w^Q3 cc ec VMM s*a rr^y gc^H-^^r usgj gc **"* • p^ r^ A L ■ ca^naSo-. Stic; 1 **-*te«c-p:!C'"'"" H &lt;N©S4""©x as H a I z a; a H jo X)iAi)e\ •aj»s jo H^i.l = S.2 *- c 9 S.2 is • i i: .&lt;? « K &lt;a _ eamcncaeQBanaoaMeaa si « « cq ca a a oo a ooo t» I c * un °3 j,j fl j| S i mil S fcO^OQC JBCO.OB: o&lt;KOKKS^C CSC « i i3 i i i : I *• • *• i i i fa i uoii»dn 3 Do iz$i j'2 \ii»i iliiiiiii s| i « ce a « ° l. o ca a^:— — « » « " « « ea s a a a i~ — — c i " i-« :: f: ■- oj »-*O »-• o&gt;-i -« o « O" o: e — — --OHO-e-i« w-h « as » o~. a; o; cs Oi x r-. c-. r-. s: a as os o» • c. r. oo 01 as os HXXOHHXififXl- Ct-XMO N CO *-i r-1 W i-iNfl 1-H a so oc &lt;m sc tc c- o-. o « o~- m os iupv }« Wly |c-oot-io«oiat-icxtctc t-&lt;c« sitet-t-ic »(- «o 6 i w«u.&lt;u:c;ffla3Cu i --««u[i.kco!E™o&lt;i I* 22222-2222^2 22222 6.2 6.2 6.222 C .-„ .•_ .•_ ."_, :_ :- •'- ••- V r- ■- •&gt; V •&gt; -r : P fe T n -C fe T T T •E'ET'C'C'E'E'E'E •-'£. ttXtt o'~ o'u oV&gt; C </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 175 I i i § i i i • I M i \ '■■ i-d S § * § S § S SS§§s - sSSl§Si£ (2z£z£jz£ "z "6_ £sS5SSZu5£dS:£55 • • • • • • • x ~222 22 X — 2 3 ''522SS" _ o'S "^1*1.1 . .1 ...... - • . . « . ... 1 .1 I a &lt; iiiis^i §iiii (ilijilli'i'i C i S ■&lt; CO K i-s i-j ■&lt; i-s&amp;,ZCZ i-3 Z CO O «S CO -"- Z &gt;-s "5 lyj a , - | -uaid io *J»H ?&gt;S§n«n« t-eoN« tiMSj:n-NNNa«S § ! " "t-t i I :j&lt;: - : \ '■i't \"t r l-C'Sb : ; I oo:::i;: aha « eeo:o5«; « .Dm i^glSIS 23?^a SzzSz££z!i££ i ii iiiiiliii H I = ; E o "*E 'C 'C 'B 'E T X X 'u X X X u X X c X X X S fc X X (2 , &amp;;oft;£cucua&lt;&amp;.a.c,g--^ a, co cu c o cu cu ft. k op cu a. j I !i ill jjjjj iWjiiiyfe iilllll illfi fiiiiifflf </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17fi FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF I ■j UipV }B 3&gt;*V - •oiv -lad uo ! s -uaa jo 3?Ba M H a 5 H h s H £jiuno3 AJdS J° M^.l E oocj &gt;io«t-* 5 ostc«o«N'^ooioxco^' H """«ej w oO'. iSinOt-'-'NW*" 1 "' Wxmw»WhhM N CO frl « Bw -•s i a — M E5 tec h 'c 'u « 'c *c 'C *c *n c *E n x *c *c o'Ctttt c x x *e *c x ££w£a.a«a.a.a-a.ft.t 1x0.0 Ccufccu a. o £ I £ £ £ ft. I — i i I !jj j ] y I" ii 1 1 i Md ! h liiiij&amp;iifli^ijiii^ I """J «.* §.* &gt;"Ha -§Sgi«-^^ 8- pawiuipv ?$ *Sa«o § « a^lSa 2 « * § I s^a-.S « jj i I M i 1 ijj I Ijl'l ! ! 1 1 ! i i 1 1 ! ! j uo^oo L fliiilliillliljii ill 1 1 1 off. -HosoieiH-HoioacOHHHaOrtOci c 5 og aoaaiiasaxoneacRoiiaioiaea f""H s i ii iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiifiii ' ' 'f : : * &lt; if i ft ! • i • i ' ! ' • ' ' ' ■"»— II llllllJilJ^liJilellJJll OC n T !O ■fl'N 00 «D ■* 00 « 00 «O ■* ■» Tf © t- to 00 -V &lt;£ </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 177 te 3 pwitupv isj's | fs-sifc-s'sggiji j ii b &amp;ea£ z I3.£i|||«l^j_a 3? ._ "z Oi OS 00 OS OS OSOSOSOSOSOOOSOSOSC^AOS OS OS OS f 9 -r OS o as a 0Q « O as H ss « s o a 6 I iil! iiMlWii t Ikl f illilillllSi I f*- oouo o oobcSSoatsKKW a aa I' pi o) w oa vp.wi^oiD^cne'iNNr- as O OS OS GO OS OS OSOSO^OSOSOOOSOSOSO^OOS OS OS OS 5| S rf 5 a a rfw '*jfa rf as«8"- a" 5a" °S ll| a s UiiihittSl I U tatnZi-s i-s &lt; O i-s •&lt; i-s I-, •&lt; o fc. Z ►? !-» » ww e * * v §£io«5 «o t- 1&gt; t-&lt;D to &lt;c 5c S ?: £ g £ 5J gg -0J( J9d UOIB I n ONCOiCt-0010^,0 « — i | ! i i i s ! j^ i \4 i i i 4 D S | I g .2 66 ; g g ; Ijg g| - g.g __O~ 00N Ci-i&gt;. lo N-H».-«&gt;_2£!S&gt; i &gt;_- ( 3,5£ ww J_5eoeo"»rHi-&lt;^n-eo w eo eo tt N eg th « S S» cc x 8 ■* JhO&gt; (m5««- ok!*"QuQHC&lt;:K[i,mk,[i.&lt; — u wo </seg>
            <seg id="p021">178 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF A»uno3 LUOJJ p*j}impv uotjBdnooo HHHHIHO »-H t-l OS OS Oi O nr-flioiOH HrtO g Ol 33 O5 C C. C. C. C, * X C X X * 3". 31 OC 00 Oi Ol Ol Ol OS *^ " tH oTus od«?^c? &amp; cS *Q *-* &lt;*$ &lt;&amp; oi g£ oTof^ 1 &lt;s| tfiiti itiiiili iliili £%■$ = 3J = o 0 IO IO 0*1 CC t^ © aoftNHflNt" © © W N O -^ 0CIOO) o" « a CQ 9 o 2 « H 8 ■ s o s c a.*» w . N m**i UhUh ill if! Us Aaa S jo m*/i|ssaSJ35 g a S "S"^52 g 2 s QWgfclotff gfcCOE o-SC &lt;!BCC«fc« 6 o •r * T - r T : r "r •&gt; : r- "r : r- •&gt; 5 •&gt; •"— •'-• S •"- •"- •"— F ."- ."— c d, cud, a. cu eu a. cu cu ft, cud. ft, £hbSil;££uii£ « &lt;: Sflffi pfifi «??B ill ■si I g-g S it!!!*!* ll=l ss sss « v g ■ j a csaoceEca'"-'* ?j:fJ=cc c c c u S &lt; z : i : : ■ js : j • : : • : : : : : |j|i)|)j| | ibtisist Hllilj jig «j.2 i-i 11 ih «« IN i* «-c NNk i-c rt«N ri O) (N </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 179 I. i m 0JJ ■■Sg'agE'a-a-.ic-a * ■•£•£•£ £■££ -g imC0,&lt;;DQZOCQB«ffifflCQfc£aKc' £,g liiiiSil-S-Jj : : ! : : : i : : : ! | ■op-dnooo » i| || l| 1 jl| j I S I I , S I il| I {I i£iSJS££SJ£Ss£|££JSJsg l SSjll^ |J •uipv»»a«v!SSSgSSg8§s&amp;SS g gggg!gSSBS?S g§ H I |«c«£2SA l 5ooz£rac£ 1 £K!Zlz?e£ : o |_^ s SJ«M^.Tl t - ol 2J^5™S2Si2S25'r i 5S!S T '5S^S:S "5 O un JUS- o'Sfc-o J^^-^rf c t ■o : = - 1+5 +j tl ~* r r r t* i* r r r i* m^ G%r r r r r r **^^ ;B* i : 111 II Hi Hi If il rfl.il ill || </seg>
            <seg id="p023">180 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF -fee B JS» !lld=.ll I ril!|?i|li!il I 5 loi^dnwo IfeifeSSiSifc | |s fc fe fe fe fc| illlj j i |£££EE£| £ &amp;5S|EEE8.g|Es« S x«aca««SK a s « s « « « « 4 o « gq o o Mi^^^^i- 3 o £ 3 C C fi 0 x i3 C $ £ %-l .2 1 ™''™'*~" H^ N "^.'^.'^. . '"!*"" l^»-^i-l«-*»-^^H'-&lt;l-H^H^H 1 _, o'x NferMet**"*! x * ~?o « oo'oToci-H^o'oi" 010*00*0* ci" V.2 -h W *M W '^ '-'^hW t— »— iM v-i (N gg O] uoijBdnaao * O ff. i^- O ?: * C O occixaaxxa as x - a x a: a oi a * a ci oioj c X5-.X?. c: x x a: 3i x^aKgiaaoiftaaaoj os B O'x I — . t- 'M cTl&gt; X »E 2 Z M "-s~-^tL.Zr/)6L,l-5COw O -r ■r^L^-J^L'jL'stc -x 5 -x »c 5: -x co SS « tc S S S S •iupv;Baav *S5?;SSSS -x S5S525§g«S?giS S •ojv jad uois _, --"a-r "' c ~ — o. a o® - Oio os^ oft jad uois _, --"a-r "' c a -i.? 10 oa..oia^»o ■* ■^ : g ■ i -^ B i B ' ' fr ■ ■ ■ : : Xa;uno3 .2 | &gt;"° ; o &gt;"g g g :| ;.« " "2 &gt; S s ■ M a ea s H O z K H X O a o B -^ c zSz2=llzSgi|l | Xa^uno^ »awn iimui i Mtliii&lt;S|il|| i JO ifyAI?BN. AMSjoiO?/iJ U! Sig5gs;;S « g§gg"55gS.ga«5! S ■^&lt; i-( •**■ cc c^ ec oj c fe.2 *J is S.2 ■II «i MO o 'C 'H 'E o 'C C 'E 'E E 'E o X 'E 'E 'E . j&gt; "E 'E 'E 'E T 'E o - E UCUCL.Q.UCUCLC1, c-cut.qcua.a.fl &lt; jo-ft,o.a.i£a.u£ jj * ! oTC'C o'CTE 'S'E'E oXT'E'S.J'E'hT'EtT o'E c — _ — — — ■_ z. — — z. c o.oP.a,tt,a. ja.a,£a.£cuo(il K ihftAi I .* iliilili! I </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 181 O 'm 5-1 a c °3 1 c ■z a O Sol's 4 •oyi asd uois -uaj jo *»«a ■^t-t«^3lf Orf-iP^ f O U3 OS w BO s a o H. -¥ SlcSlsoEEbs "cot iiililillil if!! Xj^unoa iO ?O «C 00 t- (C W « xa^faoocccoiaf co;icv AJ3g JO H^.l TT If c &gt;.. as a H w s o s 11 *- .15 tec 6 1 C X X X t X X X 1 1 X X X X X X X ; E X X X |X 8 0.0.0.0. 0- a. 73^ a, c- cu a. o. a. eu a. a. a. a. ob-jc j: o jj U 1 1 i 1 1 I N I i I Nit !J IllHdi Ira i J IllJiilll lilHii^ilii in K Z ssszzzzzz zzzc^o5^co£e £££ I ii 1 1 iii ! i i ! Mijl i i 1 1 1 Mil uoi;«dn3oo I | f k A ; f k tj S S; fc :«cfc ifefcfe I k ! i isg-iSiS-Ei iPli! |i? li- ! IO « O5 M ri (O IO i-i lO-^tC^MGO^lOtC^P^ Irt O N -«T §' O««- O HO Oii-&lt; O!-h O-H — O! — — 0«O OOOOl 9JX' : * J:C 3:Q0Oi K *?■;." X ?. * * ~ 7: &amp;i O- V- 00 «S "5 00 1" i-i t- tD t-»«KXOt-OaT» OStCIMC-. M-H-lM ii Ni-i Nn MM IN « uipY 41. jit c-t-«c «o «0 t- t-tc t- mtc tc tc tcio t- t- t- tc to * to tc cm ec ■*• eo MM^re v*s«j i ; i«H COS-IE D(j|B&lt;DOOOOfc«O&amp;,KKfcfc| </seg>
            <seg id="p025">182 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF U1OJJ pajjiuipy BE *8-§SfE DC -C uouBdn.i.io x a x c. s: a saieSoioe; x | x (N rilMIM ri ~ UU ■- E ?5 O Z -^ „ ~ T- c oipY" jb a3y - 0^ J9(l UOIS -uad jo »}Ba i- ?J — r? cm «N M N -H 'N « — « JC N CT = •M ; . : : i_ : t 25 a z 1 y: Xjjunoj jo Xjiai^bjs; gG a £l£ : &gt;S^ Ajag jo q^l.q sJ S5 ««-- iii.Ka"ea:^au:_!-coou,c ji • . oi v 4i u v a zi ~ *- *j _ t 'C X TC T T X 0:0.0.0.0.0.0. ri X — — K i= j| * a li|iJj&gt;llJi * ! = £! = ?.§ ii i sill gj^g H III = ?cS2 = ?^ 82 2 S3SS58SSSZSS1S i-- r: © i- x — ' x" o* &lt;£ tc m s £~aJz "* 3 3 » *"£ « o 3 ££i K 5 fr ® x i° cv» 05 ic t- os « ic »^ -c&lt;ct? .2.5 &gt; icci;Z&gt;z:a.a,z» c z « -. r: k r- -t — — cm m~j — ~ — -r — 2^; ™ tyiii =-£££i.£;£ cut. £ ««(£KUiSKUtfKtfK£ </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 183 i ?ll|i|l ill! | I U U MM E EElS?i| EEl§ a eg « a o— a " a a a o O i"* O O Oi O O O *. O^ 9i * Oi Oi OC Od Ol Oi Oi O5 CO O Oi t- 00* Ci't-* O OI OS *O 00 $ -units iiii ~Sv s?&amp;|H ! |J i S Els Eli |E I icon a * s s *•+ O O O O m ~- * A 3^ 03 * * ~- 7i O "5 ' w* fc ** "3 OC* OC tD CC OS =1 "i-s i-g ss-gg i UffiS.wK&amp;FO * B" KKtBKQ 0.000 • k ■ : "f . I fa •« Els Eli |E I E EElS?i| EEl§ os c o« o ca co * eo os a as a a =— a .2 a &lt;o os o +■ 2 c C 2 C Ptfi P £ i c ox a o8 * os UJh^^Xfa | = upv IB aJJv oc o n^t-BiOM 1 " «o^«t- p * * ' f; &lt;c t- x ic «c t&gt; «c S oo et-Be«S» tctcect- «c * «c c- "5 tc «c S «c cccccct- -r •o WJ3 duoi 8 e8fi ££ S8fi * © O££(goo£ )S"SS -U3 d joai^ 5&lt;n«u z -«m r?^i^55SiScc 53.-(n&lt;n e Xa,uno 3 Illl'N^ | 1 || Nil | |jJK ■*« ii-shii-3 1 i flil?ii ilii &gt;, X n O si H a S o 331jflll 1 I iiliill lill ti»TnmlT "'f'O'.xffica « oo toat-of-t-ee •-•'reoos i- c "2 : i i'S": : • • : : : ; i • i i • I : • :|j ! \~i |m *&gt; *i jS^ t-10r.M*WrHOO«Ol0'*r.*- H "t- &gt; " K^F&gt;ier-Ci- 1 ' "^ KMwoiOiicei-ii-iHwt T^" 1 oo i-c e- »-■ t »-■ r- a ec io o j |j £ £ £ £ £ £ £ £ £ £ £££a£££££le£?j r -c x p x x x x t x x x x x x 8 -c x -c ■ r t fe f x t 8 a lit C C C E C C C C C C C E C o C C IJiii I- T 6 (2 |£a.a.a.a,a.a.££££&amp;.&amp;.£a.Q;ixci.cua.ji.cc5. etc s iiiiiiiilli £ Sf .S ■? •= •= c a. 3 s ca a a; c i a, a So-oc aJtOKXtOMtCK CC CO ICXKKKKK M00KB1 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">184 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF uoijBdnDDo fesfcfjfcSfciS; ifet -sl.sifeiifcfciiSilss .£ t. _= :- .i i_l-i-i-t.5t.EEi_~i_i..i:i:&gt;-ji:i.&gt;.t;&gt;- Bsasi-sss«c8°aoso«.5«oJ««cJssa-2s ,2fc..-SoMfc[i.[i,fcfcZ&amp;.fc&lt;:zu.Zk&amp;.C fc.fcf?fe fc-^t. V 5 3 =1 li^jiliitijijttjiili^jijliiil |fc,B 1 ?O,?Zfc&lt;O&lt;Z&lt;MQS|i,m0""c&amp;,0CCS B a c o ■z i j i.i j i s y 1 1* M{ 1 1 s &lt; z \\\il\ I i 1 1 1 ! ! S ! H I U Mi ! HrtOOHliOH31r(r-HHP&lt;OwOHlHrtHO'-ianO; ' 0) * A A C". A * * QC * Oi Si 3a Ci Oi Gi Oi Oi Oi * C« Oi Oi OC C OC "UIDV J» a&amp;V lOrtNeoM-iBCH^xoeiOf ees9&gt;*^«oirt»e9c- 14 i y 1 1 1 j I j ! \4 1 \±a \i &gt;2 ;gj2 ; \i ig^ iiS i Lg ;.i§f!iSS.| j ioAwn.N g;g *.S.S.2:g g-|.S.S i-2 g 2.2 § E£ *^-g.2.S Zfc£Z000£a,£S0Z(i;0B.=C = C!2?£S0C "a8Jom*.iiS5S8SaSS5 o "°S8S58 o&gt; '-agS5a^S' lc S5 :r. =T M as s H o z Si S ■ = «fcaoocQCou.-K*j;w--ci'-ccfe.s«P5« </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 185 TS i ililii^si a -lit. Jag jjgaajfoffi&amp;aa .agggjgg •ll I Ml I I I I I I j I ■£ i = ;fcb ; uo^Bdnwo :it; si feSi&lt;: ifc&amp;SjSsS 5$ \i*c \ «c£ n.oCfctAC(,Bke4s aiic £ Cfc _ o a a a o c a b a s « = « c a 3 • a o ca M a c !»ofc fc&amp;.aaZ&amp;.feJfcfcZfc.ZtB osJZfcooz OI "^" L-Nfllt-Xfll^lOrt^'ttHiH Oi "^ q: OJ 00 IC 04 rH rt i-i O O O O OS 3! 02 O O O O rt O aOOxOlOl^ c c-. os o-. m o ss oi a I x x es a a as as es xaioiaooKa I : a &lt; iii siiisiii!Hii! iitiiii o i f ' ( " iot-S t- » to «o to io us us to S « «c t- « io tc to c- us K §g 2 I '°K a * d uo ! 8 us © u? us o ■» a&gt;ojbt--wt--«MS xooosaoo " -ua J io aiBii •-" e» us Sevicce&gt;use)rHccHiHe*N«eo «««iie««g w i : : i i '• :M i I : '• '• '• \ \ ' S ! xa,uno 0 N || !i i i \ ii i | ! I 1 |jj| \i j S IO^ A "' N III iiii^|1ii|i|ii tillill o i .vias jo m*.! I " s 3 % 5 s s * 5 s »i«»t;s3 s ta'-aaa z c : : : i :*i ;:;:;!:■ i ; i :! i; ;j ;■ m o .2 *s ivivi-j •« ; i ; jjv: i &gt;+; \+i ju • :vi«M"^kJ i 1 I! iillilf Ililplii «C 5S!nSM5.a"oei'i&gt;NirwwxxrtaiNWrtMHW8i s 1 QP 2 m X : f % X X 5 X X X t aX X -C X X X X XtXt X J X -E 111 iiiJJiiiHtflj n&amp;m </seg>
            <seg id="p029">186 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF rrv a a 3 a B-o « a a a ioocz&lt;z a s c L I 9 «i &gt;» uDijBdnooc) , i 5 I £ fe | J E £ * £ £ £ c t- -~ c t, t. t_ k e3 c c C 9 3 OQ fi J a « o cs a a • i.u.Zti'fc.S «« *qi tj&gt; HH^rtHftiH *-t *-( a as a g r. - - - - t. 5c : - IX I 00 O oflO 00 •O' O5 1 a - «i &gt;&gt; ., ■ c c s £j}uno3 1.2 : o « ™ -C— n. fll a) 3 S : 2 is a s 1 i 1 ■^sj^v^illM^^^' e- io o 1 o .2 | i : |^ : ! I ! Mm i •— t-*- eeecio goQom^afc a s ,j Z 25 W MI|3 i.i -! 5 &lt; 2: 3 t I ii* hi^^ 8t»S.S = Sf"c « g | 2 P E J. c 5 w oa f. aoe © qb'io «&gt; •o' os oo « cc el ~5 -3 "S s S S SJ -C I !-3 g 5 -uipvi«^v|^s*S^SS I ;S S S •ok -lad uois ' -. _ _ _ ,__ ._ _ X oa -. a &gt; 0 H oo 0 x M 0 = XX: £ v ml: ~ &lt; * £ 0000,0, a. cu a, , 0.0.0. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 187 In conclusion I wish to thank you for the co-operation and kindness and confidence you have shown towards my - self and the rest of the officers in charge of this Home. Very respectfully. Ferdinand Zimmkrkr. Commandant. Uurkett, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>