<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00001.00010">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00001.00010</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND TO THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. FOR THE YEARS 1881 AND 1882. LINCOLN, NEB.: JOURNAL COMPANY, STATE PRINTERS. 1883.</title>
               <date value="1883">1883</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-23</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>

			      <change>
				        <date>2007-02-22</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>

         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>


		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

F TH 

NEBRASKA 

Institute for the Blind 

I-HI 

HOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

For the Years 1881 and 1882, 

SE 

N 

PRINTER* </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
NCIPA1 

J. B. PARMELEE 

MATROX AM 

N. K. PARMELEE 

ACHER LITERARY DEPARTMENT 

L. M. HOTCHKISS. 

TEACHERS MUSICAL DEPARTMENT, 

M. G. McGINXlS. Vocal 

LIU, IE CHEDSEY, Instrvmentai 

FOREMAN SHOP. 

C. M. M'OTT 

nnsiciAN 

D. W. HERSHEY M. D </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
Nebraska Institute for m Blind. 

/,' 

Lands and Buildings 

To (In 11 

i 

Gents: I have the honorto aulnuitthe following biennial repor 
of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind for the term ending X 
vember 30, 1882. 

Very Respectfully, your obedient servant, 


Nebraska City. Neil. Nov. 30, 1S82. 



' 

• </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 



PRINCIPAL'S REPORT. 

E again becomes my duty to report to you the work and conn 
of this Institute during the term just closed, of its present 
ition and circumstances and of the needs of the future. 

At date of my last report there had been forty pupils in attendance. 
Since then there has been admitted twelve new pupils, 
making a total of fifty-two blind children who have received 
instruction here since its organization. 

Lust vear there was an average attendance of twenty tive which 
iuav this vear be increased to thirtv. 

We have at this date twenty-fire pupils in attendance. 

I. list of the names of all who have been in attendance during 
last two years with their residence, age, sex and cause of 
dness is appended. 

The increase in numbers has been steady, but not rapid. We 
the satisfaction of knowing that, after diligent inquiry, all 
blind persons in the State of proper age, with scarcely an exception, 
have enjoyed, or are now enjoying its benefits. 

i: is greatly to be desired that pupils should enter the Institute 
oon as possible after arriving at the age of nine years. This 
y training, if lost to the children, is never recovered. The 
le of touch, if neglected in childhood, never attains that deli¦ 
and nice discrimination which is such an essential factor in 
education of the blind child. 

Pew become good readers who first enter school at or after the 
ige of fifteen wars, and the disadvantage holds good in nearly the 
lame proportion in the other departments of school work. Hence 
he desirability of securing attendance at an early age. Satisfacory 
work can only be ac shed when this is done.</seg> 

            <seg id="p005">
INSTITUTION FOR THE BLIN'I'. 

¦SEBRASt 

&gt; 

\ 

The foilowin 

ive been pursued during the last two 

years 

Rea 

ipe 

and rhetoric, history, physiology, algebra and geometry. 

Hard, earnest work, 

part of these pupils in these d 

has o-iven very satisfactory results, as shown in the examinations 

it the close of each 

Topical recitations are steadily 

followed, and the ability acquired to communicate knowled. 

well as the capacity to absorb it. 

rhe lack of text-books, still a hindrance in the way of rapid 

advancement in this department, will soon be supplied. 
The Congressional Fund, which is now yielding an annual 

income of $10,000 for printing purposes, is beginning to sa 

the demand of these schools in the United State 

But a few years will elapse Before text books will be furnished 

in embossed type in all the school branches 

Ourstock of apparatus has received several important additions 

during the last year, chief among which is a set of anatomical 

models giving almost perfect representations of the various organs 

of the body, and constructed in such a manner that they can be 

studied by the blind with nearly, if not quite, the facility as by 

the sighted, and has given invaluable aid in the study of physi 

ology. A telurian has also been procured, which will greatly 

assist in studying the motions of the heavenly bodies. 
Object teaching, a great desideratum in any school, is doubly 

valuable here 

e things which shall be useful to the pupil 
ire necessary to fully develop the po 

f the mind, and to teach in such a way that the knowledge 
¦ained shall be available in the discharge of life's duties, and 

secure to each one true su 

The musical department has made commendable progress in 
the two years covered by this report. 

rammar, analysis, composition 

We aim to teacl 
in after life, and m </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
REPORT &lt;iF THE 

Eifith enthusiastic teachers the pupils have been easily kept at 
work, earnestly striving to excel. The higher grade of music 
sed, and a taste cultivated that is substantial and enduring. 

Ehe annual concerts, which serve as mile posts in the history 
lool, are acknowledged by those competent to judge, aa 
Basing in interest and excellence. 

I have had occasion, in previous reports, to mention the tact 
that a large proportion of the blind who, after leaving school, 
become self-supporting, derive that support from their ability to 
teach music. 

It has been repeatedly demonstrated that the blind can successfully 
enter the field in competition with the seeing teacher, and 
not unfrequently far out strip all competitors. 

Any policy tending to cripple this department would nadly 
interfere with the great purpose of the school. 

Its efficiency should be fully sustained and all its interests 
promoted. 

Khe following instruments constitute the equipment of thi 
irtment ; 

Kwo pianos, two organs, four violins, one violoncello, one 
ble bass, one cornet and one flute. 

Ehe industrial work of the school has been successfully pursued 
eretofore, and much been accomplished in the way of giving 
ils knowledge of various kinds of handicraft. 

We labor here with two ends in view. First: That as many 

Essible may be able with their hands to do something towards 
upport in adult life, and second, that means of employment 
be given to each and all, remembering that idleness begets 
and work simply for the sake of employment, if for no other 
B, will make all more happy and contented. 

(Hth the girls, especial attention has been given of late, to 
ous kinds of knitting and crocheting, in which many of them 
3 been enabled, through orders received for their work, to 
¦ome little revenue therefrom. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
NEBRASKA 

TITVTION I 

1HE ELIND. 

7 

In the boys' workshop we are still teaching the two trade*, 
broom-making and cane-aeating. Mr. C. M. Scott received the 
appointment as foreman in November of last year, and has very 
much advanced the standard of work. Our brooms bring the 

highest market price, and all the repair work in cane-seating of 
the several furniture stores in the city, is sent to our workshop. 

It is gratifying to find at the close of the term, a balance to the 
credit of this department. 

Appended is a statement of the expenses and receipts for the 
biennial term. 

The American Association of Instructors for the Blind met in 
regular session at the Institute for the Blind, in Janesville, Wis- 

consin, in August last. These sessions are held biennially, and 
are attended by the officers and teachers from the institutions of 
the various states for conference, discussion and general interchange 
of views. 

These meeting are highly interesting and instructive, and have 
resulted in bringing about a general advancement and co-operation 
which could not otherwise have been effected. 

Ihe physician's statement accompanying this report, will give 

you a record of the health of the pupil 

A.s you see our responsibilities extend to an oversight of the 

health and morals of those committed to us, as well as the interests 
of the intellect. From infancy to the age of 21 is the 

formative period in the life of each individual. Habits are formed. 

tastes acquired and ideas adopted which last through life, and 

nan or woman. The responsibility of the 

make or uumai 

teacher having charge of the child during this period, cannot 
be overestimated. His work must be comprehensive in scope, 

earnest and untiring 

Good morals, good habits, courteous manners, a knowledge of 

&gt;ral8 

the duties and responsibilities which adult life bring, social and 

work which must supplemental] good 

physical culture, cons 

methods ot tea&lt; 


i 

1 

r 

v 

i 

1 

X </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
REPORT OF THE 

I would also earnestly recommend a change in the manner c 
. which at present is accomplished entirely by stove: 
m is now almost universally used in heating large buildings 
is greatly to be desired ; partly because of its greater convei 
e iiud cleanliness, but more especially because the risk fror 

fire is reduced to the minimum. I 

fore recommend a 

Kropriation of $3,000 for steam heating apparatus. I woul 
her recommend an expenditure of $700 for apparatus fc 

ting the building with gasoline. 

The liberal polk}- heretofore evinced by our Legislature, and I 

- constituting the Board of Public Lands and Built 

-. who have the immediate control and oversight of the lust 

The proprietors of the following papers will please accept 

thanks &lt;rf the officers and pupils 
: ly of their respective public 

for the regular and gratui 

ltions 

The Nebraska Citv Dailv X&lt; ¦¦ 
The Xebraska Citv Daily Prei 

The Omaha Republics 
The Lincoln Journal. 

The Mute's Journal. 

Thanks are also due the B. &amp; M. Railway officials for reduct 

tuU% we fully appreciate. 

The Mute's Companion. t 

to popila traveling over their lin 

Aj contemplated by law, I submit the following ei 

(atimate oi 

,1 

01 

uses nece-sary for the ensuing year: 

1st YEAR. 

2d yeah. 

Living expenses, including fuel, employes' 

wages, &amp;c $5,000 

16,500 

Salaries, officers, teachers and physician 3,000 

3,000 

Improvements, buildings and grounds. . .... 600 

600 

Musical instruments, books and aparatus.... 250 

'250 

Furniture and bedding 250 

250 

Clothing for poor 100 

100 </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
INSTITUTION FOR TUE liLIND. 


XEBKASK 

PHYSICIAN'S REPORT 

ilth of the pupils resident at the Institute 

A 

\v of 

for the Blind during the last year, presents results entirely grati 

Within its walls arc gathered about twenty-five pupils, the 

larger number of whom are at that critical period of life, between 

y years. They are here employed 

the asres ot tv 

ntal application, without the 

pur 

i 

xnt of all the special senses, sight. 

aid 

l 

These unfortunates come from every grade of society, and it 

would not be surprising if grave disease, and even death, should 

casionally 

ur 

Not a pu 

lurin 

the last year, nor, in fact. 

1 

t! 

h 

i 

Everv case of ill 

uinated favorably, after a com- 

i 1 

paratively short time. An epidemic of measles occurred during 

the months of February and March, of the present year, and 

included nearly every inmate. There have also been serenl 

severe cases of diptheria at different times during the same period. 


By careful isolation of these cases, and thorough disinfection 

the disease has been uniformly prevented from spreading. Be 

sides these cases of formidable disease, there have been frequent 

t attacks of sore throat, coughs and other slight illness, which 

i 

o 

lort duratior 

nav 

These favorable results are largely due to the indet'ati. 

i 

zeal and attention, affectionate solicitude and educated intelligence 

with the care of the establishment 

on the part ot those intr 

The excellent ventilation of the building, with its ansarp 

\ 

v 

location, have greatly contributed in producing these results. 

The experienced skill in nursing, tender kindness and energy ••' 

Mrs. N. K. Parmelee, the matron, are worthy of all commenda- 

tion </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
The report of your physician should not 

w 

expres 

opinion that the happy combination of study with 


tsement, equally essential to the full development of the mind 
body, and the careful supervision of dormitories, food and 

xl and 

jlothine, together have had much to do with the excellent sani 

10 


tarv condition maintained. 

I&gt;. W. FTER8HEY, M. I&gt;. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
11 

A-K 

A INSTITUTION FOR THE BUSH. 

INDUSTRIAL DEPAIiTMKN'T, 

v. 

Inxt 

Da 

T 

Nov. 15, 

I no 

50 w 


»! 

II 

10 dozen brooms 

m 

II 

To mat 

)om 

1-J.OO 

100 br 

Broom twine -*.O5 

Broom wire 1.71 

25 

Cane for seating chairs 21 

;&amp;gt;ir 


| IM 7&gt;! 

Cr. 

54} dozen brooms sold 116.75 

3.61 

wbuki 

I 

Cane seatine chairs 24.t&gt;0 

THl 

(Kl 

ut 

152.06 

Bv in 

aterial Nov. 30, 188: 

-" 
andles 
landles 

J 

i0 

5 

1.70 

1.00 

•I. 30 

1 . 26 

Tw 

19.60 

$ 171.56 

Balance ov 

11.80 

I)K 

x 

r 

19.76 

:al on har 


Manufactured ar 
Material purchas 

and 

42.14 

— $ i 

( 

46.14 

By 

\ 

Material on hand 18.19 

Manufactured articles on hand 
IS ¦ 

18 </seg>



            <seg id="p012">
INI) CT8TRIA L DEPARTM ENT— Continued, 

CASR K£i KIPT8 AKD EXPENDITURES 

Cash on hand Nov. 1. 1880 

17 

Received from sale o( md whisks | 

" " " eaneseainsj 

ancv and bead work 

4".. 14 


Pa 


4LM4 

k 150 

and mirden sup 

I 

\ 

nl cone 


15 

''• incidental ex : 


N ? 0, 188 

; i 

t </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
NEBRASKA INSTITUTI'iN FOB THE BLINI". 

ENROLLMKXT OF PUPILS 

F, 

t by this report 

Vativitv When Cause of 
•*""'¦ Admitted. Blindness 

Nam 

5FFICE ADDR 

X 

Jeorge Aborn 17 M Ulysses, Butler ( 

Illinois Oct. 2, 1878 Inflammation 

2 Albert K. Aaberg... 23 -I Bazille Mills, Knox Co Norway Fei :uall pox. 

Albert K. Aat 

Norway Feb. . pox 

3 Ralph Albright 10 M Madison. Madison Co Nebraska '..imalpr' 

Ralph All 

M Madison. Madison C 

Nebraska... Sept.JT, -nalpr'tce 

4 (lurk Bruce 21 M lekamah. Hurt Co Indiana Sept. olent. 

4 Clark Bruce Jl M U 

M lekamah. Burt Co 

5 Anna M. Behrens.. 13 F Rockville Sherman Co Iowa M -ickness. 

Anna M. B' 

ins.. 13 F Rockville Sherman 

6 Edwin C. cook 21 M North Auburn, Nemaha Co Missouri Oct. 17. 1878 Amaurosis. 

M North Auburn, Nemaha Co Missouri Oct. 17. 1878 Amu 

K 

7 Harveyl. Carpenter 24 M Lowell, Kearney Co Illinois Oct. 18, 187=. scarlet fever 

8 Levi A. Coryell 11 M Clifton. Nemeha Co Nebraska... Oct. 30, 1878 Cataract. 

9 Kufus H. Crane M Orleans, Franklin Co Michigan... Sept. 8, 1881 Accident. 

10 Emma Crim 19 F Nemaha City. Nemaha Co. Nebraska... May 25, 1875 Scarlet fever 

i-9 F Nemaha City. Nemaha Co. Nebraska Mi Scarlet fever 

11 Etta J. Carr V F Lincoln, Lancaster Co Kansas Oct :!animatio 

Etta J. Car 

1 

12 Mary N. Campbell.. 25 F Spring Creek, Johnson Co.. Illinois Mcli tract. 

1 

Marv N 

F St 

Johnson Co.. Illinois Mch. in, \-:r, Cataract. 

13 Effie B. Campbell..'21 F '.' " " .. " Mch.10, 1875 

Effie B 

Mch.' 

Jl F 

14 Marg't L. Campbell 18 F " " " .. " Mch.10, 1875 

1 

Marg 

Mch. 10, 18 

15 Lucy i\ Campbell. 16 F i " •' " . Nebraska... &gt;ept 11, 1877 

Lucy i.\ Campbell.. 16 F i " " " . Nebraska... &gt;ept 11, 1S77 
Rebecca Craig 18 F liable Rock, Pawnee Co Illinois Feb. 26, 1881 Inflammation 

16 Rebecca Craij; 18 F Table Rock, Pawnee Co Illinois Fel riammatiu 

17 Clara K.Delong 17 F Alexandria, Thayer Co Illinois Nov. 2, 1*7&gt; Uloer'n corn 

17 Clara K.Delong 17 F 'Alexandria, Thayer Co Illinois.... urn cornea 

18 Christian Denholm 13 M Hooper, Dodge Co Nebraska... Oct. 20. 1881 Cataract. 

mMM Hooper, Dodge O 

Nebraska... t&gt;ct. 20. 1881 Cataract 

19Lillie&lt;;a&gt;iord 11 F Tecumseh. Johnson Co " ... tept. 14, 1881 

i GaTlord 11 F Tecumseh. Johnson Co " ... tept. 14, 1881 

20 Mary V. Green ... F Kundlett, Hall Co Michigan... Oct. 27, 1881 Accident. 

Mary V 

21 Wni. H. Gregg 17 M Pleasant Hill. Saline Co Minne-uta.. Nov. 15, 1877 Congenital. 

Win: H 

22 Mary H. Hannaii... 1« F Nebraska city, Otoe Co Missouri Oct. 17, 187S Fever. 

Mary H. Ha 

i-- Gerhard Jenyun.... Ifi M Sntton, Clay Co Russia Jan. 9, 1880 Unknown. 

16 M .Si 

issia Jan. 9, 1880 Unknown 

24 Laura Bell Lee If. F Omaha. Douglas Co Iowa Oct. 30, 1878 Impure vacc 

Iowa Oct. 30, 1878 Impure vacci'n 

25 Eliza A.Lorain 25 F BlMir, Washington Co Ohio Oct. 7, 18S1 Accident. 

Accident 

Eliza 

Un 

2« Julia Mullins 22 K Salem, Richardson Co Nebraska... Feb. 11, l&gt;7fi Fever. 

a M 

Nebraska... Feb. 14, Is76 Fever 

27 Gustave W.yuundt 1* M Qrand Island. Hall Co Wisconsin., -ept. 8, 1880 Unknown. 

¦11 Gustave W.Quandl 1^ M Grand' Island. Hall Co Wisconsin., -ep- known 

28 Nellie M. Rice 18 F Valparaiso, s-aunden Co... " ...Dec. 6, 1881 Infl'n of corn 

N\ 

•\ Infl"ii of cornea 

.aimers Co... ... uec. o. iobj inu n ui comei 
ngton Co Nebraska... Jan. I, 1882 iMilnrnmation. 

29 John .M.Taylor 17 M Dei ngton Co Nebraska... Jim. I. lv-2 Inflammation 

Pi 

30 Pearley M. Taylor.. 12 F " '• ... Sepl - eg 
M.- Warner... 25 F Dakota CUT. Diikota Co Iowa Dec. 31, 187". Intlummatio 

Mary M.- W 

\\ 

1' 

Maud W 

N 

Apr 


i 

u </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
REPORT OF TIU 

APPENDIX. 

The N ! aska Institute for the Blind is v 

in one- of the suburbs of Nebraska City, about one-halt in 

of the court house. The main building is constrn 

stories above the basement, ami is 49 bv f 

i 

rooms atford accommodations for from 35 to 40 pupils. 
The workshop recently erected for the boys' industrial d 

ment, is a commodious brick structure, 2o b 

four large rooni3. Machinery and tools for the manuf 

»&gt;ni8 and the cane-seating of chain, have been provided. 
the regular school work it is intended, as the pupi 

arrive at the proper age, to give all instruction in some industria 

work or trade which shall assist them in after life to gain a partia 

it' not an entire support. 

A- will be by this report the direct and only purp 

the institute is the education of the blind children of the State. 
It is in no sense of the word an asylum or poor house. None 

but those of suitable age, and capable of receiving instruct 

can be admitted. 

As in the case of the seeing this education should begin at an 

a home under the age of nine or ten vears, this early training 

must be given them there, and by the parents. In the majority 

of cases, for some unexplained reason, this early training is sadly 

neglected, and some of the best vears lost. In nearly all caw 

more can be done than is done, so that upon entering scho 

child need not of necessity commence at the verv rudim 

vied 

Ir is a mistaken idea that these children should be petted ami 

indulged because of their misfortune. Such a course must t 

to make the | -elf-willed, overbearing and. disagreeable 

v age. As it is manifestly impracticable to send childrei </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 

1 

INSTITUTION FOR THE BLIND. 

ASK 

i 

ting, more Decenary that they should 
avity, a kind and obliging disposition 

LI 

i 

ill give them a passport into society, and ultimate suc- 

i; 

ity it is frequently the ease thut. though 

c 

in 

:r of music; other things being equal, 
it, hence the blind, to make 
&gt; bring unusual excellenee in their art. a 
a disposition at once agreeable and en- 

The late Dr. Howe, Superintendent of the Boston Institution for 

I honored as the pioneer in the work ot 

i 

The blind child needs especial care aud 

a 

peculiar training. The mother, the sister, the brother, the little 

a 

ry useful to him as teachers, and can 

omna 

)n3 of various kinds. They can encourage 

;ive him valuab 

him to leave his couch or rocking chair, and to have courage and 

elf-reliance. They can encourage him to keep on his fee 

about* can help him to explore the room, 

&gt;on as he can 

house and yard; to climb stairs and ladders; to scale fences, 

reep through holes, hunt hens' nests and the like. They can 

jive him opportunities to feel of dogs, colts, hens, nonet and 
jattle, and can teach him the ways and habits of domestic and 

)ther anima 

orkscrew, drive the common screw, bore 
split wood with the ax and cut it with a 
lin from knowing and using these articles 
himself. All your anxieties and in 
i from wounds and bruises and hurts of vait 
incur and bear them; all children have to 
larms do not save him, but probably haw 

I, 

us- 

u- 

i 

rform what they propose, tfcey tiud a 
)n&lt;r acting ;is u barrier against them, 

uaible adv 

tical education of all children begr 

rious kinds. Hi </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

REPORT OF THE 

I effect of increasing his danger by preventing him from relyupon 
himself and so lessen his presence of mind and activity 
slf-defense when a sudden difficulty presents itself. 

Do not prevent your blind child from developing as he grows 
up. in courage, generosity, self-reliance, and manliness of character 
by excessive self-indulgence, by sparing him thought and 
anxiety and hard work, by giving him undeserved preference 
others. Much may be done for hi3 advantage by judicious 
fnnnCM, by resolutely insisting that he shall learn to do everything 
for himself and for those about him which is possible to do 
without actually looking at things. 

Ieep him out of doors and running about as much as possible, 
r in mind that he is exercising for health and strength, and 
his object is to be in the open air and to keep warm by exse, 
not by extra clothing. But the benefit accruing to your 
d child from such continued exercise and work in the open 
is not confined to his bodily growth and health;. for the effort 
lo something useful, to bestir himself and to keep himself 
m is good exercise for his moral nature ; for every habit of 
¦ting and overcoming little difficulties increases courage and 
reliance. 

These qualities are especially needful to the young and blind. 
Cultivate them by calling upon hinr to attempt and to perform 
any various acts as possible, and especially to succeed by ways 
of his own finding out. Let him join in with the boys of his own 
and strive to imitate them in all their 6ports and occupations, 
to associate- with them in Sunday-school classes, in attendat 
public lectun I, in _ r iitherings of all kinds, forgetti::. 
much u [possible 'that he is blind."" 

NOTICE TO 

APPLICANTS 

Those of suitable aye and 

•parity, and possessing 

moral character, will be admitted. 

requu 

n the ;i_ r - - of nine and Lwentv- 

f'he regulations of th&lt; 
¦ I ' mpeculiar '•* -¦ 

ill applicant? »hfl </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR THE BLINK. 

one years. Tuition, board and medical attendance are furnished 

all pupils free of charge during the school year, but parents or 

guardians are expected to provide good and sufficient clothing, 

pay all traveling expenses to and from the institute, and take 

charge of the pupil during the summer vacation. 

The school year commences the second Wednesday in Septem- 

ber, which is the proper time for the admission of new pupils. 
Alphabet sheets and other matter in embossed type will be 

furnished upon application to blind children who are too young 

to attend school 

Parents are invited to visit the school and acquaint themselves 
with the methods of instruction and general character of the 
school. 

On making application, information must be given fully and 
explicitly upon the following : 

1. "What is the full name of the applicant? 
2. Date of birth and place of birth. 
3. Parents' names — are both living? 
4. Post office address of applicant. 
5. What is the degree of blindness ? 
6. At what age did blindness ensue ? 

7. Cause of blindness. 

8. Has he ever been subject to fits 

9. Is the applicant now in good health and free from con- 

tagious disease 

10. Has the applicant any bodily deformity? 

11. What is the general moral character of the applicant? 
12. What school, if anv, has he attended ? 

13. Is he addicted to the use of tobacco or spirituous liquors 
14. Is the applicant of sound mind and susceptible of inte 

:il oultur 

15. Are the parents in any way rei. </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
K6. What are the pecuniary means of the parents or imme 
e relatives ? 

17. Who will provide clothing and take charge of the appli 
cant during the summer vacation ? 

All communications should be addressed to 

J. B. PARMELEE, 

Principal Nebraska Institute for Blind, Nebraska CUy 

18 </seg>

         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>