<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00040">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00040</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin No. 23. Distributed March 9, 1914. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Extension Service BY C. W. PUGSLEY What Is a Farm Demonstrator? Not An Expert to Advise, But a Hired Man to Help »If I should attempt to put into one sentence what a farm demonstra - s, or should be, it would be this : He is a man of practical farm ex - nce with an agricultural education, working under the joint direc - of the farmers, the state agricultural college and the United States Lrtment of Agriculture, to assist in determining the best agricul - practices for the community in which he \s located. In the term :ultural practices I would include the problems both of production distribution. \ A little later in this article I shall have more to say about the spe - cific duties of farm demonstrators, and what I shall say will be based upon what has actually been done in this and other states, rather than upon what might be done. Perhaps a clearer understanding of what a farm demonstrator is may. be obtained by first gaining an idea of what he is not. The things he is not probably make a longer list than the things he is. That is why he is of value to a community. Those who profess to be everything are usually not very capable at anything. Some Nots. In the first place, a farm demonstrator is not an "adviser." ■ Some farmers seem to think that a demonstrator is a person who has a lot of notions and theories about farming that he is trying to have adopted in the county in which he is employed. If that were true I would have no use for a farm demonstrator. No person, no matter how much ex - perience of a successful nature he may have accumulated in one section of the state, or how much agricultural education he may have secured is capable of going into a community strange to him and giving a very large amount of advice to the resident farmers as to just how to handle their respective farms. The farm demonstrator is distinctly not an adviser in the sense in which we ordinarily use that word. Neither is the farm demonstrator an "expert." No man should be employed by a county association as an agricultural expert. No man knows it all. Few men are capable of posing as experts in special lines of agriculture, to say nothing of being experts in all lines. The farm demonstrator should be able to secure expert advice from specialists </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 and authorities in different lines, and he should himself have a good agricultural education to assist him in diagnosing farm problems and to enable him to suggest solutions ; but he should never pose or be hired as an "agricultural expert." Not Agent of Business. I The farm demonstrator, in Nebraska at east, is not an agent of trust or industrial combination, any business interest or interests, or group of middlemen local or otherwise. He is simply the agent of farmers themselves. True, the demonstrator works under the direc - of the agricultural college and the department of agriculture, but e are creations of the people in the interest of agricultural advance - it. Neither of these institutions receives support other than revenues n public domain and the taxes of the people. Funds to aid in promot - county demonstration work may be paid to county associations by ness men or groups of business men, but the agricultural college and department of agriculture will not co-operate in any work if contribu - s for its support have any strings whatever tied to them. (Everybody who is interested in the growth and development of Ne - ika must be interested in agriculture, because the wealth of the state ounded on agriculture. For that reason business interests offer sub - ptions to farm management associations in the counties where dem - trators are employed. If the farmers desire to accept these sub - ptions as a county association of farmers that is their privilege and r affair. The agricultural college and the department of agriculture ply insist that such subscriptions shall be free from obligations. I Business interests in Nebraska have formed what is called The Agri - ural Development Commission of Nebraska. Their purpose, as set h by the president of the Commission, is to raise funds to assist in development of agricultural resources in the state. The Commission pay its contributions to the treasurers of county associations making ication for assistance. The only condition upon which the Com - &gt;ion will grant funds in this way is that the county association shall irganized in accordance with the state plan for demonstration work, that the funds given shall be used for such work. The business in - sts of Nebraska neither hire nor direct the work of any demonstrator, y contribute to the work if the farmers of the community desire to pt their contributions; otherwise, they do not contribute. Not a Job Hunter. (Contrary to popular belief, the farm demonstrator is not a job er. No man is employed in demonstration work in this state, or in other state so far as I know, who did not have opportunities offer - greater financial income. As a matter of fact, the requirements i good county demonstrator are such that one of the greatest diffi - es encountered is that of securing suitable men. Salaries offered ich men in all other lines of agricultural work are as great or greater the salaries offered farm demonstrators. The salary is seldom ; enough to tempt a man who has had practical experience and an rultural education and who is working on a farm of his own. Xei- </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 Kis it large enough to tempt experienced college teachers or experi - station men. I For these reasons it is very important that men be trained especially this line of work. When the farmers of a county secure the right I of a man for demonstrator experience has shown that they will a large salary to keep him. I have said that the farm demonstrator is a job hunter. Of course, many applications are made by job hunters, the executive committees of county associations are not looking for kind of men. To my personal knowledge no demonstrator who been employed in Nebraska applied for his job. Not a Milker. t Showing farmers how to do the simple operations of the farm is a part of the farm demonstrator's work. The demonstrator is not d by the farmers to show them how tawplk, because the majority of i already know how to do that. However, the demonstrator does n how to milk — if he does not, he should not be hired. Though his i is not to help with the milking, he should be able to assist farmers milk by helping them to get unprejudiced information about milk - machines and dairy equipment of all kinds. IA farm demonstrator is not hired to harness horses; farmers can cheaper labor to do that. It is possible, however, that the demon - tor may be able to offer valuable suggestions about adjusting the li or the collars to prevent or cure sore shoulders or necks. Although hired to plow, the demonstrator should know how to set a plow to the lightest draft and do the best work. No excuse would there be the community to hire him if he devoted all his time to plowing for farmer. The demonstrator must do things for the whole commu- Not An Intruder. |[t is not the purpose of the farm demonstrator, or those who em - him, to bother people who do not care for his services. That is the in it is necessary before the work is established in any county to lize an association of farmers. This association has charge of the :, and its members contribute a large part of the funds used. The :ipal advantage of the association is that the members agree to co - ite with the demonstrator, and a demonstrator will not be placed in county unless a county association of farmers has been organized enough members to make it worth while for him to work with them, n he is outlining his co-operative work he goes only to those who to co-operate. All of the attention of the demonstrator, however, a not be given to the members of the association. The members always come first, but if the demonstrator is paid in part by the depart - ment of agriculture all of the citizens of the county are entitled to a reasonable share of his services. In Madison county, this state, the work is being organized without government funds. Membership fees from farmers and subscriptions from business men will constitute the whole support. This plan I like very much, because it shows a deep interest on the part of the farmers themselves. Where the work is organized and supported in this way the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">demonstrator gives his time only to members of the association, for it is they who pay him. In Madison county they have an executive com - mittee composed of a man from each township in the county and the president and secretary of the county association. All the members of this executive committee are fanners. At the last report I had from Madison county before writing this article the association had over 300 members ,and the membership campaign had just started. Farmers' Hired Man. In the preceding paragraphs we have seen some of the things the farm demonstrator is not. 1 imagine some of my readers are saying that if the. number of things the farm demoristrator is not is so great, then he must be almost nothing. Let us see if we can learn from the work done by demonstrators here and elsewhere what a demonstrator is snd whether he is of value to fanners. The farm demonstrator is TrU hired man of the farmers of the com - munity. This is true not only because he is hired by an association of farmers, but also because of the nature of his work. The things he does are either agreed to or initiated by representatives of the farmers. They direct his work in co-operation with the state and federal agencies, and the farmers have the largest "say-so," because they best know their own needs. In Nebraska the official title of the farm demonstrator is "co - operative county farm demonstrator." This title analyzed means that the nature of his work is co-operative, that the county is the unit and that the object is to demonstrate or determine the value of new or old farm practices. The farmers and the demonstrator must co-operate or nothing can be accomplished. Learning By Trying. tOne type of co-operative demonstration work is illustrated by the hod employed in Nebraska counties to learn the value of rolling win - wheat in the spring. The Nebraska Experiment Station at Lincoln reported that tests covering a period of five years show an average ual increased yield of more than five bushels to the acre from rolling ter wheat with a heavy land roller. I The farm demonstrator finds a good many farmers who do not roll 1 wheat, and who, perhaps, do not believe in it. He asks Farmer A, is a member of the county farm management association, what he cs of rolling wheat. Farmer A replies that he tried it but did not re so large a yield as his neighbor did in an adjoining field that was rolled. Now he may be right in his assumption that rolling is not sable under his conditions, but unless all the factors influencing the [ of wheat are the same, except the rolling, he does not have accurate rmation. Farmer A's neighbor may have had more fertile soil, the ;ty of wheat may have been different, it may have been sown at a rent time, the preparation of the soil may have been better, any of h factors, as well as many others, would invalidate the comparison. t Farmer A, being a member of the county association and willing co-operate, agrees to roll a narrow strip through the center of his eat field. AH conditions will then be the same, except the rolling, for rolled and unrolled wheat. When harvesting time comes this strip </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 is harvested separately and the yield tells the story. At the same time Farmer A has not changed his practice, except on a strip where the test was being made. I But Fanner A's test is not sufficient. The demonstrator finds that tner B believes in rolling wheat and practices it every year. To secure i to establish Farmer B's belief, an arrangement is made with him to e a strip unrolled in the center of his field. Arrangements similar to e made with Farmers A and B are made with wheat growers in all s of the county. At the end of the season the figures show beyond question of a doubt the effect of rolling winter wheat in that county year. When results for a period of years are secured and tabulated t is best in regard to rolling wheat is established. Spread of Knowledge. I Knowledge of the results of these experiments spreads rapidly, e neighbors watch the fields of a fanner who is co-operating with the nonstrator. By means of meetings, reports in county papers and per - lal conversations the demonstrator spreads the information secured to parts of the county. Last year in Merrick county on a particular type soil the rolling of winter wheat gave an increase in yield of from two fifteen bushels to the acre. On another type of soil rolling was ap - ■ently of no benefit. tin Seward county the treatment of oats for smut made a splendid (ving. In one field the strip seeded with treated oats gave an increased i of twelve bushels to the acre, compared to the yield where the seed not treated. The cost of treatment did not exceed 5 cents an acre, vious to these tests no oats had been treated for smut in the vicinity re the tests were made, and the loss to fanners from oats smut must e been large every year. This year in that neighborhood many farm - will treat their seed oats for smut. tSuch co-operative tests as I have described can be applied to many ices. At a farmers' meeting I attended a few years ago two fanners issed the cultivation of corn. One of them said that cultivation of orn every week after the usual time of laying by gave him an in - ;ed yield of fifteen bushels to the acre. The other fanner, who was ghbor of the first, living only three miles away, said that cultivation s cornfield after laying by time resulted in a decreased yield of ten els to the acre. They didn't believe each other, and perhaps nobody :nt believed either of them. It is conceivable that they could both have been right, but in this instance they were guessing at results. Each had compared his field with the one over the fence, which may have been planted to another variety of corn in a different way at a different time and had a very different chance to make a crop. In other words, in each of these cases, so many factors entered into the results that it was unsafe to estimate what late cultivation had accomplished. If there had been a demonstra - tor in that community who could have induced fifteen or twenty farmers to test late cultivation of corn in the way I have described in connection with rolling winter wheat the results would have been dependable. Such tests carried on through a series of years would show conclusively </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Common Carrier of Ideas. I No phrase expresses better what the farm demonstrator is than used by a demonstrator in Colorado. He says of himself : "I am immon carrier of ideas" — not his own ideas necessarily, although he have some good ones, but largely the ideas furnished by the success - farmers of the community where he is working, the ideas furnished lemonstrators working in other sections and other parts of the coun - the ideas of experiment station and agricultural college men in his i and other states, and the ideas of agricultural thinkers, writers and kers in all parts of the world. The most valuable ideas a farm demonstrator can carry are prob - ably those that come from farmers in the community. A county dem - onstrator in Tennessee, in a locality where the soil was being rapidly depleted of its organic matter, and where such leguminous crops as clover and alfalfa did not seem to succeed, found a farmer who was maintain - ing the productivity of his soil by growing soy beans. This crop not only furnished the right kind of a rotation, but also furnished a splendid stock feed. The demonstrator spread this idea throughout the county, and as a consequence the entire system of farm management of the community was changed, greatly to the benefit of the farmers. Until the "common carrier of ideas" was on the job, the soy bean farmer's idea of successful farm management received no attention from his neighbors, although he had been practicing it for years. Alfalfa Revivals. In Gage county, Nebraska, the proportion of tenant farmers is very large. As is the case wherever this situation prevails, the problem of maintaining soil productivity is a serious one. Tenant farmers will not sow alfalfa or clover when they are not certain they will be on the place to reap the benefits. Many landlords will not furnish the seed or labor necessary to secure these crops. So universal was the prejudice against alfalfa of landlords and tenants in Gage county that it was commonly believed it could not be profitably grown in that section. tWhen Mr. Liebers took up the work as demonstrator he found a iber of farmers who had been growing alfalfa for years and who Jd not be without it. He proceeded to call meetings to discuss lfa. These meetings were held in alfalfa fields. I attended one ; Blue Springs last August. A threshing crew was there engaged in :shing alfalfa seed. The machine was stopped for two and one-half rs, while seventy-five farmers of the neighborhood listened to dis - sions about alfalfa. I The owner gave the figures showing the returns from the field for &gt;eriod of nine years. In 1913 that field yielded him about $50 an acre hay and seed ,and it had done as well in a number of previous years. s accounts showed that alfalfa was one of his most profitable crops :ry year. Meetings were held also in fields where alfalfa had been iwed up, and records were secured of the value of alfalfa and clover crop rotations. The result of this work is that many farmers in that tion who own their farms will sow alfalfa this year, and one landlord, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 \^ no Mrs s isrg'c numocr ot iztrms to rent, h&lt;is cinnounccQ thcLt be expects to put ten acres of alfalfa on every 160 acres of his land in 1914. Dairy Work. tWhen Demonstrator Culver went to Merrick county he found a good f farmers engaged in dairying, but they were not realizing as much t as they should from their cows. He suspected that one of the )ns might be the kind of cows they were milking. As a result of his : a cow testing association was organized. It was not long until ' cows were found that were not even paying their board. These i were sold and better ones purchased. Next year the plan is to i a number of such associations in that county. tMr. Liebers found in Gage county a locality where farmers were in - sted in dairying, but they were using scrub cows; very little dairy &lt; was in their herds. He found a few farmers whose herds were itable ,and called meetings on their farms. His efforts resulted in conclusion that dairymen should have dairy cows, and Mr. Liebers asked to buy pure-bred sires and pure-bred or high-grade dairy 5. Several thousand dollars' worth of the best dairy stock in the itry has gone into Gage county already, and more will follow. tA Wisconsin county demonstrator has been testing the skimmed : from hand separators, and finds that about two out of every three m separators on farms are not skimming as closely as they should, the basis of 100 pounds of milk skimmed each day, fifteen out of ity machines tested were running an average of $23.56 worth of er-fat into skimmed milk annually. One of these machines was ting $100 a year, because of poor adjustment and improper turning. One of the county demonstrators in Pennsylvania was asked to sug - gest the most economical ration for a herd of milk cows. After taking into consideration the prices of feed in the neighborhood, and of com - mercial feeds on the market, a ration was recommended. The owner of the herd, after trying the ration, said it was saving him $10 a day. Saved Many Hogs. I When Mr. Coupe began work in Thurston county as farm demon - tor he found hog cholera in a virulent form, and hogs were dying dly. He interested the farmers in vaccination and personally vacci - :d thousands of hogs with serum and virus. As a result of his work •rinarians vaccinated large numbers also. The farmers of Thurston nty estimate that Mr. Coupe has saved them thousands of dollars in season. Of 4,487 hogs vaccinated by Mr. Coupe, 85 per cent were ;d. In herds where cholera had not already broken out, 98 per cent e saved. In the four Nebraska counties that already employ county lonstrators 20,220 hogs have beell vaccinated and 84 per cent saved, well herds 97 per cent have been saved. (Probably the most important part of the work of the demonstrator connection with hog cholera, and other animal diseases, is in deter - ling and suggesting methods of feeding and sanitation that will pre - it outbreaks of disease. The demonstrator is always on the lookout sick hogs, or other sick animals, and can take steps to prevent the ead of diseases that are contagious. It is to the interest of every </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 community to stop the spread of animal diseases, and in such work a demonstrator can be of very great service. Helps to Buy and Sell. I But let it not be understood that the activities of the demonstrator confined entirely to increasing production. Problems of distribution just as important. Nearly all of the demonstrators are able to bring sther farmers who want to buy certain articles and farmers who e them to sell. Demonstrators have helped in the sale and exchange articles and commodities from nails to threshing machines in the m equipment line, and from day-old chicks to horses in the livestock :, and nearly all kinds of grains and seeds besides. tin Marion county, Missouri, Demonstrator Laude organized a fliers' exchange and listed in his office things farmers had for sale ! things they wanted to buy. The first three weeks' business amount - to $1,250, and since that it has been increasing in volume rapidly, does not buy and sell, and charges no commission for his work; he ■ely gets buyers and sellers together. We have examples of this kind of work in our own state. Mr. Liebers in Gage county, where the corn crop was almost a failure last year, has listed a sufficient amount of home-grown seed corn to supply the demands of the coming season. This is a very valuable service, for it has been proved that home-grown seed corn is much better for the main part of the crop than seed imported from outside of the state or even from a considerable distance within the state. tOur demonstrators have listed alfalfa seed, and have been able to prospective buyers in touch with farmers in their own county who seed to sell. Seed houses looking for car-load lots can often find i with farm demonstrators sufficient quantities to make investiga - worth their while. The price the farmers receive in this way is iderably higher than they would receive in selling their small lots rately. I Under no circumstances is a demonstrator to handle any of the «y or to do any of the buying or selling. His training and knowledge at the service of the farmers in deciding on the merits of animals or :les — if this service is asked. He is not the financial agent of either :r or seller, neither is he a commission merchant. He is a common car - of the fact that the farmers of his county want to secure or dispose ain commodities. i Every member of society should be interested in making produc - large enough to supply every member with his needs and reasonable forts — if he earns them with labor which is a benefit to society as a le. The elimination of waste in production and of waste and unnec - ry friction in methods of distribution will help to bring about this rable state of affairs. That is the duty of the farm demonstrator as as of every other citizen. [Reprint from Nebraska Farmer, February 11, 1914.] i Distributed by U. 8. Dept. of Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry. perating with The University of Nebraska. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>