<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association for the Year 1921</title>
               <date value="1922-02-01">1922-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA Dairymen's Association FOR THE YEAR 1921 Prepared by J. E. PALM, Secretary Nebraska Dairymen's Association </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">I. A. MORRISON. President Co'lece View, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Dairymen's Association Secretary's Office Lincoln, Neb., Feb. 1st, 1922 His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In compliance with the law in this case made and provided. I hereby transmit the annual report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Asso - ciation for the year 1921. Yours Respectfully, J. E. PALM, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p005">TABLE OF CONTENTS President's Photo _ Frontispiece Letter of Transmittal 4 Officers of the Association. 6 Board of Directors ________„___ 6 Oak Lodge Corona Clyde, W. J. Jenkinson, Monroe. Nebraska..... 125 List of Presidents and S&lt;N»T«»_ri«- 126 List of Awards in Dairy Cattle Judging Contest ltT Honorary Life Members — 6 Life Members „ 7 Annual Members , 8 County Agents , - 10 County Superintendents 11 Constitution and By-Laws. 14 Butter Statue 18 Program of 1921 Meeting. 19 Secretary's Report . . — 24 Treasurer's Report . 26 Mr. J. C. McDowell's Address 27 H. P. Davis' Address K Professor M. N. Lauritson's Address 46 H. E. VanNorman's Address ._ 56 Mr. A. J. Glover's Address 64 Ex-Governor Frank O. Lowden's Address 78 Mr. Charles Grau's Address 82 Banquet _._____________________________..___......... 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 r ■i OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOK THE YEAR 1922 Cameron J. Furry, President O. M. Enyeart, Vice President J. E. Palm, Secretary Franklii Superio Lin BOARD OF DIRECTORS Jacob Sass Prof. J. H. Frandsen E. W. Frost C. H. Starke H. C. Younp HONORARY Name *J. Dixon Avery S. C. Bassett *Hon. C. L. Gabriclson Prof. T. L. Haecker Prof. W. A. Henry *Hon. W. D. Hoard W. W. Marsh J H. Rushton Hon. A. C. Tupper. Hon. Dan V. Stephens 'Deceased. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 7 LIFE MEMBERS Address Omaha, Neb. Beatrice, Neb. Gibbon. Nab. Gibbon, Neb. Gibbon, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Fort Dodge, Iowa Omaha, Neb. Sta. B, Omaha, Neb. Gibbon, Neb. Bellevue, Neb. Gibbon, Neb. Sta. B, Omaha, Neb. Stromsburg, Neb. Albion, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Clay Center, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Madison, Neb. King, Morelle B. Kirschbaum &amp; Son Kraumhaur, Henry Lessentin, F. W. York, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Omaha, Neb. , O. H Lincoln, Neb. E. M Clarks, Neb. Mapenau, Otto Merrill, J. C. Meyer. H. W Miller, Joseph McGinnis, R. W Olson, E. A Fremont, Neb. Pierre, S. D. Route 3, Lincoln, Neb. La Platte, Neb. 845 Nye Ave., Fremont, Neb. Stromsburg, Neb. Palm, J. E Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, Neb. Pfeiffer, Otto Rector, E. T Reedy, J. A. Roberts, J. R Stewart, Wm. Elkhorn, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Wildhorse, Colo. .Lincoln, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Stouffer, Hon. R. B Stubbe, Henry Bellevue, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Sutton, Hon. W. M Schwager, Chas. P.. Tagge &amp; Boldt Table Rock, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Cairo, Neb. Omaha, Neb. Templin, A. M </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 1921 ANNUAL REPORT Thompson, F. M... Treitschke, Julius Vaughn, F. H Fairmont, Neb Omaha, Neb Cheyenne, Wyo Whitmore, Hon. W. A Wins, H. H Valley, Nel Ithaca, New York Witt, Reinold. „ Scribner, Nel .Scribner, Neb Woods, W. Righter Station B. Omaha, Net Young, Hal. C Lincoln. Net Lincoln, Net ANNl AL MEMBERS Alderman, Donald Adams, James Anderson, Arthur K. R. 2, Hav N Marqu N&lt; Springfield, Xe Avery, H. R. Baker, W. R.. Barnes, D Barth, Chas. E Boettger, 0 M Station B. Om N\ Rt. 1, Box 223. Lincoln, N« Lorettc N&lt; R. F. D Brecht, Miss Rosann ■ Brink, E. M 1530 N Barton, C. R. N Boehr, John W II Butler, Wm. Carter, Dudley Carter, Douglas Clark, E. L, N Compton, H. P Munkato, K.a Crowell, Cecil Red Cloud, M Daft, L. H „ University Place. N' Davidson, W. H Springfield. N't s Doubt, Will University Place, N« Davis, Prof. H. P State Farm, Lincoln, Ne Fithian, Glenn Lincoln, Ne Frandsen, Prof. J. H. _ 1406 N 33rd, Lincoln, Neb Friedle, J _ Lincoln, Neb. Frost, E. W. Woodlawn Dairy, Lincoln, Neb Glass, Elwyn Lincoln, Neb Grau, Chas. A Bennington, Neb. Gustafson, C H Lincoln, Neb. Hanson, Peter Station B, Omaha, Neb Harvey, Frank Auburn, Neb Hendrickson, Prof. J. W. State Farm, Lincoln, Neb Henry, John Cambridge, Neb. Hepperley, A. K Norfolk, Neb. Hogue, R Crete, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 9 Hunt, H. W Jenssen, Wir Lincoln, Neb. Station B., Omaha, Neb. Jeaurald, W. T Auburn, Neb. V Lincoln, Neb. A P R. F Route 5, Lincoln, Neb. K K Ulysses, Neb. Central City, Neb. David Oxford, Neb. vely &amp; Son, L. D. Rt. 3, Omaha, Neb. Levi R Hildtreth', Neb. Lincoln, Neb. tear Manlcv. E. W Fort Calhoun, Neb. R. ( Lincoln, Neb. Martin. O. M. Lincoln, Neb. Morrison, H. A College View, Neb. J. A. E. Geneva, Neb. T. E Lincoln, Neb. haut. M. D. Rokeby, Neb. Bn Aurora, Neb. J. A Malcolm, Neb. Frank Greenwood, Neb. 1 Simeon, Neb. West 0 St., Lincoln, Neb. M V. A West O St., Lincoln, Neb. &amp; Son, G. A Arapahoe, Neb. R. Lincoln, Neb. Win. G Fort Crook, Neb. George Station B, Omaha, N?b. ker. Charles N. Station B, Omaha, Neb. Ryan, Thos. G. Route 3, Lincoln, Neb. Rydberg, Cari. Wood River, Neb. Saumlers, Wm. Lincoln. Neb. Sass, Jacob Jac Chalco, Neb. Severe, H. L. Palmyra, Neb. Severe, 0. A. Palmyra, Neb. Shroyer, J. O. Humboldt, Neb. Starke, C. H Red Cloud, Neb. Stewart, M. 0. Route 3, Lincoln, Neb. Weeping Water, Neb. Tefft, R. F. Temple, W. J. Lincoln, Neb. Thompson, Prof. B. H. Thompson, S. D. Thompson, Pro! State Farm, Lincoln, Neb. Thompson, S. Lincoln, Neb. Voss, William Millard, Neb. Walker, D. G. ... Hastings, Neb. Station B, Omaha, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Wallis, H. C. Walters, Ralph B. Walters, R. D. Normal, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 1921 ANNUAL REPORT Williams, Chas. Woodruff, W. B. Youngreen, Elmer Union College, College View, Net Scottsbluff, Net Valley, Ne NEBRASKA COOI'KKATIVE EXTENSION WORK The University of Nebraska College of Agricultur &amp; U. S. Department of Agriculture Cooperating TY AGENT SECTION LEADERS Agricultural Agent* R. E 11 Boys and Girls Club Home Agents 1 F \ Si ASSISTANTS Agricultural Agents Boys and Girls Clul James F. Lawrence, Harry Mary-Ellen Brown, J Carl W. Jones, Alleg \\ AGRICIL RAL EXTENSION AGENTS Tl Name A( County Adams Buffalo Butler Cass L. R. Snipes &amp; Ida Wilkens Weeping \V Cheyenne Clay Colfax K. C Fout.s West P Cumin g Custer Dakota Dmwes Dawson Dodge H. J. Kleihege Br C. R. Young &amp; Geneva Ra A. R Hecht &amp; Maude Bean Lexinfc x r rem E. G. Maxwell Court House, Omaha Douglas Fillmore Frontier Furnas. Gage J. L. Thomas &amp; L. W. Thompson Geneva W. H. Campbell Stockville W R. Wicks Beaver City- Bovd Rist Beatrice Hall J. R. White Grand Island Hamilton Holt C. E. Quinn Aurora H. L. Nye O'Neill Howard. Johnson Keith G. E. Davis St. Paul J. F. Purbaugh Tecumseh C. H. Grau Ogallala Kimball O. J. Grace Kimball B. L. Montgomery Court House, Lincoln W. H. Brokaw. Director, Lincc &lt;•()! \ K. R. Dav J. E. Ludden &amp; J. G. McM E. T. Winter R. S. Scot J. H. Claybau&gt;rh &amp; V \\ I Clement Kusk F. L. Taylor R. \. Houser </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 11 G. H Kellogg North Platte R. A. Stewart Battle Creek Mad M N G. R. Schroll i Lula Boye3 Bridgeport J. P. Ross _ Fullerton A. H. Delong Syracuse J. L. Gilmore Holdrege R. E. Blackburn Platte Center Lynn Sheldon &amp; Eva Anderson Osceola \\ J. F. Holmes McCook J. L. Worrell FalU City W. C. Calvert &amp; J. C. Higgins Friend W. F. Roberts &amp; Edith Cone Wahoo Phil Sheldon &amp; Ethel Rk-hert. Scottsbluff H. P. Ripdon &amp; Edith Barker Seward Rushvillo L, C. Christie Hebron Mabel L. Lutado &amp; H. E. Huston Walthill C. C. Dale Ord Carl A. Olson Blair H. R. Fausch Red Cloud \v. DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION STATE OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN Executive Division M. Matzer State Superintendent Deputy State Superintendent Assistant Superintendent Rural School Inspector Archer L. Burnham Frank R. Beers Normal Training Inspector Assistant Normal Training Inspector Head Certification Department Lulu S. Wolford Assistants Cadta Snapp Secretory Ruth E. Wheeler, Secretary of Normal Training Department, Bookkeeper Helen M. Stacy Stenographer Helen Erb Stenographer Verdena Whitney Stenographer Bertha Crawford Stenographer Etta Brown. Clerk of Examination* Mrs. C. D. Wheeler Clerk of Examinations Lula Davis Clerk of Examinations Buelah Epes _ Clerk of Examinations ra A. Thompson X. Clark </seg>
            <seg id="p012">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 12 County Address Mrs. Harry E. Schultz Hasting* Adams Antelope C. A. Mohrman Xeligh Arthur Arthur Banner J. H. Macauley Harrishurg Blaine Brewster Boone Albi Box Butte Alhanc Boyd Nellie May Edwards Mrs. l.ciina Morris Katheryn I^auphlin W. T. Pouiher Hu Brown Ainswort Buffalo Kcartu Burt Tekamah Butler Cass Pla Cedar Har Chase Cherry Cheyenne Clay Custer Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel Dixon Dodge .IK. Ma Douglas Dundy Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas H Gage Beatr Garden Mrs. Blanche W. Riddile J. L. Jenkins F. W. Montgomery Theo. A. Frye Mrs. Barbara A. O'Malley Mrs. Ella M. Kern Arthur S. Nelson Frances E. White Oshkosh Garfield Burwell Gosper Klwood Grant Hyannis Greeley Greeley Grand Island Hall Hamilton Aurora Harlan Alma Hayes Haves Center Trenton Hitchcock O'Neill Holt Anna Donohoe MUIIHT! Superintendent Mrs D. G. Williams A. L. Shamblin Birtha M. Sheikk-r Opal Russel Oma L. Cadv Alpha Peterson Emma Schwerin Mrs. May S. OVonr Kdith A damson Anna MaiKadden Kannie R. Haylett V. .1 Vofttei Emma R. Miller W. E. Vom Eilna Rink \V. C. Bio.. Retta F. Br \V. V. Ru-ha MaUl J Una Ri.harcis .Margaret Hautfhawaut Pearl O'Nea Goldii- P. Stark G. W. Fletcher Bertha Foster Edgiththa Grant Evelyn Besack J. H. Garrett </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 13 Howard. .W. G. Baker St. Paul Jefferson Eva B. Shuman Fahrbary Johnson Helen Wright Tecumseh Kearney .Minnie Norlin Minden Keith Katherine Feather Ogallala Keya Paha Blanche Snyder Springview Kimball Rachel McElroy Kimball Knox Allen S. Stinson Center Maude Berry „ Lincoln ,anca Aileen G. Cochran North Platte r A. C. Loshbaugh _ Gandy Jga Marcia Smith _ Taylor McPherson O. A. Johnson Tryon Merrick Margaret McCutcheon Central City Morrill E. F. Kelley Bridgeport Chloe C. Baldridge Fnllerton \ Bess E. Anderson Auburn \ Mildred Mauck Nelson Charles Speedie Nebraska City Bertha Kuhlmann Pawnee City Mrs. Margaret Bailar Grant Alice A. Swanson Holdrege Marjorie Parminter Pierce Fred S. Lecron Columbus Amelia Rasmussen Osceola Willow George D. Curry. McCook D H. Weber _ Falls City Fvlyn W. Towle Bassett .L. J. Bouchal Wilber Bertha Bishop Papillion E. A. Odman Wahoo sunder: )tts Bluff Ada M. Haldeman. G«ring Sheridan Pearle E. Summers Rushville Sherman L. H. Currier Loup City Sioux Vinnie M. Meyer Harrison Stanton S. E. Eddy Stanton Thomas Mrs. Rosa Selleng. Thedford Thurston Ellen M. Brown. _ Pender Valley Lelia Moorman Ord Washington Mabel J. Marsh Blair Wayne Pearl Sewell Wayne Webster .Estelle Ducker Red Cloud Wheeler .Edith Bowler Bartlett York Telfer C. Lord. York Loup jHarcia smitn _ layior Madison N. A. Housel Madison Seward -J- C. Greenwood Seward Thayer H. E. Barbee Hebron </seg>
            <seg id="p014">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 14 Constitution and By-Laws of the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association (1) This Association shall be known as the Nebraska State Dairy Association. The principal plate of transacting the business of tht shall be where the Secretary has his residence in this State The Secretary shall audit and pay all the bills against this Associa - tion where the amount is for a less sum than Five Dollars ($5). In the incurring of expense all payment of bills against the Association of an amount greater than the sum of Five Dollars ($5), the Secretary shall ob - tain the written consent of the President and Directors of the Associa - tion. All of said transactions to be laid before the Association at its next annual meeting for inspection and approval. (8) The Treasurer shall give bond in the sum of Two Thousand Dollars ($2,000), the game to be approved by the Board of Directors, and to be in the custody of the President The general nature of the business shall be the promotion of the dairy interests in the State ,&gt;f Wiraska. 14) This association shall contract no indebtedness and incur no liabili- ties whatever except by approval of its directors and in no case for an amount exceeding funds available for the fiscal year. (5) Section 1. The officers of the Association shall consist of a Presi- dent, Vice-President, Secretary, Treasurer and Five Directors. Section 2. The officers of the Association shall be chosen annually from the members of the Association, at the regular annual meeting end shall hold their offices for the year following their election and until their successors shall be chosen. The President, Secretary and Directors shall constitute a Board of Managers who shall manage the affairs and control the business of the Association during the time that the Association is not in session. A majority of the Board, at a regular called meeting, shall constitute a quorum to transact business. (7) </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 15 ( (9) The annual meeting of the members of the Association for the elec- ion of officers shall be held at Lincoln, Nebraska, during the week of )rganized Agriculture. By-Laws (1) Each member shall pay an annual assessment of One Dollar into the ?ury of the Association. (2) The payment of Five Dollars at any one time shall exempt the mem - from the payment of annual dues (3) Public notice of all regular meetings of the Association shall be ?n by the Secretary at least twenty days before the meetings and written or printed notice shall be given to each of the members thereof least five days before the meeting. ,4, All meetings of the Board of Managers shall be called by the Presi- Secretary, or any three cf the Board of Managers, notice of which given to the members thereof, at least five days before the meet- (6) Any vacancy that may occur in the Board of Managers may be tilled ay appointment by the Board for the unexpired term for which such officer was chosen. (fi) Section 1. Any person who is a resident of the State of Nebraska and who is a producer, or who directly represents producers, may be - come an active member of this Association, by paying in advance, a membership fee of $1.00 per year and subscribing tc the Constitution and By-Laws. Section 2. Any person distinguished by his service to the dairy in - dustry may be elected an Honorary Member by a majority vote at any regular business meeting of the Association. Such membership shall expire at the end of two years unless re-elected. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 1921 ANNUAL REPORT IT) The Board of Managers shall fix the salaries of the Secretary and Treasurer, and may authorize the paying actual expenses of the officers and directors incurred while transacting the business of the Association. (8) Section 1. This Constitution and By-Laws shall become effective immediately upon adoption. Section 2. This Constitution or By-Laws may be amended or changed by a two-thirds vote of all the member* present at any annual meeting. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">PROCEEDINGS of the rhirty-Seventh Annual Convention of the NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Held At State Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska January 4-5, 1922 Alice C. Gilchrist, Official Reporter, Omaha, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 18 General J. J. l'ershing on Horse Butter Exhibit, Nebraska State Fair, 1921 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 19 WEDNESDAY MORNING SESSION January 4, 1922 The Thirty-seventh Annual Convention of the Nebraska Dairymen's Vs-im iation nn-t in the Hairy Building at the State Farm, Lincoln, Ne- ka, on Wednesday, lanuary 4, and was called to order at 10:30 A. M he President, Mr. H. A. Morrison, of College View. THE PRESIDENT: We are glad to see so many men able to brave I storm and be in this building at this time. We feel we are especially vileged that the man who is to speak words of welcome to us has the storm and is with us. Wl introducing Mr. /.eh run jr. Mayor of the city of Lincoln, I de- N tn say he is one of the men who has been in the city for many iars connected with business interests. He has been mayor of the at a time previous to this, and we feel as a dairy association that re especially privileged in having Mr. Zehrung speak words of wel - : to us. (Applause.) A WORD OF WELCOME Mr. F. C. Zehrung .Mayor, Lincoln, Nebraska Mr. President and Gentlemen: From what you read in the paper, farmer has been getting the worst of it, and I am glad to see some- ming his way today. They say what you want is moisture. now, you are going to get a lot of it. any reason I should be here this morning except a id, Mr. Krandsen, to compliment me by bringing me is ..r.y man on top of earth who knows less about usiness than I do, I do not know where he lives. I have belonged Association for more than twenty-five years that meets annually, I have been addressed by mayors from San Francisco to Montreal, we ha Canada, and from New Orleans to Boston; and when I sit in a conven - tion and hear a mayor get up and try to tell our convention something about our business, and listen to the way he gets it all mixed up and tdk us nothing we want to know, and a whole lot of things in which we are not interested. I made up my mind if I were ever privileged U&gt; address a convention, I would not try to tell its members something about their business. I do not know anything about your business, and that is something everyone should know, because milk is the first thing we get when we come into this world and it is almost the last thing they feed us when we pass out. We are too weak when we come into the world to drink anything but milk, and the same way when we pass out. In the inter - vening time we drink milk with things in it, or drink things without </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 1921 ANNUAL REPORT milk in them — i Laughter! aeptnding upor. how much ability you have to drink the fusol oils that are going around over the country. So every man should know something iibout your business, but I do not know anything. I never was a farmer. That 1 cine reason I will never be grc &gt;nce ■ pour boy and got up at four o'clock and milked til" COWS, and tir ally he gets tci be President. You will readily see I will never be I'r lent not even Governor. 1 di know how it ever happened I w ted mayor for a second term. They got me &gt;ut and then put me mm I think this will be the nun in Governor McK place, I will promise you that, i Li lighter.) Y.-t 1 do not think ther is a man in this world i* more hont t what he thinks is a right. 1 do not think ther te of Nebraska wh firmly believes ht inter than Scm McKclvic. 1 eive him credit for liinjr honest H Goven he is out ol | It is brought before yesterday. Per for a couple of weeks A a respectful way to spea but he is a Lincoln boy it I) &gt;v a dinner and th General Dawes has just President Harding So something was said about McKel' He said to Charlie. "1 wish you w and see wh.it you think of what I The General, with his characteristic manner &gt;&gt;f speech, said, "H What do I care about your budget'.' If you have as much trouble with i yours as 1 have with mine, you will newi want to see MM as long as live!" i Laughter, i Something was said about a in i Charlie Dawes said, "That's the I t mistake in the world. I am something to please the public. I man who does what he thinks lie .1, th disgusted with the man who tii ■&gt; The only man who gets anywmre is right, regardless of what the put thinks. If he must wait for the public's approval before he dm- Ml] will not accomplish much' I do not think there is any men who know that more than you. If you had sat back and waited for public approval of how you should improve your stock and handle your product, you would never have advanced. It is because you have had the courage and industry and desire to labor hard enough to g&lt;&gt; out and do whatever is right. You alway.i lvatl t hi gnat man m oi my political career. I wouldi may be bad. T hing to please the public </seg>
            <seg id="p021">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN"S ASSOCIATION 21 I do not mean you did not bave your President and Secretary and other people who could advise, or your school to come to; but you did what you thought was right. Edgar Howard said the other day that a near-great man was a man who would like to do right hut was afraid of public opinion. That is the way a lot of people are in this world. Thank God there is one class of people in this world who do not have to be afraid of public opinion) I refer to the farmers. Some of your work is mighty hard. I said I never lived on a farm, hut all of my relatives were farmers. I have three cousins who graduated from Ames and run 'arms, and another cousin who has an extensive farm in Iowa; so I have lived around the farm a great deal and I know work is not the most pleasant thing in the world, especially like this I have tried to ramble along and keep away from anything yon possibly criticize me for the same thing I have criticized other trying t &gt; tell you something I do not know anything about. I wint tc say we are very g'.ad to have ysu here. This week is a {Treat week to Lincoln. Agricultural Week is looked forward to. It comes at a time when evei./ merchant wants you t~&gt; come. He figures ht has a chance to get some of your good money. While you hear about the farmer not having any money, you will notice about the only men who arc buying automobiles are the farmers. So we are glad to have you here. We are very proud of our Univer - sity and of the people who are at the head of it and run this great in - stitution. It is a great pleasure to have you with us. I an only sorry the weather has been such so few could come. Those who did come I am sure will be amply repaid. It is a great thing to come to a con - vention and exchange ideas and get something from the other fellow. Every man can learn something from somebody else. None of us i* st «mart that there is not some other fellow who can tell us something - that will be beneficial. If you get these ideas and go home and put them in practice, that is the thing that will build up not only the dairy industry, but every other industry in this country. I want to thank you in the name of the city for coming here, and trust your ireeting will be both pleasant and profitable. I also want to express rr.y thanks for the patience and courtesy with which you have listened to the few words of welcome I have been privileged to say to you. (Applause.) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 23 RESPONSE The Mayor may have told you the truth when he said he did not know anything about your business. I would not question his veracity. But M man can come here and address you men without going out from this building knowing: something about the dairy business; so he never can tell that again. (Laughter.) The biggest question that is before the farmer and agricultural man and the dairyman today — the thing we have talked about the most — is the loss that agriculture has had to take. When you stop to think of the amount of food products put forth by our own splendid State and the rest of the states in the Union, and when you consider and know there are parts of the world that are in great need of those products and unable to gut them, it tells to every individual there is something wrong. It is the solution of that great question that the men in o'jr nation and our own men on the farm are undertaking to find today. And luestion of what we might term "good times" or the times that we ordinarily expect to exist, depends a great deal on how that question i» s ,]ved or how soon it is solved. If you will go back with me forty years ago out on these prairies, there was never richer soil, fro n the standpoint of its ability to produce, than then. Vet it was not valuable. We may have all the other great •taMBti existing, but if we do not have the facilities for transporta - tion—the getting the thing to the place it is needed — the thing itself I ecomrs valueless. An individual may know a great deal about the dairy business, but if he has not the ability to use it in that way — or : least the ability to give it to somebody else who may use it — it it &gt;t woith very much. it is with our food products. We may be able tj get the food collected, but unless we have the other question thoroughly solved, we are unable to moet the great need of the hour. There is another factor enters into this question. It is not only the financial condition of the farmer — and upon the condition of the farmer financially depends the condition of our country financially — but there is also the effect upon people's minds and hearts and characters. It tends to make anarchists and bolshevists to have these unusual con - ditions arise. So it is up to every one. of us — to every farmer and dairyman in the State— to do his part, at least, to bring about that which we can build upon for the future in a good, strong way. I read a story the other day of a little girl whose parents had been poor, and all of a sudden they came into possession of a great fortune, and bought a large and splendid farm, all stocked. It had its horses and cows, its pigs and chickens. This little girl was showing a visitor President H. A. Morrison, College View, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 about the place one day. The visitor asked if their hens laid a great many eggs. "They can," replied the youngster, "but since we are in these new circumstances of ours, they don't have to". (Laughter.) Our soil can produce gTeat crops. We have produced a wonderful crop of corn. But most of the farmers feel in these new situations of ours, it does not make much difference. But the man Who owns the dairy cow does not feel so much that way about it. The individual who has produced the corn feels he has produced it as 'a loss; so he is find - ing his way out by partially, at least, going into the dairy business. And so as 1 look over this country at the different classes of industry — I am speaking of the farming districts — I find the places affected the most by agricultural prices and where there is most depression are the sections in which they have depended entirely upon the products of the soil, sending them directly to the mill or shipping them out. Bat in such states as Wisconsin and some of our eastern states where they have been depending upon the dairy cow, we find they are moving along quite easily compared with those places depending upon the grain business alone. But the farrrer is not the only man who is suffering. Go into our country banks or to the mercantile houses. Most of us know something of the problems they are having to solve. But there is no bank losing today on the dairyman. That is the thing the bankers tell us. If that be true, it ought to encourage us to go forward with our business and learn all we can with reference to it that we may produce more economi - cally; that we may come more nearly meeting the situation that is de - manded of us and that we may fulfil the need that is before us. Now, gentlemen, I should like to say to the Mayor that we greatly appreciate the words' of welcome he has expressed to us for himself and for the oity that he represents. Ard as we assemble here to help in this £reat agricultural problem — this great national proble ii, too — I thin!&lt; we may congratulate ourselves that thpre is nothing that will come nearer solving this great quest on, as far as the farmers are concerned, than the good old dairy row. (Applause.) REPORT OF THE SECRETARY Mr. J. E. Palm, Lincoln. Nebraska * Mr. President and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Associa tion: I take pleasure in submitting my Annual Report. The past year has been a trying one in all lines of business, and especially so with the farmer. The one bright spot has been dairying, and I think that it has been the means of getting more farmers into the dairy gam« than anything else that could have happened. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 25 Nebraska should be one of the leading dairy states, for here we have the roughage, cheap feed, and everything that goes in to making: rriilk. There is not anything else on the farm that wilt pay as well aa a good dairy cow. Note these figures. A cow that givea 30 pounds of 4 per cent milk, which is a little less than four gallons a day, with butter fat selling at 40 cents, will give you $36 per ton for your al - falfa hay, $24 per ton for your prairie hay, and $1.12 per bushel for your corn, besides the skim milk, a calf every year, and the manure fur fertilizing your ground. Then why talk about burning corn and bemoan your fate that you can not get anything for your grain? It is high time that we take a hunch and dig in and milk cows, and get more cows. Let us forget the grain for a while and make- this a dairy State. We will make more money and live happier as well aa doing more for mankind, for there is no food known that will take the place of milk. In milk there is vitamine that is absolutely necessary for children, as well as grown folks. Statistics show that 40 per cent of the deaths in child life are due to the lack of milk. Do you realize that every time you feed your children substitutes you are robbing them of their health and growth? Let us remember that. Let us ad - vertise the dairy products wherever we go. Your Association is pushing the educational work constantly, creat - ing a heavier demand for milk and dairy products; but we need the in - dividual help of every man in the State. I hope that this coming year you will take it upon yourself to further the demand for your products. If you do, you will be agreeably surprised at the results which jan be reported here at our next meeting. There has been and is still a great demand for dairy cattle. In this connection, 1 would like to suggest that when you hear of any one looking for dairy cows, that you ask him to buy them in Nebraska in place of going out of the State for them. Let us keep some of this money in Nebraska. I would like to see you appoint a committee to take a census of the dairy cattle in the State, and get a list of those for sale, and also the names of those who are in the market; thereby through co-operation we can do all good. Your Board of Directors bought an exhibit — a mechanical cow, showing up various ways that milk can be used — which has been a great attraction. It is on display down town. It is constantly travel - ing-, staying a week in each town. We feel that it has been a great factor in creating a den and for more dairy products. The past year we had our usual display at the State Fair also our Dairv Parade, and it was even better than the year before. Watch </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 1921 ANNUAL REPORT us the coining year. Secretary Danielson and his assistant, Mr. W. W. Cole, have assured us that they will outdo themselves this year. We also helped defray the expenses of the Student Judging team at Waterloo and at the Dairy Congress at St. Paul, Minnesota. This year we want to do jrreater things than ever, and we ask your co-operation, for without your help it is difficult to accomplish as much as we should. Make yourself a part of the organization. One way you can all help is to get your neighbor dairyman to join our Association. Tell him to mail a dollar to your Secretary and become a working partner in the Association, for in union there is strength. This is one cf the oldest associations we have in the State, this being the thirty - seventh year that it has been in existence. LWe hope that you will feel frre to suggest anything that you havo your mind that will further the Association; for your officers ap - preciate suggestions, and will consider as a favor any criticisms you may have to give them. They will be taken in the proper spirit, for their one thought is to do what you want done I will not take ar.y more of your time, for your Program Oommitte has a real treat in store for you. I think the Committee has gath^re together the best talent ever, and I know you are anxious to hear them I hope that you will enjoy every minute of your stay ht and I know you will. k Don't forget to send in the name of some new mi our number double by the next meetinp. (Applause.) I will give you tht report of the finan Financial Statement. 1 1921 Receipts: lalance on hand Jan. 1, 1921 fembership dues ;hecks out Jan. 1, 1921 $527.90 VkM .10 $593.30 Disbursements: ►flBcer's Salary $15u.OO hher services and expenses looks and printing 196.31 Vwtajre 41.00 Students' Judging Contest Special Prize lond premium fo* Treasurer 100.00 21.51 5.00 $593.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 27 MR. JACOB SASS, Chalco: I move the report of the Secretary and Troaurer be accepted, the latter subject to the action of the Auditing immittee motion was seconded and carried. BUILDING THROUGH BREEDING. Mr. J. C. McDowell I'nited States Dairy Division Specialist, Washington, D. C A defeated candidate up in Minnesota found himself on the out - skirts of a crowd that had gathered to celebrate his opponent's victory. He was recognized and called upon to make a speech. At first he ob - jected, but finally was persuaded. He began by saying: "My opponents prophesied that I would be defeated and I was. They said that they would have five hundred votes to spare and they had. They said that they could beat me with a little yellow dog, and by George they've done it. Drouth, rain, hail, frost, wind and rust, or some other trouble over which we have no control often brings defeat to the wheat farmer, to the corn farmer, to the cotton farmer, to the single crop farmer of any kind; but defeat seldom comes to the man who diversifies his crops and who feeds those crops to high producing dairy cows. On the other hand, poverty, drudgery, disappointment, and failure are ever resent with the owner of poor cows. Everybody knows that profitable dairy cows must be comparatively large producers yet few people fully realize the remarkable rate at which profits advance as production increases. Figures obtained from the tabulation of the records of all the cows on test in 100 cow-testing associations show that as average butterfat production increased from 100 pounds to 150 pounds, the income over cost of feed advanced from $10 to $26, that is, an increase of 50 pounds in butterfat production gave an increased income over cost of feed of 160 per cent. The next 50 pounds increase in butterfat production advanced the income over cost of feed to $42; the next to $58; the next to $74; the next to $90; the next to $106 and the next to $122. Briefly stated, as butterfat production increased from 100 pounds to 450 pounds the income over cost of feed advanced from $10 to $122, exactly $16, for every increase of 50 pounds in butterfat production or in other words as butterfat production increased 4% times the income over cost of feed advanced 12.2 times. These figures are approximate as applied to any particular herd of dairy cattle, and they may apply only within a limited range of produc- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 1921 ANNUAL REPORT tion; yet within these limits they seem to hold true for all classes of dairy cows regardless of breed, age, weight, date of freshening, and geographical location. In one herd of cows whose records were tabulated by our division. the poorest cow, in one year's time, produced only enough income over cost of feed to buy a two-cent postage stamp. The owner is to be congratulated, because there are many cows that do not do so well as that. For his labor and miscellaneous expenses this owner had the manure, skim milk, and calf. An old Scotchman, when asked if he thought the manure, skim milk and calf paid labor costs and miscellaneous expenses, replied: "I'd rather have a wee bit mair." It may be that manure, skim milk and calf do pay labor costs and miscellaneous expenses, but intelligent selec - tion, breeding, and feeding should give us a big bit "mair." In one Virginia association, in 1917, there were 511 cows on test. Herd A, the highest producing herd, consisting of 16 cows had an average butterfat production of 306 pounds. Herd Z, the lowest pro - ducing herd, consisting of 91 cows, had an average butterfat produc - tion of 155 pounds. For herd A the average income over cost of feed was $75, and for herd Z the average income over cost of feed was 64 cents. The average cow in herd A produced more income over cost of feed than all of the 91 cows in herd Z. It would require 117 cows like those in herd Z to produce as much income over cost of feed as was produced by the average cow in herd A. This is not fiction. These are actual records from real herds in a well organized cow-testing associa - tion. It pays to breed for high production of milk and butterfat. We now have the records of four years' work in the Grove City cow-testing association. The first year the average production of butter - fat was 225 pounds, the second year 261 pounds, the third year 280 pounds and the fourth year 300 pounds. The fourth year as compared with the first shows an average gain of 75 pounds of butterfat per year per cow. Multiplying that 75 pounds by the price and by the average number of cows on test gives the grand total of $15,887. As the price received per pound for butterfat the fourth year was one cent below that of the first year, that $15,887 may fairly be considered as newly created wealth due to the work of the cow-testing association. In one cow-testing association whose records we have tabulated the cows that freshened in April, May, June, and July produced an average income over cost of feed of $45. Those that freshened at some other time of year produced an average income over cost of feed of $60. In that association there were a few cows whose owners did not know the date of freshening. Those cows had an average income over cost of feed of $7.82. Somehow it pays to know. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 29 The dairyman who doesn't know what his cows are doing is the man who loses out in the dairy business. He selects by guess, he feeds by guess, he breeds by guess, and he is kept continually guessing as to how he is ever going to pay his debts. He works in ignorance when he might have knowledge. He flounders along in darkness when he might have light. He is like the ostrich, that buries its head in the sand and fears no danger. Finally when such a man loses out he blames the soil, the climate, or the cows, when in reality he should blame himself. There are several ways by which a dairy herd may be improved. The elimination of low producers increases average production, de - creases total production, and usually increases net profits. Better feed - ing of the cows we now have increases average production, increases total production, and may increase net profits. The use of better sires increases average production, increases total production and nearly always increases net profits. All dairy herd improvement due to better breeding tends to increase profits to the producer and to decrease costs to the consumer. It is one of the ways by which the world may become richer without decreasing the prosperity of any individual in it. Therefore, as I see it, the breeders of good purebred dairy cattle are among the world's greatest benefac - tors. According to the 1920 census only 10 per cent of the dairy bulls in Nebraska are purebred. In the entire state there were only 1951 purebred dairy bulls. The scrub dairy bull is doomed. The "Better Sires, — Better Stock" campaign has sounded his death knell. Scrub dairy bulls have done much damage in all parts of the United States, and no county has yet been able to report the complete elimination of the scrub dairy sire. Sometime soon some county will report the timely deaths of the last scrub and grade bulls within its boundaries. Then we'll make a map of the United States showing the district that is free of scrub sires, and proudly we'll label that district THE SCRUB FREE AREA. Scrub dairy cattle, in fact scrub livestock of any kind, can be sup - ported profitably only in those districts where there is a combination of cheap land, cheap feed, cheap labor, and good markets, and I defy any living man to find any such district today. There are at least three varieties of scrubs: the scrub purebred, the low-producing grade, and just plain scrub. According to locality, scrubs are known as scrub, native, mixed, common, mongrel, and piney woods cattle. A scrub cow has four legs, two horns, a hide and a tail. In all these respects she mey resemble a dairy animal bat right there the resemblance stop*. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 1921 ANNUAL REPORT OBLIVION. The chief editor of the U. S. Department of Agriculture said to the chief artist of the Department, "Draw me a picture of oblivion." Why did he want a picture of oblivion? Because that is the place to which the Department of Agriculture desires to consign the scrub bull and all scrub sires of every kind. The chief artist called to his aid all the artistic talent of the De - partment and he is now at work on a most remarkable picture. In the foreground of the picture the pastures are green and beautiful but a little farther back the sands of the desert begin. A broad pathway leads off into the desert and disappears in the dim distance. All along the pathway are strewn the bones of the mammoth, the mastodon, the pterodactyl and countless other extinct animals that belong to the for - gotten ages of the past. For one reason or another each lost out and each has been discarded. The scrub bull has already left the green pastures and has begun his dismal journey into the desert sands. He looks back sadly and long - ingly but fate impels him on and he must go. Soon he will take his place among the extinct animals of earth and his bones shall bleach forever on the limitless desert of oblivion. Do you know that on July 1, 1921, there were in the United States, 462 cow-testing associations and that Nebraska hadn't even one? Do you know that in the United States there are 158 bull associations and that Nebraska hasn't even one? I sometimes wonder why? In bull associations, on July 1, 1921, Pennsylvania led all the States with a total of 21. South Carolina was a close second with 20. Minnesota was third with 15 and Mississippi was fourth with a total of 12. I did not come here to urge you unduly or against your will to organize cow-testing associations and bull associations, but I believe it would be well worth while for you carefully to consider the advantages of two organizations that have done so much for the farmers and dairymen in other Districts. The people of Pennsylvania, South Carolina, Minne - sota, Mississippi and many other States have found that that kind of work pays them and 1 believe it may pay you. What is a co-operative bull association? A co-operative bull asso - ciation is a fanners' organization whose chief purpose is the joint owner - ship, use, and exchange of three or more high-class, purebred bulls. The typical association owns five or six high-class, purebred bulls. The territory covered by the association is divided into as many breeding blocks as there are bulls and one bull is assigned to each block which may contain as many as 50, 60, or even 100 cows. The bull is not owned by the farmers of the block but all the bulls are owned in common by the entire association. When a bull dies, or is discarded for any </seg>
            <seg id="p031">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 31 whatever, he is replaced by the association and not by the farmers block to which that bull had been assigned. f nbreeding the bulls are interchanged, or moved from •y two years, and thus at a small initial cost, good provick-d for a period of ten or twelve years. Why, s less in money, and it always costs less in time and f ivn a share in a good pure bred dairy bull than to be the mam of the scrubbiest kind of a scrub. Through the co-operative bull association the cost of service is greatly reduced, the man of limited means is enabled to improve his herd and bulls of outstanding merit are kept as long as they live or as long as they are fit for service. Mr. Winkjer, who is in charge of the bull association work or the Dairy Division of the United States Department of Agriculture tells me that in one association, four $275 bulls were purchased at an average cost of $42 per farmer; in another association six $275 bulls yere pur - chased at an average cost of $53 per farmer, and in a third association r $1,200 bulls were purchased at an average cost of $240 per member the association. The well organized bull association does not spread infectious abortion but it encourages sanitation that helps to prevent the spread of that disease. Infection comes largely through feeds soiled with discharges and afterbirths. There is as yet, no successful medicinal curt for infectious abortion but it can generally be prevented through proper sanitation, the use of maternity stalls, immediate isolation of aborters and the segregation of all purchased animals until they are known to be free of the disease. The tabulations of the records of the Carroll County, Maryland cow testing association for the testing year 1915-16 show that of the 17 daughters of association bulls, 16 excelled their dams in butterfat pro - duction. I suppose Bryan would say "That's 16 to 1." On an average, laughters produced 1,144 pounds more milk than their dams and 26.7 per cent mort butterfat. For the testing year 1916-17, for the same association we have the records of 16 daughters of association :&gt;ulls. In butterfat production, 14 of the 16 excelled their dams, the average increase of daughters over dams being 30 per cent. That in itself is a very good showing, yet it is only when the production records of all the daughters are computed and compared with those of the dams that a bull's true value to one generation can be known. In addition to this, his influence on production will be noticeable and valuable for many generations. A scrub dairy cow is worthless because she yields no profit A scrub dairy bull is worse than worthless because he quickly drags the remainder of the herd down to his low level. The following figures are on file in the Dairy Division of the United States Department of Agri- culture. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 1921 ANNUAL REPORT In one year's time a scrub cow produced 146.8 pounds of butterfat. Her daughter, sired by a scrub bull, produced 1,263 pounds of butterfat and the granddaughter, sired by the same scrub bull produced 99.7 pounds of butterfat The owner finally woke up. sold the scrub bull and purchased a good registered bull. With respect to cattle, that farm is now a scrub free area. LThe registered Guernsey bull, Imp. Primrose's Billy of Waddington, at the head of a grade Guernsey herd in the Leon Valley, (Wisconsin) Cow-Testing Association. After he had been in the herd a couple of years it was decided to send him to the butcher to prevent in-breeding. "For a time," at the tester reported, "things looked bad for Billy as he was headed straight for the block." Just in the nick of time six of his daughters furnished records at the ages of two and three. Figured to maturity the average production of the daughters was 7,886 pounds of milk and 397 pounds of butterfat. On an average the daughters produced 1,918 pounds of milk and 105 pounds of butterfat more than the average of their dams. The cow-testing association records saved Billy's life and he is now at the head of a purebred Guernsey herd. The expression, "swat the rooster", applies to one farm enterprise and to one season of the year. The expression, "swat the scrub," applies to every class of livestock and to every season of the year. In speaking of our 10 billion dollar livestock industry, the 1919 Yearbook of the United States Department of Agriculture says: "Better breeding will save a billion dollars." If that is true it is a safe assertion that the scrub sire does more damage in this country each year than is done by lightning, hail, river floods and forest fires. Like weeds and rust, like plant disease and insect enemies, he is an ever present source of great expense and loss. That is true in connection with the management of every class of live - stock, but it applies especially to dairying. No matter what the average production of the dairy herd may be, the scrub sire will quickly drag the descendants down to the low level of his ancestors. It is dangerous, extremely dangerous to mate any untried bull with a large number of purebred, well-bred, high producing dairy cows. Sometimes even a well-formed registered bull, of pood ancestry, is in reality a scrub. His appearance and his pedigree mislead and by the time he has producing daughters, he may have undone nearly all the work of a long line of carefully selected prepotent dairy bulls. This has happened over and over again in the breeding of dairy cattle. The herd advances for a time, then comes one fatal step and the herd slips back almost to where it was before. Many years ago, the New York Agricultural College bought a purebred Holstein cow named "Glista." For five successive generations good bulls were used. Glista produced 225 pounds of butterfat in a </seg>
            <seg id="p033">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION ■ year and her daughters averaged 272. The next generation averaged 443 pounds of butterfat, the next 394. the next 384, and the next 414. Then came thr fatal step and the next generation averaged 294 pounds of butterfat a year; exactly 149 pounds below the average of the ances - tors four generations farther back. In average butterfat production that family of cows was almost back to its beginning and all because no mortal man can select with any great degree of certainty on form and pedigree alone. If you sell feeds to dairy cows you have a constant market. If you sell feeds to high producing dairy cows you have a good and con - stant market. If you sell feeds to purebred, well-bred, high-producing dairy cows you have a double market; a market for calves and a market for milk. In dairying, the feed market is always exactly what you maka it Farmers of Nebraska what is to be the future of your dairy herds? Will your herds grow better or poorer as the years pass by? The wise dairy farmer is building today a dairy herd that will increase tomorrow's inc ome. The owner must be ever on the alert to stamp out and to keep out all diseases of every kind and the herd most be well brad. Careful and intelligent feeding, care and management lift the dairy business to a certain level but the highest level can be reached only when to this is added careful selection and intelligent breeding. When all this takes place in every dairy district we will have reached the dawn of the great golden age of dairying. Whether that date may be near at hand or far way in some dim distant future) depends upon ourselves. We have not been living up to the best we know: We have been picking up a few pebbles on the beach while the great ocean of progress lay outstretched before us. Let us be up and doing and in fifteen or twenty years we can easily double the average production of our dairy cows and by doubling average production we will much more than double net profits. In conclusion, let me say, that I sincerely believe that the dairymen of Nebraska are engaged in a business of which they may well feel proud. It is fairly profitable, intensely interesting, and better than all else it furnishes an abundance of food for all our people. He who&gt; thinks only of the financial success of the business has fallen far short of our highest ideals. We all love wealth in some form. A few seek wealth in the form of power and strive for every high position. Some satisfy ambition more quietly by adding pages to the world's best literature. Many there are who prefer their wealth in houses, lands, and gold; bat there are many people who are willing to pass by all these ordinary form* of wealth and accept the satisfaction that comes from a life well spent in the service of their fellowmen. That is the kind of service that wa» </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 1921 ANNUAL REPORT i ;ir the a rendered constantly by our brave boys across the sea. May that of service be the aim, ambition, and ideal, not only of all whi assembled here today, but of every farmer, yes, of every citizen i United States of America PROFESSOR H. P. DAVIS: May I tell Mr. McDowell tna we for some years labored in the bog of darkness, we now have Testintr Association in this State and expert to have m&lt;re in th.' wr ( Mr. McDOWELL: I am very glad to hear it MR. LYNN SHELDON, County Agent of Polk County: I wondering if it would be possible to get a copy of Mr. McDo lecture for publication in our issues that we put out in the em I feel as if the farmers as a whole, whether they be wheat gr&lt; or what, would emtmtmtf be benefited by havir.p: the privilege of re, that lecture. It seems to me if it could be provided, it would great benefit to us to spread this information. .Vt w THE PRESIDENT: All the talks are reported and publish Year book. You can have access to that. It goes to every m r the Association. When we assembled a year ago at our annual meeting, considerably disturbed as to whether or not we were going anybody at the head of our Dairy Department here in the Ag College. While .ve lost the man we had, yet we did BOt lOM I the State. I am sure we all appreciate that. So ir h one splendid man leading out in the dairy business, now w I do not know what happened to Professor Frandsen— w was something held him from getting over the line or n he sti'l is with us, and we are glad. We are also glad we have been able to import the dairy business as the head of the Dairy Department of ti cultural College. I want every one of you men to get acquaim \ i him personally during this annual meeting. I am glad to you our own Professor H. P. Davis, whn will addre! t me. (Applause.) Methods of Marketing H. I\ D.vis Professor of Dairy Husbandry, University of Nebraska They handed me my topic to talk on. I do not claim to be authority • or marketing. You see like Mayor Zehrung, I am going give you an alibi. But I have found out a few things in looking at &lt; problem that may come as new points to you, at least they came new ones to me. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 35 • Mr. McDowell told you we needed better cows. That is the funda - rtal part of the cairy industry and we can have them. In fact we avi- already many good examples in this Stite of wonderfully developed erds We have dairymen of whose herds any state could be proud. The trouble is that the rest of us do not live up to that standard. We are only hi.rting ourselves if we do not do it. Now is A food chance to start in with the New Year and do that. But after we get this production increased, there still remains the - nfr problem of marketing. In the early days the farmer's problem ■f marketing was simple. He produced, and then was his own con - urver. Since he was the producer and consumer, there was no difficulty mt the middleman. But as our country grows larger and a larger portion of our people ro into the city, we must develop different methods of getting- our products to them. Today it is not practical for every farmer to bring in his own milk. It is evident, therefore, that, as r civilization develops, a different kind of service to the consumer jst be provided. Sometimes it is not realized, but the consumer iemands certain services. In Lincoln he demands that a bottle of milk be put on his front porch at the same time every morning. If we are not willing to give it to him, we are going to reduce the demand for hat product, for service is a fundamental necessity in our system of narketing &gt; Somebody must collect the milk from the individual farmers; proc - ess it— because milk today is processed to a large extent. It must b« rified, pasteurized, and liottled — all of which taVes time and labor i equipment and skill. If you do not think so. just go out and try run a milk plant a little while. We are still learning some things re at the Agricultural College and we know it takes skill to do it. Those are things very often not realized when it is said there are too many middle men. A certain service is necessary for the consumer. To do that service a middle man is needed. I do not say he may not the farmer when he operates in a co-operative organization. But s alone other lines I am poing to talk to you this morning. METHODS OF MILK MARKETING H. P. Davis, Chairman Department Dairy Husbandry, University of Nebraska Address before Nebraska Dairymen's Association, January 4, 1922. Practical profit from dairying depends upon two things, cheap or economical production and efficient marketing. Stress has been laid upon the prob'ems of production for decades and there is still abundant room for improvement. Dairy cows today undoubtedly Droduce on the averacre larger Quantities of milk and butterfat due to the improvement caused </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 by selection, breeding, and to better feeding. Probably today the average dairy cow would be considered a more wonderful animal it' other economic factors such as increase in land values, cost of labor, and feed had not risen so rapidly at the same time. Figures malign the dairy cow of today I believe when it places her production at the low figure of census and assessors' reports. If we were to believe them every kind of a bovine female must be classed as a-dairy cow just because she occasionally gives milk. Progress has been made however when we witness the fact that a Holstin cow has produced more than 37,000 pounds of milk in a year or over 102 pounds each day. Nebraska has a cow that has produced more than fifteen tons of milk and two cows that have produced more than 1,000 pounds of butterfat. While there has been a great advance in developing larger produc - ing dairy cows and more effective and efficient methods of feeding. there has not been the corresponding progress in that other necessary phase of profitable dairying — marketing. Successful marketing consists of disposing of a product so that producer and consumer both are fur - nished with convenient service and that producer shall receive and consumer get a fair return for money invested. The farmer of a half century or more ago had the ideal system, namely, he produced and in turn was a consumer of his own products. Times have changed. Agriculture has become and is constantly becom - ing more highly specialized. Consequently a farmer produces only a few products and is himself a buying consumer for many others. Marketing of dairy products has shown a gradual change in the last two decades. At first the surplus dairy products were disposed of its farm- made butter and to a lesser extent farm cheese. Then came the cream separator and stimulated dairying by increasing the market - ing facilities. Small creameries sprang up and these in many sections have been replaced by large centralizers largely because the small creameries did not have good marketing facilities for their product. Condensed milk, ice cream, and milk for city markets were comparatively recent developments as markets for milk. Today a producer of milk has the following possible markets for his product; market milk, milk for cheese, milk for condensing, milk for drying, cream for butter and for ice cream. Of course, all pro - ducers do not have any such choice of markets, the locality usually governing that. Now milk is produced in varying quantities by thou - sands of fanners few of which are so situated as to be able to deal direct with the ultimate consumer. An intermediary or middleman is necessary, therefore, in order to collect the milk, sort, grade, process •nd package it for the consumer's use. One middleman is the second shortest route from producer to consumer. But the service that con - sumer demands, ending with the delivery at his door of a uniform. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 37 well graded product of the highest quality, usually results in a sucees- sion of middlemen. An example might he selected of a country creamery that buys cream, processes it, makes it into butter, packages it into tubs or prints. The creamery ships to a commission man in Chicago who in turn sells it to a wholesale grocery or jobber. From there it goes to a retail grocer and thence to the consumer's table. "Too many middle - men,'" you say. True, yet this system is the result of each class furnish - ing a certain service which we have all apparently been willing to allow and pay for. Middlemen must not be condemned entirely for they have unquestionably enlarged the market by furnishing the consumer with a ceituin service that increased the demand. When it is made easy to do so, th-.' consumer tends to buy more of a desirable article of food. But in this development, very frequently the producer was pinched. His share of the product did not return a profit on the investment. That led to a demand for higher prices and the consequent blaming the other fellow. Producer viewed middleman and consumer with suspicion and the ill feeling engendered was returned with interest. Such all too frequently is the condition today. Producers of milk are interested in greater returns from their pro - duct. The question is therefore how to obtain such returns. Various schemes have been tried, some successfully, others unsuccessfully. There are two principles that have been used by the producers in an effort to obtain higher prices for milk which will be principally discussed, namely, Collective bargaining. Producers taking over the functions of the middleman. In collective bargaining, the producers by banding together in such numbers as to practically control the market supply have been able to have some voice in the price paid for milk by middlemen. They have never been able, and will never be able permanently, to set an arbitrary price for milk. A democracy does not believe in the exploitation of food products for private (tain. Much good has been accomplished, how - ever, through collective bargaining. Trade evils have been eliminated and better feeling among all connected with the industry is evident. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">1921 ANNUAL REPORT ■ NEW YORK DAIRYMEN'S LEAGUE The methods of operating a collective bargaining organization and the plan of operation of typical ones might prove interesting. The New York Dairymen's League is probably the largest, and is one of the oldest of such organizations. The original plan of operation is as follows: It was started in 1907 and in 1909 was incorporated as a stock corporation. Legally the voting should have been according to stock holdings, but it always has been on the basis of one man, one vote. The membership covered six states and was distributed as follows: 70,000 in New York; 13,000 in Pennsylvania; and 10,000 in the states of New Jersey, Vermont, Massachusetts and Connecticut. Of the 93,000 probably 75,000 are now active producers. The territory was divided into 24 districts or units each one of which sent a delegate to the annual meeting carrying the proxies of the members of that district. Individual members however might attend, and cast their own votes. The delegate and members agree upon a man whom they wish to represent them on the board of directors and this man's election has always been assured. A quali - fication of a director was that he must be a milk producer. The Dairy - mens' League had a signed contract with each member by which the league was authorized to bargain for the sale of the members' milk for a year. For this service the league received a fee of one cent per hun - dred weight of milk. The price of milk was fixed as at a point 200 miles from New York City and the same price was named to each buyer. In the region covered by the league, three fourths of the milk normally went to New York or other cities in the territory as market milk. The re - mainder was manufactured into ice cream, condensed milk, butter and cheese. The strong feature of the organization was that it controlled the greater part of the supply of the territory affected. Its weak* was that it had, from the very nature of its contract and forr r- panization, to consider only one price for milk no n-atter where locat the territory. Another fundamental weakness was that it provide means of handling a surplus and thus keeping the market even. A recent re-organization has been accomplished by the league. The new organization is called the Dairymens' Cooperative Association and has more than 50,000 members already. The differences in the new or - ganizaton are that it is authorized to collect the money for its members, blend the receipts, make deductions for expenses, collect working capi - tal, and to direct the producer to deliver his milk at any given point. For the purposes of sale, milk is divided into different classes: Class l-\Vhole milk for market; Class 2-Milk for ice cream making; Class 3-Milk for condensaries; and Class 4-Milk for butter or cheese making. The di - vision into classes is an important stpp since it must be evident that all the milk produced in the territory covered could not be utilized as market milk. Milk that is used in the manufacture of other products has a lower value than market milk value according to the nature of the pro - duct. The highest price is paid for market milk while that used for chees* </seg>
            <seg id="p039">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 39 : brings t.'ie lowest return. In the new form of organiza - as been made to meet this one of the weaknesses of the ii »n. So far it is not evident as to how the surplus is to be Probably the organization will use its authority in flush ira nilk to manufacturing plants and then blend the .Much |Hilii problems are encountered by this f the number of large cities within the territory tates involved. TWIN CITIES PLAN Another form of the bargaining organization is that in use in St. Paul Minneapolis, which we will call the Twin Cities Plan. Briefly it was rat a stock organization with one share of $1.00 taken by a dairy- for each four cows. This organization operated for a time but finally disolved by paying out $6.50 for each dollar paid in. It was hen reorganized on the present plan with a capital of $50,000 and shares ahuil at SoO.00. These shares can be paid for by assigning 5 cents per hundred weight of milk per month. One vote is allowed each milk producer and a limit of $1,000 is made on stock ownership. The stock pays ii interest. The territory is divided into 54 local units according p natural centers, the number of producers in each unit varying from 25 i 2i)0. Each local unit nominates a director. These directors while they iot legally compelled to do so, have always been elected at the annual ing. All directors must be farmers and milk producers. Directors and elect five of their number to serve as an executive committee uut pay or expenses. The executive committee meets weekly to trans - msiness. An important feature of the Twin City plan is that all iiilk sold is tested by representatives of the organization. They employ 'ive testers who operate in the plants of the various dealers testing the milk. The denier may test the milk also, but the payment is to be based upon the tests made by representatives of the organization. All the busi- the organization is handled from a central office. All payments rom the dealers are made to the organization which in turn pays the ndividual members. The organization has some 4000 open accounts, sup- plies milk EMM at cost, and contracts with the dealers for milk at a set price. There is now something more than $310,000 invested in plants for handlirer surplus, and a substantial sinking fund. The plants are run on a basis of cooperative creameries and the proceeds distributed in that manner. Under the above arrangement, some 13,000,000 pounds of milk a month are handled in the flush season. Only one grade is made and that is for 3.5 per cent milk with a premium for tests above that figure and a deduction for tests tunning under that. Of course it is un - derstood that only the milk of stock holders is handled. To them each month a statement is sent which gives in detail the operations and ac - counts for the month. The cost of operating under this organization of course varies but an average for each hundred weight of milk is 8.7 cents </seg>
            <seg id="p040">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 40 for general expense, 9.22 cents for plant operation, 2.17 cents for sup - plies or about 20 cents per hundred weight. NEW ENGLAND PLAN In some ways the New England Milk Producers Association has dif - ferences that are worthy of notice. It covers a territory that has not only a large central market but numerous other markets of varying size. The association, which has about 24,000 members, 50 districts and 560 locals, covers most of New England. Under the plan of organization five or more dairymen may form a local; the county locals form a District, and the district elects a representative that meets to elect the vice president, treasurer, clerk, auditors, and the board of directors. The latter then choose one of their number for president and select a salaried manager who is entirely responsible for all help. The board further selects a central marketing committee of six to determine the prices for the Boston market. Each of the other principal markets in the territory has a local marketing committee of four and one member from the cen - tral association sits with them. The New England Milk Producers As - sociation is essentially a sales organization, each of the members of which contract with the organization to sell milk at one-half of one per cent of the gross receipts. The organization collects all funds and from the amount deducted pays the local unit 10% of all money collected from that unit and in addition 5 per cent of all district funds go to the district for their financing. Efforts are thus made to avoid too much centralization. Of course all the milk in this territory is not used as market milk. Much of it goes into manufactured products. In order to determine the quantity that is so used, the dealers report to the state commissioner of agriculture all purchases of milk and all manufactured products. He, by means of a series of factors that have been agreed upon, converts such products into bulk milk. Allowing then for the tost of manufacture it is possible to determine the vahie of milk according to its use. The or - ganization and the milk dealers agree on the price of market milk and the open market determines the value of manufactured products. The territory is divided into zones, and the price to the farmer is the city price less the freight, can charge, and the country station charge for the zone. The price of milk in a zone is blended to take care of the manu - factured product which brings a lower price. In the territory there are 21 zones. The average ship to Boston is 200 miles and the cost, 3^4 cents a quart for freight or express. In order to be in a still more favor - able position, the New England Milk Producers Association has acquired several of the largest milk distributing plants in New England paying for them slowly and rotating the stock ownership according to the patronage. There seems some likelihood that they will eventually take over the dis - tribution of milk in many of the cities in the territory. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">1 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 41 MICHIGAN PLAN The dairymen's association after a severe fight with the various hand - lers and manufacturers of milk has evolved a plan for setting the market milk price for Detroit that appears to be giving satisfaction. Briefly it consists of a commission of five, appointed by the governor; or. it are an ex-governor, the state dairy and food commissioner, the state director of the bureau of markets, the professor of dairying at the state agri - cultural college, and a member of the state board of agriculture. la addition, three other members from Detroit, a representative from the chamber of commerce, a representative from the women's clubs of the city, and one from the federation of labor. This commission of eight ha* access to producers' and distributors' books and employs an accountant the price to be paid the producer and the price to the consumer from month to month. The plans discussed do not by any means cover the entire field, but are illustrative of the different types in actual operation. ESSENTIALS IN MARKETING MILK Producers have gem-rally felt that they were not receiving a fair pro - portion of the consumer's dollar. Doubtless in many cases that has been true. This feeling has led to the various forms of organization that have been discussed. In these the producers have first endeavored to obtain a better price through collective bargaining and later by taking over the function of the middlemen through a cooperative organization. Collective bargaining alone is effective when a large enough proportion of the supply ll controlled and when a proper and efficient method is devised for tak - ing rare of surplus milk and for such milk as can not conveniently be (laced on the market without processing. The latter two point* have hampered the success of the collective bargaining or sales organization. si. ice unless there are means provided by the organization for co -irulling - t'r.f supply there will be flood periods that will bring disaster. Gradually growing out of the original bargaining organizations are new organiza - tions that are acquiring milk processing plants — butter or cheese fact - ories, condensaries and drying factories. By having these plants they can control the supply to any large city, keep it even during all seasons, and prevent flooding the market. Certain organizations are acquiring dis - tributing plants in the larger centers and when this is done, the producer will have complete control of his product until it reaches the consumer. The toll of the middleman will then go into the farmers' pocket. It should be possible by eliminating wasteful duplication to reduce ma - terially the cost of distributing milk. The way is not all rosy for the success of such schemes as may be witnessed the failure in different parts of the country of such cooperative enterprises. If producers would remember four important features, many troubles would be eliminated. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 1921 ANNUAL REPORT 1. Milk is perishable — It must be consumed or processed in a few hours. 2. Middlemen are necessaiy to serve the public. The producer ganization may become a middleman. 3. Surplus milk must bo cared fVr 4. Confidence among members and of the pub If a cooperative organization is formed to take either enti part the functions of the middleman, ertain things are nect success. These are well &lt;tated l.y the I'. S. Department of A as follows: 1. A binding producers' contract. 2. Legal form of business organization. 3. Sound plan of business operation. 4. Practical and adequate plan of financing. 5. Competent supervision of all business. 6. Efficient management of all operations. 7. Skilled and efficient employees in operating parts. 8. Volun e of business that makes for economical oper 9. Adequate accounting records. Perhaps the lack of a binding producers' contract has caus operative ventures to fail than any one other thine. In perio&lt; members have been to prone to quit in order to gain a tempo The successful cooperative undertakings have all been those ii members have stayed with the organization through its trial | Perhaps the other essentials could be well sumnu-d up under the of efficient business management. All too frequently a cooperativ gsnization has started off well only to come upon the nnancial rocks in a short time through lack of business foresight. How often a fs has been selected to run a highly technical business about which he I nothing and while he may put his best efforts into the work, it mai In everyday business, the manager of a half million dollar enterpr selected because of his proven ability. It is to be hoped that coopei organizations will exercise the same care in the selection of their oj •P ing managers Cooperative movements are just beginning to function efficiently and if wise policies prevail the movement will spread very rapidly. By follow - ing just policies the cooperative organizations will gain the confidence of the public which is a necessity to ultimate success. I believe the co-operative movement is here to stay, providing it will be fair and furnish a more satisfactory means of handling than by pri - vate parties. When it does not, it will go to the wall. We blame the packers for many things, but I am not sure whether 10. Progressive and sourd business policy </seg>
            <seg id="p043">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 43 r v ou should condemn them or not. If we can operate more efficiently in larketinp meat products than they can, we should take them over. If cannot, we should keep still. Just because a business is large does not ecessarily imply it is making unfair profits because the larger your vol - me of business, normally speaking, the closer your margin can be. If we can keep those things in mind, we can make cooperative market- ing of milk a success, not only in Nebraska, but any place else; but we must keep those things in mind or we are certain to make it a failure. I thank you. (Applause.) MR. O. H. DAFT: Do they fix the price between distributor and con - er, or the retail price, in Michigan? PROFESSOR DAVIS: I think you will find they fix both prices. It works both ways. MR. J. H. FRANDSEN, Lincoln: I move the President be authorised appoint an Auditing Committee and a Committee on Resolutions at this The motion was seconded and carried. THE PRESIDENT: I will appoint the following members as Committee on Resolutions: H. Starke, Red Cloud; C. A. Willian s. College View; J. H. Frandsen, Lincoln; J. H. Clabaugh; H. P. Davis, Lincoln. Committee: MR. C. E. MORSE, Lincoln: It appears to me sinro there is no further program for this afternoon, it would be the part of good bust - ness to proceed with what little business the organization has to trans - act at the present time; therefore I move you that we proceed at once to the election of officers. The motion was seconded and carried ELECTION OF OFFICERS MR. J. H. FRANDSEN: The usual custom is to nominate from the floor. I have had in mind always we should make the Dairy Association as Auditing H. P. Davis, Lincoln; Jacob Sass, Chalco. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 1921 ANNUAL REPORT representative as possible. I do not remember when we have had a pres - ident from the western part of the State. To my mind it is the coming dairy section. I think the Association officials should be sufficiently rep - resentative to take in the various breed associations. To cut a long story short, I would like to place in nomination a man from the western part of the state and a man who is a leading light in his particular breed association. I place in nomination for the office of President. Mr. Cameron J. Furry, of Franklin. LMR. E. W. FROST, Lincoln: I move the nominations be closed, the s suspended, and the entire ballot of the convention cast for Mr. Furry- President of this Association for the ensuing year. The motion was seconded and carried and the ballot so cast MR. JACOB SASS: I should like to place in nomination for Vice President of this Association, Mr. O. M. Enyeart, of Superior. UNo other nominations being- made for vice-president, the unanimous of the convention was given to Mr. Enyeart. MR. E. W. FROST: For the office of Secretary-Treasurer of this As sociation, I nominate our present encumbent, Mr. Palm. Upon motion, Mr. J. E. Palm was unanimously elected Secretary Treasurer for the coming year. The following nominations were then made for directors Jacob Sass, Chalco; C. H. Stark;, Red Cloud; E. W. Frost, Lincoln; J. H. Frandsen, Lincoln; H. C. Young, Lincoln. It was moved the nominations for directors be closed, and the unan - imous vote of the convention cast for the nominees named above. The vote was seconded and carried and the directors declared duly elected. MR. MORSE: I would like to voice my sentiments — and I think they are the sentiments of every dairyman present — in extending a vote of thanks to Mr. McDowell and Professor Davis for the splendid remarks we have listened to on the two subjects this morning. The motion received several seconds, and was carried unanimously. REPORT OF AUDITING COMMITTEE Your Auditing Committee has examined the records of the Treasurer, </seg>
            <seg id="p045">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 45 including the canceled checks, and found his accounts to be correct a» read. H. P. DAVIS JACOB SASS. Upon motion, the report of the Auditing Committee was accepted. After sonve announcements by the President, the convention was de - clared adjourned until ten o'clock Thursday morning. THURSDAY MORNING SESSION January 5, 1922. The second session of the convention met pursuant to adjournment, and was called to order by President Morrison, who introduced Professor Lawritson as the first speaker of the morning. DAIRY EXTENSION ACTIVITIES Professor M. N. LawriUon, Lincoln, Nebraska Mr. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: I have been asked to discuss the extensian activities that have been carried on in this State the past year, and discuss briefly some of the projects we have worked on. I shall not go into them in detail, but I will be glad to try to answer any questions. The general policy in carrying on our extension work throughout the State this year has been to outline and carry out our projects in co-r .-er - ation with the Farm Bureau. We have worked with the organized ex - tension forces in the State in carrying out our projects. The main projects touched this year — those on which we have spent most of our time — were the co-operative cow testing association, the co-operative bull association, boys' and girls' club work, and the inter - esting of farmers in dairying generally, bringing in a better class of dairy stock. Due to the financial conditions, for one thing, we we'j not able to do much with the co-operative bull association; and when we did try to work it, where the prospects seemed most favorable for starting an association, the farmers said they would rather own a bull of their own. The market conditions are such that any number of good bulls in the State are going begging on the market. Due to the low price at which good bulls could be bought, thero did not seem to be a great deal of in - terest in bull association work, and we did not accomplish much on that project Neither did we accomplish as much as we had hoped for with the cow testing association work, but we have one association — the Platte Valley Cow Testing Association in Scotts Bluff county — that is composed of 2* herds with 421 cows in it. It has proved very successful so far, and has </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 1921 ANNUAL REPORT been quite a factor in increasing an interest in the dairy business in that section of the State. We are hopeful of getting at least two more such associations organized this year. The boys' and girls' club work has proved one of the projects in which we could do the most in a missionary way in creating an interest in the dairy industry in sections where it is not already practiced. I think it was David Grogan who said there is more discipline in the continued care of a cow than in many a term of school. At the time, he probably did not realize he was hitting the keynote of the newer education — boys' an&lt;l girls' club work. This year we have had eight dairy calf clubs with seven dairy club members. Each member has raised a heifer of a dairy breed ani taker • great deal of interest in the club work. Where we cannot reach th&lt;? parents through any other projects, they have become interested throuj.ii the boys and girls. Our greatest handicap has been to get the breeders to co-operate v us to the extent of selling a heifer at a price the boys and girls could f They usually asked prices that were prohibitive. We would rather them take grades than not get any start at all. If we can get the br« ers to see the value of this club work and get them f price the children can afford to buy, we will be abl more in this club work. I was talking the proposition over with a local breed a one county of this State, and several of the members said tha r\ in their association would get together and agree this club work at a price not to exceed $75, they would be willing to do the same; but that if just a few agreed, they would not do it, either. With the exception of three or four members, they all agreed. These few men said they could not afford to do it, so the plan fell through. If you breeders will get together and we can co-operate, we can get much better results in this club work. Another thing we should consider for this coming year is the devising of some means whereby the farmer can market his surplus milk at a profit. I am confronted with this question every time I go out to talk dairying or increasing production. The Sist question the producers ask is, "How am I going to dispose of this milk after I do get it? What is the use of increasing the production when I can't get anything for the milk after I have it?" They want to know what is the reason for this surplus and for the price dropping. If we can co-operate in some way — either by putting on an educa - tional campaign teaching the value of milk as a food, or in some other way increase the consumption — it would help. It has been suggested we get some of the n-ilk condensaries to put in a branch plant. Before we can get them interested we must have enough cows to guarantee a certain </seg>
            <seg id="p047">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 47 amount of milk each day. The question arises: Is it wise for us to go ahead and get enough cows and figure on them coming in, or can w« aevise some other means? We have letters coming in from farmers wanting to know where they can sell their milk. The places where they have been selling have id - vised them not to ship any more. It seems to me one of the problems wi can spend a little time on would be that of trying to work out a plan whereby this surplus milk would be taken care of. They have suggested a farmers' co-operative condensary in some sec - tions. Thty called the farmers together and we talked it over. I ex- plained how much it would cost to equip a condensary, and that was knocked in the head. They decided there would be nothing to that if they would have to invest $60,000 to get a small commercial condensary At the present time we have no solution for this problem of disposing thi- surplus milk. I should like to have the opinion of some of you, or suggestions as to how we are going to answer those questions as they are rut to us. If you have any ideas as to what would be the best method of approach I would appreciate hearing them. alls for Mr. Boomer.) MR. BOOMER: I do not know that I can give a suggestion which ■uld be of any immediate help. There has been a great deal of talk in iranl to the development of a local plant. They are handicapped in the same way the producer is They are not able to find an outlet for their product. That seems to be the difficulty in the way. There has not been very much done along the line of finding a market in a co-operative way for dairy products, that has come to my attention, in the State. MR. H. F. McINTOSH, Omaha: Does not the sale of their cream satisfy r farmers? PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: Yes, up to the time they informed them not to ship any more. I had a letter from Fillmore county where one farmer had been told by the Fairmont Creamery not to ship more milk. He wanted to know if we knew of some place where he could market his milk. A good many would rather keep the skim milk than sell the whole milk, and others are looking for a market for their whole milk. It depends on local conditions. Sometimes there is a shortage and again they have a surplus. The question that is put to me every time I advocate in - creasing production through the means of cow testing associations — cull - ing out the inferior cows— is, "What is the use of milking more cows when we cannot get anything for the milk we have?" If we can figure out some way by which we help the farmers take care of the surplus, it seems to me we will have solved the biggest problem before us at the present time. Personally, I do not know of any way to get around that. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 1921 ANNUAL REPORT MR. NO YES: We are booming the business. We have no selling or - genization and no way to get rid of the milk. Let me give you an illustration. I had a neighbor who last fall a year ago, when he was milking twenty cows, started to draw the milk to the creamery, selling as whole milk. He took it with his own truck. He in - creased his cows until by the first of Marcn he was milking forty-five cows, but his milk check had not increased a bit. The first of September this year he was milking forty cows and selling the milk as whole milk. Today he is milking sixty cows and getting the same old milk check. It looks to me as if we should stop booming the dairy business until we can market the milk. A dairyman went to a creamery and wanted • contract. He said he would guarantee the delivery to them. They said, "We do not like to take so much milk from one man. You have S20.000 invested in your dairy and you want a reasonable amount of in - terest on that investment. We buy from the little fellow and he does not figure on getting any interest. If he gets enough to buy the groceries, he is satisfied. I think it is wise to stop booming the dairy business until we get to a place where we can market profitably and get interest on the money in - vested. MR. C. L. JONES, Coif ax: I do not think we should stop producing better dairy cattle. The fanner needs education. He wants to learn to raise a patch of alfalfa and some Jersey cows; then have some cows that when he sells their offspring the butcher will buy them; then milk a good cow, and what is left over let the pigs have it. You will get some - thing besides the cream check. You will add fertility to your soil and have money at the end of the year. I do not think the average farmer has any idea of going into the dairy business, but he does need to be ed - ucated along the line of a better dairy cow which will make more money for the same amount of food. MR. SLOCUMB, Aberdeen, S. Dak.: I would like to know how fast can you increase dairy cows and get an over-production ? W PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: It depends on what you mean by an over - oduction. MR. SOLCUMB: You can double them in about ten years. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: As far as an over-production of good dairy cattle in this State is concerned I do not think there is any im - irediate danger of it. Our greatest need is better dairy cows instead of more dairy cows. Get rid of the poor ones and replace them with good ones. Your poor cow takes the same amount of food end labor your good cow does; so why not have a cow that will return more profit? If we can get the farmers interested in getting better cows, they will build up the herd in that way. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 49 MR. SLOCUMB: We threshed these same things quite a while ago in our State. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: Did you find any way of solving the pro - blem of getting rid ot' your surplus milk? MR. SLOCUMB: We do not have this surplus milk. We cream separ - ate it on the farm. We cannot get enough of the skim milk to feed. If the cows freshen in the fall and you feed your winter calves, by the time the pig's come along in May, your calves can wait if you wean them. You can feed those pigs, and that is what you want to keep th-j cholera away. MEMBER: If you feed a calf you have something to sell. MR. SLOCUMB: A calf of the dairy breed will grow just as fast as the shorthorrs if you ?et the right kind. THE PRESIDENT: The question that seems to bother them is this: If we increase the production, how long will it be before the price of batter fat drops? MR. SLOCL'MB: You want to figure on this: At how much lower price than you are now getting can you make a profit on your milk? We are paying ten dollars a ton for feed and selling it through the cow for forty dollars. That's profiteering. We can afford to sell it for twenty-five dol - lars instead of forty, if we can get help. We have a creamery costing $140,000. All the profit above expenses goes to the dairymen. We have 3500 producers. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: That is the question put to me in different sections of the State — whether or not it is feasible to market in a co - operative way? But as Mr. Davis said yesterday, if you have all the things he mentioned, you would probably make a success of it. My observation has been the main trouble with the farmers of this State in co-operative organizations has been that they might be com - pared with a group of small pigs on a cold day, huddled together for protection and warmth. That individual pig is not going into it for the benefit of the rest of them. So just as long as the individual farmer sees he is getting more than from an outsider, he sticks; but as soon as ait outsider offers him more, he leaves his organization and tho thing falls through. If they could get some binding contract it might be that would be the solution of this problem. The trouble with the average Nebraska farmer is, he does not want to n.ilk cows. He wants the calf to do the milking. He won't do it until he is right up against the wall. Then he will milk to get a littla money, and as soon as he gets on his feet again, he quits milking cows. We can buy some of the best cows there are for sale and give them to </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 1921 ANNUAL REPORT these farmers, but if that is the way they operate, they will soon tear down these herds. It seems to rre one of the best things this Association can do is to find some means to help the farmer get rid of this surplus milk at a profit. I have jrone over these projects hurriedly. If you are interested in them in detail, I will be glad to furnish you with a typewritten copy so that you can go over it yourself. I will not take any more of your time unless there are somt more questions. LMR. W. W. JENKINSON, Monroe: I believe in getting the city people use more milk. There are thousands in the city not using enough milk. There are enouph of people in this State to take tare of every bit of sur - plus milk we have, if it is properly advertised. The city children need milk more than anything else. They need it more than the pigs or calves The calves and pigs will take care of the surplus, but let the city children have it first. I think an educational campaign would ilo n ore than any - thing else. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: Is it advisable to put on an campaign to teach the food value of milk? Will that take car surplus ? MR. JENKINSON: It will surely heir MR. McINTOSH: When it takes three quarts of the producers milk to distribute one quart to the consumer, it is pretty hard story for the consumer in the cities. That is what is happening all over Nebraska as far as I am acquainted in the State. The middle man will swear up and down he has not an excessive profit. The producers are petting eleven cents a (ration and consumers are payinjr thirteen cents a quart, and yet the distributor insists he is starving to death. You have a problem there if you want to go to it. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: How are you going about it to eliminate this middle man, if that is what we are to do? No doubt the middle man is a necessary evil, if that is what you want to call it. Perhaps a farmer's co-operative association is the solution. MR. McINTOSH: The Farmers' Co-operative Association does not help out in Oiraha materially. In some cities the distribution is worked out on a fifty-fifty basir.. Why can't it be put on that basis ia the western cities? There is organized robbery goin? on in this country that is destroying 1 production. PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: The question is, how are we goin? to elim - inate it? </seg>
            <seg id="p051">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 51 MB. W. F. DALE, Lincoln: Are you making a profit here on the Farm &gt;m the cows ? Is there a profit, and how much of a profit here at the ROFESSOR LAWRITSON: I do not know whether the question could They sell their product in various forms. -w PROFESSOR JOHN A. LUITHLY, Lincoln: We only bottle and sell Wi don't attempt to deliver milk. We have a certain amount of milk experiment with and turn into .-huming of cream. MR. DALE: Is there a profit on that? PROFESSOR LAWRITSON: If we were selling whole milk at ten cenU quart, we would not make a profit. MR. DALE: I supposed with the plant furnished by the State, there a profit in making the butter. If not, what is the encourage- for the individual dairyman? PROFESSOR LUITHLY: In making butter there is a very small mar - n of profit unless it is made on a large scale. You must ship most of the butter to eastern markets. We do not sell nearly all the butter manu - factured in this State in Nebraska. There is not the population to take -are of it. A large percentage is shipped to Chicago and New York City. The freight rates have been high, and unless you are able to make hip in carload lots, your profit is small. MR. L. E. GRUVER, University Place: Isn't the butter higher here than Chicago — the wholesale price? PROFESSOR LUITHLY: The same price. MR. GRUVER: Then why pay the cost of shipping? PROFESSOR LUITHLY: Because all the butter made here cannot be &gt;nsumed here. MR. GRUVER: Why should we ship it to Illinois and pay the freight? PROFESSOR LUITHLY: The State of New York does not make enough butter. The milk is used in fluid form. They must draw on western states for their supply of butter. MR. GRUVER: Why should we ship our butter to New York City or Chicago when we get the same price for it in Nebraska? Why pay the PROFESSOR LUITHLY: The price is not regulated by the supply and demand in Nebraska, but by the supply and demand in our eastern markets. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 52 PROFESSOR LAWFMTSON: How many producers are willing to co - operate in boys' and girls' club work to the extent of letting a pore-bred heifer go at a price the boys and girls can afford to pay? I would like seme calves for calf clubs in this State if I can get them. If not, we will have to go out of the State to buy. We have been criticised for going into other states. We would be glad to help you dispose of them if you will list them with us. I have asked before that this be done, but it seems we have not been able to get the fanners to write in and list the cattle they have for sale, or those they wish to buy. If you will let us know, we will be glad to locate cattle, or help you sell them. We have been trying to buy some purebred calves, but the prices have been so much higher than what we can buy them for in Wisconsin and other dairy states and ship them in, they are not interested in getting them in Ne - braska. I would like to have a litt'e co-operation from you breeders to help solve this problem. If we are not to go to other states to select the cattle, then let us have them priced at home so we can afford to buy them. If a man can have them laid down here cheaper than he can get them from local breeders, you can not blame him for doing it. The average man who goes to a Nebraska breeder and asks for pure-bred heifers will be told by the breeder they are not for sale. I should be glad to have suggestions along this line. MEMBER: I do not think when we compare the State Farm with our tividual herd on the question of profit and loss, it is a fair criterion to by. rl have a certain amount of pasture and a certain amount of alfalfa. could buy a few good dairy cows, but the expense of a good sire would come so heavy on me I could not afford it. If several of us would get to - gether and all keep the same kind of cows we would all make more money off that same piece of ground that we use for pasture and hay at the present tin e. I think that is what we should try to do. PROFESSOR LAWR1TSON: That's the idea' If you belong to a co-op - erative bull association your share of the expense of the sire would be nominal. MEMBER: I am working along these lines all the time. The State Farm goes to hundreds of dollars of expense to get a sood sire to help us along these lines, so we cannot compare our figures with theirs. 1 keep three good cows. If I could get better cows I would make more off the same piece of ground. That is what I am interested in. MR. SLOCUMB: They can buy those sires for less than half the money they could be purchased for a short time ago. I sold some this fall. I tve one I tried to offer for $60. He took third prize at the State Fair. » have too many of them. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 1921 ANNUAL REPORT MR. KIRK WOOD: I see the Dairy Association has arrived at a place where it can do itself some pood. Th«' thing to do is to weed out ccws not paying thoir way and build up a herd worthy of your work a the industry you are following. The farmers and ranchers of this State are in need of more fund carry on their operations. They must supply their table and little m En the milk and butter they pet from a few cows. They are mill the ranches to quite an extent. That is why you are having a There il a man sitting by me who said, "I have cows in my here paying their way. I am on the Testing Committee of the Farm Bu Kick me out!" That is what you should do. Get your herds in shap busi MR. W. M. SUTTON. Table Rock: Mr. President, Ladi ( rven: I was a pioneer in this work in the organization of the Nehr Dairymen's Association. Some forty years ago tht dairy products of Nebraska was through the back door of a store at t price of soap grease, in exchange for a little tobacco or coff* It is twenty-rive years or mori since I have attended this A am glad to be with you. although I do not recognize the t' old pioneers of forty year: I can answer in one word, perhaps, the crux of the great are discussing — an outlet for your surplus. The fa we have no surplus. Quality is what is the n ,v would remind you at the time of the World's Kx Nebraska Dairymen's Association, through th carloads of Nebraska's dairy product and ker three months s.ibject to an Hurt x scored to the t:&gt;p in competition with the world af test of keeping. I was manufacturing and sellinj carloads of butter a week. The more I had, the better get, because we had created a demand for buttei poses. It was said and thoueht the Nebraska butter w :ir in cold storage better and longer than from any of our great dair We have the diplomas and the medals to prove that we had establish* a lating where such a thing as a surplus was not considered at all. Wt shipped goods from the Atlantic to the Pacific and got the top price. Ev- erything that graded as "Western Extra" brought the Elgin price here Visit your receiving stations any day during the summer time and you will find in those shipping cans a product that is not n't for good hog feed! In the early days the large creameries based their price on West prn Extra every week and paid for butter fat the price of Elgin Extra it your station. Now it usually runs eight cents below. I think but little of your butter grades up to 96 per cent, or as Western Extra </seg>
            <seg id="p055">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 55 t- II \x c le of your product and manufacture it as it should be. You he fraudulent products to contend with we had in those early ys. We spent days and weeks and years before our State Legislature d the United States Congress pleading for the enactment of laws that &gt;uld protect us from those fraudulent products. You have those laws m. The trouble is, the quality of your goods is such that those sub - tutes have taken to a large extent the place of pood dairy products, lere is no danger of an over production of good, first-class dairy and .it ( Applause. THt IMPORTANCE OF DAIRYING" an \c rman. President World's Dairy Congress, Washington, D. C. E. \ Ladies and Gentlemen of Nebraska: It is a strange sen - throuch ir.y mind thi.s morning to think that forty-two &gt;n*h I arrived in this town. 1 saw a little something of lays the last speaker referred to. Times have changed c sivn a lot of things happen. I just want to remind you hree of the tilings that have happened in this State. had throe dairy leaders I know. Professor Haecker came into this urs asro and laid the foundation for the splendid college herd. ■&gt; Krandsen followed him, and under his leadership you built this uilding. I only know of one other state I have visited in this it has ;:•&lt; well built a building as this building we are in ngratulatt* you upor having it. Now you have within the last brought another man to the leadership of the dairy interests &gt;uni» m?n whom it was my privilege to associate with Pennsylvania. I know he has it in him to do you I believe you will find him a safe leader — a mar. who will help you. know the Frenchmen and some othtr nationalities cannot talk in u thev cannot see thtir hands go. So I wan: to put ■ard up here. MF' "IS" AND THK "GOVERNMENT" es all three to make the team. There have been times in the mind farmer when he thought his whole existence depended on the ment. He was always looking to the government to remedy every verr : : i n*r that was wrong. Yet we have just elected a President on the plat - nr n of "More business in government and less government in business." Vhen sometimes we are inclined to turn around and want the government ■ correct all that is wrong, let us not forget we have had too much gov - inment in some of our business, in the minds of a great many people. Now, then, I want to jump to the other end of the game. There are two </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 1921 ANNUAL REPORT kil as of things to be done in this State, at this meeting, in your home, on your farm, in your community. We are all human. We have just as much selfishness right hire in our own home and community and family as over across the road or in the next state; and the thing that is need - ed, after all is said and done, is the thing that rises above the common faults we all have. When we are finding fault with the other fellow, let us remember he is human and we are human, and it is the fellow who is able to figure out a way to do in spite of all these things who will win out There are two kinds of things to be done. One is the thing which I can do for myself, and the other is the thing I cannot do for myself, but we car do together. I gather from the talk this morning I should not say "as dairymen," because a lot of you are not dairymen. Some of you are a disgrace to the name of dairymen. We know we have them somewhere in the State if they aren't here today. A lot of us are just owning some cows. Today, because everything else is busted, we are looking at the old cow and wanting her to do everything for us we should have done be- fore. Somebody said there is a surplus. Why have you so much surplus'.' The reason is, every fellow who hasn't anything else to sell is milking that old stripper cow three months longer than he would have been a year ago. She does not give much or good milk, but he sells it and gets a little bit of cash for it. Then he is going to milk that cow that comes fresh next month instead of letting the calf have it. The sum total in the difference in the amount of milk all over the country when a lot of fellows do that salt of thing really makes quite a difference. That is part of the condition and we might as well accept it. What it going to happen is just as soon as these things come up and the dairy product goes down, that fellow is going to quit. He won't pull teats for anybody! The things I want to speak about first are the things "me" can do to help myself. I wish 1 had some way of pounding that home because it seems to me when I ride around the country — and it has been my privi - lege to work in several states — there are so many men who have their eye on what the other fellows and the government car. do to help them, in - stead of getting down to what "me" can do to help myself to get "me" out of the hole. How many of you drive an automobile, or the wreck of one? i Laugh - ter.) You start out somewhere. You know I think sometimes the courage of some men as I see them start off is simply beyond admiration, i Laugh - ter.) They must drive through mud and ford streams, and expect to get there with it' When he blows out a tire and thore isn't a house within a dozen miles, the man does not sit around and call for the government to pull him out of the hole. He goes to work and helps himself, and the amount of ingenuity the average man who drives a machine can work </seg>
            <seg id="p057">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 57 up! The old harness that needed repairs is nothing to a machine that can be made to go with average American ingenuity. Again we have had a war, and the conditions we are in today are the result of that war; and the way to get out of these conditions is to help ourselves the same as you did with that old machine. And first are the things you can do to help yourselves under your circumstances. When I see a man raising ten or twelve bushels of wheat to the acre when by pioper methods within his reach he could raise fifteen or twenty, and when he is raising thirty bushels of corn and might have seventy, and everything else about the farm run on the same scale I think that man should be ashamed to complain of anything, because he has not done for himself and his business what he must do when he drives his machine. He must make it go himself and he has not made his farm business go with those conditions. You say, "What's the use of raising more?" This the reason: COST : PROFIT There are two ways to raise the profit. One is to get more for what you have. That is what 99 1 j per cent of all of you have your eyes glued on all the time. You are growling because you cannot raise the price to increase the profit. The price at which you sell your stuff is not fixed by "me" in agriculture. It may be in a retail store. You might just as well recognize it, for it is never going to be any other way. All the co - operation and Farm Bureaus and everything else are not going to fix the price of the fundamental products of the nation's food supply. This price will \&gt;e fixed by the law of supply and demand. Why are corn and wheat cheap? Because there are more of them available than buyers and users for them. Why are dairy products rela - tively higher than wheat and corn? Because there are relatively more buyers for dairy products in proportion to the supply and they are pay - ing a higher price. I say we spend too much time with our eyes glued on prices at this time, forgetting if we cut a little off the cost we can add just as much to the profit. This part of the game is for me in my business to do. The biggest service the government can render is in helping me to help myself to reduce this cost. Why are the railroads laying off thousands of men and all these great industrial centers cold-bloodedly turning these men out? Because they must reduce this cost in their business in order to live. All these great business organizations are at this time doing everything they can to reduce their cost. They cannot force the volume of business or the price, therefore they must reduce their cost. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">■ 1921 ANNUAL REPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p059">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 59 Now as business men on our farms, we have the same problem. And to devote some of your time and brains and energy to the inspection cf your own aifairs to see whether or not you and thus help your profit a little reduce the loss proportionally. There are which the question has been to keep the loss ds .if businesses, every time they save that much Your speaker yesterday morning told you here the man who increased production of his cows from 150 to 400 pounds, increased the net it or the margin — I do not like the term net profit — between cost and Just think of it! He could increase the margin Now I want to say to you that in those great dairy states where to say ulture means to say dairying, the men who have cows that average nds of butter a year are not worrying very nuch about present ns; because they have their business so efficiently conducted there profit in it at present prices. I remember fifteen years ago a buyer for milk in New York City said The farmer with a 6,00d pound cow is never complaining about the price k ; but you cannot pay the farmer with the 3,000 pound cow please him." things you can do to h?lp yourselves are: Better feeding of ry cow. whatever she is; the elimination of the least profitable i^ a man who must have the te&gt; dollars the cream check laa not want to kill that one cow. But there are men in tion where it woul'I pay them to get rid of two or three of the cows, net money on what is left. So we must look to the feeding f the cowl the breeding of better cows. The man who ahead to five years of dairy business can not afford not to take better cow eads to the next thing. There are certain things that can only y "us" — by associated effort. I want to remind you that in the larly days of this country, most of the men who lived on the land f&lt; d ard clothed their own families from the product of their own soil, and protected their families with their own gun. Just think a mo - ment of what that means. Tirres hav? changed, and today less than 37 per cent of our p-.-ople actually live on the land, and most of those who live on the land do not feed or clothe themselves with the stuff they produce on that land. The trade what they produce on that land. They trade what they produce to some other fellow for the food and clothing to bring back to the farm. How many farmers make their own butter? There are thousands of farmers buying butter, or — more's the pity : — oleomargarine. (Laughter.) usir.es; </seg>
            <seg id="p060">1921 ANNUAL REPORT ■ They are buying their own potatoes. They are buying all their cloth - ing, all their machinery and wagons; yet they used to be made right there at home. Not only has that change come about but these things are being done, not by the individual, but by great associations of people. What is the "steel trust" but a great association of laborers, bookkeepers, and managers and foremen and superintendents, using the capital oth.-r people have invested in that business through their stock ownership? It is an association of effort. We used to have a one-man stage coach carrying people back and forth. What have we here? Gigantic organizations — companies, we call them — trusts. The point is they are a lot of people working together in which the individual does not have a great deal of liberty of action. Isn't the brakeman on a train or the conductor on the little one-man street car a part of an association which lays down to him the rules by which he shall conduct his day's work Now that is going all through ciety. Our great department store or manufacturing or transports organization is an association of effort which has superceded vidual effort. I believe that agriculture nt of effort is necessary in order to accomplish those thing; done by "us" working together — things which cannot b« by myself. I think that is going to be the great devel period in which we ave a part: association of effort. Write it big on your minds that ever if you get the benefit of association of effort, a part of the priet up the liberty of individualism. I can not hav idual and get all the bt-r.efit of associated effort. Now theoretically — and I believe it works out in practi f and laborers working together ir. a corporation under th brains able to make the corporation a success, earns more than that ind vidual — that particular measure of ability — could have earned off by h self. In other words, the ability that made the president of that corpora tion a president should increase the earning power of every man a ed with him; because he has his own brains plus the president's brains Then it is apparent a necessity of associated effort if we should have able leadership. We only have one great general in an army. We have a lot of lesser generals and a great many captains, and so on down the line. Farmers' organizations must have leadership, and the individual must give up a part of his individualism and play teamwork with the rest behind a successful leader. Another thing: As individuals, you and Bill Brown can trade horses and be just as dishonest as the other fellow will stand for. You can shut </seg>
            <seg id="p061">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 61 your eyes and tell him the horse is sound when you know he has every - thing flesh is heir to. If Bill Jones does not discover it until you have your money and he has the horse, he can whistle, and there is no harm done to anybody but the two of you. If he traded his bay horse for your black one there is nobody harmed. That was an individual enter - prise. But when you associate yourselves together as a group and one organ - ization tries to do business with another you cannot do business that way. The association must be right and work on right principles and methods. A great deal has been said in this day and age about the California Citrus Fruit Growers' Association. It has been held up as a shining example of successful association of effort commonly called co-operation. They have succeeded because they were, first legally right. They have been morally right. Now, I am perfectly willing to admit there are just many men and women in this audience who will put the big apples n the top of the barrel as in any other audiance of the same size. Laughter. ) The individual may do that with apples or potatoes or or- ange? he has to sell, but the association cannot do it. Then this California Association to which I refer has been economi - cally right. And some of our organizations — notably some of our co - operative bureau associations — have unfortunately, from my standpoint not been economically right. They have tried to do something contrary he fundamental economic laws of business and commerce and they ave failed Now we come to the last point. They must be wisely led, and follow leader. These things are absolutely essential to associated or co- ffort: legally right, morally right, economically right, and led Now until our American farmers get so deep into the financial mire hey were ready to do anything, lots of them did not learn the lesson if how to work together. It took the club of adversity to force them to work together. But we have made great progress, and we have today a great many successful co-operative efforts. I want to warn you against one or two of the things I think are the biggest rocks in the road of our younger agricultural co-operative efforts. The biggest one of all is the assumption of superior holiness on the part of the farmers — the assumption that we as farmers are all right and the middle man and all the rest have conspired against us. It is not worthy of the man who can drive an old Ford machine over rough roads to beg the question and say, "We poor farmers ; Everybody is against us but we are all right." Remember "me" is the biggest thing. The next is "ua". Let us get ourselves together. When we try to do business as a group with the other group give the other fellow credit for as much honesty as we believe we have in our group I do not believe a thousand farmers </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 1921 ANNUAL REPORT i &gt; r J: mi. ■ hi ' ! IP ;v I |*-C 2 i &gt; li i I?? As i I ■ i i! I I U 1 . fr ij ~ : ' ■j g§ * &gt; ! — 2 - I • F 3 a m\ 2 «\ </seg>
            <seg id="p063">A- r A Y ves, mu r thir in helf Just n xes the t ment I tha NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION ■ i thousand middle men. I know there are he eye teeth out of anybody when they get are farmers who will, too. On the other iH-n t &gt;gether. they are only djing what you he middle man is making a living by render - ce, and I believe some how, some way, society ssary service and shorten the route from the of our products. We are doing that. The und the city man who is willing to go to a cheaper than up town. ■d to Washington. I happen to have landed in a com- re 50 to 75 per cent higher — so my wife declares — has ever been. Young lettuce was twenty-rive cents store next our home. A little farther, it was twenty cents. U the market it was fifteen cents. Then we went to the outside market and a lot of those people go to buy, and it was ten cents ut on the street coiner with the daga and the basket on his uld buy lettuie for five cents a bunch. Don't v'ou see? The radually evolving. It is up to the city fellow to go down hero he can get it for less. It is up to the individual to find the place &gt;n his scale of ability. I don't like to carry it home wer was, "Then you must pay the other fellow for carrying ou go down and hire an automobile for two dollars and buy worth of stuff, and you will save enough to pay for the hire of r iye glued to the two dollars she would spend instead ars she might save. We get our eyes set on one part orget the other part. *• whether I have made clear to you what I have said or it up in a few words. A lot of our troubles, we, our- jrrect. "Me" is the big end of the game. There are some n which if we can associate ourselves with our neighbor ) ourselves. Then there is a little bit the government can help nw we are cursing a whole lot about taxes. The government xes and tariff and the rates on the railroad. We are the gov- you. (Applause.) m;ik» an honest living in their part of </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 1921 ANNUAL REPORT THURSDAY AFTERNOON SESSION January 5. 1922. The final business session of the convention was called to order by President Morrison at 1 :25 P. M. on Thursday afternoon. "BETTER DAIRY METHODS" Mr. A. J. Glover, Editor "Hoard's Dairyman", Kort Atkinson, Wis. Mr President, Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association Ladies and Gentlemen: It has been my privilege on a number of occa - sions in the past 18 years to discuss with you some phase of dairying This has been a pleasure to me. and I trust some (rood has been accom- I am to discuss this afternoon "Better Dairy Methods." It is quite common, these times, to refer to our period of depression, and to offer some solution for bringing us back to normal conditions. It is easy to find fault; easy to point out the things that are not right; but it is quite another question to adjust our economic relationships. A great many people not engaged in dairying are trying tu solve th dairyman's problems for him; but after all is said and done, it is the ma behind the cow who must solve these problems. If each one of us will d our plain duty, be honest with ourselves and our neighbors, the quicker w shall get through the distressing period and be on the way with a ffrea period in American history. There are three or four things prominent before the dairyman - things over which he has control. They are: The dairy cow; the qualit of her product; organization for marketing and advertising the value c milk and its products. These are the things I shall discuss this afternooi There is a movement, so I am informed upon good author vocate decreasing the production of milk in order to secure a higher price for dairy products. I cannot conceive of anything so valueless as a body of men attempting to decrease the production of dairy products when we are not consuming in this country one-half as much milk as our scien - tists say is necessary for the health of the people and for economy. The reduction of the milk supply is not the solution of our problem. Would - n't it be better for these men to direct themselves toward eliminating the poor cow and breeding better ones, towards establishing better dairy meth - ods than to attempt to decrease milk production in order to force up the price of dairy products ? I do not feel those men will get far with a cam - paign of that character. But I think they will be in the position like the old farmer who tied a cow's tail to his bootstrap because she was swat - ting him with it when he was milking her. She then started off and he was heard to remark that he had not been goinff around the barn yard more than a dozen times, the first on one end and then on the other, before he realized his mistake, i Laughter.) </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION want to see the dairy industry of this country attempt to do ■omethinif and then find it a failure. I would rather be a party to help hese men realize their mistake before they undertake any such propo- Where is there a better market for farm products today than the \v '.' When you produce corn in Nebraska you are looking for the &gt;fst market; it may be the elevator, your hogs or beef cattle, or your ♦airy cow. It is safe to say there isn't a better market in the whole Unit - t d States for farm crops than the dairy cow. She will return you more than any other market. I do not believe the dairy farmers are going to ii.- stampeded into ignoring that market by any group of men who would regulate prices of dairy products by reducing the number of cows. The farmer who has hay and grain to sell will have to be shown a better mar- fore he will sell his cows. It is always in order to attempt to get farmers to eliminate a poor to fncourage him to keep high producing cows. The poor cow loses 1 money and creates, in many instances, the surplus milk which help* keep dairy products at comparatively low prices and to make dairy- ing unprofitable. When we compare the returns of the good dairy cow even at present prices, with those received for other farm products, we immediately see how short sighted, how unthoughtful it is for anyone to consider a campaign for the purpose of decreasing milk production. Let that effort be placed upon eliminating the poor, unprofitable cows; putting better ones in their places, giving them better care and feed, and to ad- sing the consumer of the importance and value of dairy products. No arket will pay as much for farm crops as the good dairy cow and no going to get far in urging the fanners to dispose of that market he can offer a better one. In the annual report of the Fort Atkinson Cow Testing Association 1 920 some very convincing figures are found and they show what kind market good cows are for our farm products. The best herd in this •iation returned $2.61 for each dollar expended for feed and the 382 ws returned $2.02 for each dollar's worth of feed consumed. The poor - t herd returned but $1.43 for each dollar expended in feed. Feed was figured at the following prices: Pasture $.10 a day, silage $8 per ton, hay $24, stover $6, and grain $40 and the average price received for fat wa» 70 a pound One of the best herds in the association averaged 9,066 lbs. of milk ontaining 455 lbs. of fat. The cost of the feed per cow for this herd was $136.69 and the returns over the cost of feed was $184.88. The poorest producing herd in the 33 tested averaged 5,034 lbs. milk containing 183 lbs. of fat. The cost of feed per cow averaged $80.6S for thia b«rd and the returns above cost of feed $47-42. There is shown in these figure* tba tremendous opportunity of increasing the production of the cows even in this association which contains unusually high producing cows. The </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 1921 ANNUAL REPORT W A :i H I poorest herd averaged 183 lbs. of fat per cow in the year a 4hb lbs. and the return above cost of feed was $47.42 per &lt; poorest herd and $184.88 for the best, the average tor all c association being $97.55. Isn't it well for us, .vhen wi dairy cow, to take into consideration the markt ducts; how she increases their price; how she uti corn silage be worth if it were not for the dairy six dollars per ton for it. I sometimes feel w dairy cow two dollars a ton for alfalfa hay, bee; in Idaho. But that would hardly be fair. One problem before the dairyman is the getting of good cows. \V ever we car decrease the cost of production, wt increase our profit. T jr pr is the way every legitimate business is trying to build up its profit. T tempt to control prices by cutting down production when we do not hav enough dairy products is to begin at the wrong end, and especially wht the good dairy cow is returning more for the feed she consumes thar elevator will pay. The average tow in the United States produces about I'M) Iks. o &lt;■ per year. Is it not Wetter that we dispose of these low producing and put better ones in their places before we undertake a campaign t crease the production of milk? Let us see what returns we can make nbove cost of feed. A MV that will produce one pound of fat a day require about the following ration: W lbs. of silage, id lbs. of hay. !■ of grain. If this irrain is made up of bran, oats, and corn thi-; r: f B n (1 will cost about t&amp;\kt, ■■■■■!■! that silatre M worth $l&gt; per tc bran $30, oats $2(1, ami corn $15. One pound of butterfat is wo livered to the eiMUMVJT wm4 this ghMi a return of $.20 a day al feed for a cow producing one pound fat. It should be obsen these farm products havt been marketed at a better price th ntw will pay. It may be stated here that some one will ask. ' the overhead expenses, such as the labor to care for the cow her product, depreciation, and all other items that enter int.i making milk?" It n ay hi said that upon the dairy farm whi, diversification and sells its hmtXtrtni to the hwmij or its cheese factory, that the calf, the skim milk, the manure, and tion of waste feed, which would !&gt;e valueless without the CO this overhead expense. But that isn't all. The dair&gt; cow provides a market for and crops that cannot !»■ sold otherwise and in do the price of corn. Gluten feed is selling on the market for thirty to forty ton. Alfalfa hay in Wisconsin is ~ellinu from the lain at lars per ton. In Idaho, with few cows, it is selling fof two .In </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION .V * :lt and nor milk able ow testing association I mentioned, the best herd averaged ow per year and the poorest averaged 183 pounds. The jnds fs he United States makes 130 pounds. Can we honestly vv &gt;mplain of the price of dairy products when millions of such ■yra re kept ? Can't we turn the light upon ourselves and say, here s ty for us to dispose of these cows that do not return &gt;P t of feed 1" Isn't that a better way to tackle the pro- h to pa em than go out in a campaign to create an impression that there is no - oney in dairying; That we must reduce the output, when we are pro- f as much dairy products as we should? iminate the poor cow. A man said the other day if we Mv m all good cows and keep as many, there would be an over- That might be true. But it is better to milk fewer cows if ituation. Would it not be wiser to keep ten cows yielding were ou h, than to keep thirty average cows? You have just one - ti. take care of. There iray come a time when the prk-e of j iW will be such that of necessity we will have to limit produc - fCt a proper return for dairy products. But until we have ber of efficient cows in our barns we are not justified in any reduce the production of so important a product as milk. in i N is another way of reaching this problem, and that is to ed - umer regarding the pood value of milk and its products. i appreciates that dairy products are essential foods ary for health, as well as the most economical ani- on the market today. acturers of dairy products have been silent too sity and value of their products. Thinking and f« have recognized the superiority of dairy pro- \ few nations have made milk the chief diet. We find lother under all circumstances will provide her children &gt;f milk, but our American mothers do not hold did we would not have to many children who W. D. Hoard, in testifying before the House Committee on made this statement: "Butterfat is found in the It is chemically and physically unlike any other in existence. It was designed by nature for the food and sustenance fant offspring having the most delicate of all digestions." He took position long before scientists discovered vitamines and before inves- tions had been made to demonstrate the difference between milk fat other fats. His reason and common sense told him what neither he the chemists could prove. Since that time it has been proven that [ fat does contain a growth producing substance not found in veget - fats, oils, or in all animal fats. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 1921 ANNUAL REPORT tThe British Food Journal, November, 1919, contained the following tement: "Dr. Holliday Sutherland, consulting tuberculosis, officer to the St. Marylebone Dispensary, lecturing recently on The Early Diagnosis of Tub - erculosis, made a strong plea for the abolition of the control of butter. 'During: the war, he said, 'I have noticed more cases of acute form of tu - berculosis than ever before. And the moral is this: If it is necessary to control our imports, the last thing that should be controlled is butter. At present the country is living on margarine, and yet I am told that in Ho'land there are hundreds of tons of butter which could be imported into this country. That is a very shortsighted policy on the part of the gov - ernment.' Dr. Sutherland said that during the last five years the death - rate from pulmonary tuberculosis had risen 12 per cent. The reason is to bt* found in a tre . entious change that has taken place in the dietary this nation for the past five years, and that was due to the lack of ar mal fats. The epidemic of influenza last winter was attributable to tl h same cause, because without animal fats the people kit ant to infection." Dr. E. V. McCollum has for more than a dozen years carried or &gt;ry investigations with rats at the Wisconsin Exjwriment Stetio John Hopkins University. He used these animals to demonstrai relative value of foods, the part they play in the human diet and tht binations required for growth, health and development. Through his of the various diets of people he has come to the following conclu "There can be no doubt but that the small stature and poor ph&gt; development of many people, especially the poorer classes in the Orient and in various tropical regions throughout the world, are the result of faulty' diet. I have shown very clearly by my investigations in nutrition during the last decade that it is impossible to make a satisfactory iliet from cereal products, legume seeds, peas and beans, tubers, edible roots, and lean meats of the kind composing the muscle tissues of animals We can make reasonably satisfactory diets by the use of foodstuffs just enum - erated, together with verv liberal amounts of the leafy portion of plants. but this type of diet does not prove entirely satisfactory for those specie* which have the camiverous type of digestive tract with its limited cap - acity, which prevents the consumption of a sufficient amount of bulky foods. Vegetarian diet is successful only in those types of animals which can consume quantities of leafy foods. It is because of the use of what we should term extraordinary liberal amounts of leafy foods together with a certain amount of eggs that the Chinese, Japanese, and most tropica peoples have succeeded in maintaining existence. "With experimental animals we have been able to make up successful diets only by the use of the seeds, tubers, roots, and meats, either singly or in combinations, supplemented either with fairly liberal amounts of milk or eggs, or with very liberal amount* of \vfy foods. Furthermore, </seg>
            <seg id="p069">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION ■ only those peoples who have made use of dairy products have attained high standards of physical development, together with low infant mortal - ity, and mental keenness and aggressiveness which has enabled them to succeed in science, literature, or invention, and only those people who have had dairy products as an abundant source of food have ever developed such political systems as offer opportunity for the individual of humble origin develop his natural talents. I have repeatedly stated in my public utterances during the last year that the promotion of the dairy industry is the greatest single thing we ran do as a public health measure, and the more I correlate the re - sults of animal experimentation with human experience, the more I am need that this is true. It is indeed up to the dairyman of the coun - ■ educate the general public as to the wonderful qualities of milk as One way to increase the consumption would be to increase our quality, cannot force the consumer to buy that which he does not want any t than you can force your horse to drink if he is not thirstyT So I jrsre quality for every kind of product. Better Marketing relieve, surrounding every city of considerable size, the fanners have an organization to sell their products co-operatively in order ley b-.' assured of getting full market price for them. I do not a the individual farmer is going to cope with other industries that farmed. He must work with his neighbor and subserve himself to ramzation that it may deal with other organization upon the right und not try to do the impossible which always reacts upon the f an association. A Near airo the Wisconsin College of Agriculture and all the dairy and farm organizations of the state, together with the Department of Markets, called a marketing conference and outlined a plan by which the dairy industry of Wisconsin should be organized in order to market dairy products cooperatively. The plan is this: Every local cooperative enter - prise will be federated with other local institutions. It may be local creameries, cheeseries, or storage houses for cheese, potatoes or local shipper:?' associations, etc. We have in Wisconsin 3,700 cheese factories, condensaries and cream - eries, so we have the local development well established in that state. We do not desire to relinquish it. Several creameries or cheeseries can be fed - erated for the purpose of standardizing their butter or cheese, to establish a brand, and to ship in carload lots. They will be able to sell these pro - ducts to better advantage than when shipped individually; and by group - ing their volume of business, become strong enough to employ someone to look after it. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 1921 ANNUAL REPORT When these cheeseries and creameries are federated into groups and operating these groups will be federated into state-wide organizations It is unnecessary for me to point out to you the power of such or ganizations because they can do everything other organizations can do for their members if they have the proper manager at the head of eact federation. And the farmer, by running his own local institution, whethe it be creamery or cheesery, is the master of his own business — ar the group federation or the state federation of groups groes to ever last ing smash-up, the farmer still has his market and is not particularly disturbed. The advantage of feaeration comes through the larger vo ume of business by having each lacal institution associated with other factories. Let me use an illustration to point out the advantages of feder and a central storage. Last May the price of cheese in Wi from twenty-seven to twelve rents a pound. So far as ar mine, there was less cheese in storage than in May, Ul!0, and the prospe tive supply was no greater than before; yet the price dropped in two w to twelve cents. That was a serious Hatter. Farmers received for tht milk from 90 certs to ;i dollar a hundred, am duce that milk that went into It seems to me the people liuying the dMM w. i- the market. They said. "Here's the season whin \V greater portion of he- &lt; h w will have t.&gt; sill, because they have no place to hold '.!■ consin had had trusr levera federations, and each for curing, grading and branding tr cheese until the market i-ondit would have been just a« much n Mr. Armour are masters of thei But are we not as farnu n n some of the good practices that their good practkes. We do not able. I would rather a good deal by looking at our conditions as t\ right economic principles, than to waste my time complaining of what the other fellow is doing. Let us go ahead and do likewise. Had tht cheese industry in Wisconsin done so, it could have held its cheese in \V consin through May, June and July, because July had not passed before it went to twenty cents a pound The advantages of federation and establishing storage is evident We produce most of our cheese in five summer months. It is not good business to put all that cheese on the market in those months. Why not </seg>
            <seg id="p071">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 71 \ w he market each month. This is orderly ketinsj Leadership t m* 4a not value leadership sufficiently. We j. Washington or a Lincoln or a Roosevelt Sherman; but are there not men needed in who correspond to our statesmen and generals, and aders be recognized as much as those men who excel ua upon the leader as having an easy job. All he does, draw his check and let others do the work. That isn't A manager is a man who has ability to direct others, to lay rrv the n out. He is a student of his business and he is whether in the office or on the golf field or on a railroad farmers appreciate that managerial ability is rare and demands •s and the supply ii limited — until the farmers understand this, ative institutions are going to suffer. The plan of organization atter so much as the man who has the organization to manage. :rate what constitutes a manager by two incidents that attention in the past two years. A cooperative enter - armers picked up a man who had been a failure in his 1 hired him for $75 a month tj manage their business This institution was doing a good business. When the price of hi-d 2? cents a pound in 1919, he bought a carload. By ved it was selling for eighteen tents, and before it lling for ten cents. The loss amounted to about aid, "They have it in for us." It was the stupidity Why not say, "If we had had a real manager, he would ase of a successful manager who makes money by ig factory. Whin he started in to knit socks and sto.k - rtk *:i.."&gt;&lt;&gt; a pound. In 1918 silk advanced to $11 a pound March. 1920 to $18 a pound. He would not pay $18 for silk and he formed he would be unable to buy silk any cheaper. He replied, "I am not going to pay $18 a pound for silk. I do not t to sell stockings for $6 a pair. They are not worth it." "The salesman said, "You can't get your silk later. You will have ake it now." To this he replies, "I can close my mill can't I?" Inside of six months he bought silk for seven dollars a pound. He </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 1921 ANNUAL REPORT saved his company thousands of dollars because he saw, in the study of economics, that this period of wild buying and blind leadership had to end. He is a manager. His factory is now working over time, because he has had no expensive product to work off and his price for stockings has been below the other fellow's. So when we sum up the opportunities to improve dairy conditions, to increase the returns for dairy products, we must not neglect the character of cow we keep. When the average cow is producing 130 pounds fat a year, and there are herds in Wisconsin averaging 400 pounds of fat there is large opportunity for improvement. The quality of dairy products must be uniform and good. This will cause increased consumption and create better prices. We must develop and encourage local cooperative enterprises — a local milk producers' as - sociation, local creameries and cheeseries and federate these institutions for selling their products cooperatively and so full market price for them can be secured. Leadership must be recognized as all important in the management of these institutions. If we will do these things, I am sure other things will be added unto us I thank you. i Applause, i THE PRESIDENT: The Nebraska Dairymen's Association is cred today ,and we feel the state of Nebraska is hon &gt;red today; so going to present to you our own Governor, Samuel McKelvie, who w troduce to you the speaker of the hour, i Applause, i ar HON. S. R. McKelvie: Mr. President and Friends: It is alway harassing to me to be called upon to introduce a speaker who is so much better known than I am myself. It seems that there is little that is new to be said about one who has occupied such a prominent place in the public eye for so long a time and so recently. Perhaps I can better introduce the speaker by saying ther of common interest between him and myself, in that he for four years served as the public goat of the State of Illinois, and I am finishing up my four years for Nebraska. And then, too, I have followed his leader - ship somewhat in that I have thought some of the things he did in Illin - ois were very good. They worked out well there and we put them into ef - feet in Nebraska, where we feel sure they will work out well, too. Bringing the matter more nearly home, I am reminded of a question asked me the other day by a newspaper man about what I would do when I got through with this office. I thought the first thing- I would do would be to pull off my shoes and turn myself out to grass where I could be my own boss for a while. We have here a living example of a Governor who has done that I think he has come to seek the company of "con - tented cows," and I dare say he has found a peace that was not his when he was seeking to serve the people of his State. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 73 I want to say to you the State of Nebraska feel* honored in the ex - treme we should have with us today former Governor Frank 0. Lowden, who now is a dairy farmer. Governor Lowden. I Applause.) Kl TIRE PROSPECTS FOR THE DAIRYMAN Mr. M.-Kelvie, Mr. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: I have listened the greatest possible pleasure to Mr. Glover's address. He covered the whole subject so thoroughly and so effectively that it is really difficult for me to know what to say on the subject of the dairy situation, and so I 1 shall have to content myself with some general observations on frieultural situation as it impresses myself upon my mind today. There is a great deal of misapprehension throughout the country, particularly in the large cities, as to the fabulous amount of money that has been made by the farmers of this country during the laat half century. Men from the cities visit southern California and are told that southern California is populated exclusively by retired farmers, and it is pretty nearly so, in a way. They go back home with the idea that every farmer of America has become independently rich. That is one of the reasons why it is difficult to make the people of the cities and the industrial sections of our country understand the existing conditions. It true that perhaps America has more retired farmers than any ther country in the world. This great aggregation of them in Southern California is indeed a fact. But it is also true that nearly every farmer in America who has made a sufficient competence to retire from the farm, has not made it by actual operations upon his farm, but by the increase in the value of lands. It is well to have that fact generally understood. The condition which made that possible in the past no longer exists. This rapid increase in farm values which has marked the last half century in the Mississippi valley will not continue. The retired fanner of the future must retire upon a competence which he has earned in the actual operation of his farm, or he will not retire at all. It follows from this that we must give more attention — and this applies to dairying and to all other kinds of farming 1 — to the details of farming than we have in the past. It means as I believe, also, that we must in a way today return a little bit to some of the practices which our fathers practiced, particularly in view of the greatly increased freight rates, which are not likely probably for a great many years to approach the level of freight rates which existed before the war. The old idea of our fathers and grandfathers who moved first from New England and New York and Pennsylvania to Ohio and Indiana and Illinois, and later to Iowa. Nebraska, Kansas and these other states, was that the farm was a place upon which to make a living, and the Ex-Governor Frank O. Lowden, of Illinois </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 1921 ANNUAL REPORT thing to dq was to produce upon the farm as much .1 duced which was necessary to sustain and clothe life. For that r all the pioneers sought in the first instance to follow this plan \vh possible, and were able to do so at least in those regions pari so that they had fuel of their own and were not dependent or in other words, until they CfMMi the Missouri River. They prod some sheep so that they were not dependent upon the cit and they had their own smoked hams, and produced a r quality of meat in those pioneer days than any of the packer know how to make today. And upon a little stream Wl I do not mean we must return to all th th I mean to say today that where you have agricultt certain extent you find the community more properous. T ha even in your great dairy state. Those dairy farmers who raise a ft pigs and have just a litt alfalf h neighbors, and just a little surplus of something are the ones gett along the best We have gone in the ret where everything was produt from the old meth &gt;n the farn o the othe rugged and simpler thar trying to produce just one thing Illinois, and in Iowa and parts In th 4 Nebraska and of Ka In some other sections it is shet P ;i your attention to that in passir me w regain an independence which our forefathers hac which we have lost by limiting our we will restore our independence by raising lot that in a measure, at least, we are indep fluctuations of this somewhat trouble m m Another thing which should rei v tion today is the Farm Bureau. I know meeting. That is being held somewhere else. But wher brother Glover to exhaust entirely the dair me to discuss whatever occurs to me. ( Laughu Farm Bureau, in my opinion, is the most useful fa .th t gi tion the farmers have ever atempted in this country. (Apj We have had for many years the best agricultural co the world; in fact, America, young as it is, is the mother of agricultur learning. The Old World has imitated us in that respect. And ye while we have the best agricultural colleges in all the world, as a ru we have made the least use of what they teach. ( Applause. ) I know I am on dangerous ground. I made a speech a number of years ■C before a national farm organization in which I made a statement im thing like this: "In manufacturing we do not have to apologize tc :inv </seg>
            <seg id="p075">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 75 at i&lt;in in the world; in banking and commerce we can hold our &gt; proudly erect in the midst of the best commercial and industrial iany in all the world; but when it comes to farming, there is not the world that is so poor and forlorn." ;iti When I had finished that statement, a lady arose and objected. She from California. A good many of you have been in California, and w if there is anything in all the world a Californian does not ■ be told that there is anything anywhere on earth, from aisins. that surpasses California. (Laughter.) So she arose matt bjected. She said I might speak for Illinois, but she denied me ight to speak for California. ( Applause, i I am expecting in my the right sion of this part of the subject, that somebody will say I may for Illinois, but I cannot for Nebraska. Yet the fact remains that the abundance of fertile land which we have had in this the past, but which is well-nigh exhausted, we have done farming of all the nations of the world, as a general propo - ir as I have visited other countries. hina. There is a great book written by one of your Wisconsin ■ss(ir King — called "Forty Centuries of Farming." When I Pi I formed a new regard for those people, because they ter over there now than we are in Illinois — of course' than you are in Nebraska! (Laughter.) st colleges of agriculture in the world and we have f them. That is why I say the Farm Bureau is the tion that has even been formed among farmers, se that Bureau will take the learning from these nto the country and lay it upon the fields — apply it. Farm Bureau in every county of every agricultural itry, and I want to see that Farm Bureau keep its f people in this world who can keep their heads they are in modest positions, who when they get a little rity are likely to lose their heads. the Farm Bureau inquire what the other organiza- hat county are. I want them to learn if there are. farmers' find out if there are co-operative creameries or cheese ;i factories or co-operative livestock selling organizations, or testing asso - ciations, or granges, or farm organizations of any kind; and then just the moment the head of the Farm Bureau learns what other organized activities are in that county, I want him to keep his feet on the earth and co-operate with them and help them and not antagonize them. (Applause.) The danger today with the multiplying organizations of farmers, founded in the main upon correct principles — in fact, t agree with every </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 1921 ANNUAL REPORT word Mr. Glover has said to you — is that many of them are coming into collision with one another and are letting little jealousies spring up. There develop conflicts, and that is a crime against the farmers of America. I want to see the Farm Bureau set an example to these organi - zations. I want to see it get hold of any men who at any time have been interested in these movements, gather them together and see that they work together and that there is no friction among them. They are not doing that in all instances. Some examples have come to my mind in which they have overlooked that. I believe the Farm Bureau, if it will keep its head and stand upon correct economical prin - ciples, is destined to transform the agriculture of America as no other agency has that has been found in all the history of agriculture in this country. I want to say that wherever I have been consulted in my own or any other state and have found there are efforts to begin co-operation along these lines which Mr. Glover laid down to you a few moments ago. I have always advised them first to get in touch with the Farm Bureau of their county, co-operate with it, and let it be the clearing house of all other farmers' activities so as to avoid these pitfialls of which I spoke a moment ago. No one believes more in the principle of co-operation as applied to farming than I. I have been preaching it for many years. But when any of us get together and say, "If we just organize on© great society, we can put the price of any farm product to any figure we please." we are making a mistake. The most powerful farm organization is still under the control of the operation of economic laws. Notwithstanding all the mistakes we have made, the best hope — I was almost going t&gt;&gt; say the only hope — for agriculture for the future in this country, to my mind, consists in the development of this co-operative movement. I visited Holland a good many years before the great war. I was interested in farming then. I had been farming a number of years and was just changing to dairying; so I visited a great many of their farms and the Agricultural College over there. The President of this College and I had a great dialogue, because he spoke Egnlish about as well as t spoke Dutch. (Laughter.) But I learned a lot from him and I hope he arned something from me. I visited their creameries and their cheese factories, and 1 found everything they did over there was done through co-operative societies. I never saw — I would not say anything in deprecation of Wisconsin, the leading dairy state of the Union, because I take my hat off when Wisconsin's name is mentioned — but I never saw in any state as fin« cheese factories and creameries and dairy barns as I saw in Holland. I never saw such an evidence of prosperity as seemed to me to exist in Holland at that time. Their cheese factories were all run co-oper - atively. They purchased their supplies co-operatively, and not only </seg>
            <seg id="p077">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 77 that, but they have solved the problem of foreign markets through their co-operative societies- In Leeuwarden, the capital of Friesland, which is the heart of the Holstein industry of the world, they have a great warehouse operated by a co-operative export society. They sold a large part of their dairy exports to London and a large part to Berlin. They told me one interesting thing. There was a great consumption • ■f Stilson cheese in England. In Holland they made largely Edam cheese. So they sent an expert to England from their export society to learn how to make Stilson cheese. They made it so much better than the English make their own cheese, they were practically con - trolling the English market in cheese! They were not content simply to have an export society of their wn, but they were in correspondence with co-operative buying societies in these great European capitals. They encouraged the organization of them so that these products could go direct from the producer on the farm to the home of the consumer in the largest capitals of Europe, i&lt; as to make the minimum of cost to the consumer and the maximum f price to the producer. Those things are all practicable. &gt;\ lot of people think this co-operative movement only means better s. That is only part of the story. If that were all, it probably would not be worth my while to be here. But it means better farming. They told me over there that the moment they organized one of these co-operative cheese factories, every farmer began to compare what he was lining- with what the other fellow was doing; that the best farmer was setting the standard and the others worked up to him. A lot of en supposed they were getting the best results because they were ing as their fathers or grandfathers had done; but when they had to npare what they were doing with what the other farmers were ng, they found they had not nearly approximated what they should Jgh all these year We might just as well be honest with ourselves here. We each think we are about the best farmer in our community. We say, "Why make this change ? This is the way my father did it. and the way I have always done it." The only thing that will break through our crust df self-sufficiency and self-satisfaction is to get into this co-operative movement where we must bare our operations and compare them with the operations of our neighbor. It not only means better farming but better living. Let the spirit of co-operation get into a community any - where so that the farmers and their wives and children are meeting around a common table upon some subject of common interest, and you wiU find more trees are planted in the front yard and the lawns are kept better. The first thing you know there is a new school house, and the old church is repainted. The country community begins to look up the moment its people begin to co-operate. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 1921 ANNUAL REPORT There is not any reason in all the world why life should not be mor beautiful in the country, anyway, than it can be under the most favorablt circumstances in the city. I spent a number of days in Chicago recent because of the demands of some business I had. Yesterday it was hf|j chilly. I come out here and look into the glory of a winter sk want to tell you there is just as much beauty in the country in \v if we are only attuned to it, as there is in the most bea Jtiful &lt;l; June or October. This co-operative spirit is going to make us appreciate the advar tages those of us who live in the country enjoy, because it w better community everywheit I am discussing this at great length because I know jnie of co-operative movements fail, or are failing. That is true. I do r want you to become discouraged when you hear of these th ng there is not as large a proportion of them failing as of ordi iai privately conducted. We are winning in a larger percentagt r than private business is. But now is the time to inquire v failing, where we are failing. In the first pla been told by Mr. Glover, there art ertain men who sun worked out the proposition, that if we would all agree on i which to produce a certain mnmm y, w high as the stars, and get If we have that idea, we are g&lt; i: of demand. That is a fait we mu we won't get better prices than we h ■ I admit the efficacy of the la f through a series of years it fix th But when I see wheat selling on W &gt;dnt pose of illustration — I am not quoting any actual market — f cents less than it was on Friday of the week hef&lt; faith in the operation of the law of supply and demar certain that law is not working or ne of th and applause.) Now that is what the co-operative marketing It can stabilize in a measure that price. It can mark ;m way. and when wheat suddenly drops fifteen cents, the gentlemen wh are holding that wheat can say, "We will wait until the law of suppK and demand has had a chance to reassert itself." While I am on this subject of the law of suppy and demand. I am going to discuss it a little bit. All writers on economic subjects whose articles or books I have read say that law operates only when there is full freedom on both sides. There is not full freedom under modern conditions a large part of the time among the producers. They </seg>
            <seg id="p079">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 79 aie relatively few in number, while the consumers are legion. There must be equality of conditions on both sides — on the side of the buyer alike — before we can get the full effect of this law of supply and. We can only have that equality of condition on both sides ' farmers get together and organize, and when they have just ;u i.an at the head of their organization as have the gentlemen They must be trained to know what the world's supply is and needs are. They must have brains to know the trend »&lt;li currents just as much as the gentlemen on the other side, I you have that equality of conditions where you get a just price. most hopeful, the most significant, development of these terprises during recent years is the very one described by Wisconsin. They have the right idea — namely, beginning N ni'iiiunity. This thing of all in a minute getting up i that is going to cover all the earth and function, [iifficult things in all the world. Did you ever stop ga ■» i i eat businesses were big in the beginning? Nearly i . volution — a growth from something small. In that and quality and those things necessary to make why I am stressing the Farni Bureau, so that where you local organizations, they can get into groups, and the groups the county into the state, and the states into one UK along the liner of correct economic principles. ny farmer's elevator or any society organized &gt;e in this State, even if the times seem hard and r.istake which they made in Wisconsin and have H of one of them. Let the manager go, but hold ■ome one else in; because it is out of these local ving in the rural communities that this movement live movement — is to get material to bring it its forbear to discuss just a little bit some things about dairy- ing, although I almost promised you I would not because almost any - thing anybody could say would be a repetition of what Mr. Glover has already told you. But there is one fact that came to my attention the other day I want to remind you of. The President of the Federal Reserve Bank of the district which includes North Dakota, Minnesota, Wisconsin and Michigan, made a statement in which he pointed out that pratically all the bank failures in that district had been in that part of the district where they depended upon one crop; that the only portions of this dis - trict covering those four states where the communities were really pros - perous were the dairy communities. Wisconsin was singled out. He said. "We used the surplus in Wisconsin in times of stress to help out </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 1921 ANNUAL REPORT St. Paul and Chicago. Wisconsin alone was able to finance itself during that strain, and to have a surplus to help out these cities." According to the President of the Federal Reserve Bank of that district, that was because of the dairying done in Wisconsin. I have been trying to tell the people of my State for a good many years that while I had the greatest respect for Wisconsin, I could not see wherein it had any natural advantages over our advantages for dairying; and I was bold enough to say I thought in some respects we had advantages over theirs; that I did not know of any reason why Wisconsin should so far surpass the adjoining states except for the fact that grand old man. Governor William D. Hoard, settled at Fort Atkinson, and not in Illinois or Nebraska (Applause.) Now, Nebraska, famed as it is for its production of beef, for its production of corn — I am wondering if Nebraska has not made the mis - take Illinois has made in not giving more attention to dairying during recent years? I wonder if you would not be in better condition on these beautiful prairies — and there is no more beautiful state anywhere than yours with the sweep of prairie where you see almost infinitely away — if there were more silos and dairy cattle and dairy farms dotting: their boundless expanse ? Then we live in this country, anyway, just as if th going to come to an end when we are dead. We never think of the future. We do not have the vision which they have had in the Old World. We have denuded our forests of timber without taking the trouble to reforest. In little Switzerland they have a forest which ha; produced an annual crop of pines since the eleventh century. Each yeai they have cut off a certain amount, and by the time they have K&lt;&gt;ni over the entire area covered by the forest, the first strip has com mercial timber upon it. In the treatment of our farm lands we have been just as prodigal as with our timber land. We go on the theory when we are dead the world is going to stop, and we need not pay any attention to tomorrow. That is wrong. We talk of abandoned farms. The idea of a new nation like ours confessing it has abandoned farms. I visited at one time fields in Europe which produced wheat which fed Caesar's legions, and they were producing better wheat on that land than any I saw in America. But these abandoned farms will continue unless we change our method of agriculture. I know of no way by which you can have permanent agriculture. by which you can maintain forever the fertility of the soil, except by the employment of live stock. Even out in Nebraska, which is so new a state that many of us can remember when it was almost a virgin prairie covered with wild flowers. I have no doubt that when you take </seg>
            <seg id="p081">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 81 down an old fence somewhere and plow the land up, you find you are getting a better crop along that old fence row than on either side of it. That is true through Iowa and Illinois, which shows our lands, even in the newer sections, have not that wealth of fertility which they once had. There is only one way of restoring it, and that is by combining the raising of live stock with farming everywhere. So I am making a plea for the dairy cow in Nebraska. When you produce milk, you have the satisfaction of knowing yon are engaged in producing the only food known to science which alone and in itself is complete for the sustenance of human life. There i* no doubt in the world but the health of the children of our great cities would be vastly improved if we could only make a campaign of education such as Mr. Glover described, which would result in their purchasing double the quantity of milk they do now. We like to feel in whatever occupation we may be engaged that we are really being of service to the world. That is the best compensation we get, after all. And in what way in all the world can you be of greater service than by furnishing this one absolutely essential article of human food to the babies of the ar It has been a hard year we have gone through. There is no need disguise that. I have been going up and down this land telling the business men, for more than a year, wherever I have met them, they must recognize the fact that before you can get back in any industry or section upon the pre-war basis of prices, you must restore the price of farm commodities to its natural relationship with the price of other commodities. You cannot have farm commodities selling below the pre - war level, as they do in some instances, and everything else from 40 to 100 per cent above that pre-war level; because this same old law of supply and demand fixes not only the price of any commodity, but the relative price of one set of commodities and the other set of commodities, he end It has been a hard year, but the most inspiring thing about it all is the way we farmers ourselves have taken it. We have not been happy. We have not been amiable at all when we found we were the only peop'e in all this country that took seriously this idea of readjusting things It the pre-war basis; but as I say to my city friends, while I think myself the farmers have not been in quite as amiable a frame of mind as they used to be, they have not struck on their job or per - mitted their fields to lie fallow, although the crops they have just har - vested they still hold at a loss. They have gone on. Just as it was the farmers of America during the great war who, responding to the appeal made to them not only to feed our own people, but our armies in the field and the) civilian population of our allies — just as they re- </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 1921 ANNUAL REPORT sponded then, so they are responding now to this demand for read justment. They have readjusted. They are waiting for other industries to follow their example. And so I want to congratulate the farmers everywhere that their part in the readjustment following the great war has been as honorable and creditable to them as was their part in the winning of that war; because it was the farmers of America, equally with the soldiers upon the fields, who helped to win that great victory. I thank you. (Applaust "WHAT THE MI1.K I'KOIll ( EKS' ASSOCIATION IS IX)IN(. Mr. President. Ladiet and Gentlemen: It nhm Permit me to say that what that A be best described by using Shermar as a co-operative association, of course. A because we thought it was the proper thing products of the dairy farmers around about Omaha in I&gt;ou Sarpy counties. "A new broom sweeps clean." E\ thusiastic at first, but things develop which they ha dissatisfaction creeps in. The speaker before dinner dwelt very extensiv along that line. He expressed my sentiments to a "T". But there are certain conditions which it seems as if it is impossible to MRMM iti these organizations. The reason is hard to tell. The main point is loya'ty to the Association by its members. On the other hand, we found unfair competition. That is what we are up against down there. I had always thought business men would treat one another in a business-like way. and not resort to tricks and treachery; but since this Association has been in existence and they have injured us to the extent of as high as $18,000 a month, I have changed my mind. Mr. 1'har'ifs (irau. lSt'nningiun. Nebraska addresses that have been delivered here, it would be a K'"&lt; call a hait on this program. When you put up such men a the platform recently, it appears to me to be absolute f fanner to try to tell you what the Co-operative As«iu iat In the first place. I am placed in an embarrassing pi asked to ti.l Mr. Switzer's shoes and to cover a subjec studied more thoroughly than myself. I am in an embarrassing position in other ways. tell the present condition of the Milk Product' the future will be. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION ■ n instance and use the words of the manager of arted six months ago. He told us what his com- m from getting trade. When he and a sales - r in Omaha, his competitor would follow them want to patronize this new concern ? They nly be a short time until they will have I not sanitary, and they are up in the iggers." A'hat disreputable methods some people will re»ort their fellow men. He was at a loss to know what n the employ of the older company. He, together who followed him, decided to go into a business get even with that kind of competition, he lust tight the devil with fire." He secured a couple of rominent men in Omaha and handed them to the clergy •\ pulpits and requested these men to read them from their xt Sunday morning; and they did. It was only a few days ipetitor said, "If you will quit, we will call a halt. We ne of the conditions the Midwest Milk Producers has run wo years. I could go into the history of this, but it is abso- ry. It is simply unfair competition. \ has been pointed out here today that farmers' co-oper - are the proper means of marketing farm and dairy mmm to me — and I have good reason for the belief — there nterests antagonistic to farmers' co-operative associations. have to admit that is true to a large extent. v ident the Midwest wont up against. One big restau- omer of ours. He took about one hundred dollars' The manager of the Midwest was on his vacation and had to take his place. About seven o'clock one evening the nager called up and said, "I have a telephone call from ar hman at the plant that this restaurant man has sent word ght w ot want any milk the next morning." He did not give any The supposition was he has received lower priced goods. The reas rt day I learned he had the impression that our Association was going be a baby starver — that its main object was to control the price of xt da milk in that territory. They used that as a club, and yet nothing could have been farther from the truth. Did anybody ever hear of a business man treating another business firm in that manner? And that is only one of the things. On the other hand, we have run up against this: Our Association was only a short time in existence until our competitors commenced </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 1921 ANNUAL REPORT raising the price in the country. The farmers had been getting a low price up to that time. The idea of our Association was to sell this product and prorate everything- back to the producers, less a certain per cent to be put into a sinking fund, and the auditor deducted $700 to create a sinking fund. Some how it does not take the producer long until he bites on that bait of higher prices offered by a competitor. That is one thing you must contend with. Then, too, they are continually underselling you in the city. You can see it is a hard row of stumps to hoe in a big city. My experience the past two years has led me to believe it is about the meanest business a person can get in to. Another Association called the "Cow Exchange" started in the State. The idea of better cows is all right, but the idea of producing more milk without trying to get a greater outlet for the product, it seems to me is the wrong road. I think it would be better to put on a campaign to use more milk, and the farmers would soon a eration the movement has ever had in the State if the farn and Sarpy counties won't save this institution, but let i institutior receiver's sale." Somebody is going to buy the near future. I thank you. (Applause.) REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON KKSO1A TIONS (No report was given.) THE PRESIDENT: I think we have been able to bring to this Association the very best talent that can be found in the United States on the topics presented to you by these men from out of the State. I admit this meeting has been one round of pleasure; but now I have come to the mast pleasurable thing I have had the opportunity of doing, and that is to present to you your new President. Mr. Furry. (Applause.) their end of the business. Governor Lowden has spoken of the law of supply and ( demar although he questions whether it is functioning at all times. : So it not a question of producing. The first thing is Is have a bettei for your milk. (Applause.) I would like to go into other matters, hut I feel it would l&gt;&lt; justice to the Association to do so right now. The Midwest ■ an i is w h you might call "upon the rocks." Why? Because the stockholde not been loyal to their own Association, but have bitten on I the other fellow has held out. One business firm in Omaha said: "It is the greatest slap M </seg>
            <seg id="p085">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 85 PRESIDENT-ELECT FURRY: This is rather a surprise to me. I do not believe I have anything to say this afternoon, as the hour is Retting late. I thank you. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: We will hear from Mr. Furry next year. He will be carrying the burdens, and I am sure he will be equal to the asion. Give him your support. Upon motion, the convention then adjourned. BANQUET Thursday Evening, January 5, 1922. The Thirty-seventh Annual Banquet of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association was held at the Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, Nebraska, with Mr. H. Frandsen, of Lincoln, acting as Toastmaster. TOASTMASTER FRANDSEN: Mr. President, Ladies and Gentle - : The President told me a little while ago that this Association just closed the most interesting and most successful session it has held. He said we had discussed at the rgular meeting everything mportance covering technical dairying and everything that ought to iaid to the Association had really been said. Then he added, ''Won't please act as Toastmaster tonight?" (Laughter.) %■ I said, practically everything one might wish to hear about lu-al dairy work has already been said, and emphasized. We heard deal this afternoon about the importance of dairying. Every a while we hear people talk about the tremendous amount of nroducts we have on hand, and the danger of a surplus that can - taken care of. us see what we have in dairy products. In looking up a few i along this line, I notice that from the last census report we are credited in the United States with having produced last year about "&gt;'.' billion pounds of milk. Most of us are hardly qualified to readily distinguish between billions and millions, and it may be well to put it in dinV-rent form. Should we construct a canal and run the 89 billion pounds of milk in, it would fill such a canal ten feet wide and ten feet deep and 2,639 miles long. That is some "Milky Way". In fact, this milk canal would reach practically across the continent. However, if you do not like the canal way. let us load it on freight cars. Supposing we put twenty tons in a car, that amount of milk wou'd fill a train 16.000 miles long, or about as long as five times the distance from New York to San Francisco and back to Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 86 While we are figuring, let us suppose we wanted to build a fence around Nebraska. As I calculated, there is enough milk produced in this state — 200 million gallons — to make a canal five feet wide and five feet deep from the north to the south line of the State. If we put it in cans and set the cans side by side, there is enough milk to make a fence five times around the state, or to build a wall eleven feet high entirely around Nebraska. But for fear some may conclude that there must be a big surplus. let me remind you that in spite of the fact that this amount of milk is being produced in the country, you can go into a number of cities where there are still thousands of children not getting milk to drink. I came back recently from a visit to a state not far to the south of us. where 43,000 children of school age were not getting milk in their diet. So despite the fact there are some adults daily learning of the merits of dairy products, our consumption of milk and cheese is below that of other countries, and I believe far below what it will be in this country when we have educated our people to the real merits of dairy products. So in spite of this milky wave and the apparent abundance of milk. there really is not now enough to take care of the demands that we should have for dairy products. I saw a little story the other day on this milk propositior said to Johnnie, "Johnnie, the stork has brought you a little s "Aw, go on," said Johnnie, "it was the milk man who br her. Doesn't it say on the wagons: 'Families supplied da (Laughter.) I suspect Mr. Roberts would say, "Our wagon passe? door." I hope that before long some milk man will stop at every lg The speaker I am about to call on is doing a lot of institut She likes her work and attempts to answer all questions put to Y she has a lot of such questions from hef boys and girls. Rec am told some schoolboy asked her, "Why does a red cow give whi when she eats green grass?" Our speaker quickly replied: "1 same reason that a blackberry is red when it is green She is so proficient in answering questions about milk that I hopt you will ask her a goodly number of them. As a starter I am going t&lt; ask her, "Why the Milk Diet?" I take peculiar pleasure in introducing to you Miss Florence J. Atwood, University of Nebraska Extension Food Specialist. (Applause. I </seg>
            <seg id="p087">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 87 "WHY THE MILK DIET?" Miss Florence J. Atwood, Lincoln Mr. Toast master and Friends: When Professor Frandsen asked me give this talk this evening, the only reason I could think of for hi* request was because if you looked at me. I would be a good advertise ment for milk. To make sure he wasn't giving me anything new to talk about, I trht I would hunt through the Bible to see if I could find any quota- milk. I found Judges 4:19: And he said unto her, Give me, I pray thee, a little water to drink; am thirsty. And she opened a bottle of milk, and gave him drink. e&lt;l him That was not the only one I found. There are many of them there. So from that I drew my conclusion that milk in the diet is as old Time itself. In discussing this subject, it seems to me it would be better for us iquire why we eat. I think you will agree with me our reason for g is the same as that of the animals. In the first rlace,~ we eat id tissues and muscles, and we depend on certain foods to do this ng, such as proteins, vitamines, and minerals. In the second place, we eat to replace the waste of our bodies that ■ in nually being torn down, and the foods we depend on to do this exactly the same ones that build up our bodies. In the third place, we eat to produce heat and energy— that is, the food taken into our bodies is chemically burned. The energy that is )rcduted is used to give us power for work or play, as our activities f life may be. Then fourth, we eat to maintain health; and the foods that give us function are again the vitamines. h If you will turn to the composition of milk, I think you will agree with me that aside from water, we find exactly the same kinds of food I mentioned as necessary for our activities of life. We find it contains protein, fat, carbohydrates, and the vitamines and minerals. So that is one reason for this question: "Why a milk diet?" It is because it is so nearly a perfect food. Dr. McCollum. of Johns Hopkins University, felt that milk should be given a particular prominence among food stuffs because of its unique value as a protective food. He feels milk is one of the biggest factors in nutrition work, and that many things we have accomplished we could </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 1921 ANNUAL REPORT not have accomplished without milk. You people who live in Lincoln will recall the work done in our schools along that line; that at the time they started the weighing and measuring tests, so many children were found underweight. Dr. Wolfe decided the undersized ones should be supplied with a bottle of milk in mid-morning and afternoon. The agi - tation among school children was so great, they began using more milk in their diet at home, and the results were marvelous. We found the same condition in the rural schools where we have been doing some health work and encouraging the use of milk. Where it is available, the children make marvelous improvement with more milk in the diet. So we draw the conclusion our food must not merely satisfy the appetite. It should maintain health for us. Milk is one of the things than can do this because of these protective substances we are finding out more and more about every day. Many of our foods are lacking in these substances that keep us well and produce growth, but we do have two common foods that contain them in abundance— milk and green vege - tables. The protective substance of milk is better suited for the develop - ment of mankind than that of the green vegetables, because it is easier to consume the milk in the amount needed. So that we would get enough of growth-promoting propertie another positive answer to our question: "Why the milk diet?" Again referring to Dr. McCollum, who believes the achievements of any nation in literature or art or science depend upon its consumption of milk, he says it depends more upon milk than any other one factor of their lives. Take the Chinese or Japanese or people in the tropics. and they depend mostly upon vegetables for their growth-promoting properties. You will find some of the characteristics of these people are they are small in stature, have rather a short span of life, high infant mortality, and usually follow the same occupations as their forefathers. You will find a Japanese baby takes from two to three years longer t. develop than our American child where it is given milk, and a Japanese farmer of sixty years of age usually corresponds to an American farmer of eighty. So I believe we have another answer to our question: "Why the milk diet?" Diseases such as beriberi or pellagra or scurvy or rickets are caused by faulty diets. They can be readily cured by the use of milk. Much tuberculosis is quite closely related to faulty diet, and in districts where there is high mortality from tuberculosis, usually we find that there has been a small consumption of milk. In institutions where they are s&lt;&gt; successfully treating this disease, milk is one of the most important factors of the diet. So we have another reason for our question: "Why the milk diet?" In the last few years we have talked a great deal about substitu- </seg>
            <seg id="p089">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 89 tion, and I think we have learned we can make some substitutes for meat, and milk is a good substitute for this. I like to think of it as being more than just a substitute for our meat. I think we should think of it as being improvement, for several reasons. In the first place, it will reduce our food bill. Second, it will mean better health for us. Third, it means greater capacity for work, and fourth, an increased joy in life. So that also has added something to our answer: "Why a milk diet?" I am wondering if I will be criticised by the meat producers when I say a reduction in the use of meat and an increase in the use of milk are desired. I think we might say it would be desired in the interest of health and also in the conservation of our national food supply. To be sure, meat is an excellent food when used in moderation, but too often it is used excessively. I know I have been criticised for not suggesting more meat in the diet, but I think we should encourage the use of milk more than meat. Meat is more liable to putrefaction in the intestines than any other kind of protein foods. We have an example of this in a cat's diet. The cat will thrive on a meat diet, but with the kitten, a meat diet results in convulsions. If it is not good for a kitten, it should not be for the growing child. Milk feeding will do away with this putrefaction I speak of be - cause it is more easily digested. Then why not include more milk in the diet Another reason for withdrawing meat is because it satisfies the body in such a way that we do not seem to have a desire for the milder protein foods. Too often it will replace the milk that is necessary. Another thing, meat is poor as an ash constituent. It is entirely lacking in plasma that is one of the things we find in abundance in milk which is needed in growth. The high seasonings of the meat we should not neglect, because they are very stimulating, and I believe in health our organisms should not be whipped with a whip which is the way these stimulants act. So we have several reasons as to "Why the milk diet?" Possibly I should mention the fact that meat does have some advan - tages. It teaches the art of mastication which I think every one should be taught, and it is a good source of iron. But we can get those things from other sources without the meat. The housewife can, with plenty of milk and cream, furnish to her family the most nutritious foods available. I think that is one thing we should encourage — the use of more milk in cooking. We know farmers like to feed milk to their pigs and chickens, and just in like manner, it is just as healthy for children as for pigs </seg>
            <seg id="p090">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 90 and chickens. So we have another answer to our question, "Why the Now as to my point of food conservation: I think the dairy cow can help us to utilize economically our food resources. She can take products that we can in no way handle at all, and bring to us a food that is very nutritious — one of the best foods we can mention. So again we have another answer to our question, "Why the milk diet?" However, in emphasizing the use of milk in diet, I do not want to be misinterpreted, because in one way milk can be considered as an ex - pensive food. If you want to think of milk as being used as a fuel food, it would be expensive. If a man depended entirely upon milk as a fuel food, he would have to consume seven to eight quarts daily. Milk has its advantages in being 1 a real food, first, in its ability to repair our waste tissues; in the second place, in supplying- minerals for growth; third, to keep the body machinery in good working order; fourth, to keep it running smoothly. I found a little message in a Toast on Milk that is not original I would like to read it to you and leave that with you as my messag for this evening: "Drink milk; drink more milk. Pure, fresh, rich milk is a food fit for the gods. Babies cannot live without milk, and growing children grow faster for it. It gives vitality to youth, power to middle age, and to old age it brings a goodly portion of the health ami strength of former years. It should be used more largely by people of all ages, classes, and conditions. It excels coffee, and with it it is not to De compared. We may drink it at meals and between meals. It is one of Nature's best gifts to man. Come, let us drink another glass of milk". (Ap - plause.) THE TOASTMASTER: Miss Atwood feared some might criticise her for urging the more extensive use of milk in the diet. I think I can assure her that not only will the dairymen present not criticise her. but they will admit everything she said is perfectly true and should be advocated. I am thinking of a man who for a number of years held positions as dairy instructor in different institutions of this country. He resigned to become an editor. Later on he went into politics and was successful. Eventually he died, and it is alleged that further reports from him were to the effect that he had gone to the place where none o* his friends had hoped he had gone, but it was said that the change was so gradual that he never noticed it. Let me call your attention to the striking similarity between that story and the life history of the next speaker. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 91 Laughter. ) I happened to know he has held worthy positions on the dairy faculties of at least two or three of the state institutions of this country, ft that work to become an editor. I also happen to know that ar en in politics, for he has been a school director for a number in his home town, and I am sure most of you know that he continue to be a school director unless he were something of a c-ian. Recently he has been spending considerable time in Madison, apital of his home state, trying to get certain concessions from the epislature. Nobody but a politician would attempt that! But I am going » ask him to tell it. Ladies and gentlemen, I take much pleasure in having the privilege of introducing to you Mr. A. J. Glover, editor of Hoard's Dairyman. (Applause.) "FILLED MILK AND OTHER THINGS- MR. A. J. GLOVER, Editor of "Hoard's Dairyman": Mr. Toastmaster, Ladies and Gentlemen: I feel a good deal like Pat did. He was crossing a pasture with a cradle on his back, going to the field to cradle grain, when a bull saw him and took after him. Pat started for the fence and he ran as fast as he could. As he reached the fence, the bull helped him over. Pat began to dust his clothes and pick up his hat, and then he looked at the bull, which was on the other side of the fence pawing; and Pat said: "To h--l wid yer bowing and schrapin' and many apolo - gies. D-n yer sowl, ye did it on purpose." (Laughter.) So, my friends, in that elaborate introduction which spoke of my being in several institutions — I am not so sure that was a compliment, if a man moves from one place to another. It only reminds one he is getting when a speaker goes back over the history of your life. But I am to talk to you for a few minutes on a dry subject — "Filled Milk." Here again I find myself in much the position of Bill Jones, live in Saginaw county, three miles from a little grocery \vh store that in early days handled liquor. Bill was thirsty one afternoon and thought he would go to town, although the mud was deep and the roads bad. He got the liquor and imbibed too much. When he started home, it was a dark night and thundering. Bill was having a hard time to find the way. Now and then there would be flash of lightning. The thunder roared and rather exercised Bill, and he finally got down on his knees. Listen to his prayer: "Oh, Lord, if it's all the same to you, I wish you would give me more light, and less noise." (Laughter.) So as I look at this body, I wish for a little more light and less subject. I am glad to be here tonight and discuss this subject, because I presume many of you wonder what "filled milk" is. It is composed of </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 1921 ANNUAL REPORT evaporated skim milk and cocoanut oil. It contains the same percentage of cocoanut oil that evaporated milk contains of butter fat Let us put it in another way. Filled milk is a product made from skim milk, after the butter fat has been removed and cocoanut oil has been put in its place. This product is sold under various trade names, such as "Hebe, "Nutrio," and so on. There are a doien brands at the present time. It is a product that sells as milk on the market, notwithstanding the fact it is labeled plainly it is composed of evaporated skim milk and cocoanut oil. When it sells as milk it is a counterfeit. Laws have been passed in several states requiring: it to be labeled and sold as "filled milk," or "milk compound." or as "cocoanut milk," or "cocoanut com - pound." In Wisconsin we passed a law the last session of the legislature which prohibits its manufacture and sale, and that law is now being tested in the Supreme Court to determine whether it is constitutional. It may seem to you rather drastic to ask for legislation to prohibit the sale of what is considered a wholesome — and it is wholesome — and nutritious product. Skim milk is wholesome. It is nutritious. Cocoa - rut oil is wholesome and nutritious. These ingredients are combined into a product and sold on the market under its trado name. Then you •ay, "Why hasn't it a right to be sold?" I think this is the first food product I have ever objected to having sold on the market. One man said to me: "You obj ■f filled milk, but not to the selling of oleomargarin I said, "Those two products are different. I want sold for what it is and served to the consumer for what it is sold or consumed as butter, it is a counterfeit." ga .V It was through the struggle of the dairymen in pasi oleomargarine was made to stand upon it own feet and nt in its character. That has been the fight upon the part of dairymer against the manufacture of oleomargarine. Now, when it comes to filled milk, what is the difference? Just this: Miss Atwood told you in substance the difference. Milk is our fundamental food. It has been the fundamental food of all civilized nations, clear back in the times of the Bible, as she quoted you some Scripture to prove. The Jewish people, from the time Moses led the people out of the wilderness and towards the Promised Land, were con - sumers of milk; and Dr. McCullom has said the nations of earth that have produced the inventors and educators and law-makers, and the greatest civilizations of earth, have been the people who consumed milk. He has demonstrated by experiments that animals do not grow properly — that boys and girls do not grow properly — without milk, or the sub - stances found in milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 93 While you can get these substances in green vegetables and in liver fat and kidney fat and cod liver oil, but who is going to send the boys and girls to get these substances in order to have a complete ration ? Now milk being that fundamental food, there are many of us who have taken the position that no one has a right to manufacture • product which so resembles the genuine product the consumer cannot tell the fraudulent or substitute from the genuine. The Supreme Court of the United States in testing a case brought before it, said in substance that the Constitution of the United States does not extend the privilege to any citizen to manufacture and sell a product which so resembles the genuine it is difficult to tell one from the other. The State of Ohio has a skimmed milk law which does not permit the selling of condensed or evaported skim milk. In this product, "Heb«," being sold in Ohio, a case was instituted to see if they could wh not stop the sale under this law. The Supreme Court of the United States held this: that because cocoanut oil was added to the evaporated skim milk, it was nothing more nor less than evaporated skim milk, and therefore could not be sold under the Ohio law; and it further de- he Ohio law was constitutional After this decision, we made up our minds in Wisconsin we could a prohibitory law prohibiting the manufacture and sale of this product. The law was passed, and it is being tested in the Supreme Court of our State to determine whether it is constitutional. We must admit that is drastic legislation which will stop the manu - facture and sale of a wholesome, nutritious product. But I hold it is right in consideration of the future generations of our people. I am far more concerned about the development of the American dairy fanner and the American people than I am about the farmer of the South Sea Islands, with no investment except a strap for climbing trees to pick cocoanuts. I do not know how we are going to build up agriculture in this country and educate our people unless we establish a permanent sys - tem of agriculture, and unless we produce the best food product* we know how to produce. It seems to me our Supreme Court of Wisconsin is likely to uphold the constitutionality of this law, because the Supreme Court of the United States sustained the Ohio law. We must admit that decision was an advanced step in determining what food products may be sold and what should not be sold. It must be admitted evaporated skim milk is a wholesome, nutritious product; yet the Supreme Court held the label upon the product does not protect, having in mind in reference to filled milk that the consumer, although he knew he was buying or using this product, did not know in the skimming process 80 per cent of the vita- </seg>
            <seg id="p094">192X ANNUAL REPORT 94 mines — perhaps 90 per cent — had been taken away. The label does not tell that. The Supreme Court had in mind, I am sure, that when the American mother goes to the store or to her milk man, or wherever she purchases milk, and asks for milk, she expects milk. She may not know why milk is such a good food. The Jewish mother, from the time history is re - corded, used milk, but she could not tell why it was so good. It took a scientist to do that. But as a rule, the practical man precedes the scientist, and the latter come along and tell us why. Dr. McCullom has said that milk was good. The Jewish mother knew it was good. In this country, wherever you find a colony of Jews, you will find they have liberal quantities of milk for their children, regardless of price. The label, as you can readily see, does not tell what we know about milk. The manufacturer says it is for cooking purposes only. Do you know it has the same composition as evaporated milk, and when you sell it for cooking purposes, it is necessary to add as much more fat; that there isn't enough shortening in this product to make cake or doughnuts ? If they wanted it as a cooking product, why didn't they put in enough cocoanut oil to make it a real shortening product? If they did that. I am reasonably certain it would show it is an entirely different product than evaporated milk. They have it exactly the same composition as whole milk. The housewife knows that milk alone does not contain suffi - cient shortening for her cake. She uses a little lard or butter. So the argument it is made just for cooking purposes falls by They say it saves the laboring man; that h which is going to waste on the farm. It does not gc man knows how to feed it to his chickens and cows and buy on the market as much powdered skim milk as you w milk in this can of "Hebe," and as much butter fat nut oil; and the butter and dried milk powder which w to what is in the can in fat and milk solids will not filled milk compound. Then where does the economy conu other words, you can take butter and pure skim milk eq amount of cocoanut oil and solids in the can of filled milk, ar cheaper than the product they sell you. So the laboring mar saved anything. He has been deceived The filled milk is labeled, but in thirty-four stores out of thirty - five in Wisconsin handling the product, that were visited — a man went in and asked for a can of evaporated milk, and thirty-four stores sold this compound. There was only one storekeeper who said, "We have no evaporated milk, but I have a compound made of skim milk and cocoa - nut oil." </seg>
            <seg id="p095">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 95 w id University graduates using it who thought they were ated milk. One of our State Assembly men went to a g of students one evening to have a social time with some of home. They were telling this man how cheaply they f rig, and said: "We buy everything by the case — even our lilk." It was "Hebe." If University graduates and stu- w when labeled and use it as milk, and when thirty-four t of thirty-five will sell the product as milk, or some- han milk, how are we going to control it by law? It is an ui-t which is aimed to take the place of a fundamental food. to me the only thing to do is to say the product shall not ft factured and sold. realize this is rather a dry topic for a banquet, so I am going to ;fore I get myself in the position of Ole when he proposed to his They were out riding one June morning. The birds were singing weetly, and the girl looked a little nicer to Ole than ever before. He proposed to her and she accepted. Then there was a long silence. The ame worried, and finally nudged him: "Ole, why you not talk?" Oh. ba Yove. Ay tank Ay have said too much alretty." (Laughter.) thank you. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: I am sure we greatly appreciate the oppor- :unity we have had to learn about "Filled Milk." It is a question that A-ill soon be up for serious consideration in Congress. It is almost impossible nowadays to pick up an agricultural paper what you will see notice of the remarkable achievement of some lairy cow. I ran across a description of one of these remarkable cows in a local paper. She happened to be for sale: "A cow for sale that gives ten quarts of milk, besides two grindstones, a lot of farm tools. and a set of harness." (Laughter.) A school teacher had had occasion to punish Tommy, who talked too much in school, but apparently without any effect. Finally she re - sorted to the sending of a note to Tommy's father, with the monthly report card. Underneath the monthly report she had written these words: "Tommy talks a great deal." She waited to hear from Tommy's father. In due course of time the monthly report card came back with the signature of Tommy's father, and underneath was this remark: "You ought to hear his mother!" (Laughter.) I think whenever any good Nebraskan has succeeded in making a new dairy record that the maker should have opportunity to tell us about it and so I asked Mr. Jenkinson if he would not come to our banquet and tell us about this new Nebraska record cow. He came back and said. "You had better ask mother." (Laughter.) </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 1921 ANNUAL REPORT Now, I have had some little experience with making records and know they are not easily made, even under Dairy Department conditions. That being the case, I can easily realize that to break a state record under ordinary farm conditions is an achievement that ought to be worthy of the approval of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association. So I thought it fitting that some one should tell us of this cow, which in the last year produced more milk than any other in the State of Nebraska. I am very glad to have the opportunity of presenting Mrs. Jenkinson of Monroe Who will tell us about this really wonderful farmer's cow. (Applause.) "A FARMER'S COW." Fellow Dairymen and Women: I think Professor Frandsen rather took advantage of me because he thought I was going to have the last word when he said what he did. I will admit I do a little talking up to our place, but I do not do it all. (Laughter.) He spoke of milking cows under the conditions of a Nebraska institution. We are a Nebraska institution. Both my husband and I were born in Platte county — a son and daughter of Nebraska pioneers — and our home is a Nebraska insti tution; so it is a pleasure to us to give to Nebraska her first 30,000 pound cow My part of the work has not been quite so strenuous as my hus - band's; but as "Liziie" is a name we give little machines supposed to work hard and not get much credit, so instead of calling me Sarah Elizabeth, the folks knew what was coming when they called me Lizzie. If I could change this subject, I would change it to "A Farmer's Cow in a Vision." It is just whatever the farmer himself wants to make it. I believe there are a number of good cows in the state and more breeds than the Holstein. If at the time my husband started farming, there had been a pure bred Jersey sire in the community, we would have been breeding Jerseys, and good ones. His father had a pure-bred Jersey cow. I was up there one time before we were married. They were threshing. His mother took me out to the tank. She began dipping out the cream and kept dipping. She had a pallon can. I said, "You surely have gotten into the wrong can." "No," she replied, "this is our Jersey's milk." We had a daughter of this cow for our first cow, but the daughter was not as good as the mother cow. We had other cows in our herd. Mrs. Lizzie Jenkinson, Monroe, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p097">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 97 My husband had been at the Farmers' Course the winter before we were married and he had the vision of what a real cow can be. We did not expect to milk cows. We were just going to keep one cow, and have a good time, too. We did not settle down to it all at once. But we found out if ever we were going- to have a home and the things we ex - pected to have some time, it was going to be from some other source than a grain source; so we began getting more cows and milking them. My husband had heard of a publication while down at this School "Hoard's Dairyman." We subscribed for that. Among other thing*. he had learned to test milk, so we got a little tester and began an asso - ciation of our own. He had a very fine grade of producers as they were", «( ht still had other ambitions and wanted to be a producer of pure reds; so he went to a sale at Omaha and bought a beautiful little heifer calf — a sister of Clema Wayne (Butter Queen.) We named her Hope. Hope took pneumonia. She got well, but afterwards she drank much milk she made a hog of herself and died. But not our determi- n He went to Central City and got a pure bred sire and a heifer calf. Then we got another one from Stevens Brothers. AH this time we were breeding Holsteins. Then my husband got some young heifers from Nelson Brothers. On those we did our first official testing. We had the junior three-year-old record for seven days on Thilda De Kol Pontiac She also was the first cow in the State under full age to give 20,000 pounds. All this time my husband had been using better sires, such as King Segis Pontiac Plus and Colantha Johanna Lad Phis, son of Colantfaa Johanna Lad. Before we had one of our own, we hired the services. Then we decided we would have to have another sire. In the breed papers there appeared the notice of a sale of a herd in Wisconsin. We had a full set of the Blue Books. We got a catalogue and looked things up to see if the records were as quoted in the catalogue. My husband stopped at the sale and found these animals were just as beautiful as they had been advertised to be. and gave much promise. He bought Oak Lodfre (Corona Clyde) and also her sire, Beauty Walker Pietertje King, and some others. That is how we got Corona. I do not know whether I am telling family secrets, but she is not for sale. We got her for $200. Don't offer us that today. She freshened before fair time in 1917 and my husband brought her down here, and cleaned up in the Junior butter contest open to all breeds. She made 5462 pounds of milk and over twenty pounds of butter afterward on official test. In her thirty-day record, she had over 2,000 pounds of milk at this time; so this wonderful record was indicated early in her life. I shall not spend much time In giving you figures with which you are </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 1921 ANNUAL REPORT at least in part familiar. She averaged for the year a ten-gallon milk can daily of milk, and ever three pounds of butter each day. We agree with Mr. Glover that you tan produce milk on tht much better than you can buy it in tin cans. I presume the question almost everybody is most interested in is, "What did you feed her?" There were no secret rations. In our first testing work we bought all the different kinds of things -oat meal and hominy, etc. — and we thought we must fix them up just like they did back east. Later we found out the Nebraska foods were the best; so Corona was fed practically all the foods raised on the farm, excepting oil— and cotton seed meal and salt. The ration was 200 pounds of oats and 100 pounds of corn, ground together; 100 pounds of bran; loo pounds of oil meal; 35 pounds of cottonseed meal, and 10 pounds of salt. Up tc June first she was fed 41 pounds of grain daily. She was milked four times a day all through the year. Each milking she was fed three - fourths of a bushel of beets, and until she learned to eat them readily. my husband pared the beets. She had all of the fourth cutting of alfalfa she wanted all the time. His only trouble in raising alfalfa b that it is not all fourth cutting! (Laughter.) I compiled these figures because several peoplf havi much grain Corona got for each pound of milk. She gc of grain for each two and one-fourth pounds of milk unt The latter part she was given one pound of grain for e two-fifths pounds of milk. In the summer, in place of husband chopped green corn for her. She was watered ei she would drink. In June she began coming down. We put her on th was producing so heavily and the green grass was so MM she could not get enough nutriment from the pasture, back into the bam again. My husband ordered an electric fan for her. We h house, but it was not quite so big as the one he ordered for Coroa and he was afraid to take the old fan to the barn for fear 1 wou claim the new one when it came. (Laughter.) Her stall was screene He put the fan in the stall not only to make it cooler, but to provide circulation of air. Corona gave seventeen times her weight in milk in a year. She weighs about 1.900. And we still have Corona. We also have two of her daughters, and one of them — Loup View Corona — unless there are other figures in since we sent ours — is the junior champion in the 305 - day division. She carried a calf 198 days during test, and is due to freshen in March, so she will qualify within the fourteen months spe- </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Wt' y n and ti ■d. We also have two of Corona's sons. One is in Denver, and one have at home. Loup View, Corona's youngest son, is in the Nelson Brothers' herd at Stromsburg. We received a letter from the firm where my husband bought her. In it they said there was a great deal at erest in Wisconsin about her. Her mother has two other daughters. has herself over a 20-pound record on a three-fourths' udder, losing one quarter with mammitis; so she also was quite a cow, and they are iwing the stuff back there with great success. We have done prac- y no showing. The story of Corona is just the story of planning and thinking and king and wiggling to do it. And that is nothing but what anyone an do. There have been more 30,000-pound cows developed this than ever before. When LaMay made her record, she was the cow in the world. Corona, with her record of 1.009 pounds at was ranked the thirty-fifth cow when she made her record; so have changed. There are now twenty cows in the world that (riven 30,000 pounds. Corona stands fourteenth. Times are changing, and if we are to keep at the head of the pro - ion, it behooves everyone of us to everlastingly wiggle. with a little bit of original verse: The Dairy Man of 1921. (In contrast with the fanner.) The dairyman sat on his milking stool At the close of the summer's day. Thinking how profits of fields of corn Would surely be slipping away ere it not for his herd of fine Holsteins Which put the coin into his jeans. ■ dairyman said to his eldest son, \ lad with a freckled face, We have milked our cows, both night and morn, For months in the same old place; Though prices may drop on hogs and steers, Our weekly check can cause no tears. "I have always felt that this day would come. So I watered and salted and fed. And my savings in that bank account Have never been written in red. So the squirrels that are up in the old oak tree Will never indeed for a nut take me." </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 1921 ANNUAL REPORT And this is the way back to the sun In our fair Nebraska State. With the dairy cow the battle's won, Nothing can be left to Fate. (Applause.) THE TOASTM ASTER: I noticed when Mr. Glover made his talk, he stood close to Mrs. Jenkinson. I am wondering how much he paid for that Hoard's Dairyman ad? (Laughter.) Boys are quite prune to brag about the dignity of their dads, but sometimes girls have the same failing. They tell a story of a group of little girls who were enthusiastically bragging about the dignity uf their respective parents. One little girl talked about the clothes. She had exhausted the subject of furnishings, and finally she said, "Do you know, every piece of mail that comes to our house is marked 'D. D.'?" "That's nothing," said the little daughter of a doctor. "F package that comes to our house is marked 'M. D'." "Huh." said the little new-comer, who so far had not spoker nothing. Every package that comes to our house is labeled 'C. (Laughter.) I would not be surprised but what the next speaker w a C. O. D. package. I think we all admit in spite of the wonderful things we have done in dairying here, that at least along certain lim-s of dairy work, our European friends have excelled us. Possibly no one thing has contributed more to their superior dairying over there than some of the things accomplished in the conferences which they hold an - nually. They have conferences for workers in every phase of dairy work. They call them "dairy congresses," and they were held quite regularly before the war. It was deemed a peculiar privilege for every - one in Europe engaged in dairy work to have an opportunity to attend those congresses. It has been the hope of American dairymen at some time to get dairying on such a footing in this country and organized in such a way that it would be possible for us to invite the official nations of the world to a dairy congress here; and it has been the hope of our dairy interests here to get together so that we could do this job in a way befitting the dignity of the country in which we live. It has been a difficult thing to work this matter out, for we have not had the organizations that usually handle work of that kind. Two or three years ago, some of our farsighted dairymen thought conditions were about ripe for such a congress to be undertaken. They had various unofficial meetings, but no headway was made until it was decided to get some man to "tenure the necessary funds and start this </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 101 work Dean Van Norman was selected for this work. He has been connected with the University of California as Dean of the Farmers' School. He did not volunteer, but I think he was drafted to take the presidency of this World's Dairy Congress; so temporarily he has divorced himself from all his other activities to devote his time to this. A e have not heard as much about this world's Dairy Congress move - as we would like to hear, and I think we are fortunate to have Dean Van Norman with us tonight; and I hope he will tell us what it is, what it will do for us, and what we can do for it. Dean Van Norman. THE WORLD'S DAIRY CONGRESS" By its President, H. E. Van Norman, Washington, D. C. Ir. Toastmaster, Ladies and Gentlemen: "Plan, and work, and think, ■viptfle." (Applause.) May I digress just a moment to emphasize hat has meant in the way of a contrast between work and xh ry? Think of the joy that has been in that home and all that ! up to the triumph which is here told tonight! It is that love of doing something that makes life worth while. To that man who works for wages alone, eight hours is a long day. To the man who works for the joy of accomplishing something, sixteen hours is not a long- day. We need more of that thing* for our young people on our farms to give them that vision that makes it worth while to "work, and plan, and think, and wiggle." I cannot refrain from adding that word. (Applause.) We have in this country three national organizations of the dairy industry. They have three biff jobs to do. One is the National Dairy Association, which gives an annual exposition of the year's progress in dairying. We have the National Dairy Council, whose job it is to tell the world — our own people — what a wonderfud product we have in these products of the dairy cow, and how much more necessary they are to human welfare than many people know. That is the educational work of the industry. Then we come to the newest and last organization — the World's Dairy Congress Association — whose task is to bring about an international exchange of the never knowledge on which progress is dependent. Progress is ahead of published record. I wish you could write that down and remember it after you have forgotten me. I do not care how good "Hoard's Dairyman" is, or any other paper. The newest thing has not yet been written. The written page cannot keep up with history. It is always behind. Therefore if you want to know the newest thing, you must see the fellow who is doing it and learn it from him; and then in return tell him the newer things. That is what makes possible this </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 1921 ANNUAL REPORT wonderful list of organizations we have in America — these wonderful winter gatherings such as you are having here this week, in which you come to hear the newest things in your particular line that have not yet been written. It is true we hear some things that have been written, because we have not yet grasped them. We must hear them with our ears and see them with our eyes. Europe gave us the separation, homogenization, pasteurization, and the beginning science of dairy bacteriology. We, on the other hand, have taken those things and developed them. Europe gave us the cow testing association, too. We have better cows than Europe ever had, I believe. We are making better records than Europe ever made. We have developed the machinery of manufacture — the business organiza - tions of the dairy industry — I am told in advance of anything other countries have. We have developed the wonderful city milk distributing organizations and the method of handling great volumes of milk. Think of one company running fifteen hundred wagons in one city, distributing hundreds of thousands of gallons of milk daily! Think of what it means to wash all those million bottles every day, and cap and fill them, and cool the milk, and put it on the consumer's back door step, and collect a little money for it! It is a big task, and America has develop' facilities and methods by which we do these things. Not only have we done that, but we have developec »ond new knowledge of milk in relation to the national health and welfai And at the risk of boring you, may I say that in i cities — and I would not be a Californian if I did not ring th* speech somewhere — they examined 55,000 school children — weigh measured them — and found 40 per cent were underweight a height. They paraded those figures before the school boar wise old fathers sat back and said, "What of it? Aren't thev goo kids?" That took the starch out of the investigators, anc \v their records to find some answer. They found that in every grade from the kindergarten to the eighth, not only were the non-milk-drinking children shorter and lighter for their age, but not so far along in their school work. In other words, the milk drinkers were younger in every grade than the non-milk-drinking children They finished the eighth grade two years younger than the non-milk drinkers; so milk not only made weight and stature, but brains. And we have other spectacular evidence along the same line. America has learned this newer lesson of the relation of milk to the health of her young people. And we have not only learned that lesson, </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 if the scientists in other countries knew something of the same it has taken America to develop the machinery for telling the thi t w national and state dairy councils and our extension &gt;me of our public school activities, such as the parent I visiting nurses' associations — all learning to tell this pie. And by the way, there isn't any other branch of a has as many unpaid advertisers as we who milk cows; help of all these agencies to sell our product to the other ng our opportunity if we do not cash in on it to the ica has developed this machinery for teaching the public, too. ntries are beginning to look to us to learn how to teach young hese lessons. The Ambassador from Rotterdam has said he does whether his farmers raise steers or cows, but he cares whether the children drink more milk or not. He has issued a pamphlet show - ing how we in America teach our children how to drink more milk. Bom - bay, India, is asking us to send a man to their city to show them how i-elop a city milk supply. Hongkong is importing from Australia, powder and sweet butter, and emulsifying it in American homo- genizers and converting it into ice cream with American ice machinery, and selling it to the "heathen Chinee!" Stockholm, Sweden, has had a man in this country learning how we protect our milk supply against milk epidemics in order that the cities may be well fed. London is g into the largest milk pasteurizing plant in the world all American machinery &gt;eak of these things to show America has reached a place where something to give the other fellow. w While we have developed in these ways, Germany, France, Denmark. Holland. Sweden, and Belgium have their men doing the more intensive work in making the more critical scientific study on which progress is made. It took the scientist seven years to learn this truth of the science It took Babcock a year to discover the Babcock test. So we of iwe much to the scientific man for his help. This World's Dairy Congress is planned and designed to bring about an international exchange of the newer knowledge all along the line; and not only to bring about the new knowledge, but to give publicity to that which we already know. I talked with Mr. Hoover about this thing, and he said, "There are two great values resulting from such a congress as you have in mind. One is the exchange of knowledge, and the other is a wider distribution of what we already know." </seg>
            <seg id="p104">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 104 There are two great conditions. One is the fellow in the front rank hunting for new truth, and the fellow behind who is trying to get the rest of the people to do half as well as we already know. If all the farmers in Nebraska were doing half as good work as our friend here, we would not hear one-half the hard luck stories we do about the un - profitableness of agriculture. So we have one group hunting for new truth, and other trying to get the rank and file to act upon half of what we already know. So the Congress will have two purposes: To get new truth, and to get the people to use what they already know. The suggestion of the Congress came to us from South America. It came to the State Department and they referred it to the Department of Agriculture, and they brought it to the Dairy show. As president, it fell to my lot to find out whether our dairy people wanted it. We held a meeting and called in representatives of fifteen different national organ - izations. They said, "Let's go ahead provided Congress will authorize the President to invite foreign nations to take part." You see we wanted class to these things! I do not know whether you will have to hire dress coats or not. (Laughter.) On the other side they laid a great deal of stress on the kind of coat worn. Some of our delegates had to rent dress suits. When they got to the function, they found two of them had only one pair of gloves. Each wore a glove and kept the other hand out of sight. (Laughter.) The gentleman who told me this said, "When in Rome, do as the Romans." Congress has given the President authority to invite these people. It was changed from 1922 to 1923 before Christmas, so we are ready to send out our invitation. We did not have anybody to speak for the dairymen in this country, so it was decided we should have an organiza - tion with special organizers which would take charge of this matter, so there has been organized the World's Dairy Congress Association. It takes money in America to make things go — even a farm. The question was, "Who is going to pay for this?" We said. "We will ask Congress for some help." It will help a little bit, but if we want this tiling to go, we will have to pay for it ourselves. There were three men at the first meeting who would each put in $100. I was asked to find if there were one hundred such men or organizations or associations in America. I called on thirty-six men and have $30,000 promised. I know the next thirty-six are not going to do as well. You pick the cream first. When the patch gets thin, it takes longer to fill the pail. We have $70,00 subscribed out of the $100,000 we started to get. About next December we will go to Congress and ask for help. This is not an assessment of the industry. It is an opportunity which it has been my duty to present to the biggest men and com - panies and organizations in this country. I want to tell you that has </seg>
            <seg id="p105">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 105 been some job' My wife and I have lived in a couple of suit cases and stayed in hotels in thirty-six different towns in this country in the last few months. I have had the pleasure of meeting, I think, the president of each of the largest manufactories of dairy machinery, the largest creameries, the largest milk condensaries and milk compound concerns and ice cream concerns and plants and individual men in the Jersey, Holstein, Guernsey and Ayrshire breeds of cattle, and quite a number of our state associations. I want to say to you it has been a liberal education to find as fine a lot of men scattered in these different businesses as in any business in America This Congress is a sort of bringing together of these leaders. I cannot call on a hundred thousand people to get a dollar from each. So we chose the other way to find the men who could afford to contribute to this thing and would do so because they believed it was of value to the dairy industry of America. Did you ever stop to think that progress in every branch owes a great deal to the unselfish people who do something without hope of mmediate reward? Who are the men who have made your State Asso - iation a success? Have you paid them in cash for the services they have rendered, or must they take their pay in satisfaction? I suspect the latter. So this Dairy Congress is not going to be paid for by all the people who will benefit, but by the smaller portion who can afford to help. I had the privilege of presenting this matter to the Creamery Men's rganization of this State. To the surprise of some of their members and the gratification of the rest, they promptly voted to join and con - tribute their thousand dollars. I presented it to the Milk Producers' organization of San Francisco and the Dairymen's league of New York, and they said they were glad to help. I presented it to a little bunch of Guernsey breeders around Philadelphia, and they said, "We will help." Somebody said, "Let's pass the hat and get it done with." They raited $750 in twenty minutes. One woman said, "I will put in $100 for my daughter." I do not know whether the production side of the dairy interests of Nebraska wish to help with this work or not. I do not know whether they are able to help or not. Your Chairman asked me to present the opportunity, and it is yours. If you want to help make this thing possible, and if you want the name of the Nebraska dairy interests associated with the World's Dairy Congress in literature that goes out around the world, your co-operation and support will be welcome. I am not like the missionary home on a begging enterprise. I am your hired </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 1921 ANNUAL REPORT man to present this thing to you. I leave the matter with you. I d&lt; not know whether you wish to do anything with it or not. In one sense it is immaterial. I know the work is going across and going across big Do you want to be a part of it? I thank you for the pleasure 1 have had in being here and hearing the program and speakers today and yesterday. I congratulate you on th« development that is being made. I believe the dairy industry of this state and of America has a wonderful future ahead of it. Our big prob - lems will not be solved by the individual, but by groups of individuals with wise leadership, and in a spirit of co-operation. Do not be discouraged, but go ahead in the spirit which makes f American accomplishment. I thank you. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: I am sure we are grateful to Dean Var Norman for having given us this view of the work. The meeting wil soon be back in the hands of the President, and perhaps he will havt something further to say relative to this matter. Dr. Schwab says the most interesting story he ever heard wa boy who left his brother on the farm to do the work, while ht to the city. The city boy wrote back to his brother out on the telling of the joys of city life, in which he said: "Thursday we i out to the country club where we golfed until dark. Then we m to the beach, and Fridayed there." The brother on the farm wrote back: "Yesterday we buggu-.i town and baseballed all afternoon. Then we went to Med's ami pataa* until morning. Today we muled out to the cornfield, and gee-haw until sundown. Then we suppered, and then we piped for a while. Aft that we stair-cased up to our room and bed-steaded until the clock tivec (Laughter.) That reminds me of the duties of the avera Looking over the topic assigned to the next speak ;i think of dairy work. When we see what an easy time boys in the towns have, when they work short hours for good pay, we may justly wonder how it is possible under those conditions to interest any of these boys sufficiently to get them interested in dairy work. That is the subject assigned to the next speaker. I am glad at this time, not to introduce — because most of you already know the new head of our Dairy Department — but to have the opportunity to present officially at a dairy banquet Professor H. P. Davis, chairman of the Dairy Husbandry Department of our University, who will now ad - dress us on the subject: "Our Dairy Husbandry Department". (Applause.) </seg>
            <seg id="p107">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 107 "OLR DAIRY HUSBANDRY DEPARTMENT" PROFESSOR H. P. DAVIS, Lincoln: Mr. Toastmaster, Ladies and Gentlemen: There is only one way to follow the schedule Professor b'randsen has outlined for both city and country. That is to take Miss Atwood's advice to drink milk, and drink lots of it. t may interest you to know that "Toast to Milk" was originated by &gt;f the speakers with you tonight — Mr. McDowell. At the time he originated that, I labored with him to get up a good toast, because it was a good subject. I believe he originated a real Toast to Milk, and I wish we had him here to give the toast. Now, milk is not only a good food, but a good drink. We cannot ■ it. That is one reason, I think, many people do not drink it. They jst have something to work their teeth on. You cannot work year teeth milk, if it is good milk. (Laughter.) — Not unless it is processed ia hundreds of ways miik can be processed. Milk has a soothing effect on civilization. Somebody has said all the itive geniuses come from countries where milk is an important part le diet. I would like to take that a little further, and I am going to rom a man who originated the idea. I will give him credit for it, ;hink it is a unique idea and well worth thinking about We are talking about less armament. Why can't we prevent arma - ia at all ? Milk is a good food. Maybe it is a peace promoting sub- I rather think it is. Think of the countries where dairying is a Think of Denmark. She has not been at war for years since the dairy industry has developed to any great ex - for any of us t&lt; remember when Switzerland was at war, has developer! the dairy industry. Holland — n rather peaceful for a considerable period. Ik diet that makes for peace. rmer member of our dairy fraternity, said that and country over said, "It is the one cause for disarma- M.iybe it is. We should drink more milk for other purposes and it would help us to be more peaceful in our Homes. I do not know nether after drinking a bottle of milk you would feel pugnacious or not have never seen it on the diet of our famous prize fighters. Milk certainly is a wonderful food. Being a wonderful food, it can be handled in so many different ways that the intricacies of the business are hard to master. I do not believe very many of you realize how many different dairy products there are. We know there is milk — whole, and skimmed, and evaporated, and condensed, and dried — and cheese. People say, "Yes, there is cheese," as if it covered everything. There are nearly five hundred varieties of cheese, and most of you cannot name twenty-fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 1921 ANNUAL REPORT We do not know much about our industry — about the products into which milk may go. We ought to know more about :t. Yet you put up to us the job of telling all our students all about the dairy industry I know some of you come up and think it is surprising we do not know absolutely everything to be known about the business. We do not know - it all. I wish we did. If we did, I am afraid our heads would burst with tht knowledge. But we are representing you and your institution, in your service trying our best to teach your boys and girls something about this big, magnificient industry. It is a big industry. The mere taking care of cattle is a complicated business in itself. If you do not believe it. just talk with some of the people who have taken care of these high-producing cows. It is not just going out and shoveling a little feed in every morning and more at noon and night. It is the observation and the knowledge and the keenness that go along with it. How are you going to know when the cow gets off feed? Those are the things that make the business successful. If we could always tell — and Nels Anderson will bear me out in this — when a cow is going off feed twenty-four hours beforehand we would never tat lier go off. That is just one phase of the industry We do not know very much about cheese. We manulac varieties of cheese in this country. Lately we are manufa A A cheese which is fully equal, I believe, to the best manufactured in Swil erland. It is the result of scientific work — a complicated science We u going to be able to master other foreign cheeses whose peculiar flav may not appeal to your taste, but on the market will bring a hi; return. Then the market milk business in itself is one of the most technical of businesses. It sounds easy to bring milk in and run it through a pas - teurizer and through a bottler. But how are you going to control the cream line and keep it even from day to day? If you know the answer. you can draw a magnificent salary from some of the milk companies in this country. Those are some of the problems that come to us. We are trying to solve them. Our duty is to try to be of service to you in the State through your boys and girls who come to the College, and through our Extension Service, as Professor Lawritson tries to take our work to you •nd the various county agents and farm bureaus, to bring the informa - tion we have gathered to you and try to represent, to the best of our a - bility, a centralized place where we can all come and talk over and advise with each other on the problems of dairying. I hope we may have that conception in this State— that you will feel free to talk things over with us. We do not know it all, but maybe by swapping experiences we can make this industry one of the great names </seg>
            <seg id="p109">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 109 in Nebraska agriculture. I hope for that. I think it is entirely feasible. Then we will not have- the depression we are now having because so many of our folks have labored with one or two crops. A more diver - sified farming, a little more dairying, and we will have the prosperity that has gone with our dairy states. Prosperity does not always go with fertile soil. If you have ever been over some of the counties in Wisconsin, you will wonder why any of the people ever settled in that country — Mr. Glover will pardon me if I say that — when there is so much good land the world over. The real reason Wisconsin has come out so well is because those people have had to dairy in order to get a good living on much of Wisconsin's soil. Nature is too good to us out here, and every now and then she takes a little slap. She gives us a bumper crop, but the consumer gives us very little for it. Mrs. Jcnkinson brought up a point we must not forget. Our im - provement in our dairy cows comes from selection, from breeding. Where rt we going to get that improvement if not from the great sires Wt annot tell where they are. We must develop them. When we do, let us hope we can use them to the best advantage. I hope there will be a fraternity among the dairymen for getting good sires that we may have the benefit of the use of such an animal. We have had the benefit of a the University in years gone by. When a sire can add three d pounds of milk to the daughters over the dams, let us promote work together and all push, and instead of sitting back and ther people or forces to help us in dairying, let us all get push; and let us take an active part, not only in our state n our national work in promoting dairying — the best of all lihood. (Applause.) THE TOA3TMASTER: They tell of a colored man who was sup pesed to have been in one of the battles of the world war. Sambo was caught running away as rapidly as he could well run. Someone seeing him run, yelled, "Sambo, where are you running from?" "I ain't run - ning from anywhere I is just trying to get away from where I's at." i Laughter. I If I were on a toast list and had a subject entitled "Ripe Ol - ives and Wood Alcohol," I would want to get away from it as fast as possible. I am sure, you are going to enjoy the treat there is in store for you. The speaker I am about to introduce is one of the Lincoln Rotary Club's best entertainers, and I take pleasure in introducing Mr. Risdon, who will talk on the subject of 'Ripe Olives and Wood Alcohol." </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 1921 ANNUAL REPORT RIPE OLIVES AND WOOD ALCOHOL MR. GEORGE RISDON, Lincoln: Mr. Toastmaster. Ladies and Gen - tlemen: I owe that reputation to Professor Frandsen. It was he who gave me my first opportunity in Rotary. When he called on me for my subject, I used that which was uppermost in my mind: "The Relation of Ripe Olives to Wood Alcohol." I think that was the subject he first as- After listening to the wonderful talks this evening I have decidec to change the subject. Although I have acquired a reputation as an after-dinner speaker, that reputation has been far overshadowed by one I acquired for having been arrested for being the fir=t one to have been found with liquor in his possession after the- State went I fired the office boy and he beat it had liquor in my possession. They in the water cooler two pint bottles i went to the Judge and asked him t&lt; much." dry. i Laughter. I The story is this: to the police station and told them I sent a search warrant and found down &gt;f beer. They read me the warrant. I read the law. He did. I said, "H "One hundred and five dollar I paid it. Then I beat it to the state "Journal" ar to suppress it, and they gave me the horse laugh. "Did story?" Well, yes; so much so I had letters and telegrams from all over they country. I read of the incident in all guages — even in a paper published in the Swedish language cut. That's the story. The Rotary Club took it up, and I be Pr or Frandsen was responsible for that. They said they did not war body in their institution who would raise the price of beer from a a quart to fifty-two and a half dollars a pint! (Laughter I told them I was in the same position as the Kentuckian w turned home to look after his votes, he sat down to the table he saw he ject was "Water". He said: They gave a dinner for him. Wl - was down for a toast, and the si "I have seen it in the eye of Youth; I have seen it trickle down the face furrowed with age; I have heard its sweet music in the early morn mingled with the ice in the pitcher that the boy brought up the hall; I have seen it gush from the mountainside and wind its trail through hill and vale where sweet birds sitting upon dripping branches would lend their sweetest notes to the rushing waters. I have heard it beat upon the rocky shores of the Penobscot and the Golden Gate where the sun is wont to set in its rainbow splendor; and in its oxygenic form I have known its sustaining elements to bring back to life one stilled in death. In youth I waded in it; in age I have had it massaged into me. I admit </seg>
            <seg id="p111">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 111 it is wonderful, powerful, omnipotent a d n!" (Laughter.) but as a beverage — it isn't worth am pleased to be with the ladies this evening, because I owe what littie success I have in my life to my mother — to the early training and education and confidence my mother instilled into me when a mere boy. I have been very successful, because I measure success entirely by the friends I have made and not in dollars and cents. You know, my mother was my pal. The last time I told about my back home at the time she died, the description I gave of that meet- ng filled my audience with such emotion I said I never would tell it pain. But I cannot help thinking of her because ther had two lovely eyes. As lustrous as the evening skies, And looking in. I always saw Vly image, perfect, with no flaw. Safely stored within my heart Lies her image, my sweetheart. My mother had such lovely hair. Combed around with her own air Of tender care, soft and brown, (oiled around her like a crown; Twisted round with dainty touch. Not too little nor too much My mother had a perfect mouth. Warm as breezes from the south. Like the joyous birds of spring Were the songs she loved to sing; Drooped against her loving breast. My head found a perfect rest. My mother had a charming face. Circled round the neck with lace; The softest cheeks, the daintiest ears Listening to my hopes and fears; Pearly teeth, as white as milk, Lips with kisses soft as silk. My mother had the sweetest chin. With little dimples dotted in; And her eyes, so soft and mild. Gazing tenderly at her child; My mother was my dear, my friend; We chummed until the very end. (Applause.) I was on mv way from Salt Lake City where I had been attending a meeting of the Rotary Club. The whole train was devoted to Rotarians. There was a session being pulled off in the baggage car by the Kansas </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 1921 ANNUAL REPORT City delegation. I got into it by accident. The next morning at the breakfast table I was just about to leave when a gentleman said, "I beg your pardon. I understand you are a memory expert." Then he handed me a long slip of paper on which was a poem. He said, "Here is some - thing you should commit to memory." I looked at it and saw it was something I knew. I stood and read it through, and as I was reading, I would pass my hand over my forehead tragically, f Laughter) Finally I handed the poem back to him and re- Poor Old bad Yon can scarce pick up a paper and its poets' corner greet, 'Cept you'll find a pretty poem of a sainted mother sweet. Bat you'll have a time of searchin', eyes will be achin' mighty bad Ere you run across a poem at this time for Poor Old Dad. r&gt;, it isn't wilful in 'em, them as writes of mother dear, That no mention is e'er taken of the old man sittin' near No, it's never meant to slight him, but oh, it looks so sad All these bouquets thrown at mother, not a bloomin' one for Dad True our mother watched above us until her poor old eyes would ache But Dad, he humped to feed us 'til his back would almost break Mother crooned above the cradle, grave devotion all she had But that wasn't a circumstance compared to Poor Old Dad. Do not take one line from mother when you write the soul sweet song. But if you'll say a word for father now and then, it won't be wrong Poor old soul! He is bent and wrinkled, and I know 'twould make him glad If when you're praisin' mother, something's said for Poor Old Dad. (Applause.) As I went out of the door, the big fellow said, "That's absolutel uncanny'" I Laughter.) Going back to the subject the Professor assigned me — the liquor question — all evening I made up my mind when I got home I would beat it to the refrigerator and get a good big bottle of Hunter's milk. (Laugh - ter.) I am satisfied that had Edgar Allen Poe fed up on milk, he would never have written "The Raven" for he wrote it while he was drunk. But he was goaded on to do those things from the fact he was underfed. I am satisfied if he had lived at our present time he would never have writ - ten the poetical works attributed to him. He wrote "The Raven." It is a wonderful thing, if you stop to think about it, where he says: </seg>
            <seg id="p113">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION 113 Once upon a midnight weary while I pondered, weak wear O a quaint and curious volume of forgotten re While I nodded, nearly napping, suddenly there came a tapping A.- of some one gently rapping, rapping at ray chamber door. ""Pis a visitor," I muttered, "tapping at my chamber door — Only this and nothing more. And the Raven, never flitting, still is sitting, still is sitting On the pallid bust of Pallas just above my chamber Kir And his eyes have all the seeming of a demon's that is dreaming, And the lamplight o'er him streaming throws his shadow on the floor; And my soul from out that shadow that lies floating on the floor, Shall be lifted — nevermore. That never could have been written except by a man nfluence of liquor, or just coming out. either under the Mv version is this: How distinctly I remember late one evening last November I was sitting on a barrel that the moonlight floated ntv cider barrel, and was useful now no t Worthless now forevermore As a few lone stars were blinking, I betook myself To thinking, And I thought of that old Raven Edgar Poe had wrote about. That was quite a high old Raven Mr. Poe had told about; And while the stars were blinking, blinking blinking. I kept thinking, thinking, thinking Ar.d the more I thought about it the more I was in doubt. Edgar's logic knocked me out. Think of where the lamp was sitting and you cannot help admitting </seg>
            <seg id="p114">1921 ANNUAL REPORT Twas a humpbacked, crooked shadow if it ever reached the floor. So I sought a clear solution to the shadows' dire confusion, rmy only safe conclusion was that Edgar had the snakes. ram sure he had been drinking and must have had the snakes. rd the Raven sitting, sitting on the cornice, never flitting, With its fiery eyes burning into Edgar's bosom core Was the whiskey he'd been drinking just before ht fell to thinking About his lovely, lost Lenore. It is bug juice, evermor Get 'most anybody frisky on a quart m two of whiskey. And he'd think he saw a raven perched on forty doers, And he wouldn't know a shutter from a dozer Lenore's. It is my profound opinion that had Po« but dominion O'er his brain and o'er his reason as he'd often dt before, Had he only been less frisky and had guzzled dow less whiskey, He would never have seen the raven nor the shadow on the floor. Maybe he'd been on a bust the night before, ar had got soher I will close by giving you one of Riley's poems "Like His Mother l/sed to Make "I was born in Indiany," says a stranger, lank and slim As us fellers in the restarunt was kindo' guying him, And Uncle Jake was slidin' him another punkin pie And a' extry cup o' coffee, with a twinkle in his eye — "I was born in Indiany — more'n forty year ago — And I hain't ben back in twenty — and I'm workin' back'ards slow; But I've et in ever' restarunt 'twixt here and Santy Fee, And I want to state this coffee tastes like gittin home, to me. Nevermore. (Laughter and applaust </seg>
            <seg id="p115">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 115 'Pout \.-speakin' 'crost a saucerfull, as Uncle tuck his cup — Jt yander," he went on, to ffee like yer mother used to her, and the Posey county farm ks she set the pot a-bilin', broke the eggs and poured 'em in K And I'ncle .lake he fetched the feller's coffee back, and fer a minute, as a' undertaker would; rto' turned and tiptoed to'rds the kitchen door — &gt;ld wife out with him, a-rubbin' of her sp. jshcs fer the stranger, and she hollers out, "I'ts \ m (1ml we've met him comin'- — Don't you know yer mother, Jim ?" cller. as he grabbed her, says, "You bet I hain't wipin' of his eyes, says he, "yer coffee's mighty ire so many things Riley wrote we pass up and never notice their Several things have been handed to me lately. I have so many nds who write and send clippings, so I get a chance to col - • wonderful thinps. In my travels I have always undertaken to Is as I go. In '93 I had to take to the road in order to save our and there I met with Charles Russell, the cowboy artist. It f re I had the opportunity to get the best collection of his paint- ings found in any private gallery, I believe. I ran onto him on the plat - form at Chinook, Montana. I said to the conductor, "Will you please hold the train," and he did. Russell does not bear any resemblance to these long haired artists of the movies, but he is made of the right stuff. "NoUh It on de Palin' You can notch it on de palin' as a mighty risky plan To put your judgment on de clothes dat covers up de man, And dere's no need ob my tellin' you dat you'll often come across A fifty dollar saddle on a twenty dollar hoss. ther. Daddy," says the feller, warmin' uKain, a-hanein' on her arm r kindo' halted, with a trimble in his chin: </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 1921 ANNUAL REPORT the you And a walkin' in de cornfield you'll discover as you go, That sometimes de finest shuck hides the meanest nubbin in de row I never judges people that I meets upon de way By the places where dey come from or de houses where dey stay For de bantam chicken's fond ob rocstin' mighty high, LAnd de turkey buzzard soars above de eagle in de sky; id you'll often find little minnows in de middle ob de sea. And de smallest kind ob possum up de biggest kind ob tree So it is my idea — Wen you see a man in woe, Walk right up and say "Hullo! Say "Hullo," and "How d'ye do!" "How's the world a usin' you?" Slap the fellow on his bark. Bring your han' down with a whack Waltz right up, an' don't pro «low. Grin an' shake an' say "Hullr Hags is but a cotton roll. Jest for wrappin' up a soul. An' a soul is worth a true Hale an' hearty "How d'ye &lt;i&lt; Is he clothed in rags'* 0 sho Walk right up an' say "Hullo W'en big vessels nect, thev si They salute an' sail away. Just the same are you an' mi Lonesome ships upon Kach one sailing his own jop For a port beyond the fog. Let your speakin' trumpet hi &gt;w Lift your horn an" cry "Hullo Say "Hullo" an' "How d'ye dc Other folks are good as you. W'en you leave your house of clay Wanderin' in the Far-Away, W'en you travel through the strange Country t'other side the range, Then the souls you've cheered will know Who you be, an' say "Hullo : " (Applause THE TOASTM ASTER: Mr. Risdon is a busy business man. a:.d we appreciate his taking time off to entertain us A visitor in the home of a colored man in Georgia remarked on efficiency of this colored man's wife. "That's a hard-workine wife hcve, Sambo." "Yes, suh; I wish I had two mo' like her." i Laughter.) </seg>
            <seg id="p117">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 117 cr f; 1 ■ it- pleasure of listening 1 to the United States re yesterday, could not help but wish we had our program this year. We did not know at the ivileged to keep this representative with us un - that reason his name does not appear on oar laditional thing with the Dairy Association that a !&gt;ettt'i- and larger program than we publish. So lis opportunity of calling on Mr. McDowell, who Farmer of the Future." M. -DOWELL. Washington, D. C: Where he left off is had two sons, John and George. Both desired to r father found it necessary to keep one at home. In ■ t&gt;&lt;&gt;y&gt; might have equal opportunities, he decided to send r while George remained at home, and the next year send John stayed on the farm. In that way each would fln- jcatk rst year in college, John made rapid progress, and in her achievements, he became engaged to a very beauti- iy. As he was about to go back home he told his sweet - arrangement his father had made, and said he hoped she pleasant for George the next year. and enrolled and began his class work. One evening he his brother's fiancee. Before he had an opportunity to was met in the hallway by a perfect vision of light of the hall, she thought her lover had re- Throwing her arms about his neck, she said, "I am so glad you e back'" s soon as George could recover, he replied, " I am not John, but ut if this is where John left off. it is where I would HVe to Laughter.) And for just a few minutes I would like to talk to you about "The Farmer of the Future." We have heard a great deal at these meetings about the dairymen of present. I would like to talk to you about the farmers of the future. The dairymen of the future will maintain soil fertility, and on ac - unt of the better soil fertility, he will grow big crops and feed these ops to high-producing dairy cows. The soils of Nebraska vary greatly in chemical composition. Every rmer should know something of the food requirements of the crops he producing. With this knowledge he would know what crops can be the present. I would like to talk to you a ind especially the dairynen of the future. </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 1921 ANNUAL REPORT sold. The farmer who sells the article that will brintr th&lt; reati cial returns may make money for the generations. time at the ex pen There was a farmer in South Daki moved so many times in ■ covered \v covered wagon, they would hold up thrown in. (Laughter.) ■t.i who hail solil f ngon that when his their feet in order hickt at LWhat constitutes soil fertility intain the chemical oompositior The idea has been advanced that ei Some say weeds make the trouble the soil moisture, and others emph; from plant diseases transmitted rh: \s ains 1- crop j&gt; Tim 'a- the tremend&lt; nvade the soil. Alkali soils are common ir *■ \ Wl western states; but the absence of lem, and the dairy cow will keep t The dair\ farm feed them to high-produ advantage than we are i we are advertising A certain Professor in the &lt;• tells how he acquir f. were first placed on the mar wheat biscuits. He tried them some to his dog but the torn &lt;1 advertisement again, and he bou day the Professor liked ther it all. The Professor kept out, and finally he learned to like t the difference was he could read and "It pays to advertise Do you know an acre of land w I milk; that a ton of hay and a bush in the form of milk, and a dollar will buy more food in tr than in the form of any other animal pro&lt; Do you know you can run as far and climb as hijrh and work as bag on a quart of milk as on a pound of beef The farmer of the future will use more mi fanner of today. He will be the gainer by it Miss Hoover of our Department, who has char it- the milk can paig-n work, says there is more undernourishment among he children of the rich than amontr the children of the poor; that there is more undt nourishment among the children on the farms than amon the city chil Prof. Cyril Hopkin if the soil ami M </seg>
            <seg id="p119">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 119 *nd it wouldn't if we would use more ■xptt-t the city people to buy milk and nn afford to use it freely on nilk wil juntrv. \ with me more milk r Tout that I wrote a short nint. We hail a picture taken to T ttle triil with a irlass of milk in her hand. As in it up to the other children gathered around her, she recites \ Toast to Milk, that sweet, rich drink. hen give us milk, so pure and mild lart each day for every child i a half ago I w asked by the Boy Scouts of Amer- ;e a booklet on the subject on Dairying for the Boy Scouts. In riting the Scouts' Toast to Milk. We had a picture of a Boy Scoot iimr a glass of milk. As he addressed the other Boy Scouts about him TY healthy Scout, strong, vigorous and active. I must ove to drink delicious milk fresh from a healthy cow, he - al, sweet, and pure, and because it gives me a clear n. and powerful muscles. The bony framework of my iilt from the lime and phosphates; my muscles from its pro- Its sugar me warm and give me power, and its limes w T li and milk, and milk toast. But I like ?rved alont iest w . then, fellow Scouts of America, come, let us have another Ik." (Applause.) Mr. Toastmaster. I am handicapped for lack of words. If I had the loquence of Demosthenes I would write the story or milk j n words of irold and illustrate every page with r cold and illustrate every page with r irtures of healthy children, and use tures of healthy children, and use photogTaphs of laughing babies to t photographs of laughing babies t ive it a halo of plory, and send it a halo of glory, and send it forth into every nook and corner of forth into every nook and corner of this fair land of ours to teach my this fair land of ours to teach my fellow countrymen milk makes childi The farmer of the future will fellow countrymen milk makes child en jrrow. (Applause.) irrow. (Applause.) The farmer of the future will lot only use more milk and set a only use more milk and set a better table than the farmer of today better table than the farmer of today , hut he will have more money with hut ho will have more money with which to provide better schools, "hurches, and homes npth to work and power to think jportunity to do a little advertising for milk by i and milk, mush </seg>
            <seg id="p120">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 120 A small Ohio school boy was asked to write a composition al&gt;ou Patrick Henry. He wrote: "He was horn; went to tchool; married, and cried, 'Give me liberty or uive me death : '" (Laughter As liberty was the doimnai.t though in gent service should be the leading thought of this age. The thill ul teach us how to live, and the school shou r to make a living. In muscular power we ran never compete with the ox. W this world through the power future will be adequate for the needs r consolidated rural scho&lt; Fond recollections seen do I remember my own school days in central \\ part of the room sto&lt; mornings drove the ft front row, while tr warm. It was in m the expressior around the hous In most par one just like it. Ir prominent as We will have ed and let us no that taught us to at but neglected to tea. I these things Benjamin Frank! gclden age of invention. 1 we are living at the beginr that age the farmer will hav At the present time he has the Ford, i Laughter. ) In the near futu gas or electricity and it will be as Why shouldn't he have these things? Is for them? Can't he enjoy them' What is the trouble? T very much like other people. The farnu w ford these comforts, and he will have them. TV do all these things because he will kno iV I travel quite extensively for Ur living in comfort on the swamp lands of northern Minnesota. I have serr luxurious farm homes in the swamps of northern Wisconsin, and I h seen the farmers making money in Mid in various parts of Nebraska. I think the ability tn farm successfully &lt;■• depends primarily in knowing how. ( Applause. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">K \ \IRYMEN"S ASSOCIATION 121 \ 1 will leave it to you as to whether ( Applause.) huted more to the success of these :hings accomplished during his ad- I think it is especially fitting he I little while nn "Our Dairy Asso - sident. H. A. Morrison. (Applause.) I'i OIK DAim ASSOCIATION." ry individual in the room knows professional men in giving a toast ht to feel, and if you do not believe I feel &gt;u a chance to take my place. (Laughter.) tribute that was given to Mother, I would &gt;n. It has been expressed here and proven ?ain as to what the milk diet will do for al and physiological side is concerned. It Ahat it will do for me child as far as the (1. After this tribute given to Mother, 1 t. think about: When you can bring he moral power ot tnat cnud aim r different states jther day of a suburbanite going home from The car had been blocked and it was 12:10 station, lie stopped into the telegraph office and send to his office girl the next morning: "1 will not home yesterday yet." I Laughter. ( was about the condition of most of ht my wife along tonight, and she Van Norman who said to us today this group groups of men; that they are not ther kinds of business; that we were selfish. I would like to say this We ouurl- ft ame out very indignantly to the mi farmer and You are just as bad and as dishonest as all the rest MORRISON, Collcg« View: Mr. President. tnai parted pnysique anu peneci brain, you lower men and women ntiing tnese iu'ht. If that is so. I will have to </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 1921 ANNUAL REPORT of the men — you farmeis. We know our milk men— those who are the business of distributing — water the milk, but we never knew bet that you farmers watered the milk.' "What do you mean'. 1 ' "1 saw it with m. 1 hired nu to water just before hi Laughter. If this group is not nu connection with that- spei the State of Nebraska. .V Association — I tnin ,' state; but it oug be. There are many t number of those, will not take ti quoted and statistics stales, 1 Mi sure n that number; thus \ of Nebra^ Ka with th made of d:iiry cows d you, and 1 can go airy State if )tt h f I am sure it would In tempting to develop i tr ness than any other busnio.-. » Some of &lt;iui farmer! Bad po think thai the other lines of I pockets. It reminds me of I he loaded car in Not Vmk City I he got in. he began t&lt;&gt; think a large roll of bills. Be slipped said, "Scoundrel!" The utlu i hands. There was another ma: Finally he said, "I would lik you two men please take your h \vh ng his papt \\ (Laugh I think it is true, generally lines of business, "Will you pk th just this one Now, ladies and gentlen thought. There was a young girl just getting into society in the town who had neve? been in the country. Her nd in the country invited f her was very particular. her city friend to visit her. The city (*ii n and her daughter went on to hi splendid things in that country sellish, it ought The farmer today society and ir&gt; guverni he has at last a splemj When wt- stop t&lt; niers are saying to othe nds out of my pockets? </seg>
            <seg id="p123">\K BKASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 123 1 &gt;\ci I IE TO A \ RKSI t &lt; I f asure ier said, "What kind of furniture have they? Has she ty out there?" uuther and said, "I never thought to aak; the Hulsteins and Guernseys. That is all ■u Thai doesn't sound bad. 1 believe they will make ." (Laughter.) u tonight to have your association with the any of the dairy tows and I believe it will ago the Kansas farmers started a race as to who could hog. One man put out a unique poster in front of his all hunting for the largest hog in the State. The If you want to see the largest hog in the State of me." (Laughter.) to say, and I believe the business is worthy of it, that Association and the dairy business in the State of Ne- l able to say in a few years to come: "If you wan: greatest business in this State, come to visit us." Applause.) TMASWt: Before turning this meeting back into the ■sident, 1 want to assure you dairymen of Nebraska that reflated the many courtesies you have shown me during 1 have had the privilege of working with you. This program and 1 must turn the gavel back to President Li DENT: Dean Van Norman brought before you the work flMS, and the suggestion he is out soliciting money, and gram. It is up to us whether we care to participate he Nebraska Dairy Association will be a part of this work. It is almost too late to discuss this. This work ne. The whole thing came without my having n&lt;l the same is probably true of each of you. If whereby we can handle this tonight, I would from him; otherwise I think we should turn it over Directors and ask them to work out the problem. What I </seg>
            <seg id="p124">1921 ANNUAL REPORT 124 PROFESSOR FRANDSEN: I move that the . if breed associations, together with the new president at this Ass act as a committee to take up th in; The motion was second* DEAN VAN XORM..V , matter. While it is ti'-.e m .-t: is not essential it shall be that u we can give each one credit fur a 1 only raise $200. we would is no ironclad rule about the more important part thousand names beintf se possible memberships has thousand names would n&lt; of personnel as well as t chance to come in w. fa names which would not m The motion put by 1 THE PRESIDKNT: I dividuals who participated the splendid convention \\ Good night! </seg>
            <seg id="p125">lAIKYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 125 BRA SKA OIM.K ( OKONA t 1/V I)E .tU6!:t4 is ami 11 days. Her 7-day record Hinds butter; record for 30 days. jtter. Best day milk yield. y-five-day record as follows. 30,250.1 r, average approrimate yield per ng nearly 17 times her weight in 1.01 I' VI KW CORONA, 450466, I division. Milk 20,440 pounds and th em home prown save Oil Meal, W. .1. .lenkinson. Monroe, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 1921 ANNUAL REPORT &gt; LIST OF PRESIDENTS AND SECRETARIES SINCE ASSOCIATU STARTED President Add S. C. Bassett J. Dixon Avery W. G. Whitmore J. C. Merrill C.ibbon. N Fremont, Ni-l Vallev. N 1887 lxxs Sutton, N Inland. X l^n J. W. Livinfchouse D. P. Ashburn.. &lt; ml Gibbon. N 1890 mont, N 1891 J. H. Rushton E. J. Hainer Wm. Sutton W. A. Carpenter B. R. Stouffer F 1892 \ N N TaV i: 18;.:: 1S94 v \ 1895 i \ E. F. Howe 1896 V F. H. Vaufjhn Geo. E. Haskel J. J. King 1897 T 1898 1899 J. J. King IMC IM1 J. H. Rushton E. S. Snivel}- J. K.^ Honeywell C. A." Clark 1902 1903 1904 L. D. Stilson ... E. C. GHssman H. C. Young A. E. Wilkenson A. L. Haeckor Chas. Hardinp E. T. Rector UN 1907 1908 1909 1910 1911 1912 C. F. Schwaper R. W. McGinnis E. M. Little 1918 1914 1915 J. S. Clark 1916 J. H. Frandsen O. A. Severe W. H. Ferguson Jacob Sass 1917 1918 .W \ 1919 1920 H. A. Morrison H. A. Morrison C. J. Furry 1921 n \- \ 1922 Fr </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 ASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION ! NEl The list of wereUriei of the Dairymen's Association is as follows: 1885-1886-1887 H. H. Wing (now of Come 1888-1896 inc. Bassett. Gibbon. Neb 1897-189** Neb \ 1H99-1914 April 1 Net 1914-1919 \t \V MeGinnis. Lincoln. Nel 1919-1920-1921-1922 Nel which was conducted by the Ne- • contest in jud^intr dairy cattle wnun was lonuun.™ -.... Dairymen's Association under the direct supervision of the Dairy iv i-attl nt of the University of Nebraska, was held on lav. .January S, 198S from 9 to 12 A. M. Considerable interest was ti in the contest which was divided into two sections, one for farmers breeder^ and one for students. tees were Mr. K. \V. Frost, and Professors M. N. l&gt;awritson Thoni&gt; sun. Five classes of animals were judged, consisting Holstein cows. Holstein heifer?. iW Ayrshire cow follows Karmvrs and Hreeders Class Coleee View, Neb., silver cup valued at W. ,1. -lenUinson. Monroe. Neli. cash 7.50 View Neb. cash A. .\ Ra Lincoln, Neb. cash 5.50 rsitv \ Neb. cash 1.00 Boettirer, Florence Station. Omaha, cash 3.00 W. H R. K. •"&gt;. Lincoln, Nebr. cash 2.00 Henry. Cambridge. Neb. cash l.nu F. H. Ml Fort Calhoun, Neb. cash $.™.7.-&gt; .;.-,&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 1921 ANNUAL REPORT Student* Cla •s. 1st. Hugh Snyder, Paxton, Neb., silver jp valuet 2d. A. K. Hepperly, Norfolk, Neb. ca h 3d. G. V. Jones, Fairbury, Neb tab 4th. E. L. Clark, Glen Rock, Wyo. n&gt;h 5th. R. B. Walters, Limoln. Nab ish 6th. Frank Flynn, Ulyssi&gt;, Neb a.-h 7th D. E. Lindstrom, Oxford, Nil I- 8th R. F. Tefft, Weepintf Watt Ne •Jth J. C. Adams, Marquette, N 10th. D. Barnes. Loretto, Neb. cash a ToUl w Grand total </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>