<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Tractor Tests</title>
               <date value="18??">January 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">I Bulletin 304 January, 1937 NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1936 BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST,ENGINEERS E. E. Bracken, C. W. Smith, L. W. Hurlbut ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS • : Car/ton L. Ziak ASSISTAKT IN TRACTOR TESTS C. F. Adams Some equipment used in making belt harse power tests. The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 1 General Procedure and Rules in Testing Tractors 4 Belt Tests 5 100% maximum belt tests 5 Operating maximum belt tests . . . . 6 Rated-load belt rest g Varying-load belt test 7 Drawbar Tests y 100% maximum drawbar tests 7 Operating maximum drawbar tests g Rated-load drawbar test g End of Test a. Drawbar Testing Equipment 10 Comments jq Drawbar loading machines jq Interpretation of summary sheet \ \ Horsepower w F.irm Tractor R;ttm« Oklc—A. S. A. E. Jnxl S. A. F. Si.mdard 16 Tractor r.uinp s;x-cirications \( } Tcsiinß procedure jg Fucls 17 Lubricants 17 Bl:l" ¦¦ ... '.' 18 The Law jg Tractor Specifications </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Nebraska Tractor Tests With the close of the testing season for 1936 came the end of the seventeenth year of tractor testing at the University of Nebraska. The num - bers of complete tests conducted and reported for these years are as follows: 1920 1921 1922 1923 1921 1925. 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 1934 1935 1936 Total 65 15 5 12 10 8 12 15 7 16 10 H 12 9 11. 17 28 266 This bulletin summarizes the results of 87 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported: by their manufacturers as on the market January 1,1937, If a tractor has been tested but is not listed in this bul - letin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discon - tinued. •.-•¦¦ '' '; \ .¦.""¦.' ; . ¦ : "'•'•'.¦ All tractors tested are certified by their manufacturers as being stock - model .machines, conformingrto specifications filed with the application for test. No special or high-test fuels are used except as recommended by the manufacturer as necessary.: All results shown on page 1 of the three - page reports are those actually attained in tests and are without correction or allowances for friction, temperature, altitude, etc. These results are ac - complished with the tractor in charge of skilled operators employed by the University. ¦ 1 . . . Beginning with 1928 the Vone carburetor setting" was adopted and all results shown on reports of tests made from 1928 to 1934, inclusive, were obtained with the carburetor adjustment remaining unchanged throughout all parts of the complete test. (In determining the highest drawbar and belt ratings permissible under thejA. S. A. E. and S. A. E. (American Society of Agricultural Engineers and Society of Automotive Engineers) rating code, runs are made at a 100. per cent maximum carburetor setting. The results of these runs appears in the 1935 and 1936 reports. All other runs are made at an "operating setting" which may be 100 per cent, or, as is usually the case, some percentage less than that. The' v"operating setting" appears in Column 10 of the folded summary sheet. A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test is com - pleted, and this bulletin is compiled from these reports and from the specifications filed with the application for test. Copies of the original three-page reports are available at 5 cents per report (on one tractor) from the Department of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. By remitting $1.00 those desiring future reports with - out delay will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. . ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 GENERAL PROCEDURE AND RULES IN TESTING TRACTORS When a manufacturer wishes to test a new tractor, application forms are obtained from the Agricultural Engineering Department of the Uni - versity of Nebraska. These forms call for detailed specifications of the tractor to be tested. They are filled out and returned, together with a request for the assignment of a testing date and check for $500.00 to cover the test fee. Dates for test are tentatively assigned in order in which the application for test, specifications, and testing fee are received. The actual test date depends on the arrival of the tractor and suitable weather conditions. Tractors that are shipped by way of the C. R. I. &amp; P. in Nebraska will be switched to the Agricultural College loading dock with minimum delay. It is assumed that the application for test is made by the tractor com - pany with the knowledge that it is not an experimental but an official performance test to be run under the tractor specifications submitted with the application and under the testing rules in force. One of the rules is that there shall be no revision of specifications after the test starts nor any change of parts or equipment except to make replacement for that which may be defecti\e or broken. Experimentation desired by the manufacturer must be deferred until after the official test is completed and is then con - tingent on available time. All such experimental work is charged to the manufacturer on an hourly basis. Any data and results thus attained are for the information of the manufacturer and will not be included in the official report. A representative of the manufacturer should be present during the test. His duties include unloading the tractor, installing wheel equipment or other accessories, operating the tractor during the "limber-up" run, making such adjustments as he may deem necessary before the test, making repairs when necessary during the test, and at the conclusion of the test disposing of the tractor. In addition to these duties, the manufacturer's representative makes all decisions involving permissible choices or company policy relative to the current test which are not covered in the application for test. Before any tests are made the lubricating oil is drained from the crank - case and is replaced with new oil. This new oil is selected by the manu - facturer's representative from the brands generally available in Nebraska. It is of the viscosity specified in the application for test and is purchased by the Tractor Testing Department in sealed containers. The oil is weighed as well as measured and the weight per gallon at 60° F. is determined. All figures in the test report showing consumption of either oil, fuel, or water injjallons are based on the amounts used in pounds and the weight per gallonat 60° F. The fuel used is the lowest grade recommended by the manufacturer for use in the tractor being tested. For instance, if the application for test states that the tractor will operate on gasoline, kerosene, and distillate, distillate will be used. The gasoline used is of the lowest commercial </seg>
         <seg id="p005">i Nebraska Tractor Tests ... ¦'.'¦' ' i .' ¦'¦¦.¦-¦¦' - grade available and in no case is a premium fuel used in an official test except in those cases where jit is recommended by the manufacturer as being essential to the successful operation of the engine. Fuels and lub - ricants are supplied by the University and charged to the manufacturer at current prices. The first test run is one made on the drawbar and is known as the "limber-up" run. The principal object of this test is to take out the stiff - ness likely to be found in a new machine and give an opportunity to check the condition of the tractor and ascertain if all the parts are working normally. The tractor is operated at approximately one-third load for four hours, two-thirds for four hours, and full load for four hours. A reasonable amount of additional time is granted if desired. Each one of the forward gears is used for some portion of this test. The manufacturer's representative is responsible for the operation of the tractor during this test and may make such adjustments as he may feel are necessary, provided they do not conflict with the Jspecifications in the application for test. Adjustments that are permissible include setting the valve tappet clear - ance and the gap of breaker points or spark plug points, adjusting the dutch, and making other adjustments of a similar nature. This shall not be interpreted to permit the installation of new parts or accessories with - out having the same mentioned in the official report of the test. BELT TESTS The tractor testing engineer then takes charge of the tractor and it is belted to the cradle-mounted Sprague electric dynamometer used in de - termining the belt horsepower. Before any belt horsepower tests are run, the top radiator tank is drilled to take a gas-filled indicating thermometer, a fuel line is installed from tijactor fuel system to the fuel-weighing equip - ment, and measurements are taken of the belt thickness and of the circum - ferences of both the engine and dynamometer pulleys. No allowances are made for belt losses. ; 100% Maximum Belt Test.—The engine is then run at full load until it is thoroughly warmed and has reached a condition of constant operating temperatures. All adjustments are made to secure maximum output from the engine at rated r. p.m. Rated crankshaft speed is that numbei of revolutions per minute recommended by the manufacturer for normal operation. The governor is jet to hold the throttle valve to the extreme open position, the spark is set to give the best results, the manifold heat control, if present, is set at the most favorable position, and the carburetor is carefully adjusted to that point at which an additional amount of fuel gives no increase in power output at the rated speed of the engine. After uniform operating conditions are reached, this test, known as the 100 per cent or rating maximum, is :ontinued for two hours. The object of this test is to check or'establish bi:lt horsepower ratings. At-ten minute intervals headings are taken or observations made of engine belt pulley and brake speed, load on scale beam of dynamometer, </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 temperature of water in top tank of radiator, air temperature at a point approximately rive feet in front of the center of the radiator and amount in pounds of fuel used. Barometer readings are taken every hour. The water level in the radiator is measured at the beginning and at the end of the two-hour period, and the necessary amount of water is added to raise it to the same level as at the start of the two-hour test. Water, if used in the fuel mixture, is checked in the same manner. Results of this test are used in determining the highest belt horsepower rating permissible under the provisions of the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. tractor rating code. This rating is obtained by correcting the observed horsepower to standard conditions (temperature of 60° F. and atmospheric pressure of 29.92 inches of mer - cury) and then multiplying the result by 0.85. This corrected horsepower is sometimes known as sea-level horsepower and is occasionally advertised as such. Many engineers feel that a true comparison of the performance of tractors can be made only by the use of figures corrected to standard tem - perature and pressure conditions. The correction formula used may be found in the A. S. A. ]•;. and S. A. E. Farm Tractor Rating Code, which is included in this bulletin (page 16). I he obscru-d in.tximum horsepower as determined in this initial belt test Ims not appeared in the published report of each test nor in the sum - mary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughout the complete test. On either the first or the third page of the report and in Column 10 of the summary sheet arc figures indicating whether the carburetor setting used was 100 per cent or some lesser value. Operating Maximum Belt Test.—ln case the manufacturer wishes to use a carburetor adjustment leaner than the 101) per cent setting, a series of trial runs of 20 to 5(1 minutes at leaner settings are made and the manufac - turer's representative is permitted to choose from these an "operating set - ting". This operating setting oi the carburetor is used throughout the remainder of the test with the exception of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear (to determine the drawbar rating) when the adjustment used is the 100 per cent maximum power setting as obtained on the belt. The hrst run on this operating setting is a one-hour maximum power test known as the ¦¦operating maximum belt test". The object of this test is to determine the maximum power developed and the fuel consumption at .1 carburetor setting that is practical for held operations. The radiator cover, manifold heat control, and spark arc set at the most favorable posi - tions, the engine is run until operating conditions have become stabilized, and then readings are taken at ten-minute intervals over a one-hour period! Rated Load Belt Test.—The next belt test is of one hour duration and is known as the rated load belt test. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor will carry its rated load in the belt and to secure a record of fuel consumption and other operating data. The tractor is given, </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Neb iaska Tractor Tests as nearly as possible, its rated load. The carburetor remains set at the operating setting. The go'ernor is adjusted to maintain rated engine speed at rated load. Rated load is determined in one of two ways. If the tractor is rated by the manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horsepower at rated engine speed. In case the manufacturer either does not specify the rating ot the tractor or elects to accept the highest belt horsepower rating permissible under the tractor rating code, then rated load becomes 85 per cent of the corrected maximum as calculated from the results of the 100 per cent maximum belt test. Varying Load Belt Tes:.—The last run on the belt is known as the varying-load test. All adjustments are as in the rated-load test. The object of this test is to shov the governor control of the speed and also fuel consumption when the load varies. It is comprised of six twenty - minute runs made in the fo lowing order: The first is rated load, which is the same load as the one-hour rated load test just completed; in fact, if conditions are favorable, the rated arid varying load tests are continuous and the last twenty minutes of the rated-load run are used for the first twenty of the varying-load est. This is followed by twenty minutes at no load. The minimum load is applied and the power developed ordinarily is something less than one horsepower. The next load applied is one-half of the rated-load torque and this is followed by a maximum horsepower test in which enough load is applied on the dynamometer to pull the engine far enough under ratei speed to insure an extreme throttle opening. The last two runs are mad: at one-fourth and three-fourths rated load torque respectively. : During the varying-load est the amount of heat applied to the intake manifold may be changed :ccording to the load if an easily controlled manual adjustment, such as a lever operating from the driver's seat, is provided. An effort is made to maintain the recommended temperature of the cooling medium when passible, by regulating the amount of covering on the radiator in those cases where an adjustable cover is provided. These adjustments, we feel, require no more attention than may reasonably be expected from a careful opeiator. When possible, the friction horsepower and the compression pressure at rated engine speed are checked at the end of the varying-load test. These figures do not appear in the report of the test. ' ;| -:.-¦ -. '. ."¦.¦¦ ¦¦¦ -' : ¦ DRAWBARTESTS 100% Maximum Drawbar Tests.—The first drawbar tests made are maximum horsepower runs it two carburetor settings, operating and 100 per cent. The 100 per cent naximum test is made in one gear only, that designated by the manufacturer as most suitable for plowing or ordinary farm work. It is commonly known as "plow gear", "working gear" or "rated gear". The results oi:. test in this gear, with the carburetor adjusted at 100 per cent as found or the belt, are used to determine the.highest drawbar horsepower rating permissible under the provisions of the A. S. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 A. E. and S. A. E. tractor rating code. The observed 100 per cent maxi - mum drawbar horsepower is corrected to standard conditions, multiplied by 0.75 and the result is the code rating. The results of this rating maxi - mum test have not appeared in the published report of each test nor in the summary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughout the complete test. The manufacturer's representative is permitted to select the wheel, lug, and extension-rim equipment from that supplied on stock tractors or that regularly offered to the trade in Nebraska but at extra cost. The same wheel and lug equipment must be used on all the drawbar tests. When drawbar tests are made on rubber tires, additional weight may be placed on the rear wheels or rear of the tractor. The total weight on the rear wheels is not to be in excess of the tire manufacturer's recommendations. In the case of the crawler tractors, a choice may be made in the type and width of track and the type and size of cleats, subject to the same restric - tions as obtain for wheel and lug equipment. The drawbar specifications as to dimensions and adjustments for height and point of attachment must be the same tor all of the drawbar tests. They must also conform to the specifications in the application for test. Operating Maximum Drawbar Tests.—Operating maximum drawbar tests are made in the forward gears, using the operating carburetor setting selected and used on the operating belt tests. The object of these tests is to determine the maximum horsepower the tractor will develop in each forward gear with the carburetor adjusted at the operating setting with engine running at rated speed under the prevailing temperature and barometric conditions. After the tractor is thoroughly warmed and brought to a condition of constant operating temperatures, at least two suitable drawbar runs arc secured over a measured distance of 500 feet on the testing track. A suitable run is one in which the operating temperatures are normal, the throttle is open to the extreme position, the load is relatively constant, and the average engine speed is at or very close to that specified by the manufacturer. The tractor rating code recommends that the average engine r. p. m. be maintained within 5 per cent of its rated full load speed. Very seldom is a pull used in which the variation from rated speed is more than 1 per cent and in each test in each gear an attempt is made to obtain an average r. p. m. which does not deviate from rated speed more than '/2 of 1 per cent. Rated Load Drawbar Test—The last run made on the drawbar is the rated-load test. The duration of test is ten hours' actual running time (as nearly continuous as possible) with constant load. A record is made ¦ of the time and reason for each stop, and also of any adjustment or repairs made on the tractor. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor can pull its rated load continuously and to secure a record of fuel consumption on drawbar work. The governor is adjusted to give rated speed of the engine with the tractor pulling rated load and in the gear </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests recommended for plowing or ordinary farm work. The carburetor remains at the operating setting. Ra ed load is determined in one of two ways. If the tractor is rated by th: manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horsepower at ated engine speed in rated gear. In case the manufacturer either does not specify the rating of the tractor or elects to accept highest drawbar horsi:-power rating permissible under the tractor rating code, then rated load b :comes 75 per cent of the corrected maximum as calculated from the result; of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear. Once each hour during the rated-load drawbar test a chart is taken, by means o£ the graphic recorcing drawbar dynamometer, of the drawbar pull; observations are made of the time required to travel 500 feet, the revolutions of the drive wheels over flu's same measured course, and the temperature of the air aid cooling medium. From the chart and observations, calculations are made for the drawbar pull in pounds, the rate of travel in feet per minute and miles per hour, the drawbar horse - power, the engine revolutions per minute, and the drive wheel slippage in percentage. The testing oper itor maintains the load as nearly constant as possible and by following th: progress of the test applies such a load as will be sufficient to develop horsepower equal to or slightly in excess of rated horsepower. ]:ndoftest At the conclusion of the rated-load drawbar test the lubricating oil is drained from the crankcase and weighed,, the specific gravity at 60° is determined, and the number of gallons drained is calculated. A record is kept throughout the test of al oil added or drained. The test report shows the total number of gallons oi new oil put in the crankcase and the gallons of used oil drained. At this time the tractor i; inspected. This inspection is not extensive if the tractor is apparently ;n normal condition. Particular attention is centered on spark plugs and valves, loose parts and leakage of fuel, water, and lubricants. The manufacturer's representative, when so directed by the engineer in charge, disassembles any part of the tractor or its acces - sories in order to facilitate in; pection. During the drawbar tests, or on their completion, the tractor is driven to a government-inspected faim scale on the Agricultural College campus and-weighed.* The weight wl ich appears in the test report is the observed weight plus the weight of th: operator and the amount of fuel necessary to completely fill the fuel tan c. : When all of the tests have been completed and the inspection made, the engineer in charge may relea e the tractor to the manufacturer's represen - tative or at his discretion ma' withhold the release until the test report is issued. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 DRAWBAR TESTING EQUIPMENT Comments.— All of the drawbar pull exerted by the tractor being tested is transmitted, by suitable equilizers and a hydraulic piston-cylinder mechanism called a draft unit, to the drawbar load. The pressure in the draft unit is carried through flexible metal tubing to the draft-recording instrument. The essential mechanism of this draft-recording unit is a gas - engine pressure indicator which has been so adapted to the requirements that it leaves on a special chart a continuous record of the drawbar pull of the tractor. From this chart, showing the pull in pounds, and from stop - watch readings showing the time of travel over a measured course, the horsepower developed is calculated. Rotary switches having ten contact points are attached to each drive wheel and connected to magnetic counters which record to one-tenth of one revolution the number of revolutions made over a measured distance. From these same readings are calculated the engine speed and the drive wheel or track slippage. In determining the slippage the tractor is driven without any drawbar load for a distance sullicicnt to nive at least 11) revolutions of the drive wheels or crawler tracks. I!m distance is then accurately measured and is used as a basis for computing wheel slippage. The computations are as follows: 1 he distance covered at no load is divided by the number of drive - wheel revolutions to obtain the number of feet advanced per revolution. Jlic number of revolutions made in advancing 500 feet is recorded by the electric counters. This number multiplied by the feet of advance per revo - lution at no load gives the distance the tractor would have traveled had there I't-en no loss due to slippage. However, the tractor actually advances only 500 feet. The di/Tcrcnce between these two distances is divided by ihc former, and Ihe answer multiplied by 101) is the percentage of slippage. I When speaking of rubber tire tests, soim prefer to use the term, "travel reduction '.) Drawbar Loading Machines.—ln determining the drawbar horsepower of a tractor, it is necessary to provide a source of load which may be readily varied. I lie loading machine, winch is used in the major portion of the tests, is built about a McCormick -Dccring 15-30 tractor. A gear type pump is mounted on the platform and driven by a roller chain from a special sprocket which replaces the brake pulley. The discharge line of the pump is carried up and forward to valves mounted on the top of the radiator. These valves may be closed or opened to increase or decrease the amount of (rawer absorbed by the pump. A return line from the lower radiator connection to the inlet opening of the pump completes the system. Addi - tional load may he obtained by placing the tractor in gear and operating the engine against compression without fuel or ignition. If a light load is desired, the tractor may be placed in gear, the fuel and ignition turned on, and the throttle set to give such assistance as will result in the desired load. 1 he design of this equipment is not original except as improvements have been made from time to time. The International Harvester Com- </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Nebr iska Tractor Tests pany had built two similar machines and at the time the Tractor Testing Department heeded a new machine were able to furnish the plans and part of the special equipment necessary to make the conversion. Another loading machine built about a pneumatic-tired 15-30 Mc- Cormick-Deering tractor was first used in the 1936 testing season. The rear wheel equipment has been changed to dual zero-pressure tires for the 1937 season. A four-speed tn nsmission mounted in the power line from the tractor rear wheels to the gear-type pump, permits; the use of this machine at travel speeds up to approximately 25 miles per hour. Still another machine, a smaller oni:, has a range of load from about 200 pounds to 1,600 pounds and a possible top speed of 40 miles per hour. The essen - tial parts of this machine arethe rear axle assembly and transmission from a heavy-type passenger carj a iear-type pump, a radiator and fan, a supply tankj and suitable controls. ; A close coupled four-wheeled vehicle, called the instrument car, is used to carry the recording instrunents and an observer. A: small gear, pump mounted on this chassis, and driven by the rear wheels through a reversed transmission, provides drawbar load for the very small tractors. INTERPRETATION OF SUMMARY SHEET Name, Col. I.—The engine name as it appears in the body of the summary report is the name by which it was known when the tractor was tested. If it has been changed, the same has been noted below. Horsepower Rating by Manufacturer, CoL'2.—This is a figure deter - mined by the manufacturer a: being a reasonable output for the engine. The figure appearing first is the drawbar rating and the second is the belt rating. .-.-•: . . Horsepower Rating by Cole, Col. 3.—The A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. codes have been quite generall i accepted as the standard for tractor rating. The figures are somewhat less than the maximum horsepower output of the tractor in order that the operator may be sure of having a certain amount of reserve for emergencies. The belt horsepower rating is 85 per cent of the maximum corrected horsepower as obtained in test B and the drawbar horsepower rating is !'5 per cent of the maximum corrected draw - bar horsepower determined in test F. Weight as Tested, Col. 4.--This is the weight of the tractor and full fuel tank, full radiator, operator, and such attachments as are necessary in the testing procedure. The to:al weight of these attachments varies from 10 to 25 pounds. Rated R. P. M., CoL 7.—ln this column appears the speed recom - mended by the manufacturer : s the rated engine speed. In some instances a range of speeds may be recommended but for the purposes of this test it is necessary that some one rated speed be selected by the manufacturer. The manufacturer's specifications as to drawbar pull, rate of ground travel, pulley speed, and belt horsepower are all based on the rated engine speed. Fuel Used, Col. 9.— The manufacturer specifies the grade of fuel that may be used in a tractor. In the event that machines are sold to burn </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 several grades of fuel, the lowest grade is used. High-test or special fuels are used only when recommended by the manufacturer as being necessary to the successful operation of the engine. Carburetor Adjustment for Percentage of Maximum, Col. 10.—A tractor is not ordinarily required to develop its maximum horsepower. There is a point in the range of the carburetor adjustment where the tractor will develop nearly its maximum horsepower and still use considerably less fuel than it docs at the point of maximum output. This point is determined by running a series of belt tests at various carburetor settings. The manu - facturer's representative then selects some carburetor adjustment as the operating setting. It is determined by dividing the horsepower obtained at this point —the point of operating setting—by the horsepower at the 100 per cent setting and multiplying the result by 100. This percentage figure appears in column 10. Oil, Cols. 11, 12, 13.—The viscosity of the lubricating oil used con - forms to the manufacturer's specifications and the brand is one selected by the manufacturer's representative from those available in Nebraska. The gallons of oil placed in and drained from the motor are calculated figures obtained from observations of weight and the specific gravity of the new and used oil. Belt Horsepower, Cols. 15, 23. —In these columns are figures indicating the horsepower delivered at the end of the belt under the conditions ex - isting at the time of the test. See pages 13 to 16 for detailed explanation of horsepower. Average Engine Revolutions per Minute, Cols. 16, 24, 36.—An attempt is made to maintain such loads and such governor adjustments on rated runs .is will result in a deviation of not more than one per cent from rated speed. Fuel Economy Figures, Cols. 17, 18, 19, 25, 26, 27, 40, 41, 42—The amount of fuel used is expressed in three ways. The first term used is gallons per hour. Comparisons with other tractors as to relative economy arc not readily made with this expression of fuel consumption, because the amount ot power developed is not included in the term. Two other expressions of fuel economy, horsepower hours per gallon and pounds per horsepower hour, both allow direct comparison to be made between two machines. A horsepower hour is the term applied to the arithmetical result of horsepower multiplied by time in hours. Ten horse - power hours might come from the development of ten horsepower for one hour, from one horsepower for ten hours, from two and one-half horse - power for four hours, or from any other combination of horsepower and hours which, when multiplied together would equal ten. Then, if by the burning of a gallon of fuel one engine is able to develop eight horsepower hours and another burning the same amount of the same fuel will develop eleven horsepower hours, obviously the second engine has the better fuel economy. In other words, the larger the number of horsepower hours per gallon, the better the fuel economy. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">•¦.-. ¦ Nebraska Tractor Tests The third term, pounds per horsepower hour, expresses the amount of fuel used to develop one horsepower for one hour. The smaller this value, the better is the fuel economy. Pounds per horsepower hour may be readily converted into horsepower hours per gallon by dividing the weight of a gallon of the fuel used by the consumption in pounds per horsepower hour; or, conversely, dividing pounds per gallon by horsepower hours per gallon gives pounds per honepower hour. Water Used, Cols. 20,21), 43.—These figures indicate the amount of water used in the cooling system and, where water is used with the fuel mixture, includes that also. Temperatures, Cols. 21, 22, 29, 30, 44, 45.—The atmospheric tempera - ture as recorded is the avenge for the test. There may be considerable variation of temperature from the beginning to the end of the run, par - ticularly on the ten-hour rat&lt;d-load drawbar test. The cooling medium is maintained as nearly as possible at the temperature recommended by the manufacturer. Only such accessories as are standard equipment are used to maintain this regulation. . Varying-Load Revolution! per Minute (High and Low), Cols. 31, 32.— These are the extremes of tie crankshaft revolutions per minute for the varying load, test E, as obtained with the variation of load applied to the tractor. The figures are an indication of the governor control of the motor speed. . '¦-.... Drawbar Horsepower, Cols. 33, 46,.49, 52, 55, 58, 61.—1n these columns are figures indicating the anount of horsepower delivered at the drawbar under the conditions existin;; at the time of the test. See pages 13 to 17 for detailed explanation of horsepower. . ' Drawbar Pull, Cols. 34, 17, 50, 53, 56, 59, 62.—These figures are the average pull exerted by the tractor under die described conditions. Miles per Hour, Cols. 35, 48, 51, 54, 57, 60, 63.—These speeds are calculated from observations of the time required to travel, while pulling the described load, a distance of 500 feet. : Slip of Drivers, Col. 37.--These are average slippage figures. The manner in which they are obtained is discussed under "Drawbar Testing Equipment." " HORSEPOWER Horsepower is a rate of d sing work, and work is a force acting through a distance. For instance, a farce of 150 pounds acting through a distance of 10 feet would do 1,500 foe t pounds of work. However, unless we know the length of the time in wiich the work is done, we do not know how much power is developed. If, in one case, the work is done in two minutes and in another only one minute is required, then the amount of power developed is twice a: great in the second instance as in the first. To develop one horsepower ijt would be necessary to do 33,000 foot pounds of work in one minute or 550 foot pounds in one second. Drawbar Horsepower.-—J uppose we wish to determine the drawbar horsepower required to pul a three-bottom plow three miles per hour. First, we shall have to assun e that the draft per 1 bottom is some value, let </seg>
         <seg id="p014">NtBRViM A(,KIC I I.TIKAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 304 us s;iy 600 pounds. This, of course, will vary with the type and condition of soil, the depth and rate of plowing, and the condition and adjustment ot the plow. If each bottom has a draft of 600 pounds, then the total pull required is 1,800 pounds. One mile per hour equals 88 feet per minute and three miles per hour equals 264 feet per minute. Then 1,800 pounds acting through a distance of 264 feet in one minute equals 475,000 foot pounds of work done per minute, and 475,000 divided by 33,000 equals 14.4(1 horsepower. If it were desired to pull the same number of pounds half .is fast as before, then only 7.20 horsepower would be needed. If the r.ilc of travel were twice as fast, or six miles per hour, then 28.80 horsc - |K&gt;wer, would be required to pull the 1,800-pound load. The work done at the drawbar or on the belt is known as useful work. Von useful work is done in moving the tractor, in flexing the belt about the pulleys, in slippage Ixiih of the drive wheels and of the belt, and in lAircuminj; friction in gears and bearings. Improved gear and bearing desipi and materials, as well as reduction of tractor weight, have brought the useful ilr.iubar horsepower of the modern tractor much closer to the lx It horsepower than w.is true in the early models. Work also is done in overcoming the inlerial friction (if the engine caused by piston-cylinder uiliUit. connecting rod and main bearing friction, and the resistance of Mtlicr moving f.iriv lln use nl rubber nrc. reduces the rolling resistance of a tractor, or in oiher words, less power is required to move the tractor over the ground than "hen steel wheels and lugs are used. This leaves more engine power .iv.ul.ible (&lt;&gt;r useful «nrk at the drawbar and accounts for the superior luel economy ot rubber mcr steel, particularly in the higher gears. Belt Horsepower. -The point of maximum available horsepower of an engine is .ii the llywheel. Few current tractors are designed, however, so th.it ihe Mi pulley may be attached directly to the flywheel. The belt horsepower must pass through one set of gears and sometimes more before u is delivered to the belt. The belt horsepower figures shown in our re - ports arc obtained after the power has been transmitted through the belt .hi.) the driven pulley and they represent the amount of power available lor useful belt work. In an analysis of belt horsepower, there are the same factors—force, distance, and time—as in drawbar horsepower. Force is represented by the number of pounds of effective tension in the belt and the other two. distance and time, are the number of feet of belt travel per minut^. The rate of belt travel will he controlled by the size and speed of the'tractor belt pulley. For each revolution of the pulley the belt will be advanced a distance equal to the circumference of the pulley. Then, the revolutions per minute of the tractor belt pulley multiplied by the pulley circumference will equal the belt travel in feet per minute. This is assuming there will be no belt slippage. Actually the slippage will vary from \ per cent to 5 per cent and with any given load will depend on the tightness of the belt as well as the size and condition of both pulleys and belt. With few exceptions the belt slippage on the official tests is held to 1 per cent or less. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor.Tests : ¦ While manufacturers have used a fairly uniform belt travel throughout their own line of equipmem, belt speeds as found on the various makes range from 2,450 to 3,400 feet per minute. This often proves troublesome and confusing to the operator, who may have a tractor made by one manufacturer and belt-driven machines purchased from one or more other concerns. .'"¦'., ...... "*¦•'• For instance, of, two popular general-purpose-type tractors of the 2-3 plow size on the market, tractor A has a belt speed of 2,450 feet per minute and tractor B 3,300 feet per minute. Here is an example of what may and quite often does happen. Tractor A is used to operate an ensilage cutter which is designed to run at 650 r.p.m. If we divide the belt travel, 2,450, by 650, the result is the circumference of the cutter pulley, or 3.77 feet. The circumference of a circle equals the diameter times 3.1416 or expressed in a formula: : ,/. .. • c—np v ¦¦'...'¦:.¦, where C = circumference •-. ! = 3.1416 ¦... • : ¦ ¦ ! D = diameter Then it is also true that ¦ j ¦ ,r,r v -¦.¦; j pwc/it .. . Then 3.77 feet, the cutter' pulley circumference, divided by 3.1416 equals 1.20 feet, or, multiplied by 12, approximately 14'/j inches. Either a 14-or a 15-irich pulley might be used on the cutter, although the smaller size would be preferable since it would run a little faster and compensate for belt slippage. . I '.-.;' ¦.;¦¦. ."..'. '"¦.•..'•• Suppose now that,; for one reason or another, the operator wishes to use tractor lion the cutter and he does not change the cutter pulley to the proper size. If he selected a'l4-inch cutter pulley for tractor A, then the circumference in feet is 14 X 3.1416 divided by 12, which equals 3.67 feet. But tractor B's belt speed is 3,300 feet per minute and 3,300 divided by 3.67 equals 899 revolutions per minute or an overspced of approxi - mately 250 revolutions, j .' .¦''¦'¦ The power needed to operate the fan represents quite an appreciable part of the total power requirements of an ensilage cutter. An overspced of 35 to 40 per cent would probably not affect the cutting mechanism a great.deal, but the fan would consume from two to two and one-half times as much power as at the rated speed. This means that tractor B would be able to operate the cutter at only a fraction of its normal capacity, since the excessive (power requirements of the higher fan speed would leave less power available to cut the ensilage. If the fan blast at 650 r.p.m. is sufficient to blow the ensilage into the silo, then power is wasted if the fan is run at a higher rate. An alternative would be) to reduce the tractor engine speed to about 70 or 75 per cent of its rated value. The cutter would then run at the proper speed but the engine power at this reduced speed would be so much less that the cutter could not be operated at normal.capacity. The </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Acriclltijul Experiment Station- Bulletin 304 logical thing to do would be to install on the cutter a 19- or 20-inch pulley, because 3,300 ¦*¦ 650 = 5.08 feet and 5.08 X 12 -h 3.1416 = 19.40 inches Proper pulley sizes are very important on many machines other than ensilage cutters. Some of those more sensitive to speed changes are the threshers, hullcrs. hammer grinders, and irrigation pumps. Many others are affected to .i lesser degree. FARM TRACTOR RATING CODE A. S. A. E. AND S. A. E. STANDARD TRACTOR RATING SPECIFICATIONS Belt Rating.—The belt horsepower rating of the tractor shall not exceed eighty-five (85) per cent of the maximum corrected horsepower which the engine will maintain by belt at the brake or dynamometer for 2 hours at rated engine r. p. m., the test to be carried out as specified herein. Drawbar Rating.-The drawbar rating of the tractor shall not exceed seventy-five (75) per cent of the maximum corrected drawbar horsepower developed at a rate of travel recommended for the ordinary operation of the tractor, under conditions of testing as specified herein. TESTING PROCEDURE Nature of Tests.—The following rating tests are to be conducted in the order given on three nr more tractors picked at random from factory stock run by the engineer or engineers conducting the test; the averages of all tests are to be used in determining the results. Test A (Limbering-up Run).—Before a test is undertaken it is import - ant that the tractor shall have been in operation for a sufficient length of time to attain proper operating conditions throughout so that the results of the test shall express the true working performance. The tractor or tractors to be tested shall therefore be submitted to "limbering-up" runs on the drawbar of 12 or more hours' duration. Drawbar loads of approximately one-third, two-thirds, and full load shall be pulled by the tractor during the runs, each load being drawn for approximately an equal length of time, the lighter loads being used first. Test B (Maximum Brake Horsepower Test).-The tractor engine is to be tested in the belt with the governor set to give full opening of governor valve, and the carburetor set to give maximum power at rated engine crankshaft speed. (The rated speed is that which the manufacturer recommends for the engine under normal load.) The test shall begin after the temperature of the cooling fluids and other operating conditions have become practically constant. The duration of this test shall be two hours of continuous running with no change in engine adjustments. If the speed should change sufficiently during the test to indicate that the operating conditions had not become constant when the test was started </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests the t;.st will be repeated with the necessary change in load. (The term "load", as used in this connection, means pounds on dynamometer or brake scale.) Minor changes in load to be made to maintain rated speed and the average load and average speed for the period shall be used in computing the horsepower. All belt horsepower tests must be made with an electric dynamometer, or | with an accurately tested Prony brake or other accurate power-measuring device. Correction shall be made for tempera - ture and altitude effect on horsepower output on maximum test only. Standard conditions of barometric pressure of 2932 inches Hg. and a temperature of 60" Fahr., or 520° abs.T. shall be used. The following correction formula shall be used (on maximum test only): ¦ '¦ ¦.-: '¦&#132; ./¦ .I.•; \ ¦ : • ¦ . - "' '-' BHPc = BH^o X (Ps H-Po) X V To -7-Ts where BHPc = corrected brake horsepower BHPo = observed brake horsepower Po = observed barometric pressure in inches of mercury Ps = standard barometric pressure in inches of mercury To = observed absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Ts = standard absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Test C (Maximum Drawbar Horsepower).—After the tractor has at - tained proper working conditions it shall be subjected to a series of draw - bar tests, preferably on level ground and of such a nature that it will pro - vide a firm footing and offer a tractive resistance simulating that of grain stubble ground in good plowing condition.: The loads shall be successively increased or decreased to a point where the tractor can sustain a constant pull for a distance of not less than 1,000 feet with the average engine r. p. m. maintained within 5 per cent of its rated full load speed and a wheel.slippage of not more than 10 per cent, the wheel slippage to be secured as follows: The tractor shall be driven without any drawbar load for a distance sufficient to give 10 revolutions of the drivcwheels. This distance is then accurately measured and is used as the basis for comput - ing wheel slippage. The r.umber of revolutions of all drivers shall be counted for the entire distance through which the load is pulled. The drawbar pull shall be measured by means of an accurately calibrated draft dynamometer or draft mea luring device placed between the tractor and the load. The actual dista ice traveled shall be used in calculating the horse power, no allowance being made for wheel slippage. During this test the tractor shall be run in the gear recommended for plowing under favorable conditions. ¦':,¦'¦. . ..'¦:'. .'/¦'' ; : FUELS. ;,.\:. These tests will be mad: on the lowest commercially available grade of fuel which the manufacti rer recommends. LUBRICANTS The lubricants used in tiese tests shall be such as arc regularly recom - mended by the manufacturer for the tractor. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">NEBRASKA AcjRJCILTIRAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 304 BELTS The belt or belts used in these tests shall be such as the manufacturer recommends for use with the tractor in ordinary operation. No allowance will be made for belt losses. THE LAW Purpose of the Law.—The Nebraska Tractor Law, known as House Roll 85, 37th Session (Art. 10. paragraphs 5531-55-13 inclusive, pages 1751 and 1752, Compiled Statutes of State of Nebraska, 1922), which became effective July 15, 1919, was enacted to encourage the manufacture and sale of improved types of tractors and to contribute to a more successful use of the tractor for farming. It was thought that the best method of accomplishing these objects would be to require a tractor of each model sold in the State to be tested .it the State L'nilcrsity and to have the results of these tests made public. Provisions of the Law.—Stated briefly, the provisions of the law are- Thai .i stork tractor of each model sold in the State shall be tested Jinl passed upon by a board of three engineers under State University management. That each company, dealer or individual offering a tractor for sale in Nebraska shall have a permit issued by the State Railway Commission. The permit tor ,uiv model nt tractor will be issued after a stock tractor of that model has been tested at the University and the performance of the tractor compared with tin- claims made for it by the manufacturer. That a scniic station with lull supply of replacement parts for each model of tractor shall lie maintained within the confines of the State nnd within reasonable shipping distance ot customers. Nebraska Tractor Law.—Full text of the law as found in 75-901 to 911 inclusive. Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 102'). and revised bv House Roll 526, -! c)th Session (19H) is .is follows: Section 1. That on and after July 15. 1919. no tractor or traction com - pany shall be permitted to sell or dispose of any model or type ot gas, gasoline, kerosene-, distillate- or other liquid fuel tractor engine in the state of Nebraska without hrst haiing said model tested and passed upon by a board of three competent engineers who are or shall be under the control of the state university management, l-.ach and even' tractor pre - sented to the State University management for testing, shall be a stock model and shall not be equipped with .my spcchl appliance or apparatus not regularly supplied to the trade. Any tractor not complying with the provisions of this section shall not be tested under this act, nor the results certified. Provided, no official tractor tests shall be conducted during the months of December, January and February. Applications for the test of a tractor shall be made to the testing board of engineers and shall be ac - companied by specifications of the tractor required by said board of engi - neers, and by the fee specified in Section 5535, Compiled Statutes of Ne- </seg>
         <seg id="p019">¦ . --. .-¦"•¦ Neiraska Tractor Tests ; braska for 1922. If the appl cation with specifications and fee is submitted during December, January, February or at any other time when the test can not be started at once, the State Railway Commission, with the ap - proval of the said board of engineers, may issue a temporary permit for the sale of tractors of the nodel specified in the application for test, the date on which said temporiry permit shall terminate to be fixed by the said board of engineers. Al temporary permits shall be conditioned upon such tractor as is covered th :reby being tested at the earliest available date, and the tractor company to which a temporary permit has been issued shall submit a tractor for rest which conforms to the specifications filed with the application, said tractor to be delivered for test at any time specified by the board of engineers. Upon failure to do so, all such fees deposited by said companies shall be forfeited to the State of Nebraska, and in addition such comp: nies shall be liable to the penalties prescribed by Section 5540, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and shall never thereafter be issued any tenporary permit whatever. Provided, however, that all sales of tractors upen which a temporary permit has been issued, shall be made subject to the final official test and approval of the model. Section 2. Such tests to consist of endurance, official rating of horse - power for continuous load, ind consumption of fuel per hour or per acre of farm operations; the results of such tests to be open at all times to public inspection. • ; Section 3. The State University management after having duly tested any model of liquid fuel traction engine shall certify the results to the State Railway Commission. Prior to the issuing of a permit by said com - mission to any liquid fuel traction engine company to do business in the State of Nebraska, the official tests of the University shall be compared with the representations of the tractor company as to horsepower rating for not less than ten consecutive hours of continuous load, fuel used for developing such horsepbwei, and any other representation such company shall make, and in case anj such representations shall be found false the State Railway Commissior shall deny the company manufacturing or assembling such tractor, the right to do business in the State of Nebraska, except as hereinafter provided. : ¦...-, Section 4. Likewise, the State Railway Commission shall deny to any liquid fuel tractor company the right to do business in the State of Ne - braska which shall be found, on complaint of two or more bona fide cus - tomers residing within the State,, to fail to maintain an adequate service station with full supply of replacement parts within the confines of the State and within reasonable shipping distance of said customers. Section 5. Application t) the State University management for test of a tractor shall be accompanied by a fee of five hundred dollars ($500.00) paid to the State University management as a partial reimbursement for the cost of such test. Payment shall also be made upon presentation of the proper statement for costs of all fuel and oil consumed in making said test. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 Section 6. Provided further, that the failure of any model of tractor to come up to the representations of the company manufacturing or as - sembling same, shall not prevent said company from placing on the market, other models of tractors that do comply with specifications and ratings. Any model of tractor that fails in the official test to come up to the com - pany's own specifications, may be retested after alteration and remodeling. Each and every permit issued under this act shall specify the model or models included in such permit to sell. Section 7. The report of the official tests herein provided shall be posted in the Agricultural Engineering Department of the State University and in such other places as may be designated by the State University man - agement. The same shall be incorporated in the annual report of the State Railway Commission. Section 8. Provided, that no tractor company shall use the results of said tests in such manner as would cause it to appear that the State Uni - versity management intended to recommend the use of any given type or model (it tractor in preference to any other type or model. It shall be unlawful lor :my tractor company operating in the State of Nebraska, to publish extracts from such official tests for advertising purposes, without publishing the entire report. Any injraction of the foregoing provisions shall result in the suspen - sion or denial to any company so offending the permission to do business in ihe St.ue at the discretion of the State Railway Commission. Section '). Tractors shall be tested by the State University management in the order in which they arc presented for such tests, and no discrim - ination shall he nude tor or against any tractor company in any manner whatsoever. Complaints against the violation of this provision shall be heard and adjudicated by the State Railway Commission. Section 10. After July 15, I'M'), any gas, gasoline, kerosene, distillate or other liquid fuel tractor or traction company selling or offering for sale in the State of Nebraska or any automobile, implement or other company or individual npeiatini; in behalf of such tractor company or on their own behalf who shall alter the date specified, sell or offer for sale in the State any model ul liquid fuel tractor enpne. without having in his possession a permit from the State Railway Commission to sell such model of tractor as he is offering for sale, the same shall be deemed guilty of a misde - meanor. On conviction such misdemeanor shall be punished by a fine of not less than 5100.00 nor more than $500.00 for each offense in the discretion of the court. Section 11. The State Railway Commission shall have full authority to enforce the provisions of this act, both by denial of permit to do business in the State and by due process of law to compel compliance therewith. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Nebb Tractor Tests TRACT 3R SPECIFICATIONS The following tractors w re reported by their manufacturers as being on the market January 1, 19:7. The results of the tests arc on the folded summary sheet. . . Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODSL G 2-4, Beeman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; June 22 to July 2, 192 I. Heinze "AXI" magneto; Kingston "J" carburetor; Donaldson dry centrifugal-type air cleaner; no governor. Engine vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 4'A", width 3'A" rotates at engine speed. Chassis: two drive whecli in front, 2 caster wheels in rear; own clutch, both external and internal expanding. Rated speed 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comment: Replaced carburetoi, Test No. 29. IA CROSSE 12 24, La Crossc Tractor Company, La Crossc, Wiscon - sin; August 2 to 5, 1920. Atwatcr-Kcnt "K3" magneto a id dry batteries; Strombcrg "MB3" carburetor; Ben - nett dry centrifugal-type air dealer; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine horizontal, 'valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 11", width 7'A", rated speed 900 r.p.m. Chassis: our wheels, 2 drivers; own clutch contracung-band type; open gear drive. Rated spec i 2.5 miles per hour. * Comments: Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 lines. Replaced an belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, j round valves. Test No. 73. WETMORE 12 25, H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa; April 6 to 12, 1921. ;¦¦; Splitdorf Aero magneto; Sch bier "ATX47" VA" carburetor; no air cleaner; Weidcly fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 6'A", rated speed 1,088 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.0, in - termediate 3.5, high 5.9. '¦'•'¦ . . . . ¦ Comments: No repairs nor ad ustments. Hand operation of throttle was necessary to control speed within safe limits if loads three-fourths rating and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy-grade, oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44, Minneapolis Steel «c Machinery com - pany, Minneapolis, Minnesota; Ma) 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "ZR")Ed26" m igncto; Whcclcr-Schcbler "A" carburetor; Donaldson Duplex oiled-fibrc-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, valve - in-hcad, removable head and cylind :r sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 21", width SYz", rated speed 466 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc clut:h, 7" extension rims. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.20, high 2.90, reverse 1.87. ... . u " Comments: During both the r.\ ted load brake test and the-rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had ¦to be rca ljustcd. : - ' ¦ Test No. 12S. HUBER 20-4), Hubcr Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; September 7 to 16, 1926. ' '..;.-¦ Eisemann "GS4" magneto; Kitgston "L3" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-spray - type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-ty pe governor. Engine vertical, valvc-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 'A", width 8", rated speed 666 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, cr closed gear drive; Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.47, high 3.' 8, reverse 1.94. ;,; : Comments: During the rated .'brake test the fan. belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. ¦' . Test No. 135. HUBER SUE iR FOUR 40-62, Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; May 17 to June 24, 1927. : . </seg>
         <seg id="p022">NtBHASKA AoRK.i I.TI R \L EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 304 Liscmann "(,4" magneto; Ensign "A" carburetor; Pomona oil-spray-typc air cleaner; Kingston IK-hall-lyjx.- governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-hrad, niourilcd crankshaft lengthwise: licit pulley diameter 15!',", width 9K", rated speed 733 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels. 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: W 2.00 to 2.50. high 3.00 to 3.50, reverse 1.75 to 2.25. ('iiinnienb: During the rated drawbar test and after approximately 25 hours run - ning, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced will) new ones of the same nuke but did not remedy tlic trouble. The Stilt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were ihcn replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was rX|&lt;crivlKcil. The left spindle arm sheared off, causing the front axle tr. hen.l somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The patWinv-.-l.inil nuts on the waier jiump were tightened several times during tile test, he ilcmMc &#132;il tulx- le.nl.in i" the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the tist Test No. 141 McCORMICKDEERING 10-20. International Harvester Company (.Incm... Mm,.,,; ()ct,,1,,r i t,i \ l'&gt;27. ' " Own-,,.,k&lt;' ¦]. l.v ni.ij.in to: Kmign "R" carburetor; Pomona "Vortor" Model 118 i.il-sprj&gt;-"l« .iir cleaner. &#132;wn fl\-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-hcad, m.iu/itc,' jMiuduir leiiu'ilnvisc^belt pulley diameter 15li", width 7", rated speed 661 V u T' '"," r "'"tK- : 'lri«er». cni.li.scd gear drive, own multiple dry disc clut.ii. K.iu.l ,p,,-ds. miln |&#132; r hour: |&#132;w 2, intermediate 3, high 4, reverse 2.75. ' n::&lt;:m iir. N.i repaid n.,r .iil|ust:ncn[s. Test No. 148. LALSON "Si:" 20-35, John Lmson Manufacturing Company, New Ilulwiin. Wivuntiii; .\pril 2 t.i U,. I&gt;«2^. \meiu-jn Hovh • ZKf mjunei..: lillotson "R2" carburetor; Taco fly-ball-typc ...veuiMt; |jc, w.mr-f,pe air ck-aner. ILnjiine vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft .enutm-w; hell ;,ulk\ dMiiicler ll.". widlh K", rated speed 697 r.p.m. Chassis-, four n-liu-lj. . dnwrs niclnsnl .ae.ir drive: Turn Disc, dry plate dutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2,2-) t,, 2.50, high 3.2=i to 3.50, reverse 2.0U. Comments: All s| U rk plug gaps were adjusted to 0.025". At the end of the belt tests No. 2 cylinder had a leaky exhaust valve. All valves were ground and carbon removed. The carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No 155 CASE »L" 26-40, J. I. Ci« Threshing \fachine Company, Racine, Wisconsin; March Ifi to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch ¦f-LI" magneto; Kingston "L5" carburetor; own oil-fibre-type air cleaner: own ily-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width SU", rated speed 780 r.p.m. Chassis- four wheels 2 drivers, gear and chain drive, Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, intermediate 3.25, high 4.00, reverse 2.75. Comments: Before the official belt tests were run, the weighted air valve in the carburetor was gmn a few thousandths inch end clearance. Approximately 5/32" was removed from the crown of the belt pulley. 24 T929 N°' m' BAKER 43"67' A' D' Bakcr Com Pany- Swanton &gt; Ohio, May 16 to Eiscmann "CV magneto; Strombcrg "M4" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-filter - rype air cleaner; ovvn fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, T head, mounted aank - shaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1514". width B'/:", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc smgle-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.0 to 2.5, high 3.0 to 3.5 reverse 2 5 Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in mesh during the high-gear max - imum and rated load drawbar tests. 12 tl^iV/ 7' CASE "C" 17'27 ' lL °m C°mpany ' RadnCl Wisconsi": August Robert Rosch "FU4ARS" magneto; Kingston "L3" carburetor; own oil-fittcr-type air cleaner; jnvn fly-ball-, y pe governor. Engine vertical, "I" head/mounted crankshaft lengthwise: belt pulley diameter 10'/,", width 61V, rated speed 973 r.p.m Chassis: </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Nebriska Tractor Tests four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed pea and chain drive, Twin Disc plate-type-clutch. Rated speeds, miles pcr'hour: low 2.30, i itermediate 3.28, high 4.50, reverse 2.59. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar test, the fuel tin: to the carburetor became clogged and was cleaned out. - .. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36, The Hubcr Manufacturing Com - pany, Marion, Ohio; August 19 to 24, 1929. Eiscnmnn "GV-I" magneto; Stumbcrg "M3" carburetor; Donaldson oiled-fibrc-type air cleaner; Waukcsha fly-ball-typi governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 17", width BVi", rated speed 616 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, cicloscd gear drive, Twin Disc dry-plate-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: lov 2.32, high 3.08, reverse 1.83. Comments: During the maxinv im drawbar tests the dutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC," J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; September 10 to 18, 1929. . . ¦ . Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto; Kingston "L3V" carburetor; own'oil-filter-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type govern Dr. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; .belt pulley diameter 1 )'A", width 6'/i", rated speed 973 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gca ¦ and chain drive, Twin Disc plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.C0, intermediate 3.72, high 5.14, reverse 2.95. Comments: It was necessary tc raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. " . Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michi - gan; March 11 to April 8, 1930. . . ¦• :. ¦ • : Robert Bosch "FU" 4HRS29 m igncto; Kingston "MD2" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc govi rnor. Engine vertical, L-hcad, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley - diameter. 9 Vi ", width 6Vz", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gc: r drive, own multiplc-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 3.12, high 7.75, reverse 3.00. Comments: During the prclimi lary belt tests, the cylinder head -gasket was replaced.' The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt lest. ... •¦'-.".' .¦'¦,' ¦ . Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Mich - igan; March 20 to April 10, 1930 .: . / ' Robert Bosch "FV" 48R529 r lagncto; Zenith "INSF" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-bnll-typc gov :rnor. Engine vertical, L-hcad, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 9'/z", width 6!4", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gc; r drive, own multiplc-disc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.12, interm :diatc 3.12, high 7.25, reverse 3.00. : Comments: During the rated-oad belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifth turn. Test No. 176. OLIVER HA IT-PARR "ROW CROP," Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa; Ap il 14 to 24, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" majneto; Ensign Model "K" carburetor; Donaldson 2 - unit centrifugal and oily-fibrc-tyt c air cleaner; own. fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1414", width TA", rated speed 700 r.p.m. Chaisis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beet singlc-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.60, intermediate 3.20, high 4.15, reverse 2.90. - .-. " . Comments: No repairs nor adj lstmcnts. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications and application or test of this tractor we find the following claims are not substantiated by the result of this test: Exhibit "B"—Folder A 135—"They do end wheel slippage" and "They do not slip." Exhibit "C"—Folder A 143 —Same as above. Exhibit "D" —Folder 4 144—"Positive traction at the tiptoe wheels assures dc - liery of every ounce of engine power to the drawbar." Exhibit "F"—Folder A 146— "They do not slip." I </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 Tot No. 177 MASSEY-MAMIS "GENERAL PURPOSE," The Massey-Harris Com - pany, Racine, Wisconsin; May 5 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Zenith "94T0" carburetor; Massey-Harris oil - cu-culateaW-wool-rype air cleaner; Hercules fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, /SS" moum&lt;4 cranks, haft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 6/z", rated nb, , r, PI K ? aT: f°U, r Whcds' a" driv"s ' ™closcd *Mr dri«- ™" Dhc ingle - ?verie e y?5O "" h°Ur: '°W 2'2°' intcrmi:di:"': 3.20, high •} 00, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 180. OLIVER HART-PARR (2-3 plow), Oliver Farm Equipment Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa; July 7 to 15 1930 Amcncan Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Ensign "KZ" carburetor; Donaldson 2-unit centrifugal and mly-fibre-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical I head mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter H%', width 7 X ".rated speed 726 r.p.m. Chassis: lour wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Bore &amp; Beck ft? £™ 2J&gt; dlllCh- ""*' mi'CS PCr h°Ur: &gt;°W 26 ' intc"mcdiatc 53.2, Wgb lu/cSi^atw l JraWbar ICS" IUS WM bSt Md *' '"« bent- T* pan^H^l^, Pl°W)l °'iVCr F"m E&lt;lUiPmCnt C°m" Amencan Bosch ¦'LM- ™,ncto; Ensign "K" carburetor; Donaldson 2-unit centrif - ugal and o.ly-fibre-ype air cleaner; own centr.fugal-o-pe governor. Engine vertical, "I" head m oun,ed crankshaft lengths: belt pulley diameter 16'A", width B'/,'', rated speed 5.6 r.p.m Chass.s: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Bow U Beck "7l r Peverse t&gt;2 PC63. UtCh' """' SPCCdS' "^ P" h°Ur: IoW 2'"" in«rmcaiat e 3.30, high Comments: No repairs nor adjustments Octo^r 1 2^-,o BNove^ri,"?9 Aio' ManUfaCtU" nS C°mPany ' APpUt °n ' Wi—"'n ' sprayre^S wV m? gnC'°; x""? 1 "96AT°" arburet? r ' P°n,o n a-Voru,i oil - tZ, r ik , V , fC " Kntrif "S:l|-'yP= governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft )engthw,se; belt pulley diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 rlmse 2 50. '"' " "" h°Ur: '°W 250 ' inK™«ii='« 3.33, high 4.50, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments P anyT^V. mnolXfr^S^" 35''' *" ** ""^ C° - .pra^C^cl~tr"w" TT"°'' "HDX" CarburCtor: Pomona-Vortox oil - •pray type air cleaner; Waukesha cenmfugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, •Ld92o moumed crankshaf;, l"'g*»«=; belt pulley diameter 12", width 9", raS tv^clmrh 'Pt 5 A ffaCk ayCf ' 2 ""^ enclos!:d Srar drive, Twin Disc c^-plate - rlvlrse2 65. $ P" '°W '¦9°' intcrmcdia": 2-85. high 3 SIT Comments: No repairs nor adjustments pan^fca^^olXlTf 2^3 E," 45'' *~ "~ M^ American Bosch "U6" magneto; Schleber "HDX" carburetor- Pomona-Vortox oil .pray-type „ cleaner; Waukesha centrifugal-^ governor. Engine S^tote^w' .Ll MO moumcd r^ nkihaft [^wise; belt pulley diameteV 12", width 9", nS speed 920 r.p.m Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc div </seg>
         <seg id="p025">• Nebraska Tractor Tests. Test No. 191. MASSEY-HARMS "GENERAL PURPOSE," The Ma«ey-Harri» Company, Racine, Wisconsin; May| 22 to June 12, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Zenith "TO94E" carburetor; own oil-drculated - over-wool-type air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. .Engine four-cylinder! "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 6Vi", rated speed 802 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc plate - type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.2, intermediate 3.2, high 4.0, reverse 2.5., &#132;. '. |; . : ¦ . : ¦ ' . Comments: Just before starting the rated belt test, the key which holds the belt - pulley bevel Rear to the power take-off shaft sheared off. The shaft, sear, and key were replaced with new parts. During the premilinary drawbar tests one of the dif - ferential brakes was found dragging and was adjusted at this time. During the 100 per cent intermediate maximum drawbar tests the connection on No. 3 spark plug wa&gt; broken. A new plug was used in its place. The spark plug in No. 2 cylinder was cleaned twice during the maximum drawbar tests. During the drawbar tests three lug bolts were lost and replaced by new ones. . '::".'. Test No. 193. ALLIS-CHALMERS "EK," Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; June 18 to 25, 1931. -.:¦¦ . . Eiscmann "G4" magneto; Zenith "C6EV" carburetor; Donaldson and own centrif - ugal and otly-fibre-typc air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width B'/2",rated speed 1,000 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own expanding-shoc-typc clutch. Sated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, high 3.25, reverse 3.25. '" \ * ..-.: | ' : ¦ .•¦ ¦.¦¦.'. Comments: During the preliminary drawbar runs the head gaskets on. cylinders No. 3 and 4 were found to be leaking! and were replaced. Test No. 194. McCORMICR-DEERING INDUSTRIAL "20," International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; July 20 to 27, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "CSFE" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt, pulley-diameter 15'/", width 7", rated speed 742 r.p.m. Chassis: four weels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate-type clutch: Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, intermediate 3.50, high 5.00, reverse 3.00... ;¦;.;.¦ : . .: '¦. j, ; /':¦:. ¦ ¦.¦ - Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. . Test No. 198. McCORMCK-DEERING FARMALL "F 30," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October ? to 23, .1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith )"K5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulleyj diameter 14%", width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m; Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own dry single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.00, second 2.75, third 3.25, fourth 3.75, reverse 2.50. ¦¦. ¦',• I" •; ¦'¦¦¦.. Comments: The pin which holds the,splined end of the steering rod in the splined sleeve sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during die rated-load drawbar test Each time the pin was replaced by another. Test No. 199. McCORMICK-pEERING TracTracTor, International Harvester Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; October It) to 26, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith j"KS" carburetor; own oil-washed, wire-filter type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter WA", width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate, dry-disc-type clutch. Bated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 2.75, high 3.75, reverse 2.00. Comments: No repairs nor acjustments. | Test No. 200. ALUS-CHAIIMERS MODEL "L," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; Maj-ch 17 to April 11, 1932. ! . :.. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Blxletin 304 Eiscmann "C.V6" magneto; two Zenith "C6EV" carburetors; own cenirifugal-rype governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 20", width 15", rated speed 580-1232 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer en - closed gear drive, own double-disc-typc clutch. Rsted speeds, miles per hour: first 1.94, second 2.45, third 3.05, fourth 4.10, fifth 5.20, sixth 6.47, reverse 1.45-3.07. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test, the fuel flow was restricted by a flake of solder partially covering the outlet in the bottom of the supply tank. The obstruction was blown away from the outlet and the test completed. Test No. 204. CATERPILLAR "Fifty," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illin - ois; Mav 18 to )unc 11, 1032. 1 isemann "CV4" magneto; Ensign "Ke" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, ccnlrituiMl, oil and matrcd-wirc-tvpc air cleaner; own ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four cxlimliT vertical. "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter I?',", width 10". rated speed ".! r.p.m. Cha-sis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own drv sinclc-plate-t\nr clutch. Rated speeds, miks per hour: first 1.6, second 2.4, third 1.4. fourth 4.7. reverse I. I'. t imiinmtv I luring the mavunum drawbar rots, a valic rod tube yoke was fotind to be loose. Tins was lightened. Test No. 2)0. McCORMICK-DEERING "W 30." International Harvester Company, Chu-.i^o. Illinois; July 2h to August 10. 1932. """ "F.4.\" nuencto; Zi nith Ki" carburetor: own oil-washed wirc-filta-tvpc air cle.irhr: own cntrifugal-type -nxrnnr. Encinc fmir-cvlinder vertical. "1" head, mounted cranlslult Ini^ihwis, : V!i pulle'. diameter I5!»", width 7". ratal speed f&gt;M r.p.m. riu-Mv -rur iid.i-'.. 2 il'ii.iv. enclosed cc:ir drive, own dry-disc tinglc-iihts-iype clutch. R.ur.i ,;«(,!, inns ;, • |,rt Ur: tirst 2.i0. s ennd .1.25. third 3.75. reverse 2.75. ( ¦nniiint N-. rt;..n:. iim .iilmstliK llts. Test No. 211. McCOR.MK KDEERINC; TracTr.ic-Tor "T 4fl" Imernalian.i' I lar - lestii r..11i;..m-. &lt; IHi.iLjr,. Mlirv i&gt;; (lil.lvr II to 211. I'&lt;i2. K..K-I li. sch "I I"i.|;RS =¦¦¦'• n.j-net..: Zenith "K^S" cirlnirrtor: ciwn nil-washed ivir, nit. r-t-. P &lt; ,ir i'i.»i,i mhm t : uiru ml:.il-f. ;c governor. linj;inc six-cylinder vertical, "I" l».id. n...iiiv,,l .-.iiikJ,.,-! .erolmw; Wlt |ni!lc\ ilumi-iei 16!4". width 9". rated *('•"¦ '"' v ' • •¦¦"¦ ( '¦¦¦•¦¦ tr-uli!;! 1 ' '. rlklosed -r.ir drive, own dty-disc sillalt-platc - "!'¦_¦ cUitoim. K.r..! &gt;p.o!&gt; ¦in 1.. ;m i,..,r. ;„„ |."5. second 2.25, 'third 2.7*. fourth i. 2". hltli Mm, n vit-e J .!: '"•¦minims- I&gt;ui:n^ tin ;.ie!miin.in l« t t.sts. -he cylinder head fijvket u-.is immd t. l»- leaking .ml «.!¦. rc-.'Ucid null .i new one. Test \o. 21J, .\fcrOR.\HCK-DrnRING FARMAU. "F-12." Inicrnaliwuil Uarverter Co:nji.nr.. ('.lik.i-.,, Illinois; Mai I i,, Ji). j'/ji, Own ¦¦1-.4A" nucniK .iwn "A-lu ' cuhvireior, own oil-washed wirc-hlur-typc air cleanrr: own icn-rilu-.d-r ;¦&lt;¦ -oi.rnor. Kiuinr fotir-cvlindcr verticil. "1" head, mounted cr.inksh.,ti lrni:tliwis.: Ml ;'ulVv diatrcn r 12'.". ¦vulth (,&lt;',". rated speed SOn r.p.m. Chases: three who Is. 2 drivers, enclosed -ear drive. Rockli.rd single-plate dry-disc - type clutch. R.ii.,l speeds, miles per hour; first 2.25. second 3.d11, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments; lltlorc running liie uninj; load b,lt tests, it was necessary to adjust the jzovernnr cross rod. Test No. 213. CATERPILLAR "SEVENTY." Caterpillar Tractor Companv, Pcoria, Illinois; Mav 15 to June o. I'/ji. Kiscniann "GV4" magneto: linsi K n "Keb" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, combination centrifugal, nil and mattcd-wirc-typc air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Enmnc four-cvlindcr vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15", width 11", rated speed 700 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear dme. own single-plate drv-typc dutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour- first 17, second 2.3. third 2.7. fourth 3.1. fifth 3.7, sixth 5.0, reverse 1.7 and 2.7. Comments: The exhaust valve spring on No. 2 cylinder failed at the end of the rated.load dr.iwhar test after 51 hours operation. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 215. ALUS-CHALMERS "K," AUis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; September 21 to October 4, 1933. Eiscmann 'GL4" magneto; Zciith "C6" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter - type air cleaners; own centrifugal-t pe governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width BJ4", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds,, miles per hour: first 2.08, second 3.10, third 4.50, reverse 2.39. Comments: No repairs nor ad ustrnents. Test No. 216. ALLIS-CHAL] lERS "M," Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; September 23 to October 9, 1933. ' . Eiscmann "CL-f" magneto; Zc lith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filtcr - typc air cleaner; own ccntrifugal-rj pe governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width BH", rated speed 960 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclose Igear drive; Rockford singlc-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.23, ccond 3.20, third 4.15, fourth 5.82, reverse 2.55. Comments: No repairs nor ad ustments. :.•':¦ . . Test No. 219. MASSEY-HA RRIS "3-4 PLOW," The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 24 to November 10, 1933. American Bosch "U4ED4" m: gneto; Kingston "L-3-L" carburetor; own oil-circu - latol-bvcr-wool-type air cleaner; Kingston centrifugal-type governor. Engine four - cylinder vertical, "I" head, moun ed crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 19", width 714", rated speed 525 r.p.nc. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry single-plate-typc cl itch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.25, third 4.00, reverse 2;50. Comments: During the prelii linary belt tests, the spark plug in No. 1 cylinder was replaced with a new one. ' . . Test No. 220. McCORMICK DEERING FARMALL "F-12" (Kerosene), Interna - tional Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 1 to 16, 1933. Own "F-4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filtcr-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12%", width 6'A", rated speed 800 r.p.m. Chassis: three wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc - typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.00, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. . . ¦ '.¦-.¦¦¦¦. ¦¦¦¦.' ' ' .'¦ ' ¦¦.•¦¦'¦" Comments: During the belt tests the spark plug in No. 3 cylinder was replaced with a new one. On the ratcd-load drawbar test a bolt connecting the drawbar to the drawbarradjusting plate was lost. This was replaced. ' Test No. 222, JOHN DEERE GENERAL PURPOSE MODEL "A," John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; April 19 to 27, 1934. I"airbanks-Morsc "DRV2A" magneto; Whecler-Schcbler "DLTX-8" carburetor; Vortox "2071D" oil-washed wirc-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "1" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 12 13/16, width 7'A", rated speed 975 r.p.m. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, en - closed gear drive, own disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour:: first 2.33, second 3.00, third 4.75, fourth 6.25, reverse 3.50. . Comments: During the drawbar tests grease leaked from the left end of the rear axle housing. The exhaust pipe to exhaust manifold connection became loose and was tightened during the maximum drawbar tests. . Test No. 223. ALUS-CHALMERS MODEL "WC," Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin;:May 2 to 16, 1934. ¦ Scinalla-Bendix "C-4" magneto; Zenith "124V1". TO" carburetor; United 011-balh - type air cleaner; Kingston, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, T' head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise;l belt pulley diameter 9", width 6/4", rated speed 1170 r.p.m. Chassis: four !wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford dry- </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Acricvlti-bal Experiment Station Bulletin 304 tn^tJ:faT^ mi'" "" h°Ur: 6rst 2-50 ' SKond 3-50- *W 4-75, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Four-hour Fuel Economy Tests Drawl™ 5n».,l r il t Sl', P°n Fuel consumption ifwc&lt;l Crankshaft drive . : ' P"l! ¦*'*•*• speed wheels Co//. H.P.&gt;Sr/. Li,. pfr 1 A *-P-m- P.cl. prrhr. per gal. H.P.hr. STEEL WIIEE.I.S—THIRD GEAR "J"' "M sl° UIO 7.37 1.896 5.62 1.237 Kt HIIF.R TIRES' SECOND CEAR 12,';; r ,'-'' 02 -U! LiU '"0 1-660 7.2S 0.955 Aililitmnal infnrmaii.in asailablc in test report. /ulv T*,o 2 ( r 2, 4 ,^CATERPILLAR "R"s'' T™&lt;°' Company, Pcoria, Illinois; Comments-. No repairs nor adjustments. con,b;^::n^;i g :; aß^,^;t;^;.- b™: °-. ¦»-« v ort ox p,^ on.::-- j:—trr o ;;-7,;^ s?^ ««*- - Comments: No repairs nor adjuslments. sis SavtSSiS si'SJMi 5S £ Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. 'Not tctommcndtii lor itccl whcrli Additional weight per wheel wai «t} pounds. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 228. CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" (Gasoline), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria Illinois; October 17 to 30, 1934. Eisemann "CT-4" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10'A", width 6'/i", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate] dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.6, third.3.6, reverse 2.1. . Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 230. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor "T-40 Diesel," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 25 to November 13, 1934. Own "E4A" magneto (for starting only); own "R" (modified) carburetor (for starting only); own "P 40" fuel system; own oil-washcd-wirc-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor.' Engine four-cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter WA", width 9", rated speed 591 r.pjn.. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, mites per hour: first 1.7 , second 2.25, third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. . '.'.'. ¦ '.- &lt; , ¦¦.'..-. Test No. 231. McCORMICK-DEERING "W-12" (Gasoline), International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 13 to 16, 1934. Own "F4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washcd-wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13 'A ", width 6'A", rated speed 787 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear, drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 2.75, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: At die end of the rated load drawbar test the manifold bolt, which holds the choke rod bracket, was found to be loose. Test No. 232. JOHN DEERE GENERAL PURPOSE "B," John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; November 15,' 1934 to April 19, 1935. Fairbanks-Morse "DRV-2B" magneto; Whecler-Schebler "DLTX-10" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, wire-filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "I" head,) mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 10!i", width 6", rated speed 1150 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; own, disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.33, third 4.75, fourth 6.75, reverse 3.^5. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments; Test No. 233. M-M TWIN CITY "JT," Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis Minnesota; April 17 to 29, 1935. Fairbanks-Morse "RV-4" magneto; Zenith "124-14 T" carburetor; Donaldson oil - washed, wire-filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "F" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15%", widdi 6 Vi", rated speed 730 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc gear-type, single-plate 'clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.2, sec - ond 2.65. third 3.13, fourth 4.57,) fifth 12.1, 1 reverse 1.19. Comments: No repairs nor ad ustments. ¦ ' Test No. 234. PLANET JR. GARDEN TRACTOR, S. L. Allen and Company, Incorporated, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; June 5 to June 19, 1935. Eisemann "71-F" flywheel-type magneto; Tillotson "M-20-A" carburetor; Air Maze oiled-screen air cleaner; no governor. Engine one-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 3%", width 3Vi", rated speed 1800 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers; enclosed gear and open roller chain drive; Twin Disc dry-plate, disc clutch. Ground speed varied by changing speed of motor with hand throttle.- ¦-"'¦.¦' 1 N'ot recommended for Jlccl wheel!. - .. ."; ... </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Acrici ltlral Experiment Station Bulletin 304 Comments: After the belt tests and before the drawbar tests were run, the cylinder - head cap screws were tightened. During die maximum drawbar tests, the fuel line became clogged and was cleaned. Test No. 235. CLETRAC "40" DIESEL, The Cleveland Tractor Company, C.evc - land, Ohio; June 13 to 24, 1935. American Bosch "APE6B7O AJOOS9I" fuel system; Vortox oil-washed, wire-filter air cleaner: Hercules centrifug.il-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width II", rated speed 884 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Long two-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 3.0, third 4.3, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 236. JOHN DEERE "D," John Dccrc Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; June 26 to July 2, 1935. Sphtdorf "246 T" magneto; Schcblcr "DLTXfi" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, screen-filter air cleaner: own. centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "J" head, mounted crankshaft crmiunc: belt pulley i iametcr li'A", width B'/:", rated speed vun r.p.m. Qmsis: four whrcK. two drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive; own, double-disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.5, second 3.5, third 5, reverse 2. Comments: N To repairs or adjustments. Test No. 237. ALLIS-CHALMERS "U." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; July 15 m August 5. 1935. Scintilla-Bendix "C-4" magneto: Zenith "K-5" caihurctor; Vortox oil-washed, wirc - rilter air cleaner: own. centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10", width 7'A", rated speed 10'M r.p.m. Ch.i-.sis: fnur wheels, ran drivers, enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate climh. K.,to! spec,],. mi&gt;is per hour, first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.0, tourth 11).II. 1 r&lt; \ r-t l.i&lt;~ Comments: Or. the limber-up run. it was found that of the two bolts which hold the left fender to the 'iipiwnnt saddle on the axle housing, one was lost and the other loose an.l worn. 11 ..ill l«,'.i. urn- rrpbcnl. On the maximum tests (steel), one of the same two Loirs on tlie right lender was broken and the other loose. One was replace.) am] the other &lt;ii;liirn&lt;-d On the maximum drawbar tests (steel) it was observed th.it the hra/n! connection between the exhaust pipe anil the exhaust pipe flange w.is hmkm. I '¦¦ t U' 1 v 1 l l 1 \\ MNiAIY 'Vl SVS S'kimp, Fuel consumption Jir.i\\|..ir 5..,,/ ('¦jnlcth.ilr .Irivr — 111 1 im'l \l r&gt;: .;..:¦,! ivlir, - '¦¦''¦¦¦ H.P.hrs. IMper I ¦ I I'm /'.,.¦ /''¦ '¦¦''¦ r'rH'll- ILP.hr. ¦ •' »m' 11 s- - 1111 kn (, i\p i'. -i- )."¦¦' z &gt;&lt; i.&gt;: &lt;tjis :.%,, f ,_n U27 MI, ' \ : ,1. Is' sj i M\[i i. VC I&gt;. '•" 1.--5 - o |.:,,i '&#132;,) ;.„-., - 92 osg2 , Adihtional inlorm.ition .iv.iil.ibh' in t&lt; st report. Test No. 238. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UC", Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Com - panv. Milwaukee. Wisconsin: July Id to August S, 1935. Bendix-Scintilla "C-4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" v™ ri.nmmrmlrc! for sietl Mlicds </seg>
         <seg id="p031">¦ Nebraska Tractor Tests had, mourned crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10", width 7'A", nted speed 1094 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Rocklord single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.00, four|h 10.00,' reverse 2.67. . . Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests on rubber tires, gear grease began to leak from the final drive. Thi: continued to the end of the test (15 hours). Over the same period oE time, grease leaked tfirough the seal around the steering worm shaft. " .¦¦'•: . ¦ . i . Four-hour Fuel Economy Tests . I Slip on Fuel consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive — ; —: ; ~~ H.P. pull M.p./j. speed wheels Gals- H-P-hrs. Lbs. per ..¦[.•¦ Lbs: R.p.m. V.ct. per hr. per gal. H.P.hr. STEEI. WHEELS THIRD GEAR - ' ... , l^lS .1,021 5.95 132 2.10 3.027 5.35 1.307 i RUBBER TIRES* SECOND GEAR i .18.07 2,023 3.35 1,199 8.14 2.284 7.91 0.884 Additional information availab c in test report. . Test No. 239. ALLIS-CHAMERS "M", Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; August Ito 9, 1935; " . . Bcndix-Scintilla "C-4" magricti; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own, centrifuge 1-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length.visc; belt pulley diameter 12", width 854", rated speed 960 r.p.m. Chassis: trackla er, enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: fir: t 2.23, second 3.20, third 4.15, fourth 1.83, reverse 2.55!. , ';•¦ y •.."' ¦¦••' ¦- ;¦¦: .'¦.¦'' .v Comments: No repairs or adj stments. Test No. 242. CATERPILLAR DIESEL FORTY, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois; August 19 to Sepu mbcr 9, 1935. Own fuel system; Donaldson ombination oil and wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Eiginc three-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mount - ed crankshaft lengthwise; belt p llley diameter 12", width B Vi", rated speed 1000 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclos d gear drive; own, single-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, ! econd 2.9, third 3.8, fourth 5.4, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 243. CATERPILLLR DIESEL FORTY, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois; September 10 to 1 , 1935. . . Own fuel system; Donaldson (ombination oil and wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine three-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; jell pulley diameter 12", width 814", tated speed 850 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enilosed gear drive; own, single-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, s:cohd 2.5, third 3.2, fourth 4.6, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 244. CATERPILLAR "FORTY"', Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria) Illinois; September Ifi to 20, 193 i. ;_ _ EUcmann "C-T-4" magneto; Jnsign "K-3" carburetor; Donaldson combination oil and ccntrifuK.il wirc-scrccn labyriith air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor.^En - gine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" hi ad, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diam - eter 12", width B'/:", rated spec 850 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; ' ' .Vot recommended for itccl wheels . . ¦ ¦ 3 Additional wcisht per wheel was ¦ 22 pounds. . . </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 own, single-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.5, third 3.2, fourth 4.6, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 245. CATERPILLAR "FORTY", Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 18 to 23, 1935. Eisemann "CT-4" magneto; Zenith "K-6-A" carburetor; Donaldson combination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width B'/.", rated speed 1000 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear; drive; own. single-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.9, third 3.8, fourth 5.4, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 246. McCORMICK-DEERING "WD-40", International Harvester Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; September 23 to 27, 1935. Own, "F-4" magneto (for starting only)-, own, "R" (modified) carburetor (for suriint; only;; own "PT4O" fuel system; Donaldson combination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labynnih air cleaner: own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, verticil. Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16%", width '&lt;". rated s-iced 5\S r.p.m. Chassis: four w iccls. two drivers, enclosed gear drive; own single-plate, drv disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.6, second 3.4, third i.O, reverse 2.4. Comments: Nn repair* nr adiustnicnts. Test No. 247. M-M TWIN CITY "KTA", MinncapoHs-Molinc Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 2 to 9, 11• 35. American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schcbler "TTX-I5" carburetor; Donaldson combin - ation oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type gov - ernor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter It", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive: Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles pa - hour: first 2.1, second 3.1, third 4.1, reverse I.fl. Comments: After the belt tests were begun it was observed that the pulley shaft housing and bearing were cracked. A new pulley unit was installed and all data shown in this report were taken after the replacement was made. The air cleaner stack broke off during the preliminary drawbar tests. This was repaired by welding. The right hand tie-rod bolt started tn work out during the rated load drawbar test. The cotter key which normally holds the boh in place was lost. The bolt was put into proper position and keyed. Test No. 248. MM TWIN CITY "MTA", Minneapolis-Molinc Power Implement Company, Minneapolis. Minnesota; October 2 to 17, 1935. American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schcbler "TTX 15" carburetor; Donaldson com - binjn.in »il and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter H", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis; four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.1, second 3.1, third 4.1, reverse 1.8. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 249. MM TWIN CITY KTA (HC), Minncapolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota: March 30 to April 10, 1936. American Bosch "L'4" magneto: Schclbcr "TTX 15" carburetor; Donaldson ejector and oil-washed wire-scrcetn filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical. "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley diameter 14", face 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed pear drive, Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.25, third 4.25, reverse 1.9. Comments. No repairs or adjustments. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Nebraska Tractor Tests Fovr-iic uk Fuel Economy Tests Slip on Fuel consumption . Drawbar Speed C ankshaft drive —— , ... H-p- S *.; is. t"! s «m "£;;&amp;* '-"'. STEEL WHEELS — THIRD GEAR 21.76 ' 1,788 4.56 1,151 3J3 " 3.086 7.05 0.869 ..¦.'.¦.'• ' RUSH LR TIRES*—SECOND GEAR 14.89 1,704 3.28 1,153 6.56 1.833 8.12 0.754 Additional information availabl: in test report. . Test No. 250. SILVER KING 3-WHEEL, Fate-Root-Heath Company, Plymouth, Ohio: March 23 to April 20, 1936} . Fairbanks-Morse "RV-4" magnfclo; Zenith 193-'/2 carburetor; Air Maze oil-washed screen-filter air cleaner; Hercules tcntrifugal governor. Engine: four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 614", face 6!4 , rated speed 1400 r.p.m. Chassis: tiuce wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, Borg tc Beck dry disc, clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.35, third 5.5, fourth!. r&gt; 14.5, reverse 1.5. I „ Comments: While making a 'preliminary belt test tlie motor over-heated. Tne radiator core, which was painted with aluminum paint and was not equipped with a shroud, was replaced by one unpaintcd and having a shroud. The aluminum paint was removed from the motor ami the two-grouml-clectrodc type spark plugs were replaced by single-ground electrode plugs. All official test data were taken after these changes had been made. , . ¦ i j i. it i At the end of the test it was found diat insufficiently tightened cylinder head bolts had permitted water to leak from he cooling system into the second and third cylinders. i '.¦. ¦ Fotm-muR Fuel Economy Tests . Slip on Fuel consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive —-— ¦ , „., pun &gt;&#132;, speed wheels { STEE .WHEELS' —THIRD GEAR S.lO .-• • 441 . 6.89 1,400 ¦ 3.68 1.855 4.37 1.411 ' • . RUBIER TIRES'-^SECOND GEAR . 10.50. 1,142 3.45 1,401 8.32 1.534 6.84 0.900 Additional information available in test report. '.;¦¦ . Test No. 251. CASE RC, J. '.. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; April 7 to 16, American Bosch "MJB4AIOB' magneto; Zenith "193V 2 " carburetor; United oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; ' iase Waukesha centrifugal governor. Engine' four cylinder verncali "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter lO'/e", face 6'A", rated speed 991 r.p.m. Chassis: three wheels, two drivers, enclosed chain drive, Twin Disc single plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 4.5, reverse 2.5 Comments: No repairs or adjustments. 1 Not recommended for ited wheelt. 1 Addilional weight per wheel wm 560 pound!. . ." ¦ ¦ . ¦ - . 6 Up lo 25 milei per hour according io motor ipccil. •Additional weight per wheel'wai 102 pounds. </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agrici ltlral Experiment Station Bulletin 304 Tot No. 252. OLIVER HART PARR ROW CROP 70 (HC), Oliver Farm Equip - ment Company. Charles City, loyva; April 13 to 24, 1')36. American Bosch uMJßfiAill2" ma S neto; Zenith "12-f !i EX" carburetor; Donaldson elector and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder verticil, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: damctcr 12V, face 6V, rated speed 77-) r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, llorj; Sc Beck single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour - first 2.-H, second v.&gt;2, third 1.33, fourth 5.88, reverse 2.-H. Comments: l)urin R the r.ited load drawbar test the pin in the starting crank dropped out and lodged in the tractor frame. This was replaced. On this same test a welded connection on the scat frame was broken. Tbi No. 25!. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-7 (61 H.P.—BSQ r.p.m.), Caterpillar lr.Kt..t Cnmpar.y. Pec.na, Illinois; May 5 to 15, 1936. Own fuel uMcm; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own ccntri- Icw. p.v ( -ri...r Entire: lour cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft .en,-Tlmi*e. ltd, pulk-s: diameter l.i',". face 12V, rated speed 753 r.p.m. Chassis - rr.Kki.r, r. , luloscd «,ar drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Rated s|&gt;ecds, miles per limn Ilr-l 1.i.. s.con.l 2.1. third U, fourth -1.7, reverse 1.9. ¦¦ &gt; ""inmils: The starting m.it.ir clutch was adjusted once during the test. Tea No. 254. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-7, (69 H.P.-850 r.p.m.), Caterpillar li.'.r..r ( nmp.nv. 1',,,/,.,. Illinois: M. IV If, to 21), IVI6. «&gt;«n uirl -r, m: I)„„.,! !-,, n 0,1-u a ,hed wirc-scrccn filter air cleaner; own ccntn - lii-ui -_• &#132;,-,n..r l. n; o.K- lour cylimlcr \crtical dicscl, "I" head, mounted crankshaft ,:" ,:." IM "¦'' i"'ll'- '!l"'""r ''¦'¦"• face 12':-, rated speed 753 r.p.m. Chassis: lr.uk ,-.,r, mi,.,,-..1 oar time, own •.tncJe-nUue dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour nit; ] &#132;. &#132;,„„,! ;;. ,|, ir ,| ( , (i &#132;)Urt|,, )Urt |, ¦-_ rL . v ,. rsc ,_ fj _ ' I'onin.eiits N"o n-]..urs or adlllstnunls. Tm N... 2«. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-7 (1,1)00 r.p.m.), Cterpillar Tractor I oi-i;..in-.. IV.in.i. Illinois; \\.i\ 21 to 2% l''i'i. Own fuel -w« 1),,n.,1d5,,n 0,|.w.,5h0l wire-screen filter air cleaner; own ccmri - iijj ROM-rnor l-.nsine. i..ur c)lmd,r urtic.il die-tl. "I" head, mounted crankshaft "r; lltN "I, 1 '',""¦' ¦'¦"'"¦"' )f ¦"¦ '¦"&lt;¦ I-":", "ted speed 887 r.p.m. Chassis: ¦'"'¦ ™-"-"' -'¦•" drm-. ,nvn -inutt ;.l.irc drv clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: hirst I \ uiriiml 2''. ilird -,n. fourth vS. revirse 2.2. I'nninients: \,, n -j U irs or .idltntmrnts, cJZ^^T-**^. RD-fi'"" -m '¦&amp;1* '¦¦— , u ','"¦" "": Vll';: m,: ulll-n "•'¦"¦¦¦J«-l «ir.;s,r«n hlter air cleaner: mvn centri - ;,/,»•', n'lr T r[ r " ::" k-'] 'y&lt;rl"'" ''«"'¦ mou"'«' «nfah a f ', ¦V; i - "' ?';' r, ''V""; ;'"" """'"-I'*"" *!¦ f'un-h. Ratal speeds, miles per Own ,uel ,&gt;sK_m: n..n,1,150n _oil-was"h«l wire-screen filter air cleaner: own cen.ri - rj" I™,, '""'¦l"'" , SIV f«««" *~1. T- head, mounted crankshaft '"" h r 1 CV: I"™'" H ¦ (3CC ""' rnlal s"«d S-17 r -P-"&gt;- Chassis: ra.kla,er. enclosed p-..r drtvc, mvn sin B le-plale dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles-per l-nun hrst 2 1 second 21. .l.ird &#132;.,, four.l, id. fifth ¦!.„, sixt h „.,, revc P rsc 2. 0 a ' n 3P3. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. i.-. ! a2*mT' °LETRAC CG ' C!cvdaml Tractor Com 'wny- cl"'cl'ini!- ohio= i™ American Bo S d, "MIMAIOI" ma S ne,o; Tillotson "Y-MV carburetor: Vor.ox oil- </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Nebraska Tractor Tests • :.¦¦¦ ;i' : :- V- • : ¦:.'.¦¦' : washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 13", face 11", rated speed 943 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.87, second 3.05, third 4.44, reverse 2.28. ; ¦ ¦;. - : : j •¦ ' "¦ .¦• : . ¦¦¦.'; ' Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 259. CLETRIC BG, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 16 to July 10, 1936. Delco-Rcmy "645 II" distributor; Tillotson "Y-8-C" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face iVz", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 2.625, third 3.5, reverse 1.375. Comments: During the rated load drawbaf test, the action of the external parts of the governor mechanism became sluggish. To restore proper action, the dust was washed from the parts and the cam of the cam-and-followcr group was polished. Nest No. 260. CLETRAC AgJ Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio, June 16 to 26, 1936. ¦..".'¦' American Bosch "MIB4AI01" magneto; Tillotson "P-l-B" carburetor; Vortox oil - irasjial wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter lOVj", face 8!-i", rated speed 1166 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour, first 1.75, second 2.625, third 3.75, reverse 1.375. . : Comments: During the rated load drawbar test the tractor stopped three times. The air temperature at the time of the first stop was 103°F., at the second 107° F., and at the third 110° F. The temperature of the fuel in the fuel tank at the time of the first stop was 120° F. The initial boiling point of the fuel used, was 136° F. These operating conditions indicate that the stops were due to vapor lock. Test No. 261. CLETRAC E, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 16 to July 9, 1936. •.. . ... / ¦ American Bosch "MJB4A101" magneto; Tillotson "P-l-B" carburetor;; Vortox oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter lOVj", face BVz", rated speed 1000 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry. clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.125, second 2.75, third 4, tcvene 1.625. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 262. CLETRAC FG Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland Ohio; June 16 to July 16, 1936. American Bosch "MJA6BIO2" magneto; Tillotson "YXIBX" carburetor; Vortox in - take deflector and oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical "L'j head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulcy: diameter 24 V:", face 15", rated speed 509 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.5, third: 4.3. reverse 2.1. '¦'.'• - . j Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 263. CLETRAC FD; Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 15 to July 17, 1936. American Bosch "APE6BBO 8300591.. fuel system; Vortox intake deflector and oil-washed wire-filter air .cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical dicscl, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 24 'A", face 15", rated speed 535 r.p.m. | Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two - platc dry clutch! Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.75, third 4.25, reverse 2.125. . : i ' '.'.-.. </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 Comments: During the belt tests, the fuel line to No. 6 cylinder cracked. This line was replaced with a new one. Test No. 265. MASSEY-HARRIS CHALLENGER, Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; August 10 to 18, 1936. American Bosch "U4ED4VI" magneto; Kingston carburetor; own oil circulated over wool air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "I" head mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face 6'A", rated speed 831 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 1 1 fourth 8.3, reverse 3.0. Comments: No repairs or adjustments Tot No. 266. MASSEY-HARRIS PACEMAKER, Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin: August 10 to 10, 1936. American Bosch "LUED-tVI" magneto; Kingston carburetor; own oil circulated over wool air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Engine: 4 cylinder vertical, "I" head mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face 6'A" rated speed H3l rp.m Chassis: f,,ur wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Rated peeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 4 1 fourth rt.s, reverse .3.0. Comments: No repairs or adiustmcnts. Test No 267. OLIVER HART PARR ROW CROP 70 KD, Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa; August 20 to 31 193(i American Bosch "M186A302" magneto; Zenith "124!/, EX" carburetor; Donaldson electorand oil-washed wire-screen fi|, cr air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Enginer « cvlindcr vertical, "I head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter H,*r in •.",!&gt; S| , ,4 rpm- ChasS'S: four wh"ls- nvo drivc "' ""='&lt;»«l gear drive, Borg 8, Beck sing e-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.44. second 3.j2, third 4.33, fourth 5.58, reverse 2 44 Comments: Before any official belt data were obtained, the belt pulley bevel gear adjustment was checked It was found that one bevel pinion tooth was broken. This pinion was replaced with a new one. ino^r'ame ''" "'"* '"^ '"'' thc radir"°r KmP«™'* became Te« No. 269. McCORJVfICK-DEERING TO-40 (1750 r.p.m.), International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; September 3 to 15 1936 Own R, miK ne.o; Zemth ¦•50-AYI2" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter air 'T h ;; u, n z s „ f oy"T: Enßinc: SIX cylindcr vcrlical' "r haA- mount«J cranksha/t lengthwise. M, pulley: diameter 16!',", face 9", rated speed 645 r.pm Chassis: f nur wheels. ,wo drivers enclosed drive, own single-plate dry clutt" Rated speeds mi.es per hour: firs, 2.375, second 3.125, third 3.625, reverse 2.25 l.onimcnts: .No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 270. M-M TWIN CITY FTA, Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Company. Minneapolis, Minnesota; September 10 to 18 1936 American Bosch "M/B4102" magneto; Schebler ¦¦TTXI6" carburetor; Donaldson eiecor and oil-washed w re-screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugaj governor Enrine - our cylinder verfc-r head mounted crankshaft kngZue. pulley: dtmc" If) , face , ', , rated speed 6^o r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, t\vo drivers enclosed n^zJ^^rz.^" 3 nut was tisliicned °nc-sixih turn b=fore"« During this same test the sreering column support set screw in the steering bracket </seg>
         <seg id="p037">:,-.'. . Nebraska Tractor Tests and the steering bracket felt retainer became loose and a small amount of transmission oil worked out. I Test No. 271. CATERPILLAR |THIRTY (Distillate), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois: October 13 to 24, 1936. Eiscmann "CM--!" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire - screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face B'A", rated spccdB4o r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: fiat 1.7, second 2.4, third 3.0, fourth 3.7, fifth 5.4, ¦ reverse 1.9. ..-•;. . ¦.') - :' '.'¦-¦-'¦.'--' Comments: The water pump packing nut was tightened one-third turn before the rated load drawbar test was run. Test No. 272. CATERPILLAR THIRTY (Gasoline), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; October 13 to 23, 936. Eiscmann "CM-f" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire - screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face BVi", rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.4, third 3.0, fourth 3.7, fifth 5.4, reverse 1.9. Comments: Corrosion caused the governor control rod to stick in the governor bottle during the rated load drawbar test. The corrosion was apparently due to con - densed crankcasc vapor. -... .'¦.¦'. -. - Test No. 273. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-4, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, ..¦; Illinois; October 14 to 28, 1936. I . Own fuel {system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air.cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter |l2", face 8K", rated speed 840 r.p.m. Chassis: trackaycr, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.4, third 3/}," fourth 3.7, fifth 5.4, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. . - ¦¦. . :'. Test No. 274. CO-OP No. 3, Duplex Machinery Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, ' October 22 to November 5, 1936. \ . ¦¦¦.' . Auto-lite "GAR46OB-C-5" generator; Zenith "124'/S EX" carburetor; Donaldson : twister pre-cleancr and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; Pierce centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 14", face S%' r, rated speed 754 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, IJorg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.7, second 4,6, third 6.6, fourth 13.0, fifth 20.0, reverse 3.3. Comments: The pressed steel web of the fibre belt pulley failed during the pre - liminary belt test after approximately two hours of operation. This pulley was replaced with a cast iron one of the same size. Test No. 275. CO-OP No. 2, Duplex Machinery Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, October 22 to November 10, 1936. | Auto-lite "GAR46OB-C-5" generator; Zenith \2Wi E" carburetor; Donaldson twister 1 prc-clcaner and oil-washed wire-scfccn filter air cleaner; Pierce centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 14", face BJ4", rated speed 707 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, engine enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck single plate dry clutch: Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.7, second 4.7, third 6.8, fourth 14.2, fifth 21.3, reverse 3.5, Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 276. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL F-20, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 5 to 12, 1936. Own "F4" ¦ magneto; Zenidi .["K-5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; oivn centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "1" head, mounted </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 304 crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 14", face 6V 2 ", rated speed 654 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 2.75, third 3.25, fourth 375 reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>