<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1905-1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">m m o u &lt; a. &lt; u.' ± I o z ir j. Q &lt; O o oi U 5 I -3 &gt; o o </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BIENNIAL REPORT or the ,A, DJUTANT (GENERAL OF THU STATE OF NEBRASKA 1905-1906 Jason U i 'liiiiin. Printer I'Diversity Pl»ce, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">ADJl'TAXT CKXKKALS REIH)KT 3 SUMMARY, ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT Hon. .lolin H. M lor and ('miiiiiaiiili'i in-Cliii Sir: — I have the Ik military d RESERVE MILITIA. The enrollmea i&gt;( the Milit .lied with iniiilii. and Mi ■I. making a total n uch could led uiK)ii for n NEW MILITARY CODE The enactment ot a new militia la tabling his departmen for a ider BeM il the Nebraska Na - il Guard. I l&gt;pro]&gt;riat)'d by thi this et, the Giutrd will !&gt;«■ placed m ORGANIZATION. But slight eh. in ply with the ni'W law. companies and a band \. Troop A, 9 any. and two I The Kushville and the H .1 for the i&lt;', tn of I Under tkia section al A. V. Cote, of i * tOffle- I under tl time of war or imniinem EQUIPMENT. LThe Guild is eqolpped with conii kitchens and nu ss, wltl . for each </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ADJUTANT GENERAL 8 KKCOHT 4 .nits with common ' v with magazine rifles, and each regiment with twel. tor nailery pnu IWlHm nffii h company for ! man, one uniform of blue ami one of khaki, half, out- poncho, a m. a haversack. .111. There are in tin- store room. when en suf clothing, oven ,i kitchen furniture, and folding latrine The Ambulance Compan) is equipped with two ambu e field capital of i«&gt; bospitai tents, flies, -inilo bars and nettings, and chairs, commode chest. light appa ne dispensary complete, con - iniiij: a ined, • rilizins che«t ; one hos - .iin] fly, beald&lt; ipment, fifty-six hospital iouc: - The company is ell prepared liy drill, dl (• the field on short The H equipped for field elng supplied, in ddition to the usual oompanj equipment, with fifty i &gt;lvers, cal - the officers; rubber id glass insulatot of wire with the necessary il tools for constructing aphs with shutters, field buz - rs. carbide i lightning arresters, tape in - llai The facilities offered by the Corps for rapid Mimication at encampments and i has justified the expen - tures necessary for the equipment. In the hurried concentration of Signal Corps would render quick and valuable service. I There should be an appropriation made, sufficient to pay some trusty in in each roni|&gt;any. for at least fi\ i month, whose duty shoiil.. : the equipments belonging to that com - ind.. AID TO SAN FRANCISCO On ■ • of War to your request for permission to fsti -an Francisco. i|tiatermaster stores ;onal Guard, for the use of the suffering • instructed by wire and telephone I blankets to the Depot Quarter - mast' 'luipments were shipped within tortjr-etgfcl h i&gt;t ot the news of the earthquake disaster of Apri </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I ADJUTANT GENERAL'S UKI'OKT Requisition was made for conical tents and olive drab blankets in lieu of those sent to San Francisco, which were furnished by the War la - ment about the first of July. ENCAMPMENTS. The annual encampment ol '■ m the Watson ranch three miles west of Kearney, and adjoining Industrial School. The Industrial School. The Nebraska National Guard was assemble* liis point, anil organized as a ■llent ritle range was s&gt; liled the mark - tinction by making the necessary ompany dining the prec&lt; brigade, under my command. An the north bank of the Platte River, wh of the (Juard. who had gained » 1 • at the rifle practice requiri of months The citizens of Kearney furnished lumber for latrines, and a portiea of the encampment the cani|i grounds, hay and straw, the wagon f ransiK)rtation free for Major Cecil, of the Thirtieth 8. In ! the War vain. during the en- liepartment as ii nd rendered campment. For further details of the encampment, you are respectfully referred to the re|K&gt;rts of t! and the heads of ti ments. hereto attached and marked "Exhibit On invitation of tli. ) of War, the Cuard. with the ex&lt; ■ ot the Kushville Rifles, took part in the Camp of Instruction and A Maneuvers at Fort Riley. Kansas, in August, lyml. By request of the colonels commanding the two n-gimenis. you directed me to assume com - mand of the h lie allotment for tl tor the entire command, ami pa) for the I - made by the War Department from the Arm) Appropriation, thus relieving from that expense Tl'. Miis lour of duty, by the brigade commander, is attached to and made a part of ibis report, marked "Exhibit B." The Rushville Rifles, under command of Captain Erui . was directed to march overland to White .Judge Westover'i ranch. 01 - station o ■Octotx instructions during the encampment, a rc-i&gt;ort ot the company commander is Into cat. . ii to their iliis camp an.. n field work and camp duties ■led and marked "Exhibl At the I commanding officer of the Ambulance lish an emergency hospital on thi ling the £ Fairs of 190r&gt; and 1 **o*;. and make thi ,il for their pi dance and ojitratioi ighly complini - .iy the officers of tl I thousands of peep attendance. The appropriation made by t 1 (. and the Com I instructed to ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">AD.ll TAM GENERAL s UF.Poli 1 6 the minimum, i one-half in and from en- inspei and I- 11 iliis direction RIFLE PRACTICE M hioh McLanghlln, M. Btrkoer i Girt, where }.. » K I ni thirty- i: nd Hi I' ion for the ion for thp I.i E. H If. Mullowney, HinI Mil ■ I at Ccilumlms from coin- » ( niilms from iy who li inarksmai IVe marksma Tin n \v Kille Team i;ille Team E II. Mttllowi .tin I &lt;; Workizer. lain S I it tile Qn: ttie Quart with the Adjutant i the Naiional • mipeUns. i wing A X. I i'i tlie Nationa ar, showini; Fre- Fr. n. Fr -tioiif iloable informa lion gained on point with Meal. Th&lt;- id the : in rifle i I w &lt;" to th&lt; mill i &gt;ar of 1 1 1 ■ li plenty of time and with plenty of time and but the young mai is deprived of this | li the now rifle anil mi h. w \\\\- OFFICERS OFFICERS' SCHOOLS. SCHOOUS ■an of Ihe i succeed s put inlo • aptain </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Adjutant generals report Marcus D. Cronin of the 25th I*. S. Infantry, as instructor at both terms, ring the period of this report, who presented the subjects under con- Hideration with great clearness and force, illustrating the various points I mm a storehouse rich with experience in active service. The school of was convened in Representative Hall in June and covered a wide range of subjects, including Administration. Small Arms Firing Regula - tions. Drill Regulations, Military Law, Minor Tactics, Field Engineering, Map Reading. Fire Discipline, and Camji Sanitation. The school of 19m; uaa held in February, in order that the officers might be the better pre - pared for the government and state insi&gt;ections immediately following. Profiting by the criticisms made by the inspectors of the previous ft end deficiencies noted at the annual encampment, a wider range of jectt was considered, and special attention was paid to the errors com - mitted, and questions least understood. The evenings were devoted to papers on military topics and disci \ large portion of the officers showed their appreciation of the advantages offered by the state, by close application and an effort to i&gt;erfeot tti. (of the duties for which they were commission. .1 I As a rule, the Guardsman is an active member of society and is called to perform his part in the numerous other organizations that abound rery town. He is unable to make himself sufficiently numerous to ily with all demands. During the winter months, the military feature lly suffers most, and interest lags in this department until spring, i recruiting becomes brisk. With a view to maintaining the interest % military lines, a corresiiondence school has been started by this rtnient. covering the topics of most importance, and will be continued lgh the winter. Many of the officers are responding promptly, and plan of disseminating information is meeting with encouragement. K Special attention will be given to squad drill during the indoor season, an for competitive squad drill has been adopted, with a design to de - li the squad and make it as prominent a feature in company drill as it be in active service. ARMORIES. The increase of armory rent under the new law has lessened the financial burdens of the companies, but yet does not provide a perman - ent home so much needed to induce desirable recruits and retain inter - eat and pride in the company. With the hope of creating a sentiment favorable to the building of company or battalion quarters, I have advo - cated the organization of an association to build a memorial armory at the station of each company, that should be dedicated to the deceased soldiers of all wars, who are or have been at any time, residents of the county. This plan has met with favor from the Grand Army and other similiar organizations. Klank Articles of Incorporation were sent to the company commanders a year ago, to be followed by plans for the construction of a memorial armory, with instructions to enlist the co- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKPORT 8 operation of public spirited men in the community, in this enterprise. Patriotic organizations have assisted in creating public sentiment in many towns and cities, favorable to the consummation of this project. Yet there are funds needed to pay for the draughting of proper plans, and the presentation of the subject by a com)&gt;etent officer, in order to secure definite action. 1 am of the opinion that it would be wise to pro - vide by law for the levying of taxes or voting of bonds for the erection of an armory that could be used for company quarters and the exhibition of war relics of historical interest, and for other public purposes. CAMP GROUNDS AND TARGET RANGE apparent that if the National Guard is to be a stable and effective organization, and form a reliable national reserve force, more adequate provisions must be made for its maintenance. A permanent camp ground and target range should be purchased. If properly select - ed, the site could l&gt;e made fairly remunerative to the state, and the money ex|&gt;ended each year in preparing camp grounds, could be put into permanent improvements Government money is now provided for the construction of rifle ranges owned by the state. Nebraska should avail herself of this opportunity to secure assistance by the expendi - ture of n* to meet government requirements. Every ar - mory is expected to be provided with a gallery for target practice and the young men encouraged to practice in the gallery and on the state range. Camp discipline and target practice not only fit young men for valuable service to their country when needed, bill has a moral effect far reaching, for no man can well earn and retain an expert marksman's badgs, unless his habits have torn such as to insure a steady hand and unerring sight. PRACTICE MARCHES. Companies comprising the National Guard of this state were di - ■ I to make a practice march of at least ten miles in the month of July, and at other convenient intervals; to pitch shelter tents and to cook at " meal, individually or by squads, on each occasion. The company commander was required to select a commissioned or non-commissioned officer to make a detailed map of the road over which the command should pass, showing the st reams, woodland, culti- I lands, and the fBBjwal terrain of the country, to be forwarded with the re|K&gt;rt of this tour of duty at the close of each march. These expe - ditions are intended to develop the ability of the company to care for itself in actual service, and to teach the commanding officer self reliance. SPANISH WAR CLAIMS. Having failed to secure from the state, pay for Troop A at the close of the Spanish-American War. for the i&gt;eriod intervening between the time the Troop ». led under the first order, and the muster </seg>
            <seg id="p010">AD.UTANT GENERAL'S KKI'ONT 9 Into V. S. service, at the rate allowed by the state, I visited the War Department in the winter of 18M, and found there was some hope of securing it from the government, lint having re-entered the service later in the year, the claim was allowed to rest until I returned from the Philippine service. The time havin claims, it was necessary to appeal t expired for the payment of state tins. The investigation of the account i other organizations were also entitled ing to your attention, you immediat additional pay at the state rates for Third Regiments of Infantry. I'nde )f Troop A, disclosed the fact that to additional pay. This fact com - iok measures to secure the Troop A. the First, Second and your directions, a copy of the records from this office were furnished the attorneys at Washington enabling them to successfully prosecute the claim, resulting in the collection of the following net sums: Troop A, fl.019.S3; 1st Regt. $4,046.02; 2nd Regt., $:!.'&lt;■ d Regt., $22,596.21. making, a total sun of $:: cd for distribution to the soldiers of the Spanish American War who m the state organizations, which was re - ceived and deposited by you, subject to check, us soon as individua allowances for members of these different commands were proprlj recorded in this office. Checks have been drawn on the ftbove funds, up to and including December SI, 1906, to the amount of $7,911 The large amount remaining unpaid is due to the recent allowance of the claim for the Third Regiment, and the difficulty of reaching the scattered remnants of the other commands Reference to our corre - spondents indicates that the Nebraska contingent of Spanish War vet - eran is represented in nearh In the Inion. RECORDS The muster in and out rolU in this state from 1X61 up to the pres 1 of the volunteer forces enlisted put time, as well as other records of historic value, are beeotnii compiled and rebound, and th&lt; y worn, and should be carefully lary appropriation should be made omplete all records while the evi - : year will lessen the opi&gt;ortunity of perfecting the records so long to enaMe this office to examine and c deuce is obtainable. Kach succeeding for correction, and add to the difficult' neglected. CONCLUSION. For further information yon ctfully referred to the re|&gt;ort and tabulations herewith submitted As the time approaches for the close of our official associations, I desire to express to you my grateful appreciation for the uniform court - esy and evidence of confidence manifested on all occasions. Realizing that 1 would nave your approval, backed by your characteristic firm- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT new, in all laudable efforts to raise the standard of the Guard and make it an efficient force, this department has l&gt;een encouraged to greater exertions in the effort to prepare, equip, and discipline the Guardsmen fur the more important duties that may await them To the general staff and th iated with Be in this depart - ment, I wish to express my thanks tor their faithful anil efficient •Mistance. I. H. CULVBR. Adjutant General eapectfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">ROSTER NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD JOHN H. MICKEY GOVERNOR AND COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF THE GOVERNOR'S STAFF Name Jacob H. Culver Adjt. Gen Brig. (ien. Feh -incoln Colonel Jan. 9. '03 Fairbury Colonel Jan. '■&gt;. "08 Lincoln Colonel j Jan. », 'M Columbus Colonel Jan. !t. 'M Stanton Colonel Jan. B, M Superior Colonel Jan. I, 'M Hastimjs Colonel Jan. !•. "iKt Tecumteh Colonel Jan. 9, 'M Lincoln Colonel Jan. aha Colonel Jan. &lt;■&gt;. 'M WakeKeld Colonel Jan. », o:t Red Cloud Colonel Jan. naha Lt. Col. Jan. 1, 'M Lincoln Lt. Col. Jan. 1, 'M Fremont George E. Jenkins Charles J. Bills Carroll D. Evans y. M. &amp; jCom'y Gen I nap. (ien. Surg. (&gt;en John A. Ehrhanlt Judge Adv (ien. Clarendon E. Adams Aide Clarence J. Miles Aide Jacob S. Dew Aide Samuel M. Melick Aide Joseph VV. Thomas Aide Herbert P. Shumway Aide Charles W. Kaley Aide Theodore W.McCullougb Aide John G. Workixer Aide Fred H. Richards Aide &lt;r Major Ernest H. Pbelps, Asst. Adjt. (ienl.. Lincoln, August 17, 1U03 Captain Samuel D. Davis, Asst. Q. M., Lincoln, May 1, liX' * MILITARY BOARD Brigadier General Jacob H. Culver, Adjutant General, President Colonel Joapeh A. Storch. First Regiment Colonel John C. Hartigan, Second Regiment, Recorder Colonel John A. Ehrhardt, JudSaAdvocate General Du * R » nk Com»f»°ion »•««• </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 AIUL'TANT GENERAL S REPORT BRIGADE HEADQUARTERS ADJUTANT GENERALS OFFICE, LINCOLN, FIKST REGIMENT OF INFANTRY-FIELD AND STAFF Headquarters, Fullerton orgi.niyed by (ieneral Order No. 4. July It, 1HM1 Joseph A. stun h Colonel. Fullerton. July IS, 1H04 Fred (Jegner. Lieutenant Colonel, Madison, .luly M, 1906 W. Edmund Baebr. Major. Omaba. Octoter 1*. 100*1 James J. &lt;&gt;rimin. Mujur. Wilber. August 5. 19416 (ieorge A. Eherly. Major. Stanton. August t, l!*(Mi • ieorire H. Holdeman. Captain. Adjutant. York, July 22, 1004 Arundle M. Hull. Captain. (Quartermaster. Fremont, July :U, 1MB Otis E. Davit. Captain. Commissary, David City. July M, l»04 Fletcher M Sisnon. Captain. Chaplain. Omaha. March 20, 1905 Frank s Nicholson. Major, Surgeon, Lincoln. August 11, 1004 James B Hungate. Captain. Assistant Surgeon, Weeping Water, July 81, !'.«« Emile C. t'nderlurg. Firtt I.ituitrnnt. AfHfctsnt Surgeto. Stanton Augast M, 1 SON COMMISSIONED STAFF James H. Duncanson Sergeant Majoi . South Omaha, August «, 1904 John F. Steele. (Quartermaster Sergeant, obitina. July 1, llHiti Morgan 1. Flaherty. Commissary Sergeant . Kullerton. August I, 190S Hospital Steward -mith. Color Bcrgeant, Fullertcn. February 14, HH'ti Milton E. Cornelius, Color Seigeant. Lincoln. July -.'6.1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 13 FIRST REGIMENT OK INFANTRY Station, Original Date of Muster Date of Commission Rank Officers Co. A York Elbert (i. Buttertield William A. Myers William E. Oshorn Captain 1st Lieut, ■-'ml Lieut Jan. IT, 1908 Jan. 17, 1906 Jan. it, mm June 1, 1XM Co. B [ver S. Johnson Howard H. Antics William N. Orris Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Auk. -~. 180ft Auk- *T. 1906 Aug. 27. 1906 Stanton Jan. 2, 190-.! Co. C .lease C. Pen rod Walter E. SLinih.ll Chester R. Macy Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lifiit Jan. 15. 1906 July 81, 1906 Dec. 4. 1905 Beatrice June 1 . 1M81 Co. D Frank If. Smith Captain July is, 1906 Co. D Frank If. Smith Captain Jut Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Weeping Water June •"&gt;. mm Weeping Water Kicbard V. McDonald lm Lieut. Jane 1, 1906 Richard V. McDonald Walter J. Schneider Jane 5, lmm Walter J. Schneider nd Lieut. Nov. 11. 19U5 Co. E John H. Linton ("apt. tin Auk. •"'■ 1906 Co. E Wilber John H. Linton Jacob C. Ferguson Joseph L. Grimm Captain Aug. 5. 1906 Aug. ft, 1906 Aug. 5. I9t« Wilber Jacob C. Ferguson 1st Lieut. Aug. 5. 1906 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Dec. 27, 1- Joseph L. Grimm 2nd Lieut. Aug. 5, I9(&gt;6 Dec. 27. 1N«* Co. F Charles E l-'raser ain Aug. 13,1904 Co. F Charles E Kraser Ivan McKay Captain Aug. It, 1904 June 13, 190B .Ian. 3. 1906 Madison Ivan McKay 1st Lieut. June 13, I '.mm; Madison 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Aug. T, Ml Harry B. Hobbs 2nd Lieut, .lan. 3. 1906 Harry B. Hobbs Aug. 7. 1HI».-) Co. (J Co. (i Kalph A. Bringman Captain Aug. 31. 1903 Ralph A. Bringman Claude M. Chenoweth Harry E. Ford Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Aug. 31. 1903 Jan. 31, 1901 Oct. U, 1905 Geneva Genera Claude M. Chenoweth 1st Lieut. Jan. 31, 1901 Apr. IK I- Harry E. Ford 2nd Lieut. Oct. IB, 1905 Apr. IK. 1KK2 Co. H Nathaniel L. Moore Captain July M, 1906 Co. H Nelson Nathaniel L. Moore John M. Crandell Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. July 88, 1906 July 88, 19IW Nelson John M. Cntndell 1st Lieut July 2X. 190K June 1, 1h*1 2nd Lieut. Jane 1, 1W1 Co. I Louis W. Ohmstede Captain 1905 Co. I Louis W. Ohmstede Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Oct. 25, 1905 Wahoo Wahoo 1st Lieut. Feb. 20, 1900 Charles E. Ault 2nd Lieut. Oct. 25, 1905 Feb. 20. ISttKi Charles E. Ault Oct. 25, 1905 Co. K August Wagner Captain Mar. 10. 1904 Co. K August Wagner John II. Brock Captain 1st Lieut 2nd Lieut. Mar. JO. 19(U June 22, 1805 June 8, MM Columbus Columbus John II. Brock let Lient June 22, 1MB June 3. 1X96 Hillyard C. Wilson 2nd Lieut. June 8, MM June 3. 1896 Hillyard C. Wilson Co. L (iuy D. Solomon Cartain Nov. !t, 1MB Co. L (iuy D. Solomon Cat tnin 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Nov. 9, P.MMi Jan. 2!t. 19W Jan. 29, 1906 Omaha Char'es L. Burmester 1st Lieut. .Jan M, l'.nr, Omaha Char'ee L. Burmester Halph S. Edmunds Dec. 1H. 1H93 Kalph S. Edmnnds 2nd Lieut. Jan. 29, VM»&gt; Dec. 18 Co. M Edwin C Pickett Captain July 22, 1!HU Edwin C Pickett Lilburn F. Oxford George L. Dean Captain July 22, 1!HU July 29, 1904 July 24. 1 !«&gt;.-. Broken Bow Lilburn F. Oxford .1st Lieut July 20. 1904 list Lieut. '2nd Lieut May 1«, l«9ti (ieorge L. Dean '2nd Lieut. July 24. 1 !*&gt;.-. Band Wianer Harry Pritcbard 2nd Lieut. May 1. 1905 Aug. 24. 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT SECOND REGIMENT OF INFANTRV-FIELD AND STAFF Headquarters, Fairbnry Organized by General Order No. \ August 13. 188? ■l.ihn C. Hartigan. Colonel, Fairbury. January 24, 1906 Oliver (• Osborne, Lieutenant Colonel. Oinaba, January 24, r.*» Fred .1. Mack. Major. Albion. May 1*&gt;. ! Herbert J. Paul. Major. St Paul. February 10. 1906 Walter F. Sammons. Major. Kearney, February 20, lHOfi H. Elton Clapp, Captain, Adjutant. Steele City, August 11. 1904 Elwin E. Culver. Captain. Quartermaster, Sutton. September 2(1. IMS Tbomaa A. DeNoon, Captain, Commissary, Lincoln, January 24. 1906 John E. T uttlp Captain Chaplain. Lincoln. May 17. \'MC Major, Surgeon George A. Heatb. Captain. Assistant Surgeon. Daykin, January 24, 19U« Charle* E. liiblxjn Lieutenant. Assistant Surgeon. Kearney. January -,'4. l!HNi NUN COMMISSIONED STAFF Lon C. Kesterson. Sergeant Major, Fairbury, June 1, 1908 George A. Withers, (^nartermaster Sergeant, Lincoln, July 28, 1906 George H. Howe. Commissary Sergeant, Beatrice. July 28, 1906 George E. Spear, Hospital Steward, Ingleside, June 1, 1906 Jasper F. Cole, Color Sergeant, Aurora, June 1, 1906 Edward J. o Shea . Color Sergeant, Lincoln. June 1, 190A </seg>
            <seg id="p016">AIUITANT GENERALS REPORT 15 SECOND REGIMENT OF INFANTRY Station. Original Date of Muster Date of Officers Rank Commission Co. A Jacob Kanzler George A. West J. Fred McNee Captain 1st Lieut. Jnd Lieut. July 5, 1906 Aug. », 1901 July 5, 1908 Kearney May fl, 1H»1 Co. B Willard 3. Paul Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut Feb. IT, 190K July 11, 1908 Feb. 17, 1908 St. Paul ■lames A. Crawford Walter B. Steen Sept. 38, 190U Co. C Samuel F. Shannon .lack Benson Captain 1st Lieut. .'ml Lieut Oct. 5, 1904 June 8, 1908 Oct. 5, 1904 Nebraska City May 24 Clyde E. McCormick Co. D H.irrv J. Engels Lewis R. Lambert Joseph F. Hulka Captain 1st Lieut. Jnd Lieut June in. 1906 May 9, 1905 July 81 . 1905 Fairbnry May H, 1hn~ Co. E Albert H. Barker George P. Thomas Walter T. Beum Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. June 20, 1U0H June 20. 1S0K June 20, 1906 Tekamah Aug. !!•. l»01 Co. F William C. Ramsey Montie E. Lum Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut June 25, 1908 Feb. 19, 1908 July 24, 1905 Lincoln April 22. 1X!K&gt; Glenn C. Fancher Co. G Allan D. Falconer Earle C. Hervey (Juy V. Furay Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. July 27. 1903 Sept. 21, 1908 Sept. 21, 1903 Omaha Oct. 17. lHSCi Co. H Aurora Otis M. Newman Anton Henriksen Myrl S. Mather Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Feb. 4, 1903 May 24, 1904 May 24, 1904 Jan. 9, 1HSW Co. I Julius A. Wiig Bayard T. Eller Bert McMahill Captain 1st Lieut 2nd Lieut. May 14, 1908 May 14, 1906 May 14, 1U08 Omaha Nov. 11, 1901 Co K Charles H. Johnson James F. Haghberger William L. Koltn Captain Aug 9, l»o-t Auk. 1. 1905 Aug. 1 , 1905 Schuyler 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. July 6, 1887 Co. L Alma Martin C. Shailenberger Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lient. Apr. II, 1905 April 11. l«0.-) Otho E. Shelburn Mar. 12, 1906 Wilbur S. Price Captain May 24, 1905 May 24, 1905 Aug. 7, 1906 Co. M Albion Edmund H Mullowney Howard B. Heath 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. Dec 21, 1898 Hand George W. Gregg. Jr. Oaceola 2nd Lieut. May 1, 1905 Oct. 14, 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 ADJl'TANT GENERALS UEPOKT FIELD ARTILLERY. BATTERY "A Station Original Date of Muster KanK Commission Officers Clinton W. T. Garrison Captain .June 23, 190« Kymore .hie P. Temple jv. IS. I87S ha B Jackson 1st Lieut. June ,':(. 1!K)6 1st Lieut. Aug. 1. lltoti 2nd Lieut. June 1H. 1&lt;M)4 Frank E Crawford CAVALRY TROOP' 1 A Station Original Date of Master K»nlr Date of KanK Commission Officers* AUiert 8. Hisey Captain Dec. 15, 1906 1st Lieut July 25, 1301 2nd Lieut. Milford William 8. Baldwin July 1 SIGN A 1 CORPS Station Original Date Rail, Date of KanK Commission ( )fticers of Mn-tf&gt;r Louis H ' Captain lApr. », l»0ti Ut Lieut Apr », 1!K*&gt; 2nd Lieut. Apr. 9, l»06 Fremont | Henry A. Jess Mar William C. Mallonee AMBl'LANC E COMPANY Station Original Date nf Mueter Rank D&amp;ta of Kank Commission &lt; )rticern John M. Birknur Major May 15, MM Captain Lincoln Feb. 10, 1903 John F. Spealman 1st Lieut. May 15. 1905 KISHVILLE RIFLES Station Original Date of Muster Rank Date of KanK Commission Officers Ernest Aubert ain July 8. 1905 1st Lieut. July 8, 1905 2nd Lieut. Apr. 8, 1905 Roabville Charles L Hopper Apr IS, HKtt Lee Fritz </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 HASTINGS RIFI BS Station Original Date Date of Commission Officers Rank or Muster Hastings John P. Madgett George E. Boggs Everett W Swart/ j Captain 1st Lieut. -2nd Lieut July 2, 1906 July 3. 190« July ■&gt;. l«0« July 2. liMKi RETIRED I 1ST Brig. -Gen. A V Cole, Hastings An. Brig. -Gen. L W. Coiby. Beatrice, Aug. 8, I9M </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 18 REPORT OF COL. C. d. BILLS, INSPECTOR GENERAL. Lincoln, Nebraska. November 80. 1806 To The Adjutant (&gt;• Lincoln. Nebraska Sir . 1 have the I i tun it of the Nebraska National (iiiard |H&gt;rt of the inspection UThe in- ! r.«'-"&gt; was made t-, of It n March 10th aa neral Orders No. 3. I April 15th, by the various officers designated in said Older, aad uataltaneoaaly with that made, by General I" S \ Retired . who had lieen designated by the Sec - rotary of War to make tin- Iaapu liim for the War l)e|iurtment. The num - ber pr&lt; - -h inspection wan .i^ (oil 1st Re^iim-nt Infantry -Headquarters, IS; Band, H; Company A. 15; OMqMBJT H. !A . t *« ■ i 1 1 1 &gt;; i n \ C, 44 ; Company 1). M; » ] &gt;;in&gt; E, not in - spected, account small pox; &lt;'.myuuy K. tt; Coaapany (i. not inspected. account armory Imrnt : Company li, ;!.'. Ooapany I. Owafaay K. Ml; Company I npany M B. iml Heximeiit Infantry HeadqMOten, 11. Hand. MrfTnmpMIJ A. 34; i'omi&gt;any IS; Compauy U. ;t.") . &lt; 'om]iaiiy K. 2fl; Coin pany mjiany &lt;t. .")1 ; UaiDpaBy H, 41: Coni|«ny I. 26; Company K. W; Coinjiaii: Mpaay M Bati nal Corps, M; Amtiulaiue Company .ishville Rirl.- Kl At this ins]Kftn&gt;n the enlisteil men and cominissioiieil othcers w«re allowed $1 00 j- k nuinlierof deri&lt;ieniie&gt; was noted in he equipment and laymteJ by tin- lna|iu Illlg otticers : the common tents used by the ■ nhtrtwl men nil.- liailly worn, and aiiuie were mil - ewed. sh i 1 not haw taken of them on the return roui camp. In obediei - 1905, 1 attended the an - nual em-ampinem at K. arm&gt; and acted as HriKaile I—pwrtnc at OMB) Amasa refill inapection, under the direction of the Brigade ■ the tii-st and sconii! regiments of infantry. Rushville Kirles Signal Oil pi. Amlmlanre Coaapany, liatteiy A. and a detachment of Troop A. each mornint; and evening, and found a marke&lt;l improvement over previom encan Many new features had l»*en added in camp sanitation, win, wai and m I in the care of com - pany, streets, tents, kitchens and latrine, throughout the camp, with the exception of that of I which waa not up to the standard required. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 ■ The discipline and mora rommendabie ; do die ly i indiM.1 rame radar my observation daring the entire encampment The tour of duty en arranged by the Brigade Command furnish instruction in duties that would devolve on the rroojis in a service, and was we) i Th Quartermaster aixl Comin spection given by 1 1 1- for the liwpectors criticism ir Close and extended order drill and to interest the men, am! the command when the encampment closed A not hi inane\iver- • itlinent change liad fairly gotten down to hard work •r week would have Urn much more sufficient appropriation bad not been profitable. and it was unfortunate tl t made to complete tile W .t y con value to this portion of the reserve f The inspection of IS made by field officers of the tw of appropriaton. only twenty- ti at this inspection, which was i he lack 1st Regiment tnfanl Company l&gt; :v\ Company &lt;;. 'i'i . Company II H (\&gt; ( ( I.. '£i&gt; ; Company M, IT Battery A, W; Signal &lt; Rifles, 45. Many bad storms the usual attendance. Men \\ rirle. complete, and cart i t t shelter tent, poncho, haver- sack, canteen, knife, fork, sjioon and •at can. one suit of blue and one nape tluri in former in - d was equipped with conical wall r khaki, and the equipments in liettei Daring the month of July, ti tents and stoves, olive drab woolen hi to replace those sent to the its and blanket roll straps r' the coni]ianies when rei|aired. Thus the National O'.iard of X rfore. and is ready to take the held The annual encampment of- 1901 Ills! :ilar servii mi. Very respectfully ll.lMi : the alertness and careful in- his snlmnli room he army n .lanuurv and Kebraarv and \\;i~ sillnwetl i«t man Fur attendance iny I!. 80; npunyK, ,'T Company 2nd Regiment Infantry: Band. IB; Cotnpiui li. (8; Company ( '. -,'ii . Company 1). :\ I : Company I 19; Cum l«nv O, in. Company H, 3H; CVunpanv I. 29 ; Company K. ■.'•"&gt;. Compai mpany II, M. Rnshville ity. whii'l 1 11 ■ ]&gt;]»■&lt; 1 with thi Mrthqn&amp;ke miffei we held in &gt;t m in the i|iiart Fort Rili rpertion was maile by ; Appre -iatin^' tli ■ m r c. .1. HILLS </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 ADJUTANT GENERALS KKPOKT REPORT OF COL. C. D. EVANS, SURGEON GENERAL SURGEON GENERAL'S OFFICK Nebraska National Guard Colambu*. Nebr. , Dec 1 lituti. I H. Culver Adjutant General iska National i 1 Bil I have the honor t" submit my report on the Medical Deparmenl of the Nebraska National Guard for the years I80S ami litoti. The markeil improvement in the Medical department of the National Guard of Nebraska since the ; - worthy of mention in this report. Th&lt;' character of the- oaken Bad enlisted men is such as to call for sonic consi deration officers .mil men have distinguished themsehras in the pro - giniiB of Military Medicum. Military Sanitation, and are developing rapidly in the scientific knowledge of how to prevent disease, as well as to combat r having inveated the indiviilna) or the camp I sanitary measures employed, drainage, water supply, removal of garbage, rare of latrines, policing company and regi mental quarters and ve all lieen so thoroughly considered that the death rate at camp or resulting therefrom, is nothing, and the sickness -g from camp lid- N s,. slight that it needs no further consideration in this report It was with \ lint 1 Mapoaalai to Oaawtal Orders No. ! &lt;nd reported for duty at Camp Aimisa Oofab, Kear - ney, Nebraska, on August titli. Arriving at Kearney in advance of the command, I ajaiated in preparing beadqnarten and locating the Field H&lt;« - pital. The tir-t and aecond mfciiaMiti were located ujHin ground sloping to ■nth. and aloatg a well traveled road running directly east and west The ('am] ranged that the Field Hospital could \h- situated almost in the center of the camp, comprising the Brat and second regiments, bat - tery, troop and signal oorfja. Thus as a matter of economy, and to batter drill the mad teal officers of the regimenta, the only hospital established wa~ the Field Hosptial The regimental surgeons, one being specially detailed for the troop, battery and signal eurjis. attended sick call at their respective quarters All that could not lie attended to in quarters were removed to iei,i BoafttaL For s]ie»iaJ comment CM sanitary conditions you are resjiectfnlly refer - rwl to the official re(&gt;ort of Major ( ieorge |{ Cecil. :«&gt;th I'.S. Infantn". 1 was pi i spdad to General Orders No 10. A. &lt;;. o. 1906 am report for duty August 4. IMS, to participate in the Camp of Instruction a Fort Kiley Kansas The Medical officers of the drat and second regiments were Biased in charge of the different trains to !»• on duty en route witl ular instruct! ~;i!iitation l'i&gt;on arrival at Fort Kiley thev assumed their duth mental siirgi-ons and through the courtesy a talBoi I" s. A ed, where the apaortajaity presented, t. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">AD.H'TANT (JEXEKALS KEPoKT 21 sjiecial duty in the V. S A. Field ottoar in the command an opportunity Hutpital, thus giving each and every for instruction in the regular service. ra.ska Hospital Corpi -rned a Field H.wpital No 1. of the Nel near the Field Hoprital, I' B • ■hi Hoapital No. I. m men of the Field H.rspitul, 1 munication with the regular s|&gt;ecial work in all departments. A . whereby ti md men of loselv associated with the officers and that they were continually in earn- ml had frequent opportunity for ictioii to me that while attending the maneuvers at Fort Kiley in August. 1906, I found the medical department, under the direction of Colonel HoflF. Assistant Surgeon tieneral.. V. S. A., carried out the same amusement in that camp, for the care of H4HHI men. as I had for our state trooi&gt;s at Kearney; one hospital, known as the Field Hospital. Those that could not lie cared for in quarter! were sent to the Field Hospital. Those that would require medical treatment beyond the camp I«*riod. were sent home or to tin- lias.- Hospital at the Fort, its the night lie. The medical department of tin- State of Nebraska has made rapid pro - ress in the past few veal's Through the untiring zeal of (ieneral Culver lie loyal rapport of the officer* of thi;dcpartnient. it has risen from the onnative iieriod to a permanent organisation, which is a credit to the and an honor to the nation Vet i uic things to lie secured. id further work to lie done to place this department on an indei&gt;endent noting, and to lie ready to meet the requirements of actual service, with - it injury to the individual soldier and I therefore l&gt;eg leave to make the allowing recommendations : t Every man in the Nebraska National Guard should lie supplied with shirts and two pair uf khaki trousers, and a cot to sleep Bpom. Clean » is the first law of nature— without cleanliness, no one can be sjuii tury, and even in the short time w weather— one not to exceed two dajn especially with the arduous duties of : sary. have for our cam]) life, in warm produces such a condition in men. ■oldier. tl: _&gt;■ of clothing is Again, our young men. leaving ted to sleeping on the ground, eq j hitmen, should not lie sub iallv in rainy weather. t The Ambulance Company should is for kitchen, and the hospital t &gt; camp, to see and know that they be supplied with better accommoda - ■nts should be insi*fted liefore going are free from leakage in the rain. ause of which we wish to prevent, is uiisanitan and I sincerely tThe character of disease and the &lt; llv 1 may say, due to the above in this your consideration. In conclusion. I wish to sjieak of the noble sentiment that characterizes and every memlier of the medical department at this time their loyalty to their pui-p&lt;&gt;se and the zeal with which they show their devotion to the state and to the nation. The standing of the medical officers, result - ing from competitive examinations, has placed Nebraska along with the regular service, anil a higher level following the prin- It \m-. a trrvut -"uric of satisf; </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SKUA I KEl'OlM i la t ion of which is the Army ;mil Navy School l UK. ami it is mv ambition to see it stand mvoih! to none in tin- States Adjutant ( miitti'il AliKOU. I). EVANS X S r. REPORT OF COL. J. A. EHRHARDT, JUDGE ADVOCATE GENERAL Stanton, Nebraska November '■'■ ltii it; - Supplement t. ibtnil tin 1 following that with yuur pero idati tii \\o a I this my hi eonial ..f th. Milil ■ liich 1 am a m lered orally n lent in ra at Cani| t tin i I tien t t that time for tin- full )&gt; a m ing that they had t UtOt mi) all -ti-lii gi It ha-. Ih-vh my ileNire t" ]&gt;1 Ill tin-. 1 the sii|&gt;i«'it "t Hi- Kv.IIimkv. the ( tlv lei rincipally ii tile Hi Eurt •» Martial, bat I 1 at ha\ Tli' my K ill iroiijjh inves which von ui&gt; the farmer captain du ■ ii it us there are n I iv ■ iiumend that I aathoril . in ,i Ulition t&gt;&gt; iiy il or at [nstruction, Fort Riley, illy, JOHN A EHEHAROT, ..neral </seg>
            <seg id="p024">AD.ll TAXT GENERAL'S KEI'OKT 23 REPORT OF BRIG. GEN. A. S. DAGGETT, U. S. A., RETIRED IN SPECTION OF N. N. G. I9O5. Extracts fnmi BMasoraoda of remark! of inflecting oAcer in coMMet - ion with the iaafjaetiaai of W86 &lt;if tlif Nefaranka National (iuard by Brig, ({en. A. S. Daggett. V S A . Retired). First Regiment of Infantry. r&lt;l— The band has lnul no instruction in foma for inspectioa, etc. It knows nothing alxmt railing pack*. It is a fine liaml of musicians rmpany A.— Company not well instructed The captain has been in command only alxmt two Booths, lias had some gallery practice rmpany B. — Officers and men manifest a fair degree of zeal. Could be depended upon for any kind of work Oosnpany baa had consider - able gallery practice and with good remit* A fairly gcxxl shoot - ing gallery well arranged rjmny C. — Officer* and men manifest a good decree of zeal. The com pany is in a creditable condition in every respect It oovld ho re - lied it|K&gt;n in caae of domestic trouble. rpikny D. — The ca]&gt;tain baa recently been appointed. He lacks zeal and efficiency and the men the same 1 think they would le reliable as far as they know in domestic emergency. rl&gt;any K Cccapany prohibited from assembling on account of small pox. rpany F. — Captain Fraser is intelligent anil zealous His company could be depended upon for any duty at any time The company has had considerable nailers practice, anil with giMid results. Is preparing for range practio condition. Captain I The Company is i; Factory among the l&gt;e&gt;,t officers in the guard. Has a good armory &lt; 'omiKiny (».- The armory of this impany was destroyeil by fire a few portion of its pniperty. The company weeks ago, including a largi WM not asscmlil.il rpany H. — Officers lack interest anil zeal in their work. ( 'oni]Ktny very poorly instructed. Could not )»■ depended upon in un emergency. rpany I —Neither officers nor men sec m to take any interest in their work. The captain is almost wholly ignorant even of the rudi - ments of his duties. No nailery or target practice is even thought of. rmpany K. The captain is intelligent, but does not give sufficient time to the instruction of his company. The oompaay has had a little target practi&gt; rmpany L The men appear fairly well They could probably l&gt;e de - pended upon in case of emergency. The captain do m to show the interest in his company he </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 Cv M H&lt;- livea sixty miles away and MM train did not arrive The lieutenants are nut intelligent and ■ difficult to conduct th&gt;- iaafMetioa properly. The captain is said to In- an intefligi ■ '■ The coinjuiny riwwi - of good work. The eomjmny has had some gallery pn Second Regiment of Infantry reunion is an excellent roaapaoy coininander, but somehow his coni]«any did not a]&gt; 11 as it did Mat He 1, ■ rwhelnicd with bai ently which may BC - unt for it Hi- has the capacity to BBCIOBMB one of the most eftici- His company coaid be aeawaMad aanau however, in case of ' rpany 15 -Officers and men ma and could be de]«ended upon in an emergency Tlie company has had ne gallery practice. Captain Paul is an intelligent and efficient officer. Lieutenant Paul is an unusually good officer rpan) ■ b and men manifest a fair amount of zeal a-id I think could l»e relied Bam in case of domestic trouble. rjiany I) Tliis ooaBaaay BM had no officer for some time, until a few days liefore iaapectioa. The new captain knows little or nothing aUmt military matters Property is scattered and it was impossi - bli .'tuni of it I have bean unable to obtain the papers that should accompany this memoranda Major Hartigan, of the same i ivho was pi f the thirty two men present and showed himself to lie a thoroughly competent officer. rpany E —The ■ .mong the liest in the Nebraska National Mid. The captain and lieutenants are tine officers ( Irlicers and men manifest a good degree of zeal and could lie lelied upon for any duty at any timt Captain Cameron is an esjiecially good ofti - - aboaj c.nnpleted The building used for an armory was blown down a few months ago. destroying con nible property. riany F — The captain is competent ; the men seem to have no respect fur his orders He ha- resigned. I'ntil a good captain is appointed, the company could not be depended npon for any kind of service. r.l men manifest a good degree of zeal They could landed ujion for any duty at any time On the whole it is the best BOBBpaay in the Nebraska National (iiiard Captain Fal coner is a superior ofticer The company has had no target prac no gallery pm rpany H . — Officers and men ma iL They could be depended upon in c ) Have had a very little gallery practice; BO target praet i Company I— This company lias changed captains frequently Captair Kro- - resent one. has a difficult task liefore him. He i- fairh I. Just al )&gt;&gt;■ should not want to • </seg>
            <seg id="p026">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKI'oRT 25 I ( T C)mi)any K.— The captain has been recently api&gt;ointed t.ut rimn a good degree of zeal and has inspired his men with the same The com - pany has had considerable gallery practice, and with good results. They have fine arrangements for practice. Company L — This company has just l&gt;een organized. All the property arrived on the day on inspection, and boxei were not opened. In - voices and marks on boxes showed a full supply. It has an excel lent captain and fine class of men, and baa bright prospects. Fifty - one enlisted men, thirty eight present. Three officers present. rmpany ML— Captain Mack is a superior officer ; his company could be depended mpsm for any duty at any time. This company has a fine target range, and has had some practice with good results Good work may be expected this comiag season ndependent Company.— This company has just Bean organized. It has a full supply of property in excellent condition It has g,*&gt;d men for officers but without experience; also, a fine class at men It pity this company could nut have a captain with military exper - ience. There are fifty enlisted men and three officers in the com pany ; forty-six enlisted men and all the officers wen present at inspection. Cavalry rp A— The lieutenant in command is ignorant of his duties The troup is drilled but very little and has had no target jiructi could not be relied upon for any duty. Artillery. ight Battery A. Officers and men maim . i degree of zeal and could, I balleTa, lie depended upon in case of domestic trouble I think Captain Yoder would develop into an efficient battery com mander. Signal Corps. '.iptain Henry and his officers and men are lealou anil efficient , they could be deluded upon for any kind of duty at all times Captain Henry and Lieutenant Richards are very fine officers and a credit to the National Guard of the country. Hospital Corps his corps is in a creditable condition in every </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 ADJl'TAN &lt;JKNERALS KKIH)KT 1 h il ■I REPORT OF BRIG. GEN. J. H. CULVER, COMMANDING PROVI - SIONAL BRIGADE, N. N. G. 1905 EXHIBIT "A IIKADyiAKTh KS PROVISIONAL I'.HICAIih amp Amasa Cobb. ( Amkh To the Adjiitam C&gt; Lincoln. Nebraska Sir: — In compliance with den command of tin- Provisional Hrlgj ■-tins of the First and S Rifles. Signal Corps. Ambnlai of Troop A (unveiled Nebraska *th, 1H iTitl Orders No It;, p. s.. 1 i I he Nebraska National (Jua nient of Infantry, the Rushvill. [inipany. Battery A. and a I). ■tuchmen i 15, c 8., A. G. ().. u The command went int. of Kearney, in h or n'ile north of I drain.*. at Watson s Kauri' miles w Industrial Scho jienth sloping uromid. affordit ■(•mi Wl •olive ient iir line of -oniimnv ki nientu and b; | • llent quality of water was found a moderate depth by this method, and tl iraiaaae The government ration » of other cooked provisions w the V M (' A., for the tit of the ad profit! lot ■ B tha ff du ipany drills an as I deemed it aH to drill and discipline uled order, outtiost duty and time h&lt;- i encamp such as nainalile a ni otll 1 b The larj;. land own* joiniuK. afforded excellent ppni i uni for maneuvers, and one day was liially divided, and Coloue •-d to this exercise 'I i ODBell placed in command of the lirown forces, and Colonel Storch &lt; • the Blue. Colonel Store -I io march with his command M a i&gt;oint thu the northwest and then proceed in the direction of the camp, with the apparent intention of attacking he same. Colonel McDonnell was dispatched to the northeast with his command, and di (1 to intercept the Hlue Ion they could reach their des tination. The terrain was admirably advptKl to develop the resources ■I—din ofti. | divided and subdivided by deep can and broken hillsides Both omnnai 1 handled ml all pit- wagons, and vender prohibited from camp A camp ex chaiiKf w«i iiruiiuiiiziini, to pine aid jiastiual land ad </seg>
            <seg id="p028">AlMt'TAXT OKNERAL'S KKl'OUT 27 t but the troops showed lack of experience in scouting, and the officers in many cases failed to take advantage marching his command in column of enemy's fire, until ruled out by the the necessity of devoting more tiim of conditions that may obtain in act of cover, one battalion commander fours along a o tlm lmpii • vationa proved Held i study la I The failure of the city of Ktanu portattoa retarded the detraining u y to furnish sir man nans - (i entraining of the command, bin with this exception, the work was well handled by the quartern; deportment, showing knowledge and alertness on the pan of some of the officers that would do credit to the i my. The bus: methods adopted by the CommU • ral and the dispatch with v which rations were issued, di avoralile mention Hut few cases of sickness wt wing to the excellent location of the camp, the ex-elusive n- tion rations, and the careful inspe - ;ary conditions by the Surgeon Geiu (ion and watchful care of tin The movement of troops from t with General Orders Xos. 1.*. and IT 'amp Aniasii Cobb was in accordance 1 am under obligations to Mai Inspector, for many valuable sugge his daily round of duty. 1 aiso desi services rendered by Captains We II, of the 30th Infantry, V. B pstions and instructions, given during lire to express ray appreciation of the ?lsh and Palmer, of the Thirtieth I" i on maneuver day. Lieutenant Hen- S. Infantry, who acted as umpires on "f the i;Sth Cavalry. I n Nebraska, volunteered to act as aid( where. He was assigned to many and i i lent service, which was thorough ng Officer, and those of his command being on leave, and visiting friends aide, and made himself useful varied duties, and performed most lly appreciated by the Command re Military Secreta Washington. I). I them Division 1 have the honor to submit the following report on the encampment f the Nebraska National Guard, near Kearney. Nebraska. Atlgl 18th inclusivt (1 daring t h&lt;* encampment, Headquarters N. X. ( rPORT OF MAJOR G. R. CECIL, 3OTH. INF. U. S. A., CH'f I'M- 111 i rmrtrrr camp amasa cobb. Through Headquarters N </seg>
            <seg id="p029">AD.UTANT tiKNKKAL S RKPOKT 28 ment of the Missouri. Omaha Nebraska, Augv Kort Crook, to Lincoln. Nebraska, where I reported to the 0ov&lt; instructions. After a very pleasant call. 1 was inform represent a &lt; »l •'■ H. Culver. Adjutant General ol the siaie. wa already at Kearney, and that 1 would receive ins I left Lincoln for Kearney, where I arrived ■boul 11:45 p. m The nex iDorning. August sth. I went out to camp and reported for duty. 1 was instructed to cull attention tt irregularities that I observed and lo aid him and all the officei - camp by advice, to the end that th it field *.» l^ and l-".. Headquartt Nebraska National Guard, providin. iichiui bllng of the troops thei' ral Orders 1 and J. llcadqti* Provisional Brigade National Guard, Kearney. Nebraska. Aug 1H05. instructions for the encampment anil for. All ot herewith enclosed with a quired by paragraph 1 of my instructions By the wa red by me late in ti On my arrival I found the Hri- Iquattf ted Regiment, the si and \ unimportant delays the troops arrived at Kean bv rail, direct from their hon* -■ hedule giv in G. i ■ but thei ing the ca •ral organizations on the Cotton Mill switch where they were d tiained. Although Um it companies that got into can too late that night to pitch theii ked for he nigl but the weather was flue and no great hardships resulted. From tr switch lo • I camps the distiii. from a half mile I ■ mile, and the hauling was don.- 1 &gt;&gt; local teams under an agreemei with a commitn •• Kearney. In this there was a gn of friction and some delay in that the many of the teamsters were unwilling to work after d The entire movement was under the control of the Adjutant Gene Taking the schedules of departure fiom their home stations I i • •rage time en route to include the arrival of their baggage in can to have been l&gt;etween nine and ten hours. They travled in regttl passes lies with ample room, with I r freight their baggage The entraining for their hoim ■ I even more than tr arrival in camp. The teams were not on hand to haul the ba the cars in time to make the connections scheduled, causing several ho delay in starting There was further delay in switching the cars I the Cotton Mill switch The last troop left Kearney about '■'•:&gt;») p. m. In compliance with paragraph l.adquari. ile profit to thf stai&gt; I was fun field hospital alv ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">AD.HTANT GENERAL'S KEPOKT 29 Encampment. he camp was located within the city limits of Kearney, on farm ilxmt t% miles to the west of the city proper. Along the northern imp site is a boulevard direct from the city one hundred Hie which afforded wood communication with the city. ited on a height to the north, which overlooks the camp. To the northwest the country is broken, much cut up with ravines, well suited Saturday, the 12th. was devoted to maneuvers around, which I will refer to again. The camps were made and broken without disorder and the wort was neatly and substantially done; the tents were well align. Unhappily no regular n icipated in the encampment for the presence of a battalion of Infantry, much more could have been irned by observation from a well disciplined organization Sewerage System tThe water was supplied from wells driven at convenient places ughout the camps and was of excellent quality. These wells w. ) that the) took only water that had filte levels beyond probability of infection tThe sinks of the opnoatti , amp from the kitchens were five a half to six feet deep and covered by tents. They were burned with mineral oil every day. under the direct supervision of the medical ers. I lie encampment was by brigade with the greatest possible latitude :ad. le glvea lo Ow regimental commander. Thy were permitted to lay out their own cam,! within a certain area wherein there was an abundance nf room foi I ..,, close a blue print of the ■ever*! campa from ■ map made by Lieut. F. H. Richards, of the signal ■orps. The grand has ■ natural slope southward from the boulevard to- vard Um I'latu- river, over two miles away, sufficient to drain. The amp was situated on what might he called the second mesa from the liver on land cultivated mainly in alfalfa, which had been very recently mowed. The general outlines of the camps followed very closely the diagram .1 the Infantry Drill Regulations except that the space between the com mny and battalion officers' line and the kitchen was reduced, and that &gt;etween the company officers' and Hie colonels' tents very much im did not obtain any satisla. ,„ for this change, though I iuquired. lutside the limits of the camps prof** there was ample room for all iinds of drill and ceremonies, by cutting off the grass there is space there or ten thousand men. The camp proper was made on the Mh and broken &gt;n the It'.th. The main line of the Union Pacific railroad passes by it. fd the Burilagton fc Missouri baTC a line to the city of Kearney. There • no iHimanent buildings within the area referred to, except five frame rwith necessary outbuildings shown on the blue print. The State Industrial School for boys, with five brick buildings is </seg>
            <seg id="p031">AIMITAM" OBNERALS RKPORT 30 Dm; mpment they were well cared for and when camp was ln-oken tin y were all filled and the camps neatly policed. I iiiade a careful insertion after the troops had gone, and I found the camps proper exceptionally well ]K&gt;liced and the rubbish incident to break - :ini|i had not lteeti left scattered over Ihe ground. Behind the first -linn-ill. tl-. MM rubbish around a hay stack that might ha\ moved with propriety, and some straw from bed - dumped in U I in front of the camp. The garbage was placed in bands and hauled away by contract. It was supp. lay, but this was not always done, and the oontn refill as they might have been in &lt; niptying the barrels, but there was not much fouling of the ground about ihe I i |H&gt;n the whole, from the beginning to the end. I wish tn oend the neatness of the camps and the careful attention to sanita - lion. The Suit ial, who was chief surgeon at the camp, made day .and sometimes 1 accompanied him: a 1 times 1 am sure nothing unsanitary was overlooked. The water used for drinking was not iMiiled. nor did there appeal be any good reason which required i! to be boiled. Clothing and Equipment. The men won- habitually the Khaki trousers, leggings, service hat and blue flannel shirt In n. ihe officers wore the service uniforms, (hough sometimes the blue shirt with the rank insignia on the shirt collar. Th&lt; ilation field equipments, blanket roli uidn. kit They did not have overcoats in camp. Paragraph •"&gt;. \2. Nebraska National Guard, prescribed the clothing and equipment, and 1 hav. son to believe this order was complied with. How Subsisted. :md cooked on the I". S Army field rang ally by the enlisted company cooks. I observed in several com - panies that cn ! in the kitchens; I did not Inquire whether or not they were regularly enlisted. The commissary general oi the state was in camp and made the issues to the regimental coin ■ &gt;i to the companies. The main iiortions of the ra - linns n the Chief Commissary. Department of the Mis soui. i vegetable*, and a few additional articles ned in open u. IjJ contract. I heard of a few complaints of the inefficiency of the rations, resulting mainly from the ineX|&gt;erienc-. - of the Company Cooks Bu&lt; Kin adjusted and altogether 1 An allowance of I went i day, in lieu of travel rations, wa to and from camp. Drills and Ceremonies. The drill- rled in the different organizations, including both ■ ednesday. Thursday and Friday they </seg>
            <seg id="p032">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 31 had drills every morning Me 1 each period being two hours. All of Saturday was Riven 0 Ter to maneuvers. There were drills Monday forenoon and a few organizations drilled on Tuesday. There was Ruardniounting every day except cuun and battalion parades od&lt; Mental parades on other Saturday in each of the regimental ■:igade parade on Sunday and In the drills and ceremonk ■ Iways apparent a lack of •Idler had been neglected and ar to be sufficiently familiar with the mus training; the school of ally the officers did not app Drill Regulations to make the nio of the time allowed them in the in- ■ion of the men. At the beginning I was discouraged, and upon my Mimendation, Lieut. \. . X. Hensley. l:!th Cavalry, a graduate of the «ho had volunteered hi^ was assigned to give in - struction in the guard mounting and guard duty During the last four of the encampment he supervised the guard mountings and spent I very large part of his time instructing the officers of the guard in their duties. Before the en:l of the encampment ihis influence was clearly per - ceptihle, not only in the ceremonial part, hut in the way the sentinels did their duties. There was a corresponding improvement in the parades, Ethe review for the (iovernoi y good. The marching ■ commanding officer*. Distanc ; i&gt;oor and a few were not in tr on Monday afternoon, the 14th, wa. - 1 and no serious errors were made by not well observed, the saluting ir proper pi: he maneuvers on Saturday oused the enthusiasm of (he men and work was |&gt;oor, and the attack forma- Es were weak and unsuppported, but I thing all men were able to n some ini|x&gt;rtant lessons in warfare from the events of that day. re was not to my knowledge any instructions given or practice had duties of advance and rear guard Tuesday was devoted to muste early Wednesday morning. and payment, and camp was broken Personnel and Discipline. immissioned personnel eav me the impression of an earnesi r duties, and that they were in the. I many of them said to me, they the time K) familiarize them.*-' I these ciK-.mipments are so shorl in camp. It is admitted that the to provide competent officers who ilge to properly instruct and care aptitude to instruct and command. lere were undoubtedly many who ire to learn what they could of Ihei I rice from patriotic motives, but a: e busy men at home and had not i all the duties of their fnuh * have not lime to learn them all it problem for the national guard i. - onlj he requisite knowle Iheir men, but have the D those I met a: this encampment t ild make good held soldiers uiulei have time for training and the i k required. In the short time that el thai I cannot in justice to myself proper guidance, but they must xperience to fully appreciate the 1 was with them among so many nor to them single out individuals irorkerd hard. Inn. the patrol </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ADJITAXT GENERAL s REPORT 32 a or depreciation. To condemn upon such short be fair to them: and to commend under such cir - uld be but little more than flattery. The best officer with upany of recruit* would appear to poor advantage, and none of these organizations were much more than recruiis. The enlisted met were generally quite youthful, many in camp for little previous training, but they seemed of good quality, capalil rtag instructions and of rendering good servce if called ii|K&gt;n to take the field. Guard Duty. I ti|x&gt;n under the head of ceremonies and the ■a »il siin, -wered here. The guard duty was not well performed: the officers and non-commissioned officers were not gen - erally well instructed, not inels familiar with their duties iard for the first time and but few performed in I tour in this camp, yet during the last days under the influence of Lieut Hensley ti marked improvement. Target Practice. The* nifi located about two miles to the south of the camp: where competitors competed for places on the team selected to . trt, X. J. This competition was completed about the time of the beginning of the encampment and the team with alternates continued to practice on the range until after the encampment 11. There was no other target practice engaged in by the troops i for this encampment. The range is ample for a large force up to l,(M»o yards, but it nece»»i - that it was impracticable to use it except for a short tini" in morning without the disadvanage of firing at a shaded la i . Record Keeping I jn&gt; of the two regiments of infantry, and found them generally incomplete In I ■ I communications were nol t all. and in the few instances where they not indexed according to l T . S. Army require - ment 'hey kept letter press copies of letters sent, but theii home. Almost all the companies kept The »ik up. and many had also entered the men's names in tli- ind Clothing Book furnished by the War Department. 1 fcund no order booki up to date and I did not find a properly kept i regiments, indeed in most instances none were kept. I suggest that each organization be furnished with a model page and vi encampments. The sick books were .illy up to date The morning report books, including the consoli - orts at regimental headquarters were incomplete in that the chaiu ined in remarks as explained on model </seg>
            <seg id="p034">w I n f &gt; !1 VDJUTANT GENERAL'S KEPOKT me wltheai at of infantry and one at brigade headquarters supervise the whole and to look after special troops ■ \s I have previously Mated « well set up battalion of n &gt;&lt;&gt;ps would be of incalculable benefit to ttie national guard an •ment could be utilized to impart instructions. There is one feature of the encampment to which 1 desire to invite mpany commandei do letter books had been lrnished them but mil- ire more generally ■ no reason hy they should be furnishe I As to what instruction I gare during tlw nn rani pm tint I ran say ver&gt; • ■pt t hat I was busy at all time Ing irregularities wl. found them. I gave particular attention to t)&gt;- ■tail of the encampment I endeavored to point out the right or most radical way. I ilways foun.l ready listeners and was heartily supported effort to improve the guard In the short period of encampment like this a brin. much ir one officer to look after. In case there are no regular troops partici- itins in the encampment. I would suggest that enough of! .tailed il attention an. I that is the field hospital. I nu tion of it on Sumlay the i:;th and though I only found a few men about a half a dozen, sick in the hospital. I found an establishment in • ible. II is neat, orderly and complete for its purpose. Two bospital tents used for the sick and it was at no time crowde 1 I la in tion I casually observed its working Major Birkner. who of It, has seen service in Germany, I believe, and the German system was apparent in his daily work. In closing this repot;. I wain to s:iy that I trie , of the instruction! sent me for my guidance in the spirit of thi that authorized my detail. 1 am in hear with the idea of helping ■i the patriotic citizens of the country who give what they can spare from their" civil avocations to preparing I nre the public when the time of trial comes, and I hope and re my efforts ■ irit. The) are civilians. i they have shown a willingness to do their duty and all they learn advances them |i the man who .uu till tbe excitement of war comes when it is often I I want to thank General Culver and all the staff for their many kind i. .■ in camp and all the officers of the camp for meal and patient fo in all the ther. Ver fully, O. K. (Kill., IS </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 AD.Tl'TANT OEXEHAI/S KEPORT REPORT OF COL. J. A. STORCH, 1ST INF., ON CAMP AMASA COBB HEADQIARTKRS FIRST INFANTRY 1 Nebraska National Guard tFullerton. November 25th, 1!M&gt;5 rigadier General .1 H Culver. Conidg Provisional Hrinade. N. N ( bSIr:- — I lime the honor to submit tke following ri'imrt on the en - mpmcnt of tlie Firs! Regiment Infantry. N. N. (■.. at ('amp Amasa •b, K.Hrn.v. Nebraska, \u000e Mh to lKth, IMS, inclu- In compliance with Q. (). No. No !■"■. A G O.. Lincoln. Nebraska. dated Aucust :!. IMS; Um Firm* Regiment. N. N. G. (Field. Staff. Hand • nd twelve companies i proceeded to Kearney, Nebraska, arriving there as |kt routing order, except that all of the companies and band were from three to seven hours late. No satisfactory reason was ever given railroad company for the delay. The camp having all been marked out for the coni|&gt;anies. those arriving at night bivouacked in their shelter tents, and as the weather was fine, no great hardship resulted. The work of detraining was delayed somewhat on account of dark - ness and lack of teams, but considering those disadvantages, the com - panies arrived in camp, from the Cotton Mill Switch, which was about one half mile west of camp, with very little confusion. The quarter - master sergeants and baggage derails seemed to be well instructed in regard to their dun The entraining was very much delayed on account of lack of trans portation wagons, which caused most of the companies to miss their regular train connection and delated their arrival at their home stations from two to twenty-four hours. The First Regiment was cani|&gt;eil 2'/z miles west of Kearney on the north side of the main line of the V. P. R. R. The ground had a natural slope to the south and east sufficient to drain well. The camp was c.cated on an alfalfa and blue grass meadow of sufficient growth to pre - ent mud or dust. The camp was outlined in accordance with the dia - gram In the infantry drill regulations, with the exception that the space between the regimental headquarters and the company officers' tents was increased to afford a suitable ground for parade The camp ex - ended MM feet in length and 66n feet in depth. Water was supplied e driven well headquarters, and four for the companies and band There was an abundance of water and the quality was excelv The sink- ileep. were placed in the rear of th» oom|&gt;any street am: with tents. Garbage barrels also in rear of the company M \&lt;ept on the first day, kept emptied, and in good sanitary condition The men were well equipi&gt;ed with all clothing and equip - ment for service in the field at that season of the year. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">AIUTTAXT GENERAL'S KEPOKT 35 o LThe army ration was issued, and in kw thought t insufficient, but generally the ration was satisfactory. The drills as prescribed in Kiel visional Brigade, ("ainii Abmi followed. The drills were Generally order, also advance and rear guard, mpany and battalion in ex each battalion and company. Y li except in cerent The different maneuvers wer VI ry instructive to l&gt;oth ofl 1 drilled in th&gt; ormations, man. many of whom had n&lt;vt v tt the officers and men a! owed much good judgment in nded promptly to any coniiuand and their company and individual ma- neuvers The effectiveneM of the regiment was lessened on account of the loss oy absence of the lieutenant colonel and three majors, two Iwing me the rifle team, and two beinn excused. Tip licer* ■rare experienced in actual warfare. The discipline of the officers and men in camp od, in I think the liest we have had at an encampment Guard duty was very poorly performed by some of the officers and i;&lt;ost of the men. This was especially true at the beginning of the tcampment. but with the assistance of Major Cecil and Lieut. Hens - ', I believe that great improvement was made. The Quard made a ruch better ap|&gt;earance toward tin the encanipni' In the maneuvers we ware Corps who gave us reliable information as to the location and movement!* of the Blues"; the artillery and the Ambulance Coinpan I wish to thank Gen. Culver. Major (i. K. Cecil. 30th Inf.. and Lieut W. N. Hensley. 13th Cav.. for their able and untirir n all occasions Very respectful Sinned I .lOSKPII A STORCH Col. 1st Inf.. N REPORT OF MAJOR G. R. CECIL, 30TH INF., U. S. A., CHIE* UM - PIRE, MANEUVERS CAMP AMASA COBB il Order No. L'. Headquarters Pro- ill. Auku&gt; 'osel&gt; and out |Hist duty was drilled by le rinse order drill » Cain 1 1 An Adjutant (ieneral. Provisional Brigade. Camp Amasa Cobli, Nebraska. Sir: I have the honor to submit the following lers of this command on the 12th instant, in compliance with G hqtre. Provisional Brigade, Camp Amasa Cobb, August I lth, IM The troops moved out in ample time to reach the stations ini, In the orders, but the senior umpires. Captains Palmer ami \\ • </seg>
            <seg id="p037">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S IfKPOKT 36 Infantry, were an un them ■' o'clock, the hour nninp of hostile operations, hut joined theii com- mands in time to follow their movements Their reports, very complete in &lt;1&lt; •■ nclosed herewith, for the information of the Brigade Commander, accompanied bj ■ sketch of the main part of the terrain, made from memory by Captain r The re|»orts of Lieut. Hensley. 11th 1 ry, umpire v-ith the Browns, and Capt \V. F Sanimons. 2nd Infantry. N. N tied to duty as umpire with the Blues, by ti Commander, to replace Capt. i h V S Infantry. ,i for that dutj by t tie orde above i also en&lt;l&gt; I it&lt;-&lt;(.ni]&gt;anit&gt;d Britr i \*&gt;-\\ rode over a large part of the field and followed the niovemen'.-i of the traopi M well M I i-oiilil iivit the very lirokipi ground \xlnn- the romhat occurred I'pon arriving on the ground, it was seen that \U&lt; lion of the 1st Infantry was far in advance of wl- iwn force should h;i t that hour It mi I to move back to the next ridge in order to total collapse of the entir scheme. 1 then rode hack to ih»- i&gt;osition of the commander of the Brown and directed him to di here w at that time no umpire with tl I'poi n. I four owing to a mistindei indicated in the order: n ommand was deplo o'clocl The disjiositions of the two comni. th in the rei&gt;orts of the two senior umpin I not be : fnfortunately. no gcxxl map of the terrain wa neitr inmanding officers nor tl This was not wholly a misfortune, for it sance u|&gt;on the part of l»&gt;th forces, thus giving cfflcers and non-commissioned officers to patrol work It also required the commanding officer quickly upon the information furnished them This inn with the idea of making the maneuvers conform the usual conditions of actual war undi-r lii learned that any well defined plan commander of either force. This migh: lack of knowledge of the movemtn From wl I could see. the patrol work was not efficiently performed. Th not enough patrols sent out to keep the command)'! those sent Rained little or no information, and reports naturally expected of them. They did nn tions to have made certain th. carry back the information they hail - screen themselves as they could have done « </seg>
            <seg id="p038">ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT 37 s their presence felt, and fired when mniamls and carried valuable infor- Cy might have tion. Wagn u anil Informati and a catechii )f Kansas Citv in would be valuable reading for im of the same published by the would be useful in the hands of much that would aid them in Kny of i lison-Kimberlv C( non-commissionc 1 off who coul nclm :n ing p, I think 1 taking the battle formation before n with the en with the result that thtir move- ■ontaet had n later the Cnts wei contro nes so extended as to be beyond at every point. The attack forma - strength to have insured success, &gt;f the cover afforded by the broken mels ami w ed in suffic k tions were n nor did the offlcf n nif errain The sn na did c li able work, though they were not called upon II. l&lt;! any oons vir I thou 1 for the first position by both sides. On the F and separated f rear, exposed to capture, wn It wa Me ravines I&gt;ater it was brought in ion. but n -i opportunity during this hostile force. move, to tire ui&gt;on n vine columns Th wi far north, unless assured that K enemy woul y of U* right and reach camp by N Th red by me which I feel can and to the requirements of the latest u u should in Amids Oil work done, producing upon the war. When it is considered that il ■ctacle of mini ■ii who rive t hi this is the wi order to prep ir time ami services to the state, in rm their duty to the nation, almost trard, we have a strong additional in thet &gt;rs, in that spirit, and I hope my criticisms will be so received. The effect of fire on either si it would be folly to attempt to decid had been used. Who could tell whetht about noon would have succr. effect of their flank movement to the m such indeterminate quantities that which would have won if bullets r the brilliant charge of the Browns failed? Or who could guess the uth just as the recall was sounded? L Neither side was out there to win a battle from the other, but to learn to defeat our country's enemies when the time comes. Very respectfully G. R. CECIL, Major 30th Infantry, Chief Umpire nclined to mal iped to their c '1« &gt;m Fhout compensation or bop ?ntive to help them on. I have only indicated what 1 deer </seg>
            <seg id="p039">ADJUTANT (iENKKAI/S REPORT 38 REPORTS OF UMPIRES Capt. W. E. Welsh, 90th U. S. Infantry up Amasa Cobb. August 12, 1905 MaJ I Wth inf.. Chief Umpire, Camp Amasa Cobb, Nebr tin- honor to suhnii! the following report of the Brigade Coblj. in accordance with G. O. No. 6, dqtrs. Prov I'amp Amasa Cobb, Aug. 11, In &lt;■■ with the above mentioned order, I joined the second division, or Brown fence at about 9:20 a. m., when I found it deployed in battle formation the broken country to the north of the main road leading to Camp Amasa Cobb. my observations were confined principally to the operations of th&lt;&gt; troops forming the left of the Brown force and neces - sarii coeapoatag the right of the Blue force during the latter stages of the manein Lieut. HensU'v. whose report is enclosed herewith, accompanied the roo|. right of the Brown force. The Brown force advancing in battle formation as above stated and occupying a front of about one mill ind took up a position as indicated on the accom ian.\ I m. bK and 1. i • hed themselves at this time, making a flank vement to the right, for the details of which see report of Lieut. Hens - ith. bi. tiring commenced on the right of Brown force. Blue force were observed in corn fields front of the left wing of th.- Brown ton Fire iong the entire front, the artillery also Bring upon wti lie main position of the Blue force. At aboui - made Company C was detached and \- its object the turning of the right flank of the Blue force. This turning movement was made under cover and out of range of the Uli. n completed in time to deliver Its . with that made by companies E. V and G. .ind H advanced with small loss across the ravine and took up pa ■mpanying diagram, driving small parties of Blue force out of corn field and back to their main |*&gt;sition. bAt tl il least one company of the Blue force was in an unten ion. occupying Um llope of the hill facing and in full view of the own to E, K and Q emerged from their up the slope of the hill Companies I </seg>
            <seg id="p040">M rid M also moved forward to the attack, at the same time moving upon small body of the Blue force in their front, as indicated in diagram. t Companies E, F and G arriving within about 100 yards of the opposing rces, halted, and afterwards assembled. Company H moved forward the assistance of Companies I and M. I The accidents of the ground were such that it was impossible for e to judge or determine what the actual result would have been, of the tack made by Companies C, E, F, G and H of the Brown force. Very respectfully, Capt. 30th Infantry. Camp Amasa Cobb, Kearney. N'eb., Aug. 11, 1905. Major Geo. R. Cecil, Chief Umpire, Camp Amasa Cobb, Kearney, Xeb. Wir: I have the honor to submit the following report of the Brigade ivers conducted in accordance with G. O. No. 6, dated Headquarters iional Brigade, Camp Amasa Cobb near Kearney, Neb., Aug. 11, 1905. I reported at 9:40 a. m., to Col. J. W. McDonnell, commanding first division, who was with his command, halted, facing south on road, about 1 1-4 miles north of Camp Amasa Cobb. Found command at this hour disposed as follows: one company, H, 600 yards in advance of main body, all in column of squads, resting. H company on high point in road and plainly visible for probably two miles in direction of supposed position of route of march of enemy; two companies, G and C, under command of Major Hartigan, 500 yards to right flank of H company on elevation of ground in open field. This company remained here for some time, stand - ing "at ease" in column of squads. Et 10 a. m., in accordance with verbal instructions, Major Hartigan i his front for, approximately, 1,200 yards, moving west in direction sedly of enemy. ■was noticed here that men wore their ponchos folded white side 1 hanging from belts in rear, making these men very conspicuous .t distances, scouts widely separated. At H):20 scouts reached ridge marked No. 1. At 10:20 C. O. orders Capt. Henry to reconnoitre ridge (No. 2). See accompanying sketch. At 10:20 a. m. first firing heard by Blue scouts on ridge No. 1. Enemy encountered. Brown scouts retire towards ridge No. 2. E10:30 main body of Blues were sent west from road towards ridge This in response from Signal Corps that Brown forces bad been tered. Artillery of Blues went into action N. on ridge No. 2 at . m. ■\V. E. WELSH, Capt. G. G. Palmer, 30th U. S. Infantry </seg>
            <seg id="p041">\1).U"T \ N I (JENEKAL S !;i 40 .hi No. 1. Al 11:15 artillery fir. .1 thin line of skinii housand yards on ridge |Mo. 2. company in skirmish III of com (s A on map i and Immediately \ in knoli I In ruled on ridge No H. 1) Artillery on right supported by companies I from x !reme left ■ omi Blue right with : il iioint of charging of Browns advanced four of these compai Blue's right At 12 in., line became very irre tion « many men ular on a difficult ent on enj lortant principle of seekin in ex Bghl than the in Qg npi up in plain view of the enemy. I taking i) men in m Communication with different main nally in many I jrtions of the line n&lt; acting the moven w lir :iads an The Signal Co led to nder most efficient an r ammunition on both :o hurried sketch made f 'illy. To Major Oeo. K. Cecil. :!"th lnf . D. S. A. Sir: 1 honor to submit the following report on the ope a National Guard at the maneuvers near Kearn -ka, August 12, IMG I »;, with the Brown and left camp at 4:&lt;&gt;0 a. m.. taking '(instituting the Second Division station on a range of hills about thret itbout two Brown squads captured by B! li-ft of L company, K. H. B. I). Brow No. 2 about ii front. lory firing continued at ranges varying • lit 11 a. in. until 12 in About 11:4" treme left of line facing N. \V ;h, al Yen n GUY &lt;i PALMER lnf . 1 Lieut. W. N. Hensley, 13th U. S. Cavalry V&lt;&gt;l)l&gt;, Koarne\. Neb! - &gt;ist 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 41 A JW1I1 ommanding OffU On the left were K and F com pal \ and 1) compaaie ing the Battery. In the renter were B. C anil (i rmnnaalaa nn.i n ind (J companies, and on t right I. K. L ami M companies T .mmanding ition, having a good field of t « n, aw lished. The moi v slow l my w niovir w Irove the enemy's main body of the but w ■nd of companies K an ving arout companie V, X and K, of etion. At \ WILLIAM N. HEN8LEY, IK m.l I)i com! Division were advanced ris the inicrveniiiK ravin.' between ih«' i and charge*! ni&gt; tht l)in were repulsed witb g .11 terminated \&gt; 13th V. s Capt. W. F. Sammons, 2nd Infantry, N. N. G. Camp An efl, Chief l"ni|.! Sir: I hare the honor to report that I ions of the Blue Brows armies from |&gt;oints east of a draw extending north and south. intersecting the laid out road renal .on which is situ. Part of the Browi. ,rd with about fou •int directly opposite the Blue, and w&lt; 1 on the crest of the hill. Parts of companies K and I. of the Brown army. equalling an entire company, occupied a position south of a field of corn. t&gt;sing themseh-es to the fire of the enemy, without protection. Company G of the Blue occupied a position on the extreme north </seg>
            <seg id="p043">ADJUTANT UENEftAL'S REPORT 42 attracting the fire of the enemy. Company L and Company M of together with the Battery, occupied concealed positions on the c fit-Id of corn. the real Bine n .. Company H and Company I of the Brown forces advanced t enemy, of greater strength, entirely exposing themselves to the of the blue army. dthe 1 flre &gt;war rapi A scout of the Blue forces captured a scout of the Brown the blue uniform Wt ■urine Very respectfully W. F. BAMMON8, C;ipt. 2nd. Inf.. N. N. ( </seg>
            <seg id="p044">43 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT STRENGTH OF NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Camp Amasa Cobb, Kearney, Nebraska, August 8-16, 1905 AKK 1 * Prrs«Mit Absent Ka 7«. ( im. Enl iCom. Enl. P. &amp;A General Staff ■ Totals 1st Regt. Headquarters U IT 1 ,'B 1 M IB &lt;a Company A .'ompany B Company C Company D 'ompany E ■■■ompany F .'ompany U 'ompany H Company I Company K 'ompany I, Company M I u 8 86 47 *\ " *» M ;» 81 a M M 8 ■».l 54 2 37 1 « a :u i 14 SI ■ 3 34 8 88 !t 47 3 46 I 3 88.... 10 4« 3 m 4. r &gt;| _J__ _M» Totals tad. Regt. Headquarters 11 1 1 21 21 M S 11 1 H 1 1 1 S7 38 Company A Company B Company (.' Company D Company E Company F Company Q Company H Company I Company K Company L Company M :f « 7 58 :\ 43 ;t 35 &gt;l ~&gt;W I 35 :&gt;1 I 41 H 64 I 41 211 64 I 4(1 1* Bl I 4(1 1* ttl 3 14 43 3 ■-'« 14 44i I 40 1M 81 ■ 40' 1M 81 I -a: n u m 14 54 40 M :&lt; -w ■ M ■i» ;« 32 :!•» 17 44 44 4 51 4 81 8 46 II 70 a: 46 Totals 48l 4X3 1 T-.M Battt&lt;rv A :&lt; 33 13 4H Det. Troop A Signal Oar/m 1 10 II 8 28 \&gt; 4S 10 Ambulance Company Rushville Rifles 3 44 3 38 1 1 H Totals 13 154 IIS Grand Total 118| 10051 5| 15»y </seg>
            <seg id="p045">AIUITANT MBNEKAL'S KKCOK I 44 REPORT OF COL. G. E. JENKINS, Q. M. AND COMY GENERAL CAMP AMASA COBB Fairburv, Nel Nov Adjutant General, Linculn. Xeti Sir:— In accordance with your ratal order, 1 reported to y.mr ..tti for duty, ■■* awo«»n««ied you to arrange for transportation of tr.«»|^ the annual encampment, to In- held immediately following Thia du performed, 1 reported to tke Brigade Commander al Camp Am Con Kurt Kearney. S «»• '* 8 - I' lirM1;l " t to Oeneral Onk (Vim tn I herewith submit Abstract of Rations ! idated Report -&gt;f atiimut of eacfa article of unbsisteno. ami lain ill, with Money raloe, ur amount juiiil . ,,, sni^i- petty PorchMed. I's.-&lt;1 and Return* All&gt;t , i, Lmber, and Fora-.- Parchaaed and lamed Payment of Wwm Traaaportation, and for Saddle Bon By your direction. I iavned rations to the riti.' team. i;aini&gt;ed &lt;m th. tomporan, state rai «th of the camp, and wihsislence tor thi ■ :h man per day, dnrinx the encampaMHt iiu-lmlini; iMinmiitation of rations !»■„ cents ended under the direction of the commanding oftk for iubsistence for the competitive rifle owmp, a— mhlnd prior to the .-ami traction, wan *1'.'4 &lt;&gt;•"&gt;. or SIS* „ h man jk-i- day. \vh ,•&lt;! by me at the close of the encampment T1 , e . I quality, and bat little wartage occurred ,v appreciation of the many courtesies extended t Miinandei (tenet*! Staff and Officers of the (Juard i fully submitted i l.y lii&gt; directioRii. acted as Brigml is included in the Abstract of Ration OBO. K JENKINS. Colonel, t^ M. ami &lt;miimiv.ary (Jem-ial, N. K. ( </seg>
            <seg id="p046">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKl'OKl 45 r&gt; CONSOLIDATED REPORT ON SUBSISTENCE STORES Received and Issued at Camp Amasa Cobb, Kearney, Nebraska August 8 to 16, 19O5 Article ."iU 1 , 2.-)T7 16 1 ix .lam. I1» Pepper, 11 Vinejrar, -M', _'(KI 136 11(1 4(K) :{-l4 Lard, \h- Com. s\v Lemons, Ice, lbs ;i 1H2 i 12 llfK) 1KMI Subsistence Property Articlo tilKI Oil Cloth, yd Setting, yds Musli,,. yds Klaiincl. yd- 12 -.irv Ch 1 Received IsmkhI Return il \\ (f, flvsh. 11* f. corned, 11k id. tott, Hm ;ul. hard, lbs oils 11 - 7341 7MI I7U0 17(10 KM P.") U»0.j 268 1 , 12210 I 1090 1090 926 &gt; 4 2468^ -'4tW'., MB " MM '.ICil I 118 lid Tonal Salt. 11&gt;- El.-s. \\m bea, pk, Kxpenueu [{••iiivtfl Heturn^l and Imnn] </seg>
            <seg id="p047">46 AD.IIT.VNT GENERAL S REPORT QUANTITY IN POUNDS. AND MONEY VALUE Ration* of No. of Rations 7100 (Quantity Money in 11*. * Value Fresh beef Bacon at 5.12c at 12 52c at 18.5 r at 1 71&lt; - at 3 BOc at I 2 c at 6.5 a at 10. c at 4. 75c at 1 IV at 2. 25c at 10.5 c at 7.5 e at 12.5 c at 11. c 8875 $454.40 MM 2289 286 .58 427 79.00 Corned Beef Flour 1138 11040 12420 212.88 250 9iiO Hard Brea.1 Bran-. 250 8»03 1835 42.: 3 Beans, baked. 1 ll&gt;. Beans, baked. I It. Rice can ran 53 3 45 117 11.70 1249 Potatoes, fresh Oniona, fresh 8117 20K5 Tomatoes. 3 lb. ran Prunes 44.%&lt;&gt; Apples I'ea.h.-. 2251 3451 Toffee. LAG Sugar at AMe at 4.38c at 8. c at 1H e at .22c at 22c at 4 40c at 12.50c at 13 5 c at 83c at 4. c at .22c 11290 ll£*l n«pt ■M 52 4 20 50 9.14 Pickles, cucumber Salt 5075 10152 10152 10152 10152 406 ■ Pepper Soap 25 5 56 406 17.86 Candle* Ice 152 19.08 20804 101.52 Candles, lantern 18 a 4a Matches, safety Imxes Toilet Paper, pkp. 840 2 ho 219 8 78 Coarse Salt 35 Total money value of ti&lt;'lil and travel rations, Aug. 4 t inclusive 13. $1758.65 Commutation of ration*, paid by state KI.M $2109.90 125 H.flH 8117 2035 258 83 35 45.79 28.57 445 33.38 225 345 28.13 37.95 903 119.65 2801 M.« </seg>
            <seg id="p048">ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT 47 COST OF CAMP OF INSTRUCTION, 1805 Average cost per ration, 197* ' ■ if Sulisistence Competitive Rifle Camp. Kearney, $194.05, not in - cluded in above ItSBM of BzpMM u.i ' Pd. from 'cr Diem transportation of Troop* ■MiVisistencc ■"reijtht and Dravaw r uel and Forage lardware and LumUT Hospital Supplit- Telegraph, Telephone, and Exi'i Miscelliinoms $18U9.54 W755.47 $11394.07 ,-&gt;3m; M41.71 1844.18 215112 168 71 1982 41 +.'&gt;4.7a 454.73 406.OI' 408.00 163&gt; 183 89 W5.73 *»; 71 40.44 40.44 36 76 36.76 49i) 499. r.5 — — Total :&gt;737K.«.V 11992 1» 16884.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 ADJUTANT GENERALS KKI'OKT GENERAL ORDERS, HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE CAMP AMASA COBB. HEADQI'ARTEI \AI. KKICADK IB, K .rusk Aug 1 1 M\ oininan ibldl in fiei I i; o II This camp III. S .■ ann follow oinnii - ral; .irroll I) I ■in] Gen 1 A. Khrti. K H Phelps, Adju mi Q. M : I W. N. !!■ ill Cavalrv. V. 8. A . 4Ml Baldwin. 'I an, A Maldwin. Troop A . N. N. G., Aid. dins ingly IV Th«. I mental command IV. T unian an I M companies the opi&gt;ortun nills an:l disri ■ uiual)ili(. • nili'ii )|&gt;ortun luct of drills a and dis Hintahili • if the drills V. I .mil the most made of tin- op i and it liortunities offered in thi rectkm. VI '■■. battalion, compain )f tli. .■ then hem ti) |&gt;ul forth the u VIII I thai much t . by the Infantr ills and outpn- VIII much tin liy i In- Infantr v« VIII Bach in- I will be placed ti|x&gt;n hi luard w tion lo duties. He should fctl that th&lt; ollectirely is in his kei nl for all d IX. for all (lutifs reqn; IX mal (Ilia ■ clOM ■Idler wili M- disciiiline. v.-ii- discipline By 'i Culver. E. H. PHKI.l'S N n &lt;; Adjutant Gen </seg>
            <seg id="p050">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 49 HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, Nebraska National Guard Camp AMASA COBB General Orders ) 1. The following order of daily of all concerned: rvico is announced I first call Trumpeter's march a. in Reveille Assembly ii. m M a. m 45 a. ni Police cull .i. in a. in a. in Surgeon's call Guard niountinti second re iniem, Au Guard mounting, first regiment. Auk. 9 (Regiments to alternate each day thereafter.) Drill i. ni First sergeant's call 11:30 Dinner 12:00 M Drill 1 : 30 p. in Supper "" p. in Dress parade, second regiment 0 p. n) Dress parade, firs: regiment. Auk I Tun p. m Retreat will be sounded at close of last parade When dress parade is omitted retreat will he sounded at 7:30 with companies parade. I in their streets Tattoo p. ni Call to quarter P. in Taps 9:60 p. ni Recall sounded at the discretion of regimental command ers. J. H. CULVER. Brigadier General Commanding Provisional Brigade, N \ HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE Camp AMASA COBB, No. 4. L Captain A. S. Pin ,,, rt to g ur Kearney. Nebraska. \ No. 2. \ Breakfast (Regiments to alternate t-tch day then Kearney Nebraska, Auk. 9, 190 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 V Ambulance Companj la appointed Brl w 1 Hr N N G PROVISIONAL BRKiADK AMASA COUH. HEADQl Al K N K. X ff K i ■ wo l Ami i, ill M&lt; line Ot! ntion II CULVKR, : General, Hiding Provisional Br X N C'onni HEAD ("ami) A ma PROVISIONAL BRIGADI ill- will lake pi I A An » •ionel I W. McDoniu 1 A - </seg>
            <seg id="p052">DJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 1 V. The first division will ■*■ haki trousers and blue shirt, with tints and campaign hat, and I 1 as the Blues. "he second division will wear lion khaki uniform, and will inspection of their commands. vi ?i i" fit 11 1 1 11 cartridp* and also ie same minx irst halt made after leaving camp. ,,-i for an: n in the |&gt;erformance of this H. The firing will cease at the di yards. Fifty rounds of Iires will li&gt; t&gt;T the first halt alter lea . m n HI Private property must be n ■ carefuli' aired, if disturbed. Orchards, privat I crowing crops iv In' inillr will be i in Ti^n'ii Ran VIII. The ireneral situation w of the in) intend nK :iln na fi'on: mil (he mil 4 n^aoo r Th.&gt; ilivision will t; ion as neai- to the northwest limit if the terrain above disc ribed as n ..inliin.,, r'ami. Pnllll actlcable and will attempt to Thti firtit rliviKil II A commanding officers of th&lt; , ie forces with instructions to int&lt; iu reinforcine Camii Cobb, and » )t and prevent the Brown forces ake position on the east line of moi 1 1« it idi by tilt mpeters accompanying each division. The lime for cease firing ant will be indicated by th&lt; umpei jartment will be under direct control of the Brigadi ii who will indicate the location of field hospitals as may !. essary and regimental surgeons will report to him for instructioi ons ' commanding officers of thi iv Thu ai»ntti ichmei »ill ki "ii wit it headquarters, which will tx X Major G. R. Cecil, Capt. Pali \ and Lieut. Hen ipt. Castle, ('apt Welch, of th the 13th Cav.. 1 S A., hav timer and Capt. Cast! m ii..&lt;it'ii:i fid HA ill* 1 HrilWIlS ' Pnnmanv officers will 1 impassible. nfined to S uih to the U. P. R. R. rv... tv., &gt;sition until !•:("&gt; a in., nor n inforinalion regard </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT will act with the first division; Capt. Welch and Lieut. Hensley with the second division. Provisional instructions tot maneuvers, issued by the War Depart meiit in 1904, will govern. Hy order of Brigadier General Colre E. H PHELPS Major N. N. G., Adjt. Genl HKADQl'ARTKRS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE) Camp Amasa C'obb, Kearney, August 12, 1905 General O: \ I. All payrolls must be at the quarters by S:Wi p. m., August Kith. liaymastei s office at Brigade Head II. In column No. 3, show those total days present. :! and absent for each day. als&lt; III. Enter nothing in columns 4 10 is not required. and I. Witness in col«mn No IV. Company commanders of the first and second infantry regiments. and commanding officers of Troop A. Battery A. Signal Corps and Ambulance Company, will sign in (111 and (12) on the back. The rolls a first and second infantry regiments to be delivered to regimental headquarters, when the colone' will sign in (16) and (17) before forward - ing to. the paymaster's office. By order of Brig. Gen. Culver E. H. PHELPS Major N. N. G., Adjt. Genl HKADQl'ARTURS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE I Camp Amasa C'obb. Kearney, August 13. IM General Orders ) No. 8. I Cases requiring hospital treatment should !»■ sent promptly to the brigade hospital. The regimental surgeons will render such assistance at the brigade, as may be ordered by the Surgeon General. II. In accordance with General Orders No. 1, the heads of the different departments should I 1 and respected accordingly." bill. The Commissary General procures the rations, and deals directly th the commissaries of the regiments, and the quartermaster sergeants the detached organizations, upon properly executed returns. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">53 IV. The Surgeon General is charged with the sanitary conditions of the camp, and to take such action as is necessary to prevent sickness and to care for those who require medical treatment. In this he should be assisted by every surgeon in the command. It will require the earnest and willing co-operation of all officers, to make the camp the success desired. V. Officers neglecting the i&gt;erforniance of duty must be reported to th» commanding officer. By order of Bridg. Gen'l Culver E. H. PHELPS, Major N. N\ O.. Adjt. Gen'l HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE Kearney, August Ifi. mnii General Orders ( No. 9. \ I. The Provisional Brigade will be reviewed by Governor Mickey at M p. ni . August 14th. Khaki uniform will be worn. til. The following formation will be observed: The 2nd Regiment the right, followed by the 1st Regiment. Signal Corps. Ambulance Com - ny and Battery A, in the order named. Bv order of .1. H CULVER, Brig. Oen'l, Commanding Provisional Brigade. HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE Camp Amasa Cobb. Kearney. August 1 1 rneral Orders ) No. 10. \ I. The payment of troops will commence at 8:15 a. m.. Tuesdn gust 15th, at Brigade Headquarters. II. The Second Regiment will be paid by the Central National Bank of Kearney. Nebraska, in alphabetical order; also the Ambulance Com- 1 any. hThe Signal Corps, Battery. Detachment of Cavalry, and First Regi - nt will be paid by the City National Bank of Kearney, Nebraska, in the er named, and the regiment in alphabetical order. 1 1 The Field. Staff and Band of each regiment will be paid at the uclusion of the payment of their respective regiments. IV The troops designated for payment by the Central National Bank Camp Amasa Cobb. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKPokT 54 will be mustered prior to payment, by Col. ('. .1. Bills. Inspector General: those by the other bank, by Col. .1. A. Ehrhardt. Judge Advocate General; who will carefully note any irregularities in the enrollment of the ti and see that all members are accounted for. V. Hattalion commanders will su|*&gt;rintend the payment of their con mands. The khaki uniform will be worn, with bell and side arms. By order of Brig. Gen'! Culver K. H. PHELPS, HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE Camp Amasa Cobl Kearney. Nebraska. August 1",, inot No. 11. \ 1. The general will sound promptly at 7:90 a m. Wednesda: II. Cam)) equipage, other than tents being struc';, must be carefully packed and ready for trans[&gt;ortatioii ti&gt; the train, prior to the sounding of the general. This includes kitchens, flies, and heavy baggage. III. Travel rations already drawn should be issued to companit each company prepared to fall in, in heavy marching order. IV Quarters must be thoroughly policed, ditches and sinks filled; dt tails made for various &lt;K in entraining and handling th baggage expeditiously. i mental i| onimanders of independent or Kanizations will make application for transportation this evening, to tin end that the entraining order wil be carefully complied with. VI. The Inspector General and the Surgeon General will make a care - ful insi&gt;ection of the camp, after the removal of the troops, and make a report of the condition of the camp, specifying the^ companies that have neglected to comply with this order. VII. Company A of the 2nd Infantry, and the Sign«l Corps, will re - main in the camp until such time on the 17th instant, as may be directed by the Adjutant General of the state. VIII. Latrine tents should be carefully folded within latrine frames and retained with other company proiierty, and accounted for in quarterly reiKirts. J. H. CULVER, Brig. Gen , Comdg. Provisional Brigade Major N. N. G., Adjl Gen] </seg>
            <seg id="p056">ADJUTANT UENEKALS KEI'OKT REPORT OF CAPT. F. A. WILCOX, 30TH U. S. INFANTRY. IN - SPECTION N. N. G., I9O6 WAR DEPARTMEN Militai binston, July I ible .lohn II M Referring to the recenl inspection a I militia ol ■Min F A. Wl oilder il 71, \\-;ir Department ment ieg of 1903, I am directed by tl of War to inclo. ■ iiir Informatioi Sj ;in ,| our information memorandum of intent of ■ ni au inventory of the qaarters that I ipply the deficiencies noti Tioien I. &gt; supply m of o i wl iy an ealUted strength of ) In this COWMM ;inment ! thiit equipment for incomplete without -■ition for ■ number sum. In this connei ninient I I withou liiisition for a nuiiilM-, iency in thi should he made immi Battery A, Field Artllle uniformed, and equipped for bi in the Bi • rder. Steps shoul : uticable. The inspecting oAi , ample in uniformed, and equip: in- aiiiian bad order. practlcabl (■ting offic p^ in 111 too old to ■ &gt;o old to vi innienils lhar conical teni - that ron: com - unservic w 1 shoti! lie actioi c \ nf r ■he issue of new tan In order that the I cruinK tld receive the nctln the issue of new tM cruing to it under the operatic tniended. the Department hai to allow allotment, with idlnc that prompt steps wii; 10 stipiily the deflc llotment, with t lV iU 1)O \' 'illy, v INS WORTH, \ INS WORTH, The Military Secretary's Office. Memorandum. The Military Secretary's Office. Memorandum. Extract of mei illltia of X- ed militia i </seg>
            <seg id="p057">AD.ll TANT (lENERALS REPORT 56 ka. showing di uniforms, and equipments, as noted in. First Regiment of Infantry Headquarters — Five enlisted No revolvers or holsters reported, and -ick straps; no overcoats or *ht-l(er tents, and no 2 tin cups short. Band Twent] No revolvers, belts or holsters, blanket roll straps or overcoats, : Other deficiencies; 2 shirts. Company A — Thi: nlisted. No revolvers or holsters (8 r I), blanket-roll - reported. No spoons. Company B — Forty-seven enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (5 re - quired, blanket rol straps or overcoats reiiorted. Other deficiencies; la serviceable shi: Company C — Twenty-eight enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (8 re - ir overcoats. Company D — Fifty-eight enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - quired I. blanket roll straps or overcoats reported. Other deficiencies: I tit'- k of bayonet scabbards and cartridge belts, 6 gun slings, and IS blankets, 11 campaign hats, 16 pairs leggings, 12 shirts, and 3 pairs idue). to complete uniform. Company E — Thirt . v -eight enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - lanket roll straps, or overcoats. Other deficiencies: 2 bayonet ■ eable campaign hats. Company F— Forty-four enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - ■eported. Other deficiencies: 29 kn nd 6 ]&gt;on&lt; ! Company G It enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (5 required) i&gt;orted. Other deficiencies: 71 canteen _' shirts. Company H M , nlisted. No revolvers or holsters (8 required I. [lorted. Other deficiencies: 3 tin cups, 17 blankets, and 4 poncli Company I — Thirty-eight enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - quired I, blanket-roll straps, or overcoats re|&gt;orted. Shortages: 2 bay - arts. Company K Thirty-nil, I. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - ianket-roll icoats reported. Other deficiencies: 5 tin cups, 8 knives. It for • Company L — Thirty-eisht enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - quired or overcoats. Company M — Forty-five enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - quired I, blanket-rol, its reported. Other deficiencies: In tin cups, 1 fork. 17 s|x&gt;ons, 16 blankets, 6 campaign hats shirts Second Regiment of Infantry Headquarters No enlisted men </seg>
            <seg id="p058">AIXIl'TAXT OEXERAL S REPORT 57 Band— Twenty-eight enlisted roll straps or overcoats reported. N'o revolvers or li Its. blanket- Company A — Forty-three enli quired), blanket-roll straps, or ov 18 each of tin cups, knives and ponchos. ited. No revolvers or holsters (1 re - reported. Other deficiencies: forks, 28 spoons. I blankets and 13 Company B — Fifty-three enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (5 re - quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats. Other deficiencies: :! rii' extra bayonet, 7 bayonet scabbards, 4 cartridge belts, :'. gun slings, 1 can - teen and strap, 8 meat cans, and tin cups, and S blankets, 7 eampaig-i 14 pairs leggings, U ponchos and HI shirts. Company C — Forty-one enlisted. N'o revolvers or holsters (7 re - quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats reported. Company D — Fifty-four enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats. Other deficiencies: 12 rides. 4 extra bayonets, 17 each of bayonet scabbards, and cartridge belts, 14 gun slings, 12 canteens, 14 haversacks. 24 canteen-haversack straps, 25 tin cups, 8 forks, 42 spoons, and 15 blankets, N khaki coats, 11 pairs khaki trousers, 6 campaign hats, 21 ponchos, 7 shirts. Company E — Firty-one enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats reported. Other deficiencies: 16 tin cups, 1 knife, two forks, .! serviceable campaign hats, 2 pairs leg gings, 3 ponchos and 5 serviceable shirts. Company F — Thirty-eight enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - quired), blanket-roll straps, overcoats. Other deficiencies: 3 tin cups, 6 blankets, 4 serviceable campaign hats, 3 ponchos, and 1 shirt. Company G— Thirty-nine enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re - q"uired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats reported. Other deficiencies: 12 serviceable knives, 17 serviceable forks, 1 spoon. Company H — Forty-nine enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (7 re quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats reported. Other deficiencies: 1 meat can, 11 tin cups, 11 knives, 12 forks, 4 spoons, ami 4 blankets and 3 ponchos. Company I — Thirty-six enlisted. No revolvers or holsters (6 re - quired), blanket-rol) m OTMtsotU, excepting three. ."&gt; knives and 21 spoons short Company K — Thirty-one enlisted. No revolvers or holsters it; re - quired), blanket-roll straps, or overcoats reported. Company L — Forty-six enlisted. No revolvers or hols' quired), blanket-roll straps, or oveico .kids and 7 ponr (in- quired Company M — Sixty-one enlisted, quired), gun slings, blanket-roll snaps 1 rifle, with pertaining equipni havt-isaek straps. 14 meat cans, 4 1 1 s No revolvers or holsters [t or overcoats. Other deflcien. cantet'n. 5 haversacks, I •able tin cups. 17 knivi - forks, 32 spoons, 21 blankets, 5 serviceable campaign hais l'I pom I. •hlrt </seg>
            <seg id="p059">ADJUTANT &lt;iKNKKAI. s HKfoKT 58 I ii Rushville Rifles en enlisted. No revolvers or hi and pertaining equipments. 4 canteens. I li en-hart sack straps. 4 i -lioons. Ambulance Company, Hospital Corps — Thlrtj N nientio REPORT OF BRIG. GEN. J. H. CULVER, COMMANDING PROVI- SIONAL BRIGADE, N. N. G, I9O6 EXHIBIT "B HKADQI ARTERS PROVISIONAL HRIGADE ('ani|&gt; of Instruction. Ft Riley. Kansas. Ausust 14. 1 TO the Adjutant General. Lincoln. Nebraska. the honor in submit the following report on the oper t th&lt;- Provisional Bi S G., at the Maneuver Camp at Fo required I. blanket-nil deficiencies: 7 rifU blankets. 4 kh;i. is khaki nous- ipaign Signal Corps ---Thirt.wisiht enliste.l. N iIkt equi| spurs ind no ha 7 tin nips, an blank' &gt;orted Noti 11 Tents, complete with luppli to ih&lt; ■npply of i I blank roll si: &gt;ept in n of in th« for. with the exception of thi Troop leggings, 21 pom Troop A. Cavalry — Thirty-nine enlis: curry oomb laiat strap with snap. links, picket |iins. or surcingles: an. I no blankets or overooat! Other denci- nrs asd spu curb brill. 16 saddle hlankeis. 14 campaign hats. 14 ponchos end '■'•&lt;&gt; shirts. Battery A, Field Artillery — Thirty-one enlis.c I No revolver! o; ho Bters, s ■ wry combs, ta bnishe: watering brli or shelter [cnts; no curry comb: Number of curb if halter headstalls an wheel and lead harm &lt; replace ible. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">.\ iJwl I 1 A !\ 1 ( t r&gt;N KKA L. .*&gt; R KPORT 59 to the command of which I was assigned by General Orders No. 13, O., c. s.: K command consisted of the first and second regiments of infantry, tings Rifles, Signal Corps. Amlmlance Company. Mattery A. and ment of Troop A The various companies constituting tk« hrlf 4» entrained on Satur - the 3rd of August, at their home stations, with the exception of Bat- A, which marched from Wyniore. Nebraska, to Marysville, Kansas, lining at that point. The balance of the command assembled at ind Beatrice, and moved in six sections over the I'. P. R. R., an; at Pawnee Flats. Kansas, on the morning of the 4th, detrained, camp I and policed in time for noon mess I reported to General Wint. l\ S. A., commanding the Camp of In- Uon, on arrival, was courteuosly received, and directed to the camp ground assigned to our state. ■Monday morning the real work of encampment commenced and d throughout the week. The accompanying orders and reports, you are resi&gt;ectfully referred, will give a detailed report of the &gt;rs and exercises during the week. Captain Games of the 10th Infantry and Captain Hunt of the l*th In fantry. assign) &lt;1 to duty with the two regiments, rendered valuable assist - to the officers of these commands At the end of the week our tour ;ty was brought to a close, all too soon to apply the brief lesson* GENERAL AND SPECIAL ORDERS AND CIRCULARS, PROVISION - AL BRIGADE, N. N. G., 1906. IUARTER8 PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. \ X. O. / -incc In Neb., Julv 10, IMC I al Orders ) 1 \ K following Brigade Staff is an tant General, John (!. Worki inn jimced Z« Captain 2nd V . S. Infantry Chief Quartermaster, Col. Jenkins, Q. M. and Com. Qaa Commissary, Col E Jenkins, Q. M. and Com lien., N Snrseon, Cd, C, I) Evans. W s Surgeon On . X N \ . V N (i </seg>
            <seg id="p061">60 AD.UTAN OENERALS UKPOR1 Assistant Mustering Officer. Col. .1. A. Ehrhardt. .1 A ("... N. N. (i By command of Brigadier General Culver: JOHN G. WORKIZER, Captain 2nd r S In HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE iska National (JHard HKADQIARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADB Nebraska National Guar Lincoln. July 31, 1'inti Captain Ernest Aubert. Ruahville Rifles. X N C... will report on ar rival at Lincoln, Nebraska, August :frd. ltM, to Major J. M. Birkner, com manding Ambulance Company. N. N. C. for duty wiih that orsanization By command of Briagdier General Culver JOHN G. WORKIZER Captain 2nd I". S. Infantry. Adjutant (Jen HEADQIARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, Nebraska National Cuar .incoln, Auk J, 1Wii6 Si&gt;ecial Orders / No \ EXTRACT • ♦ 111 1st l-ieut \V S Hal.Jwin. Troop A. \ N t; , will iv|&gt;ort his d S|&gt;ecial Orders / Ma ) Lincoln, Neb., July • •". !»&lt;&gt;•!. I '.II Special Or&gt;!' No. 1 \ The following officers are detailed on ipeclal duly ;ii ili^s.' Headquart era and will report for duty at the times anil placet veciBed. Major. E. H. Phelp lj. Gen., N N &lt;1 . August 1st. at Lincoln Nebraska. Captain S. D. Dm '.! M . N N 0., August 1st. at Lincoln Nebraska. By command of Brigadier Ceneral Culver: .IOHN O. WORKIZER. Captain 1'n.i 17. 8. Infantry. Adjutant Gene </seg>
            <seg id="p062">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 61 rnicnt to the Adjutant General. Provisional Brigade, N. N. G., on August 1 !i&lt;»;. for mounted duty By command of Brigadier General C'ulv JOHN O. WORKIZER, Captaia 2nd V. S. Infantry, Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE,] Nebraska National Guard, Ey A, 1st Inf., Company H, 2nd Inf., Company E, 1st Inf., Company C, Inf., Company C, 2nd Inf., Company 1., 2nd Inf., Company G, 1st Inf., npany A. 2nd Inf. Equipment. 12 coaches, 1 standard sleeper, 3 bag - e. Total, 16 cars. I TRAIN NO. ::.— Captain F. M. Smith, 1st Inf., Commander. Baggage train. Company O, 1st Infantry, Company A, 2nd Infantry, Band, 1st A. 1st Inf., Company H, 2nd Inf., Inf., Company L, 1st Inf., Company tlst Inf., Company I, 1st Inf., Company D. 1st Inf., Company K, 2nd Inf., npany E, 2nd Inf., Band, 2nd Inf.. Company B, 1st Inf. Equipment. 1 ch, 1 horse car. 7 baggage cars. Total, 9 cars. t TRAIN NO. 4 — Lt Col. Fred Geguer, 1st Inf.. Commander. Band, Inf., Brigade Headquarters. Company I.. 1st Inf.. Company M, 1st Inf., pany G, 2nd Inf., Company I. 2nd Inf.. Company F, 2nd Inf. Ambulance pany. Equipment, 1 standard deeper, 11 coaches. Total. 12 cars. t TRAIN NO 5 — Lt. Col. O. G. Osborne, ted Inf.. Commander. Baud Inf., Company I. 1st Inf. Company B, 1st Inf.. Company E. 2nd Inf. pany K, 2nd Inf. Equipment. v Total. 8 cars. tlnf.. Company K. 1st Inf. Company B. 2nd Inf. Company M, 2nd Inf.. lal Corps. Equipment. 1 sleeper. 1 horse car, 12 coaches. Total, 14 The commanding officers of trains will supervise the entraining of he troc their train, and when notified by the railway ofll- t Company B. 1st Inf., Company pany O, 2nd Inf.. Company I. 2n TRAIN NO. fi— Col. .1. A. Storeh. 1st Inf.. Commander. Company K Lincoln, Aug. -J, II I Circular. The following i.s published for the information and guidance of all concerned: The trains on which the Nebraska troops will move to Fort Riley will follows: k TRAIN NO 1 — Col. J. C. Hartigan, Commander, Company H, 1st Inf., pany I), 2nd Inf.. Battery A and Hastings Rifles. Equipment, 4 1 platform. 2 stock. 1 baggage, 1 coach, 1 Arms Horse Sleeper. Total 13 cars. TRAIN NO. 2 — Major Walter F. Sanmions, 2nd Inf., Commander. Com- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">62 ADJUTANT (iENEHAI. s KKI'OIU ( i the lime of departure of their trains, will notify the commande of organli ng on that train. Wind of Brigadier General i ulver JOHN G. WORKIZER, Adjutant I HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL -BRIGADE, N. X. G nip of 1 nst met ion. Ft. Riley 1; ■ 4. \ EXTRACT III. First Limit 0. E. Bans, Hastings Rifles. N. N. G.. will re|)ort wltl fanny, N N. 0., who will attach Lieut Boggs and the enlisted mer UHld to the organizations of his regiment for duty By command of Brigadier General Culver: JOHN G. WORKIZER. Captain 2nd U. S. Infantry. Adjutant Gen HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. N. N. ( - No \ EXTRACT * * v H Ambulance Co., N. N. G.. is appointed Fosl for the Provisional Brigade. N. N. G.. and will maintain an offic for the receipt and delivery of mail at the Y. M . C. A. tent between th 1st and 2nd regiment Infantry, N. N. G. Regimental commanders will pal iis order for the information o. their commands By command of Brigadier General Culver JOHN G. WORKIZER, Captain 1'nd D. S. Infantry, Adjutant General HKADQIARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. N N. G Camp of Instruction, Ft Ki ii., August 6, 19' al Order ( 2. \ Kis command will be inspected and mustered for pay on Tuesday 7th, l -lins.s Ritifs. N N O., to the CoBunaading offlror of th, nil) of Instruction. Ft. Riley Reservation. Kan.. Au </seg>
            <seg id="p064">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 63 I in i ( Camp of Instruction Pursuant to Instructions from Headqu* wing is published for the information of this Command: I. In transporting fresh meat fn -at will !&gt;e suitably covered to prevt &gt;m tli • H to companies, the ■nt contamination by flies. II. There will he artillery firing at 2: mi P. M today Visitors desir siting at that hour just west of Gen s. to witness this will find guides aw al Wint's headquarti III. Fatigue details onto! nied by regiments and marched in re|&gt;ort to any headquarters will be charge of a non-commissioned officer • quiring th IV. The use of brush s, for latrines will be discontinued inny sacks can be obtained from the depot Quartermaster for this pur ise, and after being placed in position will be whitewashed felon 1 lie exercised in cleansing woodwork around latrine My command of Itrigadier General Cul\ JXO. (i WORKIZER, Captain 2nd V. 8. Infrantry Adjutant Gei»eral HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, V N Q.,1 Ft Riley Reservation, Kansas, August B First Call, I:M P. M tembljr, &lt;:•« P. M. Vhe 2nd Regiment ot lnfantr&gt;. U ■cups. Troop A, Hastings Rifles, and Batter; A. X. X. C... will he ■ iv Colonel John A. Ehrhardt. J. A O., N. X. G. The 1st Rtjriment of Infantry. X. X. G. will be mustered by Captain T K. Hunt. 18th V. S. Infantry. toOMMOden will uraaaa the details of the muster and napeeUoD of their regiments. The Cumntanding Officers of the other or ;anizations will report to Colonel Khihardt for instruoti' ;me anil By command of Bi I NO. G. WORKIZER, Captain 2nd 1'. S. Infantry, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S REPORT FIELD AND SPECIAL ORDERS AND MESSAGES, BLUE FORCES, MANEUVERS FORT RILEY, 1906. HBADQUARTKRfl PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. N. N. G.,1 Camp of Instruction, V\ Riloy Reservation. Kansas. August 8, 1906 The Chief «.f Staff. Provisional Brigade, Camp of Instruction, Ft. KiltM Reservation, Kansas -I have the honor to report that Captain Martin. 18th l\ S. In - fantry, with a battalion of the 18th V. S. Infantry, reported to me at 8:45 a. m. today for co-&lt;&gt;|&gt;eration with the Nebraska troops in the exercise laid down for this morning on page :!. circular No. ."!. Headquarters Provisional &lt;rigade. July L'6. 1!&gt; He immediately left to carry out instructions he had already received tegarding posting an outpost. I directed him not to post his command until I could get my officers in a position to witness it. I directed the issue of the orders hereto attached, which were carried out Captain Martin completed the posting of his command at 11:45 a. m., the delay being due to my directions. Owing to this delay and at the suggestion of the Brigade Commander I did not carry the exercise further. &gt;ut directed the trooim to return to camp, at which point they arrived at 12:30 p. m. Position sketch of ontpoat M posted l&gt;y Captain Martin's battalion. IMh U S Infantry attached hereto. Very respectfully J. H. CULVER. Hrigadier General. N. N. G.. Commanding Brigade HEADQ1ARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. X. N. G.,1 ri'amp of Instruction, V Kt. Riley Reservation, Kansas, August 8, 1906, 8:50 A. M. J held Or* So. 1 * Troop*: 1. No information of (he enemy ha» Advance Guard. LL Col. been received. i. 1st Inf., N". N t The brigade will march linmedi- 1M Battalion 1st Inf., N. N ately, the main body halting at Main Hody in order of inarch. the packer's camp, with the ad- ■gt Inf.. X N. G. (less 1st vance and rear guard conforming Battalion i to these movements. Field hospital 3. a — The advance guard will march Rear Guard: ('apt Newman. from the camp of the 1st Regt . </seg>
            <seg id="p066">AD.HTANT OENERAL'8 RKPOR1 65 HEAIKJl'ARTERS PROVISIONAL URIGAtW, N N. Q On No 1 No information of the enen ceived. Relieve ompo - talilished liv the 1st battalion of the ,18th I' S. Infanuy Place one battalion in a ]K)int now occupied by one company of the 1Mb D. S. In - fantry. Re|X)rt names of com - manders on lines of resistance to these Headquarti Three-fourth* mile north of I lamp, PI Rlli atlou, Kan 1 1 in A M -'"' '"f ■• N v O. • maintaining a distance at 800 liattalion 2nd Inf.. N N &lt;;. yards from the main body, and will move via the bridge near Pseker'i camp. ■ l&gt; — The main body will march from Um ramp of the 1st R&lt; ■- a. m. I. The rear guard will maintain a ills from the main body. ill*- commanding general win at the head of the main i li&gt; niiiiuiainl of Brigadier General Culver. .INO. 0. WORKIZBR, (aplain tmt U. S. Infantry. Adjutant General. Verbal!) to regimental commanders and *urgeoa&gt;. ■ HKADQUARTBR8 PROVISIONAL HKICADK. \ One-half Mile North of 1 amp, Ft. Kiley Reservation. Kansas. AugiMl 8, l!tml. 10:46 A M Kield Orders / No. 'I. \ The entire coinniaiKl will proceed one-lialf mile north of Pacier'l camp ■wall ordi i By command of Brigadier Qeneral Culver. INO 0. WORKIZKR. Captain I'ml I S Inl'antry. Adjutant General To Regimental Commanders per l.ieut. Baldwin. A. I). C. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">66 ADJUTANT GENERALS KEI"OKT A HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, N X. 0 . in ,&gt; of Instruction. Ft. R: ■. ation. Kansas. August 9 al Orders ( No. 9. I. I'pon recommendation of the Chief Burgeon, Provisional Brigade Camp of Instruction, ft Hil&gt; urn. Kcn^as. Captain J. 1!. Hin Assistaii! and Captain i Heath. Assistant Surgeon. N duty at the Field Hospital and Reserve Hospital. II r Milnilanoe Company. N N. G., is de tailed as Acting Hospital Steward, 1st Infantry. N. N (J. Sergt. Hlava will report at once to Major F. S. Nicholson, Surgeon 1st Infantry. N. N G . for duty. nimand of Brit • ral Culver INO. G WORK1ZER Captain 2nd V. S. Infantry Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE Camp of Instruction Ft. Riley. Kan . Au« 7. IDcif Memorandum for Instruction No. 1 The following named troops will participate in tl prescribed in Circuit' narters, for Thursday, August '.*. IMI Blue Forces. ganisc Militia niiimlg •ops Mth I F. A. ittalion, isth Inf I)&lt; Corps. Detachti it offlcera and ( men I U. S. Signal Organized Militia ol S ..-halt cuiiUMiiy SiKiial I nated by the brigade coni- and two battalions of infantry, to be maml' Lt E. D Warfi- ;;ned to command the Signal Corps t roops 3. Cossack posts with connecting sen tinels to be established on lim of resistance. ,n&lt;] of Brigadier General Culver: INO. G. WORK1ZKH, Main :!d I'. S Infantry. Adjutant General. 'opy lo the ocinmianding; officer 1st Rept.. N. N. 0. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">ADJl'TANT OENEBAL'S REPORT 67 Regimental and balialion commanders, the Chief Surgeon and the Chief Signal Officer will designate the troops required of their respective commands and send list of same to the Chief of Staff at 8:00 A. M., to- One squadron, 9th Cav , less one troop One platoon horse artillery. Detachment I". S. Signal Corps lone non romniissioned officer amd six men). Captain Joseph Frazier. 14th Inf. Lieut. E. R. \V. McCabe, 6th Cav Corps troops Designations v. i forces Major Morgan will manners of designated detachments - lc» Major Morgan for Of* for Instructions. Coin - will report tomorrow at S:00 1' M . By command of Brigadier General Wint I.ieut. Col. 30th Inf., Chief of Staff Official JNO. T. HALVES. One-half company Nebraska Signal Corpi Umpire*: 1st Lieut. C. L. Wlllard, .nth Inf., . l to &lt;■. mmand the Signal Blue A. C. SHARPE, Capt. anil Adjt., 11th Cav., Adjt. (;• Commanders of designated organizations will report at 5:00 P. M. to- morrow to the Commanditi Nebraska Brigade, and arrange for with his command. I'm pi res: Captain .1 I) l»ng. 11th Cav .. Lieut. .). .1 Mayas, 24th Inf.. I.ieut. D. A. Lindsay, 1st Inf., I.ieut. John Cooke, 11th Civ. To be assigned to duty with the Blue fore*; Captain H. W. Butner, A. Brown Forces. Major lulm C. Morgan, '.'th. Cav.. commanding HEADQIARTERS Bl.lE FORCE,] Pawnee Flats. I Fi. Riley Reservation, Kan., Aug. 8, IMC, 5:08 P. M. I »ld Orders / No. 1. \ Order of March. 1. Hostile CavaJry and artillery re- Advance Guard: ported operating 20 miles north tiptain Geo. Martin, 1Mb 1 of Wilson's ranch. Inf., Commanding. :' This command will march tomor- </seg>
            <seg id="p069">68 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S UKPOKT Copy to each Regimental. Battalion. Company and Detachment Cum maud' One noncommissioned offi row and make camp in tli&lt; and 1% miles northwest of !'• Cav. camp. :frd Ban ..ml will marc Main Body: from the camp of the Xeb. Brie Signal Corps. A. M. along th.' 1st Inf.. N. N northeast from camp to Three 2Hth Matt r. A Mil, Miming north befon 2nd Inf.. N. N i mui thence along Wii Detach H&lt; - V X. (i son's much road to |&gt;oint desii: Rear Guard: Bated for camp. Major W. F. Samnions. 2nd Int.. b— Tl e main lx)dy will follow th. N. \. G., Commanding. yards, an&lt; ud F. 2nd Inf., N. N G. will ry outpo- Klank Guard: arrival in camp. Lieut. Herman. Hth Cav . Com &lt;• Tfce Signal Corps will manding. out instructions already r» , Tr&lt;K)p D. Hth Cav. (k :i- 4 — The C. O. 29th Batt. F. A., wil commissioned officer and ten report to the Commandin- "I. for further 01 I. The rear guard will follow tin main 1.. I yards. The left flank guard will noitre for one mil* west of cami and north to the Saddle thei ,&gt; camp on Wilson* ranch road. cental trains will follow the main body without distance 7. The commanding General will be at the he:id of the main body. Bj coinmaiiil of 11 JXO. G. WORKIZICK. Plain 2nd U. g. Infantry. Adjutant General Field From Hi inp Qeaarai Cul\. ■ i it i f hour of yew |. oops on tiling lin,. ,],.. ratal , ff BLUB VAN &lt;;r.\Ki&gt; irtk Thiw-Mtle Creek, \ .\1 Captain Marlin. C'ommanrlinp A G.: — Point report* Brown I </seg>
            <seg id="p070">UMITAXT GENERALS KKPOKT 69 ng one troop, moving north acros Shelton, Commanding. Brown IV ront in the ravine. Adv. Guard h yon a rnmand of Hris in dislodging hem Gen WORKIZER, Capt. 2nd Inf Ann) . Field Mes IT, Headqua Cam | A iv n X. W. Pscker'i Camp, eight V M « xp m Will he governed by circumstance CILVER, Brig. C.en -rn;i i Corps, I A I'm Field H. Militia B rr. Ho amp: 1 and tindc Y&lt; &gt;d to take effect at one o'clock CULVER, 1 I' M Brig. Gen HKADQl ARTERS BLUE FORCER nip near Wilson's Ranch, } vat ion, K;i! 1906. I Field Or N.i TROOPS 1RDER OF MARCH Enemy is advancing from the northwest. Force not known. Tliis command will march in the lirection of Sheridan's bluff. —The advance guard will march Main Body 2 Batts. 2nd Inf. X N 1'. M.. maintaining a dis - nce o from the ain body. any Ird Batt. lMh V. a Ambulance Co. X. X. Q in Train. — The right flank guard will re - connoitre the country to the west if the line of march, screening ommand. .1. A Headquarter! Bine l-'oi- \. m. Herman, CommandlBg L. PI. Kllill ( Militia ( ■iip and quai inched shelter tent ramp, where Ft. Ki &gt; Advance Guard: iptain A. D. Falconer. I'ml Inf., S. N &lt;;.. Connnil.c. G Inf.. N. X. G. Rear ( h, 1st Iiif </seg>
            <seg id="p071">70 AD.U"TA\T GENERALS KKPOKT G. ( Commanding. c — The rear guard will follow the Detach. Signal Corps main body at 400 yards 29th Batt. F. A. 4 The regimental trains will follow 2 Batts. 1st Inf. N. N. G the main body without distance 1 non-com, officer and 10 enl men Troop D, 9th I The Commanding (Jeneral will bt at the head of the main IhmIv Right Flank Guard Troop D, 9th Cav. (Less 1 non com. officer and In enl. in By command of Bi Culver ( Signed i .INO. G. WORKIZER, S. Infantrv. Adjutarr ally to all organization anil Detachment Commanders REPORT OF BRIG. GEN. J. H. CULVER, COMMANDING BLUE FORCES HKAIXjl'ARTKRS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, N. N. ( Camp of Instruction, Ft. Rile&gt; on, Kan.. August in. 1M« The Chief of Staff, Provisional Brigade, Camp of Instruction Ft. Riley Reservation, K Sir: — I have the honor to rapMi as follows on Ou - prescril&gt;eil for Thursday, August 9th, in Par. 6. Cir. No. '■), Headquarters Provisional Brigade, Cam|i of Instruction, Ft. Ril. t ion. Kansas. July 26th, 1906. The provisions of this paragraph were strictly complied with. In ac - cordance with Memorandum for Instruction No 1, your office, 1 issued Field Orders No. 1, hereto attached. The command, as thus orgai left camp at 6: In A. M. t at which time the - ups and Ambulance Company had not yet arrived. The route, as laid .lown in Field OriM 1, was folio v At 6:4n A M i information that ■ troop of Brown Cavalry was three-quarters of a mile west, moving north. This troop appeal various points on our left flank during our march into camp. On arriving at the Saddle Back road, 1 opened fire with Battery on the Troop and Battery while they wer- a ravine just north and east of the Saddle Back, distance tJMO yards. At this point, ordered the advance guard to hold its position and advance with the main body along the road towards Wilson's ranch, going into camp about 500 years south of Wilson's ranch. Camp was made aliout Ioihi ,\. M. The outpost, con - sisting of two battalions, m ntirely around the camp, the line </seg>
            <seg id="p072">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKIt&gt;KT 71 of observation following of the ridges to the east and west of Emp. Captain Martin's battalion of the Infantry was drawn o ramp as soon as this outpost w.is In position. At 11:M the outpost s relieved. At 1:M P. M d from the Chief of Staff, ins information of a MpsrlM force of the enemy advancing from the rthwest, and directing me to retire quickly. Whereupon, I issued Field dets No. 2. herein attached. The command was formed and in march 1.04 P. M. On arriving at the Saddle Hack road, our advance guard be- The right flank guard em driving them from |«&gt;sition. Upon •n train was fired ui&gt;on by a right rear. I directed my battery if dismounted c -tant abou: to the left flank under cover, arrival near th lioad, my lattery Jo&lt; ids to our o return their fire, concentrating the main bodv under cover in a gulch 15i &gt;0 yards east of the junction of the Sad die liack and Wilson's Ranch road At this i&gt;oint, reinforced the advance trd with four companies of infantry as a supi&gt;ort. and one battalion of 18th U. S. Infantry as a reserve, and directed them to continue the ad- and directed them to continue the ad- vance towards Sheridan's Bluff x&gt;n as the advance guard and support was sufficiently advanced. 1 directe the ix)int that we had just left. Shr on a battery and troop in column mi The entire command arrived at Sin ver, we marched into camp en il the rearguard to go into position at irtly after this, my artillery opened fire irehing towards us at about 22i"i yards. ■ridan's Bluff without incident. Cross - route to the lui'l of Pawnee tla. On arriving in camp. I communicatrd with the Chief of Staff and i directed to discontinue the ■ i this iioint. L Sketch maps and copies of correspondence and all orders issued hereto ched. J. H. CULVER, Brigadier General. N imanding Blue Forces REPORT OF COL. J. A. STORCH, COMMANDING 1ST INF., FIELD EXERCISES. Adjutant General Prov. Brigade, N. N. G., Ft. Riley Reservation tSir: — I have the honor to submit the following re|&gt;ort of the field ex - ses in accordance with Circular No. :!. for the date of August 9, 1906. I My command, which was comiiosed of two battalions of the First In - try. N. N. G.. was formed in column of squads M . at the t side of camp, ready to march. command marched in front of the main bod] nee of 800 s from the a. I id Aft&lt; j : the junction of Forsyth HEADQIARTERS 1ST INFANTRY. V N. &lt;;., 1 Ft. Riley Reservation, I An. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">AD.irTA.NT GENERAL S KKPolM DHW road, (on the Saddle Back Road I one eompan&gt; was eployed in line of skirnii iaad of the Commanding (Jen 10 the front. The march was continuous . t half an hour ne camp for the artillery to get into action On arrival in camp, one battalion went into shelter tent camp, and th other battalion camp outpost. rovring 1M the left of camp around to the north and right M . the battalion Jn camp prepared i individual cookln their noon-day meal, and rj to march at l":4n A. M At 11 n.5 the outjM» ittalion from the outpost returning; and preparing dinner. On the return to camp 1 had charge of the rear guard which wa : of two battalions of the 1st Infantry. N. N. &lt;;., mo sections of 3th Artillery. I ,, troopers of the Mk Cavalry, f. S. A. Ainu immediately on leaving camp th. artillery was locate! to tlu right. Our artillery went into action at ;m Immediate retiremen of the enemy. One company of infantry was deplc battery. This fire action did not delay tli. pd enough to canst ; »ce of more than 8 he main bod; a The advance guard ami main i&gt; iked immediately aft and the artillery put into action, having located the en to the right. The halting of the main bo i a more extensive &lt;l&lt; ployment of tl uard than would have been nee. main body not t» 'ply my artillery » hi the main body in dislodging the enemy on the right. I w in body, but was unable to do so. for the enemy's cavalry ■ in concealment al&gt;oin 80 Near the junction of the Wilson's Ranch Road and the Saddle-Bac Road, the rear guard was foi. -ist an attack of tw&lt; valry. The cavalry advanced to within "&gt;cmi yards of two si companies of infantry deployed where they w 'inpany I.", under the command of Captain Baeh ning their right Hank and firing three vofleys into their flank. The cavalry retreated by the left Hank .in. I w surprised by a 350-yard fire from a small eompan me right of th. Four companies in all were deployed The main body, having been deployed and marched to th mlf to allow them io reform in column and then imp without further dlst urbane lectfn the Commanding Ccnerai to ailvanre my J. A. STORCH. Col. CoininamliuK 1st Regiment Inf.. X N ( </seg>
            <seg id="p074">AIUTTAXT GENERAL'S REPORT REPORT OF COL. J. C. HARTIGAN, COMMANDING 2ND INK. FIELD EXERCISES HEADQUARTERS 2ND INFANTRY. X. Mant'iiwr Camp, August 9, 1906 n.-ral J. H. Culver. Commanding Brigadt following report of the movement 1 Infantry Regiment under my com By order of the brigade mmander. "A" Company of this regi Kt followed column as rear gua command marched in column I, 40(i yards in the rear of the column v Igden, Saddleback and Wilson ranch of Thr -Mile Creek, where a slight advance 1 skirmish took place, the enemy withdrawing. After crossing the camp was pitched and the command massed. The rear covered by t consisting at four companies of this regiment. The command was ordered to face about and commenced a retrogradt tnent, the objective of which was not indicated. Being unable by he limited time to relieve the outposts. "A" Company was ord. &gt;utline the outposts, and to close on the column as it moved. The outpost hen called ill, and with "O" Company designated as the advanr noven. I. The right flank being co» i trooi avalry. The advance guard upon arriving at a point south of the June Saddle Back and Wilson Ranch roads, reported dismounted he northeast limi &gt;f Sheridan Bluffs. Captain Fal- 1 in "A" Company and used it in support and in strengthening Ivance guard. The position held by the enemy was admirable, and ioi Brigade Commander, the remaining five companies giment were deployed in skirmish line, in sup|&gt;ort of the advance Eil. and were directed to lie down all 1 of Saddle Bark road: discovering tsltion to enfilade this i&gt;osition. the ared by a ridge of 2&gt; lion of the men inevented an immei during which tire was maintained which was done, and the enemy. ■ s(|ikmIs. was dislodged, or had w i'il and ordered to camp. The left Kd. and were directed to lie down all l of Saddle Back road: discovering Hong the military crest of the ridge. ing the military crest of the ridge. g artillery on the heights southwest artillery on the heights southwest le line was advanced across the dry nils from the enemy. The ex- line was advanced across the dry K) yards from the enemy. The ex nen prevented an imm ediate rush of the hill; after a short ediate rush of the hill; after a short ng which tire was maintained d. the line was ordered to rush the dered to rush the which was done, and the enemy . which consisted of about two or which consisted of about two or (Iliads, was dislodged, or had w withdrawn. The column was again thdrawn. The column wi f( of the line co-operated with eaT- the line co-operated with c:i\ "' '&gt;&gt;■ i the road map of the topographical offl •i fully. JOHN' C. HARTIGAN Colonel 2ud Regt., P. H. Q N I I Sir: — I have the honor to make the conitucl of two battalions of tli- (1 in the maneuver of this ilay. regiment le»'i camp as jian of the main bod) and in rear of tht I herewith mm Hi erf this rei&gt;ort. the iwrot of t!: </seg>
            <seg id="p075">74 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT GENERAL ORDERS NO. 4, PROVISIONAL BRIGADE ral Order Nu. 4. This command will lie mmd and inapected tomorrow by the In s|«rtur QflBjanl of the liris.' nm Cull - 4(1 A. M. AaMm)&gt;ly. I tf A. M Full Field equipment will lie carried The Amlmluiii-e Company. N. X. ti.. Battery A. X X. (,!.. ami the Signal Company X. X. (i . will lie rejmrted to the Adjutant General at the Headquarter* Provinioaal Brigade at h :iu A M liv i oinmaiul (if BriKii'lier (ieneral Culv .IOM.X (i WOKK1ZEK Adjutant General MEMORANDUM ORDER, PROVISIONAL BRIGADE HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL, DR1RADE, N X Q C'ani; Fi K Meinoiandiini / Details for Friday. Ansnst loth To rei&gt;ort la l.ient hi lie force: ,,f iii,. 1st Infantry, X. X &lt;; 1 Battalion 2nd Infantry. X. X Major H. J. Paul. I -11(1 liaitalidii ciimniandi'd by Ambulance Coi One-half Comi&gt;any Signal Corps. H M All'iiews, x x a Artilli r\ Corps, as iiart of the brown 2nd Infantry. X. X. («.. less one battalion One-half company Signal Corps. X. X Q Battery A. X X G.. will follow the 2(ith Battery Field Artillery dm ing tomorrow's problem. Commanding officers of Organizations will report to the officer^ nated .. M. today. nimand of Brigadier General Culver JXO (1 WORKIZER, Captain 2nd U. S. Infantry, Adjutant (;• HEADQUARTERS PROVISIONAL BRIGADE, N N &lt; ( 'amp of lii-tnutimi, It. Kiley Reservation, K;m UmI in. i'.hw Capluin .'ml I". S. Infantry </seg>
            <seg id="p076">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 75 ( i r ( R r n I I GENERAL ORDERS NO. 5, PROVISIONAL BRIGADE. HEADQUARTISR8 PROVISIONAL BHIQADE, N. 0 Camp of Instruction Ft Riley Reservation. Kan . August 12, 1 f+ot; neral Orders / No \ I. This command will *»nt rain tc ■ I:M P. M. In the following der Train No. 1. Ca H. 2nd Infy.. Si •s baggage of Co. M. 2nd In Paul. baggage oar to St. Paul (also oaches I also takes Co. M. 2nd Infy. I. Lggage with Co. B, 2nd Inf.. shares M. 2nd Inf.. Alhion, loads 1 .aches with Co. B. 2nd Inf. Co. f, 1st Inf., baggage to Maili ilumhus, 1 coach. takes bag- i K. 1st Inf., to Co. K, 1st Inf.. loads baggage with Co. V, 1st Inf.. 1 coach Signal Corps. Fremont, •■gt. Hdqrs., 1 coach. ur to Fremont, takes baggage of 1st Ambulance Co., Lincoln, 1 baggag car, 1 coach Hand, 2nd Inf.. Osceola. 2nd Inf., 1 coach. •ar to Osceola, takes bags 2nd I nl. 1 coach One tourist Train No. 2 Hastings Rill in Hasting!, l coach Co. II 1st Inf.. Nelson, bftftm d Inf., 1 coach. it- to Nelson, loads baggage Co. D. &lt; Co. D, 2nd Inf.. Fairbury. i Anns Palace tar No. ;gage with Co. H. 1st Inf.. I coaches 1 tourist si The above are transferred to th St. .1. &amp; G. I. at Marysvilk Mattery A to Hlue Springs, 1 coach, 1 baggage car, 2 stock. Mattery unload- ns and limbers from flat car on train No lie Sprint arne\ car to Kei it at Sutton. 2 coacl nggae of hdqrs. 2nd Inf. and drops Co. G, 1st Inf., Cenev.1 H, 2nd Inf., Aurora, ba - o., 1st Inf., to York. 2 coa&lt; i Co. A, 1st Inf.. York, loads bas car to Geneva, 1 coach car to Aurora, takes baggage of A age with Co. H, 2nd Inf.. 1 coach Co. M. 1st Inf.. Hroken Mow car to Mroken Mow. tak&gt; age of Co. I., 1st Inf., to Lincoln, 1 coach. Co. L, 1st Inf., Omaha, baggag.- with Co. M, 1st Inf., as far as Lincoln, coacli- 1 standard sleeper. Co F, 2nd Inf., baggage *iih band Ai niK, palace car No Train No -ml Inf., Kf </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 ADJUTANT UKNERALS HKI'oKI Haggage cars through to destination All companies on Hurlington r &gt;aches to Lincoln Alma, baggage car to Alma 1 coach. takes ha loads baggage with Co 1 nd Inf.. akcs bagg • with Co. E, 1* ■ 1 Inf . Omaha Inf. 1 CO* imaha, loads ■ with Co. Q, L'nd Inf. 2 coach) Ui toiiri- to Lincoln termination of inai Hand. 1st Inf.. to Wisner 2 coachc Hand. 1st Inf., Wisner. loads baggage with Co. H. 1st Inf. 1 coach Pereafter shelter tents will lie pitched in the center of the eompan&gt; Garbage cans and all other property i&gt;ertaining to the Quarter ri&gt;ei&gt;artnient. Ft Hilt y. Kan., will be returned to the Quarternia at one o'clock P M IV. The following allotment of transportation will obtain: 14 Wagon: eact) regiment: I wagons to the Signal Corps, 2 wagons to the Am Ci to Battery A: 1 wagon to Hastings Kill. Jnder re|K&gt;rt to Colonel .lenkins. Chief Quartermaster. V Camp will ba thoroughly ]&gt;oliced. all ditches filled, broken staki pulled, and camii left in the neai. ile condition. VI. Mess call will be sounded at 5:30 P. M VII. All blank ammunition will I* I under the supervision i Train No. 4. Co. L, 2nd Inf.. -•nd Inf . to Beatrice inaska City 1st Inf. Will*! inf.. in BMtrfe lm . Beatrice, load car to Omab Baggage &lt;-:irs through to d Train No. I. Co. B, 1st hit . Stanlon. baggage ear to Stanton 2nd Inf.. Tekamali rai to TV iainah. takes baxnc K I'nii Inf. to Fremont. 1 coach. to K. L'nd Inf. Sell nyli j,,,| | n f ,,, (.■,.,.. iimiiH. 1 coach Co. I. lsi Inf.. VVahi to W'ahoo. takes l. Co l&gt; Ut Inf.. to Uneoln. 1 coach. 0, 1st Inf. Weeptaft Water, loads ba^sase with Co. I. 1 si Inf. t,, Lincoln, lcoach. itrisadc Hdqrs I! ,nx car 1 •' I No. 1 1 in. 1 flat car. nnloadii us and 1 Maker at Blue Sprii; II nent will form on its own color line at I:4S P. M. and li to ihe entrainins point, and report on arrival to the Adjutant den- .-ral. Ill The General will be mounded at S:M P. M. Immediatelv elv </seg>
            <seg id="p078">AD.HTANTM SXERAL'8 REPORT c impany i'iimni;iiid"is prior to Um sounding of the general, ami bov shipment. VIII Company commanders will take an inventory of all property im mediately on arrival .it their home station. IX. Commanding officers will be held responsible for the eonduci of r commands while M route to home station. X. The seniot officer present on each train will command that H.v command of Brigadier General CuIti .INO. G. WORK1ZKR. Captain 2nd I'. S. Infantry, Adjutant General REPORT OF MAJOR J. M. BIRKNER. CAMP OF INSTRUCTION, FORT RILEY ARMORY AMBULANCE COMPANY, / Lincoln. Nebraska. Atlgusl Brig. Cell. .1. H. Culver, Adjt (leu . N N. G Lincoln. Nebraska have the honor to submit my port about the operations neuvers from Aagm III compliance with C. () Nos in and 1. the Compain assembled at the Armory at Lincoln. Nebraska al I A M . August li immediately loaded the bftgsac* on the car at the U. P. depot At 4::i» P. M. the command marched in full marching order depot and entrained at I P. M. Train left Lincoln at 16:30 P. M . an ;as, at 7 M A. M . August 4. II to unload, the Company did not d- - immediately to the assigned camp A., and went into camp. Sketch ot On account of not getting ti trail until 11 :4.'i A. M. Pn» ground near the Field Hospital. I'. S camp during location each according to instructions fron Nebraska Company were pla&lt; ■ During the routine work in camp Chief Surgeon. I*. S. A., the men of thi work with the I S A men as understudies, and at drill. .nt of the I". S Hospital Corps acted as drillmaster and a August 8th In the morning a detachment consisting of 1 medical officer. "p non-com, officers 20 privates. Ainliulam-e ('(Mill any. N N O., (iiirin lived at Fort Riley Reservation. Kan fith | lar routine work 7th | </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 iring the maneuvers, returning at 2:?&gt;ii P M drawing station at tahe field of action, and on the return march, attended I who fell out on account of sickness or prostration. One serious case had to be .sent to Um field hospital immediately. tist 10th. The company furnished two details, each consisting of e medical officer. 4 non-com, officers, and 11 men. with one ambulance transport wagon each, for the two operating forces, liiown and ue. both establishing dressing stations at the point of action. August 11th. A 'ion of the whole brigade t August 12th. P. M.. struck camp and loaded the baggage. ;ip ground- P. M . and entrained at 5:45 P. M. Left foi ncoln via the V P. K&gt; P. M. t Arrived at Lincoln. Nebraska. August IS, IMC, at 8:0fl A M. I&gt; lined at ti: in A. M. Inloaded the I. A.M. Dismissed tli tnpany al '.«: 15 A. M. tlteing pla iiei with the Hospital Corps of the l\ S. A.. Um inpan. 1 . gain L) deal of valuable experience and was vei -ated b&gt; the regular foil' • • K. l&gt;ectfully submitted I Signed I .1. M. 1URKNER. Comdg. Ambulance Co , N. N. &lt; Major, Surg ' maining men attended drill. August 9th. The whole company, except the detailed men. J medical officers, 1 line officer. .". non-com nfti' :M men. 1 trans|K&gt;rt wagon, ■.tnied the blue forces durinj; the maneiners. and established I </seg>
            <seg id="p080">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KEW&gt;KT 79 STRENGTH OF NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, CAMP OF IN - STRUCTION, FORTRILEY, KANSAS, AUG. 3 13, 1006. AgKIf Absent Enl. P. * Britfiulr Hcadqnarten uartrr* 11 1 1 1 I ■A r&gt;l &lt; '&lt; iinpaiiv K ( '.iiniKiny H ( &lt;I|I1]&gt;UI1.V I ( 'mni&gt;any K Company I. CoiniKiny M 1 12 21 II 17 in i-t i.-) 1 13 1 in » 1 168 4.-&gt; 466 10 H 1 ! 1 Company A Company B ComjKiny C CoiniKiny I) Company E Com|&gt;any F ComiKiny (• Company H (dinp;iny I ( 'oinpany K Compaaj L :(s ;&lt;, lii 17 ■M .-•0 Hi ■&gt; II i :i 27 10 A~ 1 II 11 134 10 i ■A 1 10 41 l.» n 12 IM (Jrand Total 108 113-1 XV&gt; Com '■ Knl Com L'nil lit'Kt. Hta&lt;liniartci&gt; +11 l),t. Troop A 1 1 Con* Ainbiilaiict' • '&lt; &gt;ni] &gt;;in\ Hastings KiHi - </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 AIMITAST GENERALS RKPOKT REPORT OF COL. G. E. JENKINS, BRIGADE COMMISSARY CAMP OF INSTRUCTION, FT. RILEY. IIKA1KJI AKTKKS PROVISIONAL. BRIGADE i,;i National Guard, Qaarternu irtmenl n! Instruction, Foil Kilcv Ka&gt;- Vim ! ..I .1. M. Culver, Commanding Provisional N X. &lt; Fort Rile&gt;. Kansas I have tin- honor to report that in oompllanoe with Q. (). No. Inly 27. 1H&lt;Kj. 1 reported for duly August 1. IMC, ami iiow at tl,. the encampment. I most respectful)" report all work completed, and attach to and make a part of this re|&gt;ort (each under its ..'(1 to your brigade and in te|&gt;endeni organizations by Captain Edwards, Chief CoBMatM Lll quartermasii to your brigade and lnde| i conn iin Walsh. Chief Quartermaster. ly of all ordm&lt;: issued to your brigade and in hpendei compa officer. Major Bun. &lt; h and make a part of this rei&gt;ort. each und wn Triplicate liills of lading both ways, for horses and artillerj eqai| Duplii . il lading for horses and artillery equipment to F( A |K«rtion or the duplicate bills of lading from fort Riley. The bal ioucl Storch and Colonel Hartigan, Captaii .tin Hull. Major C.egiHi. who will report di you. originals in the several irans|K)rtation books, which I return wi reiK.rt. I ni. ill) ackmi ■ many courtesies ai.d assistance e; iMitmem by Captain Edwards. Chief Conn; plain Walsh. Chief Quartermaster. Camp of Instruction re«i&gt;ectfully subirii' QBO K. JENKINS Colonel, Quartermaster and Commi Provisional Brigade, Nebraska National Guard CI.IKK CROC Clerk All romnuinicati' ilelivt : .ill requests for Pullm;.; inent truaporU 'irneil to me. you will find attaci ills 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">O c/j O &gt; I i ! ► i p»-. ' I </seg>
           
            <seg id="p083">\H.irT.\NT «EXEKALS REPORT 81 Abstract of Subsistence Stores Ksued tn Nebraaka National GhNwd at Fort Riley, Kausun. to 12. 1S08. by Captain Arthur M Edwards. ( 'oiumissary 1 i £ \\U ■§ i V f. To TroojiK | i. fl LS i H 1 w* l £ - i^tS •r. X tad Band 1st - i u 4 | M 24 -t UK 810 M .)ni]«iny A g |0 M 'omjiany B 'omiKiny C 'ompany I) omjiany K nin|iany F 'ompaay (i 'omiiany H 'ompany I 'ompany K 'omjijinv L 'nmimnv M &lt;im]iany H ■ 4.1 7 -)!! omiKiny C ;i M,; .-, !)4 oinpany I) ompany E - 774 43 • &gt;iii]iuny r (| &gt;•),-, iM&gt; t si era 4ao ■omiKiny (i !, - ! ( :. 'omiiany 11 &lt;i - 41 ;.. ml .any I ., •#-, m M - ompany K ., ;{ •..m]«in.v L !i 4.-,,, , MH) "nmpany M [. ('. S. and Band timl go - .-&gt;4d •&gt; '4 4 1 it; Jompaay A ti 7 'ompany B 'omdany (' oinpaiiy D oinpanv K 'omjKiny F 'ompany &lt;J ompoay H omiKiny I. ompany K 'oni]Kinv L 'ompany M fcltt«TV A VrapMiy B h cmulany ( -tit n 7 4'.l !l J. ompany U :,,-, » uh ji&lt; k) x ompany B a? '.1 a7 H 4.'i B !■ ompnny F 4.-, 9 ompany U y ompany H 411 ompany I . . r,i &gt; 'ompany K :{n J ompany U •ttery A . Jti s , 4 .-,,, •Jti 2". H 234 4«s' 2 24 I 450 r&lt;i&lt;| i» -\ ;t 4 a si .-,4 1 TriK&gt;p A 4 !• 27 :&gt;4 ) 1 Signal Corp* Amlmlancf ( o Hastings Hifiles l^iiaJ Corpi 37 ■V, inlmlance Co 41 II ■ •tftingi KiHles 4 4 Headqnarten Pro* &amp;ig eail.mart.i-&gt; Pro* Brit; 10 ! in ! Tnivt-1 Katii.n- I ravel Ratiim- Auk II il C'orpn Ambulanif On Hastings Rifles *• Kejft. 4,jf, 1 4iii; id. Kejft. 1 I 4M I MB 1 2ii 1 lattery A 1 41 1 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">at K'J AIUITAXT GENERAL S KKPOK'I Returns of Forage, Straw, Wood. Lime and Mineral Oil, issued Fort Riley, Kansas, August 4 to 13 I9O6 Batten- A 1 3(H» Amliularw Signal Cori*' 'ii'^r'"'**"' ■Jrvl ' M 1 12 1 1 M 4!M 1320 ItKttn 1584 Brifj ;ind IVt Tnx.j 1 fl«l 1.VKI Total 11 73»2 :«»614 COST OF CAMPS OF INSTRUCTION, 1906. Item- of Ezpeaa Per Diem 8 ht and I li Horara ritNt.OOSulwistfncr « (Ki.j.l 80.22 SW.SSAppropr't i -mmtm.ijhi 103:; Average owt per ration. 169 in (■lit ' ijuipetitivt iiK-lnd KihV ('aiiiji CnlamboH. $T7. 17. not U(M)I) Bhl&gt;. Llis IM. fro.n l '. J ' l s fr " 1 ) " ".:: 1.V*. 17 41.",. m. . n 25.06 25.0«Balan&lt;i of TriKi|is Fuel and Y • anl Lnmlier ST. OB S?.6Mby IS Ay </seg>
            <seg id="p085">AfMKTAXT (JKNKKAI.s REPORT 83 I i i REPORT OF MAJOR J. M. BSRKNER, FIELD HOSPITAL, STATE FAIR GROUNDS, 1906. Lincoln. Xel Bil I have the honor to report that in compliance with S. (). No any established ;i Field Hospital ot uction ;&gt;t the Fair Grounds at ix beds and a Dispensary in Cam] tncoln. Nebraska, from Septein Halve, for special drill and nra and five privates. 1st class hiring the races and ball gatr was also maintained an ncy ikjsi. consisting t the race-track, according to the (UiiMiissioned. and two privates &gt;t the Hoard of Manu. During the til ampniei r ■ tended vein \ comprising small injuries and nature. lai tiv Forty-four cases more adininis 'Stly bowel tronl wo ea I medical treatment for ailment ea and linor affectiot There wa ml $I4.:&gt;iii dollars, of which raw. three and sixl \ ne-hundredtli $(3.«0) Hollars, leav and ninety one hundred! hs $i I li\ check from tl orty ($4(1.110 1 Dollars, as partial n expense account and receipts attach sum of aeration f&lt; idered ted on the efficient and prompt Hospital proved a great 9 rendered and the mainteiiai commodation to the people of the The Commanding Officer !t d. and compliments the men on ir good behaviour and excellent we Inn J U. BIRKNKR. Gen. .1. H. Culv Adjutant General, N. N \. G. O.. !■■ ambulance Comi Septembei and reported with one medical officer, two BOD-Oomml toi (iuty Septc allotted by the Man. hing camp &lt;&gt;■ the - mi i&gt;m medicine Ernlahed, fourteen and f in was expended balance in the Company fund Dolla iel was greatl; complin ectfull lajor, Surgeon \ X. (J Comd'g Ambulance Cooapanj Armory Kushville Rifles. X. N </seg>
            <seg id="p086">84 4WUTAXT QENERAL'8 RKPOB1 a REPORT OF CAPT. ERNEST AUBERT CAMP WESTOVER, I9O6 Rustn N'ovc n Adjutant (i- Lincoln, Nebraska 8ir:- In obedieir my runiniand marched 10 .Ind White Clay a distance ol twenty-two mile from Rush vi II d went into cam] The camp location w imkhI. and i|i-:il s|iii-iidni target range During tin anipment. the usua camp routine was followed, and tlm« iled to out mi guard duty il within h ui miles of th» I'ine K and w. ■ India who appea ially in th target : the camp »■ idenced by ;itire lack iring the tern of duty We broke camp on the 4ili of Octobi The weather was very disagi' ainy and cold, and the n I, conditions Your in camp, and that of Captain Tu Im plain of tht 1 Infanti j and inst i n to the offl men. w. helpful and ei, target range will be of much valut to this command in the futi The encampmeni liu ;ed thi ■•■rtions. anr I feel assured that much . I will be felt hereafter liv not the men. but the community ERXKST AIHKRT audB Rushville Rifl we broke ramp on tne 4in &lt;&gt;i uctoDer, and ti»ok ui for Rushville. arriving at the armory ai 7:66 p. in I al.&gt;- my appreciation of the aaaisuuH ii-in K H. Mullowmx . Actll Hi of Small Arms Pr;i- who paiiicipai. il in the entire encampment, and his iustructtions on the at larpe. in the welfare and pr of the roni|ian&gt; V. 'fully </seg>
            <seg id="p087">ADJUTANT (JEXERAL'S REPORT 85 SCORES MADE BY THOSE WHO QUALIFIED AS MARKSMEN AND HIGHER GRADES, 1906. • 1 ffl SLOW FIRE fl K.\|it-ri RihVim-n r^t. (ii. L. 2nd Inf. r B. Brick i Inf Marksinei Id .1 Mack. \ Inf r, 1st. Int mel I y M Depl ■ S. .Inhnsiin. Cut. 1st. Inf .ill's I ' ;i]it. 1st. Inf ;ust Wagner, ('apt. 1st. Inf ibert, ( a]it Rushvillt- Rifle* ill ( ' Pergoaon, 1st. Lt. 1st Inf Haahberger, 1st. Lt 2nd Inf irli-s L Hopper, lst.Lt. Rushvill.- Rirl Ham K Osborne, 2nd Lt. 1st. Inf vunl H Antics. 2nd. Lt 1st Inf tter 3. Schneider, 2nd Lt. 1st Inf •ry B HnliU, 2nd. Lt 1st Inf hnr C, Boone, S&lt;T^ r t. Co. K. 1st. Inf t .1 Brian, K 1st. Inf jt E A. M ill.) id. Inf M. 2nd. Inf n Dollagnan, s.Tf,'t. Rmhville Rirli~. les Bu •■ Rifles vanl K 1st. Inf hH 21 81 SI tn :(l 24 4li 21 • .i -, -"O &gt;00i laqM B fl\iiiK:it'' Capt. 1st. Inf Shanmhiiott'P- ler. Major 1-t. luf M.irtin &lt; '. Shallenberger, ('apt. 2nd. Inf i John H. Brmk, 1st. Lt 1st Inf i »8«0 ml H. H.Mth. ind. Lt 2nd. Inf rgt ( '&lt;&gt;. E, 1st. Inf i k F. Will. • M, 2nd Inl John Gibson. Cook, Co. 1.. lad Inf nil .1. Lane, Priv. Co. M. Jn&lt;l Ini WUliiini Duffy, l&gt;riv. C, B, 1-t Inf li. Priv i Inf H.-rt Ueiamhaeh, Priv. Co E, 1st Inf I Co. K. .'lid Inf </seg>
            
            <seg id="p088">86 ADJUTANT (iKNKKAL S KKPoKI SCORES MADE BY THOSE WHO QUALIFIED AS MARKSMEN AND HIGHER GRADES, 1906 Continued SLOW FIKJ a: r. Slonerker A. 1st [nf 4.". r*rod C. &lt;;i :t. 1st inf 44 t Kov ('. Shank! 11 2nd. Inf :.; Knink .1 Bri;u Inf ) EL K. Miller, Corp. Rnahville KinV- j. ir, Corp. Kiishvillf K j rl 1 • (riinlork. Art il 1st. Inf a. ml H. DavicM. Artif &lt; '&lt;&lt;. K. 1st. In- Zander, Man Co. B, 1-t Inf iiehr. Corp. Koahrille KiHl.--- 1st. Inf ::. Kay K &gt; luf Kay H .. K, 1st Inf Karl M H. 2nd. Inf : hit 1st. lnt \. 1st. li ■ .ianifs I) A. Nt Inf :i| 41 Jamm 1) i \. Int. inf g| 41 Knval A. Wellington. Priv.t'o. B. lnt lnt VVinfnxl Cuhoon. Pi 1st lnt 4:, i;&gt; 1 111111. Priv ('&lt;■ K. 1st In- P. Wvikufl. l'riv. Co. E, 1st Inf koff, 1'riv. Co. E, 1st Inf II. 2nd. Inf Inf wart, l J ri\ ( ... H tnd. Inf :■ Alvin K. I 11 11. -.'nil lnt ird Kudri tod, lnt ird Kiulnia. Priv. 1'.. K tod, Inf Ed. &lt;rcptlnT. I'm ( '■■ L. 2nd Prank Allinicton. Priv. ('.. L, _&gt;n(l Inf Kr.uik Allin^ton I'm (,, L, 2nd Inf William 11 .11 .Davis. Priv. &lt;'.. M 2nd. Inf 1 \". Hulse. 1'riv c. M. 2nd. Inf :r, l'riv. Knshville Kitten :il : '• iv. Kushvill.- Rifles 84 87 41 j; :',( iv. Knshville Hiti.-s m iv. Kushvill.- Kitii-s :u :\: 41 :(n j; :',4 1I11111.111. I'rix Kushville I 1^« (iaiiiin.in. 1'rix Kushvilli in K Matliis 1'iiv Idis! ird V. HipptM-h. l'ri\ l&lt; u- ■ Herman K Matins I'm I; ml V. Hippai li l'ri\ l{nsl Richard Ninm. I'riv. Rnshrille KiHes </seg>
            <seg id="p089">ADJUTANT HENBRAL S KKI-oKT 87 THE FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS OF THIS OFFICE for th&gt;; period December 1,1904, to November 30, 1906, are as follows Office expense, 1008 appropriation #2hs. IS I.. 1 1«(M BtUaiu ■ ■&lt;■ iKithin Armory rent, lift appropriation. I). I. 1904, Balam Disbursement Balance. nothing Per diem officers and men, 1900 appropriation. I). 1, l!Hi4. Balance $1837. 21 . 1637.31 Disbursement Balance, nothing Payment for horses 1903 appropriation. l». l'.Mit Balam I234.SU 884.5(1 Disbni - Balance, nothing Expenditures in nspection, 1903. l», 11MJ4. Balam *IH««.B? . lH«M.fl7 Disbui-Mciiii'iits Balance, nothing Salary Adjutant General, 1903 appropriation. It. 1. 1!HM. Bahini ■ 4"&gt;(MKI UisbursementH Balance, imthinjf. Salary chier clerk, 1903 appropriation 1.. I, 1!K)4. HalaiH 333.34 Disburseinent Balance, notliin^ Salary clerk and storekeeper, 1903 appropriation. 1 19M, Balance Salary stenographer i9O3 appropriation. Balance, uothin •jtit;. H l)i-lnirM'iiieiit&gt; Bulunce, nothing l. 19(M, Baku Uislrarseinents ♦ &gt;80. 00 •.•HO. 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">ADJUTANT (JENERAL S KEPOKT 88 Office expense, 1906 appropriation April 3, 1(08, Amount of Appropriation MM -'&lt;■• Nov. 30. l«0H. Balance $ 413 74 Inspections, target practice etc., I9O6 appropriation. ,it inn April 3 1805, Amount of Appropri MM0.00 6603. !« Disbursement N 1806. Balance ♦ lWi rtH Armory rent, I9OS appropriation. April 3. 1905, Amount of Appropriation ♦ 14800.00 10670 M lii-liursement s ltfoe, Bu 4129.17 Per diem officers and men, I9O5 appropriation. April 'i. Amount of Appropriation 125000.00 24196.63 Disbursements N Balance I ma Payment for horses, 1905 appropriation. April I 1906. Amount of Appropriation $600.00 476.00 Disbursements N l»06. Bitonrr ♦ 124. (Ki Salary Adjutant General, I9O5 appropriation April :f. 1905. Amount of Appropriation ♦3600,00 Hi-lmrsement 15*08. Balance * ?HT&gt; UP Salary Assistant Adjutant General IS05 appropriation April 1 Amount of Appropriation ♦2400. Wl DiHburaen • l'.Hie lialaixe Salary assistant quartermaster, 1905 appropriation. April 3, Amount of Appropriation ♦-•000.00 15U1.61 Disbursement* Nov. 80, l»08. Balance ♦ 408.39 Salary stenographer 1905 appropriation April B, Nov. 80, Amount of Appropriation ♦ 1680.00 1400.00 Disbursements 1906, Bal.iv ■ ♦ 280.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">ADJUTANT (iKNEK A I. S REPORT 89 U. S. government funds, appropriations Act of March 2. 190H. " Deo. 1. 1904, Balunce to credit of St;it« ♦3.V27 «U ;«27.8» Amount of Stores issued I Balance, nothing. Nov. 30. 1906 U. S. government funds, appropriations. Section 1H61. Revised Statnta Balance to credit of State Dec. I, liHW *4478. 6« Amount Re allotted Appropriations 2436.98 40081.74 Kecredits by Disbursing Officer Recredit for Stores returned 4515.01 120.00 *.-&gt;1577.:» 47762. 00 Hot. so. 1906 U. S. government funds, appr priations Promotion of Rifle Practice Julv I. 1906 Amount of Appropriations $7979.08 Amofint plated to credit of Dis. Officer fc&gt;000 00 Amount of Ordnance issued to Stat. 68 41 2 Amount of Stores issued to State *K Placed to credit of Dis. Officer :t()000.00 Balance to credit of State ■0.19M, Balance to credit of State ♦5910.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">90 \|).IL TAN I &lt;iKNKUAL S KKPORI LIST OF ORDNANCE STORES, I9O6 X. ract of Qi iwn by 1,70* Blank n, O. D oa«, Kh.i, * 'airs Trousers Khaki, foot Kits. Infantry 16ip Tents She! 1M Pin 1 1 H Flannel Shirts Tent Ki4 Teni Flies, wall. :i.1Tt'i small Tent Poles. Hospital Kidy r;e Tei tal uprights ill upright 1"" ! 134 Tents. Coniral. wall ston 1"4 IVi :: i ■iNikinu K f&gt; Trumi 6 Tn '1 Ta 1 National Colors, silk.. 1 KfKiin.-ntal lUlors. silk list R nd Recruiting ions, Khaki ft Q M B iruns. Kl: Chevrons. Kl fi Princliial Mil- Khaki 1 i Khaki ■a. Khaki. rgt. Infantry Chevrons, Khaki 111 I';, ii Inf. Chevrons, Khaki ■ iriiorals. Inf. Chevrons, Khiti. nipaiiy Q Inf. Ch.'vrons. Khaki in Ti-nt Poles, couical wall . </seg>
            <seg id="p093">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 91 4 1 » Conical Tent Tripods... 40 Conical Tent Pole Strai 1 Guidon Artillery 4.",o Campaign i t.M 7o2.Od $24.2»4..'!o ABSTRACT OF Q. M STORES DRAWN, I9O6. Milium drawn 7- Colts Revolvers. Cal. ::.s 1.2oo Blanket Roll Strap- 8 Waist Belts, Russet 78 Revolver Cart Boxes, Rnss. 78 Revolver Holsters, Rn - 2 Revolver Arm Chests ulges, Expert Rifleman. . 1-1 Badges, Sharpshooter^ 22 Badges, Marksman.. 30 Rear sights Rifle. I M Front sight- Small ii rin - 1st Sections cleaning rods 2nd and :!rd Sections cleanin Rifle Stocks 100 Infantry Cartridge Belts, wov 400 Tin Cups Ball Cartridges, Cal Blank Cartridges, Cal. M Ball Cartridges, Cal Friction Primers. Cannon Blank Charges, lib. Gun erg, Black Pasters, Whitt 4IHI Paper Targer - 15,060 Pai&gt;er Targets, Y " 15,( Paper Targets, "Z" 1 Bolt Action for Cal. SO Ritit Year 20 Front sight pin KXJI1 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">MILITIA LIST-1906 '**,' N,,,n Kx XTY it i .\ mi I Num tio tia mem)) r -"■I" ter N. N &lt; ■nipt N Aihun .\nteli&gt;]»- 11H44 1816 1114 l."i»i I 1 l'.IT' ia .v»4 B.ix Butt*- 111 U&gt; 11174 :M?o id 47:: 21411 1-JH 4 M 111!-* 11 B :« »10« til TO 87 4 1« 4I». in M 2104 11211 1571 7 1 1 7SX' li ."KM B4 .'1 :«7 34 12..", I'.w :«wi :«x»4 7.4 .01 14MHM 8B1H i:lH -' 21. t Dnndy Pill more llti 21('~ 17 - ."..Si ;( II I 214(1 MUSI *-''" 1( ;tl7:i '* 4 c llumiltnii 2708 4H| 17 4m 0 44OM 72» :« '•'•'•■. I 148« x 8=r Hi 7»:t I I '.I 091 - 1 I72MJ 7.H 17 1H«1 7.1 .«• :&gt;) l-i:}s 08: 4* H. I.V.I 1581 .04 21-17 7.W (tt 111117 1.4 1» 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 93 MILITIA LIST, I9O6 Continued. 3 lie!' 1*1 cor.NTY Kx Nuin- Ratio tia member* ti,,M '"■'■ '-"'I'' X S &lt;;. Keith 7.H 8.08 122 ti 8 19"&gt;1 Paha KiinlKill :&gt;«m 1 1 7."&gt;8 ltt K IK IX 14348 20«2 44 Lalliastcl 'Lincoln I.o K an MM 12 411 Hi 14.04 1 107 8 S 1141h 1247 ."&gt;(&gt; • Loop Madison 6.7 5. 1 BlcPherson errick 511 UK 119U Nance saaa m? :«i Eemaha ackolbt I4it52 1861 &lt;M !i414 1812 7.2 0-21 W7-2 1M 7.3 IVrkins 11771' 1494 ■2ti I4«8 8.01 1702 2til 12 10772 1291 K44") 14l:t 1413 5.9 I'latte Pulk 17747 MM I 017 10542 14911 21 147* .Ml K.-&lt;1 Willow Richardson K.Kk « 06 9004 1H12 34 P.M5I4 HH .".11 Saline 2558 43 2313 Saanders .011 - Bluff il 2352 4«&gt; 15690 .017 Sheridan Sherman Sioux H033 65SO 1119 2055 319 Thoiiiits Thurston Valley 1884 .044 14325 1704 •"&gt;(i 12 •") 7til 11.5 50 H756 815 54 7338 1391 \\;tshinjfton Wayne :t* I '.'.I', 7 :; 1 588 12 1587 ti 4 Weiwter Wheeler 11619 171ti •".4 1362 365 38 ■a 4 1 York 2619 HIM Total 1066:i00 lH(M.-)9 2741 Estimated </seg>
            <seg id="p096">94 ADJUTANT UENEKAL'S KKPORT I I I ABSTRACT OF SPECIAL ORDERS. 1905 NiiiiiUt 1st liifanl ry Hand an detaehnif in Battery A for (July at adjiitan His office mi January "&gt;. IN Numb. Meeting of MUitarj Hoard Number -nation of Captain Kdwa I V Cooper and 1st. Lteutenanl Johl H. Hath. Co. I. 2nd Infantry, election of lieutenant order NllllllKM" 4 ctlon of Captain ('•■ H 1st Infant .\ Niinil" Appointing non-cominissioned office n Signal Cor| Nuni a ol Captain Charles li. Dean and 1st. Lieutenant Cliffo !•;. \v«.., t 2nd. Infantry. . tilisted men in Number ■ nlisted men in :\iu\ Hattei\ A Nuiiilier Col .1 A Klirhatdt linu offlce January 17. I Nil in I &gt;• (Mineral lor dut\ at adjiitan • ling of Military I NmnlKT 10. Relieving Captain CD II 1st lnfuntrv limn roimnaiK i'f Compaii) Number 11 -nlisted men Company V 1st Infantry and Coinpanie jnd Infantry fantry and Captain I • Full* • us in name Compaa NuinlHT 13 Dis&lt;liai&gt;'&lt;' "t e«ll»ted men Comi ComiwaieB A. K and F 2nd Infantry. Number li. Resignation of Captain Harry 1 and election in same company. Bberly and 1st Lieutenant Iv Companies (' and E -nil Infantry Companies II. I) and F 1st hilanti Nunit* of Captain Kdward I-. Kodn''. &gt;'iimj&gt;aiiy D lsl In faiiiry ami Captain Chester A Puller Company L 2nd Infantry, and ■ and M 1st Infain Hull, ('unii&gt;an&gt; A 1st Infantry </seg>
            <seg id="p097">95 Xiiinl. men in Com, .Mack, 2nd Infantry Nil a of Captain chair held and 2nd Lieutenant Win Calkins. 1st I. A Myers. Company A 1st Infantry teWolf and 1st .Lieutenant Ernest n of Captain Emory I: Kroeger, fst Lieutenant Hayard T of enlisted men rod Company C 1st infantry ff 2nd Infantry Nun Eleetioi ■ I U D 1st. In large ot enlinted incu v Restoring Captain C I) l'&lt; M Military Hoard Discharge of e i Hated men ( Disch.i ■allies li. I and II 1st h N'uinbt Discharge of enlisted men Com \ and F 1st Infantry Number Resignation of Captain Robert ;ind election in same Company. .in. Chaplain 1st lnfy nisclu nlisted men ( Dischai : nu-li Si^-na Nuinbt of abseuce Captain F. I Jtoasr, ('(imiiany I) 1st Infantry Election of Captain Ansiust W. Company I 2nd Infanti Dipaniea I! and II lsi Infantry, Hat \ and Hospital Corps imuiand of Cum pan y 11 l&gt;: inaics \ (' &lt;; ;tnil K ."nil In: A. t'lapp. Company I) 2nd Infantry, Number 24. AppoiBtmeat of CapUUn Fletrhe Numb. I) Is) Infv . ami Co. A and ( Election in Co. M .'ml [a lMscli 1 liii'ii ('" I! 1st lnf&gt; Co I. Iuf&gt; A </seg>
            <seg id="p098">96 AIVl'TANT (iENEKAL S RETORT Numb. Organization of Infantry Co. at Aim Ntimli. Authorizing Xoimal School. Peru, to dr Niiinti. Muster-In of Infant r\ Co. at Alma Numbei &lt; tion of Captain Martin ShallenberHei . 1st Lieut. Charles H and 2nd Lieut f, I Reed X n nil. uiution of Infy. Co. at Kushvill Xiiinbe r Muster-In of Infy Co. at Rushvillt Number Election ot Captain Chas. P. Itresee. 1st Lieut. Krnest Auher 2nd Lieut. l,ee Fritz. Infy. Co. at RushTille. a.,,1 Numbi of enlisted men Signal Corps Appointment of non-commissioned officers Sign*! Corps and H&lt; spita X umbel Discharge of enlisted men Co. It. c. K and L 1st Infy Xuml&gt;i Discharge of enlisted men Co. C, &lt;;. H and L 2nd Infy X umber u4 Charles H :ify.. and el in same I ■c - t ion unation of 1st Lieir in sain- Xumbi Discharge ot enlisted nn Infy. and Hospital Co Xumber 42 PermisBion Hand 1st Infy. to leave home station Ke-el. ■ B. H Miillowuev. Co. M. 2nd lnfy. nation of 1st Lieut . I 1st lnfy., and election .i|&gt;iain John H. liond. Co. I&gt; 2nd Infy. Resignation of 1st Lieut. Harry .1 Ki I) 2nd Infy.. and elo tion in sanx Oischai - Number 39. M**wii&gt;n of Military Hoard Namher 4n. '■*"*• ■ Captain F. .1. Mack. Co. M 2nd lnfy. Nun) tier 41. nliuted men Co. C and D 1st lnfy. and Co. E and M M </seg>
            <seg id="p099">97 Resignation of Captain A. K. Knic Ap|M)intment of Captain .Ino. E. kerl&gt;ocker. Chaplain 2nd Infy Ttitile Chaplain 2nd Infy Numlier 44 Klection of Major Fred .1 Mac Kleotion in Co. M. 2nd Infy. 2nd Infy Election of 1st Lieut. Lewis K I ambert. Co. D, 2nd Infy A|,|&gt;ointnient of 2na Lieut. (In W. Cress. Hand 2nd Infy Ohmstede. Co 1. 1st Infy. I 1st Infy y Pritchard Band 1st Infy r Co. F 2nd Infy arils Co. F 2nd Infy Discharge of enlisted men in ( L 2nd Infy Number 4"&gt; Resignation of 2nd Lieui ;e K. Si&gt;ear. Hospital Corp*. Hospital Corps Cut, Hospital Corps Kleciion of 1st Lieut. John F Transfer of enlisted man Co. h S])ealman, Hospital Corps. , 2nd Infy. to Hospital Corps. Appointment of non-commissioned officers Hospital Discharge of enlisted men Sigiu i Con Number 4t; Board of Examination Captain S I) Davis to report Number 47. i Resignation of Captain Chas tion in sanu 1 se, Rushville Rifles, and elec Resignation of 2nd Lieut Hai tion in same Co. 'V L. Dussell, Co. K 1st infy., and elec- ■ice. Co. M 2nd Infy Klection of 1st Lieut. Kdmund Klection of 2nd Lieut. Gilbert Mullowney Co. M 2nd Infy McOUl Co. M 2nd Infy. It Number 48 Discharge of enlisted men ( I st Infy . Co. it. C. Q and L 2nd Infy Number 4H Resignation of 1st Lieut. Otto K ii, sail" Hagel. Co. K 1st Infy., and election Klection of 2nd Lieut. Hillyard ( Wilson Co. K 1st Infy Discharge of enlisted men Co. ( nd Infy., and Hospital Corp*. Niimut Captain Kdwin C. Pickett, Co. M 1st Infy., authorized to attend In - fantry and Cavalry school I". S. Ainiy. Number 51 Delegates to Int. laUonal Guard Association. Election of 1st Lieut. Louis W. Kleetion ot Charles C. Myers ( Appointment of Uixl lift Har Election of Captain ( K. UVavt lection of 1st Lieut. B. J. Rich iou of Major .1. M. Itirkne Election of Captain E. Arthur Election of Captain Wilbur S. Pi Election of 1st Lieui. Kdmund H </seg>
            <seg id="p100">98 Number ection of Captain John P. Dischaifie ol enlisted men Si 1st hrfjr. and Hi ( K Number Klection In .1 lnfj Discharge of enlisten mi 1st In Jnd. ai I T V A Number 54 Disch ulisted 1111 1st and Co. M III Infj NuiiiIh&gt;i' l.lilV ' l.iikin Nunil.- Ll.ll! I. .1)11 II Hrock, Co K 1st Infy Klertion in Co. M 1st Infy Discharge of enlisted men Co B, B, F. K and 1.. 1st Infy :ili.sted man Rnshville Kifle NunilHT Re-election of Captain \\ I o A 2nd Inf !t;nation of 2nd l.ient Chas. R Weeks. Co. 1) 2nd Infy i ion in 1 .in oa in Co. F 2nd Inf) ■;ain .Ino E. Tattle, Chaiilain 2n&lt;l Inf FurlouKh enlisted man Co. ('■ 2nd Infy. isted men Staff. Co. B, F. and H 2nd Inf Nunil • it State contest in rifle shooting N'unil.. t H. Btooer, Co. 1) im ii it Mil L. Gilkerson. I'o K 2nd hit am Discharge of enlisted men 1st Infy and Battery A Nu nil Klection ol Kushville Rifle in of 1st l.ient ('ha Jnd Lleul Hopper, Rustnille Rifle; ancher. Co. F 2nd Infy I'eniod and 2nd l.ient in sain- Ha J B Smith. Asst. Sm 1st lnf\ Numl Detachn &gt;t in \uinln rifle shoolinv ii of 2nd Lieut m of 2nd Lieut Dean. Co. M 1st Inf Thomas, Co. K 2nd lufy Caint'iun, Co. K -in] I HIT 2nd Infy., (n. I. L'n.l Inl if Captaii ■ iid .-li-otiiin ApiKjiiiinifin of 1M l.iiu' I \V. H enlisted nun Co K </seg>
            <seg id="p101">ArUlTANT OEXERAL8 REPORT 99 :&lt; L Discharge of enlisted men 1 (I Infv. ■sd, Co. B, II and M 1st infy C. Bbernberger, Co. K 2nd Infy.. and lection in same (' (Discharge of enlisted men Staff. Co. L) 1st Infy , and Hand and Co 2nd Infv. Number ii4 Kl ** &lt;-Ii ►' Captain Melvin H. Guile., (•„ c i st i nfv . Hlection of 1st I.ient. McCullough. Co. C. 1st Infy. Klection of 2nd I.ient. Joseph Hnlka. Co. I) 2nd Infy Discharge of enlisted men.Co. I. 1st Infy., and Hand 2 Infy Nil in Im Leave of ahsence 1st Lieut. C. U Hopper Furloush Win C. Ramsey. C nissaiv M sergeant 2nd Infy Discharge of enlisted men Co. H. C and Q 1st Infy., Co. 0, K and L 2nd Infy. and Troop A Number 6 Klection of 1st Lieut. Prank M. Smith, Co I) Ist Iufy Discharge ot enlisted men Co Hospital Corps Number (17 and 6 MeetinK uf Military Board 'spital at State Fair Grounds BlCCUon of Captain Ralph A. lirii Permission Hand 1st Infy. to leave gman, Co. Q 1st Inly home station. Delegates to annual meeting A •ciation Military Sin- 51^29111 Number i;.;. Resi K nati&lt;.ii of tod Lieut. Clovd W. Bfa*. Oo. I) 1st Infy.. and etoettai in same Co. Resignation «l 1st l.irui. Join Election in ('-&gt;. G Isi Infv I. 1st Infv . C(. I), 1 ami K L'nd Infv inn iii Xaiional Competition L Hospital Corps Ui establish tit-Id h il)er 71. L Discharge nf enlisted men Co. (' and G l-'iid Infy her 72 Election of 1st Lieut, .lames F Haihberger Co. K tad Infj Klection i&gt;f iTnti I, it ut. William I.. Kolm Co. K 2nd Infy. Re-election of 1st Lieut Clinton W. T. Garrison. Uatiei.v A 1)iscl Bltated men Co. M 1st lufv . Itatteiy A and Hospital rtkar 74. Laavt "f alisence Captain S. B. Voder Batterv A </seg>
            <seg id="p102">ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT 100 Number 75 Election in Co. G 1st lnfy. Discharge (if enlisted men Battery A. Numl ■ Resignation of Captain Emil Placek Co. I 1st lnfy . iind election in same company. • Captain M. H. Guiles Co. C 1st lnfy harge of enlisted men Mattery A. Number 77. Leave of absence Col. W. R of absence Major Fred .1 Reduction in grade of enlisted Mclaughlin 1st lnfy Mack 2nd lnfy men. Hospital Corp* Discharge of enlisted men Co. Signal Corps and Hospital On Xnmbt: C 1st lnfy. Co. C and F 2nd lnfy Election of 2nd Lieut. Harry E Ford. Co. Q 1st lnfy Discharge of enlisted men Hospital Corps, and Co. G 2nd lnfy Meeting of the Military Board. Number 79 Resignation or Captain W. F. Summons. Co. A 2nd lnfy Number 79%. Revoking special order No 71 Number 80. Election of Captain Louis W Ohmstede. Co. 1 1st lnfy Election of 1st Lieut. Charles C. Myers, Co. I 1st lnfy. Election of 2nd Lieut. Charles E. Ault. Co. I 1st lnfy. Election of 2nd Lieut. Walter J. Discharge of enlisted men. Hand Schneider, Co. D, 1st lnfy Co. A, C and M 1st lnfy., and 2nd. Number 81 Resignation of 2nd Lieut. Paul W. Hutchins, Co. C, 1st lnfy., an election in same company. Discharge of enlisted men in Co. C 1st lnfy N'umbe Board of Examination. Captain E. Arthur Carr. to report to same Number 83. Resignation of Captain Wilbur S. Price. Co. M 2nd lnfy., and el. in same Co Election of 2nd Lieui Macy, Co. C 1st lnfy 1st lnfy. Discharge of enlisted men Co. K Number 84. Board of Inspection. Number 84%. Board of Inspection. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">A !}•! I XANX wENERAL S REPORT 101 Number 85 Revoking parts of special order No. 8 L Resignation of 2nd Lieut. Jacob H. Evens, Co. F 1st Infy., and ection in same Co. L Resignation of Captain Chas. A. Calkins, Co. A 1st Infy., and election same Co. Discbarge of enlisted men Co. L, 1st Infy., and Co. L, 2nd Infy. Number 86. L Resignation of 1st Lieut. Charles C. Myers, Co. I, 1st Infy., and elec - n in same Co. Discharge of enlisted men Co. E and Co. K 1st Infy., and Hospital Corps </seg>
            <seg id="p104">102 ADJUTANT GENERAL \S KEPOKT ( I r-i 1 I in GENERAL ORDERS, 1905 HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL CCARn. Adjutant General's Offloi Lincoln. .lamia: General Orders ( No 1. In accordance with the provisions of the military code, the tern staff officers expires with that of the officer appointing them, tl i he following eommi 'In- staff of the Common Chief, are honorably discharged from the military service of t! Brigadier General .1 H. Culver. Adjutant G Col. Geo E. Jenkins. Quartermaster and Commissary Genera Col Chas. J Hills. Inspector General. Col. Carroll D. Evans. Surgeon General. Col. J. A. Ehrhardt. Judge Ad AIDES-DE-CAMP Col Clarendon E. Adams Col. Clarence J Mi Col. Jacob S. Dew. Col. Samuel M Melick Col. Joseph \V Thomas. Col. Herbert P. Shumway Col. Chas. W. Kaley Col Joseph J. Latu l&gt;roy \V. Garoutte The Commander-in-chief desires to express his high appreciate the services rendered by the members of his staff JOHN H MICKEY. rnor and Commander-in-chief Official: J H CULVER, Adjutant &lt;".• HEADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD, Adjutant General's Office -incoln. Janimry ti. lSit, No. 2. \ Having been re-elected and inaugurated as Governor. I resume c t&lt;&gt; lake effect Januaiy ,5 1905 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">103 HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, / Adjutant General'! Offic \ Lincoln, Fi al Orders No \ ommandint Northern Division, having ordered . S. A. (retired), to inspect the Ne - ision of sections :! and 14 of Act or , the Companies will be paraded for Brigadier General A. S. DagRett. I", i luaska National Guard, under provisi Congress approved January II, IMS, this inspection as follows: P. M ;iment. Weeping Water N:00 P. M inient, Nebraska City S:0li P. M !:00 P. M :i It!, Company C." 1st K. - n 17, Company 'E,' 1st Re; :i IX, Company •D," 2nd Rei ii 20, Company • H. " 1st Re; i 21, Company ■(;," 1st Rei P. M ;inieut, Wilber P. M iment, Fairburv l'. M, iment. Nelson P. it P. M P. M March 10, Hospital Corps Lincoln March 13, Company "D." 1st Regiment, Weeping March 14, Company "C," 2nd Regiment, NVbrask; March 15, Hattery Wymore March 16, Company ■('." lsi Regiment, Heatrice ;iniem h H. Compan; il Regiment, York maud of the Militia of the State, as Commander-in-chief, and announce the following staff apiKjintmei, Urigadier General J. H. Culver. Adjutant General. Col. Geo. B. Jenkins, Quartermaster and Commissary General. Col. Chas I. Hills, Inspector General. Col. Carroll D. Evans. Surgeon Oeoerml. Col .1. A. KhrhardT. Judge Advocate (ien. A1DKS -DK-CAMP. Col. Clarendon E. Adams Col. Clarence J Miles. Col. Jacob S lVw Samuel M. Melick. Col. Joseph. W. Thoni.: Col. Herbert P. Shumway Col. Chas. W. Kal. Col. T. W. McCulloush. The members of the staff re-appointed will take rank from the datf in their original commissions: new appointments from date ol this order. JOHN H. MICKEY, Governor and Commander-in-Chief Official: .1 H. (TLVER, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">AIMITANT QENERAL'8 HEPORT 104 March 23, Band 2nd Regiment Oscenla 8:00 P. M March 24, Company "H," 2nd Regiment. Aurora 8:00 P. M March 25, Coni|&gt;any "A," 2nd Regiment. Ke^iney P. M March 2S, Company "H," 1st RagtaMBt, Broken How March 29. Company "B," 2nd Regiment, st. Paul 8:00 P. M Man: i|&gt;any "K," l8t Regiment. Columbus 00 P. M March 31. Company "K." 2nd Regiment. Sriinrler 8:00 V M April 1, Signal Corps, Wisuer 8:00 I 1 M April 3, Band, 1st Regiment 1' M Fremont April 4. ('ompaii&gt; "H. April 5, Company "L." 2nd Regiment. \ April 6, Company "F." 1st Regiment, M 8:00 P. M April T. Company "M." 2nd Regiment, Albic April 8, Company ■G," 2nd Regiment, OmaKi April 10, Company 'L." 1st Regiment, Omali; April 11, Company "1." 2nd Regiment, Omal,:i 8:00 P. M April 12. Company I Regiment. Tekai 1' M April 13, Company "I," 1st Regiment. Wuh(K 8:00 P. M April 14, Troop "A Sew^i M 1' m April 15, Company "F." 2nd Regiment. Lin?&gt;ln 8:00 P. M II. The state insjiection will also be made on the dates indicated in the foregoing section, by the Ins|&lt;ector General and field officers, in th following order: Col C. J. Bills, Hospital Corps LJeut. Col. F. J. Bolshaw, Company "D." 1st Regiment, and Company C," 2nd Regiment Major J. C. Hartigan. Mattery Regiment. A." Companies "C" and "K," 1st Major George Lyon, Jr., Company Col. J. W. McDonnell, Companies D, " 2nd Regiment H" and 'G." 1st Regiment Major George l.yon, Jr., Compai Regiment and 2i: iment Band. Lieut. Col. W. R. McLaughlin. Companies 11." A, 1 and M B Regiment, and Company "M," 1st Regiment ich. Company 'K," 1st Regiment, and C'onipan\ K ' 2nd Regiment Major C. M. Richards. Signal I Major Fred Gegnei . 1st Regiment Hand. Comi&gt;any "B»" la) iment, and Company I.. i&gt;nd Regiment. Major C M Richards, Coni|&gt;any -.M." 2nd Regiment, and Company F," 1st Reghuent. Major O. Q. Osborne. (\&gt;m|&gt;anies C." and I," 2nd Regimei, Company I.,' 1st Regiment Major C. M. Richards, Company "K. " 2nd Regiment. Lieut. Col. F. J. liolshaw. Company I," 1st Regiment Major E. H. Phelps, Trot&gt;p A." Cavalry. Col. C. J. Bills, Company. F," 2nd Regiment </seg>
            <seg id="p107">ADJUTANT GENERALS KEPORT 105 III. Company commanders will assemble their commands for inspec - nn dates above mentioned, in heavy marching order. Campaign Mine shirts, blouses, and trousers, and leggings will be worn. 11V. The officers and enlisted men of the commands inspected will t»f wed One Dollar ($1.1)0} each foi in compliance with this in compliance with this allowed such compensation as my hoard V. Each officer detailed ;i- ?tor. will also act as mustering offi- illy instructing the company E maniler in the preparation of ion of his tour of duty, forwar tion, to the Adjutant General. the muster and pay roll, and on com - 1 Hie same with the report of his in- tVI. It is expected that each c ed, and prepared to enter on a rders. camp equipage, ordnanct ines for inspection. &gt;mpany will be found fully equipped. trice; all company hooks, flies and quartermasl will be in VII. Field and staff officers will .lent company ]&gt;ost, on the date report for Inspection at the most )f its inspection. By order of the I .1. H. CULVER. Adjutant Gem HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, I General's Office. \ Lu&lt;O ii. April ti, INI .il Orders i No. 4. \ 11. Company L. 2nd Infantry R erly care for public property, &lt; ired, is hereby mustered out of ■giment, N N G.. having failed to lin the standard of efficiency Officers and enlisted men will be honorably discharged, when gov - ernment and state property issued to the company shall have been prop - accounted for. The commanding officer will at once collect. t oil v pack, ami safely store all public property, awaiting shipping in and send an invoice of the same to Adjutant General. III. The West Point Rifles, failing to attain the standard required the Rules and Regulations of the Nebraska National Guard, is hi stered out of service, and officers and men will Ik- honorahl rged when government and slate pin; i.il to the company Ehave been properly accounted all public property is carefully tant General. Lincoln. Neb in. The commanding officer will see lacked, invoiced, and ship|ied to Hie without di By older of the lSo\ J H. CLLVER, Adjutant General The Inspecting officers wi may l&gt;e determined ii|&gt;on by the niili cer for each company he \u&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p108">106 HKADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD,/ to provide for the organiza 1 innient. and compensation of tlu militia, and to provide for the enrollment of the unorganized militia Hi conform to the act of Congress entitled. An act to promote the effic it-ncy of the militia and for other purposes," approved .lanuary L'lst and lo repeal Chapter M, Session Laws ol IM7, entitled. An act b tablish a Military Code for the State of Nebraska, and to provide for tl organization, government and compensation of the organized militia •eal Chap -ion Ijws of 1NX7. known as Chapter 5(1 Compile Statutes approved March :'.lst. entitled an act to amend ai entitled. An act to establish a military code for the State of Nebraska approved February :!Mh. A I) 1881. and to rejical Chapter 64. Law as now existing, approved February 12th. 1SH7. the same beii Chap he Compiled Statutes of 1901 and Chapter :'.:'. of Col, Annotated Si;. titled Militia." ot Chapter 56 of the Compiled Statutes of IM1, and Section 7MS of Chaptt - Annotated Statute! of IMS, relating to Dmum O H&lt; it enacted 1' ifXebrask on 1 All the able l&gt;odied male citizens and able bodied males of foreign birth who have declared their intention to become citizens, who are more than IS and less than '&lt; I aue. and who are resi - dents of te the militia, subject lo the following exemptions I. Pet- ,&gt;ted by the laws of the I'nit. mpted by the laws of this slat :'. The meml&gt;ers of any regularly organized fire or police department in any city, village, or town, and exempt firement who have served their full term in any fire company; but no meml&gt;er of the active militia shall lie relieved from duty because of his joining any such fire company or department. 4. Justices and clei I deeds; sheriffs, ministers of the gos|&gt;el: practicing physicians, officers, and assistants of hospitals, prisons, and jails, conductors and engineers of railways. ."&gt;. Idiots, lunatics, paup' &gt;nds. confirmed drunkards, i&gt;ersons addicted to the use of narcotic drugs, and Bsraou convicted of infamous crimes All such exempted persons, except those enumerated in subdivisions I and 5. shall be available for military duty in care of war. invasion. i ction, or imminent sang' Adjutant Gteneral'i Office. \ Lincoln. April 15. II No The following Art of il; U« is pnMisti. nitnrinatioi iii.d (jovernment of all concerned : An act to establish a lillitJ »a am </seg>
            <seg id="p109">107 citizens of this state, and all who i become eitize! ion 2. The names of all male shall have declared their intention t( of eighteen and forty-five shall annu of property for taxation for county ■Mich enrollmeir occupation of On or naval service On such enrolltm person exempt from military word 'exempt" and the reason for s nd rile them in the offlc. ally, at the time of the assessment and state pan) ihe name, residence, age. an d their previous or existing militar •nt list, and opiK&gt;site the nai duty, the shall write th uch exemption and shall sign sue ive county clerks at th returning the assessment rolls, an \ugust in each year then ibed by law for filing and the clerk shall, on or before the first d make a certified report of same to th on file in his office. adjutani Section :!. The militia of the ■ shall he divided into two classes: The active militia shall consist of late, which shall be the active and the reserve militia, the organized and uniformed milita v known as the -Nebraska National Guard;" t) militia shall coi of all those liable to service in the militia but not serving in the National Guard of the stat Section 4 The Nebraska National Guard shall be recruiter: volunteer enlistment; and to be organized into not less than twenty nor more than twenty-eight companies of infantry; not more than two troop: of cavalry, and one battery of artillery, one signal corps, one ens- corps, and one hospital corps; which may ladrons battalions, and regiment Section 5. The Governor, as Commandei -in-Chief of the militia, may ■mploy it or any part of it in the defense of or relief of the w any part of its inhabitants or territories, and shall have all the pa to carry into effect the provisions of th Section fi. The staff of the Ooniniander-in-Chief shall consist of an Adjutant General, with the ran'&lt; of Brigadier General, who shall l&gt;e ex offlcio Chief of Staff: a Quartermaster and Commissary General; a Sur treon General; a Judge Advo&lt; . ;il; and an Inspector General- with the rank of Lieutenant Colonel The inspector of Small Arms Practice and as many aides-de-camp as he may deem pro]&gt;er. n ed ten with the rank .if Lieutenant Colonel. The nspector of Small Arms practice iind two of the a; ip to be ap|K)inted or detailed from the office! I the National Guard. Th" aides-decamp shall serve without pay in time of i&gt;eac ction 7 The Adjutant General shall be in control of the military department of the state and subordinate only to the governor in ma pertaimlim to the said department He shall issue and transmit all orders of the Commander-in-chief with to the militia or mil ization of the state and shall keep a record of all ofli&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p110">108 and of all such matter* as pertain to the organization of the state militia and N \alional Guard, and iierforni all the dutit the quartermaster and commit nient, war, or insurrection, in which c '■ral shall .•i issue clothing, camp and garrison eqtiipa* taining to the militia or National C ixirtation and subsistence when nect ernoi . Me shall ha- and c in time of encamp - le duties of the quartermaster rfonned by that offirer. He shall ! all ordnance and ordnance It ;e. and other public property per luard Ot the state; provide trans under authority of the Gov .f the colors, flags guidons, and trophies of war belonging to the state, and shall not allow the same to be loaned out or removed from their proper place of deiKisit He shall furnish at the ex|&gt;e! blanks, ami forms, and such military by th&lt;- Commander-in-chief. He shall also, on or In -ulat session of the Si;r all trai ith the il&gt;er next preceding make out a full account expense ol the same, for the pre ug two years, and such other ma hall be required by the nor, and on at such other times as the Governor may reqn and returns to the War De - l&gt;artnient or r i the In as may be required by law neral may have an assistant Adjutant ral, with the rank of Major, and an assistant quattermaster with the rank of Captain, who appointed and commissioned by the • uiniendation of the Adjutant General, and the neces - oleiks and employes, not i&gt; hree in time of peace, who shall be api&gt;ointed by the Adjutant General. The Adjutant General shall 1k&gt; the disbursing officer, unless other* &gt; il by the Gov - ;illotment to be made by tli- of War under the provisions of the Inited States law approved January 21. 1903, entitled an Act. "to promote the efficiency of the militia and for other purposes." -uch l&gt;onds to the I'niti ,nd the State as may be required by th&lt; Wai and the Governor of Nebraska respec - tively for the faithful iteeountiii ping of public moneys coining into hi* hands or entrusted to him for disbursement. The Ad - jutant General shall provide a seal which shall be the seal of his office, and shall be delivered by him to his He shall reside at the Caiptol and shall hold his office during the pleasure of the Governor. 'I be Adjutant General shall receive for his services one thousand eight hundred dollars |&gt;ei annum. The Assistant Adjutant General shall aid the Adjutant General by the iierformance of such duties as may be -:ied to him. and shall, in en- nee or inability of the Adju - tant General i&gt;erforni all. or such portion of the duties of the Adjutant latter ma&gt; expressly ilHegate to him. He shall give a bond with sufficient uig five thousand dollars. he state all |&gt;ro|K&gt;r l)lank books all lie ag&gt;- </seg>
            <seg id="p111">\ruiT.\NT GENERAL'S KEE'OKT 109 conditioned for the faithful performs us ODsapensatlon the sum of twelve hoi liis duties, and shall n i ired dollars per annum The Assistant Quart* 1 1 li-siRiied ro him by the Adjutant ill perform su&lt;-h duties as may be neral. lit- shall give ■ IhuiiI with ( sufficient sureties in a sum not ditioned for the faithful perfonaai than one thousand dollars, con - r his duties, and shall reo i compensation the sum of one thou Section 8. The Quarrel i qadred by the Commander-in-chief, -ing to his department, shall .subsistence, for the troops. He sh the War Department and th. and Commissary General when re - call take care of all paMic property transportation, supplii nil make such reports and returns to dent of the United States as may be required by law or regulation. an&lt; mander-in-chief. on or before the ti shall annually report to the Com - "tuplete in toe in which it is deposited, with a Etory of such property and the | uled account of all artich art meal not preriotialy n ! " n 9 - T1 &gt;' General shall, ander the direction of the Commander-in-chief, have general supervision and control of all matfeis ion and control of all matters lining to the medical department of the militia and Nebraska Na - il Guard. He shall prescribe the physical and mental disabilities iptinc from military duty, and the standard of physical examina - tion for enlistment, in compliance with the requirements of the War M*Mlt When so directed, he shall make inspections of the sani - condition of camps and quarters, and the care of the llc'i in hos- pitals: reports of which shall be made Immediately to the Adjutant ii Iob in. The .Indue Advocate General is the total adviser of the military department of the Nebraska, in such matters m ruining to the militia and National ( as may be referred to him by tin Commander-in-chief. He views edinss of court martial quiring the action of the Commander-in-chief endorsing thereon his (.pinion in writing. He shall brine such suits or actions as mav be suits or actions as ma ed in writing by the Comtnandei -in-chief. He shall on or I ■ the first day of December make his annual report to the Command, &gt; annual re|K&gt;rt to the Commander ief through the Adjutant Gent Section 11. The Ins, shall make such inspections of i he milita: uid of the milit d National Guard and its equip- s as the Commander-in-chief ii *1 from time to tin* l ions, with his reeommeu - y and for the abatement of any ■Section 12. The Inspector of Small Arms Practice shall inspect and uct the troops in small arms practice, assist in locating and en. n small arms prmctii m locating and con rlag ranges, and perform such other duties as may be required of He shall compile and make out a semi-annual report to th. uinl dollars per annum u'lii'd ,,!nl mm; expended General of the sta iiraska. in siieh Batten ikt- iianl as may \n- referred to him b* tht- shall re)H&gt;rt Immediately followii Ks for the condemnation larities found h&gt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p112">110 ADJUTANT (iENKRAI. s REPORT lain General of the laiK»'i praoiict laul General of the target practict of the Nebraska National Guard, or of the Nebraska National Guard, or thf ts May and the first ii be required thf Bret day of May and the first (lav of NovemlMi and such other re day of November and such mired i) 13. The Nebraska National Guard shall lie liable at all tim ordered into activ and shall be fi Commander-in-chief on all occasions for military service within th in time of war. invasion, riot, rebellion, insurrection able apprehension thereof. 01 ii|K&gt;n the requisition of the Presiden &gt;ned States And ill case the National Guard is insufficient it number the Commander-in-chief may by proclamation order the eni l.ient for active such additional portions of the militia as In iiuiv deem necessary to meet the emergency or to comply with tt by draft, if a sufficient number shall not volunteer, and may organize the same in the manner herein provided for organizing Ine Nebraska al Guard; and when so ordered out for service, the militia sha 11 ions and render the Ear |i:ired of the Nebraska National Guard, Baa the same conn ilted at the time of said service for the army of t le arn Tinted 14. Members of the militia ordered into the active authority shall not be Hal inally. foi their duty When inst any officer of the militia for any act done by such offi&lt; in his official capacity in the discharge of any du liust any person acting under the authority ly virtue of any warrant issued by him pursuant to law. tt lant may reqin isecuting or instituting img to file security for the pay meat of costs that may be aw efeudant in all cases may 111 udant therein, and the d 1 denial and give the matter in evid plaintiff shall l&gt;e non-suited, or have a verdict or Judgment ■Sains* him. the defendant shall recover his costs and a reasonable at 1 the county, in s.ich manner as he may prescril shall, in case of any such draft. appoint a time and place of parade and shall I other ami further power as may be necessary to car ffect the provisions at this Act relative to any such draft. Ion 16. Whenever any portion of the militia is employed In Hid of the civil authority, the governor if in his judgement the main tenanee of law and order will thereby be promoted, may by proclamatio c.uisiiion of the President of the l"nii • i^natins tt a draft thf Commander in-&lt; lion it equitably ■ lining the several counties, taking &lt; are that the iiiinent shall Ik&gt; made equitably annul- ownslii </seg>
            <seg id="p113">N *■ I ( i w 1 h 1 11 iare the coutm m which the troop r any dfled portioo thereof, to be in a state of insurrection Insurrection Section IT. The C'omnianderin chief may from time to time. mak&lt; {illation irders for the government of the h law. and cause the sam. National Guard, to be printed and ational Guard, not inconsistent w ■ther with any laws relating to the ublished in hookforni. in such nm lokforni. in such nun as lie tnav in his judgment ction 18. The o lunent. a! of discipline Nebraska shall l&gt;e the organiza- "ii 19. No enlistment shal ale citizens of this state and ev ko has declared his intention to allowed other than of able-bodied able-bodied male of foreign birth me a citizen, between tin d fortv-fiv ace no minor shall i his parents or guardian. All en be for three years, and made by tments in the National Guard si ■ning enlistment papers in triulic ii according to the form pros lie following oath or affirmation the Ai &gt;minissiom-d officer command) I offi wit: "1 do solemnly sweat (or affirm United States of America, and to rve them honestly and faithfully whomsoever: and that I will nt 1 will bea ate ot Nel rtt 1 w id op| and that I will ot&gt; • rve and obey the ord int of the Tailed S he officers appointed over me. verm me. and tin EnllstOK i ;le anil prescribed for the Natio ( Hard l Jl Whenever the word &gt;uipan ( | in ■ militarv and const tiled to mean ■ y of infantry, a troop of cavalry, a Section T2. The companies, battal n . and regimenta of the Nebraska a brigade by the ('ommander - ihe Senior Field Officer. i an offic A it ional Guard, of I shall consist of one Held band utenant colonel: three in. le adjutant, one quartern and one chaplain. ■•m with the ran'i m it Ive companies, one colonel: one ■urseon with the rank of major commissary, &gt;n assistant su lank of captain; one as&gt; a and National Guard iment. and system of discipline of the army of the United ts neatly the hum as may be practicable. without the written i rules and article! for the gOYernment of the army of tin id of this slate. So help me Cod." h called out by proclam ■cifled in such proelunattc it shall be um f artillery, or corps detailed on duly with 1 iiffic Kadi infant </seg>
            <seg id="p114">112 • . three battalion adjutants and three battalion quartermasters, provided in time of peace the adjutants shall be appointed from the first lieutenants, and the quartermasters (who shall art as commissaries) tram the second lieutenants, of their respective battalions, by the regi - mental commander upon recommendation of the baitalioii ronitnander; ant major: one qua ue commissary ser - 1 one hospital steward, who shall be a practicing physician or a pharmacist: two color sergeants, and three battalion sergeant majors, to be appointed by the regimental commander iiihhi recommend aiion of their n nattaliun command. •i-li regimental liand shall consist ol one chief must - with rank of second lieutenant, one principal musician, one drum major, four sergeants, eight corporals, one ci&gt;ok. and twelve privates. .•■h company of infantry schall consist of one captain. one first lieut&gt;ii:mi nd lieutenant, one first sergeant, one quar - leim. •ant. four sergeants, eight eorporals, two musicians, two cooks, one artificer, and eiuht&gt; -s.veu privates. The minimum strength of a couipauy shall be fifty enlisted men. Provided. The number of non-commissioned 'I the maximum strength during time of l&gt;eace ma d by the Commander-in-chief in General Orders. aea troop Of cavalry shall consist of one captain, one lieutenant, one second lieutenant, one first sergeant, one quarter - master sergeant, si uht corporals, two cooks, two farriers and blacksmir aidler. one wagoner, two ministers, and not ity-six primates The minimum strength of a troop shall be fifti-one enlisted men. The number of non-commissioned officers and tl»e minimum and maximum strength during time of ]&gt;eace may be designated by the Commander-in-chief in General Orders. ion L'T Kach battery of artillery shall consist of one captain, two first lieutenaii -&lt; cond lieutenant, one first sergeant. OM quartern!.. neant, Bix sergeants, twelve cor- IHirals. two cooks, four artificers, two musicians, and not to exceed ninety - one privates. The minimum strength of a battery shall be fifty-three enlisted men Provided. The number ol commissioned and non-com - missioned officers and the maximum strength during time of peace may U designated b.v the Commander-in-chief in General Orders. tea Signal Corps company shall consist of on. tain, one first lieutenai I lieutenant, five first class igeants. ten cori&gt;orals, thirty first class privates, tv. The minimum strength of the company shall tx - il.irty enlisted men. Provided. The number of non-commissioned oil during time of peace may i&gt;. ud b.v the Commander-in-chief in .1 Orders.; ion M. The ambul;, a subdivision of the Hospital Corps, shall consist of one major surgeon, commanding; one captain: -lant surgeon; one first lieutenant, assistant surgeon, four sergeants, </seg>
            <seg id="p115">113 musician: one cook; thirty pi i filsI The niininmni strength of thi Tke mininiuni strength of the company shall he forty-one enlisted men. Providing during tini. •-, the Providing during time of pea. nna-commlss to— d ofteen and the maximum strength may he desi^ the ConimantliT-iii chief in General Orders, and the ambulant-. non-commissioned officers and the maximum strength may he desist Commander-iii chief j n General Orders, and the ambulanc. 1 Many shall perfom mm attaining ■ ■equired. pertaining Hospital ("in "'" :: " Ti ■ .'lid number which shall constitute imber which shall constitute tiie Kngineer ('dips, and other authorized organizations of the Nel unizations of the Nel National Guard, may he designated by the Commander-in-chief in (;. be Commander-in-chief in G Orders, conformiii- Halted States Army Orders and regulations. the exigencies of the occasion ma&gt; require. ion 31. The Governor may appoint and commission a Brigadtei \rniy Orders and regulations 1S1OM 11 Section 31. The Governor m int and commission a lirigadiei General from the officers of the Nebraska National Guard, when he ■us such action for the best interest of the service, who when coni - niooed. may appoint th&lt; members of his staff. The rcgini -inal Held officers shall be chosen by the votes of the f X« a National Guard, when he vice, who when com niemlK-rs of his staff in -nuil Held officers shall be chosen by the votes of tht ( oniinissioned officers of t heir npany ffic 1 I" officers shall be elected by and from the members of their respi !f shall be elected by and from the member* of their resjx companies The candi.i \ing the greatest Dumber of votes shali milled to a certiric.' ion. The regimental staff of officers are appointed by theii candii ivins the lumber of votes shal ;rtlflca ion. . ff of offic. l. landers 1'iovided, That all (lections and ap|K&gt;intments of commissioned ideil. Thai all (lections and appointment! of commissioned officers in the Nebraska National Guard shall be subject to the approval hi the Nebraska National Guard shall be subject to the approval of the Governor Provided, further. That no parson shall be com -ioned to any office until he shall ha^ -factory examination &lt;&gt; his fitness for ttu position, or may have graduated from- the mili- ■I the Governor. Provided, further. That no person shall bt issioned to any office until he shall ha\.- a satisfactory examination nay have graduated from- the mill tary department of the State IHiversity. not to exceed th prior -neb appointment, when he may be commissioned as either ri &lt;nd lieutenant without passing such examination. Section ::i' The regimental non-commissioned staff officers, the hos- I'niv not to exceed ti prior id lieutenant without such examination Section ::i' The regimental non-commissioned staff officers, tin pital (toward urn recommendation of the Burgeon), the chief musician ilium major, and BOD-OOI of the band shall ! :il steward ion recommendation of the surgeon), the chief musician 1 officers ol the band shall he ap licaited by the rc-iniental commanders. 1 ;: ts and eorpor company shall be appotetod by the regimental commander, on immandei otg and oorporaii or mpany shall be appointed by the regimental command! i he ndation of tin live Company eomnuuaders. The tiist and snartenn ■ appointed by the company com and qnartermaMi ■pointed by the eotnpai u mand amOBK I nts. The trumpeters, musicians, arti - hllers. and wagoners aie appointed by the company inder. from among the sergeants. The trumpeters, imisieian- iaddlers. and » Comma Odors from among the members of tli- ive coinp., .n ::::. The commissions of the itaS officers of the Commander of their n ompanies .n ::::. The commissions of the staff officers of the Commandei in-chief and regimental staff officers shall expire with the term of office ei the officer* appointing them. All other officers shall hold tlieii e othcers appointing them. All other officers shall hold theii nun missions tor the period of irs, unless sooner atachai When </seg>
            <seg id="p116">ADJUTANT (4ENEKALS KEPOK1 114 appointment will !»■ em officer sliall lake rank from the date of his original commission A commissioned ofl .flic ■worn ■me &lt;"ivil authority having power to adminlste re-appointed, the bi majt tint, hospital stewai musician, and drum major, wi turn of ofl officers who a and deliver to tin- adjutanl hi-chief may direct, not • sand dollars (95,UV0.u«), ,,a. a l,le to tl. i «iili lufficienl sureties, to be appn l,v tk&lt; r, conditioned ami use of said pi ,md the ret are of mum, when ordi anpetent authc wh in ttood order; ordir tad unavoidable loss and dan rdinary wear and unavoida and dan x&lt; un ,l , . . in iimi nnish Ihe adju ,il with properly '|'li a" ih e f and in • dama al with prop' attending sucli :&gt; LI public prop |ii when in use in the All | -hall be kept iii armories, or other proi , it shall l&gt;e unlawful tor an&gt; pe :iire of mil .,,,) win, . public property to allow out of hi '"&lt;! any niembe charged with tl aid public prop* nw out of hi* (fee \ National Quard who shall fail to return any proper! ate or United - othei place of deposit, v the \ National Guard who aha -late or 1'nited Statt notified by the nwilrtln offlcer m&gt; to &gt;U&gt;. shall ba fined in any notified by the commanding oft"i&lt; not exceeding fifty dollars i$5im. to he prosecuted and collected a oihet 101 other cases of misdemeano 6 \\hetie\ei an&gt; aiseiKil. iii iii ■hi. or other qnai militia, camp mound or rifle raime. i^ owned or leased by the s under the char;:e of an armor] commission. \\ hall be under the i an armor) commission. Whf -nch property of the Nationi ;iny such propert) of tlie National (luard. i iininilsslnn in chai aerml, (oinmission in chaise theivol shall consist of the adjutant general, thi • immandinf; a repin lor colonel commanding a regiment .in ■',' There shall 1. • paid to each (-.mipany. troop, hat the sum of two hundred and fifty dollars l$2&amp;0l per annul in of two hnnd ami litty do! tud one hundred ($1(hii |&gt;er annum to ea:h hand and regimental headquarters. Kach n knd band of the Nebraska Nad id ji- ihorizecl to Im 'or the purpose of const owning, and opera' mor&gt;% an 'l may make by-laws foi rnment. not in conflict with this act ;uid general order ilations; which shall lie binding upon its members, and all IM'iialties j tn |x &gt;- ill be collected as herein: ided p«&gt; the rent for armi and one hundred do $111111 |kt annnni to ea:l) hand and - .1 to incorporate for the puru lent, not in conflict with this act and general order leculationa; which shall lie liindiiiK upon its members, and all fin&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p117">\I).H T\N I I SEKAL'S KEI'OHI 115 imauding officer of each company shall ma eporU ti&gt; r In- adjutant general and the regimental com »tlon of each quarter beginning iisi da\ of March in 'tins; forth the the number and kind of unce thereat; and the quantity and which he is responsible be made by commanding officers of regiments and all ■ n'citi will, at the discretion of the mmand and liable to trial by n lowhi. iministiat vi( |5) hree dollars (|3); tpiartermastei B dollar I $1 I. —the merit of sucV art ifiot ined by [Y and eo of quarterly - Bach company of ilie N ~&gt; twice in each calei ebrash idar month for instructions in • i practice; In- n duriiiK at least two hours. The e number and method of drills will &lt;lesij than twenty-five centa inn ■omniaiu ird shall encamp for tnstruc itialion. regiment, or brigade ma lered by the Ccmmander-in- Ciiiaid will ,1 from rtific i disability or dangi lember. nimediate famllj i •ompany when in a tii j&gt; shall have roll call on in the remaining andiiiK officer of th ave. shal the pay rolls a forfeiture &lt;&gt;! neb and every abseni nnniaiiding officer of any encampment or parade er his command to perform any camp or field nipany. with all the chang uu-hments and accountable endev the quarterly uniisgioned officers and non rvice as »uch. ma&gt; and of public prop Commanding officer of a coin owing amounts i&gt;&lt; miial and Bpecial lnap&lt; nil itarticipating nauding officers of regiment! and compani- my additional drills as they may teen ae ka National Gu i^ku Nation* up in orders deemed a:. for an lall I*- entered on </seg>
            <seg id="p118">ADJUTANT OEXERALH KEPOK1 116 he may require, and may pat under arrest during such encani nient or parade an. nimand who ma\ d a sn lierior officer or be guilty ot disorderly or unmilitaiy conduct other iierson who may &gt;i|&gt;on the encampment mounds or ]&gt;a she orderly discharge of duty by members of his con mami. and he shall prohibit I i all spirituous and malt liqun vithin (inr iniH- of such encampment or parade. lamination of to their fitness ■ m 4.Y The examination of -s for con ( iall lie made hy a hoard (if .all In- made by a ofltam ruled aim cribed in offici the Commander in i th. Unit in-chief S( Army regnlatio: Army regulations and when Wished :iiid when an offU shall ha\&gt; ntinuousl) as an ofllaer or ai shall ha\&gt; ntinuousl; (Boer or an enlisted man and officer, li. poa such retired li- man and officer, he may lie placed ii|m&gt;ii such retired list on his ow application, and an enlisted man shall also be entitled to retir application, and an enlisted man shall ■ titled to retirement o his having served twelvi mtiniiously Provided, That than one &gt;miss his having served twelve Provided. That when ni i t han one nut her. That servic mi I her. That &gt; the I'nit. i my shal ut. bi double time, and need not be continuous Whenever an officer of tin National Guai isqualified from an proper i nd need in Whenever an ofl -«a National Guard is d&lt; :isqualified from an i proper perfonnani the duties of his office, the shall have power to c ing iKiard and order such oft ■ animation the duties of his office, the Governor shall have |K&gt;w the reiKJtt of the retiririK board ordered to examine an offic ■ . and be appn be officer so exanii iproved by the Governor, the oftV .imined sha immediate on. Retiring ball 1 iinmediatei n Retirin tnted and conduct!, the Comi The president and recorder of a retiring board shall h* tuted and conduct) ■• the Command retiring board shall ha&gt; to adtninistei oaths and aftiimations isitiesa. ;on 47 Tile militai wl to administer oaths and affirmations ii 47 The military : I Nebraska A' i'ctual (ruction or in lime of w;i lion or in lim w niMirr.-ction. imasion. .- ,|e apprehension thereof, sha lows: The offieeis and enlisted men while si ction. Invasion, or follows: The offli' ilisted men whi ••hall ik' entitl.-d to ih' and transpoi I allowm men ol correspondii allowance as offl. i I nit. itled to by law enlisted men one dollar i$li per diem additional pay ma' on of the Command* Offii • I men oi ial duty away f enlisted men one dollar i$li pei diem additional pay nay be allowed • ii ot tin' Conimandi Offlceis 01 enlis-ieii men ordered on special duty away from tin v. commands shall receive such pa* foi commands shall ir-li pay : I'otnmandt in-chief may determine in-chief may determine own A bort&gt;&lt; •■ under proper it </seg>
            <seg id="p119">ADJUTANT OEXERALS KEI'oKT 117 thereof as may be determined the military board, with the approval of the Commander-in-chief. in V.&lt;. All commissioned onV- ntitled to an honorable In writit, by their company, regimental and brigade ntnandera, and the adju&lt; il, al the expiration of their ternu ifiic ty for which he is res|M&gt;n All enlisted men who b 1 faithfully three yeai- ivelv are entit iible discha eeified for com ■ction i Hi] commissioned commissioned officers will be for i to the ii their ii for the action &lt;&gt;f the Commander-in-&lt; heir intermediate command BC offi( lei -in-chief, who may accept id grai ant an honorable 'I :. Thii &gt;he officer shall not lorahly discharged unti counted for ali ty he mi i the ssion of an] ction 51. Enlisted nivn may be disrha ne Commander-in-chief, for lowin i in application, showing a he following On application, showing good reasons therefor: licence, In permanent removal iron on certificate of a medical officer, by from coin;' •■; for f a court I or company court of discipline: and w and without honor, on the nendatioo of all the commissioned oBi ifficers of the company. Kn men may be disch any time ny time, by order of the United or State Courts having Jnrlsdictlonron a writ n I writ of habeas corpus Ction "i- There shall he a military iHiard. ral, the brigadier | ■ f the ad- such officer is ap|K&gt;inted ninii-isioned i. the two senior colonels eomm IW( commanding regiments, and ! l be the duty duty of the military board it all claims and acoou Kainst the mi other* led by law. and to act a ■uy body to \v mniander in chief when called u|&gt;on by him &gt;nch. The y board shall :he call of th&gt; Hijutant genera] for the ■tion of such Inisiin ,L, r ht I board shall const it uti a quorum for the tr it A majority It he transaction of busines; unpensation, the n the military board (except the adjn- iiliensation, the members ol the militai i;enerall will be paid two and ."&gt;ii-]iih dollais i$l'.."iiii for exp&lt; a nerall will be paid two and 50-106 dollars day. while in actual attendai the board, and five y. while in actual attendance i mile each way from their place of r mile each way from their place ol ihe place ting, by the direct and usually traveled lout imander i court !.artial far the trial of officers- and enlisted men of the militia and Na- &gt;ffenses committed in violation of this act, and against illations promulgated for the government of the Nebraska al Guard; and for al! offei itted by them when in service </seg>
            <seg id="p120">AI).HTANT OENERALS WKI'OKI 118 ■.id order of any coin by the civil authori- i inn .".4. Th.- brigade, regimental and battalion &lt; when their mniMam in c-iim i&gt; or united for i approval of tin Commander-in-chief older courts in ot enlisted men of their commands, for offenses in violation of tin regulations and camp order nay he appointed by tin- commanding ofTn ■ ndinate on animation when in ca 1 l&gt;e vested with the I "nil &lt; \riiiy led for duty, which sha I summary court of the may nder his authci it &gt;w A lewed by the come ma&gt; tutor his aathority. ProWdli ■hall not exceed a fine in I the d for ihis tour of duty, nor be c;mf flictpn ! for this tour of duty, nor be c;mfi limit of encampment. The pro .JiidK' aeral for the examination and re eluded in his annual report Commani ompa approval of the Commander-in-chief, order Company ( lorflie trial of enlisted men of the company lor viola ind authorized di ( xc limit of encampment The ]&gt;&gt;■ shall l&gt;e \v; Jnds&lt; neral for the examination and n eluded in his annual report Cotnmai com pa w approval of the Commander in &lt; hi Company ( ial of enlisted men of the company for viola .uid authorized by-la ioi irts oi Disci pi I tin! Compan) &gt; instituted and conduct* icrlbed by the I'rovided. That the proceeding) lie constituted and condin lied h\ the Commander-in-Chh n &lt; That th. shall i war. am shall conform to the legulatiot martial in the Ann) Of the United St;. martial in the Army of the '"nited S Provide further. That in time of ]ieace no member of the further. That in tlm&lt; • no member ot the Nebraska Nationa ;i ill lie placed on trial before a &lt;;■ XI uiKiii duly prepared charges and specifications, whit ujKiii dul) which hav &lt;!ficial scrutiny of the Commander in-chief, and tri; &lt;!ficial scrutiny of the Commander-in-chief by endorsement ill.-; 7 A .Indue Advocate shall be appointe, by endorsement ill- A Indse Advocate shall be appointed militj ( ourt s|&gt;ecified in this Act. who shall eacl ( ourt s|&gt;ecified in this Act. who shall ), of tl A Nebraska, and shall render such oil of th- raska. and shall rei court, and to the m ;aid down in r« a the niili: he Tinted Btati inandins officei shall detail a compete • hi ■"&gt;&gt;&gt; The president ot a court martial mi court, and to the ai may laid down ie ihe miliU nf the I'nited States Armj : Provided, hov I manding officer shall detail a competent officer to def ' of a court martial n mill punish enfoi and punish i ovided in civil actkM '&lt; The president and enfoi kV Ml provided in civil actions or of a company court of discipline, shall have auth all oaths and affirmations which ii but t Section tin. The proceedings, finding </seg>
            <seg id="p121">119 ■ial. who shall is opinion do sentence of military court lew son. Provided, Th oval of the ('ominuii Section 61. When fin* : or company i e not paid within ten da nmiediate commanding said fines, with the names f a justice of tht will and render jud- nii |&gt;roof nch deliii ,id of the her with • .f the it ion thereon, directed to .ible of the w he collection of I Mil tiny pi' \ Pa ii duplicate by brigadf. - and oaths t \\ I to the Auditor f Pub The Audit .man in iy of ofti md enlisted men. armor) ii taiion. care of clothing, a immarjr compai &gt;\u the | &gt;a y of auy if approved bj rouchen and pay rolls to i the appn &gt;|ioit and main if the rial Guard. 66 T imt of lipments, mid tentai:' Kre, may prorMi iproprtetion out ol :;il KihhIs ffieicnt sum to i! </seg>
            <seg id="p122">120 All comi the Nebraska National G are hereby authorized and empowered to administer oathi and affinii.i to written affitl for the due administration of niilit The officers and enlisted niei Guard \empt from working on mads and highways, and Iron . nieiit &lt;*f any | M ill tax levied for that purpose, and shall bi from silting on any grand Jury or petit jury withi live n 1 No member at the Nebraska National Guard sha ( exemp eved from militar) dut) by membership of servic* on pan; n "" l[ • National Guard n wounded or otherwit I. or is killed or di w while doing military duty according to law. in .11 di disturbance of ihe ]«eaee lit-, his widow or Dm die slate such reasonable i&gt; proper. ion 71. No master, or assembly, tor Inatr ) proper Section 71. No muster, or assembly, for instruction A parade shall Iw held or called in any county, or on an; ■leral or ip&gt;cUI eledion shall l&gt;e tield therein, parade shall Iw held or called in any county, or on any day during whic a general or special election shall l&gt;e tield therein, except in .-. riot, invasion, insurrection, or imminent danger then riot, invasion, insurrection, or imminen •&gt;&gt;' U i the Commander-in-chief; and if any liv the order of the Commander-in-chief ; and such muster, as ,\. or pal such muster, assembly, review, or parait. of Ik- fined in any amount not less than twenty fi l&gt;e fined in any amount not less than tw i more than one hundred I $100) doll l«i ~rl It shall not be lawful for any body OM one hundred I $100) dollars 1 1 shall not be lawful for as oilier thdii the regularly organized Nebraska National oilier thaij the regularly organised Nebraska Natl and the troops of the United Itafa .ciate then nd the troops of the Unit a military company or organisation, or to drill or parad ;i military company or organization, or to drill or 1 ad&lt;- with arms withi the limits of tl &gt;ithom th. the limits of this state, without the ! whicr may at any time be revoked I'rovided. That stnde idei institutions may. with the consent of the Governor, dri in public, and take part in any encampment, tit institutions may. with the consent of the Governor, drill and parade wi aims in public, and take part in any encampment, under the comman of their military instructor, and while so —mm prill ?id regulations for the government of tl ot their military instructor, and while so encamped shall be govern. nd regulations for the government of the National G mid shall Ue subject to the orders of the commanding offi the orders of the conimandi encampment Provided further. That nothing herei .nstrued so as to prevent benevolent or social ( encampment Provided further. That nothing herein contain ' benevolent or iis lroni wearing swords "11 ',:',. Whosoever offends against the p .11 or l&gt;elongs to or parades with any such una ing sword against th« section or l&gt;elongs to or parades with any such imauthoriz o men with arms shall Ix- punished l,v ■ fine noi men with arms shall Im- punished |,v ■ fin,, not , hundred dollars ijlnin. or by imprisonment h iIV j a ■ ling thirty days </seg>
            <seg id="p123">121 h i i » ( \ i i w i " i lan for the commission of any crime punishable under the laws of the an- while on any duly authorized by this Act, and may proceed against ich offender liy information or complaint before any court of law having isdiction of such offense, and may call to his aid as many men as may sary to make the an tion. 7. r &gt;. Chapter 56 of the Compiled Statute, and Chaptet obbey'i Annotated Statutes, and all ith this Act are hereby re|&gt;ealed, exc ompiled Statutes of 1M1, ami &gt;imntated Statutes of 190::, relating U cniain in full force and eft. acts or parts of acts inconsistenl »Bt Seel ion till of Chapter M of the &gt;n 7M5 of Chapter 33 of C'obliey's Doane College Cadets, which shall Section Tti. Whereas an MMrgi w and be in force and effect on an ■ncy exists, this bill shall lx»eoiiie a d after its pasasge and approval. Approved April ler of the Govern I. H. CII.VER. Adjutant General HRADQIWRTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL C.l'ARD. | Ad jut an General's Office \ Lincoln. April .7 neral Orders / Ho \ n of 1905. will be conducted in accord ilit-il in Firing Regulations for MOO will commence May 1st and close October ::ist All officers anil enlisted men will be required to practice with the in with which their respective organizations are equipi&gt;ed, except the cillery, which will use the caibine. Companies will be allowed ammunition at the rate of 50 rounds per lan. toml commissioned and c-nlisted strength. Field and Staff officer:; ill be allowed 50 rounds each. LThe oldest ammunition u indicated by the dale marked on each box t be need tirst. Any Officer or enlisted man qualifying as a marksman, between Ma\ liine '!oth, will be allowed to participate in the competition which ill determine the personnel of a State Team, consisting of 12 men and altern tlf proficient, this team will attend the National competition at Sea N. .1.. subject to the provisions of General Order No. 41 War Depart- in The Inspector of Small Arms Practice will visit each organization ami e such Instruction as limited time will |&gt;ermit; he will, under direction t Target practice, ilming the with Speoiiil Cow 11 An. </seg>
            <seg id="p124">122 AD.UTANT GENERAL S KKl'OKT ol the Adjutant General, have immediate charge of matters i&gt;ertaining t( M work, and ,- ninmnicate direct with all officei. - • ling this Monthly reports of target practice will 1h&gt; forwarded within Ire aaj month for which same is ma Bj order of the Governor I. H. Cri-Vi Ad jut :int Genera] HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA .NATIONAL GUARD Adjutant General's Office Lincoln. May 1. 1* General Orders I \ In coni|iliance with 6 and 7 of the Military code, the following details and apiiointmeni.-- are made I. Lt. Col. W. R. Mclaughlin, ot the 1st inf. tUgt., X. X. G.. is detailed tor of Small Arms Practice, and will re|K&gt;rt to the Adjutant Gen era! for duty on May 1st. II. Major E. H Phelps. of the 2nd Inf. Regt. N. X. &lt;;., is hereb.&lt; appointed Assistant Adjutant General, and will re|tort to the Adjiltan .il for duty on May 1st. Ill Private S. I) Davis, of Co K. 1st Inf. Re,gt . is hereby honorably Uaekarcad trora the servi. re promotion. Private S. I) l):ivis. ot Co K. 1st Inf. Rest.. X X C. . is hereby ap|H)inted Assistant Quartermaster, with the rank of Captain. ,&gt;nd will re|&lt;ort to the Adjutant General for duty in the Quartermaster departmen: on M IV. A v:. irrint; in the rank of major. 2nd Inf. Regt.. vice K H Phelps. apiKjinted Assistant Adjutant 0— eral, an election will be held on May lath, litdo. to nil such vacancy. The officers of the 2nd Inf. S X «', . will express their choice lor this i&gt;osition. by ballot, whicii ,.t the Adjutant Ceneral's office on or before I:M p. m on the date named. V. The Board of Election will consist of Brig. (Jen. J. H. Culver, Adjutant General, ('apt August Wagner, and Cant J. C. Penrod of the 1st Inf. Regt.. which boaj-d will convene at the Adjutant General's office at 3:M p m on May ir&gt;th. UM, to canvass and record the votes of the in ordered in the preceding paragraph. enjoined is necessary for the public service By order of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p125">ADJUTANT HENERALS HKI&gt;OKT 123 HEADQIARTERS NI BRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, / leneral'a Office i Adjutant ( s Lincoln. May g, 19OE oeral Orders / No I. In compliance with Section !• Of tile Military Code, approved ipital Corps is changed to that of a subdivision of the Hospital Corps. id the commanding officer of said miniand at a convenient date within of expressing its choice for Major. he name of the Hoi Ambulance Company, to be known as in take effeer on May 10th, IM6, a pany is directed to assemble his o next thirty days, for the purpose Id I vacancy occur among the other officer- in of sucli ion. the company will pro I In compliance with Section _'J. elect officers to fill such vacanc&gt; &gt;f the Military Code. Chief Musician Hand, and Chief Musician (!■ are ap|«&gt;inted Second Lieutenant-. Harry Pritchard. of the 1st Regiment I the 2nd Regiment Hand like rank from May 1st. ISO der of the Govern) .). H. Cl'LVliR. Adjutant General HEADQIWRTERS NERRASKA NATIONAL GUARD.) neral'e Office Adjutant ( \ Lincoln. May 27. lUiif) ieneral Oi.lers / 1 I. The Nebraska National Guard will be held on uue 12th, Kith. 14th Officers' School and Examination and 15th. in Representative Hall. Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska, convening at T:!o P M. Monday. June 12th. All officers of the Nebraska National Guard will be required to attend, unless excused by the Adjutant General on surgeon's certificate (.1 serious illness of himself or members of his family, or Important business engagement that will justify such excuse. II. Officers attending the school and examination will be furnished rans|;ortation from their home station to Lincoln, and return and will eive pay at the rate of $:!.im&gt; pet day for the time actually in attend which is designed to cover the necessary expenses III. A competent officer from the regular army will l&gt;e detailed to act as instructor, and lecture* on Important subjects under consideration will be delivered at the evening sessions, by officers chosen for that IV. The examination of candidates for commission will take place in the last day of the session and will be conducted in compliance with Section 31, new Military Code, and in accordance with General Order </seg>
            <seg id="p126">124 h ra it l I t No ]n, series 1MIU. with such modifications as may Ik- prescribed by Adjutant General. V The Board of Examination will cou.sist of Colonel Joseph A. Sto Major E. H Phelps. Captain George H. Holdeman. Major C \V. Wai ;md Captain Otis M Newman, who will report at the Adjutant Genei office \ M . Wednesday. June 14th. The mi inlwrs of this 1« 1 such compensation :iitary Hoard. for their set vices as may Ik- fixf VI The dress uniform with impaimi hat will !&gt;■■ worn, wit! &lt;■ By order of the Goi I. H. C I.VEK. Adjutant Gen HEADQt ARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD Adjutant General Lincoln. May 29, 190! "' \ The following officers of the Nebraska National Guard will t for examination at the Adjutant Generals Office. June 14, IHii FIRST REGIMENT jner. ,in Charles A. Calkin Captain Hatcher M Sisson. Captain Charles K Pit* Captain Emory 1! DeWotf, First Lieut Ernest H. Stoner. First Lieut, l^iuis W. Ohmstedf Second Lieut. James McMillan, • 1 Lieut. Charles L. Hurme I Lieut. Harry H Harlan. Second Lieut. Cloyd W. Hish. 1 Lieut. Harry Pritchard. First Lieut. Ell&gt;ert G. Hutterfield First Lieut Lilhurn F. Oxford. Second Lieut Jacob Ferguson. Second Lieut Howard \V Antles. Second Lieut Jacob H. ■*&lt; S«-cond Lieut William A. Myers. Lieut Charles C. Myers. SECOND REGIMENT Major Fred J. Mack. ,:u H Elton Clapp. -amuel F. Shannon, mi John H. Bond. Captain Clifford E. Weaver, First Lieut. Jack Baa First Lieut John C. Ehernlx'tnet . First Lieut Julius Wife Captain John E. Tuttl Captain Charles H. Johnson. Captain August \V. Kroeger. Captain Wilbur S. Price. Captain Martin C. Shallen First Lieut. Willard S. Paul. First Lieut. Albert H. Barker. Fit. -I Lieut E H Mi.llownfy, Benjamin J. Richard a is K I Jill </seg>
            <seg id="p127">AD.UTANT GENERAL S REPORT 125 I First Lieut. Charles H. Keed. Second Lieut. Frank H. Gaylord, Second Lieut. Clyde K. McCormick Second Lieut. Gilbert H. McGill, Second Lieut. George W. Gregg, Second l.ient. Walter S. Ptae, Second Lieut. Mile Qilkei Second Lieut. Hayard T. Eller, Second Lieut. Edgar Gaskill, RCSHV1I ,E RIFLES First Lieut. Ernest J. Aubert cond Lieut. l^ee Fritz AMBULAN( K COMPANY Major John M. Hirkner ( .iptuin E. Arthur Can. First Lieut. John F. Spealnian TROUI' A &gt;nd Lieut. Charles \V. F\ink SIGNAL CORPS Second Lieut. I»uis H. Gage Uniform, dress with campaign li ;ii. without side arms By order of the Governor HEA1HJIAKTKRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD. I Adjutant General's Office I Lincoln, June '1. 1905 General Orders { No. 11. \ It becomes the sad duty of the Commauder-in-Chief to aimoiii death of ex-Governor Robert W. Furnas. which occurred at the Lindell Hotel in Lincoln, Nebraska, on June 1st, 1905. The funeral will i.lace on June 4th. Flags on all public buildings will be lowered to half staff be sunrise and sunset on that day and all armories of the Nebraska National Guard will l&gt;e dra|&gt;ed in mourning for the next thirty it Governor Robert W. Furnas was born M I. on a farm in Miami County. Ohio. At the age of seventeen, he went to C'ovin- Kentucky, and there served an apprenticeship in a printing office for hmr years, where he secured the principal part of his education. At the age of twenty-three, he became publisher and editor Tiny i Ohio I Times, which he disposed of rive years hi le served as agent and conductor on a railroad, and then ;i ance agent, moving to Brownville lished the "Nebraska Advei ■: ville. Nebraska. Nebraska, in 1H56. where he which is still published at Brown He served as clerk, and four years a member of the Territorial Council J. H. CIILVEK, Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p128">126 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KKPOK1 i I 1 Ha wa* i'iiiiiiiii.-miiiiimI by President l.mci&gt;lii as colonel in the D S Army, and organized the Indian Brigade of three regiments, which h* commanded during its service in Kan- nrl, Arkansas and I: Territory Resigning this commission, he returned and recruited 1 1 1 - Nebraska Cavalry, and as its colonel, served in General M l it ion Sioux Indians. After the war. he served as agent for the Omaha and Win Indiana for nearly four years In the fall of 1x72. he was elected Governor of Nebraska, in Was elected a member of the State Hoard of Re| -ident of the State Hoard of Agriculture, and afterwards as seer* tary of the same, which position he held at the time of hi - nt of the State Horticultural Society. Me was Vice President of the National Pomological \ I the I. (). O K. ; Past Grand Master, High Priesl, Past Grand Commandei of the Masonic bodies ol \. His .out and useful career will endear his memory to Ihose whr have occasion to read Nebraska's history. By order of the Governor H CULVER Adjinant Gen HKAHQl ARTKRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL lilARM Adjutant General '■ Offic Lincoln, July ■ nlers J \ I. Tl ka National Guard will ubled at Keami ramp of instruction, from August Sth to l*ith inclusive .imps will \h located separately, lindei ihe conimai .eh regiment f laoCtlTCij |iui|Kise of inde[&gt;eiident drill, discipline, and administration. Detached commands will lie assigned on arrival at caini Rl Requisition for trans|K&gt;r(ation will l&gt;e made upon the I ral as fol a. The Colonels of the First and Second i. | ition for trans|M)rtation for the commissioned and noii-rommissi iiimand id officers will make requisition direct to this otti iiinniaii(1iiiK officers of th» various coinpaniis •rill isition for trans|H&gt;rtation of the officers and men of their respi which will lie entered the actual number of office! - men iiansported. III. The following insti . g of equi| </seg>
            <seg id="p129">ADJUTANT UENEKALS KEJ'OKT 127 ( !. served: Mlanket rolls, made with the shelter tent half, from the left shoulder: haversacks from the right shoulder to the left side and in ■ear of the hip. strap under web belt; canteen from left shoulder to right side, rear strap under web belt. Poncho folded white side out to &lt;&gt;f 6x24 inches; then hung over the web belt under haversack; tin nip in fastener at bottom of haversack tlV. The service or Khaki uniform with blue shirt will l&gt;e worn, blue uniform will l&gt;e carefully stored at the home station. Kacli pany will report at camp equipped for field ser\: IV Government and state inspections by designated officers will be ide during the encampment, and should disclose that each enlisted m is provided with campaign hat. coat, trousers, blue shirt, and can - s leggings, shelter half, ]K&gt;le and pins, woolen blanket. Poncho, canteen. k. meat can. knife, fork, sixxm and tin cup Company equipi&gt;ed th regulation tents, field range and proscribed cooking utensils. fiinecessaiy canvas and baggage will subject the company com mander to adverse criticism Camp equipage will be limited t, Army allowance. I VI. Company officers will be held to strict accountability for the r(1 all( ' overnment pro|&gt;erty. and also for the conduct of men and from encampment; and all damage to cars or other property rough carelessness or wanton destruction will be deducted from their y. Firing from car windows, or at any time without proper authority. II subject the soldiei discipline Any soldier absenting hini- If from camp will forfeit his pay and become liable to court martial VII No tire arms excepting those issued to the company by the will be permitted to be carried. Only blank ammunition will be -in to camp, and companies will be carefully ins|&gt;ected by a oned officer before entraining and detraining, to see that no fixed ammunition or revolvers are in possession of member! of the commands. Company commanders will make requisition for two days' rations ich will include traveling day. on arrival at camp. No member of the Nebraska National Guard will l. in attendance at camp, except on surgeons certificate of disability serious illness in their immediate faniilv. By in . Qovernoi I H Cl I.VKK Adjutant G&lt; HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD. | Adjutant General's office \ Lincoln. .Inly 13, I9V6 No. 13. \ I. The Hoard of Oti </seg>
            <seg id="p130">128 AD.HTAXT QEXERAL'8 KKPOKT ining officers as to their qualifications for coin missions in the Nebraska National Guard, having reported that the follow - ing officers passed a satisfactory examination, and recommended that Bed, the rei&gt;ort and recommendation of said Boa - i). and the said ofl, .inmiBsioned. I FIRST RKGI.MEXT Davi Major Captain. Regimental limiiiii Captain. Chaplain larj Fleti • Charles K. Fraser Kniory H DaWaU Elbert G. Butterfield l.illnirii F. Oxford Captain Captain First Lieutenant First Lieutenant Second Lieutenant Second Lieutenant Second Lieutenant Second Lieutenant Ferguson Howard H. Antles Harry U. Harlan iND ! EGIMENT. H. Kit &lt;m Ckmpp John E. Tuttle Captain. Regimental Adju Ca|)tain. Chaplain Charles H. .lot August \V. Km Wilbui B. I Captain Cai&gt;taiu Captain Captain Captain Samuel F Shannon Martin C ShalUnbeiRf Ueason Lieutenant First Lieut. First Lieut' First Lieutenant First Lieutenant Fii-st Lieutenant First Lieutenant First Lieutenant Second LJeu Second Lieutenant lull ms Wiin K I^amlH it Charles H RM Willard S. Paul Albert H Harkei Kdmnnd H. Miillowney uin .1 Richards mick it II McC.ill AMBULANCE COMPANY lohn F SlK-alman Major First Lieutenant SIGNAL COUPS Looki Hi; Second Lieutenant II Tie -aiu Hoard of K\:urination. having r&lt; i .nut James McMillan. First H lailed to [&gt;ass a satisf actoi examination, and recorameuded that he be discharged, the report and </seg>
            <seg id="p131">129 I ond Ueutenanl McMillan h ™ '7;-&gt;. ,„, fn)m the date of , his ' 1 o i ; d( ; N r lcM "' a " hlvin^/"!'?!"* Ili "" l " i ° m ° er - '"" haVi ' 1R n9Ort * i f "' r -"mination nawiiK failed to render ir,uwi ,, &gt;,,i ....&lt;*.. I. Tr I hawn K fa.led U) render .ood and .oUclen! ,, r his absen( ,, ailed to render Ud sufficient excuse for his a! "' 7""»-"'l«' &gt;' -he Board .,f KxaminaMon. he is here , nendati 7""7'. th^ ""^ f«.n. the date of this o^ei- Second L.Hutenan, Frank H. (Ja.Monl. Second Re Killl enr IV. Ihe fol],,wi, ls officers, offered U, a,,,.ear hefon- said l',,,ani '"■V'"""^ 1 -I— to... the time d^.ted u^ , '"*"■ s ""&gt;"'' imina.ion to be ord, , ,J Ing commlasioned, viz.: ni the in h rank IV. Tr wins; officer appear before said Board : fro,,, , ak ,n, the examination a, the time designated. B pon low xamina Major Fred J. Mack Captain C. A. Calkins Firs, Regiment Captain j. ft Bond „„, Kegiment Is. Lieut, j. C. Ehernberser Second Reglmeni I-ieut. J. C. Bhemb. ilm , m ■'nd Uent W S Pine , Ed Kegin.en, - nd U « nt Wm * " First Ke^i.nen. - n&lt;i '''• n.i Regimenl '"'"' (: "" W '■ eond Regiment 2nd Llent C. I.. BnrweMmr Firs. K, B i,,,, -'•"" ( ' !- B urm&lt; First Regiment 2nd Ueut M. Gilken ,„„ Re K i ni en. U. (Jilk &gt;, in Resinient .'nd Lteut C. K W. „,„ Kesimen, Uei:K c R w &gt; ment Sad Ueut C. \v. BtaH fj, SI Resi,,,. C. \V. Hi First R si ment !nd Llent. H. Pritchard Firs. R, ieu H. Pritchanl First R iment V - H " al(l llavi "- * 'ha. .he following oa eer, fai ied ,„ •n. in til.- examination. an«l lded t , K1 , V. The Board hartai d that the following meen failed nt in the exaniin on. and recommended that • and reconnnendation are approved ail ,l ;aid officers ordered to report for examination at utefa tin ant General may din \djutant ( •ap.ain E. Arthur ( Aml.uiance Conpi CapUin E. Arthur Carr A.nl.Miance Company ' a i" ai " c v - W« s,,,,nd Regimen! Kiinent st '-'"'" K H Firs , R(1KII11 , iment st Lieu.. L. W. Ohmi First 1; W. Ohmsi, First Regiment »( Ueut. Krnest Aul.ert Kushville Ki- Lieui. Ernes) Anbert Kushville RiHe nd Lient. B. T. E „„, ReKini , Mlt 1 Regiment 1(1 Uem ' «JI ,,„, Regimeni ( ad Ueut. C. CM Fi , id Ueut H. C. Wilson First Kesim, Id Lieut. Lee Fritz Rushville Ri it. Lee Fritz Rnshville Rifle Id Lieut C W. Funk ,,, \ I. office, will receive his individual rating fc, mai | Thl . C. W. F troop A VI. Bach officer w id ill rating In mail. Th&lt; National Guard off ■tkwal Guard officers as shown l,v ,|,,. , Hie Commander Iih own by tl underin-chief order of or. ■I. U CULVBR, Adjutani I </seg>
            <seg id="p132">130 ADJUTANT UEXEKAL'S KEPOI HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONA1 Adjutant No. 14. The m&lt; National Guard having qua a .Niiiiiin.il ( marksmen, ami made the ill he aihnittei; (inning of Lieutenant Colonel \V. K IfcLMghlin. Thi ii Khaki uniform, t, will Im- worn as I Small Am and : .Ismail will i- *'i"t. •*■ -man will rew 1 canteen, have: ick, in ki half wiih ci of undei half, ban will toilet am. The Mtoua iiM-ii making I hi .id will be designated a: toilet Nebraska National C.uaid ti ihe national a N .1 . the latter pan of the nioni ihe natini \ ,| ,|,,. latter pm of the month of AuKii.st Tke usual camp disriplini- ami Malta August. The usual lisriplin w &lt;-llfe&gt;! The ■ I] |,,. ;| || (1V d men am luiin; inforced v «nd l i men one dollar it l" a&lt; "t ,luti,s required under this By order of I enjoined m By order of the I I. U. (TI.VKIt. hAdjutai HEADQIARTBR8 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUAR Unooln, Augu No. 15. No. 15. 1 The N ' in ramp I. Th» si i union, in coniplianc.' wit I .,„,, wj 'ion. in compliance will atl( ] wj n ! by the : ! 1)&gt;- tke : ■ FIRST HKCI.MKNT. KIKST 1 KGIME.VT Rout« v H. A: M . Aac v ; ,„, ., ,,, i C.i I!. .Stanton. C A; N. W anil B. A: If. Anj; I H A.- M A a ('.) I). Weeping Water, \1 P., N \\ I Co. B. Will A I'.n Co P. Madison. V. F </seg>
            <seg id="p133">131 II. Nelson, B. *• M \ _ ( ,, ni 1- * v N W. an.] B. i M . . . Auk 0 p.m K. Colombaa, U P v-- » i :lll &gt; ,, .„,. :: : nc&gt; ,,.,,, K. ( I &gt;i" p.m. 3:M pin U Omaha. I". P.. g „„, L, Omaha. IT. I VI B I „...,. M Broken Bo, .., „ „, OND KKtil.M K KK' ME. N'T Route I Arrive ''■ Sl1 IP 12 a.m. 3:25 p.m. 8, 11:41 a.m. ;!:25 p.m. A.Keurney, march from borne station to camp An. • a.m. PmiU. V P \ ._ , pm K. in borne siatiiiii to camp A Paul. I 1' Auk. I, I:M a.m. 12: U p.m '"• Nl • lm ■ p.m. '• I and t\ P : 44 a.m. 12:45 p.m. B, T»'kamah. M. A: () and \. \\ I p „, K. l.incoln. li. A.- .\l . 4n a ,,, :; (M t p.m. Q, Omaha. I P , ,, ,„ Oi ' p.m "■ *&lt; H • '"I a.m. 10:30 a.m II. A \- M a. in I. Omaha. V. P , p.m P Lug. S, 11 M l m ; M |).m K !■■ \ |! '■''■ I 17 a.m. 1:00 p.m. U A! M, A M M. Albion, IT. P Ins. S. 11: 10 ■ m S:M i&gt;.m. '•' • p.m. 1 A. Wyn 0 p.m al Co .ni. r 1' p. in. Dlance Company, Lincoln. I! *• M Aik 7. io:. r &gt;:; a.m 1:30 p.m ivllle Rifles, Rushvll W \uu. i • p.m II- T' 1 idlng o0ci ip A. \ N (',.. with a detachmenl n enlisted men. will man d report to Captain i a. in.. T 1 1 • si|, nid report in Captain m.. Tuesday II The Second Regiment Band will march overland froa w ilver ('reek on the morning of August stli, and the eutumanding ■ ek mi tli«- morning • it Auxusl 8th, and Hie commanding ■i is aiiihorizi'd a transportaUon for thai parp « V. The followii Ail] proceed to Kearney on the Aini: da iU'u. l. II Culver, Col. 0«o. K. Jenkins, Commissary lien. - l&gt; Darii 4th. \! Hull Quartei master, and the ti. M Bergt of the ,.i K K Culver. Quartermaster, and y. .\i .- ( v ( ant C la \miiiiII.' \: Hull. Qu mid the Q. M. SerfCt. of tin leKiment: Capt. E K Culver, Quartermaster, and Q. M. Bergi &lt; iecoad Regimei K II I'l, Adjutant Oaai i-i-nnd Regiment; Maim E II. Pin- Vdjutanl Gi \iiiius Col ( imusi ."iih. 'ol. C. l&gt;. I John W. M. l&gt; Miin-11 : I V Ilion Clapp. Adjulai I. E. Hurtx, Conimiss. i ttlH ('l)llllM of the St mi Regimenl ihU'inau. Adjutant: Capt. (). K d the Commissary Sergeant, of in I ph A Storcb; Captain Oeo. II H M I </seg>
            <seg id="p134">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPOK I 132 Col. C. I Bills, lnsi" I A Khrhaidt. Jud fcl, on Au- V. Company commanders will be supplied wttn orders for uanspoit. V Company i supplied with order* for iransi lion from hon. '"1 retWB, and will certify on th as in lli - obtained and the remainder included in one tie'&lt;et. VI. Tiim commutation of rations ;it i ■■ lion from home stations to Kearne) and return, and will certify on tr 11 der as to the exact nil itagle tick&lt; lonld l&gt;e obtained and the remainder included ir VI. Trooi commutation ol n tw« wen l«r capita In lieu ol travel rations, for thi onte. Vii Main will assume command of tl .ipita in ])■ Broutt VII lor off d out, ceporttei on i iti\ ■ ; ,i an&gt; in i the officer responsible hi any hip any n be train, and repo san ji. Company comma] Cnn will report alng. VIII. On Hirivil f, tin- troops will remain on th&gt; until ptoa tx Compan; 'ful ins|H- itherwi ii ( ,i, itTainlmi fixed ammnnition is carrie hat no fix and that .lintained throughout Lh( minimum. ully and at ling. or: IT. CTJLVEft, ( I. H. CULVER HCAOQUARTBR8 NKHKASKA NATIONAL GUARD,) HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, i iffici \ l.inc ■■ lcoln It 1 . I I,,,,,, led in camp ot instruction, in pursuance to General 0 ■ mbled in oaiti|&gt; ol Instruction, in pursuance to General Ord&lt; Nos. 1- and 15. e s. and proceed with such preparaCii -;iry for tl 'i the encampm II The staff mental, not personally named era! Orders Nil IB ■ imp at Kearney by the n Nob. 1- and ''i aw* imp at Kearney by the m ,(,„!. commanding ofl 111. Colonel I A al, will report nte on Ai. omandlng offic* imp of instruction Nebraska National Guard il instruction Nebraska National Guard at Kean • Ordei- IOIIN If MICKKY GorenK </seg>
            <seg id="p135">MUITAM GENERAL S KKPOKT 133 HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, ) Adjutant (. I np Amaha Cobb, near Kearney, August IB, II Kearney, Augu fi No. 17. I. The National Guard, aaaembk Cobb, Nebrask; he Nation Camp Amaaa Cobb, Nebraska will entrain on Aogn«l lt;th. in the folio win Companies A. C, E. G, and II of I 'onipanies C, F, and ] he 2nd Refit: Battery A and Ambulance Company; on U » a in. in be entrained ion mill switch, with th ■ I"'" 11 '"' ! f, which will entraii Com pan] and I) of the inpanies ( nd H of the 1st. one i ,,,1 y ,,f tne 2 nd, one ag~ oiniiany l. ,,f the 2nd, oi car, via Minden, transfe: } th *" K It cars, and on&lt; at a One coach will he allowed each company. II. Companies IS. D, 1. and the Hand oi coaci ■ a»&lt;i one , ( . n . with I Hand and B, which will 1,,., : Company B, of thf id. one coach and oach and a ar; entrain on the C. a.- N. W. special III. Company H. of the 2nd ,,- C ar, occupying &lt;-oach with detachment of Troop A The Troop, one stock car in hich they will load their b -I stock: entrain on the It. &amp; m ain on August Itith. in the following mpanies A. C, K. G, and II of h mipanies C, F, and I \ and Ambulance Company; on the I!. &amp; M )tton mill switch, with thf . wliioh will entrain K.-; ( mpany a owed ar; Com- II) of the : Companies C. C. and F of the 2nd, one ar. via Minden, transfer t) nd one Ol « w roach of the Hand and Com B, which will occupy o nipauy K, of the Kifit-s &gt;ach and a i. Ill III. Company H. of the 2nd K ( it^e in regular car, occupying ach with (!• A. The Troop, one stock car in which they will load theii . r rain on the B. &amp; M in. at Keain,&gt; . leaving IV. Companies K and F of the 1st l; ompuy M and Rand • • 2nd Bear't, oi O f k of t! { m o f the mipany M and Rand Hi. .'nd I It, and M of the nd "* ""■ By F of the 1st. in regular car (at earney) at 10:06 a in in Hand, one baggage v Conn I k. H. and D of the one coach each Company I and I of the will occupy '': Conip ;,[ k of the ted, one hasgage car; Com - and n of the Snd, one bf mpaay U of the 1st, one ar; eatrala on U. I' I m : ::&lt;i, learimg Kearney at 11:30 ni. VI. The Signal oorpa will break lam; 7ih, entrain "ii. tearing on V. V. So. 8, at ln:tn; Cona the 2nd Reg't, 1 p. m.. AuKiist 17th, and march to home station. VII. Brigadier General .1. H. Culver. Adjutant General; Col. Geo. E. nkius. Quarterns Major E. H. Phelus. Assistant Adiutant F of the 1st. in regular car (at Kearn earn&lt;x and, one baggag. V. Companies L and .\l oi panies C, I. K. H, and D of the one coach each Company I and I of the 2nd will occupy i K of the 2 the 2nd. one baggage car; Com- t) lie 2nd. oni car; Company M of the 1st, one nil ii VI Tli w ' 1 ■ ih, entrain "ii. tearing on V. P. No. 8, hi 10:40; Company A of the 2nd Reg't, m.. Auv Inline s VII E. H. Phelps. Asiistant Adjutant raI: ( ' a l' f - s ! mnt Quartermaster; Capt. A. M. Hull. ("apt. B. K. Culver, and the Quarterraa ants of the 1st and 2nd </seg>
            <seg id="p136">ADJUTANT GENERAL S KKI'OIM 134 Win. K. Keiso will remain on duty in cl&lt; will re 11 eactmpawt, returning to their heme sutioni m heir h«n &lt;iaff. and Regimental Staff and Field Officers not ■ !&gt;h. will i their home station: iff and Field Off to their ho All unused rail iportatkHM and order* for iransj&gt;ortat taut Gen&lt; • .1. H. CULVER Adjutar HBADQITARTBRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL QtT. ntanl Oeneral's Offlce. iRASKA NATIONAL (MARK HEADQUARTER \ ii.i II I ;l It I (•( Lincoln. 1 1 j No 1 tl Lieut. Col. Warm K McLinmhlin. Major Ernes) H. Ph Lieut. Col. Warren K McLaughlin, Major Ernest H. Pheh : from duty under General 0 d from (inty under Qeaen mber 31, II. i Warnn R McLanghlin. who has performed i of Small Anns Practice ilif paal is bj d from duty under General I nor. rt .11 Arms P from duty unit. nor. J. H. CULVKK Adjatai HEADQITARTKR8 NBBRASKA NATIONAL QC HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Adjut Lincoln. December 9, Lincoln. 1)« ,il Orders / No IS. ral Ord( i No IS. I. A hoard of appointed to meet ai the llead&lt;iuaiti Nebraska National Guard. Lincoln. Nebraska, at 11:00 o'clock .' \ M ., 1 &gt;. &lt;■, ml&gt;er 14, 1906, and at such other time and place! as may he d nat by the Adjutant General, for the p ir i tainins wl rtain ordn master Bti whifh the commanding oft :i ■ f of Ordnance and Quai </seg>
            <seg id="p137">\D.ll "I'ANT (JEXERAL'S REPORT 135 tain .1. J. ('■ .in S. I) l&gt;;i\U. Qu iot. iiiirtnient. I H. CULVER, Adjutant General. I. H. CULVER, Adjutant Genera] HEADQUARTBR8 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GIWRD, ) Adjutant General*! Ofti Lincoln, December LM, i ueral Orders ) No. I'". \ I. The annual itate hupeettoo of the Nehraska National Guard w O No Nebraska National Guard will ike place at the comi ins during the month of January, and the e place at the company ■Utiom during the month of January, and t k&gt;WiD| named nfl , Hi wi) | j 11S|)ect mi will inspect the npanii Col. I. \V. McDonnell. Corapan&gt; L. , n j j • Col. J. A. Storch, Ci W. McDonm ft, and TrtK&gt;ii A. ! F - '■ ''" Company Rest. Lt Col. \V. R. ifcLanshliB, Companlei C and H, 1st Keyi: Compai Holshaw and E - ompany 1) 111 K Col. W. R. MeLaugblin, Compa impaay !nd Rest, and H. Major .1. C llartiKan. Cimr ■'ouipanies \ B and 1 \ Major J. C Hartigan B , and H. k. Major (). Q. Osboine. CoBpax ., n( j ,] .Major O :id the lal Corps Major C. M Richards, Com pan &gt; I). 1st I; nnH ,y Ma and the Major Fi. ,,,,! u ;lll ,| impaay H Major F. .1. Mack. I K, 2nd Regt; Companlea W and K R G A. mhville Rit v iled at such time during the •ting officer. e troops will lie inspected in heavy marching order, blue uni- IV. Company commander* will see that the armor ■ ord n readiness for « same, to he handed irriv lH-t;i </seg>
            <seg id="p138">136 ADJUTANT GENERAL S KKI»OKT V. 1: to facilitU \.hich the ted. and re|&gt;ort all company commanders who permit rnment proi&gt;erty to be taken from the armory, when no Hired for state or government VI. Blank Inspection report* will be sent to the commanding offu npany for his information, and will be filled out and forward inspect!!!!: officer immediately after the Inspection is mad VII. In accordance with Section 41 of General Ordi in of twenty-five cents will be allowed each n mber present at Inspection in accordance with thi Pay rolls will be signed v verified by the in«i&gt;ector. and will be held by the Company command* oils will be used at the annual government inspection V1I1. TransjMirtation for the insiiectinj; officers will be furnish* the Adjutant General: pay and travel allowance for this fixed by the Military Hoard. By order of the Governor I. H. CULVER Adjutant Gene </seg>
            <seg id="p139">ADJUTANT GENERALS KFPOKT 136 1/2 He took part in the battles of th&lt; ant Hill. Lou l sail a ; Old Oaks, Ifiaui engagements participated in li Ked River cauipaign. those of Pleas - ippi ; Nashville, Tennessee, and other A. .1 Smith's command. At the close of the war he returned to Clayton Cowity, Iowa, and soon .itter went to California, where he remained four years. In May, IB; came to Nebraska, and lotateil in what is now known as Red Cloud. Web ster County, where he 1. i;,. engaged in farming and mercantile bus veil as Probate Judge, a member of the letfisla Hire, and register of the U. 8. land In I87H he wa&gt; nlectad Ooremor His honorable reoonl in the serv &gt;tiic and served from 1*7^ to 1878 inclusive ice of his country anil state.has passed hijis at the pioneer and tilled the full into history He endured the hard measure of duty wherever called. The Hags will he lowered to half staff on the day of the funeral, from unrise t&lt;&gt; sunset, on all public building*, and the com pan \ arr Nebraska National Guard will !r- draped iti BOUning for the next thirty By onler of tin- (tovenn I H Cl LVKR. Adjutant Genera). HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln. January 13, 1 ■ neral Or* No The death of Ex Governor Sihis &lt;iarl&gt;er occurred at ."&gt; M A M , on the twelfth day of January. IMS, at Red Cloud. Nebraska. The funeral will take place on the 1 ."it h inst. (tarter VM born September 21. 1*33. in l.o K an County. Ohio, where he received his preparatory education. At t! . fiil.en.he uii^- to Clayton County. Iowa, and engaged in farming. At the breaking out of the w.ir of the Rebellion, he enlisted in the 3rd iri, known as Lyons Regiment, and served for about one &gt;• He then returned to Iowa, recruited Company D, 27th Iowa Inf.. and became 1st Lieutenant, and was soon thereafter promoted toCaptain of h is company. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p140">ADJUTANT OENERAL'S KKKMtT 137 ( ABSTRACT OF SPECIAL ORDERS. 1906. nation of 1st Lteat. Fred II. Richards. Signal Cor]»s; election KtJ *' L ''" M H Guiles, c,,. c, 1st Inly ; election ordered Election of 2nd Lieut. Harry B. Hohhs. Co. F. 1st Infv. Discharge of enlisted men 1 Ban- mber 4 aid of Survey Delegates to Inter-State National Guard Association M Military Hoard Xumhi Reli iiin officers from duty as ImuMoh, and appointing Relieving Captain A. \V. Kroeger from command of Co. I. 2nd Infy Number 9. Discharge of enlisted men, Co. H, I and M, 1st Infy. Appointing non-commissioned officers Hospital Corps t Election of Captain Elbert G. Hutterfield, 1st Lieut. William A. Myers (1 2nd Lieut. William E. Osborn. Co. A. 1st Infy. Election in Co. H. 2nd Infy Discharge of enlisted men Co F K 1st Infy. and Co C and L. 2nd Infy Nuinbe Election of ("olonel John C. Hartigan. and Lieut. Colonel Oliver C borne. 2nd Infv Election of Colon*'] and LJeut. Colonel L'nd Infy K and U 1st Infv. Co. (i. 2nd Infy Election of Captain Jesse C. Penrod, Co. C, 1st Infy. Resignation of 1st Lieut. W. (J. Browne. Co L. 1st Infy. Election Number 10. Discharge of enlisted men, Ca Q, 1st lnfy., and Co. II ami M. -ml ranker 1 1. Election of 1st Lieut. Arthur L. Huddleston, Co. I, 1st Infy </seg>
            <seg id="p141">138 AD.H'TANT (iKNKK.M. S KEKJKT Disc! &lt;l men Co ( H. 1st and Oo. H. 2nd Infy Number 14 .Iiid^ Numl)er IS .ipiain Otis M Newman. Co. H. 2nd lnfy Election of 1st Lieut l-onis H Sinai Corps. and 2nd Lieut I lei V .les l&gt;t ] 1 1 f \ \ Number Ifi Election of Major Herbert .1 I ml nd Infy Election of Major of 2nd Infy Number 17 Commission of Captain E. Arthur Hospital Corps Commission of Captain Samuel I) Davis. Quartermaster Depat 1 men. Staff. 1st lnfy . and Hospital Co Number IS mm Hoard Number I* 1 Election in Co. I'.. 2nd Infy L Resignation ot Captain B. Arthur Cair. Hospital C( ered Election Num. ■• Discharse of commissioned and non-commissioned officers 2nd Infy Number 21 Apitointment of staff officers, 2nd Infy Number Elect ion of 1st Lieut. C. L. Runnester and 2nd. Lieut. R. S Edmunds Klection of Captain W. S. Paul. \V. B H. 2nd Infy. ■ ut \V S I'ine and 2nd Lieut Klection ol M. E. l.um 1 Infy Niiniber D. 1st; Cn. C and D, 2nd Infy and IMscharge of enlisted men ( Hattery A Number 24 -Il'l Lielll (I K II. Co L, 2nd Infy. Klectiou C^hailKes in dales, and inspection officers. State inspection NunilKT 13. Lieut. Percy C. ZI«'j;1«m Co H 1st lnfy. Kleetior ed. Resignation of 1st l.i.iu I! I Kicha f 2nd Infy Kleei urn ordeivd ;.. 1st lnfy </seg>
            <seg id="p142">139 \ N w i I 111 I It Meeting of .Military Board mil Resignation of 2nd Lieut. ("has. \V Discharge (if enlisted men. &lt;'&lt;i H Dilated men, Co. 1!. I and K. 1st Infy and Co. H and K I'isch (1 men Co IV F and K. 1st Int. ami Co I) ('. K M, ted Infy. mlit Details (if officers and men t&lt;i report to the adjutant general. V Detail from the Hospital Corps to report lor duty at the Capitol ilding. March 22a ml T-\. : I). .mi .f. Rex Henry, Signal Corps. Klertion ord Discharge of enlisted men. Signal Corps. Hospital Corps, and Co. I.. Discharge of enlisted men. Co. B, F and L, 1st Infy.. and Co. I and K. 1 Infy. Appointment of non-commissioned officers. Signal Corps niber .17. Funk. Troop A. Election on t &lt;; .ukI I. 2nd Infv. Election of 1st LJeot .\ I. Moore iiml .ml Umt I M. Crandell rmbar .17 i&lt;u! i: II Miillo\vnc\ a|i|iointe&lt;l I? Aj-ms Resignation of Captain .1 V. Cameron, Co. B, 2nd Infy. Election ocd- ,«I. Dtockarse of enlisted men, Co. I. 2nd Infy. iml&gt;ei Dtsefaarce of enlisted men. Co. IS. F. L and K. 1st Infy., and Co. F. d Infy. imUer :;4. Klection of Captain U H. Case. 1st Lieut. II A .less, and 2nd I.ieut C. Mallonee. Signal Corps k. situation of Captain C. K. H i l-\ 2nd Infy E iered Disrharae of enlisted men. Co. C. 2nd Infy., and TnK&gt;i&gt; A iinbei Meeting of the Military Hoard. </seg>
            <seg id="p143">ADJUTANT (1KNERALS KKK)KT 140 Number .°&gt;8 nation of Captain A \V -it. Co I. 2nd Infy Elect ior Discharge of enlisted n. Staff 1st Infy.: Co. K and E, 2nd Infy Number 3S Station of Troop A moved from Seward to Milfonl Number 40 lation of K M Electi Smith. Co I). Is) 1 11 r Discharge of enlisted men. Co iiid Uattei It. K. and I., 1st lit f &gt; ; C H, 2nd Xiinii" st Infy Election in ,d Infy ion of Captain J A W'iiR ■!. ■Mahlll. Co. I. 2nd Infy 1st Lieut It. T. Eller, and ml I. itu&lt; Discharge of enlisted men. Co I) 1st. and Co. I. 2nd Infy Number 42 rig of Military Hoard Number 43 Captain .1. H Hond Co D, 2nd Infy Discharge of enlisted men. Co K. and Signal Corps. 1st Infy.; Co. F. (', and I 2nd Infv Niimbvi 44 Resignation of Captain S. K Yoder Mattery A Election ordf red He election of 1st Lieut. Jack Reason. Co. C. 2nd Infy DtochaDcc d men. Co. B, 1st Infy. nation of Captain K SV Shafer. Co. E. 2nd Infy Election ordered Leave of absence, Lieut Col. \V Discharge of enlisted me: R Mclaughlin, 1st Infy. A. K. 1st Infy.. and Hattery A Number 46 ion of Major W. F. Sammons. 2nd Infy Election in Co A. 2nd Infy. Discharge of enlisted men, Co. G and H, 2nd Infy Number 47 Election of 1st Lieut. Ivan McKay, Discharge of enlisted men. Co A Co F, 1st Infy 11. F and L, 1st Infy Number 48. Election of Captain Harry .1. Ei D, 2nd Infy Authorising Iii'1.-|»ni1.-nt Coni|&gt;anv at Hpstin Number 45. DMdN 04 Isi I.it-ut. R. V. McDonald. Co. D, 1st Infv </seg>
            <seg id="p144">ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT 141 Discharge of enlisted men. Co. (J and I, 1st Infy ; Co. t, .'nd Infy., and Halter Number 48». Judge Advocate General to report for duty at office of adjutant general n July «, lHOfi Resignation of 1st Lieut. W. S I ine. Co. H, 2nd Infy Number 49 Meeting of Mill K McLaughlin, 1st Infy. election Klection of Captain A H. Barkt Klection of Captain W. C. Ram r. Co. E, 2nd Infy. sey. Co. F. 2nd Infy Klection of Captain Jacob Kanzler. Co. A. 2nd Infy. Election of 1st Lieut. Geo. P. Thomas. Co. K. 2nd Infy. Election of 2nd Lieut. O. E. Shelburn. Co. L, 2nd Infy Klection of 2nd Lieut. .1. Fred McNee, Co. A. 2nd Infy. Election of Ca;&gt;tainC. \V. T. Garrison. Battery A. Election of 1st Lieut A P. Temple. Battery A Election of 2nd Lieut. \V T. Heum, Co. K. 2nd Infy Number 51 Election of Major 1st Infy Number Resignation of Captain E. B. DeWolf. Co. D, 1st Infy Discharge of enlisted men. Co. A. C and E. 1st Infy. Discharge of enlisted nun. Co H G and 1. 2nd Infv Number 54 L Discharge of enlisted men. Co. ( wl Corps and M, 2nd Infy.. Hospital ( orps, and Number 55 Resignation of 1st Lieut. LeRoy McCulloUg] -r |nf\ ordered Dischaige of enlisted men Number 56 Resignation of Captain C. l&gt; Election nrdered Discharge of enlisted men. Co. A and H. 1st Infy.. and Hath Appointment of non-commissioned officers. Mattery A and Hospital Corps. N umber Election in Co. G. 2nd lufy. Number 50. Resignation of liituit Col. \V oidered. Ember Resignation of 1st Lieut. C. H. Reed. Co. L, Jnil Inly ered. Pwbter, Oo. H, 1st Infy </seg>
            <seg id="p145">142 AD.HTANT GENERALS REPORT Election of 1st Lieut. J. A. Crawford. Co. I!. 2nd Infy Muster-In of Hastings Rifles. Election of Captain .Ino. P. Madgett, 1st Lieut. Qi Everett W. Swartz. Hastings Rides. IMscharge of enlisted men. Co F. 2nd Infy Appointment of non-commissioned officers. Signal Corps Number 57%. Election of Lieut Col. Fred Ueguer. 1st Infy Election of Major 1st Infy Election of Major .1. J. Grinini, 1st lnfy Election in Co E. 1st Infy. Number 5£ Discharge of enlisted DM Number .V E F and M, 2nd In Detail of officers to re|H&gt;rt to ci must i. m jmnianding officer Prov ial 1 ill imber 5M Election of 1st Ueut. Walter E. Shindoll. Co. C, 1st li Election of Captain F. M. Smith, Co. I). 1st Infy Election of Captain X. L. Moon, 1st Lieut. .1. M Cr fv in in ,1 Lieut \V. P Peebler. Co H. 1st Infy Transfer and election of 1st Lieut. John H .lack Discharge of enlisted men. Co. A and C. 2nd Infy. ■ ii I '..in, ry A ii"Iht So tlon of Captain A. I). Falconer. Co. G, 2nd Infy. Changes in entraining of companies ea route to Camp of li Riley Disci .mil K. l&gt;t Inlv Co I',, unci . uni -iid Infy Ni.h.i. Resignation of 2nd Lieut. Q I Mc-Uill. Co. If. 2nd E In tioi Ele&lt;'tion of Maj.' Mwily, 1st Infj Election in Co I!. 1st Infy. Election in Co. L. 1st Infy Election of Captain John H. Linton. 1st Lieut. Jao _nd Lieut. Joseph L. Grimni. Co. E. 1st Infy. Ki ( Discharge of enlisted men. Co. H. 1st Infy N'unilx Election of 2nd Lieut. Howard li Heath. Co. M, 2nd luf i of Captain W. Edmund Itaelir. &lt;'n. L. 1st li f&gt; Discharge of enlisted men. Co. F. 1st Infy.; Co. K and li, 2nd hit v A and Troop A SVmber 62% Detail from Hospital Corps for duty at State Fair Ground </seg>
            <seg id="p146">AIUII ANT (iKNKRAL S KEPOKT 143 Number 6:1 Election of Captain Iver S. Johnson, 1st Lieut. Howard H. Anile . nd 2nd Lieut. William N. Orris. C H. 1st Infy Discharge* of enlisted men. ( Infy.. and Rushville Riff- A, li and M, 1st In B, 2nd Number 64 Meeting of Military Hoard Number 85. Camp of Instruction of Rushvilk Election in Co. G. 2nd Infy. Hi lies, and details for same Number 6ti Election of Major, 1st Infy Number 66V Rushville Rifles ordered to br ak camp and march to home station Number 67 Re-election of 1st Lieut. B. C Co. G. 2nd Infy. Hervey and 2nd Lieut. G. H. Fun; Discharge of enlisted men. Co Infy.. and Signal Cot K and L, 1st Infy ; Co. V and F, 2nd Numb) Discharge of enlisted men. Co \. and Hospital Coi 1st; Co. C and 1. 2nd Iufy.: Battery Aixjpintment of noncommissioned officers. Hastings Rillt Number M. Resignation of 1st Lieut. A. L. Huddleston. Co. 1. 1st InTy., and etee tiom ordered. Election of Major W. Edniund Baehr, lsi lnf&gt; Election in Co. L, 1st Infy. Discharge of enlisted men. Hospital Coi|p.n. Co. l&gt; and I. 1st Iufy Number Discharge of enlisted men, Co. K. 1st Infy. Discharge of enlisted men. Co. D. 1st Infy. Election of Captain Guy D. Soloman. Co. L, 1st Inly Resignation of 2nd Lieut. Wni. P Discharge of enlisted men, Co. h Discharge Staff. Co. K. lsl Infy 1 •eebler, Co. H, lsl Infy 2nd Infy. Number Discharge of enlisted men. Co Discharge of enlisied men. Co. Discharge of enlisted men. Co Discharge of enlisted men. Co II 1st 1 1 i r \ H. Is Infy A 1st Inly 1st Infy 1. .Number Discharge of enlisted men, Co I, 2nd Iufy </seg>
            <seg id="p147">AD.HTANT GENERAL S KKPoRl 144 I GENERAL ORDERS, 1906 (G«Berml Orders No. W is the lasi of 1! HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, I djutant Genera] '■ Ofllct Lincoln, .lanuar al Orders / No. 1. \ I. The following additional staff appointments are hereby annotim rr the information of all concerned To be Aides-de-camp ("attain John G. Workizer. 2nd Infaniry, V. S. A , Lincoln Lieutenant Fred H. Richards. Signal Corps. Fremont. With the rank of Lieutenant Colonel, and they will .1 an i dingly. H&gt; order of the Governor J. H. Cl'LVER Adjutui: HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Adjutant ral's Olfici Lincoln, January 1. l!mt; t] Orders | No \ The following named officer ational Guard, having qualified ai and enlisted men of the N :t riflemen, sharp ahoot4 tirksmen during the target season of 1905, will be. issued the badgt d pins to which they are entitled, viz.: Ex|K-rt Riflemen: Lieut. E. H. Mullownc\v n.l li Pvt Harry B. Hobbs, Pvt. Durward H. Davi Co. K. 1st In Hharpahooti Lt Col. W. R. Mclaughlin. t In Major Fred Gegner. Major J. M. Birkner, Samuel I IM William Duffy. Pvt. Conrad Wegner, Corp. .1 Balderson. 1st In Anilmluiice Compan Co. B. 1st In ('.). B Co. K Co. E. Co. K. 1st In Co. H, 2nd In Co. L. M In Corp. R. D. Meisenbach. Mus, Ray R. Young. Corp. Roy C. Shankland. Corp. George S. Jo? </seg>
            <seg id="p148">\D.H TANI UEXERALS RETORT 145 Co. L, 2nd Inf Serct Roy C. Hurt Co. M. 2nd Inf Frank F. Wi Corp. F. .1. Brian Co. M. 2nd Inf riarksm ,ieut. Jacob Fei . Lieut. K. Auber Rushviilf Rill .it. .1. F. Hash 2nd Inf nt. u. i 1st Inf Co. B. Co. F. Co. F, Co. K, Co. K. Co. K, Co. K. I C. Chris Co. K. Roy R Russell Co. M A. C. Dahl W, Inf I'm. Ed. Kudrna Co. K. 2nd Inf ii. (ion Co. L, 2nd Inf Fred A. Hosfoi Co. M. 2nd Inf Artif. A I! H.-.M W. 2nd Im ition of ihc above name. I officers ami men i.s railed •"irinn Regulations for Small Anns. 1!&lt;h4 III. Certificates will be forwarded as soon .is complete n-|&gt;or in I his office by or of Small Anns I'i I H CUL.VKR, Adjutant G HEAUQl'ARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Adjutant General's Office Lincoln. Januai n No ecially desire. I that evi I and coinmissi ~ka National Guard lit Pvt. Edgai Bn Cain. C. E. Fia Capt. () II. Newman, Capt. August Wagner ('apt. E. C. 1'ick I'vr A. r Felsch. Pvt. Kred (1 Fia I'vi. Frank Drapmjr, 8*rgt. Arthur C. Boon*' \ R McFarlanil Bert .1 lirian. Corp. Anton Johnson orp. Fred Kanzelm. Co. 1., Jml Inf 1. The Annual convene ;it Representative Mall, Capitol Building, Lincoln, Neb 111.. Monday. Februan 19, IMC. </seg>
            <seg id="p149">146 ADJUTAN1 GENERALS KKPXMU III. Orders for transportation will bu sent dlrec* to the field ,,n officers, and to the company commanders Cor the compaii \ offi. returned to this office promptly, if it is found ini|K)s.silile, for Imsim other reasons, to attend the school. IV. Those attending will he allowed |3.M per day, which is it ' actual i. in addition to tranaportatioa. By order of the Governor I. H. CII.VKK. Adjutant CJenera HEADQIARTEKS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD nenU'a Ofl reiKjrt for examination to the President of t!ie Board, Colonel J lour name, I in paragraph I: .eiih A FIRST INFANTRY RKt.iMKN B. &lt;; Batterfleld. INn rod. R. A. BrinKman. U W. Oh 1st Lieut. W. A. M&gt; - 1st Lieut. L McCulloush 1st Lieut, r. M Smith, .ieut. .). H Brock. 2nd Lieut. E. W. Hu: 2nd Lieut. C. R. Mm 2nd Lieut. W. J. Schneider 2nd Lieut. H. B. Hobbs. 2nd Lieut. H. E. Ford. 2nd Lieut C. E. Ault Lincoln, January It, II General Or: No 4 I. In MHNil Xebiaska, Hoard of Examination will convene at the Adjutant General's Offi&lt; Capitol Building. Lincoln Friday, i 0MlMk| of: ■""♦•' ■'■ -* - ' Infantry R, Majoi E. H I Adjutant General -Major F S. Nlekofa Isi Infantry Regiment. .tin J. P. Camera*, 2nd Infantry R ,iin A. 1). r«le 2nd Infantry 1. Captain K C. Ptd Infantry Re S ii,; Captain S. F. Shannon. 2nd Infantry R II The following i braaka National Guard w\ </seg>
            <seg id="p150">AD.MTANT GENERAL'S REF'OKT 147 KY REGIMENT il. O. G. 0 Major P. J. Mack 2nd Lieut. L. Fritz lamination will b Orders No. 1 IV. The oi \ ilnatlon will be allowed :';&lt;■ sane - the Officers' Soluxil. in iscribed Ic Empensatior neral Orde The Boa llowed such compensation as |, n . 1 tl. The insiiection of the Nebraska National Guard, in accordance with tion 14 of the Aci ol Comgnm approved January 21. 1903, will February I ml Lieut. H. (". Wilson ml Lieut, (i. I.. I ml Lieut. H. Pritehard 2nd Ltout c. u Bam SECOND INFA.VI Col. .1. C. Hartigi ('apt. 1. H. Bond C'apt. C K 1st Limit. .1. W. B. Bn 2nd Lieut. J. F. Hulka 2nd Lieut O. P. Thomas 2nd Lieut. G. ('. Fancher. 2nd Lieut. B. T. Eller. 2nd Lieut. \V. L. Kolm. 2nd Lieut. Q. K. Gaskill. rd Lieut C W. Gregg. TROOH A L'nd Ue«t. C. W. Funk RU8HVILLE R1KLI ("apt. K. Anbert. Lieut. ('. I. Hoi ilit'il in i of Kxaiiiination wi Military Board [ the Governor, </seg>
            <seg id="p151">ADJUTANT UENEKAL S KHIMKI 148 uk A. Wilrox. :iuth Infair by the Comniandin. of the Northern Division, lo perfonii duty III (onipaii.v roniniandeis will a nible lln 1.1 mm a I company quai Felmi.i Feliru.. March 1. Tliu March 2. Fi i hi' following ciion in Coni|j Infantr) . Weeping W Wa Company V" 1'nd Infant. E 1st Ir.fan Wii ( Com | N. March 1, San. March i. Moo March March 7 March 8, Thu March March 12. Mm. Match 11 March 15, Thn: Maich 11 I) .'ml 1 Kai Infantry, H WA nt ry. Aim: -nil Infant A XI" 1st Infantry, Broken How I: 2nd Infant onipany "H" 2nd I' nfantry, Yo K End Inlan March 17. 9 Maich l'.i. Mob March March Maich 2:\. Fri March March March March 2«. Thin March M, Fri. March \pril April April April VI" 2nd Infantry, Alii ilumbu Infant Rill H 1st Infantry, Stantoi 1 11 1 Ml Wisi nd Infant I Infantry, Oin On March npan\ I. 1st Inlantrv, Om Marc npany "I" I'nd [aiutry, Omaha March 2H. Tin. 2nd Infantry, Tekamah ml Infantry, Tek.unah Marcti Fremont r'ifii in Marrl . hoo nil \\ \pril 2nd Infantry, I. in. ml Infantry, Lincoln April iiiv. Lincoln n pan April \. ii. I April Lincoln IV The of the Infantr.x I a Sif;n;il Coi IV. Th^ Signal (\ Ambulance Company, will i .. littery A ami Troo Ambulance Company, will i ,. Lathery A and Troo| A. at :!:&lt;ki p. ni.. and will l» in heav\ marchli V. 'I mlform (shirt, blouse aad trouaersl win i&gt;«- worn, m i.HKii hat ami Ii VI Field and staff o(fi&lt;&lt;rs will report at tin niosl convi in attorn ii ion Vll. All aaan and ordnx imp equipage, books will l» in heavy marchli - V. The blue unifon i will be w «i . VI Field and staff ofliois will report at the n ion upon t ho arriva </seg>
            <seg id="p152">ADJUTANT GENERALS KEPOKT 149 of the inspecting officer on date of Inspection, or at such hour as may be ated by him. VIII A li i, wbetbei rltfe or without leave, and number present, must I** prepared ami delivered to the inspecting officer iiml a duplicate copy sen Mutant General immediately thereafter. IX Officeis and men complying with this order will be allowed one Iollar each for such .• rolls to ■ad promptly forwarded Mutant Oeneral. Pay Rolls must ed on date of Inspection. X. This inspection is made with i lining what organiza- -iifneiently aimed, uniformed and equipped for active duty in he field, and to determine what nized niiliti.i of the -everal states and territories is entitli the I'nited St. tXI. All ofti- . pin ton] ffort.s to have every ■resent, ■ By order of the Governor: i. ii. cuLvn, Adjutant (Jen. HRADQIARTER8 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD,) H. Lincoln, M hral Orders / i It is with dei-; vti nor announces the death of Q— era] John M Thaver, which o n., March 19th, it! his residence in the city of Lincoln. John Milton Tha&gt; era at Hellingham. Mm January .'4, farm, gradual- Brown I'niversin , and noved to Nebraska tling in Omaha where he was admitted to the bar. The first territorial legislature authorized the enrollment of militia men for the protection of the frontier and commissioned John M, Ti Her general and placed him in command and la as major general of th. rltoriaJ volunteers, in whicli po«itton he continued until the firins on Fort Bun pier in IM1, when he raised and tendered the servi( . trhst 1,-gimeni. Xehraska Volunteei lden( Lincoln, which was accepted, and he coiihiii onel, reported to Gfneral Fremont at St. Louis, then ,,t at Pilot Knoh; partici- pated in the campaign of Forts Hear] and Donelson; promoted to briKadier general for gallant conduct; sent to southwestern Ten- nessee, taking part in the battle of Shiloh. the siege of Vicksburs and engagements incident thereto; « ,1 major general for </seg>
            <seg id="p153">150 ADJUTANT HENERALS REPORT for mi i meritorii parlmeni of Al I i later At tic turned to Nebi 11. 1 then one of the first Ihe fii - iiventi ooogn turbulen ;iltirl|ijtiliu ii ins the reconstruct^ nor of Wyoming; am n period. In 1X7 (I nearly four j • •int. n returne d it o pnv nd Arm onferred upon him b Brown University and 1. L. 1). by the University of Nebraska . : Th • in the hi of the firm mili; i of th: its from tht battlefield winni: nfidenci ihe most prominent offict i in the War of the Rebellion arks . of unusua izer and conruander Indian dt predations, then on the neral Grant and returning Territory of Nebras His loyalty to his country w ircunisi no bounds and : only by his ma^nific citizen am on 'h- history that will have ■ beneficent influence on sue itions The flaws ai aJ -minions will be displayed at half staff on the day of the fun. 23rd instant, and the armories of the -.-.a National Guard will I in mourning for the nex thirty days in testimony of res|&gt;ect to the menu r and statesman. By order of the (Jovernoi T. H. CULVER. Adjutant Gen HKADQIARTKRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD.) A d J u I n^ral Orders j No. 7. I Th. .invm. the purpose of examining officer il Orders No. 4, p. s. i.ii qualifications for com I" In&lt; " Nl ional Gaard, nariiic reported (hat the follow office- xamination, and recommended that thev He ■ rred to the De in command of the Armv Id N&gt; Mzen of Lincoln and ■ Commander &lt;i &lt;ic the Republic. who successfully pretect in courage and sterling integrit ive officer, he has left his imprin Lincoln. March 2fi, ISM, </seg>
            <seg id="p154">ADJUTANT OENERALS REPORT 151 R ■ 1 Hoard i hereby FIRST REl.IMEXT Captain Captain First Lieu IcCultoagh First Lieutenant ank M. Smith First Lieutenant William E. OsIkmii ind Lieutenant Chester K Ma nd Lieutenant Harry R Hoi nd Lieutenant nd Lit J. Mack Willard S. Paul Walter S. 1'ine Montie E Lum Wall. Majo F Lieutenant Lieutenant RIFLES i CORPS Louig H. i i II. The Board recommends that &lt;nnent, he commissioned withou »ptain Penrod, 1st Infantry xaniination, on account of previous animations, commissions and serv III. The following named officers in the Nebraska National Guard ■tfore said Board. d from taking the examination at the time designated, upon Mown, subject to an examination to be ordered hereafter, ore being commissioned, viz Colonel .John C. Hartigan cond Regiment ■cond Regiment cond Regiment lad Lieut. B. T. Eli 2nd Lieut. H. Pritcharu 2nd Lieut. W. J. Schneider 2nd Lieut. C. E. Ault Second Regimen' Regiment First Regiment First Regiment IV. The Board having reported that the following officers failed to ain I he required per cent in the examination, and recommended that niniissioned. the reiiort and recommendation uz.: Blbert G. Riitterfiehl Ralph A. Bringmar William A. Mm ECOXD REGIMENT Lieutenant I.U'utenant ■cond Lieutenant •i-ui.l Lieutenant ■eonil Lieutenant First Lieutenant Second Lieutenant First Lieut&lt; I.itMit. Col. Olh »nM Captain J. H. Bond </seg>
            <seg id="p155">152 ADJUTANT GENERALS KEPORT ■xamined. the report and recommendation are appro unatloi Captain 1.. W. Ohnisted 2nd Lieut H K For. 2nd Lieut. H V Wilson 2nd Lieut .[. F. Hulk; Second 2nd Lieut. C. P. Thonia SmiNu 2nd Lieut. II A. .les Signal ( V. Th&lt; lied to his hoim in ■der of the Governor I H Cl'LVKR A.lj HEADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD,! Adjutant General's Ofi'i reral ( I I Small arms practice will be conducted in a w Firing Regulations of the I'. S. Army, ami in t illations hs may be promulgated from time to time by nt. or by this office kill. The jiraoi || anils is during the entire will be from etober ::i. litiiii. - ini \ ifter. klV. All field and staff officers and non-conm -taff officers, ik tned, may report for small arms practice with the lompan venient. commanders will furnish rifle and ammunition f , and account for the same in their company report of \ny officer or enlisted man qualifying as a marksman inn flv. h com 1 1a 1 1 May 1st and June SO, will be kliOWC to participate in the competition which will determine the personnel ( of the fifteen making tin • neral On: uartment All taiKet practice on tli. nated range, must k *'&lt; u " fflcer who wiil be held resjK.i • red to re|x&gt;rt f Artjin. ,v dir 1st Lieut J. H. Brock 1st Lieut. A. L. Mini Lincoln Ap Lll. S|. rifle. I hf* ,j pj-^ </seg>
            <seg id="p156">ADJUTANT GEXKRALS REPORT 153 •tUe for strict discipline, instruction, and careful handing of irms ami ammunition. VII. Fifty rounds of calibre 22 for gallery practice, and fifty round iilitire :;n for range practice, will he allowed to each man du.ing th' VIII. Gallery practice should he conducted hy the organize! squads lie company, under an officer or non-commissioned officer capable of Imparting proper instructions and enforcing strict discipline. Company commanders should designate the time for each squad to practice, and healthy rvalry between the squads for the place of honor IK IX. Officers and enlisted men participating as contestants at th. competition will he allowed transportation and subsistence and such com- nsation as may he determined by the .Military Board, and approved by e Commander-in-Chi' X. Re|&gt;orts of target practice must he made promptly by the command n officer of each company at the close Of each month, to this office r of the Governor Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA .NATIONAL GUARD, / Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln. May 1. IMM ■neral Orders ) N&lt; \ It is with regret that the Commander-in-Chief announces the death Ex-Governor James E. Hoyd, which occurred at Omaha. April 34th, IMt, he age of seventy-two years. The funeral will take place at Omaha :i"&gt; p. m. May ::. lHmi .lames E. Boyd was born in County Tyrone, Ireland, September I In 1X44 he came to America with his parents, who settled in Belmont County. Ohio. Early in youth he learned the carpenter's trade, and migrated to the west. In 1S56 he engaged in carpenter and contract work with his brother at Des Moines, Iowa. Later in the year they moved to Omaha, where they continued in that vocation, building the first court Dm in Douglas County. Governor Boyd was elected County Clerk of kal County in 1*67, which office he resigned and the following year amoved to Buffalo County, where he secured land and engaged in farming tnd stock raising. A few years later he started a store at Gibbon, and ;tnother at Kearney, where he did a triving business, filling contracts hay and grain to the government, supplying the garrison at Fort Kearney When the construction of the Union Pacific railroad began, he secured ■xtensive grading contracts from this company, which proved quite profitable. In 1868 he moved his family back to Omaua. where he has I. H. Cl'I.VER. </seg>
            <seg id="p157">154 AD.ll TANT (1ENERALS KKl'OKT I. He was t* ,1 Omaha, and eler ernor of Nebraska i He will Ions be reinemh. "' "&gt; minded official The H ,11 public building! wili ,ff „, the funeral, ud the Brnoriea of the National Ci he N will Ik- draped in mourning for thirty &lt;i ■ H\ order of I he (iovernor: rill be draped in mourning for thirty da H&gt; order of the Governor: J. H CDLVBE, Adjutant Qenerml. I. H CULVER Adjutant Gen HEAnQlARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD, HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD Bee. Lincoln. Inn. no. ie. No. I*. '■ °" !l War, i he First an&lt; : I. On the In li Ri-Kiinents of infant, vmliulance Company ani - ill participate in the encampment and man. Kilev. Kan: h to 12th (inclusii. II. The Wlrthi ■ :iizations above named ! iieii coniinanrls in i roni their home stations &gt;hich the] will return on August 1 :;i h. as may he direc -equent 01 III. No recruits will !, | after July ;&gt;th, and prior to Aug of Infantry. B Imbalance Company and Sim will participate in (he encampment and man. Riley Kana rin August Its to U'lh linclusit. II. The commanding &lt;&gt;m&lt; organization w heir coniinanrls in move fron &gt;ns which the) will return on August ISth, as may be directed nt orilf 111 - N ifter -July ,-,th, and prior to Augus onipany cooks, the time for reuniting m ins nion I in Circular N I to include July 3th. C( Com pany comm Hn ,l ,. n | ist j,,,,,,, cooks w j t h oll I and enlist good cooks with IV. Regimen thai [he companies are divic 1 squads, as provided in Section.- IV. Ri-Kim.nt il conn ai the eomj into - ad squads, as proi I inclusive and inclusive, am &lt;&gt;4, and that non-commissioned offic ructed in their dutit v Tt and khaki uniforms will be worn The commanding h company will make requisition prior to July loth for actually needed lo equip his command, as quarte For Rlley. Company 'commander autioned not to make requisition for more than is actually required VI. Bagsage will b. , o the minimum. Each enlisted mar will provide himself with two suits of underwear, two pairs of socl tooth brush, comb and hoa :.ich squad, one small wash basin, an necessary towels VII. Each company is required to make a practice march of at 1 he month of July, and should be carefully </seg>
            <seg id="p158">155 t pitching the conical wall, anil slit ns under the head •'Pitching Tent Her tents, in accordance with i s." page 1%. Drill Regulations. nt to the commanding officer of each erly filling out. and accomplishing the VIII. Blank pay rolls will company, with instructions for prop and one copy must be return nation on or before the 15th of July &gt;d to the Adjutant General fo: dei of the Governor H. (TI.VER. Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA .NATIONAL UITARD, } neral'a Office i Lincoln. .In rneral Orders / No. 11. * I, By authority of section ~'12i mutes, supplement of IMS, the ■&gt; of cha maximum enliste.l .strength ol infantry company will consist of ( .int. four sergeants, six corp&lt; artificer and forty-eight priv.i me hi - ■. one quartet rals. two cooks, two musicians. &lt;&gt;n&lt;' in tEach troop of cavalry will cons ister sergeant, fo ata, six idler, one wagoner, two trunipete d a maximum of forty-six private lit, one nil wporala, two cooks, one farrier, one an;l I minimum of thirty pri . i ( I. H. CULVER. Adjutant General HKADQl'ARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GT ARD. } neral's Office I Lincoln. .Itilv 27. IHiPt; tl. In compliance with General Orders No 10, A. G. () . c. s., thr&gt; . tions named therein will move to camp of instruction at Fort Riley. :i August 3d, 1911*!, on the following schedule: FIRST REGIMENT rnd, Wiaaei W.. 7:ftfl a. u\.. via Lincoln, thence I". P. S| loads bacKage with Co. II, 1st. rA. York. It \- \l . 11.25 a m. via Lincoln, them Adjutant ( </seg>
            <seg id="p159">1 ( ( ( w ( ( H ( C ADJtTAMTIOENERAL S RKPOKT H -tanlon. ('. &amp; X. \V. I:M a m . via Lincoln, thence I" P. special - with bam. Hand. 1st. in. V. I with Co. E, 1st (i I). Weeping W a. 111.. M. I*, via Lincoln, thence V. P. special load with Co. I. 1st. at N. W de|&gt;ot. Lincoln (i K. WillK-r. B. &amp; M.. 11 • urice. thence 1' P. special, stai picks 11 1 f Co. C, 1st ladison. C P. ll:;:l a m.. special from Columbus. st:ins with bau ii Colnmboa. in . via Lincoln, thenec V P. speci.il. load b.i. i A. L'd. ai Fairmont O M. Nelson. C. R. I. A P.. »:M a in . via Fairbury, thence Si I. &amp; O. 1 ir. picks up b.i 1 o I). 2.1. 'o. 1. Waho 7 a 111 . via Lincoln, thence V I'. s|«&gt;cia picks up hasgage of Co. I) 1st, at X. \V. clepi 'inaha. B .&lt; . via Lincoln, thence 1' P. special will picks up M. 1st, at Lincoln. O M. Broken Bow. B &amp; .\i 111., via Lincoln, thence V. P. special loads basRa^e with Co L. 1st. at Lincoln. SECOND RECIMKNT land. Osceola. l\ P. \:44 a m. loads Lincoln 'o. A. • It &amp; 14.. 8:4i a ill. 1 is with Ir. 1 , picks up via Lincoln, thence I". P. special 1 Co. 0, 1st. at Fairmont ial from Columbus, starts with bag Oliimbus. a 111.. via Beatrice, theme D. P up baggage of Co. L, 24, .it o I). Fairbtiry, St .1 &amp; Q. I. sin-cial, l:im p. m.. via Marysvilk', thence 1' P. s|&gt;ecial. loads basga^e with Co. H. : Lincoln, thence 1' P special, starts with baggage &lt;- a r. picks up ba K. I'd. ai Fremont o F. Lincoln. V P s|i*»cial. 1 p. 1 with Ambnlance Co lo. O. Omaha. B. A M., »:U a. m.. via Lincoln, thence V. P. special taking I,. Co. I, 2d. 'o. H. Aurora. B 4: M 10:44 a 111. via Lincoln, then i&gt;ecial, pick? up bagt: 1st. '&lt;&gt; I, Omaha. B. &amp; M . i* : 1 &lt; &gt; a ni.. via Lincoln, thence U. P special, loads baggage with 1 O K. Schuyler. V. P :u.. via Fremont, C. &amp; S. W. to Lincoln ihei" 'ecial. loads baggage with Co. E. M, at Fremont Lincoln: m . lo.ul&gt; with Co. F, 1st ih.t. H A: M., »:18 ,i m.. via Lincoln, ihenc- I' P. ■neetal. - -•■ with brigade heailquarte Co B. Si. Paul. T. (' I . spec picks ii| if Co. «pe&lt; Fairlmrv. St .1 &amp; Q I St. P. M. &amp; O., 7:45 a. ni., via Blair. Fremont and </seg>
            <seg id="p160">AD.irTANT GENERAL.'!* REI'OKT 157 rL, Alma, B. ft M , K:21 a. m., via Beatrice, thence 0. 1" special loads baggage with Co. C, M, at Beatrice. t. M. Albion. I'. P.. 11:10 a. m . special from Colambm, lo;i with Co. B. 2(1, at Columbus. BATTERY A WYMORE • home .station August 2d, marching to Marysville, Kansas, thence I*. P. special at 3:00 p. ni. on AugUi SIGNAL, CORPS. FREMONT 1' P. special. 3:36 p. in., starts with bat &gt;f 1st Rest. Headquarters at Fremont AMBULANCE CO., LINCOLN HASTINGS RIFLES. HAST! a. in.. Si J. &amp; (!. I . special from Fairbury. via Marysville, LT. P. special, starts with baggage car. takes in baggage of Headquai ■rs I'd. al Hasting BRIGADE HEALKJIARTERS rcoln. 1:M p. in . V. P. special, starts with baggage i of Bami. Id, at Lincoln. II. Battery A will march overland to Marysville. anil entrain as abovi indicate&lt;l III. Captain Madgett. of the Hastings Rifles, with his command, will rei&gt;ort to Col. Hartigan. at Fairbury. on August :!. and will pr.ice. tve indicated, and will personally Brigade on arrival at Fort Riley, report to the commanding officer of for special duty LIV. Officers of the Ceneial Staff duty on the followiii- will report to the Adjutant (;. Col. Ceo. E. Jenkins and l.i CoL Col. John A. Ehrhardt. on Angus Col. C. I) Evans, on Align - lohn (;. Workizer, on August 1st :&lt;l men. to the Adjutant General at Lincoln, on VI Capta&lt;n Aubert and Lieutenant Fritz. Rushville Rifles, will report see that li reduce I to the nated. quart) int, for its pro permitted to ride in l&gt;.i - i company quarters must t&gt;e l&lt; Knimum. and packed carefully and (1 detail guard, under direction of n Two thus detailed may l&gt;&lt; While in camp, a sufficient guard nv the proper protection of property. VIII. The senior offi&lt; • train will assume command of tht ihat all ii promptly carried out. appointing officer of the day, and detailing such guards as may be I to insure ) and good ord- I'fcial, l:M ]&gt;. in., starts with hassa^e ear, tak.s huKKUKf of Co. F Id. at Lincoln. V. Lieu!. Baldwin, Troop A, will ie|K&gt;n, mounted, wilh a detail of ttvt thf Adjutant General for duty, on Attgiu VII. Company commanders will see that 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p161">158 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPOlO Tli* 1 OMUMUMltag officer of the train will detail an officer, surgeon r red. to inspect and re|&gt;ort on the sanitary conditions of the train, am whether properly iced, watered and lighted. He will also report time o •niiis command of the special train, and the delays en route; the timi required to detrain his command on arrival at camp, to the brigade com mander. Commanding officers of trains will see that cars are thoroughly policed and left in good condition before detraining. IX Railroad companies have been requested to pla opening at the end, next to the coaches, for the purpose of putting up range for the cooking of coffee for those on the train. A mess officer should bt ■ mied by the commanding officer to carry this order into effect. Com panies will furnish their own coffee and cook details. X. No ammunition is to be taken to Fort Riley, and no arms other than tho.- mined to be taken, and company com - manders will make thorough inspection on entraining, to see that no ball XI. Order must be maintained, and boisterous actions prohibited, am men not permitted to straggle during train stops. One commission. ■&lt; ■iild remain wilh each company. The officers and men ar. reminded that the credit of the Nebraska National Guard is at stake, and and iiny overt act will reflect on its good name By order of the Governor I H. CULVER Adjutant C- HHAIKJl ARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARJ Adjutant General Lincoln. July 30 \ !■ accordance with Section Tl Q. O. No. 5, A. c;. u N N &lt;; and upon the | the Colonels commanding Regiments. Itrig era! .1. H. Culver. Adjutant General. Nebraska Naiiona] Guard, la ■&gt; placed in command of the troops of the Nebraska National Guard participating in the maneuvers at the Camp of instruction at Fort Riley -i 1st to 15th, inclu - B\ o F. H. i.TLVER. Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p162">159 IIRADQl AKTKKS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD,) Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln, July 30, 1906 onl. No O. No. 13, A. (',. ()., N. N. O., .In PC tin i iiiiiiii ml of the troops of the Nebraska Xationa Rlley, Kansas, from Auk. lsi to 15th, indusiv omprlse the Provisional Brigade, Mowing organizations w N. National G R A h offi 1 ellisu-d men belonging to oilier Guard as may be detailed. I. H. CILYER Adjutant General Lincoln, An. &gt;i N( iind by authority i TlM.". of Chapter ::::. Statutes of Ni ! W. Colby, All Ired list of the onal Guard, with tl I. H. CULVER. Adjutant i i HKADQl'ARTKRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD,) aneuvers at the Camp of Instruction L'nd Regiment Infan Ambulance Conipan Nation HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, ) eral'a office. own requee I u|K&gt;n the Adjui.ii. \ UBCOln, August I ieneral Ordi No. I*. \ I. The s lor Um mmou of ISM will be establisheil on tin Hlller farin. about two ami nwti liilf milea soutaweal &lt;&gt;r the city of Coluni hi.-, under the command of Limn. B. II htnllovacy, Id, Inf., Actin;; lnspec :iall Arms I'rai </seg>
            <seg id="p163">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S KK!&gt;UH 1 160 II. The re|x&gt;rt of the Acting lnsj&gt;eoior of Small Arm shows the following named members of the Nebraska National Guard have quali ititleil lo take part in the Suite oompel in larget practice, to determine those best qualified under the nil - form the Nebraska Rifle Team for Col Fred QognMT, 1st Inf Major Fred Mark. 2d Inf. Maja V Klterlv. 1st Inf. Captain .lames B. Hungate. 1st Inf. &lt;in B. D. 1 i Q. M . A. Q. O. Capt. Chas. B. V K. 1st Inf. August v o. K. 1st Inf. --hallenberger. Co. I.. 2d Inf. oibert. Rushville Rr 1st Lieut. Jacob C Ferg K. 1st Inf leut John H. Brock. Co K. Is; Inf. 1st Lieut, .lames F. Hashberger. Co. K. 2d I lit 2d Lieul. Win. E. OkIxm ■ 1st Inf. I'd Lieut. Howard H. Antles. Co. B. 1st Inf 2d Lieut. Walter .1. Schneider. 1 Lieut Harry B. H. F, 1st lnl I Lieut H&lt;.v.:t&lt;I B. Heath. Co M. 2d Inf Arthur C. Boone. Co. K. 1st Inf. .1 Brian. Co. K. 1st Inf. ■ irge S. J&lt;&gt; I'd Inf. inl. I. M Inf Frank F Willott. Co. M. 2d Inf. John Dullaghan. Rushville R. :.&lt;rnes. Rushville Ri! Corp I B, 1st Inf Corp Jacob Balderson. Co. E, 1st Inf. Corp Rov C Shanklan(i. Co. H. 2d Inf Corp Frank .1. Brian. Co. M. 2&lt;1 Inf. Artif. Fred C.unlack. Co. A, 1st Inf. Artif Durward H. Ii K. 1st lnl Mus l&gt;ouis Zander. Co B. 1st Inf. Ferguson. Co. E. 1st Inf Kav R Young. Co K. 1st Inf. Ear) I MHxel. Co H. 2d Inf. Cook John Gibson. Co. L. 2d In! I'riv Howard C. Sloi Ki lnl I'riv Inf. Inf. I'tiv Royal A. Wellington, Co. A. 1st Inf. I'riv William Duffy, Co. B, 1st inf. Hriv Albert F Felsch, Co. B, 1st Inf. </seg>
            <seg id="p164">ADJUTANT (JEXERAL'S REPORT 161 Priv. Winfred Cahoon, Co. B, 1st Inf. Priv. Jay DeWolf, Co. D, 1st Inf. Priv. Clarence C. Grimm, Co. E, 1st Inf. Priv Nelson P. Wyckoff, Co. E, 1st Inf. Priv. Bert Meisenbach, Co. E, 1st Inf. Priv. Joseph A. McCloud, Co. K. 1st Inf. Priv. James A. Hoes, Co. H, 2d Inf. Priv. Charles M. Stewart, Co. H, 2d Inf Priv Alvin E. Blades, Co. H, 2d Inf Priv. Edward Kudrna, Co. K. 2d Inf. Priv. Fred Mohr, Co. K. 2d Inf. Priv. Frank Allington. Co. L, 2d Inf. Priv. Edward J. Lane. Co. M, 2d Inf. Priv. William H. H. Davis. Co. M, 2d Inf. Priv. Augustus N. Hulse. Co. M, 2d Inf. Priv. Charles Brooks, Rushville Rifles. Priv. Everett Dale, Rushville Rifles. Priv. Leu Gammon, Rushvrlle Rifles. III. Of the above named, those desiring to enter the competition will report to Lieut. E. H. Mullowney, 2d Inf., Acting Inspector of Small Arms Practice, at the range above named, on August 18th. IV. The fifteen receiving the highest markings will constitute the team which will take part in the national competition at Sea Grt, N. J., beginning September 4, 1906. V. The following compensation for this tour of duty has been fixed by the Military Board: $3.00 per day for commissioned officers, $1.00 per day for enlisted men, and subsistence. VI. The commanding officer of Co. K, 1st Inf., will detail eight cade - fully selected men, and the commanding officer of the Signal Corps will detail Lieut. Mallonee and four competent men of the Corps to report for duty to Lieut. Mullowney on August 18th. bVII. Lieut. Mallonee will take such equipment as is necessary to tahlish and maintain signal service and telephone communications as iv be desired. VIII. The service uniform, as prescribed for the U. S. Army, will be worn, which includes the olive drab woolen and khaki colored cotton, russet leather shoes, leggings, blue shirts, and campaign hats. tlX. Each National Guardsman reporting for duty under this order ust be equipped with shelter half, woolen blankets, poncho, haversack id canteen. LX. The usual camp discipline and sanitary requirements will be forced. Travel enjoined necessary for public service. By order of the Governor. J. H CULVKR, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p165">162 AD.HTANT (iENEKAI. S KKI'OKI HEADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL ClARD, / Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, August 25, 1906 il Orders / 17. 1 The Nebraska S lard Ritie Team for the season of 190€ will consist of 1st Lieut. E. H. Mullowney, 2nd Inf. Captain .1 G. Workizer, 2nd Inf., V. S. A.. Coach Capt. S. D. Davis, Q. M. Dept.. Spotter Lieut Col. Fred Gegner, 1st Inf J. B. Hungate. 1st Inf. M C. Shallenberger, Co. L, 2nd Inf. 1st Lieut. J. H. Brock, Co. K, 1st Inf. 2nd Lieut. Howard B. Heath, Co. M, 2nd Inf. Priv William Duffy, Co. B, 1st Inf. Priv. AlberuF. Felsch, Co. B. 1st Inf. Jacob Balderson. Co. E, 1st Inf. Priv Bert Meisenl Inf Priv Fred. Mohr, Co. K, 2nd Inf. &lt;&gt;rge S. Joyce, Co. L, 2nd Inf. Sergt. Bert E. Bridges, Co. L, 2nd Inf Cook John Gibson, Co. L, 2nd Inf. Frank F. Willott, Co. M, 2nd Inf. Priv. Edward J. Lane, Co. M, 2nd Inf. II. The Team will continue to practice on the state range at Columbus until the 3(ith instant, when it will proceed to Sea Girt, New Jersey, and take part in the National Match, as prescribed in G. O. 56, c. s., War Dept.. and on completion of this tour of duty, the members of the team will return to theii resp&gt; • ions. III. The members of the team will receive the same pay as prescribed for the annual encampment, and allowance for subsistence, as provided inG. O. li IV The Adjutant oeneral will provide the transportation and sub - sistence, and accompany the team, arranging all details necessary to carry out the full intent of this order. V. The uniform will be the olive drab and khaki Travel enjoined necessary for public sen By order of the Governor. J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p166">INDEX Ent General &gt; Report, Summary tit Generals Financial Report MM Company, Camp at State es * i ■ ¥ air Grounds Board of Survey isa Governor .Tame* E , death at Camp Groui ds Camp of Instruction 1905, Kearney. Net Orders covering Report of Brigade Commander KeiK&gt;rt of U. 8. Officer Orders of Brigade Commander Report of Colonel, 1st. Inf Maneuvers. Reports of Umpires Strength of K. X. G., Present and i braska l-'ti. ISO, 13H •2H n M M, 40. 41 Absent i:\ Report of Q M. and Corny General 4 44. 45. 4ti 47 : of Instruction, 190H, Ft. Riley, Kansas Orders Covering, !«rt of Brigade Commander Orders of Brigade Commander Maneuvers 5 154, 155 se 59, 74, 75 t54 to ::&lt; tngth &lt;jf N. N. ti. , Present and Absent bulanc* Company. Report of 7!t Report of Q. M. and Corny General ■si I ■of Instruction, Ambulance Com]&gt;any, State Fair of Instruction, Rushville Rifles, Camp \\ - y. Change in strength of troop ( rounds lu,-&gt; Ej)uipment of National Guard I FurnaM, Governor Robert \V. . death of 125 General Orders. IM ral Orders, 1906 102 144 Er's Staff, appointment of Governor Silas A., death of Companies, change in strength of 144 </seg>
            <seg id="p167">ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT 164 Inspect inns Report of Inspector General United States. 1905. 18 23, 108 55. 147 United States, 1U06. State. 1905. order covering State. 1908, order covering Judge Advocate General, Report of L. Company, 2nd. Inf. , Muster out Military Code Militia List bv Counties, 1906, Ordnance Stores drawn in 1906 Organization Officers School Officers Examination Orders, Adjutant General, Special, 1905, Abstract of Orders, Adjutant General. Special 1906, Abstract of 137 Orders. Adjutant General, General, 1905, Orders, Adjutant General. General. 1906, Practice Marches Quartermaster Stores drawn in 1906 Records Rifle Practice Rifle Practice. Scores made in Rifle Practice. Orders Covering Roster of Officers Rifleman. List of Rushville Rifles. Camp of San Francisco Earthquake . Supplies shipped to Spanish War Claims Special Orders, 1905. Abstract of Special Orders, 1906, Abstract of Surgeon General, Report of Target KangH Thayer. Governor John M. , death of West Point Rifles, muster out of ion 124. Ml, 146, 150 94 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>