<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1922-11">1922-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">November, 19*22 Bulletin 18-_&gt; Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska H. O. WERNER DEPARTMENT OF HORTICULTURE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">I CONTENTS I'a.- Summary . . Climatic factors influencing potato production — Temperature as a factor in potato production. Rainfall as a factor in Hie production of putat Soil as a factor in l&gt;ctato product! n Commercial potato growing region Plan of variety trial experiment Object of conduct ins the trial Location of the trial plats Varieties used in the trials. . 4 Source of seed of the various varietit For table purposes Varieties for dry land seed production Varieties for the irrigated regions of northwe-itern Wbrask Varieties for relatively heavy and level soils Varieties for light sandy soils Varieties for eastern and central Nebraska v Acknowledgments Method of selecting seed potatoes for continuation of the tria's in Size of plats 'ariat ion within a variety ...17 17 'ariety recommendations Varieties for the dry lain! rvgion-i cf northwestern Xebra -sta- ...24 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. Relatively low temperature during August and Septein- Ut i^ one of t lit' most important factors in producing good seed potato* •J. The U-st seed potato areas of Nebraska are located at an altitude of 4.(HN) feet or more, where the average temperature for tin- seed potato growing season (June 1 to September 30) is below »',7 ■ '■&gt;. (iood seed potatoes can In- produced in the wanner parts if the State if the soil temperature is reduced from ti to 7 . as done by ii straw mulch that is from 3 to 4 inches deep. 4. The July and August rainfall is of most importance in producing a crop of late potatoes in western Nebraska. •*». 'I lie chief commercial potato growing areas of the State lie (lie high altitude (over :'&gt;.(MMI feet) dry land and irrigated regions in the northwestern part, the river valleys of the central mimI eastern part ( IMaite and Republican Rivers), and the north central area (in Brown County). &lt;■&gt;. (ireat differences in yield and quality of tulmrs, between different lots of potatoes of the same variety, were discovered in the comparative trials. These differences were largely due to the climatic and soil conditions under which the various lots were produced as well a- to the prevalence of disease and the differ - ence in seed selection. Much seed potato improvement rpmains to Ih' done with most varieties. Because of the variation exist - ing within a variety, great care should lie exercised in selecting seed potatoes for variety trials. 7. When proper seed selection is practiced, very good seed potatoes can !»■ produced in the dry land areas of western Ne - braska. 8. Irrigation increases the number of potatoes )&gt;er plant. l&gt;ut the increase in yield resulting from irrigation is mostly due to the increase in the size of the tuhi'r-. rather than to an in - crease in the number of tuliers. '.». On dry land the least number of tubers |&gt;cr plant, with greatest weight per tuber, were produced by the Karlv Ohio and Pearl varieties. The Downing and several late varieties pro - duced most tubers |&gt;er plant. 10. I'nder irrigation the greatest number of tubers ]&gt;er plant were produced by the Downing and King varieties, and </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 1&amp;2 the least number per plant by the Early Ohio. The largest tubers were produced by the King and Early Ohio varieties and the smallest by the Downing variety. 11. The number of potato varieties grown in any locality should be reduced to the lowest number possible, consistent with the soil and climate conditions and depending upon whether they are raised for seed or table pur|x&gt;ses. 12. In northwestern Nebraska, in the dry land areas the early varieties. Triumph. Early Ohio, and Irish Cobbler, are most suitable for lioth table and seed purposes. In the North I'latte and White River Valleys. Downing, Rural New Yorker, and Pearl potatoes can be grown for I m &gt;t 1 1 table and seed pur - poses. In dry land area&gt; above 4.(MH) feet, the Downing and Rural New Yorker potatoes are generally too small and imma - ture for table purposes, hut are very good for seed purposes. 13. The Triumph. Rural New Yorker. Downing, and King are especially recommended for the western irrigated regions. The Irish Cobbler is recommended for the Hue sandy &gt;oil&gt; thai are irrigated. 14. In central and eastern Nebraska the Early Ohio is the most reliable variety, but the Irish Cobbler i- worthy of further trial, especially under irrigation. l. r &gt;. Dry land grown pot a toe- have been found to U' -u |K*rior to irrigated potatoes for seed purposes. 1C&gt;. The principal markets for western Nebraska dry land seed potatoes are in the irrigated region- of western Nebraska and Colorado, the eastern and central parts of Nebraska, adjoin - ing Corn Belt States, and the Southern or (iulf State-. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">VARIETIES OF POTATOES FOR NEBRASKA H. O. WERNER DEPARTMENT OF HORTICULTURE The nioNt important factors to be considered in selecting a variety of potatoes for any locality are. adaptation to soil and climatic conditions, susceptibility to disease, and the availability and character of the markets. Other factors to consider are the availability of good seed potatoes of the variety, if seed potatoes cannot U' produced in the locality, and the possibility of develop - ing tlie variety thruout a community. It is the object of this bulletin, and of the variety trials reported in it, to consider most of these various factors as they are related to several important potato varieties, under the conditions prevailing in Nebraska. It is based on established facts or experimental data. CLIMATIC FACTORS INFLUENCING POTATO PRODUCTION TEMPERATURE A8 A FACTOR IN POTATO PRODUCTION The potato crop requires a comparatively cool climate for normal development. For most ideal development the mean daily temperature for the warmest month (generally July) should be below 70° (Fahrenheit) and there should be relatively few excessively hot days. Frequently, if all other conditions are favorable, very high yields of potatoes can be produced in re - gions having an average daily temperature considerably higher than the maximum just mentioned.* However, it is a well - established fact that potatoes produced under those conditions will not be as satisfactory when used for seed purposes the fol - lowing year as those grown in a region having a lower average temperature. Early potatoes can be grown successfully in the Southern States and in the Corn Belt, but to secure satisfactory yields it is necessary for these regions to secure their seed pota - toes from regions where a cooler climate prevails. Such climate is secured by either more northern latitude or higher altitude. Probabiy the temperature during August and September is of more importance in producing good seed potatoes than that * Emerson. R. A.. Rome Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes for Eastern Nebraska. Nebraska Experiment Station Bui. 146. Dec.. 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Expkhimext Station Hi u.ktix 182 during the earlier months. However, at no time &gt;hould it lie sufficiently high to cause a check in the growth of the jilant or to impair plant vigor. The very best seed potatties in Nebraska seem to be produced in the dry land sections of northwestern Nebraska where the normal mean daily teni|&gt;erature from June 1st to Septemlier 30th is about •&gt;&lt;&gt; or less (fig. 1). At Lincoln, during 7 years. Emerson found that |M&gt;tatoe.s grown by ordinary methods of cultivation produced - 24 per cent less when used for seed purposes the following year than pota - toes grown in cooler regions, such as the Red River Valley of Fig. 1. — Normal isotherm map of Nebraska for the late potato crop reason (June 1 to Sept. 30), based on temperature records taken at I". S. Weather Bureau observation stations for a period of ten years or more. Good seed potatoes can be produced on dry land west of th« isotherm. South and east of the 70° isotherm it is advisable each year to secure seed potatoes from a region of lower average tempera - ture. ( Location of trial plats indicated by dots. &gt; the North. However, he also found tliat potatoes grown under a thick mulch of straw, when used as seed potatoes the following year, produced practically a&gt; well ih the potatoes direct from the more favorable regions. Thermograph ic records taken during the summer of llhil at Lincoln show that the mean daily tem - lierature of the cultivated soil surrounding a hill of potatoes and at a depth of 4 inches was 71.4 for the |&gt;eriod from April 15th to August 28. During the same |&gt;eriod the mean daily tempera - ture of the soil at a depth of 4 inches, under a mulch :\ to 4 inches deep, was 64.4°, or 7° less than in the case of the cultivated soil. (See figure 2.) During the same period of time the air tempera- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Vakiktiks ok Potatoes koi; Nebraska 7 ture recorded by the thermograph located 1 foot above the ground \\a&gt; 71.1 . (These mean temperatures are calculated from the temperatures recorded every % 2 hours thruout the entire period.) Evidently the average decrease of '21' \&gt;er cent in the yielding ability of potatoes produced in a cultivated soil at Lincoln as com- t'd with that of potatoes produced under a straw mulch is due to the higher average temperature of 7° in the cultivated soil. Fig. 2. Thermograph used to secure air and soil temperature for mulched and cultivated potato plats at Lincoln in 1921. A large metal bulb filled with liquid is buried at a depth of four inches between the two white stakes at 'he extreme left. This bulb is connected to the re - cording apparatus in the shelter by means of a hollow flexible tube. Th-- record is based on the expansion and contraction of the liquid in the bulb and tube. High altitude in western Nebraska i&gt; the principal cause of the low mean temperature during the growing season. The maximum altitude for this region is about 5,250 feet, whereas in the southeastern part of Nebraska the altitude is just below l.(HN) feet. (See figure 3.) It is estimated that potatoes make practically no growth, if any. at temperatures Mow 43° F.* "Daily effective tempera- • Smith. J. Warren. The Effect of Weather Upon the Yield of Potatoes. Potato Mainline. April. 1919. p. IS. |iart </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nkbraska Kxpeuimkm Station Hi i.i.ktin !*•_' 8 ture" i- the term applied to the excess of the daily mean tem - perature above 43 C F. The sum of all these "daily effective tem - peratures"' for the period the potatoes are growing is considered the "total effective temperature." The total effective tempera - ture offers a good means of arriving at the relative value, for seed purposes, of the potatoes produced. The normal effective temperature for the four months June to September inclusive in Fiu. 3. — Altitude variation (in feet) in Nebraska (after Warren i. The altitude ranges from less than 1,000 feet in the southeastern part of the State to more than 5,250 feet in the southwestern part i Kimball County). Most of the late commercial potato area is located above 4,000 feet altitude, except in Sheridan County where the increased latitude compensates for lower altitude. (See figures 1 and .', i the northwestern part of the State ranges from -2.794 = (at Hay Springs) to 3.038° (at Scottsbluff. Bridge|K&gt;rt. and probably Chadron) (see Table 2). Regions of slightly higher temperature prevail in western Nebraska in the North Platte Valley (in Morrill and Scotts Bluff Counties) and in the White River Valley in the northern part of Dawes County. This is largely the result of the rela - tively lower altitude existing at these points. (See Table 1 and figures 1 and 3.) The temperature in these localities is. how - ever, favorable for potato production (l&gt;oth table and seed stock). </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Varieties &gt;K 1'oTATOE Nebraska 9 it* Tabi.k 1. — LtMnt/i/ii. altitude, unil soil type i&gt;f the variety trial /i/atg. (The same 10 varieties were used at each trial point.) 23 21 52 Morrill MM Loub 3 4,670 Pine sandy loam k.ni 15 54 Kimball ;l KASTEMN AND ( ENTHA1 SKHRASKA I NOT lUIKiATBI) Lancaster 1 .200 Silt loam :l K.a Buffalo 2.150 Silt loam :l Ni.rmal temperature and rainfal. data fur various Mai points a« taken from nearest Weather Bureau station are given in Table 2. RAINFALL AS A FACTOR IK THE PHODICT1ON OF POTATOES With all Held crop* grown in Nebraska, rainfall is a limit - ing factor. The seasonal requirements of the potato crop are somewhat different from thorn of other crops as they aiv grown in i iortli western Nebraska. The amount of rainfall during the pwwing season, especially during the middle and latter part of the potato prowing season (from mid July to mid September in northwestern Nebraska), is the most important. The potato yield depends very largely upon the amount of moisture in the xiil during ilu- time. It is during this jwriod that irrigation water is applied. .V high percentage of soil moisture is not especially necessary during the early part of the growing season. The potato crop can probably withstand the effects of a mid - summer drought batter than the other crops raised in this region. providing the temperature i&gt; not too high. It is. of course, very essential that weeds be kept down so the potato plants will be able to utilize all the soil moisture without outside competition. p PoM OHlce Sec- tion Approx- 1 Town- Range County imat«* Soil type ship altitude No. of years trial conducted Bu»&gt; nell 24 WUTUN NKWA8KA MY LAND PLAT! 14 58 Kimball 5,200 Loam 3 l'had-on 25 33 48 Dawes 3,400 Very fine aandy loam 3 Angora 28 22 50 Morrill 4,000 Very sandy loam 3 Alliance 8 25 47 Box Butte 4,000 Silt loam (Jordon 33 33 41 Sheridan 3,550 Fine aandy luam 1 Kushville Morn 1 1 :ll 27 32 44 Sheridan 3,700 Very fine sandy loam WESTERN NEBRASKA IRRIGATED PLATS 24 57 Sioux 4,100 Very fine aandy loam 1 3 M mature 20 22 52 Scotts Bluff 4.050 Very fine aand 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Xkbrask.v Experiment Station Hii.i.ktin 1m' Table 2. — Trin/HfituiT mid ruinf&lt;iH &lt;it \Y rut her Huremi i&gt;hx, rru tion atutitm* located nun tri'il pint*. Normal temperature 1 Normal rainfall June 1 to Sept. 30 '"Normal temperature' is average temperature recorded since the fstablishmt Weather Bureau station and represents a p-'riod of tt-n year* or mor*. -Data for several trial points are not available, ao records of nearest puinu are fi NEAREST OBSERVATION APPROXIMATK [&gt;!8TANCt 'Normal temperature and rainfall data not fiven for (hadron because record has not been kept for 10 years. Temperature similar to Scottsbluff and Bridgeport and rainfall similar to Hay Springs. Smith.* from the data of \Yood&gt;. ami Briggr&gt; and Shantz. esti - mates that approximately &lt;&gt; inches of rainfall is required for it 200-bnshel (j&gt;er acre) crop of potatoes. This is assuming that the entire &lt;i inches of rainfall i&gt; utilized by the crop. The con - dition of the soil (whether it i&gt; cultivated x&gt; a&gt; to retluce the ritn-olf) and the presence or altsence of wee&lt;ls are important factors in governing the extent to which the rainfall can be utilized by the plant for tulnr production. The average yearly • Smith. J. Warren. The Effect of Weather Upon the Yield of Potatoes. Potato Macaiine April. 1919. p. IS. Observation point Altitud ie Mean Total daily effective From June 1 to Sept. 30 From Oct. 1 to May 31 Feet Degree* F. Degree* F. Inches Inchex Kimball 4,697 66.7 2,892 7.37 8.51 Bridgeport 1 3,658 67.8 3.026 7.38 8.47 Scottsbluff- 3,888 67.9 3,03s 7.36 8.53 Mitchell- 3,950 66.8 2,904 7.90 7.18 Chadron 3 3,371 Hay Springs 3,821 65.9 2,794 8.72 11.28 Gordon 3,550 66.0 2,806 7.94 9.21 Kearney 2,148 71.9 3,526 13.73 12.48 Lincoln 1,189 72.5 3,599 14.4 12.79 K1A1. POINT Bushnt-ll Anform Kushvillp Merrill Minatare Bayard STATION Kimball Bridgeport Hay Springs, Gordon Mitchell ScotUblufT Bridfeport KKOM IKIAI 20 miW~ 2(1 mil— 17 miles 12 milm 16 miles 18 miles </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Yariktiks ok Potatof.s fih: Nebraska 11 rainfall in Nebraska diminishes from 32 inches in tin- southeast - ern part uf the State to Hi inches or less in the western part, as indicated in figure 4. The amount of rainfall during the grow - ing season is of more significance than the yearly rainfall. The rainfall (hiring the four months of the potato season is reported in Talile -2. The data in this table are based on the records of the weather stations near the various trial points. The average or normal rainfall during the growing season for the various point- in the northwestern part of the State ranges from 7.36 inches to s.7 - J inches, (iood crops of potatoes can be produced Flu. 4. — Average annual precipitation for the different sections of Ne - braska (inches). Based on average rainfall at 17. S. Weather Bureau observation stations for a period of ten years or more. (From Nebr. Research Bui. 19.) in a region having an annual precipitation of from 14 to 15 inches or more, if a minimum of (&gt; to 7 inches comes during the growing season, especially the middle or latter part. Good methods of dry land fanning and the selection of the proper variety are essential under droughty conditions. It seems quite evident that a large amount of water is undesirable for the pro - duction of good seed potatoes. We have considerable data that will lie published 'later which indicate that quite generally irri - gation reduces the productiveness of seed potatoes from 10 to 25 j&gt;er cent or more. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin l$'2 SOIL AS A FACTOR IN POTATO PRODUCTION Tubers of desirable quality cannot Ik&gt; produced in all soils. The physical characteristics of the soil are of most importance in so far as the type or sha|&gt;e of the tubers is concerned: while fertility, together with the amount of moisture available, is of greatest importance in determining total yield. A relatively nigh percentage of sand is desirable in a soil intended for potato production. A high percentage of clay is very undesirable, as it interferes with normal t niter development, tho some varie - ties can develop good tubers more easilv under -uch conditions than others. Fig. 5. — Distribution of potato acreage in Nebraska in 1921. represents 100 acres. (Based on 1921 crop report of Slat.- I of Agriculture. ) Kac-h d nt COMMERCIAL POTATO GROWING REGIONS OF NEBRASKA The total acreage devoted to potatoes in Nebraska ii was 102,074 acres, on which were produced S.ltMMNX) bushels of potatoes, at the rate of !&gt;&lt;'&gt; bushels per acre. During the 10-ywar period 1!&gt;1J to IM1, tlie trenge potato acreage was !MJ.(tt:j acres and average total production 7.!&gt;7o.s&lt;l| bushels. Potatoes can !*■ grown and are being grown in every county in the State. How - ever, due to soil, climatic, or market condition- or a combination of these, some parts of the State are very well adapted to the growing of the crop on a commercial scale, whereas some other parts of the State are very unsuitable. (See figure •"•. t The greatest commercial potato growing area in the State is in northwestern Nebraska where the altitude is high (over 3.."&gt;00 feet) and the temperature consequently low. Here the potatoes </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Varieties &lt;&gt;k Potatoes for Nebraska 13 arc grown a&gt; late potatoes The crop is produced commercially and on an extensive scale on dry land in Sheridan. Dawes, Box Butt-. Sioux. Scott- Bluff. Morrill, and Kimball Counties and on irrigated land in Sioux (southern part), Scotts Bluff. Mor - rill. ami Kimball Counties. Most of the crop from this part of the State is shipped from the Held in curlots to distant points as table (or eating) potatoes in September and ()ctol&gt;er. or from tlic storage cellar a&gt; late as the following May. A special seed potato industry is developing in the dry land regions. This industry is especially active in the highest alti - tude regions of the State, above 4,000 feet, where the average daily temperature of the potato growing season is Itelow 67°. When the altitude approaches 5,000 feet, the daily mean tem - perature drops to 66°. (See figure 1.) The temperature in this region is 7° to 8° lower than in the southeastern part of the State. This is about the difference in soil temperature found to exist at Lincoln lietween straw mulched and cultivated soils, which difference was shown to be responsible for the fact that straw mulched potatoes are superior for seed purposes. The seed potato industry has developed rapidly in western Nebraska as a result of the brisk demand for seed based on yield perform - ance and the improvement of the quality thru the establishment of a &gt;eeil potato certification service. The early potato region supplying the commercial market during August and September and sometimes to some extent in Julv is located in the Platte Valley. At present the greatest commercial early potato producing region is in the vicinity of Kearney. The industry is rapidly developing east and west from Kearney and promises within a few years to be an impor - tant industry- in the Platte Valley across the entire State (and possibly also in the Republican River Valley). The use of irri - gation water and soils that have a water table close to the sur - face assure sufficient moisture for the production of relatively lane yields in this region. It is most desirable to have potatoes follow alfalfa as a means of producing large yields in this region. It is very important to secure new seed potatoes from the north or west each year, as the temperature in eastern and central Nebraska is too high for the development of good seed tul&gt;ers. — averaging higher than 70° during the season (fig. 1). The varieties seem to be limited to Early Ohio and Irish Cob - bler. Hot days, especially hot windy days, during late June and July, are probably the most serious uncontrollable factor limit - ing profitable production of potatoes in the Platte Valley. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">NkBKASKA K.XI'KRIMKNT STATION Hi I.l.KTIX 18'2 14 Storage is not advisable in this region, because the early market (Julv and August) is generally l»est. Each year several hundred carloads of potatoes are produced in north central Nebraska, principally in Brown County. These potatoes go to the market in September, between the Platte Val - ley crop and the heavy movement of the late crop. No irriga - tion is used in this region. The Early Ohio is practically the only variety grown. Thruout northeastern Nebraska the various communities buy in the aggregate several hundred cars of potatoes each year. In view of this fact the commercial production of potatoes can l&gt;e greatly increased in this region, where climatic conditions are reasonably favorable. New seed |M&gt;tatoes from cooler regions should probably be secured every few years, especially after al &gt;- normallv hot season-. A large quantity of potatoes is produced on small areas for sale in wagon lots at local markets in all parts of the State. These l&lt;K*al fields are generally depended upon to supply the &lt;l&lt; - mand l&gt;efore the late crop i- on the market. Thrnout most &lt;&gt;f southeastern Nebraska the climate and most of the soik are not favorable to potato production. However, in tlii&gt; region many of the river bottom soil- are desirable, especially along the Platte. Republican, and Missouri River-. Thruout tlii- part of the State, potatoes should l&gt;e planted very early, so that most tuber growth will have taken place l&gt;efore the middle of July. PLAN OF VARIETY TRIAL EXPERIMENTS OBJECT OF CONDl'CTINU THE TRIALS The variety problem has l&gt;een a perplexing one to potato growers in Nebraska. In the early potato producing areas and in the irrigated regions many of the difficult ic- encountered have l&gt;een due to the use of improper varieties. In 1!U!&gt;. variety trials were inaugurated at various points ii Nebraska — 1. To determine the i&gt;i'-t varieties of |&gt;otatoes for the mi otis parts of the State: a. Western dry land region: 1). Western irrigated region c. Eastern and central irrigated regions. d. Southern and eastern unirrigated region 2. To determine the possibilities of growing seed potatoes - of good quality of the various varieties for local use and for shipping to other parts of the State or to other states. 3. To study the effect of various condition-, as moisture </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Varieties of Potatoes run Nebraska 15 temperature, etc. upon Che yield and quality of the varieties at the several points in each region. 4. T&lt;&gt; study the variations existing within a variety due to soil, climate. -*-ed selection, disease, or other causes. LOCATION OF THE TRIAL PLATS The trial plat&gt; were located on various farms operated by good, representative potato growers. Most of the plats were located in the western part of the State. The object of scatter - ing the plats was to try the varieties under the various climatic, soil, and cultural conditions prevailing in Nebraska in regions where potatoes are an important commercial crop. The legal location of the farms on which the variety trials were conducted, the approximate altitude, and the soil type are given in Table 1. The trial points are also indicated on the isotherm map in figure 1. The range in seasonal mean tempera - ture ;it the various points is from less than 66° (Bushnell) to 7-_' or more (Lincoln and Kearney), with a normal effective teiujxrature of from less than 2,800° to more than 3,500° for the period from June 1st to September 30th. VARIETIES USED IN THE TRIALS Ten standard varieties were selected for the trials, each va - riety representing a distinct type of potatoes. Eight of the eleven &gt;tandard variety groups, as suggested in the classification system by Stuart.* were represented in the trials by these ten varieties. (This classification system is based on tuber, sprout, and vine characteristics.) Each variety used is of major impor - tance in some part of the United States and is recognized as a distinct varietv. The varieties used in the trials and the groups they repre - sent are: T . . , „ Variety Group Triumph Triumph Earlv Ohio Earlv Ohio Irish Cobbler Cobbler Dowsing Early Michigan Pearl Rural New Yorker Russet Rural New Yorker Green Mountain (ireen Mountain (Sec. 1) Burhank Kusset Rurhank Kin* Rose •U. S. D. A. Bui. 176. Sept.. 1918. Group Classification and Variety Description! of Some American Potatoes. Wm. Stuart. Pearl Hum] (Sec. 1) Hural (8k. $) </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Kxi'kkimk.m Station I5i i.i.ktin 1v_! The varieties were arranged in each of the plats in the order named. (A detailed description of the various varieties is •riven in Table :5. The varieties are illustrated from figure- fi to 1* inclusive.) SOIRCE OF SEED OF THE VARIOl 8 VARIETIES The source of the seed potatoes used in a variety trial is of utmost importance. The climate, soil condition, plant diseases, culture, storage, and seed selection practiced, all exert an influ - ence upon the yielding capacity of the seed potatoes. (See Tallies 4. ."&gt;. and 6.) In thex' trial- every effort was made to eliminate as many of these sources of error a&gt; possible. The original seed stix-k of each variety was secured from the region in which tliat variety was recognized ;i&gt; being of major importance and well adapted to the conditions. In the case of each variety an effort was made to select for foundation stock the l»est strain of the variety available. Five bushels of the original seed stock of each variety were shipped to Lincoln. All seed potatoes of each variety were treated with corrosive sublimate solution. The potatoes of each variety were divided into lots of -20 pounds each. — one lot of every variety for each trial point. In this way the seed |H&gt;tatoes used in all trial plats were as nearly identical a&gt; it was practically possible to secure them. Several lots of seed from different sources, of ead eral varieties, were planted. This was done for the purpose of determining to what extent the foundation stock for the experi - ment represented the productive condition of the variety. ;il-&lt;&gt; to what extent variations existed within a variety a&gt; a result of climatic or soil conditions, seed selection, or disease. These strain tests were frequently conducted on the same farm with the variety trials. METHOD OF SELECTING SEED POTATOES FOR CONTINl'ATION OF TRIALS Seed potatoes of each variety, for the following season, were selected from the best hills (generally the best 10 hills i that could be located in each variety plat. These potatoes were all stored under the same conditions on the farm where they wen - grown or were to be planted the following season. In each of the dry land points, seed potatoes have lieen continually selected from the potatoes grown at that point. In the irrigated plat - the 1020 crop was raised from potatoe- produced in the respec - tive plats of 1919. In 1921 all irrigated plats were planted with </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Yakiktiks or Potavow FOR N~K1»KASKA 17 |«»tat(H'&gt; grown on dry land at Buslinell since 1919. At Kearney iiinl Lincoln tin- 1!&gt;2&lt;I ami l'&gt;21 crop-, were produced from west - era dry land grown &gt;eed. SIZE OF PLATS Iii 1919 and li'-jo practically all plantings of each variety at cadi trial point consisted of 1 40th acre plats. In 1921 the plat- on irrigated land contained 1 l(H)th acre and on dry land 1 50th •ere. On dry land the rows were generally 314 feet apart with hills Is to inches apart in the row. In the irri- gated plats the rows were from 3 to 31/. feet apart with the hills 16 inches apart in the row. VARIATION WITHIN A VARIETY In Tables 4 to 7 are given the results secured in representa - tive tt'st&gt; of a number of lots of seed of Triumph and Early Ohio varieties at nine points. These trials were conducted in 1919, H'-JO. and 1921. Similar tests were conducted at other places. Imt the results are not shown here as they were very sim - ilar to those in the tables given. There was a very wide range in the yield secured from the various lot&gt; of potatoes of any variety. At Hayard in 1919 (Table 4) the lowest lot yielded at the rate of 241.5 bushels per acre and the highest producing lot yielded at the rate of 306.5 bushels of I*. S. (irade No. 1 potatoes. This is a range of 115 bushels |H*r acre in the yield of the same variety of potatoes, but coining from different sources. All lots included in the trial were supposed to be high yielding lots from the various state&gt;. On dry land at Alliance the range in yield with these same 13 lots of Triumph potatoes was from 34 bushels to 75.9 bushels of (irade No. 1 potatoes. When \\l western Nebraska grown lots of Triumph potatoes were planted in Scotts Illuff County (Table 0). the range in yield of Grade No. 1 tul&gt;ers was from 148.3 bushels to 231.7 bushels, a difference of N3.4 bushels per a&lt;Te. The same 12 lots planted at Lincoln had a relatively greater range. — from 19.2 bushels to 51.5 bushels |&gt;er acre. (Conditions at Lincoln were very unfavorable for Triumph potatoes in 1921.) Similar variations in yield were secured with nine lots of Early Ohio potatoes procured in Box Iiutte County (where they had been grown for many years) and planted at Alliance in </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Kxi'kki.mkm Station Hii.i.ktin 1m-J 18 &gt;- X- jl jjtlljj | jjl I j |f I " I 111 jfli h i\ MIS til it I XI M ill . I ■** 5- I i iJi Jii » a mm sg 5; 5 5.5 IB A ! i si it n - »• fe s I i"J -^1 -J *J «^£ lit ill ill ill lit 1 ii * ---' I « * *;« at at at a * s - 1 s z &gt;. ■*^ i^ •S £ -- !|^ i=* lit ill lit I ill e« le-e Je^ 'si iU 1 III iff fe, 3 t s s j J, , Ul 1 W i Jft |gt in ir iJii in lit i i ih M mi h A i - r- *«s 511 &gt;6-i i^s iJ lsi 9 i;;^ I I i ill Ii i it I jfii jH i 5 ,1 Jli *B «? I II III li I rt = Jill 11 «. s^ » a laf* iP* i ii»io i«« 2 i jSSj ill iif J J liii W |SI ii 4 4 - = I III llllj « HH z'- I «f jii m flii = 5^.5. i /, ■ ■ = / x </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Varieties ok Potatoes for Nebraska 19 t &lt;£• op IX i fa I Ml 4 I J» IJ*s il I it A i i« P ill | » I II III I JijH Ji 1 jlf i| t j| r- * &amp;~" I £ I ill II III 111 II! ? KB F* £*■ ;3ii a* ii i j isj i# a ? j-«' g ia n ■ * Ii - I 1 J II l '; m i in e* = Ii -5 = 5 is. ill mm* 1_J? I" ill i </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 182 w ceo *_ »«5N «t-;Cvl TO US O e^ O I.* 3 2 O 35U5t~ -*CCCC OU5O TON 00 «O : O S — OZ r ~*- ( - t-ooao »oe* xc- f- S » — o t- ?1 X l- i 5 IS .O N»- 3: — 7] 103Z n«n n3« 71 r? — m - * ? *. e: - V • a i 8 s s a a s a I ■*■** **^ 7.7.7. 00 S « iii III ?V? £ *- — -= * 5. ■ - : • ■ : ■* * : -5 ? * ii 1 in hi a jh a 1I1 HI Hi !i 1 1 ■1 H E S I" "*|Z rt M« -fiato t-x» o-. » s &gt; &lt; ? b t -S-s m -"*-'°- x . t -.'°. *.«?» "*- o ■• t- - s S S5?J SSS SSj: 5S 5 g 3 I j 1 11- 1 h i « Si S5S SSS Sg£ » » = I 8 5 &amp; } -5 1 1 • I 8^*2 - •!•*•! C^O X (C n » 4 i?la( »&amp;s ss§? s$» ss s s 5 1- 1 5 ■ — i — — L i, C 2 :/r tj-«~ r] _^ C • lt*&gt;i W 09 « ««~ Ill =3 X •S-g-g iii .1.1.1 J.i I £ ZZZ Z2Z £££ SSS2 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska 21 I I able ."&gt;. — Com pa rat ire trial, in IUJI. of irextern Xebraxka certi - fied Tiiiiin /ih xi ril potatoes produced in 1920. ahi.k (&gt;. Variation in yield and quality of xcnnil lots of Early Okie xi ill jnitntocx. Al/ittnrr. 1919. (All lots of seinl from Box Butte Countv.) No. of years Yield in bushels per acre -■ot No. grown in [j£ Town County 13 Bu«hn.-I] Kimball Yield in buaheb point Per cent of tubers , i dU. 8. Grade U. 8. Grade No. 1 Total yield I No. 1 ScotuBluff ,. . SrotuBluff ,. . 8cottt Bluff ExpM Farm Lincoln Expi Farm L" 1 ™ 1 " Expl Farm Uncoln 180.0 45.8 1*8.0 W.8 j M.» 66.6 19 Hu.hn.-ll Kimball 171.7 22.8 187.2 i 4S.1 »1.7 50.3 20 Bushnell Kimball 185.0 45.1 207.1 73.0 89.3 61.8 21 Kimball Kimbmll 206.7 47.0 2T7J 65.9 91.0 ! 71.:) 22 Kimb.ll Kimball 195.0 30.4 210.4 47.4 91.2 64.1 23 Mimlud IHwn 231.7 | 19.2 242J S7.1 95.5 61.7 24 Sidney Cheyenne 148.3 27.2 ! 176.0 57.3 84.2 47.4 ■ Chadron Htm 235.0 47.4 21* I 72.0 94.7 65.7 2« Chadron l&gt;awe« 195.0 51.5 211.0 73.9 92.5 69.6 ■ Glen Sioux 161.7 28.2 ' 176.2 Mi j HJ 77.8 27 Hfiningford Box Butte 156.7 15.7 177.0 38.4 } 88.6 40.8 ■ Chadron Dawea 106.7 219.9 M.« I L/&gt;t N 4o. grown in county U. S. Grade No. 1 Total Per cent U. S. Grade No. 1 2 15 57.4 79.8 71.9 8 7 86.6 108.0 80.1 4 6 82.6 100.0 82.6 I 6 52.0 74.6 69.7 I 5 49.3 69.4 71.0 7 22 42.7 62.5 68.2 8 8 47.8 72.0 66.4 9 7 69.4 88.0 78.9 10 6 52.0 66.7 78.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 XkIIKASKA KxPKRIMKXT STATION Hi I.I.KTIN 18*2 l'.'l'.i. (Table l&gt;.) The high yielding lot (Xo. :i) traces from high yielding hills selected in the field in 1!U7. The next lot in point of yield ( Xo. 4) was from u grower that planted the best type tul&gt;ers each year. The other lots received no selection, while some were propagated each year from culls. Great varia- Tabi.e 7. — Strain textx of Early Ohio potatoes, I'.tja xea*on. YieU in biaaeis per acre Source of seed Per CMt U. S. Grade No. 1 U. S. Grade No. 1 Total yield KBAKNBY, KlfKt.r COUNTY IIMUGATKD Sheridan County, Nebr Box Butt* County. Nebr Moorehead, Minn 151.5 205.6 737 Mi 70.4 162.6 214.4 71.0 152.1 Glyndon, Minn 2« i ■ 76 1 Kearney, Nebr. (1 year) Kearney, Nebr. (29 yean us.i 165.4 Sti.l 4 100.1 VAUXY, 1 IG1JU I III &gt;.T1 Sheridan County, Nebr Clay County, Minn Clay County, Minn Clay County, Minn ni ■fcl Dnmtoi County, Nebr. il yeari IM HAY SnUSliK, SHEKIIIAN .1,1 NTY Hay Sprints, Nebr Hay Springs, Nebr Gordon, Nebr 161.0 130.1 141.0 iau 143.0 M.4 Gordon, Nebr Alliance, Nebr Ulen, Minn ... 102. 115. 146.U r.i.ii 147.0 &lt;*. 136.0 85.0 Moorehead. Minn UK." ■C-OTTl! BI.UFf COUNTY {IBJIIUATBD Scotts Bluff County, dry land L'yv: 412.5 72.4 Seotu Bluff County, irrigated 4 yean ScotU Bluff County, dry land 250. 1 92.9 ■I -, M.4 Scotts Bluff County, irrigated 3 yean Scotts Bluff County, irrigated 2 yean 241.0 75.3 24.;. i 314.2 75 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Yahiktikm ok Potatoes kok Nebraska 23 tions in yield of Early Ohio potatoes at four widely scattered trial points are shown in Table 7. Similar variations in yield, some greater than any here re - ported, were Hewed within varieties when many lots of Irish Cobbler, Downing, Rural New Yorker. Early Ohio, Peachblow. and Triumph potatoes were planted in comparative plats. Sev - eral times the difference in yield of two lots of the same variety in the same plat exceeded 200 bushels |&gt;er acre. Variations in the tuber type and market quality were almost as great as the yield variations. These yield variations are the result of many causes, all of which cannot l»e explained here. Low yielding lots within a variety are frequently the result of unfavorable climate, such as too high temperature, where the Heed potatoes were produced ('2 Kearney lots in Table 7) : lack of proper seed selection or, fre - quently, the planting of culls: disease injury or diseased seed -tock: storage conditions: maturity or immaturity of the seed l»&gt;t;itoe&gt;: or sometimes soil conditions unfavorable for the pro - duction of good seed tubers (such as irrigation). Irrigation of -eed potatoes has an injurious effect upon the yielding ability of the &gt;tock. The production of good seed potatoes is not limited to any one state, as shown by the yields reported in Tables 4 and 7; neither is it limited to any one county or community, as shown especially by Tables 4 and ."&gt;. A suitable climate is the first e-sential for the production of good seed potatoes. However, it i- not sufficient if other factors, such as seed selection or disease control, are ignored (as illustrated in Table 4 and especially in Tables •"&gt; and &lt;&gt;. where great variations existed even tho all -eed potatoes were produced under favorable climatic condi - tions). That western Nebraska dry land grown potatoes when properly grown are equally as good as similar lots from Minne - sota. Wisconsin, and other states is shown in Tables 4 and 7. The data in Tables 4 to 7 and manv data as yet unpublished emphasize the necessity of l&gt;eing very cautious in the selection &lt;&gt;f the -&gt;ced stock that is to represent any variety in a variety trial, or the results may Ih&gt; verv misleading. Several good lots or rtrauM of each variety could well be used in a variety trial. In the trials herein reported on. the particular lots selected for each variety were found to l&gt;e representative of the better lots of wed of the variety, llv growing all seed potatoes under the same conditions, the variations due to effect of climate on the xeed stock were probably eliminated after the first year. Lack </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station Rm.i.ktix 182 of uniformity in the seed stock was eliminated by the adoption of a uniform system of selection at each plat for each variety. The presence of disease was uniformly reduced to a minimum as far as possible in all lots by uniform selection of sound seed, and consequently was not an important factor in the comparative results. Uniform storage in all lots planted at any one place eliminated another common source of error. The accompanying summary table (No. s) is published for the purpose of showing the relative results secured with the various varieties at the several representative trial plats. VARIETY RECOMMENDATIONS A large number of varieties of potatoes should not In - grown in any one locality. A few standard varieties should l&gt;e used so bs to facilitate the improvement of the seed used thruout the lomlity. to simplify storage, ami in simplify marketing. Sometimes one or two varieties are sufficient. In other localities it may l&gt;e desirable to grow several varieties because of differ - ences in soil or growing conditions (dry land or irrigation). The recommendations herewith are based on the experiinent - referred to anil upon general observation-. In Table 8 are given the averages of the results of the |&gt;otato trials (ten varieties! conducted at the two dry laud and three irrigated points named. In Table '.' are given results of some tul&gt;er formation studies. These were representative trial points in that they received good culture and represent variou- condi- i.d tions. As there are great variations in soil in any locality and great variations in temperature and rainfall from year to vear as well as considerable variation in the lot- of seed of the same variety, these results cannot be considered a- finally answering the variety question. However, they serve as a general guide to the possibilities of the varieties in the different parts of the State. (The detailed results for each year from each trial point are not given liecause of the amount of space they would con - sume.) Detailed variety descriptions are given in Table :'.. Tin varieties are illustrated in figures &lt;"&gt; to IS inclusive. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Vakiktiks of Potatoes mi: Nebraska 25 »t-;C -■ X £ » © m ■"•'. * s * 53* -" K» Ml Hi K -" --. S8? §S •ONtt MX 'N sjac; »s x- -C 35 s gg» 18*: |g o x 'c o&gt; — -~ a « £5 ! SI swi 34 xi * 2'* H ?1 ■ * ■« » 3; co-^»^ t-« ■♦ •*? ss3 sasss? iiS sits niS g23 .-r£:? ■W N-^ WN i^ SS? 2=3 88S5 522 ill Hi *U I I JIJ f »~ ;p:§~ E d|s =§5 {&lt; ft* * &gt; "S £ S3 10 , i -»*=. ' -•=» «-» oo^- .-^ &gt; | | ss? 3** p&gt; 8 H 8 Si* Sa^lli^ t »N« aos -.»» *• -.OSi; ao-» oot-~ ■-- S3 tSS ! fc» I sp tii iti &lt; " N ""* "N SI- | = P« iii I$3 g S s S iiS i^jii? i HV . — i h — ■Si " %°-^!- &lt;e .-. t »m* «« 9«s z w^;'; avglo. iii * ! Sl* 2£* «S* .| 1J | g« ii«|9S* a sP sP i&lt; !gp j S -: I »«.«. »9». ! ■« 5 -5 sr:** as,-: |is ||5 3ss s§;; |p -C j xt-i SStX ox aa ac : — us -* 8SS£ 5p SS5: P-J! 38«* |S? ( SSI 2SSS S5 I" ffil; Hf :-ii ;-j Mi :-| Ijj U\ ■w 111 1 6 5 lu lh U* lit lo s i - 5sUs h 1 rt 1 i^ 1 rt« rtl rtl S5« :z -s -sins _:? _t Inli istfg I &amp; 111 IJi Hi felh IfcSi It H rl S - 15 I 1 1 1 If? « I i f! * 5 i&lt;* s s 5 IS P I ! ?i ii i! ~ ? i 5 3 I^-B i I i_ S *jl ""i* 5 . •••'! i •ooi'- oooo* t-t--, O..-T </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Kxi'krimkxt Station Bcixetin !&gt;■_' Tabi.k 9. — Tuber production ttudiex. Areragt number of tuber* per hill, average weight per hi/1, and averagt weight of tubers of ten varieties, at tiro dry hi ml /»&gt;intx (Angora in 1919. Bushtwll 1920) and two irrigated point* (Bayard 1919, Morrill 1920), on ba*i* of total production from )&lt;&gt; hilh of each variety in each plat. As irrigation did not start till after the tubers had formed or about the time of forming there is but little difference in the number of tubers per hill in the irrigated and dry land plats The increase in yield from irrigation resulted mostly from the greater size attained by irrigated potatoes and only to a small extent from heavier setting of tubers. The Downing set more tubers per bill than any other variety. The Early Ohio and Pearl set relatively few tubers per hill under irrigation. The King, Early Ohio, and Pearl had the highest average per tuber weight, while the Downing averaged the lowest. Tubers of the late varieties on dry land were not able to develop as much size as the early varieties. This would handicap them for table purposes but not for seed purposes. VARIETIES FOR THE DRY LAND REC.IONS OF NORTHWESTERN NEBRASKA i Sheridan to Cheyenne County and west Early Ohio. — For table purposes the most popular variety in the dry land sections of northwestern Nebraska ( es|K»cially Sheridan and Box Butte Counties) i- the Early Ohio. La-t year the car lot shipments of thi&gt; variety in Nebraska exceeded those of any other variety. This variety has. however, been sur - passed in yield in the variety trials l&gt;\ Itoth the Triumph and the Irish Cobbler (see Table S). The pwtfc of the Early Ohio is very easily checked by adverse conditions, resulting in knobby, cull potatoes when growth is resumed. (See per cent marketable potatoes. Table H.) The amount of U»th knobby |&gt;otatoe- and FOR TABI-E Pl'RPOSES Variety Average number of tuber, per hill Dryland Irrigated Average waigkt per winpouZi) Dry land Irrigated I 1 • ■ _^ Average weignt per tuber (ouacai) Dry land Irrigated rriumpk . 4.M S.M .M l.M 3.50 S.M Early Ohio .1 4.17 it* 1.11 1.SX t 4.41 6.83 rish Cobbler Mi Mi 1.20 2.1» 1.21 5.82 Downing CM n.27 1.S7 I'.nl S.01 3.87 &gt;«rl M «4 1.53 Ml 5.63 6.40 tural New Yorker Mi 1.2* 2.18 3.36 6.12 tuaet Rural New Yorker 6.41 5.95 1.32 2.48 2.05 5.86 "■reen Mountain 6.34 7.01 l.M 2.64 2.58 5.37 tuwt Burbank . j 4.14 Mi l.M Mi 3.69 5.39 *9~~ I venae of 10 varieties . . . C.4K 7.»1 J! 6.41 S.22 1.17 1.2:1 T«6 «7 2.S0 7. ii: a.*» </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Varieties of Potatoes kor Nebraska 27 Mai) can Ih- reduced by late planting. It seems to 1h&gt; more sus - ceptible to !x&gt;th powdery dry rot injury and common scab than the other varieties. The variety has a tendency to set relatively few - potatoes per hill, lender favorable conditions these are often ex - cessively large (Table !&gt;)• It is probably best adapted to the con - ditions in the extreme northern part of northwestern Nebraska. This i&gt; probably due to slightly more rainfall and the greater cer - tainty of rainfall during July and August in this northern section. This variety undoubtedly has a permanent place in western Ne - braska, but it should not l&gt;e accepted as unquestionably the liest Fig. 6.— A good type of Early Ohio potato for the dry land regions, as other varieties have shown considera - ble merit. There is an established market for the Early Ohio potatoes thruout eastern Nebraska and the Missouri Valley in jreneral. ///- Triumph variety (tigs. 7 and 8) yielded more than the Early Ohio at most dry land points (Table S) and also produced a higher percentage of marketable potatoes (see Table 8). In fact, the Triumph produced the highest average yield of all va - rieties (Table H). The Triumph is rapidly becoming more ))opu - lar than the Eiirlv Ohio. It withstands unfavorable climatic conditions better than the Early Ohio. There is danger of secur - ing very low yielding lots of Triumph potatoes localise the mosaic disease (fig. !•) is very prevalent in this variety. There i- a great difference in the yielding power of many lots of seed </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nkhhaska Kxi'kkimkxt Station Hi i.i.etin 182 28 Fio. 7. — Two views of an ideal type potato of the Triumph variety. The netting is characteristic of potatoes grown on light sandy soils. Fio. 8. — Normal Triumph plant growing in western Nebraska. Photograph taken Just after blooming period. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Varieties ok Potatoes for Nebraska 29 secured in the same locality. (See Table 5.) Only very good potatoes known to be high yielding, or. better still, a high yield - ing lot of "certified" seed, should be used. The market for late Triumph table stock potatoes is becoming very well established. Irixh Cobbler (fig. 10) is the best white variety to grow on dry land. In the trials, the Irish Cobbler produced more than the Early Ohio and also produced a greater percentage of grade Fig. 9. — Triumph potato plant showing the curly dwarf type of mosaic ID nipare with healthy plant shown in figure 8.) No. 1 potatoes. It ku a preference for sandy soils. It is ad - visable to investigate this variety for the production of early potatoes in northwestern Nebraska if one desires to market pota - toes in early Septemb?r. Potatoes known as Irish Cobbler are being raised in several localities in western Nebraska. Many of these lots now lx-ing grown contain a high percentage of potatoes of other white varieties. (See Table IS.) Really good seed pota - toes of the variety are rather scarce at present. In localities having a slightly higher temperature, with a greater total effective temperature, as the dry land areas in </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NkBRASKA Kxi'KKl.MKXT STATION Hi l.l.KTIX IH'2 Scotts Bluff and Morrill Counties and the White River Valley in Dawes County, some of the later varieties, as the Downing (figs. 11 and 12) and Rural New Yorker (also Russet Rural) (fig. 13) can l&gt;e produced advantageously. (See Chadron, Table B.) The Pearl variety (fig. 14) also produces good yields, but is undesirable because the potatoes are frequently excessively - large iind knobby. VARIETIES FOR DRY LANI&gt; SEED PRODUCTION Triumph. — For the production of potatoes to be marketed for seed purposes, the Triumph i&gt; by far the most popular in northwestern Nebraska dry land regions at the present time. Triumph potatoes from this region have given quite uniformly good results in the (iulf States during the last few years. The relatively good results secured are probably due to the relatively small amount of mosaic (fig. !») found in the Nebraska Triumph seed potatoes. This disease is very serious in some states. It greatly reduces the yield of the crop in the South. Triumph seed potatoes are sold and delivered for use in the Gulf States from digging time until about January 20th. For use in the irrigated regions of Colorado and western Ne - braska, deliveries are generally made in April and May. Early Ohio (fig. (i) has not yet been grown extensively for seed purposes in northwestern Nebraska. The Early Ohio pota- Fk;. lt&gt;.— An ideal type of Irish Cobbler potai </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Varieties i&gt;k Potatoes for Nebraska 31 «•«. I i 4 i! p I a t -B i I 5 as ¥ S x i s* H I IS si 5t O 3 *&amp; S« 22 S I II liii II ii V i- ■i Q_OS(S«_|00« t 5 o SigSS I . !| •a 8t« •§•- *S o Z * _ !« c «J; .2-=-5 £35 l! Si j{ I S&amp;fcg-Sl g 1 1.5 si QQi E-SV aiaoiixi |f •a r- n So 6 c * 5°§ I I a • &gt;»! I sri c 8'i • OS i a * 8 I ■ 11 _ * I 1 lit t i i|J I i ii ! Kg «. I ~tjit -S"sg 1 -a C c « &gt; "5 S I | J |V — s I SI S5-S ■StfH _ £ Q M II gg glla si.2 Jl! a .i il .23 5g {! h ! • I 5 I *j t </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Biu.etin 1 v J 32 toes from this region have produced very good results in the comparative trials in Nebraska and other states. This variety S probably be produced for seed purposes much more profit - than for table use. as there is a great demand for such s 1 i at hand. The leading markets for Early Ohio seed pota - toes are: the entire Platte Valley, but especially in Hall. Buffalo, and Dawson Counties; eastern and southern Nebraska: the Kaw Valley of Kansas; and all thru Iowa. Missouri, and Kansas. The Early Ohio seed market is seldom very active before Febru - ary 1st. Mo^t deliveries are made during March and April. Iritih, Cobbler I tig. l&lt;0 can be grown for the xvd market, but at present the acreage grown for this purpose i- very small. Irish Cobbler seed |&gt;&lt;&gt;tat&lt;&gt;«'&gt; are somewhat in demand in the (Julf States. This variety is produced extensively thruout Missouri and is important in the Kaw Valley of Kansas and to some ex - tent in the Platte Valley. There i&gt; also a demand for &gt;eed pota - toes in the western irrigated regions, where the variety i- gftmm for the early market. Since Irish Cobbler seed potatoes are relatively scarce, there i&gt; considerable opportunity and need for establishing a suj&gt;erior strain of this variety. Seed potatoes of the Downing (fig. 11) and Rural New Yorker (fig. 18) varieties can he produced advantageously thni - out the western dry land region. In the region- of highest alti - tude the potatoes of thes** varieties may !«• too small for a good grade of table potatoes, but they are sufficiently larir.- for seed purposes. There is a great need for good dry land -&lt;* •&gt; 1 of these varieties, especially of the Downing, for use in the irrigated r&gt; - gions of western Nebraska and Colorado. Tlie Kini: (tig. 18) can also l&gt;e grown for seed purposes thruout this region, but i - not recommended for that purpose except in the regions having relatively liijrher temperatures and sufficient moisture ( Morrill County and White River Valley of Drwea County), where yields have been satisfactory (Table S). The yields from several other varieties are often quit* 1 -atis - factorv. but the type i&gt; sometimes inferior and the tubers are always too immature (in case of late varieties) to warrant recommending them. VARIETIES FOR THE IRRIGATED REGIONS OF NORTHWESTERN NEBRASKA There is a great variation in the soil- on which potatoes art grown with irrigation in northwestern Nebraska (see Table 1) Some soils are fine sand for 3 feet or more in depth, while other? iScotts Bluff. Merrill. Sioux, and Kimball Count ir </seg>
            <seg id="p033">VaRIKTIKS CIK lVlATOKS K&gt;I! NEBRASKA 33 are relatively heavy sandy loams and loams. There is also a great range in topography. Many of the light sandy soils are quite rolling, with many relatively steep areas. These soil char - acteristics need to l»e considered in selecting a variety. Quite comprehensive experiments conducted in western Ne - liraska with a number of lots and varieties of potatoes, during the la&gt;t ."&gt; years, indicate that as a whole irrigated potatoes are Fig. 11 11. — An ideal type of Downing potato. In western Nebraska the potatoes of this variety are generally a trifle longer and not quite as round as this illustration. not as good for seed purposes as dry land grown potatoes. This condition is more marked with some varieties than with others. As it is advisable, in the irrigated regions, to renew the potato seed supply every year or every few years, it is quite important to consider the availability of the supply of good seed potatoes of a variety under consideration. VARIETIES FOR RELATIVELY HEAVY AND LEVEL SOILS On the relatively heavy and level irrigated soils that are well supplied with organic matter. — because of a crop of alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Kxpekimext Station Bcixjctin 182 or some other legume having l&gt;een plowed under. — the Triumph and Downing varieties are most desirable of the early varieties §the Rural Xew Yorker and King are most desirable of the varieties. Under these conditions, when good seed |x&gt;tatoes used, the Downing variety (tig. 11) has many steins per plajit and sets niai\y |x&gt;tatoes jht hill (Table !&gt;) and produces a very heavy yield of good, smooth, medium-sized tul&gt;ers. The production of this variety i&gt; limited at the present time, proba - bly because of the lack of good dry land seed. The vigor of thi&gt; variety deteriorates rapidly under irrigation. The Triumph is Fig. 12. — A normal type of Downing potato plant in the irrigated sections of western Nebraska. Note the numerous slender stems and the spreading habit of growth. very popular, and a large quantity of very good seed i&gt; available in the neighl&gt;oring dry land regions. Some of the strains of Triumph potatoes that are distinctly later than others produce very high yields, but the tul&gt;er t.V|&gt;e is inferior when compared with the earlv strains. The Rural New Yorker. Russet Rural New Yorker, and King are all satisfactory late varieties. The Russet type of the Rural New Yorker (fig. 13) is quite popular. It seldom con - tains a serious amount of scab. The potatoes are usually uni- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Varieties of Potatoes fob Nebraska 35 Fiu. 13. — Two types of Russet Rural New Yorker potatoes. Most of the potatoes produced in the irrigated section resemble the longer type shown at the right. The Rural New Yorker has the same type but its skin is not russeted. Fig. 14.— Ideal type of a Pearl potato. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">NkHKASKA Kxi'KKIMKNT STATION Hi 1.I.F.T1N 1 &gt;J 36 form ill size and are smooth. Consequently they present a good market appearance. They are inclined to be hollow if grown on too rich or too moist soil. This can be eliminated to some ex - tent by closer planting. This variety sets tubers under adverse midsummer climatic conditions Iwtter than any other late va - riety. The tul&gt;ers of the King vary in size, many of them being very large (see Table !»). Both the King and the Rural New- Yorker are very vigorous in habit of growth and are very late. They seem to withstand the deteriorating effect of irrigation better than other varieties. Fig. 15. — A field of irrigated Russet Rural New Yorker potatoes in Sioux County in 1921. The Pearl variety (fig. 14) is not recommended for these conditions, because it produces a high percentage of excessively large, knobby, scabby, and sunburnt potatoes. For the same reasons and because of low yields secured, the Early Ohio is not recommended for irrigation regions. The Irish Cobbler pota - toes are generally very ill shaped under these conditions. The Russet Burbank is too liable to be knobby under the conditions prevailing and the Green Mountain generally too immature. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Varieties of Potatoes h&gt;r Nebraska 37 VARIETIES FOR LIGHT SANDY SOILS On tlif lighter and more sandy soils (as in the Minatare plat. — see Table 1), many of which have rather steep topogra- Khy. making irrigation difficult, the Irish Cobbler and Rural &lt;'\v Yorker varieties have given U'st yields. (See Table 8.) Fig. 16. — An ideal type of Green Mountain potato. Tubers of idea! type of this variety are produced only in the light sandy soils, in western Nebraska. Pig. 17. — Ideal type of a Russet Burbank potato. Triumph, Downing, King, and Pearl produced good yields in the trials. The Irish Cobbler is desirable for the production of early potatoes. The percentage of marketable tubers produced </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 18-J by most of the varieties, es|M?ciallv the Pearl, is greater on thi&gt; ty|H" of soil than on the heavier types at Morrill and Bayard (Table 8). On this sandy type of soil all varieties produce tubers of good type with few knobs and few hollow potatoes. The yields are relatively low because of the physical ini|x&gt;ssi - bility of getting sufficient moisture into the soil. The set of tul&gt;er&gt; of all varieties is generally light. Fit;. 18. — An ideal type of King potato. The hrte varieties (King an&lt;l Rural New Vorkar) have given poor results under irrigation at Kimball. where the results with Downing and Pearl have lieen fair and where the Triumph and Irish Cobbler have given good results. VARIETIES FOR EASTERN AND CENTRAL NEBRASKA The Early Ohio (fig. (&gt;) i- practically the only variety Iw - ing grown in eastern and central Nebraska south and cast of the "Sand Hills." It seems adapted to the prevailing conditions lietter than any other variety. Under irrigation it is liable to produce knobby potatoes unless the irrigation water is supplied at the proper time so that a check in growth is not permitted. In this region new seed potatoes should l&gt;e secured each year from the more favorable regions of the north or west or should \te produced at home under a straw mulch. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska ■M The Irish Cobbler (tig. 10) is the only other variety of merit for this region. It should Ik- tried out more extensively, esjHfially in the irrigated ivjrions. The Triumph (fig. 7) is not recommended. It gave fair re - ults several vears. hut it is not reliable, as the leaves are very tender and are liable to l&gt;e killed prematurely during hot days of June and Jiilv. with a considerable loss in vield as a result. Late varieties are not recommended: but if one is desired, the Rural New Yorker is to be preferred as it withstands hot. droughty conditions better than any other. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The author acknowledges assistance rendered by R. V. How - ard of the Department of Horticulture thruout the conduct of this project, to T. A. Kiesselbach for many suggestions on com - piling data, to (I. A. Ijoveland for advice concerning climato - logical data, to J. C. Russel for mechanical soil analyses, and to all cooperating potato growers who cared for the plats or fur - nished lots of seed potatoes. Figures &lt;). s. 13, and 17 were supplied by the Department of Horticulture of the Colorado Agricultural Colleges, and figures 1&lt;). 11. 14, 16, and 18 were supplied by W. A. Stuart of the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Figures 3 and 4 were supplied from Nebraska Research Bulletin No. 15&gt;. [SMI </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>