<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska at a Glance</title>
               <date value="1921-07">1921-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA /$ ataglanceJ I H»rJAffilbftj&gt;l#T &gt;■ I" ! M i « x^f ■i • « H ! . &lt;! E2i STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING BULLETIN No. 11O LINCOLN JULY. 1921 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">d FORKWORD The puipose of this booklet is to present in condense form, leading and up-to-date facts about Nebraska. Fi are principally from Federal and State official reports. further information in regard to the resources and indu iguit F&lt; of Nebraska, address the Department of Agriculture R1 House, Lincoln, Nebraska. LEO STl'HR. Secretary of Aericultui </seg>
            <seg id="p003">FACTS BRIEFLY STATED NEBRASKA OFFERS More than 100 kinds of soil and a A WIDE RANGE OF wide range of climatic conditions NATURAL CONDI- make Nebraska especially adapted to TIONS diversified agriculture. The type ot fanning practiced varies from ranch- he most intensive soil culture. No state in the union .\ ider range of agriculture possibilities. Nebraska ranks first in alfalfa, second in wild hay, third heat, third in corn, fifth in oats and fifth in sugar beets. In lie state are 400 species of native grasses and sedges; 50 in - roduced grasses; 200 kinds of trees, 60 of which are native; 27 species of native birds and 100 species of mammals. AREA AND The total area of the state is 76,808 square DIMENSIONS miles or 49,157,120 acres. The extreme width is a little over 200 miles and the ex - treme length more than 400 miles. POPULATION The present population according to prelimi- nary census reports is 1,296,372, an increase of 104,158 or 8.7 per cent since 1910. The average number of inhabitants to the square mile is 16.9. The average was 15.5 in 1910 and 13.9 in 1900. The </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Department of Agriculture 4 percentage of the population living in cities of 2,500 or more increased from 23.7 in 1900 to 26.1 in 1910 and to 31.3 in 1920. ELEVATION The altitude ranges from 840 feet in the south- eastern to over 5,000 feet in the western part of the state. The highest point is 5,340 feet in the western part of Banner County. TEMPERATURE The average temperature lowers from east to west as well as from south to north. The mean ranges from 51 degrees in the southeast to 45 degrees in the northwest. In January, the coldest month, the mean temperature is 21.8 degrees. July is the warmest month. For a period of forty-two years, the average temperature thruout the year was 48.6 degrees. GROWING The length of the growing season varies fror SEASON 160 days in the southeastern to 13o days in th northwestern part of the state. The last killing frost is usually the latter part of April in the extreme south - east. The date grows gradually later toward the north and west to about the 25th day of May in the extreme northwestern comer. Frost sometimes occurs the latter part of August in the northwest and usually does not come till the first part ol October in the extreme southeast. The earliest killing frost </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Bulletin No. 110 IK &gt;n record for southeastern Nebraska was September 12. This occurred in 1902. RAINFALL The average rainfall for the state over a period of more than 40 years is 23.64 inches. Averages for the different pails of the state follow: Southeastern part Northeastern part Central part 29.87 Southwestern part 23.03 27.43 Northwestern part .,19.11 24.49 Western part 17.72 About 46 per cent of the annual precipitation occurs during the eason of growing crops, from May to July. The heaviest may be expected in June, Map showin&lt; the distribution of annual rainfall in Nebraska. The annual monthly rainfall which shows the heaviest precipitation during the growing season follows: The 52 in. July 3.43 in. January February March _ 72 in. August 2.81 in. September 2.13 in. 1.11 in. April May June 2.41 in. October 1.57 in. 3.63 in. November .68 in. December .74 in. 3.81 in </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Department of Agriculture irrigation Approximately 700 irrigating canals are in operation in the state. The 1920 assessors reports show 289,242 cultivated acres under irrigation. The total acreage of irrigated land in the North Platte Valley is approximately 500,000. In addition about 400,000 acres in other parts of the state are watered by smaller and individual projects. Besides what is already under the ditch, the state contains approximately 3,500,000 acres of irrigable land. TOTAL ACREAGE In 1920 the 16,178,404 acres in culti- AND VALUE OF vation in the state produced a crop NEBRASKA CROPS valued at $306,469,000. The acreage in cultivation in 1919 was 19.0 1&lt;&gt;.&lt;m and the total value of the crop that year was $54S,220,00&lt; EABULATED DATA Acreage, yield, production and N EIGHT of principal crop 192n. of principal crop 1920 PRINCIPAL CROPS Acreage Yield Production \ aim Ccrn 7,560,355 33.8 bu 255,544,816 bu 1127.772,408 Wheat 3,592,995 16.7 bu Oats 2,400,062 34.6 bu 60,560,416 b « t : 83,037,162 bu. :«.il4,864 Rye 264,370 14-1 bu 3,751,104 bu. 4,876.4: Barley 255,503 29.0 bu ,424,615 bu. 4,454.71 Potatoes 85.439 98.7 bu 8,435,554 bu. «,748,443 Alfalfa 1,232947 2.86 Ton Wild Hay_ _2.3 15, 359 102 Ton ,527,689 Tons 35,276,81 2,319,777 Tons 18,558,21«l.2( </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Bulletin Vo. 110 7 SUGAI The sugar beet industry is rapidly growing in the BEETS state. Five factories are now in operation. The beet crop last year reached the total value of $8,570,520. Acreage and production figures for the last two POTATOES Altho commercial potato growing is a compara- tively new industry in the state, last year's ship- ments totaled approximately 3,000 cars, about 76 c /c of which graded No. One. A total of 407 cars were shipped into twelve different states for seeding puiposes. VALl'E OF ALL The total value of livestock on Nebraska LIVESTOCK farms in 1920 was $344,000,000, the state ranking seventh. The 1919 total value 107,000,000 and in that year the state ranked fourth. M'MBEK AND VALl'E The number and value of livestock OF KINDS OF LIVE- on Nebraska farms, 1920 and STOCK 1918. years are given below. T( tal number of acres harvested-- 1920 71,730 714,210 89,517-75 1919 59,253 600.669 60.854. Total tons of beets TYta! tons of sugar produced J-il Number Value Number Value Cattle Htm ■ Mules Hfgs Sheep &amp; Gotta . _2,.~&gt;!t8,057 .- 8711,763 _ 93,438 -1,7O7.O!I2 . 236,402 $113,778,114 ..6,698.709 10,700,342 28,204,860 l,!ir&gt;"t,740 2,904,875 910,079 102,192 2,038,236 278.821 $213,943,510 81,907,110 10,219,200 61,147,080 3.345,852 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Department of Agriculture OMAHA SECOND The total combined receipts of LARGEST LIVESTOCK cattle, hogs and sheep at each ot MARKET the five leading markets for the the five leading markets for the year 1C20 rhow that Omaha stands second. Total 1920 Chicago Omaha 15,500,1 M»i 7.201,000 6,650.000 rsas City Loui.; __ 35.000 St. Pau' 4 IWO.OOil OMAHA RECEIPTS The following table shows the total re FOR 10 YEARS ceipts of cattle, hogs and sheep on the Omaha market each year for the past ten years. Omaha Receipts For 10 Years Cattle Hogs S 1,17 IMS ma 1HU 1MJ 4 I»U l.i'lT 1911 1.174 I»M 1.223.531 1.8S4S14 2.K 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Bulletin No. 110 9 SWINE Nebraska ranks high in the quality of pure-bred hog*. The estimated number of brood sows on Ne- ka farms April 1, 1921 was 667,000; an average of 5.2 i per farm, in the average number of sows per farm, the state ranks second only to Iowa. l.rooH Sows in Five Leading States and in the United States April 1 1921 Total Number Average per Farm l.tt 7 rt 8«T. 1'47. I ■ I t 1 3 HI x nt DAIRYING More than loo.ooo Nebraska farmers milk a total of approximately 435,000 cows which pro- duce annually 60,0(mi,(MM) lbs. of butter and 200,000,000 gallons of milk. The total income from milk cows in 1920 is conserva- tively estimated at $40,000,000. Considerable milk and butter i.* consumed on the farm, the exact quantity of which no re- cords are available. The following table shows the quantity of dairy products manufactured in the state the last two years. I ni a I Production of Licensed Butter. Condensed Milk and Cheese Factories in the State 1920 1919 Nun 78 56 r;umen .50,085,943 60,298,666 Butter, pi u ..mleiised mi'k ami milk powder, lbs 446.031 9,266,000 n. i ___ 7,180,714 33,579 Cheese, 1 1 2,308.102 1,994,889 u I'OILTRY The poultry industry is well developed in the state. It is estimated that 12,000,000 birds COn- iribute annually nearly $50,000.&lt;mi&lt;&gt; to the wealth of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Department of Agriculture MARKETING Nebraska is centrally located. The geograph- FACILITIES ical center of the U. S. is near Kearney. There are 6,742 miles of railroad in the state, oper- ated by seven companies. Four trunk lines extend across the state east and west. In the east end of the state, in an area representing 29 r ,i of the total area and where 72 7&lt; of the population is found, there are 3,255 miles of railroad. In this section the average distance from a railroad station is only seven miles. C&gt;ADS AND The total extent of roads in Nebraska is GHWAYS 80,000 miles. Federal and state aid road planned 4,800 miles; federal and state aid road completed 2,600 miles. Total amount spent on roads and bridges in 1920, federal and state aid. $6,350,000. Cost of road to be constructed 1921 9&amp;4CM&gt;,000 Amount spent annually for maintenance $2,oo&lt;ummi Total amount appropriated by the government to date, to be duplicated by the state, $5,866,762. TELEPHONES The total number of telephones in Nebraska in 1921 is approximately 275,000. About 300 companies maintain exchanges. The total number ol stockholders is 20,000. Approximately 75 rural lines art owned and operated by farmers. The number of rural tele - phones is 80,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Bulletin No. 110 11 co-operative The total number of co-operative concerns CONCERNS in Nebraska is over 650, more than half of which are elevators or have elevators in connection. The volume of business transacted by 401 patron - age films in 1920 was $79,659,637. These 401 companies have stock distributed among 50,665 stockholders more than 33,000 of whom are farmers. The total capital stock invested is W.688,244. I'lBLIC Nebraska spends annually on public schools SCHOOLS $20,000,000 Number of children of school age 392,592 Average daily attendance in 1920 234,954 Number of school districts 7,264 Number of teachers employed 13,789 High schools accredited to the State University 402 Smith-Hughes high schools offering Agriculture 38 Total value of district property $42,145,280 Smith-Hughes schools offering Home Economics 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Department of Agriculture MANUFACTURING While Nebraska is primarily agricul- cultural, at the same time the total value of manufactured products amounts to nearly $6&lt;&gt;&lt;i,o&lt;ki, - 000 annually. A preliminary statement of the results of the census of manufacturers in Nebraska for 1919 gives the fol - lowing summary comparing figures for 1914 and 1919 by FARM EQUIPMENT The total value of machinery on N« braska farms is approximat $10,000,000. Number of trucks \2-: Number of gas tractors. Number of gas engines. Autos on farms Modem water systems. _ Modern heating plants.. Modem lighting systems 8.H8S 4(),.-)6:) 88,61.°, 5.718 5,301 5.64X Summary for Stat&lt; tor s a e Cen 1919 nsui 1914 ' i of in 1914 1919 of in 'o establishments t-mons rnpVtl in nifg. .. apital "&lt;«TViCM :ilaries \aRej iMt.iial.i •Hue nf Product al. add&lt; i U by mfn LM4 4'.i."7K $i'4.", ■&gt;:,:. i&gt;i&gt;i:i. ■ l."..74S.'M.n W.W7.(KHi 479.349.iNMi 594.712. U5.M3. AM lin.w.1 ji.i'ii .»■• 7.111 u.m 174.11 231.«1&lt; 17 ■••■ U M Ml IS1 ui Ifl 17^ M 14J </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Bulletin So. 110 13 Number of Transfers. Number of Acres Included and Actual Sale Value of Land by Counties Covering Period from July 1. 1918 to July 1. 1919 No. of No. of Average Tfri. Acres Sale V. 136 nun $ is. «o 74 9625 $112.33 33914 $ 79.00 34 12287 * 28.00 12 «:.*:; | 6.90 M HIM I1M.M '.•7264 $ 27. 4» 188 ilHV. { 6167 17!i IUM $ 17.1X1 21U 38044 t K.M 112 18886 $l«4.(l» 118 l «:•«:&gt; jiK.sr, 1*5 21918 Sl.~&gt;4 no J43O« $132 00 «fl 124811 $ 35.0(1 .' - 149243 $ 8.00 194 l^«&gt; $ 49.00 17J 22232 SI 26. oil 142 1834« JIM 79 8T1C I171.IXI 263 :.7.-.n:f $ 45.00 33 3."&gt;38 $163.00 131 " Mil t 23 .8.-. MM S S4.5O MR $ 56.08 iinty Authoritii 1K(I IM61 $l!l«.lMI 1186 I267.7H IK.". ll.'iH $ 18.00 6441 (130 107 17732 t M.M 7241 | .il.no 251 \oiti i 4S IM 17111* $123. IK! ••&gt; IT.". 1^!* $ 12 US U1W !••-» 23746 t 41.IH( J8 ZM7I I 7.5S 12K31 I 63.0O ll» 1SM7 » »!'.fl6 1MS7 $140.80 116 18181 $ 57.00 1«7 3S4«fi $ 20.00 62 14322 $ n.H 18!&gt; 38157 $ 41.00 71 ON $ 7.00 271 4 7!»&gt;6 $ 76.76 7623 $107.80 .lolll Kta 13S 17:".i7 $122.00 123 16431 $ 76.00 216 71635 $ 29.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Department of Agriculture No. Of Tfrs. NO. Of Acres Average Sale V. County » 21 Kaya rWi Kmil.:ill . $ 29.5(5 HI 12213X Knt« $ 3t2tn J143.O0 Lancaster Lincoln . 1435 !Z n 48525 i H.Of lilMiT * 14.43 .M.HtlMlll IMiMn ManMk Morrill . 142 1859:' » $ M18 I 6141!" t X.-iim Ni-niaha Nuckolls OlM ... ll«2 HawM IVrkins* I'll. |.s Pierce I'hitt. I ',.lk lied Wi.l Hi«-l);u-«l&gt;. ■Hk (Ki Sa'in.- . . tt Rep !•■ A Sar] iv Haunder t Is i,r S.'Ward S!u-ri,i;il: Si. mx *t;tnton I ll;i\.r Thomas Tlnir.-t n Vall.y Washinut \Va\ iu • M .I&gt;s1. r V,,rk . </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>