<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Housing and House Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms</title>
               <date value="1931-11">1931-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 264 November, 1931 Housing and House Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms • J. O. RANKIN Department of Rural Economics * • °. i * • * ♦' iW ; .* - \-- *• a - : •••I I, • f~3P 1. y • tgS ~.—. • .•. *. Tr..*;i-~ SS.o\ &gt;i^l ■ •10 HOIS3 IX 1356 .+ . *.|. » . !*..*.*•*.* j .*•.!*» » **_* 7*«».V •10 HOES IB 1919 |*. * I«*. )*» &gt; *»\ THE HOMES STUDIED The homes were sufficiently scattered in location and time to repre - sent most parts of the state, and to give a little idea of the progress which has been made in the last ten years. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Introduction _- 3 Scope of this bulletin. .' 3 Sources of facts 4 Size of House and Household 5 Rooms and persons per house 5 Frequency of sizes of h0me5....... 6 Rooms per person 7 Cases of overcrowding g Unused rooms 0 ' : • o Household Conveniences ;.,.. r, Summary of conveniences ; ' 9 Water in the house y, Sewage disposal ..' :. _ y~ Heating facilities 00 Cooking facilities ; &#132;5 Lighting facilities 07 Power on the farm ; 29 Rental and Operating Costs per Year 32 Summary of costs 39 Value and rent of house 34 Furniture and furnishings 36 . Fuel and light ..„ ; 3g General Summary 40 Farm housing in Nebraska compared with other states...... 40 Conclusions 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Housing and House Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms A Comparison of Houses and Their Equipment and Operation on Farms of Owners, Part - owners, and Tenants ' J. O. RANKIN &gt; Farm housing conditions are of vital importance not only to the individual farm family but also to the industry of agri - culture and to the rural community as a whole. The health, comfort, efficiency, and social life of the individual family are partly dependent upon the kind of house in which they live. The maintenance of health and comfort requires ade - quate shelter, space, sanitation, water supply, and heating facilities. Efficiency in house work and farm work may be greatly aided by a well-arranged house and yard and by modern household conveniences. For a normal and satisfying social life centering in the home, a pleasant, reasonably well - lighted room is needed as a living room. Housing conditions directly affect agriculture, since they affect the health and efficiency of the farmer and his family. By affecting the contentment of the farm family, housing conditions may help to determine the type of young people who become farmers and farm home-makers. Where farm housing conditions are markedly worse than those prevailing in near-by towns, the pull of the town will be strong, especially upon the more energetic young people. Where homes as good as or better than those in town exist or are seen to be obtain - able, a better type of person will prefer the farm. Scope of this bulletin. — The present bulletin deals mainly with three aspects of farm housing: (1) size of house and household, (2) household conveniences, and (3) costs of housing and house operation. For a more general study of Nebraska farm housing the reader is referred to an earlier bulletin by the same author. 3 1 The terms owner and tenant are here used in the usual sense. The part-owner is n farmer who owns part of the land that he operates and rents part of it from someone else. A mortenee on an owner's land does not class him as a part-owner • Based mainly upon a survey conducted in 1924 in co-operation with the Bureau of AKricultural Economics, U. S. Department of Agriculture. Data from other surveys made in 1919, 1920, and 192G are included for comparison. Acknowlede - ments are due to the members of the Department* of Economics, Rural Economics, and Home Economic* of the University of Nebraska for counsel and suggestions, and to a Held worker in each of the areas studied. Tabulation was at first under the immediate direction of Miss Elizabeth Paschal, but was later completed by l Miss Eleanor H. Hin - man. * Rankin, J. O. Nebraska Farm Homes. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. May 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 TABLE 1. — Number and tenure of farm homes included in the study of Nebraska farm housing a e ana county tenures Owners owners [Tenants Mgrs. men Total 1,826 752 219 838 9 8 1924 342 114 60 160 0 8 Washington 80 41 7 31 0 1 Lancaster 100 22 21 51 0 6 Clay 84 35 8 40 0 1 Kimball 78 16 24 38 0 0 1920 1 • 1( 141 412 159 561 9 0 1919 2 343 226 117 0 0 . 1 For distribution by counties of the forms Eurveycd in 1920, see Rankin. J. O.. Nebraska Farm Tenancy — Some Community Phases. Nebr. AgT. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1023, p. 4. The cover page Rives the location of the areas studied. 3 For distribution by counties, see the figure on the cover page. The reports obtained in 1919 did not classify part-owners separately from owners. Sources of facts. — Data from the following surveys are used in this bulletin: (1) A survey of 342 farms in the four localities indicated by Table 1. They were visited by field workers in June, 1924. (2) Some data are also presented from crop-reporting correspondents whose wives answered a questionnaire mailed them in 1919 by the Cooperative Ex - tension Service of the United States Department of Agricul - ture. These homes might be expected to rank slightly higher than the average, but comparison with the 1924 figures shows conditions substantially identical with those of the unselected homes in the later survey. (3) Some data on size of house and household obtained in 1920 in co-operation with the United States Bureau of Agricultural Economics from 1,141 farm homes in eleven counties are briefly summarized for comparison with the two studies just mentioned. (4) Data on home equipment in 1926 are presented from 3.477 farm homes of members of. Home Demonstration Clubs. 4 These homes were widely scattered over the state as indicated in the map on the cover page. Although their equipment is doubtless considerably better than that in the average farm home, the figures indicate in what respects home equipment was deficient. They reflect conditions in the more progressive homes. These homes were classified as to type of farm but not as to tenure group. Eighty-one per cent of them were designated as general farms ; five per cent as specialized dairy, livestock, poultry, hay-and-grain, or truck farms; and four - teen per cent did not indicate type. •These data were obtained by the Home Demonstration Office of the University of Nebraska Extension Service as part of a nation-wide, survey conducted by the General Federation of Women's Clubs. They were tabulated by the Department of Rural Economics. More reports came later but they did not chance the showing enough to justify retabulation. The Nebraska urban data quoted for comparison were supplied by the General Federation office in Washington. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Housing and House Operation Costs size of house and household Table 2. — Rooms, bedrooms, and persons per house in Ne - braska farm homes studied in 1919, 1920, and 192U Item and year tenures Owners owners Tenants Mgrs. men Rooms per house 3 surveys 6.5 7.0 6.6 6.1 4.6 6.1 1924 6.5 6.8 6.5 6.2 .... 6.1 l!&gt;20 | 6.4 7.1 6.7 6.0 4.6 1919 ! 6.8 7.0 .... 6.4 Bedrooms per house; 2 surveys 3.1 3.4 3.2 2.0 .... 2.1 1924 3.0 3.3 3.2 2.8 .... 2.1 1920 3.2 3.5 3.2 2.9 Persons per house 3 surveys 4.6 4.8 5.0 4.4 | 4.6 4.6 1924 •. .-. 4.4 4.0 4.9 4.1 .... 4.6 1920 i 4.5 4.7 5.1 4.2 4.6 1919 ! 5.3 5.2 .:.. 5.3 1 Rooms and persons per house. — The average Nebraska farmhouse, as indicated by the combined surveys of 1919, 1920, and 1924, contained 6.5 rooms and housed 4.6 persons. Very little difference in the average number of rooms per house was found in the different surveys; but the average 70 — 1 f— 1 70 % £ owNtn 80 V; ca „„ «o | | m^T-oww* [ o _ ill II PZ»- \ \ (COM3 PCR HOUSC Fig. 1. — Distribution of 342 Nebraska farm homes studied in 1924, by size of house and tenure group. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 size of household varied from 5.3 persons in the crop-re- Y Or $Zl S A h T 6S £ 1939 to 4A persons in the homes surveyed «n xr A K COr ? in f to the United States census, the popula - tion per Nebraska farm dropped- from 4.7 persons in 19*0 to 4.4 persons m 1925 = While this is not quite the same thing as persons per dwelling, both the census and the surveys re - flect a tendency toward smaller farm families and fewer resident hired laborers, which should operate to reduce over - crowding Owners had the largest houses and part-owners the largest households of any tenure groups ; but the differ - ences were not great. Owners' homes averaged seven rooms part-owners six and one-half, tenants' and hired men's six' and managers homes only four and one-half rooms. Pantries' closets, halls, and bathrooms were not included in these totals. 3S. e S J Z fL° f !?°^ se £ enerallv decreased toward the west and rwt fc T , n 1924&gt; the Wash i"gt°n and Lancaster County homes studied averaged about seven rooms each ; the Uay County homes six rooms, and the Kimball County homes five and one-half rooms. In 1920 the range was from 1.6 rooms in Cass County to 5.8 in Logan County; in 1919 from 7.7 rooms in the east district (including mainly data trom Saunders and Seward Counties) to 4.8 in the central district (mainly Custer County data) and 4.9 in the north - west district (mainly Sioux County data). The. only marked exception to this trend was in Thurstorf Countv, where the homes studied in 1920 averaged only 5.8 rooms. But this county contains the Winnebago and Omaha Indian Reserva - tions and was not opened for settlement until 1910 There - tore, although one of the easternmost counties, it still re - flected pioneer conditions. The difference between tenure groups in size of house was even less noticeable in the western than in the eastern counties. The size of household showed a different and much more irregular geographic distribution. the largest households being found in the northeastern western, and southwestern districts, while the smallest house - holds were found in the southern district. Frequency of sizes of homes.— The six-room house was the commonest size found, although owners had nearlv as manv seven- and eight-room houses. Houses ranged in 'size from one to nineteen rooms, but those of less than three or more than ten rooms were infrequent. More very small and very large houses were found in the 1919 and 1920 surveys than m the 1924 survey. P.rt F r r pp TO n h 2 2 C a n n 8 d U! il O 7 f 5 U - *' 1020 ' B! . 41 a " d 8 ° 4 - U ' S " C — &lt;* A 8 r..l02B. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Housing and House Operation Costs Table 3. — Percentage . distribution of 1,826 Nebraska farm homes by size of house Tenure 1 Year o£ survey Kooms per house All — — ■ — — 1 j — w homes ' ! I Mftrs. Part- j I &amp; hired Owners, owners | Tenanta| men 1924 1920 1919 . P ct P. ct. P. ct. P. efc. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. et. 1 o i o.o o.o o:i o.o o.o o.o 0.3 2 1.2 1.0 1.4 1.3 0.0 O.G 1.4 0.9 3 i 4 G 4.3 3.2 5.0 20.0 3.2 4.7 5.8 4 10 9 7.5 13.7 13.1 20.0 9.7 11.1 11.7 -5 15 8 11.1 12.8 20.8 20.0 16.2 16.7 12.6 6 20 7 18.9 22.4 22.3 13.3 22.1 21.2 18.1 7 16 0 17.3 17.4 14.4 13.3 17.7 15.8 14.7 8 .' 14.4 17.8 12.7 11.9 6.7 18.3 13.8 12.3 9 7 1 8.7 7.8 5.7 0.0 5.3 6.6 10.4 lo' :. 5.3 8.0 4.6 3.1 6.7 5.3 4.6 7.7 11 ' 2 1 2.3 3.1 1.7 0.0 1.2 2.6 1.5 12 ... 0.9 1.6 0.6 ' 0.3 0.0 0.0 0.8 2.1 13 and more| 0.8 ■ 1.5 0.4 0.3 0.0 0.3 0.6 1.8 1 Surveys of 1919, 1920, and 1924 combined. Rooms per person. — The Nebraska farmhouses studied in 1919, 1920, and 1924 averaged 1.4 rooms per person living in the house, increasing in successive studies from 1.3 in 1919 to 1.5 in 1924. Tenure differences in this respect were slight. These averages in themselves do not indicate widespread over - crowding. The average number of rooms per person, by areas surveyed in 1920 and 1924, decreased from east to west, from 1.6 in Washington, Lancaster, and Cass Counties to 1.2 in Kimball and 1.1 in Perkins. The only exceptions to this trend were Thurston County with 1.2 rooms per person and Polk County with 1.7. The crop-reporters studied in 1919 Table 4. — Rooms per person in 1,826 Nebraska farmhouses of specified sizes Tenure l Year of Burvey Rooms per house , ; , M Rrs. j Part- &amp; hired I J Owners owners Tenants men 1924 | 1920 1919 Total 1.4 1.5 1.3 1.4. 1.2 1.5 1.4 1.3 1 0.5 .... ' .... 0.5 .... .... .... 0.5 2 0 6 0.8 0.6 0.5 .... 0.3 0.6 0.7 ' 3 "'" 0.8 0.7 0.7 0.8 0.8 0.9 0.8 0.6 4 '.' 1.0 1.0 0.8 1.0 0.9 1.1 1.0 0.9 5 ■ 1.1 1.1 1.1 . 1.1 0.9 1.2 1.2 0.9 6 1.3 1.4 1.3 1.3 1.2 1.3 1.4 1.2 7 ■"■" 1.5 1.5 1.6 1.6 ' 2.0 1.7 1.6 1.3 8 [..... 1.7 1.7 1.5 1.9 -2.7 1.8 1.8 1.6 9 1.7 1.5 1.8' 2.0 .... 2.0 1.8 1.4 10 1.8 1,8 1.5 2.2 1.7 2.1 1.7 1.9 U 2.0 2.0 1.6 2.5 .... 2.0 2.0 2.1 12 1.8 1.8 1.7 1.9 .... .... 1.8 1.8 13 and more 2.G 2.7 1.9 2.9 7.0 2.6 2.4 1 Surveys of 1919, 1920, and 1924 combined. . • </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 were less regular, but ranged from 1.5 rooms per person in the eastern and central districts to 0.9 room per person in the northwestern district. These averages indicate some overcrowding in the western and northwestern areas studied. The number of rooms per person increased from 0.5 in the only one-room house found to 2.6 in houses of thirteen rooms or more. If 0.7 room per person is accepted as the minimum space consistent with health and seemliness, it is seen that the one- and two-room houses are overcrowded and so are some of the three-room houses. 0 On the other hand, some of the very large homes doubtless had more rooms than could be profitably utilized. Size of family increased much less than size of house, ranging from two in the one-room house to a maximum of 6.7 persons per twelve-room house after which it declined to 5.4 persons in the houses still larger. Cases of overcrowding. — Eleven cases of serious over - crowding — that is, more than 1.5 persons per room and 2.0 per bedroom — were found in the 1924 survey. Among these overcrowded homes were two two-room, three three-room, one four-room, two five-room, two six-room, and one nine - room houses. These eleven homes constituted only a small portion of the total : 3.2 per cent of the 342 homes, including 2.6 per cent of the owners, 1.7 per cent of the part-owners and 4.4 per cent of the tenants. Nine of the eleven cases of overcrowding occurred in the westernmost area studied, where 11.5 per cent of the homes of all tenures and 18.4 per cent of the tenant homes were over - crowded. The worst example was a two-room tenant house in this area which sheltered ten persons. Thirty homes having more than 1.5 persons per room were found in 1919. This was 9.2 per cent of the. homes answering the question — 7.9 per cent of the owners and 11.6 per cent of the tenants. Twenty-two of the thirty examples of over - crowding were in the west and southwest, districts— 27 6 per cent and 13.2 per cent respectively of the homes in these dis - tricts. 7 The amount of overcrowding may have been ab - normally high in this year, because of the* post-war housinir shortage. Unused rooms. — At the other extreme from the over - crowded houses were some with vacant rooms. Half the homes studied in 1924 had rooms unused in summer averag - ing two per house. More than four houses out of every seven had rooms vacant in winter. Most of the vacant rooms were room for every 1.5 persons was chosen with reference to waKc-earncrs' "familie, New York City. It i. perhaps rather low to apply to Nebraska fa™ " famiMe™ 'The number of bedrooms was not learned in the 1010 study The 1020 -t,,,iv was not rctabulated for examples of overcrowding. .' e 1J *" study </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Housing and House Operation Costs Table 5. — Unused rooms and bedrooms in Nebraska farm homes studied in 192U AH " P^Jt~ Hired Item I tenures Owners owners Tenants men Houses ' 339 xi3 60 150 7 Unused rooms, summer Houses j 1G8 58 26 79 5 Per house ! 2.0 2.1 . 1.7 1.9 2.6 Unused rooms, winter Houses 194 G8 29 | 92 5 Per house 2.1 2.3 1.8 2.1 2.6 Unused bedrooms, summer Houses 137 51 24 62 ' 0 Per house : 1.5 1.8 1.5 1.3 0 Unused bedrooms, winter Houses 156 61 25 70 0 Per house 1.5 1.8 1.5 1.3 0 bedrooms. The larger number of houses having vacant rooms in winter may be due in part to the expense or inconvenience of heating and in part to larger households in the summer. Sons and daughters away at school as pupils or teachers re - turned to some of these homes for vacation, and hired men ■were often engaged for the crop season only. A spare bed - room may be a convenience, but several unused rooms in a farmhouse mean wasted space, unnecessary housework, and possibly fuel costs higher than they need be. HOUSEHOLD CONVENIENCES SUMMARY OF CONVENIENCES Improvements in modern household conveniences, 1920 - 1930. — Nebraska farm homes improved greatly in modern household conveniences between 1920 and 1930, as indicated by Table 6. This table is based on reports from precinct asses - sors, who obtained answers from between 90 and 9-5 per cent of all the farms in the state as reported by the United States census of nearest date. The difference between the number of census farms and assessed farms is mainly due to the omission from the latter of farms of one and two acres located near towns. Before 1928, the definition of the terms "modern water, bath, heat, and light" was apparently left to the discretion of the various precinct assessors; in 1928-30, "water piped in" and "tub or shower bath" were specified, while the query on heat was dropped and that on light sup - planted by one on electricity. Tube radio receiving sets were specified in 1923, but all receiving sets from 1925 on. The radio increase was the most rapid, from less than one per cent of Nebraska farm homes with radios in 1923 to 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 TABLE 6. — Household conveniences on Nebraska farms, 1920 - 1930 — percentages of farms reporting each specified con - venience * • | Modern ■ ~ | • j j ~ Year 1 Water 5 | Bath' | Heat | Light | EUectricity j Radio | Telephone P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.et. -P.et. P. ct. 1930 21.0 14.5 13.2 15.4 45.0 1929 19.1 13.7 ...... 13.5 41.1 75.1 1928 18.1 12.4 11.7 34.1 . 74.8 1927 16.4 11.0 11.7 1S.6 28.0 • 1926 14.1 8.9 11.8 11.8 18.7 1926 10.8 6.6 9.2 9.1 11.0 1024 8.6 7.6 7.7 1923 7.3 6.0 6.6 7.2 0.5 1922 7.3 6.5 G.4 ..:... 1921 6.6 6.3 5.4 1920 4.7 ■ 4.7 4/7 .^ .^^ 76.7 1 Nebraska Agricultural Statistics. 1920-1930. U. S. Dept. AgT. and Nclir. Dept of Agr., published annually. The figures are based on precinct assessors' reports • and cover from 90 to 95 per cent of the farms in the state as reported by the United States census of nearest date. The precinct assessors did not enumerate small farms of one and two acres near towns, but the census enumerated them. 1 "Water piped in" in 1928-30. • "Tub or shower bath" in 1928-30. per cent in 1930. Homes with "modern" or piped-in water increased from nearly five per cent in 1920 to 21 per cent in 1930; and all other conveniences also showed an increase ex - cept telephones. This improvement continued through the depressions of 1921 and 1930. It is possible that the per- . centages given in Table 6 were slightly lower than the actual conditions, since the data were obtained by the assessors at the same time that the property was being assessed for taxa- TABLE 7. — Summary of household conveniences in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 192 % — percentages of homes reporting specified convenience, by tenure groups ' _ ~. _ . part _ ' Item and year tenures 1 Owners I owners I Water piped into house I P. ct. P. ct. | P. ct. P. ct. 1924 39.4 50.0 1 3G.7 35.0 1919 33.8 42.0 17.9 Bathroom 1924 ...| 20.2 ■ | 31.G 23.3 11.9 1919 | 18.4 | 25.2 5.1 Septic tank or cesspool 1924 .[ 20.1 29.0 20.0 15.0 1919 9.9 13.2 3.5 Central heating system 1924 19.0 25.4 28.3 11.9 1919 V 17.1 23.9 3.5 Central lighting system 1924 13.7 27.2 20.0 2.5 1919 :.... 15.3 . 19.0 7.9 1 Based on 342 homes studied in 1924 and 313 in 1910. This includes eicht hired men's homes, none of which had any of tho specified conveniences. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Housing and House . Operation Costs tion, although the queries about conveniences were included solely for general information and not as a basis for taxation. Summary of household conveniences, by tenure. — Of the farm homes studied in 1919 and 1924, about one in three had water piped into the house, including both running water and hand-pumps in the kitchen. One in five or six homes had a K&gt;: j 11 ALL TENURES PART-OWNrRS PIPED- IN B SEPTIC TANH CENTRAL CENTRAL | WATER | """ | OR CESSPOOL | HEATING | LIGHTING Fig. 2. — Percentage of 342 Nebraska farm homes reporting specified household conveniences in 1924, by tenure groups. "bathroom" — that is, any room having a stationary bath tub with running water and a drain ; and about the same propor - tion had furnace heat. About one home in seven had "modern" light — including under this heading electricity, acetylene, carbide, Blaugas, and piped gasoline vapor systems. Sewage disposal was the only item in which a considerable divergence was shown between the crop-reporters of 1919 and the unselected homes of 1924. In the former survey, about one home in ten had drainage to a cesspool or a septic tank; in the latter, one home in five. The showing of the owner homes was greatly superior to that of tenants in every item and in both surveys. Part-owners occupied a middle position. None of the hired men's homes had any of the household con - veniences listed. Very nearly the same proportion of homes in the Washington, Lancaster, and Clay County areas re - ported the above-named conveniences, but the Kim'ball County area stood far behind the other three studied in 1924. A much higher proportion of survey homes showed these conveniences than of all farm homes reported by the precinct assessors for Nebraska or even for the four counties in which the 1924 survey was carried out. The difference is partly a </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 Table 8. — Water piped into the house on Nebraska farms studied in 1919 and 1924— percentages of homes by tenure groups 1 Water piped into Tenure ond date Kitchen j j J ' Houae and Kitchen I Bathroom \ l'orch . „ . bathroom only . only only All tenures p. ct . p. ct , I P . c , p , j p 1924... 39.4 i 18.4 I 19.0 2.0 I 0.3 n 191&lt;J ••••! 33.8 18.4 14.8 0.G 0 0 Owners I ■ ™24 j 50.0 28.1 18.4 I 3.5 0.0 „ . 1019 ; -12.0 25.G 15.5 0.9 0.0 Part-owners I I' I „ I 924 ! 36-7 i 21.7 I ' U.7 3.3 0.0 Tenants . J984 ;... 35.0 11.3 23.1 0.G 0.G 'B"ed on 342 homes in 182 1 and 313 in 191D. No hired man's home reported water in the hmisc. "Runnrnu water" was specified in the 1024 schedule but as the perccntawe is fo high it is likely that some hand-pumps were included matter of definitions; for example, it seems evident that the precinct assessors, or some of them, did not count hand-pumps in the house as "water piped in". The following factors may also enter in: (1) Standard-of-living surveys nearly always reflect somewhat better conditions than the average of the class _fvom which the sample is taken because better coopera - tion is generally obtained from the homes with better living conditions. Information cannot be obtained from some of the poorer homes. (2) The crop-reporters' homes, as stated, mav be supposed to be somewhat above average. (3) Two of the areas studied in 192-1 — Waverly in Lancaster County and Fort Calhoun in Washington County — are fairly close to cities (Lincoln and Omaha respectively) and therefore more acces - sible to salesmen than the stafe as a whole. (4) The figures gathered by the precinct assessors may perhaps be a little low, for the reasons previously stated. WATER IN THE HOUSE Water, by tenure groups. — The two-fifths of the homes studied in 1924 which had water piped into the house were rather evenly divided .between those with water piped to both kitchen and bathroom and those which had- it only in the kitchen, although a few had it only. in the bathroom. One home reported running water on the porch, but this was not included as piped into the house. More than one- fourth of the owners, one-fifth of the part-owners, and one-ninth of the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Housing and House Operation Costs 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 PERCENT 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 ■ KITCHEN, rag KITCHEN VTn BATHROOM BATHROOM 883 ONLY KM ONLY Fig. 3.— Percentages of 342 Nebraska farm homes with water piped to kitchen and bathroom in 1924. tenants had running water in both kitchen and bathroom; while about one-sixth of the owners, one-ninth of the part - owners, and one-fourth of the tenants had it in the kitchen only. Homes with water piped into the house were commonest in the Clay County area, where slightly more than two-fifths had it, and rarest in the Kimball County area, where only about one-sixth had it. Water, by districts. — Three-eighths of the Home Demon - stration Club women's homes studied in 1926 had water piped into the house. About half of those having water in the house used machine power to pump it, usually a windmill ; seven per cent depended upon hand-pumps; and three per cent upon gravity. Eleven per cent did not specify the power used. Water in the house was commonest in the southwest district where a lai-ge number of hand-pumps in the house were indi - cated; it was rarest in the west district. 8 Water pumped by machine power was commonest in the ce.ntral disti-ict. Plumbing fixtures, by tenures, 1924 and 1919. — The most detailed information on kitchen plumbing fixtures comes from the 1919 survey, while for bathroom fixtures it comes from the 1924 survey. In 1919 a little less than one-fourth of the homes reported both faucets with running water and sinks ■ No reports were obtained from the northern nnd northwestern districts. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 TAS ffi 9 &lt;£Z Water pi P ed int0 h07iSe °» Nebraska farms studied in lM6~percentageo) 'homes, by geographic districts 1 ™ . . Power forcing water water „. —^--7 — -^ .^___ District Piped Machine ■ to Station- Electric Wind- Gravity Hand Unspec - hou.se An V ary motor miir or power ified -__ I engine . ' siphon State £g C 2 '- nr'- P i C t- P ° l - Peu Pct - Pet- ''■ ct. Southeast T. 111 VA |* £.9 11.7 2.9 .6.0 | 10.8 East 37 V, V I'* ? 9 1LB ' °- 9 &lt;-9 10.4 Northeast I 39? \H J! fg ." 5 -° «•« 12.9 South 35 B \i r, 1i I 5 . \'\ °- 4 2 -9 J6-8 feGF: S I : : , : 1 a * SfcS -a? : £i; ii U; 7 g g _^ Th^ta 0n ar^ m H Z 8 SKSTSStSf women's homes answering this ouestion. iTs't i t S - ri Cass C1 C &gt; o'f FilIm n re - /""-""•NuckolLs, Otoe. Richardson. Thayer. Seward. Washin B toS * ' "*'*? ' HamlIt ""- Lancaster. Nan.e. Polk. Saumlers. S &gt; u r th K 5 ?t f ia . triC i : , C"™' 1 " 1 - Dakota. Madfcon. Thur.ston. South district: Adams. Furnas, Phclps Central district: • Custcr. Dawson. Hall.' Howard. Valley Southwest .district: Keith. Lincoln. Porkin.. Red wfllow • West district: Cheyenne. Deuel.- Kimball. Morrill. Scotta Bluff. own h d^ nS ln th f * itchen - About thirty per cent of the owners homes and nine per cent of the tenants' homes were so equipped Nine per cent of the homes studied had a pump at a sink, while fourteen per cent had only a kitchen sink with neither pump nor faucet. Of _ the twenty per cent of homes having bathrooms with fnh mn£ 5 « w' •?H 0Ut x! 1 u lf were fully equ»PPed with bowl, tub and flush toilet. Others had the bowl or tub only, or the bowl and tub together, but no homes had the toilet'onlv, or the toilet and bowl without the tub. The flush toilet was ob- v i°Hfly the last of these conveniences to be acquired, because of the difficulty of sewage disposal. In the 1919 study, twenty-four per cent of the homes re - ported bathrooms but only eighteen per cent had funning water connections. About five per cent had bathrooms con - taining a bath tub with a drain, but no running water con - nection. Homes without indoor water connection. — Nearly two - thirds of the homes studied in 1919 and 1924 had 'neither running water nor indoor pump. Water was carried an average distance of 60 feet to the 204 homes without piped-in water studied in 1919. The distance was practically the same l n o«« ase of owners as of tenants. The range was from five * oX« f ee £- To five homes wat er was carried from a distance of 300 feet or more. To 131 of these homes (64 per cent) the water was regularly carried by the housewife ; in thirteen others, she carried water part of the time. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Housing and House Operation Costs Table 10.— Plumbing fixtures in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 192 % — percentages of homes having specified fixtures, by tenure groups • ■ ' ■ v ~7~ ~ Part- | _. u&gt;ar "nd item j AJ1 Owners owners | Tenants Kitchen, 1919 , p. ct . p. ct , p. ct , p cU Tap and sink with drain | 22.7 30.1 8 6 Pump and sink with drain \ 8.7 9 3 7*7 Pump only........ I 1.2 1.4 ""'.. 0*.9 Sink with drain only j 13.7 14.2 12 8 • Bathroom fixtures, 1924 \ 20.2 31.6 23 3 119 Bowl only. ! 2.0 0.9 3.3 25 Tub only | 4.7 9 . 6 0 0 3 x Bowl, tub, toilet | 10.2 13.2 16.7 63 Bowl, tub I 2.9 7.0 3.3 0.0 Tub, toilet ;. I 0.3 • 0.9 0.0 0 0 Lauhdry tubs, 1924.... I 2.9 5.3 3 3 12 Bathroom, 1919 23.6 31.4 8.5 Running water 18.4 25.2 . 51 • Tub only 10.5 13.3 5 # .l Running water 5.2 7.1 .. 17 Tub, toilet- 13.1 18.1 .""" 3*4 Running water .: 13.1 18.1 3.4 Homes without running water 1919 65.9 58.0 81.2 No report 6.4 7.1 5.1 Housewife carried water 42.0 36.3 • 53.0 Usually 38.2 ' 32.3 49°6 Part of time | 3.8 4.0 3.4 Chemical closet •'... 0.7 0.4 „,.;. 0.9 Bathtubs without water'" 4.1 4.4 3J4 ■Based on 342 homes, surveyed in 1924 and 343 in 1919. No hired men's homes reported any of the plumbing fixtures listed here. No home in any tenure reported a tap or a toilet only, and none reported a bathroom having bowl and toilet without tub. ■ Includes 2 chemical toilets reported as having running water connection. Chem - ical toilets are of several kinds, some requiring to be flushed by running water, and others having a receptacle which is carried out of the house by hand. The former only are included here, the latter in "homes without running water". 1 In homes without running water. Plumbing is necessarily at a minimum in these homes with - out water connection. Ninety-eight per cent of them were dependent on privies for the disposal of excrement, while the remainder had chemical toilets. A few other plumbing fix - tures were occasionally | installed. Ten of these homes had bath tubs which were filled by hand, while 47, or nearly one - fourth of the homes without running water, had kitchen sinks with drains. Sinks, tubs, and bowls. — The fixtures listed in Table 11 include kitchen sinks, bath tubs, wash bowls, flush toilets, and stationary laundry tubs, decreasing in number in the order named. Kitchen sinks were found in nearly a third of the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 PER CENT O . 10 • 20 30 4 0 ■ FULLY gg TUB &amp; ffi TUB &amp; (^ tub B BOWL EQUIPPED E3 BOWL ™ TOILET &amp;2 TUB BOWL PlG. 4. — Bathroom equipment in o42 Nebraska farm homes in 1924. The bars represent the percentages of homes equipped with the speci - fied kinds of bathroom equipment. club women's farm homes. The percentages ranged from one-sixth in the westernmost district to over one-third in the central district. Bath tubs and wash bowls were found in one-fifth of the homes, the proportion varying from nearly one-twelfth in the western district to one-fourth in the north - east district. The reports, seem to show that each fixture Table 11. — Sinks, laundry tubs, and bathroom fixtures in Nebraska farm lwmes studied in 1926 — percentages of homes having specified fixtures, by districts District Kitchen Laundry }&lt;nth Wash Flush sinks ' tubs tubs bowls toilet P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. All .'. 31.4 4.1 19.6 19.4 13.4 Southeast 27.5 2.7 20.5 18.2 12.1 East 32.5 3.9 22.2 22.4 17.5 Northeast 30.9 13.7 25.0 24.6 23.7 South 32.7 0.8 15.4 24.3 .8.4 Central 36.3 4.9 ! 23.5 22.2 18.2 Southwest 33.7 4.2 16.2 12.5 10.1 West ■ 17.0 2.0 7.9 6.6 6.0 1 With running water piped to sinks. The schedule does not indicate -whether running water wqs piped to the bowls and tubs. In many clubs there were more homes reporting stationary bath tubs and wash bowls than sinks with running water. It is assumed that if water was not piped to the sink, the bowl and tub in that house were also unconnected although equipped with drains. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Housing and House Operation Costs was frequently installed without the others, and that they sonietimes appeared without running water connection. Flush toilets were found in about one-eighth of the homes, ranging from six per cent in the west district to 24 per cent in the northeast. Stationary laundry tubs were found in only one out of every twenty-five or thirty homes. Conditions in these club women's homes were fairly similar to those in the 1919 and 1924 surveys where comparable items appear; but all three studies showed a higher proportion of homes with con - veniences than the assessors' reports summarized in Table 6. SEWAGE DISPOSAL Table 12. — Sewage disposal in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 1924 — percentages of homes, by tenure groups x ■ 1 : j I Part- I I All tenures \ Owner | owner! Tenant Item ~|l924Ti9i9Tl924 | 1919 | 1924~j 1924 | 1919 '. . .:■:: • . I • :■ • . P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Homes with drains to ! 38.8 46.3 50.0 54.9 40.0 32.5 29.9 Cesspool j 19.5 7.3 28.1 9.7 20.0 14.4 2.6 Septic tank | 0.6 2.6 0.9 3.5 0.0 0.6 0.9 Other outlet 18.7 36.4 21.1 41.6 20.0 17.5 26.4 Stream 1.5 2.6 3.3 0.0 Hillside 0.6 0.9 0.0 0.6 Open ditch i 7.3 10.5 3.3 6.9 Yard ! 5.8 4.4 8.3 6.3 Unspecified I 3.5 2.7 5.0 3.7 1 Based on 3-12 homes in 1924 and 343 in 1919. No hired man's home reported drains. Drains, by tenure groups. — Less than half the homes studied in 1919 and less than two-fifths of those in 1924 were equipped with drains to carry off waste water and sewage. About half the drains in 1924 emptied into cesspools and half into the open — generally into an open ditch or yard although sometimes into a stream or draw. Only two homes out of the 342 had septic tanks. About half the owners' homes had drains of some sort, but only forty per cent of the part - owners' and thirty per cent of the tenants' homes had drains. Cesspools and septic tanks, by districts, 1926. — Nearly one-fourth of the club women's homes had either a septic tank or a cesspool. About four per cent had the former and twenty per cent the latter. Both were commonest in the northeast district, where eleven per cent had septic tanks and thirty per cent cesspools. These homes showed slightly better conditions than those in the earlier surveys, but even here there is great room for improvement. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 O io 22 22 12 J&amp;£ 60 TENANTS Illllll limi WZMgfk PER CENT O 10 20 30 *0 50 60 H SEPTC TANK' gg CESSPOOL ffl DtTCH TARD STREAM Up HILLSIDE £j|3 UNSPtCif ED FlG. 5. — Percentage of 342 Nebraska farm homes with drains to the specified locations. These Nebraska farm homes were less progressive with respect to sewage disposal than in any other aspect studied. The usefulness of running water and bathroom facilities was understood and a great effort had evidently been made to attain them; but an adequate and sanitary system of dis - posing of wastes was very rarely achieved. A hydraulie - engineer has this to say concerning the relative value of the types of sewage disposal discussed above: Table 13. — Cesspools and septic tanks on farms studied in ■ 1926 I Percentage ■with District | Homes 1 I studied I Either ! Septic tank 1 Cesspool i [ : f~ I ; Wo. P. ct. ' P. ct. P. ct. State I 3,440 24.4 4.1 20 3 Southeast I GG9 14.3 3.4 10.9 East 818 27.4 I 2.G 24.8 Northeast 274 40.5 10.9 " 29 6 South 358 17.3 1.1 | 1G.2 Central 017 I 33.0 6.3 | 26.7 Southwest 396 26.5 3.5 23.0 West 317 12.0 1 3.2 . 8.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Housing and House Operation Costs "A tight, underground septic tank with shallow distribu - tion of the effluent in porous soil generally is the safest and least troublesome method of. treating sewage upon the farm, while at the same time more or less of the irrigating and manurial value of the sewage may be realized. . . . That a septic tank is a complete method of sewage treatment is a widespread but wrong impression. . . . The effluent is foul and dangerous. . . . Hence the farmer should safeguard wells and springs from the seepage or discharges from a septic tank as carefully as from those of liquefying closets and cesspools." '•' a • 2T I ' — v, | CESSPOOL Bio I C I =-l §§3 FLUSH TOILET Kami J Ma \ DID SEPTIC TANK S.W.f S. "ifa S.e\ Fig 6 Percentages of 3,449 Nebraska farm homes with cesspools, sep - tic tanks, and flush toilets in 1926, by geographic districts. The farm homes studied were those of home demonstration club members. "Where farms have water under pressure an open or leach - ing cesspool is a common method of disposing of the sewage. . Except under the most favorable conditions the con - struction and use of a cesspool cannot be too strongly con - demned. They are only permissible where no other arrange - ment is possible. Leaching cesspools especially are open to these serious objections: (1) Unless located in porous soil, stagnation is likely to occur, and the failure of the liquid to seep away may result in overflow on the surface of the ground and the creation of a nuisance and a menace. (2) They re - tain a mass of filth in a decomposing condition deep m the ground where it is but slightly affected by the bacteria and air of the soil. . . . There can be no assurance that the foul liquid with little improvement in its condition may not pass into the ground water and pollute wells and springs situated long distances away in the direction of the flow." 10 • Warren Georitc M.. SewaRe and Sewerage of Farm Homes. U. S. Dept. Aar.. Farmers' Bui. 1227, pp. 28-29. Jan.. 1922. "Ibid., pp. 26-27. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 Table 14. — Running water and sewage disposal in Nebraska farm and town homes studied in 1919, 1924, and 1926 ' | Farm homes | Towns, 192G Item "24 1 '. i ; and Under! 1,000- 2,500- I 6,000- 10.000-' 1326 1919 1000 I 2,500 5.000 | 10,000 25,000 Omaha Towns surveyed 67 36 14 9 5 1 Percentage having Public water system 76 100 100 100 100 100 Public sewer system 12 86 92 100 100 100 Regular garbage col* lection 9 11 0 71 100 100 Homes surveyed 3370 685 .... ...... Percentage having Kitchen sinks * 31 31 42 58 ,■ 59 • gl • ■ , 80 94 Stationary wash basins • 19 15 34 49 32 75 75 94 Stationary bath tubs | 20 | 18 28 I 4S 32 72 65 85 Stationary laundry | | tubs I 4 13- 4 6 7 21 15 0.2 Flush toilets | 13 | 12 29 | 45 . 54 • 77 82 94 1 Town data from a survey by the General Federation of Women's Clubs. Figures in the box heads refer to total population of towns. Only fixtures with water connection are counted. = Percentages of farm homes having kitchen sinks are based on 343 homes surveyed in 1919; those having laundry tubs and wash basins arc based in 3 12 homes sur - veyed in 1924; other items in this column include both surveys. Unsafe practices. — Drainage into an open ditch or on the ground surface is even more objectionable than the cesspool because of the danger of fly-borne diseases, while seepage into. a stream or well may spread pollution far and wide. The following "don'ts" may be quoted from the same source as the preceding: "1. Never allow the farm sewage or excrements, even in minutest quantity, to reach the food or water of man or live - stock. "2. Never expose such wastes so that they can be visited by flies or other carriers of disease germs. "3. Never use such wastes to fertilize or irrigate vegetable gardens. "4. Never discharge or throw such wastes into a stream, pond, or abandoned well, nor into a gutter, ditch, or tile dis - tribution system which naturally must lead to some water - course." u Very few of the Nebraska farms studied came up to these standards. Farm and town homes compared. — -The farm columns in Table 14 summarize the data on farm homes presented in the preceding tables. The urban data were gathered at the same time by the General Federation of Women's Clubs in 132 Nebraska towns and cities. All towns over 10,000 in "Ibid., pp. 8-9. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Housing and House Operation Costs iooi — ' . ' 1 H9 @ 90 "" ■■ KITCHEN SINK \ [ ■ z BO — B££J STATIONARY WASH BASINS — J 1 F/773 STATIONARY BATH TUB B I '/\ '0 — f=^ FLUSH TOILETS " ;: : I 5^= I ' - I = ' - 60 S ; E J ! R &lt; = L : L || ||_ ||_ |||_ — 1 II — -:_ pi— \\— \\ !°^ |.^ B j^- jggg- °^ FARMMOMCS I TOWW HOMES BY POKJUfflON OT TCWNS Fig. 7. — Percentages of Nebraska farm and town homes studied in 192G, having specified plumbing fixtures. For the origin of the data and the explanation of the terms used, see footnotes 1 and 2 of Table 14.. population except Lincoln were covered, and so were 90 per cent of those between 5,000 and 10,000 and a considerable proportion of the smaller towns. A conscientious effort was made to cover every family in each town surveyed. Accord - ingly, this report should give a very complete idea of Ne - braska urban housing conditions. Every town of more than 1,000 inhabitants surveyed, and three-fourths of the smaller towns, had a public water supply, but such a public utility, of course, was not within reach of the farm homes. Nevertheless, 31 farm homes out of a hundred had kitchen sinks with water, while urban percent - ages ranged from 42 in towns under 1,000 to 94 in Omaha. The farm showing would not be quite so good if the homes equipped with a hand-pump in the kitchen were subtracted. They constituted ten per cent as shown by the 1919 survey. They are not shown separately by the figures for any other year. In Omaha, substantially every home with running water at the kitchen sink had also a stationary wash basin and a flush toilet, but only 85 per cent had bath tubs. In the smaller towns there were more kitchen sinks than fixtures of any other kind. In all these conveniences there was a steady de - crease from the larger to the smaller towns, the farms having </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 TABLE 15. — Heating systems in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 192 A — percentages of homes using specified means, by tenure groups ' - ' ' "'" ~~] Aii- I PaTtT^ Heating system 1 homes \ Owners owners' Tenants 19 ?4 , , ■ I' P. ct. ! P. ct. \ P. ct. \ P. ct. Wood and coal stoves ! 81.0 74.6 717 88 1 Furnaces : \ 19,0 25.4 28^3 ll]o Hot air | I7.r, . | 21.9- 28.3 119 1 H °t water I 1.5 3.5 0 .0 ' 0.G 1919 Heating stoves :.... 79.4 ! 72.6 93.0 Tended by wife - 1 69.5 i 72.6 60 0 ' Usually ! 59.4 60.8 J ...... 57*3 Part of time ' 10.1 11.8 7.8 Cookstove only , -. 3.2 3.1 I 35 Furnaces i 17.1 j • 23.9 ...... ■■ ! 3.5 ' Nased on 342 homes in 1924 and 340 in 1!U9. This includes eicht hired men's homes in 1924, all of which had wood and coal stoves only. = TendinB means carryinir fuel and ashes. 3'ercentaKes are based on number of homes having stoves for which this service wan reported. Three tenants and eleven owners did not answer this question. them from one-seventh to one-fourth. as often as Omaha. The farms, however, were better supplied than Omaha with stationary laundry tubs. These were most frequent in towns of 5,000 to 10,000 and rarest in Omaha. HEATING FACILITIES House heating, by tenures. — Four out of every five of the homes studied in 1924 were heated by wood and coal stoves only — nearly three-fourths of the homes of owners and part - owners and nine-tenths of the homes of tenants. All hired men's homes were heated by stoves. Of the 65 central heat - ing systems, 60 were hot-air and five hot-water. The enumerators did not ask whether the hot-air furnaces were of the pipeless or multi-pipe variety. Four of the hot-water systems were in the homes of owners and one in the home of a share tenant. The 1919 survey shows practkally the same proportions except for fewer furnaces among the tenants, but it presents a more detailed analysis. In seven-tenths of all homes in 1919, the housewife carried the fuel and disposed of the ashes. This was the case in a slightly larger proportion of owners' than tenants' homes. Eleven homes, or one-thirtieth of the total, had no source of heat but the kitchen stove. These were smaller homes, averaging only 2.9 rooms per house. The houses with furnace heat were more than three times as large (9.4 rooms). The four tenant homes which reported furnaces averaged eleven rooms each. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Housing and House Operation Costs O_ 20 AO 60 60 igp TER CENT 0 20 40 — 55 80 i&amp;O ■ HOT WATER HOT AIR £M HEATING STOVES Fig. 8. — Percentages of 342 Nebraska farm homes with furnaces and heating stoves in 1924. Houses heated only by kitchen stoves averaged 3.5 rooms each in 1924, as compared with 6.2 rooms in stove-heated houses, 7.8 in furnace-heated homes, and 8 rooms in those heated by hot-water systems. By districts, 1926. — The coal or wood stove was the means of heating four-fifths of the farm homes studied in the Home Demonstration Club survey. In the different districts of the state this ranged from about two-thirds in the east and northeast to nine-tenths in the south and southwest. The central heating plants, such as steam, hot-water, and pipeless Tarle 16. — House heating in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1026 — percentages of homes using specified means, by districts ' Furnaces | District Stoves' ■ Multi . , pipe _ ■ jj^— j p7^ - ' All I pipe I leBs I water ) Steam | place r.ct. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. I P.ct. State 78.9 23.1 9.8 9.8 2.8 0.7 0.8 Southeast 84.6 1G.1 7.4 • 6.4 1.7 OS 10 Enst G8.5 33.6 15.4 14.2 3.6 0.4 06 Northeast C7.1 28.8 21.5 6.1 1.6 0 7 2 6 South H7.4 . J3.4 3.6 7.5 2.0 ' 0.3 o'o Central 79.8 24.6 . 7.7 11.4 4.0 1.5 0.6 Southwest 90.4 18.6 3.0 13.7 1.5 0.3 0.6 West 81.4 21.1 10.4 ' 5.7 4.4 0.6 0.9 1 Based on 3,331 Home Demonstration Club homes! All homes with fireplaces had also some other source of heat, and 64 homes hail Loth stoves and furnaces 3 Includes wood and coal stoves. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 ■ I '•'• 'JfMfWW'i-y&amp;iy:.-:-'.-'-.--. ': ■-. ■:'-. ■. : - / ;■■■:• , ■. V- ■ ■ ' --TT 18211 -^%^%%^r/'yr&gt;-^ ; :::U.V::;-;^ VZIZ.L.A ' ' ' ' "'"' T ' 'SO^'-SOPp^i^^^^/^ .■ =.' ■;■ •;-■ -~ s.ooo-io.oooK%%%%^^^^^^^^^;^^; ; /&gt; •. .B.V-: :Vy.*:VA.'' •■"'•' •"■ '" : ; •'''•'■■• ™*™-*s.°°^K%&amp;ZZ?Z^/y/y///y///^ ■■:■ .;-.'.•■■' :.-/ &gt; .--.TTP? PERCtNT ° » 2 " "" £ 5 B 0.L FVJRNACt COAL FURN^E E?]hEAT IW C aTOVE OMLY □ COOKSTOVt ONL* Fig. 9. — Percentages of Nebraska farm and town homes studied in 1920 with furnaces and heating stoves. or multi-pipe hot-air furnaces, heated nearly one-fourth of the homes. The central heating plants were most numerous in the eastern and northeastern parts of the state in such a way as to offset almost exactly the smaller proportions of home's reporting coal or wood heating stoves in these districts. A few homes reported both stoves and furnaces as heating systems. A few others, in the northeastern district, ap - parently depended upon the kitchen cookstove for heat The great bulk of the furnaces found were hot-air furnaces almost equally divided between the pipeless and multi-pipe types More than one out of every forty homes included in this table had a hot-water heating plant. Less than one out of every hundred, even in these selected homes, had a fireplace Doubtless all or nearly all of these homes with fireplaces had also some other source of heat. • re furnaces in town. — In comparing heating facilities in the farm homes surveyed by the Home Demonstration Clubs and town homes surveyed by the General Federation of Women s Clubs, the reader will find a steady increase in the proportion of homes with furnace heat, from less than one - fourth of the farm homes to two-thirds of the Omaha homes </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Housing and House Operation Costs Table 17. — Stoves and furnaces in Nebraska farm and town homes studied in 1926 — percentages of homes using specified means, by population groups 1 [ Homes Homes with furnaces Population p^-oups with ■ ' stoves Any Coal Oil „ P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. i-arm homes 79 23 23 0 Towns Under. 1,000 64 27 2G 1 1,000- 2,500 , 61 39 38 1 2,500- 5,000 „ 64 41 39 2 5,000-10,000 50 50 49 1 10,000-25,000 54 55 50 5 Omaha 34 66 57 9 'Table 17 covers. 3.331 farm homes and the homes of 132 towns and cities 67 under 1.000. 30 of 1.000-2,500. 14 ot 2,500-5.000, 9 of 5.000-10.000 6 of 10 000 - 2K.O00, nnd the city of Omaha. The proportion having oil-burning furnaces was one and two per cent for towns under 10,000, five per cent for towns of 10,000 to 25,000, and nine per cent for Omaha. COOKING FACILITIES Cookstoves, 1919 and 1924.— Nearly one-third of the homes studied in 1924 had only wood or coal stoves for cook - ing. Three-fifths had both a kerosene stove and a wood or coal cookstove. One home in twenty-five had a kerosene stove only. Five homes, all belonging to owners, had some other kind of stove — three had gasoline stoves, one an electric stove, and one a gas stove. Table 18. — Cookstoves in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 1924 — percentages of homes liaving specified kinds, by tenure groups . Part^ Hired Year and item All Owners owners Tenants men 1924 &gt; .P.ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Wood and coal stoves only.. 32.7 36.8 26.7 30.6 50.0 Kerosene stoves only - 4.1 3.5 3.3 4.4 12.5 Both 61.7 55.3 70.0 65.0 37.5 Others 3 1.5 4.4 0.0 0.0 0.0 1019 ' Kerosene stoves" » \.\ 73.2 72.6 0.0 74.6 0.0 1 Based on 3-12 homes. 3 Gasoline and distillate included. 3 Includes 1 electric, 1 gas, and 3 gasoline vapor stoves. * Based on 340 homes. •Only kerosene stoves were asked for by the questionnaire, but one carbide and ono BlauRas stove, reported in marginal notes, are included here. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 Table 19^—Fuei for cooking in Nebraska farm homes studied in 19^6— percentages of homes using specified kinds by districts * ■ ' J n . . 1 Wood | j Dlstrlct j and coal | Kerosene 1 Gas :i lElectricitv g a st •• - .92.6 53.0 1.1 03 K£ ea8t -•! 93-8 50.8 0.4 7 6 S ou th 89.9 42.7 1.7 0 0 Central 90 . 2 52.2 3 7 08 J 92 . 8 504 £ 0 * West ■■- I 7.6.3 i 58.7 6.C j 0.9 M&amp;^K'dS^ WMch ""* »»« «».» «»• "--of fue.. • Pipe sytscm. A larger proportion of part-owners than of any other tenure group had both kerosene and wood and coal stoves while a larger proportion of hired men had wood and coaf stoves only. The possession of a kerosene stove is a great advantage, especially in summer, because it does not heat the kitchen so much as the wood or coal range. The 1919 questionnaire asked only about "kerosene stoves for summer use". Nearly three-fourths of both owners and tenants reported this convenience. The homes of 1919 made a better showing in this respect than those of 1924, two-thirds of which had kerosene stoves. Fuel for cooking, 1926.— Nine-tenths of the club women's farm homes used wood or coal in cooking; half used kero - sene, gasoline, or distillate; one in forty used acetylene or other gas piped to the stove by a pipe system ; and one in one hundred reported cooking by electricity. From, this it appears that nearly two-fifths even of these club women's homes used the coal or wood cookstove at all times, half had kerosene - type stoves at least for summer use, and nearly one-tenth had only kerosene-type stoves for cooking. It may well be doubted whether the one per cent who reported cooking by electricitv made it their main reliance, It is at least possible that some of them merely supplemented other types of stoves by using electric grills, toasters, and percolators, but did not rely upon electric ranges for all their cooking. Water-heaters.— Water-heaters were connected with a piped water system in one-fourth of the club women's farm homes studied. The proportion was quite variable, ranging from two-fifths in the northeast district down to one-eighth in the west district. Practically all the heaters were attached to stoves or to furnaces, usually to stoves. Only one out of every </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Housing and House Operation Costs Table 20. — Water-heaters connected to piped water in Ne - braska farm homes studied in 1926 — percentages of homes tvith specified types, by districts 1 j Any | Type of heater District I connected | Stove | Furnace Gas i heaters | heaters ] heaters heater • I I P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. State 1 25.8 19.1 6.C O.I Southeast i 26.5 22.1 4.3 0.0 East i 29.8 21.0 8.8 0.0 Northeast i 41.6 . 26.3 15.3 0.0 South 1 17.9 ■ 14.8 3.1 0.0 Central :.. 26.9 .18.3 7.9 0.6 Southwest i 21.7 18.2 3.5 0.0 West : | 12.2 9A 3.2 I 0.0 1 Based on 3.449 Home Demonstration Club women's farm homea. thousand reported a gas heater attached to a modern water system. Incidentally, this table shows that at least one-fourth of these homes had hot and cold water piped to some part of the house. LIGHTING FACILITIES Lighting, by tenures, 1924 and 1919. — A little less than nine-tenths of the homes studied in 1924 depended entirely upon lamps for artificial light — from 73 per cent of the owners to 98 per cent of the tenants, and all of the hired men. About two-thirds of all homes had kerosene lamps" only, one-sixth Table 21. — House lighting in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1919 and 1924 — percentages of homes using specified means . ~~ —] AlT Part- Year and item | tenures Owners owners. Tenants 10041 P.ct. P.ct. P. ct. P.ct. Lamps 8(5.3 72.8 80.0 I 97.5 Kerosene only 66.7 57.0 61.7 73.8 Gasoline only 15.5 15.8 16.7 15.6 Both I 4.1 0.0 1.6 8.1 .Electricity 9.6 19.3 13.3 1.9 Farm system 4.7 &amp;.3 13.3 1-3 Central system 4.9 14.0 0.0 0.6 Other* 4.1 7.9 6.7 0.6 1919 :t Lamps 84.7 81.0 92.1 Electricity 8.2 11.5 1.8 "Gas" :•- 7.1 7.5 1 6.1 ■ Based on 342 homes. Only kerosene lamps were used in the eight hired men'l homes. The "All tenure" column is affected accordingly. 5 Vncludes carbide. Blaugas. and any other illuminating gas. 9 Based on 340 homes. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 PER " NT ° » « is -~i J o ■ ELECTRIOTY BE] ILLUMINATING «wj GASOLINE prj KEROSENE KSS GAS v!^ fc22 LAMP lU LAMPS ONLr § GASOLINE ANL&gt; KEROSENE Fig. 10.— Percentages of 342 Nebraska farm homes with specified types of lighting in 1924. .. ' Includes carbide. Blaueas. and other illuminating gas. ■ Gasoline lamps only. had gasoline lamps only, and one home in twenty-five had both types Electricity furnished the light for a tenth of 5Itfr eS 'rfW* O i whl ? h obtained it from a central power station and half from individual generating systems Onlv three of these homes were those of tenants, and none was that of a hired man. Of the seventeen homes connected with central systems, ten were in Washington Countv. Fourteen homes, or one-twenty-fifth of all, had systems such as carbide plrt-owSs ThirtGen ° f theSe Were the homes of owners or The 1919 study showed only unimportant divergences from these proportions. There was not so wide a difference in the proportion of owners and tenants dependent upon oil lamps only. Fewer homes had electricity, and more had gas, but these differences were slight. ,.-■'■ By districts, 1926.— Of the 3,407 homes included in Table 22, one out of every six was lighted by electricity, and nearly one out of every twenty by gas. Most of thenvwere lighted by means of kerosene lamps, almost equallv divided between kerosene mantle lamps and those of the wick tvpe In tab ulation, mantle lamps which burned gasoline 'or distillate were included with kerosene mantle lamps. The proportion of homes relying upon the different kinds of artificial lighting varied greatly from district to district in a way that i" not </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Housing and House Operation Costs Table 22 .—House lighting in Nebraska farm homes studied J?J? 2G SI 1 L?L &lt; i entages °f homes ™in9 specified means l _.:■... Wick Mantle | -gi strict lamps 2 lamps 3 | Gas * Electricity State : ! -ft? P 4h f \f P h f |o«Jheasl G 4.9 5G.8 \k ill East 37.3 37-5 ? £ |J-| SS^ east I 47.8 29.9 0 7 274 S° u J h , ' • J 48.3 61.5 39 7 0 g en £ al 44.3 45.9 4.2 237 Southwest 48.7 42.4 3 5 154 **.?*- 40.1 54.C 6.G 101 maTu^^e'Tamps. '" dU ° l ° thC fabt thSt many h ° me * P«~ -"dffih 3M[ 1 Kerosenc-burninjr. 1 « l l'T!e" US -» kCrOSOne- Basoline - and distillate mantle tamps. entirely easy to explain. In the southeastern part of the state only one home out of every nine had electric lights as compared with one out of every four in the northeastern' corner of the state and in the central district. Gas was more irequently found in the east and west districts than in any others of the seven from which data were obtained In the northeast corner of the state where electricity was most commonly found, gas was practically absent— found in less than one home out of every one hundred. POWER ON THE FARM The extension of household conveniences in the farm home depends very largely upon the utilization of power. Electricity is the most convenient and adaptable form of power where it can be had. Table 23 shows how many of the club women's homes had this convenience and how many others were within three miles of a transmission line, and Table 24 compares the electrical and gas equipment used in farm and town homes. Electric current. — One out of every six homes had electric current, usually from a home plant but sometimes from a central station. The proportion ranged from about one-third in the northeast district to about one-twelfth in the west and south districts. Current from a home plant was found in one-tenth of the homes, but that from the central station in one out of every forty or fifty (2.3 per cent). Current from a transmission line from a central station was used by larger proportions of the central and east district homes than in the other districts. More than a fourth of all the homes were </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 Table 23. — Electric current in Nebraska farm homes studied in 1926 — percentages of hatyies with and without current by districts l - I Districts ItM " | All [, S. E. E. | N, E, | S. | C. | S. W. I W~ I ~ ' I I _ . P- C- P- cl. P. ct. P. ct. 7*. ct. I', ct. | P. ct. I' cl Farms having current 1G.0 12.0 20. 9 32 3 8 7 23 •» 1" 1 I S " Home plant 10.4 G.8 15.7 12.5 7.G 144 S'l 4*i Central station 2.3 2.5 2.7 0.0 1.1 4.4 13 V2 Unspecified 4.2 2.7 2.5 19.8 0.0 4 4 S 7 2 7 Farms with no current. 83.1 88.1 70.1 G7.7 01.3 76 8 878 ill'! Miles to transmission lines: - Under 1 10.4 15.5 16.4 7.3 3.8 G.4 6 4 j 1 8 J-2 "7.8 8.1 13.fi 3.1 G.5 5.3 4.0 3.2 ' * " »- • 10.4 8.0 16.2 9.4 10.3 G.2 10.4 5.9 O y er 3 54.5 55.G 32.0 47.9 70.7 58.9 G7.0 80.G 1 Based on 2,815 Home Demonstration Club women's farm homes within three miles of a transmission line from which current might have been secured, and yet did not have it. The small proportion availing themselves of this opportunity is doubt - less due to the high cost of the transformers and installation. Farm and town compared. — Table 24 summarizes the percentages of farm homes using the various electrical and gas household devices and compares them with homes in towns of different sizes, as shown by the club women's survey. All the towns of more than 1,000 population and all but one of the 66 towns under 1,000 had central lighting plants. From three-fourths to nine-tenths of the town homes availed them- Table 24. — Electricity, gas, and gasoline power in Nebraska - farm and town homes studied in 1926 l I | Towns Item I Farm Under I 1.000- J 2,500- I 5.000- I lO.oTlO- |~" ; I homes 1.000 | 2,500 I 5,000 I 10,000 ( 25,000 j Omaha ' Towns surveyed 66 36 14 9 g 1 Percentage having Electric plant 99 100 100 100 100 100 Gas plant 0 G 21 78 " 100 100 Homes surveyed 3,407 Percentage with electric Lights 17 84 85 82 75 8!) 74 Irons 13 54 62 48 fin 5&lt;) ' 57 Washing machine.. 14 29 33 24 40 48 ' "&gt;G Vacuum cleaner .... 6 21 28 18 31 17 Jo Range 1 4 5 4 1 I 2 T Sewing machine .... 1-4 .6. 3 22 4 Refrigerator ' 1 . 0.'4 0.6 0.2 1 1 ■ o.5 Percentage with gas Main connection 0 0 3 '10 40 51 G8 Lights * 6 0 0 0 0.5 0 1 Range 1 _. 3 0 2 8 35 47 I ' 68 Water heater * 0.1 0 0.G 2 13 21 I 41 Gasoline engine 48 .... .... .... .,„ . I 1 Town data from a survey by the General Federation of Women's Clubs Box head* refer to total population of town. 3 Carbide and Blaugas are included for farm homes but nowhere else. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Housing and House Operation Costs 901 1 80 ■ 70 _ 60 - g so : 3 — _ 5 § § | % -l.fi ° £ §1 = — ~ % a. 5 i 5 E J = g q.^0 i- 5 $-. &lt;z &lt; . |l_ |l L |r pi p ™» «»« Ss" al- T^ q^ ~ ' TOWNS .BY POPULATIOM ■ LIGHTS S IRONS g WASHERS FIG. 11. — Percentages of Nebraska farm and town homes studied in 1926 with specified electrical conveniences. selves of this facility. The lowest of all the urban percent - ages was in Omaha,- where 74 per cent of the homes were electrically lighted. Among the farm homes seventeen out of a hundred were so lighted, or a little less than one-fourth of the Omaha proportion and one-fifth of the highest urban pro - portion recorded. On the other hand, when the farm home does have elec - tricity, it is more likely than the toyn home to make use of a number of power devices. Seven-ninths of the farm homes which had electric lights used electric irons, and more than four-fifths owned electric washing machines. In the towns about two-thirds of those with electric lights used electric irons, and from one-third to one-half used the electric wash - ing machine. These devices were less frequently found in the country, but where the connection for them existed at all they were more frequent, and the same was true of vacuum cleaners although fewer homes possessed them in either town or country. Electric ranges were rare anywhere, but rarest hi farm homes and the towns of over 5,000. The figures for farm homes, however, may be a little high for the reasons discussed on page 26. Electric refrigerators were found in one farm home out of a hundred, and no group had them more frequently. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 The place of illuminating gas in the towns is occupied, to a limited extent, by carbide or Blaugas systems on the farms No town of under 1,000 in the survey reported a gas plant so no illuminating gas was used in these homes. How many of the town homes used other gas was not reported, but in towns having gas works the use of carbide and Blaugas would naturally be negligible. The proportion of homes having gas connection mounted from three per cent in towns of 1,000 to 2,500 per cent in Omaha. Except in that city, however, not all the homes so connected used gas for cooking. Few or none of the town homes used gas lights, except "in Omaha, and even there only one home in one hundred had them. On farms where electricity is not available, a stationary engine can often be used for household purposes such as pumping, or running the washing machine, cream separator or churn. Forty-eight farms out of a hundred reported stationary engines, but only three out of a hundred used them for pumping water into the house, and not more than 37 per cent used them for laundering. RENTAL AND OPERATING COSTS PER YEAR SUMMARY OF COSTS £? s * 1 ?t' , by tenures - — The rental and house-operation cost on the Nebraska farms studied was $373 per home for the year ending June, 1924. The rental value of the house, assumed TABLE 25. — Rental value of dwelling house and operating costs per Nebraska farm home studied in 192J t } Tt m (• A » I" I Part- I • I Hired". ■ " cm | tenures | Owners | owners | Tenants) men Total family expenditure • S1.G81.2S $1,654.97 $2,05G.7G $1 593 ?9 397&gt;&gt; 86 Rental and house-oporatinp; costs :i72.GG 393.61 439 S7 838 66 24004 Rental value of house' 203.52 225.93 245.7B 17550 126.68 House-operatinz costs 1C9.14 1G7.GS KM. 12 loridfi lSiflg Furniture and furmshinRs • 42.9S 39 75 53 io 11V.S a?7s Fuel and li B ht , 95.70 HG^O llts? 9 .09 ?,V« Telephone .......: ,. 11.82 ic.ir, 13.7.11 11.7' 1 00 Clcanine supplies' 10.23 9.43 10.10 10*70 12.49 « c ••-; ■• 2.27 2.31 2.21! -&gt;•".! 7'.n Insurance* .....I 3.]., :!73 ., s ,. 2.fi3' . ' o'.OO Percentage of total expenditure for : I P. ct. P. ct P ct \ P ct /• rt Rental and huusc-operatint; costs 22 2 23 8 "13 i 21" •&gt;"-? Rental value of house. 12 1 n'7 j,'), Tin fir? Housc-operatinc eosL-i 10.1 lo'l r{\ ' in'o i-.- Furniturc and furnishinRs _. " c, "I •&gt;&lt;• &lt; or -ji' FubI and licht ". 5'; ?,'h 54 I (, 2" Miscellaneous l. s | {;g \\.. \ J;J |-« 'Includes estimates for the value of jroo.ls and services furnished In- the farm •Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house 4 Purchased during the year. 5 Lye. soap (except toilet), clcaninc powders, bluinc matchn -in,! "nih. , •• </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Housing and House Operation Costs O [00 200 300 400 iOO DOLLARS 100 200 300 400 300 ■ RENTAL VALUE ra FURNISHINGS rrnHHiX. OF FUEL nTTI M1 c r OF HOUSE ESS PURCHASED K2JAND LIGHT "M Fig. 12. — Rental value per dwelling and average cost of house operation in 310 Nebraska farm homes. The figures cover the year ending June, 1924. to be ten per cent of its estimated value, was $204, and the cost of operating the house $169. Fuel, at $96 per home, was the main expense item in house operation, but $43 was spent for new furniture and furnishings during the year, and $15 for telephone costs. The .remaining $15 was for cleaning supplies, ice, and insurance on furniture. Insurance carried on the house is not included sepai'ately because the sum esti - mated as the rental value of the house includes an allowance for risk, whether the risk was carried by the householder or transferred to an insurance company. The rental and house - operation costs aniounted to more than one-fifth of the total value of family living, including both cash expenditures and estimates for the value of goods and services furnished by the farm. The rental and operation costs of part-owners were higher than those of any other tenure. The part-owners lived in more valuable homes and spent more for fuel and furniture than the other tenure groups. The hired men lived in the cheapest houses and spent less than the other tenure groups for every item of house-operation costs except cleaning sup - plies. Yet, because their expenditures for food, clothing, and so forth were still further below those of the other tenures, hired men devoted a slightly greater proportion of the total </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 value of their family living to housing and house-operation costs than did the other tenure groups. Proportion of homes reporting various costs. — All the homes included in the table reported on rental value of houses, fuel costs, and cleaning supplies. Ninety per cent of them paid something during the year for furniture and furnishings, averaging $48 per home making such purchases ; 75 per cent had telephones costing $20 per home so equipped ; 45 per cent paid insurance on furniture to the value of $7 per insured home; and 28 per cent used ice to the value of $8 per home using it. Twenty homes put up their own ice; the other 76 which used ice purchased it. Relatively more homes of owners than of i any other tenure group reported telephones ; more part-owners reported the purchase and insurance of fur - niture; and more tenants reported ice. Cost summary, by areas. — The two easternmost areas, in Washington and Lancaster Counties, resembled each other in housing costs. With total family expenditures of $1,910 and $1,793 respectively, their rental and house-operating costs per home averaged $422 and $481, or 22 and 27 per cent of the total family expenditures. House rent and the annual cost of furniture, fuel, telephone, and ice were higher in the Lancaster County homes than in those of any other area studied. The Clay County homes, with a total family ex - penditure of only $1,284 per home and with rental and house - operation costs of only $270, stood lowest in both housing costs and general living costs. Their house-rent and furnish - ings costs were lower than those of any other area studied The Kimball County homes, with a total family expenditure of $1,736 and with rental and house-operation costs of $295, devoted the lowest proportion of their total living costs to housing (17 per cent). They also spent less than any other area for fuel, telephone, ice, and insurance on furniture. VALUE AND RENT OF HOUSE Value of house. — The value of the dwellings studied in 1924 was estimated to be replacement costs minus deprecia - tion, as nearly as these could be ascertained by the field work - ers with the help of the occupants of the house. Since farm dwellings are rarely if ever sold apart from other farm prop - erty, the usual basis of valuation — the price which the dwelling would bring if sold — could not be used. The average value per house, estimated as described, was $2,035, and ranged from $1,253 in the Clay County area to $2,639 in the Lancaster County area. This was somewhat higher than the average value of farm dwellings as given for April, 1930, by the Fifteenth Census of the United States. According to this </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Housing and House Operation Costs census, Nebraska farmhouses averaged 81,719 for the state and $1,779 for the four counties in which the 1924 survey was conducted. Some allowance must be made for the fall in farm property values and in building costs between 1924 and 1930, but the survey should be expected to show higher hous - ing standards than the census. .According to the census farmhouses in Washington County in 1930 were worth $2 255 in Lancaster County $1,899, in Clay County $1,348, and iii Kimball County $1,146. 1:! This was considerably less than the survey figure for each area except that in Clay County The part-owners studied in 1924 had the most valuable houses, while owners, tenants, and hired men followed in the order named. Besides being classified by tenure groups, the 340 homes reporting family living costs were classified into four ex - penditure groups according to the total amount spent for family living, including estimates for the shelter, food, and fuel furnished by the home farm. The value of the dwelling house rose steadily along with the total expenditure from $1,367 in the group spending under $1,200 for family living to $3,389 in the group spending over $2,400 for family living. In each expenditure group the homes of owners and part - owners were more valuable on the average than the homes of tenants and hired men. The owner-operator and his family get the benefit of any improvements made on the dwelling and are therefore more likely to have them than the tenant of equal income, who has to depend upon the landlord for such improvements. Age of house. — The age of the farmhouse is a factor of considerable importance in its value. The average age of the farmhouses studied in 1924 was twenty-four years. Part - owners' houses, besides being the most valuable, were the newest, averaging nineteen years old; owners' houses came next at twenty-three years ; tenants' next at twenty-six years ; and hired men's houses at forty years were the oldest of all. The houses in the Washington, Lancaster, and Clay County areas averaged about the same age, between twenty-five and twenty-eight years. The houses of the Kimball County area were much newer, averaging twelve years old. This explains why the houses in the Kimball County area were more valu - able than those in Clay County, although they were smaller and had fewer modern conveniences than those of any other area studied. The number of farms in Kimball County has increased from 112 in 1900 to 527 in 1925.'- This recent in - crease accounts for the presence of many new farmhouses in 15 Fifteenth Census of the U. S.. 1930, pp. 4, 7, 15, and 22. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 that area. The number of farms in the other three counties combined has decreased during the same period, from 7,144 to 6,390. "■..". Rental value. — The rental value for a year is assumed to be ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. Table 26 presents this rental value by tenure and expenditure groups. The proportion of the total family expenditure de - voted to rent decreased from fourteen per cent in homes spend - ing less than $1,200 for family living to eleven per cent in homes spending $2,400 and more. The rental value of tenants' houses constituted a slightly lower percentage of their total family living cost than that of owners' houses in the same expenditure group. Table 26. — Rental value of dwelling house per Nebraska farm, home studied in 1924, by tenure and expenditure groups 1 ■ ' I AU j I rnrt- I ]~Hire&lt;r Expenditure groups [tenures | Owners [owners | Tenants | men Rental value of house All expenditure groups I J20S.B8 $225.03 $245,751 S175.. r &gt;0| $126.06 Under $1.200 1S2.66 136.20 154.29 12."&gt;.7h 132.24 $1,200 - $1.799....: .-. 170.95 103.. r &gt;7 1G2.22I 100.91 ■ &lt;IO.OO $1,800 - $2,390 2G3.15 300.91. 251. 5'J 245.3" $2,400 and over 3.18.88 382.14 400.70 1S2.22 PercentaKO of total expenditure • I', ct. | /\ ct. P. ct. 1'. ct. 1*. ct.- All expenditure croups 12.1 [ 13.7 11.9 11.0 13.1 Under $1.200 13.6 111 14.3 12.8 14.4 ,$1,200- $1.799 11.4 ; VS.\ 10.2 10.8 0.5 $1,800 - $2.399 12.7 I 14.7 12.0 | 11.9 $2.400 and over 11.2 | 12.0 | 12.7 | r,.5 ' | 1 The 340 homes reporting family expenditures were grouped according to thuir total expenditures for a year, including estimate-; for troods and services furnished by the farm (Kirkpatrick's "value of family living"). Kijchty-three homes indicated a ' total expenditure of Ics3 than $1,200; 182 .spent S1.200-$1.799 ; 89 spent Jt.«00-S2.3'ja : and 36 spent $2,400 or more. The rental value of the house is assumed to he ten per cent of its estimated value. FURNITURE AND FURNISHINGS Furnishings on hand. — The value of the furniture and furnishings on hand at the. close of the year studied was $603 per home in the 330 homes where it could be estimated. The value of the furniture and furnishings decreased from $712 in owners' homes to only $232 in hired men's homes. The Washington County homes had the most valuable furnishings, worth $769 per home; the Lancaster and Clay County homes stood about even at $595 and $589 per home, while the fur - nishings in the Kimball County homes were worth only $456. In the homes spending less than $1,200 for family living, the value of the furnishings was $406. per home. Homes in the "Fourteenth Census of the U. S., 1920, 0:091-098. U. S. Census of Ai:r., 1925. Part I, p. 1,129. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Housing and House Operation Costs Table 27.— Value of furnishings on hand and purchased __dunng year in Nebraska farm homes studied in lS AlMenures __Owner3 Part-owners! Tenant Hired men " Item ■" •» n s^ ULLA±jLJ_iL±jL i^HJuJ!li!il inB°t n he^ r at C ' OSO ° f y ° ar - Thc sepdrate items in «=l«de only purchases made dur - • Includes linens and draperies. Includes musical instruments and phonograph records f. Includes mantles and chimneys. Includes pictures, shades, tools, trunks, and babj&lt; carriaees. $2,399) were a httle above the general average, owninjr fur - ?nfSoin?^ ?6 J 3 % nd 8 Homes s g pen5 - ?Allrf 00 r r a u nd^ mOr - e u- Or family llvin^ had furnishings valued at $890. The furnishings of the owners in each expenditure group were valued at considerably more than the average for the group while those of tenants and hired men were valued at less Owners, being somewhat older than the other oper - an^Tfurnlshin S Set time in which to accumulate furniture Purchases during the year. — Purchases of furniture and madp durin £ the year averaged $43 for each of the 340 homes studied, or $48 for each of the 304 homes indi - cating any such purchases. The articles most commonly bought were laundry equipment, lamps, rugs and draperies, kitchen utensils and tableware, and furniture, in the order named. These and other purchases are shown in Table 27, together with the cost per home reporting such purchases Part-owners spent the most and hired men the least for turnishmgs. Owners, although they owned more valuable furnishings than any other tenure group, spent less for new purchases than part-owners during the year ptudied. Less than two-thirds of the families in the Washington County area indicated any purchases of furniture and furnishings although the 46 families so indicating spent $84 each In the </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 Lancaster, Clay, and Kimball County areas nearly every family bought something, to an average value of $61, $27, and $31 respectively. Purchases by tenure and expenditure groups. — The fur - nishings purchases per home rose from $11 in homes spending less than $1,200 for family living to $116 in homes spending $2,400 and more. The furnishings cost in this highest ex - penditure group was perhaps abnormally high because of one Table 28. — Furniture and furnishings benight per Nebraska farm home studied in 1924, by tenure and expenditure groups l . - I All 1 I PartT"] I Hired expenditure groups | tenures | Owners |owncrs | Tenant-s| men Value per home All expenditure croup* $42.08 $30.75 $53.30 $4103 $37 73 $1,800 - $2.300 55.68 80.30 50.19 40 581 J2.400 and over 115.75 91.43 84.25 199.0D| ""Z" Percentage of total expenditure I*, ct P ct I* ct V ct I P ct All expenditure croups 2.7 2.4' 2.G ' 2.6 ' 39' Under $1.200 1.1 0 8 OS 1" 10 $1,200 - $1,799 2.3 "5 3 og ' 2"? $1,800 - $2,399 ; 2.7 3.9 23 21 ' $2.400 and over 3.g 3.0' o!l 7!l ' Th ?. . 34 ° n ? mcs reporte.1 family expenditures were grouped according to^Lheir~total "Penditurcs for n year, including estimates for goods and services furnished by in" Washington County tenant home which was newlv furnished throughout at a cost of $1,500. The variation in furnishings cost was extreme — from .nothing to the $1,50.0 just mentioned — and on this account the averages shown for the tenure and expenditure groups in Table 28 are somewhat irregular. The proportion of the total family living. cost spent for furniture increased steadily in successive expenditure groups from one per cent in the under-$l,200 group to four per cent in the $2,400-and-over group. FUEL AND LIGHT Total fuel cost per home. — -The total value of fuel for heating and lighting the farm homes studied was $96 per home. Owners and tenants did not vary greatly from this average, but the fuel of part-owners was worth $111 and that of hired men only $64 per home. Since the value of the wood, corn cobs, and electricity produced on the home farm for familv use was $47, the cost of purchased fuel was only $49 per home. A little less than half the value of owners' and tenants' fuel was home-furnished ; a little more than half that of part - owners', and about five-sixths that of hired men's fuel </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Housing and House Operation Costs The value of the fuel used in the Lancaster area was $116 per home; in Washington County $96; in Clay CouSy $88 and m Kimball County $78. The size of the fLmhouTe, the number of rooms unused in winter, and the type of fuel were important factors in the fuel cost. Table 29.— Fuel arid light costs in Nebraska farm homes studied in 192 A ii,.,,, . „ Per home reporting " ems iHomes reporting ' specified fu.1 Any fuel . "?~ ,£;&lt;* P»f« Amt. Value Furnished lil 1 ??»° 186.70 nouKht ■ ■■ • |i5 . "i B7 - 14 Wood il° "f-J ••■• ■••• 49.52 Furnished , }2l ™-} C ° rd 9 -&lt; 48.98 Coal • - „?? *■* " 4.4 20.50 Electricity 234 , 68 .-* Ton 3.7 47.36 Furnished .. ! " 14 *i K.W.H. 140.G 30.42 Bousht :...ZZ" ,J 2? , 100 ° 2B - 00 Kerosene \ ," O 2™ J. 143 - 6 SO -8S Gasoline' V ■ 3 J5 ™r\ G ,?'- 8B.6 13.08 Furnished P? | 2 " 4 25.21 Three household boucht part and furnished part of their wood nnd cobs. Types of fuel used.— Most homes used several kinds of tuel. Kerosene, corn cobs, coal, and wood were each burned by more than half the homes, decreasing in frequency in the n /S, ed ' 3S f° Wn in Table 29 ' Near] y all the cobs and most of the wood came from the home farm. One home in s?ovPsnvT*! an a T e h age ° f twent y- six gallons !of gasoline in wT L TJ The avera * e amount of electricity consumed foi household purposes was estimated at 141 kilowatt-hours per home using it. Most of the homes using electricity were those of owners. Otherwise tenure differences in type of fuel . W? oc | . w as burned by about seven homes out of ten studied m Washington and Lancaster Counties, by six out of ten in Clay County, and by only one out of six in Kimball County Correspondingly, the use of coal was commoner in the two hn,tV?\ C °u ntie ? Yu e l e more than four homes out of five bought it, than in the two eastern counties where only a little more than half the homes bought it. Almost everv home in the Lancaster and Clay County areas burned corn cobs but only three-fourths of those in Washington County and hatf of those in Kimball County. Because so few Kimball County farms had home-raised -wood and cobs to burn' the homes in </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 264 this area, although the value of the fuel burned was lower than in any other area studied, paid $66 for purchased fuel, or more than was spent in any other area. The Lancaster County homes, burning fuel worth considerably more than that of the Kimball County homes, spent only. $36 for pur - chased fuel, or less than the homes of any other area. GENERAL SUMMARY . FARM HOUSING IN NEBRASKA COMPARED" WITH OTHER STATES Nebraska and eleven other states. — The Nebraska farms studied had slightly, smaller houses and families than 2.886 farm homes in eleven states studied by E. L. Kirkpatrick at about the same date, which averaged 4.8 persons and 6.8 rooms per household. 14 The number of rooms per person was exactly the same (1.4) in the Nebraska homes as in the 2,886 homes. The rental value per house was closely similar — $200 in the 2,886 homes and $204 in the Nebraska homes. So was the value of purchased furniture and furnishings, which averaged $40 in the 2,886 homes and $43 in the Nebraska homes. The average value of fuel was a little higher in Ne - braska — $96 as. compared with $85 in the 2,886 homes — but 1,130 of the latter were located in three southern states^ Kentucky, South Carolina, and Alabama. Modern housing conveniences in thirty-three states. — A questionnaire sent to 10,044 farm homes in thirty-three states by the United States Department of Agriculture in 1919 showed that 47 per cent of . the homes replying had water in the kitchen, 32 per cent running water on the farm. 60 per cent sinks with drains, 20 per cent bath tubs, and 18 per cent furnace heat. The eastern states stood above the percentage for the thirty-three states in all these items and the western states below it ; no southern or southwestern states were circularized. 15 If these responses are typical, the Nebraska farm homes rank a little low in respect to piped-in water and sinks with drains, but about medium, in respect to bath tubs and furnaces. CONCLUSIONS The Nebraska farm homes studied appeared to be fairly typical of the average American farm home in size, rooms per person, value of house, and the annual value of housing and house-opei'ation. Overcrowding was not a problem ex - cept in a few western counties where the number of farms 14 Kirkpatrick, E. L. The Farmers' Standard of Livinjr. U. S. Dcpt. Apr. Bui. 14G6. pp. 21-24. 102C. 11 Unpublished report of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, Extension Work Department. Summarized in "An Undeveloped Country for the Plumbing and Heat - ine Industries," National Trade Extension Bureau of the l'lunibini; and Heating Industries, 1926, pp. 3-5. Evnnsville, Ind. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Housing and House Operation Costs has been rapidly increasing because of the breaking-up of grazing land for dry-farming and tractor farming. This rapid recent development of the extreme western counties of the state has brought about conditions in some places resembling those of pioneer days, with a good many small, crowded, hastily erected homes. The number of Nebraska farm homes with modern water bath, heat, and light has increased rapidly and constantly between 1920 and 1930. Farmers have evidently made great efforts to obtain modern household conveniences, especially piped-in water, tub or shower baths, and radios. In spite of these efforts, only a minor fraction of farm homes have any of the conveniences studied except telephones. Nebraska farm homes rank distinctly below Nebraska town and city homes of every population class in every important modern home convenience for which comparable data were obtained. Modern sanitary sewage disposal is seldom found in Nebraska farm homes. Owners' and part-owners' houses were larger, more valu - able, better furnished, and much better equipped with modern household conveniences than the houses of tenants. Even when owners and tenants spent about the same amount for family living, the owners had the more valuable homes. Owners and tenants spent about the same amount for furnish - ings, fuel, and miscellaneous house-operation costs during the year studied, but part-owners spent more than either. Housing standards generally decreased from the eastern areas studied to the western areas, although there were some exceptions to this trend. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>