<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00044.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00044.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Second Biennial Report Department of Labor Department of Compensation 1917-1918</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SECOND BIENNUAL REPORT Department of Labor DEPARTMENT OF COMPENSATION 1917-1918 GOVERNOR KEITH NEVILLE COMPENSATION COMMISSIONER GEORGE E. NORMAN CHIEF DEPUTY COMPENSATION COMMISSIONER </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT SECTION II Second Biennial Report of Compensation Department IF- If you keep your head when all about you Are losing theirs and blaming it on you; If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you, But make allowance for their doubting, too; If you can wait and not be tired by waiting, Or being lied about, don't deal in lies, Or being hated don't give way to hating, And yet don't look too good, nor talk too wise; If you can dream — and not make dreams your master; If you can think — and not make thoughts your aim, If you can meet with Triumph and Disaster And treat those two imposters just the same; If you can bear to hear the truth you've spoken Twisted by knaves to make a trap for fools, Or watch the things you gave your life to, broken, And. stoop and build 'em up with wornout tools; If you can make one heap of all your winnings And risk it on one turn of pitch-and-toss, And lose, and start at your beginnings And never breathe a word about your loss; If you can force your heart and nerve sinew To serve your turn long after they are gone, And so hold on when there is nothing in you Except the Will which says to them: "Hold on!" If you can talk with crowds and keep your virtue, Or walk with Kings — nor lose the common touch, If neither foes nor loving friends can hurt you, If all men count with you, but none too much; If you can fill the unforgiving minute With sixty seconds' watch of distance run, Yours is the Earth and everything in it, And — which is more — you'll be a Man, my son! — Rudyard Kipling. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 3 PARTI Introduction and Recommendations "Personal caution is the greatest of all means of preventing ac - cidents. Accidents are preventable only as the seed of caution is sown, and men act in a safe way. Every accident is an indication that something was wrong either with men, methods, or materials." "Better be safe than sorry." </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT INTRODUCTORY AND RECOMMENDATIONS In Part II of the report of the Chief Deputy Compensation Commis - sioner a review of the Nebraska Compensation Law is given. In this re - view attention is called to the much needed amendments made by the legislature in 1917. While the changes were salutary and undoubtedly increased the efficiency of the operation of the law, there are, however, other amendments which are necessary to insure still greater efficiency in carrying out the requirements of the law. By far the greatest number of accidents occur in Omaha and Lincoln, with Omaha far in the lead owing to its greater size and greater num - ber of manufacturing establishments it has. When cases are tried in Omaha the Commissioner is compelled to rustle an office each time where hearings may be heard, and to send out special notices to the interested parties to this effect. Not only so, but the settlement of most accidents is brought about without a hearing. This is done by getting the employer, the adjustor for the insurance company, and employee together, either by having them come to the office or by using the telephone, or writing. At present there is no regular office in Omaha where this can be done. There is not a day passes that the need for an established office at Omaha is not felt. A provision in the law needs changing so as to expedite settle - ments. In 3693, Sec. 29-G, Laws of Nebraska 1917, the law says: "Every order and award of the Compensation Commissioner shall be binding upon each party at interest unless notice of intention to appeal to the District Court has been filed with the Compensation Commissioner within seven days following the date of rendition of the order or award; Pro - vided, that the order and award shall be binding and final, notwith - standing notice of intention to appeal has been filed within the time limit, until the appeal has been perfected and service had upon the op - posite party or parties." In order that all danger of delay may be obviated the law should be amended requiring a definite time for the District Court to perfect an appeal. Such a requirement is made for an appeal to the Supreme Court and the same requirement should be made for the District Court. Again, there has been considerable annoyance occasioned by the disparity of the fees charged for medical or surgical services by the various doctors. It would be better to follow the example of some of the other states and establish a schedule by law of fees that shall be charged for any specific kind of injury. Another source of trouble in the settlement of compensation cases is the matter of hernial injuries. There are three kinds of hernia: Traumatic Hernia, hernia caused by a sudden blow on the abdomen; Force of Effort Hernia, hernia caused by strain, twist or effort; Con - gential Hernia, hernia caused by the neglect of nature to close one or </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 5 more of the hernial orifices. It is difficult to establish which one of the three kinds of hernia an applicant for compensation may have. So important is the decision in this matter that the compensation law should contain a special provision for hernial cases. Perhaps the chief hindrance to efficiency in carrying out the pro - visions of the compensation law is the limited means at our command. Only $2,500.00 for the biennium were appropriated for this work. All expenses such as printing, office equipment, postage, traveling expenses, clerk hire, etc., must come out of this sum. No regular clerk is pro - vided for the Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner, which mitigates against a continuous and orderly method of conducting the office. The Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner is preparing two dockets in which to keep the record of all injuries. One of these docks records all injuries that last one week or less, and all injuries lasting more than one week for which there is money compensation in addition to medical and hospital and over which there is no dispute, either on the part of the employer or employee. The other docket re - cords all disputed cases which have been filed for hearing before the Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner. This latter, of course, are cases lasting more than one week and therefore involve a money award. At a moment's glance one can get the history of all points covered by the law regarding compensation for injury. There should be three competent stenographers, one to be placed in the Omaha office, and two in the Lincoln office, who are familiar with court proceedings and who are regularly employed, to take down all the hearings and keep the records up to date. There should be two field men employed to work under the direc - tion of the Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner; one stationed at the Omaha office, the other at the Lincoln office. It it therefore recommended, First, That an office be maintained at Omaha for the holding of compensation hearings, where injured em - ployees may come at any time for consultation and advice and for the performance of such other duties as fall naturally to the settlement of compensation claims and disputes. Second, That 3693 Sec. 29-G, Laws of Nebraska 1917, should be amended by stating that an appeal should be perfected by the District Court within thirty days after an appeal to this tribunal. Third, That a schedule of doctors' fees for injuries should be pre - pared by law. Fourth, That a special provision should be made for hernial cases. Fifth, That three competent stenographers should be provided for the Compensation Department, one for the Omaha office, and two for the Lincoln office. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Sixth, That two field men be employed, one stationed at Omaha and the other at Lincoln. Seventh, That owing to the increase in wages the maximum weekly compensation shall be increased per week and the minimum increased per week. Eighth, That the salary of the Chief Deputy Compensation Commis sioner be increased. Ninth, That $20,000.00 be appropriated for the next biennium. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 7 t PART II Workmen's Compensation Law "If you think you are beaten, you are ; If you think you dare not, you don't; If you'd like to win, but you think you can' It's almost a cinch you won't; If you think you'll lose, you're lost. For out of the world we find Success begins with a fellow's will — It's all in the state of mind. If you think you're outclassed, you are; You've got to think high to rise, You've got to be sure of yourself before You even can win a prize. Life's battles don't always go To the stronger or faster man; But soon or late the man who wins, Is the one who thinks he can." </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION LAW All the states of the Union, with the exception of North Dakota, Missouri, Arkansas, Tennessee, North Carolina, South Carolina, Missis - sippi, Alabama, Georgia and Florida, have compensation laws. In addi - tion to the compensation laws of the states, the territories of Alaska, Hawaii and Porto Rico have passed similar acts. The first law in this country was passed in 1905 by the State of Maryland. While compensation laws are a new thing in the United States, they have been in operation in continental Europe for a long time. With the great manufacturing concerns that hare developed in the United States it is difficult to account for the delay in accepting the principle of compensation. The compensation law of Nebraska was passed in 1913, ratified at the general election in November, 1914, and became effective December of the same year. The law as passed at this time made no provision for machinery to carry out its provisions. As a result it was found to be difficult for an injured employee to get the benefits which the law en - titled him to. We shall shortly consider the amendments which were made later. We shall now take up some of the leading provisions of the law and discuss them. There is a list of the kind of employments that come within the con - sideration of this law and such establishments are required to carry insurance in companies, associations, or organizations licensed to do business in the state. An employer may escape carrying this insurance when he can show proof that he is able to carry the compensation him - self in case of injury to his employees. Should the employer fail to comply with these conditions he is denied consideration under the law and must respond to damages for personal injuries. This means that he would be liable for judgment for injuries under the common law, with the three common law defenses denied him; namely, that the employee was negligent, or, that the injury was caused by the negligence of a fellow employee, or, that the employee had assumed the risks inherent in, or incidental to, or arising from the failure of the employer to pro - vide and maintain safe premises and suitable appliances. The law provides that acceptance of compensation shall be elec - tive, but unless notice to the contrary is posted in the place of busi - ness and a duplicate filed with the Compensation Commissioner, ac - ceptance is presumed and action will be taken accordingly. The em - ployee likewise may refuse to accept these provisions, but he must notify the employer and the Compensation Commissioner. In case he fails to do this it will be presumed that he alco accepts. The employer who elects not to be bound by the provisions may waive such election at any time, but must post about his place or places of business where his workmen are employed a written or printed notice to this effect. A duplicate of this notice must be filed with the Compensation Commis - sioner. The same privilege is granted the employee. He must send a </seg>
            <seg id="p009">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 9 written notice to his employer and a copy of same to the Compensation Commissioner. These waivers do not become effective until after noon of the fifth day after the filing of the required notice. All personal injuries received while engaged in regular employment are subject to adjustment by this act, unless these injuries came because of wilful negligence or intoxication. Occupational diseases are not in - cluded. Written notice with particulars must be served on the employer or his agent as soon as possible after the accident. Failure to send notice forfeits compensation unless employer or the insurance company is mis - led thereby. It is further held that notice to the employer is equivalent to a notice sent to the insurer. A claim for compensation must be filed within six months after in - jury or death. No compensation is allowed until after seven days. Com - pensation begins on the eighth day after injury, unless disability lasts for six weeks, when it is payable from the date of injury. The employer must furnish medical aid when needed during the first twenty-one days of disability, not to exceed $200.00. However, in case of major surgery the employer is liable for medical assistance be - yond the twenty-on edays period not to exceed $200.00. Some important changes were made in the law by the legislature in 1917. The original law proved to be inadequate to meet the situation and it was seen that changes were needed to make the working of the law really efficient. Following are the most important changes which were made. As first enacted there was no Compensation Commissioner provided for. In case an employer refused to pay compensation or in case of dispute the matter had to be taken to the District Court for settlement. Formerly an injured employee could draw only 50% of his weekly wages with a maximum of $10.00 per week and a minimum of $5.00 per week. The waiting time was two weeks and after an em - ployee had been laid off eight weeks on account of injury he received his compensation for the two weeks. Now an injured employee can draw 66 2-3% of his weekly wages with a maximum of $12.00 per week and a minimum of $6.00 per week. The waiting time has been reduced from two weeks to one week, for which he receives compensation after being injured six weeks. The 1917 legislature created the offices of Compensation Commis - sioner and Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner; the law provides that the Governor shall be the Compensation Commissioner and that he shall appoint a Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner who shall have all the powers of the Compensation Commissioner. All cases must first come before the Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner where the employer refuses compensation or if there is a dispute between the interested parties. An appeal may be taken from the decision of the Chief Deputy Commissioner to the District Court and from the District Court it may be taken to the Supreme Court. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT In case of partial disability, two-thirds the difference between the earning power of an employee and his former wages, with a maximum of $12.00 a week for not more than three hundred weeks shall be paid. A special schedule is provided for the loss of certain members of the body, as thumb, finger, toes, hand, arm, etc. The terms total disability and partial disability are clearly defined. In the event of death due to injury, an employer is held for an amount up to $100.00 for funeral expenses. This is payable regardless of the dependency of the family. Where the injured party leaves total dependents, two-thirds of his weekly wages, with a maximum of $12.00 per week and a minimum of $6.00 per week, shall be paid for a period of three hundred and fifty weeks. If partial dependents are left the compensation shall be the same proportion as provided for total de - pendents, that is, the proportion which the amount contributed bears to the total wages. Death during disability terminates liability for further compensation, unless the death is due to injury, in which event previous payments are to be deducted from death benefits. The law declares that railroads engaged in interstate commerce, or foreign commerce, are subject to the power of Congress, and do not come within the jurisdiction of the state in matters of compensation laws of the several states. The history of this provision probably dates back to the case of Winfleld vs. New York Central Railroad Company. Winfield was a resi - dent of New York State. He was employed as a section hand on the New York Central. While engaged in tamping ties on the carrier's main track he struck a pebble which rebounded and destroyed the sight of one eye. He sought and was granted compensation under the laws of New York, the award being made by the state commissioner. The railroad appealed the case and the award was confirmed by the appellate division of the Supreme Court, and also by the Court of Appeals. The case was then carried to the Supreme Court of the United States. The decision of the lower courts was reversed, the Supreme Court holding that the liability and obligations of interstate railroads, or other -car - riers, for compensation for personal injuries suffered by their employees while engaged in interstate commerce are regulated inclusively and ex - clusively by the Federal Employers Act; that as Congress has fully cov - ered the subject no room remains for state regulation. This holds even where injuries occur without fault and where the federal act provides no remedy. This decision was handed down in 1912, and all state acts since that time have been in harmony with this decision. The provision which excludes the state from adjudicating cases of injury where the employee is not at fault seems unjust. A recent case in Nebraska seems to bear out the injustice of such procedure. The case referred to is the Pettit vs. the Union Pacific Railroad Company. Pettit was a resident of Omaha and employed in the railroad shops. While repairing a hose </seg>
            <seg id="p011">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 11 coupling a piece of metal struck him in the eye and destroyed his sight. Pettit claimed compensation under the Nebraska compensation law, but this was denied by the Compensation Commissioner on the ground that he was employed by a carrier engaged in interstate commerce which took it out of the power of the state to grant his claim. In nearly every case an employee thus injured is a resident of the state where he receives his injury and it seems that simple justice would require that the state be permitted to make such awards. One point in the law has caused a good deal of discussion. It is that part which provides a waiting period of seven days before claim for compensation may be made. The law as originally passed called for a waiting period of fourteen days. The purpose of the waiting period is to prevent small claims fo.r inconsequential injuries. It is held by some that the absence of this waiting period would cause malingering on the part of those but slightly injured. Another argument brought forward for limiting the amount of com - pensation for minor injuries is that it will leave more money to care for those who sustain graver injuries. There can be no doubt but that the imposing of a waiting period reduces the number of accidents calling for compensation. According to the statistics gathered on this point, 43% of all accidents reported result in disability for one day only. According to the standard accident table, consisting of one hundred thousand accidents causing disability for more than one day, 37,000 did not last more than seven days. The establishing of a seven - day waiting period would eliminate 65 accidents out of each 100. Two weeks would add 14% to this number, and in all would leave but 22% of all accidents to be compensated. The experience of American Insurance companies is that less than 25% of accidents develop into claims under a two weeks waiting period, and from 35% to 40% under a waiting period of one week. About eighteen of the thirty-seven states having compensation laws have a waiting period of two weeks. There is a noticeable tendency to shorten the time of the waiting period, while some are demanding that there be no waiting time at all. In fact this rule holds in most of the European countries. It is primarily a concession to the employer and its purpose is to reduce the cost of compensation. The employer who holds rigidly to the compensation law gets the benefit of this reduc - tion. I have found, however, that so far as local business is con - cerned, employers are inclined to disregard their legal rights and gen - erally compensate their injured employees without reference to the waiting period, standing the difference out of their own pockets. The theory that the average employee is able' to do without his weekly pay for a period of one or two weeks without serious inconvenience is probably erroneous. No less interesting is the medical aid stipulation of the law. Ex - cepting in cases resulting in immediate death, every injury calls for a </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT certain amount of medical and surgical aid. On this point there is ab - solute harmony between all interests concerned. The injured man wants his pain relieved, permanent results or complications prevented, and his recovery hastened. The employer and the insurance company are directly interested because relief tends to reduce the economic law involved, and therefore the cost of compensation. The exception would be the case of an injured man without dependents, whose death would cost less than the lifelong support of an invalid. The tendency is distinctly toward liberalization in the matter of administering medical aid. The Nebraska act originally provided for twenty-one days, and a maximum amount of two hundred dollars, but it has been amended so as to ignore the time limit in cases where major surgery is necessary. The California act of 1911 limited medical aid to ninety days, with a maximum of one hundred dollars for medical fees. It has been amended and has removed the limit as to amount of fees, and time in the gravest cases. The Connecticut act of 1913 limited medical aid to thirty days, but here again a later amendment did away with all limits as to time and amount of fees. The Federal Employees Compensation Act of 1908 made no provision for medical aid; the new act of 1918 has removed the limits of time and amount of fees. Using the standard accident table as a basis of cal - culation, it is apparent that the limits most states have imposed are still sufficiently low to strike a considerable proportion of injury cases. According to this table the number of cases in 100,000 in which the temporary total disability has not expired is: After seven days, 62,504 After fourteen days, 38,218 After twenty-one days, 25,792 After twenty-eight days, 18,479 After fifty-six days, 6,043 After ninety-one days, 2,204 It would appear from this table that in Nebraska over one-fourth of thet accidents would be affected by the time limit of twenty-one days. But as the smaller share of accidents affected by the time limit repre - sents the severe injuries, many of them calling for surgical operations, the percentage affected is less than one-fourth. There is no provision of the Compensation Act more vital to the interests of the employer and employee than adequate medical aid; without it the injured person may be obliged to leave the hospital too soon, or go without a necessary operation. If this should happen it would not only be a great incon - venience to the employee, but to the man who hires him. The cost of medical assistance is a question of importance and a further word regarding it is here in order. The best figures on this point are furnished by the State of Massachusetts. On a capital rep- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 13 resenting something like $900,000,000 the amount paid out in compensa - tion amounted to $3,496,876. This included medical aid. The number of employees among whom injuries occurred were nearly two million. Twenty-one per cent represents the part of the above amount that was paid out for medical aid. The Nebraska Act is intended to leave the choice of the physician to the employer or the insurance company. In actual practice the choice is frequently left to the employer. The law presupposes that the employer is more competent to select a good physician; that the em - ployer or insurance company being required to stand for the costs should have this right; that the employer is entitled to the supervision of such matters; that this arrangement will insure against malingering. Our personal experience has been that equally good results are ob - tained no matter whether the employer or the employee chooses the physician. There are other parts of this law which we have not touched upon, but the main provisions have been reviewed. While there may be places in the law that might be improved, yet taking it as a whole it is as good as the best of such laws that have been enacted in this country and much better than most of them. Herewith is appended the Workmens Compensation Law of Ne- braska. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT PART III Workmen's Compensation Law "Accidents not only result in needless suffering and dis - ability to the workman, but hamper the industry. A workman in a hazardous industry should familiarize himself with the way in which he might do his work and receive injury — and then do it some other way. In other words, reduce the hazards of the business to the minimum." "Watch Your Step — A few simple precautions cause less bother than an administrator." "It is better to be careful a thousand times than to be crippled once." </seg>
            <seg id="p015">COMPENSATION DEPAETMENT 15 WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION LAW OF NEBRASKA As Amended by the Legislature of 1917 Effective July 24, 1917. PART I Compensation by Action at Law — Modification of Remedies. Employer'* Liability — Negligence— Compensation. 3642.. ..Sec. 92. When personal injury is caused to an employee by accident arising out of and in the course of his employment, of which the actual or lawful imputed negligence of the employer is the natural and proximate cause, he shall receive compensation therefore from his employer, provided the employee was himself not wilfully negligent at the time of receiving such Injury, and the question of whether the employee was wilfully negligent shall be one of fact to be submitted to the jury, subject to the usual powers of the court over verdicts rendered contrary to the evidence, or to law. (1913 p. 579.) Action — Employee for Injuries — Defenses Not Allowed. 3643 Sec. 93. In all cases brought under Part I of this article It shall not be a defense (a) that the employee was negligent, un - less and except it shall also appear that such negligence was wilful, or that the employee was in a state of intoxication; (b) that the in - jury was caused by the negligence of a fellow employee; (c) that the employee had assumed the risks inherent in, or incidental to, or arising from the failure of the employer to provide and maintain safe premises and suitable appliances, which grounds of defense are hereby abolished, except as provided in the second next following section. (1913 p. 579.) Defenses— When Not Available. 3644 Sec. 94. If an employer, subject to the provisions of this article as shown in section 97 of this chapter, elects not to come under Part II hereof, he loses the right to interpose the three de - fenses above stated in any action brought against him for personal Injury or death of an employee. (1913 p. 579.) Same— When Available. 3645 Sec. 95. If an employer becomes subject to Part n of this article, and the employee does not, then the defenses existing under the laws for Nebraska, other than the provisions of this ar - ticle, at the time of the personal injury or death of the employee shall be available to the employer in any action brought by the employee or his dependents for personal injury or death. (1913 p. 579.) Application of Preceding Sections. 3646 Sec. 96. The provisions of the four next preceding sec - tions shall apply to any claim for the death of an employee arising under sections 164 and 165 of chapter 17 and sections 127, 128 and 129 of chapter 67 of the Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913, and the acts or parts of acts amendatory thereof, concerning death by wrongful act. (1913 p. 580.) Provisions of Article to Whom Applicable. 3647 Sec. 97. (1) The provisions of this act shall apply to the State of Nebraska and every governmental agency created by </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT it, and to every employer in this state employing one or more em - ployees, in the regular trade, business, profession or vocation of such employer. (2) The following are declared not to be hazardous occupations and not within the provisions of this act; employers of household domestic servants and employers of farm laborers. Rail - road companies engaged in interstate or foreign commerce are de - clared subject to the powers of Congress and not within the pro - visions of this act. (3) Any employer not included in the preceding paragraphs of this section and the employees of such employers may, by their joint election, filed with the Compensation Commissioner, accept the provisions of Part II of this act, and such acceptance shall subject them to the said provisions of Part II hereof to all intents and purposes as if they had been originally included in the terms of Subdivision I of this section: Provided, however, that either such employer or workmen (prior to accident) shall have the right to waive such election to come under Part II hereof, the pro - cedure being the same as indicated in Subdivisions (a) and (b) of section 103 of this chapter. (As amended 1917, p. 199.) . Wilful Negligence — Burden of Proof. 3648 Sec. 98. In all actions at law brought pursuant to Part I of this article the burden of proof to establish wilful negligence of the injured employee shall he on the defendant. (1913 p. 590.) Legal Services — Disbursements — Claims For. 3649 Sec. 99. No claim or agreement for legal services or dis - bursements in support of any demand made or suit brought under the provisions of this article shall be an enforceable lien against the amounts to be paid as damages or compensation or be valid or binding in any other respect, unless the same be approved in writing by the judge presiding at the trial, or ,in case of settlement without trial, by the judge of the District court of the districts in which such issue arose. After such approval, if notice in writing be given the defendant of such claim or agreement for legal services and disbursements, the same shall be a lien against any amount thereafter to be paid as damages or compensation: Provided, how - ever, where the employee's compensation is payable by the em - ployer in periodical installments, the court shall fix, at the time of approval, the proportion of each installment to be paid on account of legal services and disbursements. (1913 p. 581.) PART n. A. Elective Compensation. Schedule of Compensation Binding. 3650 Sec. 100. If both employer and employee become sub - ject to Part II of this article, both shall be bound by the schedule of compensation herein provided, which compensation shall be paid in every case of injury or death caused by accident arising out of and in the course of employment, except accidents caused by. or re - sulting in any degree from wilful negligence, as hereinafter defined, of the employee. (1913 p. 581.) Compensation Without Regard to Negligence 3651 Sec. 101. When employer and employee shall by agree - ment, express or implied, or otherwise as hereinafter provided, ac - cept the provisions of Part II of this article, compensation shall he made for personal injuries to or for the death of such emnloyee by accident arising out of and in the course of his employment, without </seg>
            <seg id="p017">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 17 regard to the negligence of the employer, according to the schedule hereinafter provided, in all cases except when the injury or death is caused by wilful negligence on the part of the employee; and the burden of proof of such fact shall be upon the employer. (1913 p. 581.) Other Method* of Compensation Barred. 3652 Sec. 102. Such agreement or the election hereinafter pro - vided for shall be a surrender by the parties thereto of their rights to any other method, form or amount of compensation or determina - tion thereof than as provided in Part II of this article, and an acceptance of all the provisions of Part II of this article, and shall bind the employee himself, and for compensation for his death shall bind his legal representatives, his widow and next of kin, as well as the employer, and the legal representatives of a deceased em - ployer, and those conducting the business of the employer during bankruptcy or insolvency. (1913 p. 582.) Method of Election. 3653 Sec. 103. In the occupations described in Section 97 hereof, and all contracts of employment made after the taking effect of this act shall be presumed to have been made with reference, and subject to the provisions of Part II hereof unless otherwise ex - pressly stated in the contract, or unless written or printed notice has been given by either party to the other, as hereinafter pro - vided, that he does not accept the provisions of Part II. Every such employer and every employee is presumed to accept and come under Part II hereof, unless prior to accident he shall signify his election not to accept or be bound by the provisions of Part II. This election not to accept Part II shall be by notice as follows: (a) The employer shall post and thereafter keep continuously posted in a conspicuous place about the place or places where his workmen are employed a written or printed notice of his election not to be bound by Part II hereof, and shall file a duplicate thereof with the Compensation Commissioner. (b) The employee shall give written or printed notice to the employer of his election not to be bound by Part II and shall file a duplicate with proof of service attached thereto with the Compensa - tion Commissioner. (As amended 1917, p. 199.) Waving Election. 3654 Sec. 104. An employer who has given notice of his elec - tion not to accept or be bound by the provisions of Part II hereof, may waive such election at any time, by posting about the place or places where his workmen are employed a written or printed notice setting forth a withdrawal of his previous election not to be bound by the provisions of Part II. A duplicate of such notice with proof of such posting attached thereto shall be filed with the Compensation Commissioner. An employee who has given written or printed notice to his employer that he elects not to be subject to the pro - visions of Part II, hereof, may waive such election at any time prior to the happening of an accident resulting in personal injuries to said employee, by a notice in writing directed to the employer and served upon the employer or his agent. A duplicate of such notice with proof of service attached thereto shall be filed with the Compensation Commissioner. The waivers referred to in this sec - tion shall not become effective until noon of the fifth day after filing the required notice with the Compensation Commissioner. (As a mended 1917, p. 200.) </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT "Employer" Described. 3655 Sec. 105. The following shall constitute "employers" sub - ject to the provisions of this article: (1) The state and every governmental agency created by it; (2) Every person, firm or corporation, including any public service corporation, who is engaged in any trade, occupation, busi - ness, or profession as described in section 97 of this chapter, and who has any person in service under any contract of hire, express or implied, oral or written, and who prior to the time of the acci - dent to the employee for which compensation under this article may be claimed, shall not, in the manner provided in section 103 of this chapter, have elected not to become subject to the pro - visions of Part II of this article. (1913 p. 583.) "Employee" Described. 3656 Sec. 106. The terms 'employee" and "workman" are used interchangeably and have the same meaning throughout this ar - ticle: The said terms include the plural and all ages and both sexes, and shall be construed to mean: (1) Every person in the service of the state or of any gov - ernmental agency created by it, under any appointment or contract of hire, express or implied, oral or written, but shall not include any official of the state, or any governmental agency created by it, who shall have been elected or appointed tor a regular term of office, or to complete the unexpired portion of any regular term. (2) Every person in the service of an employer who is engaged inany trade, occupation, business or profession as described in Sec - tion 97 of this chapter, under any contract of hire, express or im - plied, oral or written, including aliens and also including minors who are legally permitted to work under the laws of the state, who for the purpose of making election of remedies under this code shall have the same power of contracting and electing as adult em - ployees. No parent or guardian of an injured minor employee shall be entitled to recover any damages Dy reason of said injury other than as expressly provided in this article. (3) It shall not be construed to include any person whose em - ployment is casual, or not for the purpose of gain or profit by the employer, or which is not in the usual course of the trade, business, profession, or occupation of his employer. The term "casual" shall be construed to mean "occasion; coming at certain times without regularity, in distinction from stated or regular." (4) It shall not be construed to include any person to whom articles and materials are given to be made up, cleaned, washed, finished, repaired or adapted for sale in the worker's own home or on other premises not under the control or management of the employer, unless the employee is required to perform the work at a place designated by the employer. (As amended 1917, p. 201.) B. Third Person's Rights and Liabilities. "Employer" Construed — Sub-contractors — Insurance. 3657 Sec. 107. Any person, firm or corporation creating or carrying into operation any scheme, artifice or device to enable him, them • or it to execute work without being responsible to the work - men for the provisions of this article, shall be* included in the term "employer" and with the immediate employer shall be jointly and severally liable to pay the compensation herein provided for and be subject to all the provisions of this article. This section, however, shall not be so construed as to cover or mean an owner who lets a contract to a contractor in good &lt;€aith, or a contractor who, in good faith, lets to a sub-contractor a portion of his contract, if the owner </seg>
            <seg id="p019">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 19 or principal contractor, as the case may be, requires the contractor or sub-contractor, respectively, to procure a policy or policies of in - surance from an insurance company licensed to uuke such insurance in this state, which policy or policies of insurance shall guarantee payment of compensation according to this article to injured work - men. (1913 p. 584.) Compensation — Calculation. 3658 Sec. 108. Where compensation is claimed from, or pro - ceedings taken against a person, firm or corporation under the foregoing section, the compensation shall be calculated with refer - ence to the wage the workman was receiving from the person by whom he was immediately employed at the time of the injury. (1913 p. 585.) Subrogation. 3659 Sec. 109. Where a htird person is liable to the employee or to the dependents, for the injury or death, the employer shall be subrogated to the right of the employee or to the dependents against such third person, and the recovery by such employer shall not be limited to the amount payable as compensation to such employee or dependents, but such employer may recover any amount which such employee or his dependents would have been entitled to recover. Any recovery by the employer against such third person, in excess of the compensation paid by the employer after deducting the ex - penses of making such recovery, shall be paid forthwith to the em - ployee or to the dependents, and shall be treated as an advance payment by the employer, on account of any future installments of compensation. (1913 p. 585.) Schedule of Compensation. When Compensation Shall Begin. 3660 Sec. 110. No compensation shall be allowed for the first seven calendar days after disability begins, except as provided in the next following section, but if disability extends beyond the period of seven days, compensation shall begin on the eighth cal - endar day after the injury: Provided, however, that if such dis - ability continues for six weeks or longer, such compensation shall be computed from the date of the injury. (As amended 1917, p. 202.) Medical Aid. 3661. Sec. 111. During the first twenty-one days after disabil - ity begins the employer shall be liable for reasonable medical and hospital services and medicines as and when needed, not however to exceed two hundred dollars in value, unless the employee refuses to allow them to be furnished by the employer: Provided, however, in cases of dismemberment or injuries involving major surgical operations, the employer shall be liable for reasonable medical and hospital services and medicines as and when needed beyond as well as within the twenty-one day period, not, however, to exceed two hundred dollars in value: Provided, further, that where the injured employee refuses or neglects to avail himself of such medi - cal or surgical treatment, the employer shall not be liable for any aggravation of such injury due to said neglect or refusal. (As amended 1917 p. 202.) Compensation Schedule. 3662. Sec. 112. The following schedule of compensation is hereby established for injuries resulting in disability: (1) For the first three hundred weeks of total disability the compensation shall be sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT wages received at the time of injury, but such compensation shall not be more than twelve dollars per week nor less than six dollars per week: Provided, that, if at the time of injury the employee receives wages of less than six dollars per week, then he shall re - ceive the full amount of such wages per week as compensation. After the first three hundred weeks of total disability, for the re - mainder of the life of the employee, he shall receive forty-five per centum of the wages received at the time of the injury, but the compensation shall not be more than nine dollars per week nor less than four dollars and fifty cents per week: Provided, that if at the time of the injury the employee receives wages of less than four dollars and fifty cents per week then he shall receive the full amount of such wages as compensation. Nothing in this subdivision shall require the payment of compensation after disability shall cease. Should partial disability be followed by total disability, the period of three hundred weeks mentioned in this subdivision of this section shall be reduced by the number of weeks during which com - pensation was paid for such partial disability. (2) For disability partial in character (except the particular cases mentioned in Subdivision 3 of this section), the compensation shall be sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of the difference be - tween the wages received at the time of the injury and the earning power of the employee thereafter, but such compensation shall not be more than twelve dollars per week. This compensation shall be paid during the period of such partial disability; not, however, be - yond three hundred weeks after the date of the accident causing disability. Should total disability be followed by partial disability, the period of three hundred weeks mentioned in this subdivision shall be reduced by the number of weeks during which compensa - tion was paid for such total disability. (3) For all disability resulting from permanent injury of the following classes, the compensation shall be exclusively as follows: For the loss of a thumb, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during sixty weeks. For the loss of a first finger, commonly called index finger, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during thirty - five weeks. For the loss of a second finger, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during thirty weeks. For the loss of a third finger, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily v:ages during twenty weeks. For the loss of a fourth finger, commonly called little finger, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of dally wages during fifteen weeks. The loss of the first phalange of the thumb, or of any finger, shall be considered to be equal to the loss of one-half of such thumb, or finger, and compensation shall be for one-half of the periods of time above specified, and compensation for the loss of one-half of the first phalange shall be for one-fourth of the periods of time above specified. The loss of more than one phalange shall be considered as the loss of the entire finger or thumb: Provided, however, that in no case shall the amount received for more than one finger exceed the amount provided in this schedule for the loss of a hand. For the loss of a great toe, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during thirty weeks. For the loss of one of the toes other than a great toe, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during ten weeks. The loss of the first phalange of any toe shall be considered to </seg>
            <seg id="p021">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 21 be equal to the loss of one-half of such toe, and compensation shall be for one-half of the periods of time above specified. The loss of more than one phalange shall be considered as the loss of the entire toe. For the loss of a hand, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during one hundred and fifty weeks. For the loss of an arm, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during two hundred weeks. For the loss of a foot, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during one hundred and twenty-five weeks. For the loss of a leg, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during one hundred and seventy-five weeks. For the loss of an eye, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during one hundred weeks. For the loss of an ear, sixty-six and two thirds per centum of daily wages during twenty-five weeks. For the loss of the nose, sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of daily wages during fifty weeks. The loss of both hands, or both arms, or both feet, or both legs, or both eyes, or of any two thereof, shall constitute total and per - manent disability, to be compensated according to the provisions of Subdivision 1 of this section. Amputation between the elbow and the wrist shall be considered as the equivalent of the loss of a hand, and amputation between the knee and the ankle shall be considered as the equivalent of the loss of a foot. Amputation at or above the elbow shall be considered as the loss of an arm. and amputation at or above the knee shall be considered as the loss of a leg. Permanent loss of the use of a hand, arm, foot, leg or eye shall be considered as the equivalent of the loss of such hand. arm. foot, leg or eye. In all cases involving a permanent partial loss of the use or function of any of the members mentioned in Subdivision 3 of Sec - tion 3362, the compensation shall bear such relation to the amounts named in said Subdivision 3 of Section 3662 as the disabilities bear to those produced by the injuries named therein. Should the em - ployer and the employee be unable to agree upon the amount of com - pensation to be paid in cases not covered by the schedule, the amount of condensation shall bo settled according to the provisions of Section 3680. » Compensation under this subdivision shall not be more than twelve dollars per week nor less than six dollars per week: Pro - vided, that, if at the time of iniury the employee receives wages of less than six dollars per week, then he shall receive the full amount of such wages per week as compensation. It is expressly provided that not anything contained in this section or this entire amendatory act is intended to or shall operate to affect the amount or amounts recoverable for any character of iniury sustained by any person or persons prior to the going into effect of this amendatory act. (As amended 1917, p. 202.) Injuries Resulting in Death — Dependents. 3663 Sec. 113. (1) If death results from the injuries and the deceased employee leaves one or more dependents wholly dependent upon his earnings for support at the time of the accident causing the injury, the compensation, subject to the provisions of the next fol - lowing section, shall be sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of th«» wages received at the time of the injury, but the compensation shall not be more than twelve dollars per week nor 'ess thpn six dollars per week: Provided. If pt the time of iniury the employee rece'ves wages of less than six dollars per week, then the compensation shall </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT be the full amount of such wages per week. This compensation shall be paid during dependency, not exceeding three hundred and fifty weeks from the date of the accident causing the injury. It is expressly provided that not anything contained in this section or this entire amendatory aet is intended to or shall operate to affect the amount or amounts recoverable for any character of injury sus - tained by any person or persons prior to the going into effect of this amendatory act. (2) If the deceased employee leaves no dependents wholly de - pendent upon his earnings for support at the time of the accident causing the injury, but leaves one or more dependents only partly dependent upon his earnings for support at said time, the compensa - tion shall be the same proportion of the benefits provided in Sub - division (1) of this section for persons wholly dependent as the average amount of the wage regularly contributed by the deceased to such partial dependents at, and for a reasonable time imme - diately prior to the injury, bears to the total wage of the deceased, during the same time. (3) Upon the death of an employee, resulting through personal injuries as herein defined, whether or not there be dependents en - titled to compensation the reasonable expenses of burial, not exceed - ing one hundred dollars, without deduction of any amount theretofore paid or to be paid for compensation or for medical expenses, shall be paid to his dependents, or if there be no dependents, then to the personal representative of the deceased. (4) Compensation under this article to alien dependents, widows, children and parents not residents of the United States, shall be the same in amount as is provided in each case for resi - dents, except that at any time within one year after the death of the injured employee the employer may, at his option, commute all future installments of compensation to be paid to such alien de - pendents by paying to them two-thirds of the total amount of such future installments of compensation. Alien widowers, brothers and sisters not residents of the United States shall not be entitled to any compensation. (5) The consul-general, consul, vice-consul general, or vice - consul of the nation of which the employee, whose injury results in death, is a citizen, or the representative of such consul general, consul, vice-consul general or vice-consul residing within the State of Nebraska, shafl be regarded as the sole legal representative of any alien dependents of the employee, residing outside of the Unitd States, and representing the nationality of the employee. Such consular officer, or his representative, residing in the State of Nebraska, shall have in behalf of such non-resident dependents, the exclusive right to adjust and settle all claims for compensation pro - vided by this article and to receive for distribution to such non - resident alien dependents all compensation arising thereunder. (As amended 1917, p. 205.) Death of Employee Receiving Disability Compensation. 3664 Sec. 114. The death of an injured employee prior to the expiration of the period within which he would receive such disabil - ity payment, shall be deemed to end such disability, and all lia - bility for the remainder of such payment which he would have re - ceived in case he had lived shall be terminated: but the employer shall thereupon be liable for the following death benefit in lieu of any further disability indemnity: If the Injury so received by such employee was the cause of his death and such deceased employee leaves dependents as hereinbefore specified, wholly or partially dependent on him for support, the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 23 death benefit shall be a sum sufficient, when added to the indemnity which shall at the time of death have been paid or become payable under the provisions of this article to such deceased employee, to make the total compensation for the injury and death equal to the lull amount which such dependents would have been entitled to re - ceive under the provisions of the next preceding section, in case the accident had resulted in immediate death; and suc-h benefits shall be payable in the same manner and subject to the same terms and conditions in all respects, as payments made under the piovisions of said next preceding section. No deduction shall be made for the amount which may have been paid for medical and hospital services and medicines or for the expenses of burial. If the employee die from some cause other than the injury, there shall be no liability for compensation to accrue after his death. (As amended 1917, p. 207.) Dependents. 3665 Sec. 115. The following persons shall be conclusively pre - sumed to be wholly dependent for support upon a deceased em - ployee: (a) A wife upon a husband with whom she is living at the time of his death; (b) Husband upon a wife with whom he is living at the time of her death; (c) Child or children under the age of sixteen years (or over said age( if physically or mentally incapacitated from earning) upon the parent with whom he is or they are living at the time of death of such parent, there being no surviving parent. In case there is more than one child thus dependent, the death benefit shall be divided equally among them. (d) Compensation shall be payable under the two next pre - ceding sections to or on account of any child, brother or sister, only if and while such child, brother or sister, is under the age of six - teen. No compensation shall be payable under said section to a widow, unless she was living with her deceased husband at the time of his death: Provided, a wife or a husband living in a state of abandonment for more than two years at the time of the injury, or subsequently, shall not be a beneficiary under this article. The terms "child" and "children" shall include step-children and adopted children if members of the decedent's household at the time of his death, and shall include posthumous children. If the compensation payable under said sections to any person shall for any cause cease, the compensation to the remaining persons entitled thereunder shall thereafter be the same as would have been payable to them had they been the only persons entitled to compensation at the time of the death of the deceased. If a widow or widower of a deceased em - ployee shall remarry, then the compensation benefits shall become payable to the child or children of such widow or widower, if there be any such child or children; but if there be no such child or children of such dependent widow or widower, the rights of such widow or widower shall not be affected by such remarriage. (e) In all other cases, questions of dependency, in whole or in part, shall be determined in accordance with the fact, as the fact may be at the time of the injury; and in such other cases, if there is more than one person wholly dependent, the death benefit shall be divided equally among them, and persons partly dependent, if any, shall receive no part thereof; if there is no one wholly de - pendent and more than one person partly dependent, the death benefit shall be divided among them according to the relative extent of their dependency. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 24 (f) No person shall be considered a dependent, unless he or she be a member of the family of the deceased employee, or bears to him the relation of widow or widower, or lineal descendant, or ancestor, or brother, or sister. * ♦ (g) Questions as to who constitute dependents and the extent of their dependency shall be determined as of the date of the acci - dent to the employee, and the death benefit shall be directly recov - rable by and payable to the dependent or dependents entitled there - to, or their legal guardians or trustees. No dependent of an in - jured employee shall be deemed, during the life of such employee, a party in interest to any proceeding by him for the entorcement or collection of any claim for compensation, nor as re3pects the compromise thereof of such employee. (1913, p. 590.) Compensation — Periodical — Payments. 3666 Sec. 116. Except as hereinafter provided, all amounts of compensation payable under the provisions of this article shall be payable periodically in accordance with the methods of payment of the wages of the employee at the time of the injury or death. Provided, fifty per centum shall be added for waiting time for all delinquent payments after thirty days' notice has been given. (As amended 1917, p. 208.) Wages — Definition. 3667 Sec. 117. Wherever in this article the term "wages" is used, it shall be construed to mean the money rate at which the service rendered is recompensed under the contract of hiring in force at the time of the accident, and shall not include gratuities received from the employer or others, nor shall it include board, lodging or similar advantages received from the employer, unless the money value of such advantages shall have been fixed by the parties at the time of hiring. In occupations involving seasonal employment or employments dependent upon the weather, the em - ployee's weekly wages shall be taken to be one-fiftieth of the total wages which he has earned from all occupations during the year im - mediately preceding the accident, unless it be shown that during such year, by reason of exceptional causes, such method of computa - tion does not ascertain fairly the earnings of the employee, in which case the period for calculation shall be extended so far as to give a basis for the fair ascertainment of his average weekly earnings. In continuous employments, if immediately prior to the accident the rate of wages was fixed by the day or hour, or by the output of the employee, his weekly wages shall be taken to be his average weekly income for thte period of time ordinarily constituting his week's work, and using as the basis of calculation his earnings during as much of the preceding six months as he worked for the same em - ployer; the calculation, furthermore, to be made with reference to average earnings for a working day of ordinary length and ex - clusively of earnings from overtime. (As amended 1917, p. 208.) Interested Parties — Settlement 3668 Sec. 118. If the employee is injured by reason of his in - tentional wilful negligence, or by reason of being in a state of in - toxication, neither he nor his beneficiaries shall receive any com - pensation under the provisions of this article. (1913, p. 592.) Injury Increasing Disability. 3669 See. 119. If an employee receives an injury, which, of itself, would only cause partial disability, but which, combined with a previous disability, does in fact cause total disability, the em- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 25 ployer shall only be liable as for the partial disability, so far as the subsequent injury is concerned. (1913, p. 592.) Liability of Joint Employers. 3670 Sec. 120. In case any employee for whose injury or death compensation is payable under this article, shall, at the time of the injury, be employed and paid jointly by two or more employ - ers subject to this article, such employers shall contribute to the payment of such compensation in proportion to their several wage liabilities to such employee. If one or more, but not all of such employers should be subject to the provisions of Part II of this article, then the liability of such of them as are so subject shall be to pay that proportion of the entire compensation which their pro - portionat wage liability bears to the entire wages of the employee: Provided, however, nothing in this section shall prevent any ar - rangement between employers of a different distribution between themselves of the ultimate burden of compensation. (1913, p. 592.) Contributions by Employee. 3671 Sec. 121. No savings or insurance of the injured em - ployee, or any contribution made by him to any benefit fund or protective association independent of this article shall be taken into consideration determining the compensation to be paid hereunder; nor shall benefits derived from any other source than those paid or caused to be paid by the employer as herein provided, be considered in fixing the compensation under this article. (1913, p. 593.) No Waiver of Rights. 3672 Sec. 122. No agreement by an employee to waive his rights to compensation under this article shall be valid. (1913, p. 593.) Minors and Mentally Incompetent. 3673 Sec. 123. If an injured employee is mentally incompetent or is a minor at the time when any right or privilege accrues to him under this article, his guardian or next friend may, in his behalf, claim and exercise such right or privilege. (1913, p. 593.) Notice of Injury. 3674 Sec. 124. No proceedings for compensation for an injury under this article shall be maintained, unless a notice of the injury shall have been given to the employer as soon as practicable after the happening thereof; and unless the claim for compensation with respect to such injury shall have been made within sit months after the occurrence of the same, or in case fo the death of the em - ployee, or in the event of his physical or mental incapacity, within six months after death or the removal of such physical or mental incapacity; provided, that all disputed claims for compensation or benefits shall be first submitted to the Compensation Commissioner, as provided in Section 3680. The said notice shall be in writing, and shall state in ordinary language the time, place and cause of the injury; and shall be signed by the person injured, or by a person in his behalf, or, in the event of his death, by his legal representative or by a person in his behalf. The notice shall be served upon the employer or an agent thereof. Such service may be made by delivering said notice to the person on whom it is to be served, or leaving it at his residence or place of business, or by sending it by registered mail addressed to the person or corporation on whom it is to be served at his last known residence or place of business. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT A notice given under the provisions of this section shall not be held invalid or insufficient by reason of any inaccuracy in stating the time, place or cause of the injury, unless it is shown that it was the intention to mislead, and the employer, or the insurance company carrying such risk, as the case may be, was in fact misled thereby. Want of such written notice shall not be a bar to pro - ceedings under this act, if it be shown that the employer had notice or knowledge of the injury. (As amended 1917, p. 209.) D. Examination and Verification of Injury. Examination of Injured. 3675 Sec. 125. After an employee has given notice of an in - jury, as provided in the next preceding section, and from time to time thereafter during the continuance of his disability, he shall, if so requested by the employer or the insurance company carrying such risk, submit himself to an examination by a physician or sur - geon legally authorized to practice medicine under the laws of the state, furnished and paid for by the employer, or the insurance com - pany carrying such risk, as the case may be. The employee shall have the right to have a physician provided and paid for by himself present at the examination. The refusal of the employee to submit to such examination shall deprive him of the right to compensation under this article during the continuance of such refusal and the period of such refusal shall be deducted from the period during which compensation would otherwise be payable. (1913, p. 594.) Autopsy. 3674 Sec. 126. In all death claims where the cause of death is obscure or disputed, any interested party may require an autopsy, the cost of such autopsy to be borne by the party demanding the same. (1913, p. 594.) E. Settlement of Payment of Compensation Interested Parties — Settlement. 3677 Sec. 127. The interested parties shall have the right to settle all matters of compensation between themselves in accord - ance with the provisions of this article: Provided, that a copy of such settlement shall be filed with the Compensation Commissioner, and no such settlement shall be binding unless in accord with the provisions of this article. (As amended 1917, p.209.) Arbitration — Action. 3678 Sec. 128. All disputed claims for compensation or for benefits under this article must be submitted to the Compensation Commissioner for an award. If either party at interest is dissatis - fied with the award of the ComDensation Commissioner, then the matter may be submitted to the District Court of the county which would have jurisdiction of a civil action between the parties, which court shall have authority to hear and determine the cause as a suit in equity and enter final judgment therein determining all ques - tions of law and fact in accordance with the provisions of this article, which judgment shall be final and conclusive unless re - versed or modified, on appeal or otherwise modified pursuant to the provisions of this act. (As amended 1917, p. 210.) Claims Barred — When. 3679 Sec. 129. In case of personal injury, all claims for com - pensation shall be forever barred unless, within one year after the accident, the parties shall have agreed upon the compensation pay- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 27 *~^ able under this act, or unless, within one year after the accident, one of the parties shall have filed a petition as provided in Sec - tion 3680 hereof. In case of death, all claims for compensation shall be forever barred unless, within one year after the death, the parties shall have agreed upon the compensation under this act, or unless within one year after the death, one of the parties shall have filed a petition as provided in Section 3680 hereof. Where, however, payments of compensation have been made in any case, said limita - tion shall not take effect until the expiration of one year from the time of the making of the last tpayment. In the event of legal disability of an injured employee, said limitation shall not take effect until the expiration of one year from the time or removal of such legal disability. (As amended 1917, p. 210.) Action* — Procedure — Practice. 3680 Sec. 130. Procedure in cases of dispute shall be as fol - lows: Either party may file with the Compensation Commissioner a verified petition setting forth the names and residences cf the par - ties and the facts relating to the employment at the time of the in - jury, the injury in its extent and character, the amount of wa?es being received at the time of injury, the knowledge of or notice to the employer of the occurrence of said injury and such other facts as may be necessary tor the information of tho Commissioner, and also stating the matter or matters in dispute and the contention of the petitioner with reference thereto. Upon the filing of such petition a summons shall issue and be served upon the adverse party, as in civil causes, together with a copy of the petition. Return of service shall be made within four days from the issuance of the summons. Within seven days after the return day of such summons the party upon whom the same is served shall file an answer to said petition, which shall admit or deny the substantial averments of the petition, and shall state the contention of the defendant with reference to the matters in dis - pute, as disclosed by the petition. The answer shall be verified in like manner as required for a petitoin. At the expiration of the time fixed for filing the answer the compensation commissioner shall proceed to hear all parties at interest and make such recom - mendations and awards as such compensation commissioner may be authorized by law to make. In case either party refuses to accept the recommendations or awards of the compensation commissioner, either party may sub - mit to the District Court a verified petition setting forth the names and residences of the parties and the facts relating to the employ - ment at the time of the injury, the injury in its extent and char - acter, the amount of wages being received at the time of injury, the knowledge of or notice to the employer of the occurrence of said injury, and such other facts as may be necessary for the in - formation of the court, and also stating the matter or matters in dispute and the contention of the petitioner with reference thereto. Upon the filing of such petition a summons shall issue and be served upon the adverse party, as in civil causes, together with a copy of the petition. Return of service shall be made wHhin four days from the issuance of the summons. Within seven days after the return day of such summons the party upon whom the same is served shall file an answer to said petition, which shall admit or deny the substantial averments of the petition, and shall state the contention of the defendant with reference to the matters in dis - pute, as disclosed by the petition. The answer shall be verified in </seg>
            <seg id="p028">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 28 like manner as required for a petition. At the expiration of the time fixed for filing answer the court shall proceed to hear and de - termine the cause without delay and shall render judgment thereon according to the form of law. Any appeal from such judgment shall be prosecuted in accordance with the general laws of the state reg - ulating appeals and actions at law except that such appeal shall be perfected within thirty days from the entry of the judgment and the cause shall be advanced for hearing in the supreme court so as to bring said cause on for argument before such court within sixty days from the filing of the appeal and said supreme court shall render its judgment and opinion in such cases within thirty days after submission. (As amended 1917, p. 210. Lump Sum Payment. 3681 Sec. 131. The amounts of compensation payable periodically under the law, by agreement of the parties with the approval of the Compensation Commissioner, may be commuted to one or more lump sum payments, except compensation due for death and permanent disability, which may be commuted only upon the order or decision of the District Court: Provided, that where commutation is agreed upon or ordered by the court, the lump sum to be paid shall be fixed at an amount which will equal the total sum of the probable future payments, capitalized at their present value upon the basis of interest calculated at five per centum per annum with annual rests. Upon paying such amount the employer shall be discharged from all further liability on account of the injury or death, and be entitled to a duly executed release, upon filing which, or other due proof of payment, the liability of such employer under any agreement, award, findings, or decree shall be discharged of record. Whenever an injured employes or his dependents and the em - ployer agree that the amounts of compensation due in periodic pay - ments for death, permanent disability, or claimed permanent dis - ability, under this article, shall be commuted to one or more lump sum payments, such settlement or agreement therefor, shall be sub - mitted to the district court in the following manner: An application for the approval of such settlement, signed by both parties, shall be filed with the clerk of the district court, and shall be entitled the same as an action by such employee or de - pendents against such employer; and shall contain a concise state - ment of the terms of the settlement sought to be approved, together with a brief statement of the facts concerning the injury, the nature thereof, the wages received by the injured employee prior thereto, and the nature of the employment. The judge of the district court, immediately, or within one week after the filing of said application, unless there be good cause for continuance, at chambers or in open court and in or out of term time, shall hold a hearing on said ap - plication, and proof may be adduced, witnesses subpoenaed and ex - amined, the same as in an action in equity. If, after such in - quiry, the court finds said settlement fair, just, and for the best interests of said employee or his dependents under all the circum - stances, he shall make an order approving the same. If such agree - ment or settlement be not approved the court may dismiss said application at the cost of the employer or continue the hearing, in the discretion of the court. The fees of the clerk of the district court for filing, docketing, and indexing such application shall be one dollar. (As amended 1917, p. 212.) </seg>
            <seg id="p029">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 29 Settlements to Be Final — Exceptions. 3682 Sec. 132. All settlements by agreement of thu parties with the approval of the Compensation Commissioner and all awards of compensation made by the court, except those amounts payable periodically for six months or more, shall be final and not subject to readjustment. (As amended 1917, p. 213.) When Compensation Payable Periodically May Be Modified. 3683 Sec. 133. All amounts paid by an employer or by an in - surance company carrying such risk, as the case may be, and re - ceived by the employee or his dependents, by lump sum payments, shall be final, but the amount of any agreement or award payable periodically for more than six months may be modified as follows: (a) At any time by agreement of the parties with the ap - proval of the Compensation Commissioner. (b) If the parties cannot agree, then at any time alter six months from the date of the agreement or award, an application may be made to the court by either party on the ground of increase or decrease of incapacity due solely to the injury, or that the condi - tion of a dependent has changed as to age or marriage, or by reason of the death of a dependent. In such case the same procedure shall be followed as in Section 3680 in case of disputed claim for compen - sation. (As amended 1917, p. 213.) Employer May Pay Award to Trustee and Be Discharged. 3684 Sec. 134. At any time after the amount of any award has been agreed upon by the parties and approved by the compensation commissioner, or found and ordered by the court, a sum equal to the present value of all future installments of compensation may (where death or the nature of the injury renders the amount of future pay - ments certain) by leave of court, be paid by the employer, or by the insurance company carrying such risk, as the case may be, to any savings bank or trust company of this state, in good standing, and such sum together with all interest thereon, shall thereafter be held in trust for the employee or the dependents of the employee, who shall have no further recourse against the employer. The pay - ment of such sum by the employer, evidenced by the receipt of the trustee to be filed with the Compensation Commissioner, shall operate as a satisfaction of said award as to the employer. Pay - ments from said fund shall be made by the trustee in the same amounts and at the same time as are herein required of the em - ployer until said fund and interest shall be exhausted. In the ap - pointment of the trustee, preference shall be given, in the discretion of the court, to the choice of the injured employee or the de - pendents of the deceased employee, as the case may be. (As amended 1917, p. 214.) Same to Would-be Administrator. 3685 Sec. 135. In case of death, where no executor or admin - istrator is qualified, the said court shall, by order, direct payment to be made to such persons as would be appointed administrator of the estate of such decedent, upon like terms as to bond for the proper application of compensation payments as are required of administrators. (1913, p. 598.) Reports of Settlements and Accidents. 3686 Sec. 136. Reports of accidents and settlements shall be made in form and manner as prescribed and directed by the Com - pensation Commissioner. Such reports, if filed by an insurance </seg>
            <seg id="p030">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 30 company on behalf of an employee, shall be deemed to have been filed by the employer. When an injury results in the death of an employee who is a citizen or subject of a foreign country, the Compensation Commis - sioner shall, after such death has been reported to him, at once notify the superior consular officer of the country of which the em - ployee at the time of his death was a citizen or subject, and whose consular district embraces the State of Nebraska, or the representa - tive, residing in the State of Nebraska, of such consular officer, whom he shall have formally designated as his representative by a communication in writing to the Compensation Commissioner. Such notification shall contain in addition to the name of the employee, such further information as the Compensation Commissioner may possess respecting the place of birth, parentage, and names and ad - dresses of the dependents of the employee. (As amended 1917, p. 214.) Insurance. 3687 Sec. 137. Every employer in the occupations described in Section 97 of this chapter shall either insure and keep insured his liability under this article in some corporation, association or organi - zation authorized and licensed to transact the business of work - men's compensation insurance in this state, or shall furnish to the Compensation Commissioner satisfactory proof of his financial abil - ity to pay direct the compensation in the amount and manner and when due as provided for in this act. In the latter case the Com - pensation Commissioner may in his discretion require the deposit of an acceptable security, indemnity or bond to secure the payment of compensation liabilities as they are incurred. Every employer who fails, neglects or refuses to comply with the conditions set forth in this section shall be deemed to have elected not to come under Part II hereof, and shall be required to respond in damages to an employee for personal injuries, or where personal injuries result in the death of an employee, then to his dependents, in like manner as if the employer had filed an election with the Compensation Com - missioner rejecting the provisions of Part II of the compensation act. (As amended 1917, p. 215.) Insurance Policies. 3688 Sec. 138. No policy of insurance against liability arising under this act shall be issued unless it contains the agreement of the insurer that it will promptly pay to the person entitled to same all benefits conferred by this act, and all installments of the com - pensation that may be awarded or agreed upon, and that the obliga - tion shall not be affected by any default of the insured after the injury, or by any default in the giving of any notice required by such policy, or otherwise. Such agreement shall be construed to be a direct promise by the insurer to the person entitled to compensa - tion enforceable in his name. Every policy for the insurance of the compensation herein pro - vided, or against liability thereof, shall be deemed to be made sub - ject to the provisions of this act. No corporation, association or organization shall enter into any such policy of insurance unless its form shall have been approved by the compensation commissioner. All policies insuring the payment of compensation under this act must contain a clause to the effect that as between the employer and the insurer the notice to or knowledge of the occurrence of the in - jury on the part of the insured shall be deemed notice or knowledge, as the case may be, on the part of the insurer; that jurisdiction of the insured for the purpose of this act shall be jurisdiction of the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 31 insurer; and that the insurer shall in all things be bound by and subject to the awards, judgments or decrees rendered against such insured. (As amended 1917, p. 215.) Existing Liability Insurance Contracts. 3689 Sec. 139. Nothing herein shall affect any existing con - tract for employer's liability insurance, or affect the organization of any mutual or other insurance company, or any arrangement now existing between employers and employees, providing tor the pay - ment to such employees, their families, dependents or representa - tives, sick, accident or death benefits in addition to the compensation provided for by this article; but liability for compensation under this article shall not be reduced or affected by any insurance of the injured employee, or any contribution or other benefit whatso - ever, due to or received by the person entitled to such compensa - tion, and the person so entitled shall, irrespective of any insurance or other contract, have the right to recover the same directly from the employer, and in addition thereto, the right to enforce in his own name in the manner provided in the next preceding section the liability of any insurer who may, in whole or in part, have insured the liability for such compensation: Provided, however, payment in whole or in part of such compensation by either the employer, or the insurer, as the case may be, shall, to the extent thereof, be a bar to recovery against the other, of the amount so paid. (1913, p. 600.) PART III A. Miscellaneous Provisions. Employer — How Released From Claims, 3690 Sec. 140. If any employee, or his dependents in case of death, or any employer subject to the provisions of Part II of this artcile files any claim with, or accepts any payment from such em - ployer, or from any insurance company carrying such risk, on ac - count of personal injury, or makes any agreement, or submits any question to the court under Part II of this article, such action shall constitute a release to such employer of all claims or demands at law, if any, arising from such injury. (1913, p. GOO.) Payments Not Assignable. 3691 Sec. 141. No payments under this article shall be as - signable or subject to attachment or garnishment, or be held liable in any way for any debts, except as provided in Section 99 of this chapter. (1913, p. 600.) Preference as to Compensation. 3692 Sec. 142. The right to compensation and all compensa - tion awarded any injured employee or for death claims to his de - pendents (without limit of amount), shall have the same preference against the assets of the employer as unpaid wages for labor, but such compensation shall not become a lien on the property of third persons by reason of such preference. (1913, p. 600.) B. Words and Phrases Defined. Definitions. 3693 Sec. 143. Throughout this act, the following words and phrases as used therein shall be considered to have the following meaning respectively, unless the context shall clearly indicate a different meaning in the construction used: (a) The term "Physician" shall include "Surgeon" and in </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT either case shall mean one legally authorized to practice his pro - fession within the State of Nebraska, and in good standing in his profession at the time. (b) The word "Accident" as used in this act shall, unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context, be construed to mean an unexpected or unforseen event happening suddenly and vio - lently, with or without human fault and producing at the time ob - jective symptoms of an injury. The term "Injury" and "Personal Injuries" shall mean only violence to the physical structure of the body and such disease or infection as naturally results therefrom. The said terms shall in no case be construed to include occupational disease in any form, or any contagious or infectious disease contracted during the course of employment, or death due to natural causes, but occurring while the workman is at work. "Death" when mentioned as a basis for the right to compensa - tion means only death resulting from such violence and its resultant effects occurring within three hundred and fifty weeks after the ac - cident. (c) Without otherwise affecting either tne meaning or interpre - tation of the abridged clause, "Personal injuries arising out of*and in the course of employment," it is hereby declared: Not to cover workmen except while engaged in, on or about the premises where their duties are being performed, or where their service requires their presence as a part of such services at the time of the injury, and during the hours of service as such workmen. (d) For the purpose of this act, wilful negligence shall consist of (1) deliberate act, or (2) such conduct as evidences reckless indifference to safety, or (3) intoxication at the time of the injury, such intoxication being without the consent or knowledge or ac - quiescence of the employer or the employer's agent. (e) Whenever in this act the singular is used, the plural shall be included; where the masculine gender is used, the luminiue shall be included. (f) The designation "State Insurance Commissioner" or "In - surance Commissioner" as used herein is intended to mean the state official who has charge of the Insurance Department of the State of Nebraska. (g) The "court" as used herein shall mean the District Court which would have jurisdiction in an ordinary civil case involving a claim for the injuries or death in question, and the "judge" shall mean a judge of said court. (h) The designation "Compensation Commissioner" or "Com - missioner" as used herein is intended to mean the state official designated by the statutes to administer this article. (As amended 1917, p. 216.) Rights of Action Preserved. 3694 Sec. 144. Every right of action for death by wrongful act, or for injury by negligence, accruing to an injured employee prior to the taking effect of this article, is continued and preserved under the existing law. (1913, p. 602.) Extension of Time Limit for Commencement of Actions at Common Law if Article Repealed or Held Invalid. 3695 Sec. 145. If the provisions of this article relating to the compensation for injuries to or eath of workmen shall be repealed or adjudged invalid or unconstitutional, the period intervening be - tween the occurrence of an injury or death and such repeal, or the final adjudication of invalidity, shall not be computed as a part of </seg>
            <seg id="p033">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 33 the time limited by law for the commencement of any action relat - ing to such injury or death, but the amount of any compensation which may have been paid for any such injury shall be deducted from any judgment for damages recovered on account of such in - jury. (1913, p. 602.) As to Constitutionality 3b96 Sec. 146. In case for any reason any paragraph or any provision of this article shall be questioned in any court and shall be held to be unconstitutional or invalid, the same shall not be held to affect any other paragraph or provision of this article, ex - cept that Parts I and II are hereby declared to be inseparable, and if either part be declared void or inoperative in an essential part, so that the whole of such part must fall, the other part shall fall with it and not stand alone. Part I of this article shall not apply in cases where Part II becomes operative in accordance with the pro - visions thereof, but shall apply in all other cases when the employer is subject to the provisions of this article and in such cases shall be in extension or modification of the common law. (1913, p. 602.) NEW SECTIONS. Attorney General and County Attorney* Represent Employee*. It shall be the duty of the county attorneys of the several coun - ties and the attorney general cf the state to appear as counsel for claimants for compensation and benefits under this article, and to assist and act in an advisory capacity to the Compensation Com - missioner, upon his request. (New amendment 1917, p. 218.) Act Not Affect Past Injuries. It is expressly provided that not anything contained in this en - tire amendatory act is intended to or shall operate to affect the amount or amounts recoverable for any character of injury sus - tained by any person or persons prior to the going into effect of its amendatory act. (New amendment 1917, p. 218.) Compensation Division in Labor Bureau. There is hereby created a Compensation Division in the Bureau of Labor for the State of Nebraska. (New amendment 1917, p. 218.) Compensation Commissioner — Duties — Powers. The Commissioner of Labor of the state is hereby made the compensation commissioner and there is hereby imposed upon him the duty of executing all of the provisions of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for the year 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof. To aid him in the discharge of his duty he is hereby authorized to appoint a chief deputy compensation commissioner who shall serve for a period of two years from the date of appointment and until his successor is appointed and quali - fies, and shall receive such remuneration for his services and in such manner as provided by legislative enactment. The chief deputy compensation commissioner shall succeed to the powers and dis - charge the duties vested in the Compensation Commissioner. The Compensation Commissioner shall from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary and proper to promptly and effectively enforce the provisions of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for the year 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof. In the performance of his duties the Com - pensation Commissioner, or the Chief Deputy Compensation Com - missioner is authorized and empowered to examine under oath or otherwise any person, any employee, any employer, any agent or </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT superintendent or foreman or officer of any co-partnership or cor - poration, or any officer of any domestic insurance company, or any agent of any foreign insurance company, or any medical practitioner; to issue subpoenas for the appearance of witnesses and the produc - tion of books and papers and administer oaths with like effect as is done in courts of law in this state. In the examination of any wit - ness and in requiring the production of books, papers and other evidence, the Commissioner of Compensation shall have and exer - cise all of the powers of a judge, magistrate or other officer in the taking of depositions or the examination of witnesses, including the power to enforce his orders by commitment for refusal to answer or for the disobedience of any such order. (New amendment 1917, p. 218.) Assistants to Commissioner. The Compensation Commissioner may employ such assistants as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this act: Pro - vided, that the expenses incurred shall not exceed the appropria - tion therefor. The Compensation Commissioner shall provide a seal for the certification of his orders, awards, and proceedings upon which shall be inscribed the words "Compensation Commissioner, State of Nebraska— Official Seal." (New amendment 1917, p. 219.) Powers — Procedure Before Compensation Commissioner — And General Provisions. The Compensation Commissioner shall, for the purpose contem - plated by this act, have power to issue subpoenas, compel the at - tendance of witnesses, administer oaths, certify to official acts, take depositions within or without the State of Nebraska as now pro - vided by law, compel the production of pertinent books, pay rolls, accounts, papers, records, documents and testimony. If a person in attendance before the Compensation Commissioner shall refuse, without reasonable cause, to be examined or to answer a legal and pertinent auestion, or to produce a book or paper when ordered to do so by the Compensation Commissioner, the Compensation Com - missioner may apply to the district court of any judicial district in the State of Nebraska, upon proof by affidavit of the fact, for a rule or order returnable in not less than two or more than five days, directing such person to show cause before the judge who made the order, or any other judge aforesaid, why he should not be committed to jail: upon the return of such order, the judge before whom the matter and such persons shall come on for a hearing shall examine under oath such nersons and such person shall be given an opportunity to be heard; and if the judge shall determine that such person has refused without reasonable cause or legal excuse, to be examined or to answer a legal or pertinent auestion, or to produce a book or paper which he was ordered to bring or produce, he may forthwith commit the offender to jail, there to remain until he submits to do the act which he was re quired to do, or is discharged according to law. No person shall be excused from testifying or from producing any books or paners or documents in any investigation or inquiry by or upon any hearing before the Compensation Commissioner, when ordered to do so by the Compensation Commissioner, upon the ground that the testi - mony or evidence, books, papers or documents required by him may tend to incriminate him or subject him to penalty or forfeiture; but no person shall be prosecuted, punished or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture for or on account of any act, transaction, matter or thing concerning which he shall, under oath have, by order of the Compensation Commissioner, testified to or produced documentary </seg>
            <seg id="p035">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 35 evidence of. Provided, however, that no person so testifying shall be exempt from prosecution or punishment for any perjury com - mitted by him in his testimony. (a) Subject to the provisions of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Re - vised Statutes of Nebraska for the year 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof, the Compensation Commissioner shall adopt reasonable and proper rules to govern procedure, which procedure shall be as summary and simple as reasonably may be. The Com - pensation Commissioner shall regulate and provide the kind and character of notices, the services thereof, and in cases of injury by accident to employees, the nature and extent of the proofs and evi - dence and the method of taking and furnishing the same for the establishment of the right to compensation; he shall determine the nature and forms of application of those claiming to be entitled to benefits or compensation, and shall regulate the method of making investigations, physical examinations and inspections and prescribe the time within which adjudications arid awards shall be made; Provided always that such rules and regulations shall conform to the provisions of Article VIII, Section 35, Revised Statutes of Ne - braska for 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof. (b) The Compensation Commissioner shall not be bound by the usual common law or statutory rules of evidence or by any techni - cal or formal rules of procedure, other than as herein provided, but may make the investigation in such manner as in his judgment is best calculated to ascertain the substantial rights of the parties and to carry out justly the spirit of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof. (c) A transcribed copy of the evidence and proceedings, or any specific part thereof, of any investigation taken by a stenographer for the Compensation Commissioner, being certified and sworn to by such stenographer, to be a true and correct transcript of the testi - mony, or of a particular witness, or any specific part thereof, or to be a correct copy of the transcript of the proceedings had on such investigation so purporting to be taken and transcribed, may be received in evidence by the Compensation Commissioner with the same effect as if such stenographer were present and testified to the facts certified. A copy of such transcript shall be furnished on demand to any party in interest upon payment of the fee therefor, as provided for transcripts in the district courts of the State of Nebraska. (d) The Compensation Commissioner shall keep and maintain a full and true record of all proceedings, of all documents or papers ordered filed, of all rules and regulations, of all decisions or orders. (e) The Compensation Commissioner shall prepare and furnish free of cost to employers, and to insurance companies licensed to write compensation insurance in this state, blank forms of applica - tion for benefits or compensation, elections to operate under Part II of Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof, reports of injury, proofs of injury or death, reports of medical attendance, of employment and wage earnings, and such other blanks as may be deemed proper and advisable. The Compensation Commissioner shall provide rules for the distribution of the blanks so prepared, and it shall he the duty of employers to constantly keep on hand a sufficient supply of such blanks. (f) Annually on or before the first day of January of each year the Compensation Commissioner shall issue a bulletin which shall Include a statement of the number and amount of settlements and. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT m awards made by the Compensation Commissioner, the causes of the accidents leading to the injuries for which the settlements and awards were made and a total statement of the expense of the Compensation Commissioner, together with any other matters which the Compensation Commissioner deems proper to include, as well as any recommendations he may desire to make. (g) Every claim for benefits under the provisions of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for the year 1913, and any act or acts amendatory thereof, may be presented to the Compensation Commissioner for adjudication and an order and an award. Any party at interest may present a claim in person or by an attorney. Every order and award of the Compensation Commis - sioner shall be binding upon each party at interest unless notice of intention to appeal to the district court has been filed with the Compensation Commissioner within seven days following the date of rendition of the order or award: Provided, that the order and award shall be binding and final, notwithstanding notice of inten - tion to appeal has been filed within the time limit, until the appeal has been perfected and service had upon the opposite party or parties. (h) Each applicant for an order or an award by the Com - pensation Commissioner shall pay all expense of his or their own making. Provided, that there shall be no filing fees charged by the Compensation Commissioner, and that the Compensation Commis - sioner may at his discretion assess the costs of the applicant or ap - plicants against the respondent or respondents as in like manner done in courts of the state. (New amendment 1917, p. 219.) Saving Clause. In case for any reason any paragraph or any provision of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, or any paragraph or any provision of this act shall be questioned in any court and shall be held to be unconstitutional or invalid, the same shall not be held to affect any other paragraph or provision of Article VIII, Chapter 35, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, or any paragraph or any provision of this act, except that Parts I and II of said Article are hereby declared to be inseparaole, and if either part be declared void or inoperative in an essential part, so that the whole of such part must fall, the other part shall fall with it and not stand alone. Part I of this article shall not apply in cases where Part II becomes operative in accordance with the provisions thereof, but shall apply in all other cases when the em - ployer is subject to the provisions of this article and in such cases shall be in extension or modification of the common law. (New amendment 1917, p. 222.) </seg>
            <seg id="p037">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 37 WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION ACT ELECTING TO COME UNDER Employer No. Employees City Date John Wilhelm Omaha Jan. 5, 1917 Jan. 5, 1917 Jan. 11, 1917 James Skreks 4 Nebras 4 Nebraska Omaha ... Fred G. Caldwell &amp; L. O. Paine 6 Omaha Fred G. Caldwell &amp; L. O. Paine 6 Efficiency Motor Corp. (E. Con - way) 1 Omaha way) 1 Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Jan. 12, 1917 Jan. 17, 1917 Jan. 20. 1917 Jan. 20, 1917 Feb. 3, 1917 Feb. 23, 1917 FeY 27, 1917 Feb. 28, 1917 Mar. 14, 1917 Mar. 24, 1917 Apr. 9, 1917 Apr. 18, 1917 Apr. 18, 1917 May 1, 1917 Apr. 24, 1917 Apr. 24, 1917 Apr. 24, 1917 Apr. 24, 1917 Young &amp; Henderson Co 3 Omaha Young &amp; Henderson Co J. V. Rosenblum Omaha J. V. Rosenblum Jesse Coursen 1 Omaha Jesse Coursen 1 Geo. Kasland Nebras Geu. Kasland Nebraska Omaha ... Young &amp; Henderson 2 Omaha Young &amp; Henderson ■&gt; Efficiency Motor Corp 2 Omaha Etficiency Motor Corp Omaha Omaha Ralston Omaha Omaha 9. Jesse Coursen 1 Omaha Jesse Coursen 1 Brown Truck Mfg. Co 5 Ralstoi Brown Truck Mfg. Co. • r . J. Reisman 1 Omaha J. Reisman 1 A. C. Christiansen 1 Omaha A. C. Christiansen 1 R. C. Killian 2 Nebras R. C. Killian 9 Nebraska Omaha Levison &amp; Robinson 2 Omaha Levison &amp; Robinson •&gt; Burrell Engr. &amp; Constr. Co Chicagi Burrell Engr. &amp; Constr. Co. Chicago Omaha Omaha ... Nebraska Omaha ... Standard Accd. Ins. Co 2 Omaha Standard Accd. Ins. Co •&gt; Central Machine Works 4 Omaha Central Machine Works 4 Chas. G. Trumble 1 Xebras Chas. G. Trumble 1 J. N. Rapp 6 Omaha J. N. Rapp g Myers &amp; Wolf 4 Omaha Myers &amp; Wolf 4 Apr., 1917 Apr., 1917 Sullivan Bros 4 Omaha Sullivan Bros Becker, Hockenberger &amp; Cham- Platte &amp; Box bers Co Butte Counties Nebraska May 1, 1917 May 5, 1917 May 24, 1917 June 9, 1917 June 12, 1917 June 12, 1917 .June 16, 1917 July 11, 1917 ..Oct. 19, 1917 ..Oct. 26. 1917 Oct. 20, 1917 June 28, 1918 June 13, 1918 ..July 17, 1918 July 19, 1918 Aug. 10, 1918 Sept. 9, 1918 Sept. 30. 1918 Sept. 30, 1918 Sept. 30, 1918 Feb. 23, 1918 F. H. Fuller 4 John H. Boner Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Albion 1 E. R. Linderman Empl. Co 3 Central Machine Works 9 A. D. White •&gt; Young &amp; Henderson 1 Marsh &amp; Smith A. P. Ballah g Wolf Bros. 4 Lautzz McNerney Marble Co Poplin, Mo. Shelton Warren &amp; Son Zimmerman Henry Beatrice P. S. Heaeock &amp; Son s Chicago, III. Columbus . John Zentner Southern Surety Co 1 Shelton Omaha Beatrice Beatrice Beatrice Woods Updike Land Co Gustav Penner Henry Penner Frank Thinnson Chas McLeod t Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION ACT ELECTING NOT TO COME UNDER Name City Date John L. Lynds Mill &amp; Elev. Co White Cloud, Kans Feb. 13, 1917 Ordinance Revision Co. (O. B. Clark) Lincoln, Nebr May 23, 1917 Weber Chimney Co Chicago, 111 June 20, 1917 Grand Union Tea Co Omaha, Nebr July 9, 1917 N. C. Brorson Blair, Nebr July 19, 1917 C. J. Beckman Blair, Nebr July 19, 1917 Lincoln Brick Works (C. Klose Mgr) Lincoln, Nebr July 21, 1917 Roy Deets Kearney, Nebr Aug. 20, 1917 Haddoff Music House Omaha, Nebr Sept. 20, 1917 Elsasser's Barber Shop Omaha, Nebr Sept. 20, 1917 Bemis Omaha Bag Co Omaha, Nebr Sept. 7, 1917 H. R. Koopman Furnace Co. (L. A. Warne) St. Paul, Nebr Sept. 20, 1917 C. F. Antles Lincoln, Nebr Oct. 9, 1917 Strode &amp; Beghtol Lincoln, Nebr Jan. 3, 1918 City of Sidney Sidney, Nebr Jan. 3, 1918 Emerson Braxingham Imp. Co Omaha, Nebr Jan. 11, 1917 Morse Sales Co Lincoln, Nebr Feb. 6, 1918 J. C. Penney Co Beatrice, Nebr July 5, 1918 David City Falls City North Platte Ord Grand Island Hastings McCook </seg>
            <seg id="p039">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 39 WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION ACT CARRYING OWN LIABILITY Name City Date Swift &amp; Company Cudahy Packing Co )maha, Nebr July 10, 1917 )maha, Nebr. July 23, 1917 Omaha &amp; Council Bluffs St. Ry Omaha Gas Co )maha, Nebr hnaha, Nebr July 24, 1917 Intl. Harvester Co Omaha Printing Co Merchants Nat'l Bank Hugh Murphy Constr. Co. Standard Oil Co "hicago, 111. July 24, 1917 Dmaha, Nebr July 24, 1917 )maha, Nebr imaha, Nebr July 24. 1917 )maha. Nebr July 24. 1917 Dempster Mill Mfg. Co. Morris &amp; Co Beatrice. Nebr Aug. 1, 1917 )maha. Nebr July 24, 1917 Nebraska Power Co Stroud &amp; Co Imaha, Nebr Aug. 14, 1917 Dmaha, Nebr Aug. 14, 1917 M. M. Johnson Co Hastings, Nebr. Aug. 14, 1917 American Smelting &amp; Ref. Co. Hydraulic Press Brick Co Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Co }maha, Nebr. Aug. 15, 1917 3t Louis. Mo Aug. 18, 1917 &gt;maha, Nebr. Aug. 20, 1917 City of Kearney Kearney, Nebr. Aug. 22, 1917 Nebraska Telephone Co. American Express Co. .. H. J. Heinz Co Dmaha, Nebr. Aug. 27, 1917 )maha, Nebr Sept. 26, 1917 Pittsburgh, Pa. (Omaha) Oct. 1, 1917 National Refining Co. &gt;maha, Nebr. Oct. 12, 1917 B. F. Goodrich Rubber Co. City of Omaha Akron, O. (Omaha) Nov. 3, 1917 Omaha, Nebr. Nov. 17, 1917 Morton Gregson Co. Nebraska City, Nebr Nov. 24, 1917 J. I. Case Threshing Co Western Union Company.. Chicago Bridge &amp; Iron Co. Nye Schneider Fowler Co. Lincoln Traction Co ..Racine, Wis. Dec. 15. 1917 New York City Dec. 26, 1917 Chicago, III. June 6, 1918 Fremont, Nebr Muyl3, 1918 Lincoln, Nebr. May 27, 1918 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Telegr. Co. American Tel. &amp; Telegr. Co. American Ry. Express June 11, 1918 New York June 21, 1918 New York July 25, 1918 Lyman Sand Co. Omaha, Nebr. July 25, 1918 Central Granaries Co. Nebraska Elevator Co. Armour Packing Co McKeen Motor Car Co. Lincoln, Nebr. -Lincoln, Nebr Aug. 24, 1918 Omaha, Nebr Aug. 17, 1917 Aug. 17, 1917 Omaha, Nebr. July 29, 1917 July 23, 1917 July 25, 1917 Lincoln, Nebr. Au=;. 24, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 40 PART IV Workmen's Compensation Law Statistical Data "Accidents result from the carelessness of ourselves or those with whom we come in contact. Safety, like charity, begins at home. We must become careful men and women, and by the power of example can teach the careless ones. Continued care - fulness and thoughtfulness makes us alert to the welfare of those who cross our path. This must result in fewer accidents. Let us be careful." "And when your work is done, it is done well if it is done safely. "If you don't believe in Safety First, visit the reception ward of a hospital." "Safety First is a mighty fine rule to follow; especially if you haven't lost a limb first." </seg>
            <seg id="p041">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 41 £0 THE WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION LAW STATISTICAL DATA It will be noticed throughout the Biennial Report no attempt is made to go into extended detail. We are using, for the most part, the totals and such other information as the reader will most likely carry away with him. Often so much unnecessary detail is given that the average reader is at a loss to lay his finger on just the exact knowledge he is after. In the compensation tables which follow, for example, we have purposely omitted details of facts by months, but have instead grouped them all into general tables. A brief explanation of terms at this point will help to more clearly read the report. There has been a mistake in interpreting such terms as compensation and non-compensation. The following definition of com - pensation taken from Bouvier's Law Dictionary should make the mean - ing clear. Compensation is: "Something to be done, for or paid to a person of equal value for something of which he has been deprived by the acts or negligence of the party so doing or paying." According to this definition an employee who was injured and who was allowed only medical care would have to come within the meaning of this definition. What he received (medical care) is considered to be of equal value with something (capacity to work) of which he has been deprived. Had it been considered that his deprivation was greater than this, he would be given more by way of a specific amount per week for a definite number of weeks, as it would take this extra amount to equal what he had been deprived of. A Non-Compensation case is one, therefore, for which any returns whatsoever, medical, hospital or money, are denied. Where settlement is effected between employer and employee through the offices of the Chief Deputy Commissioner without filing for a hearing, it is wrong to designate them as non-compensation cases. Non-compensation cases, therefore, are cases filed for hearing with the Compensation Commis - sioner and after filing does not refer in any way to the manner of settle - ment. That is to say, after a case is filed it may be settled without a hearing or with a hearing, but in either event compensation must be denied or not paid to come under the definition of non-compensation. The following statistical data of compensation cases are divided as follows: The first tables are a general compilation for the entire year with no attempt to classify them as to the time injuries lasted. The second set of tables goes a step further by classifying the in - juries of duration of injury ranging from no days lost to seven, with the number of cases under each division for the year, the amount of medical and hospital, and the average benefit. In many cases an employee may receive a minor injury which will not cause him to lose any time, but which will call for treatment. In other cases but one-half day is lost and so on down to seven days. The compensation cases which cause the loss of more than one </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT week are divided into periods of weeks. The tabulation begins with in- juries lasting two weeks and run up to those which cause the loss of twenty-four weeks time. All injuries causing a greater loss of time are put in one class, "More than twenty-four weeks." It will be noted that money compensation is added to this table: the total compensations, therefore, would be the sum of the medical and hospital and the money compensation. This sum is averaged and placed in the last column, headed, "Average Compensation." It should be borne in mind that the tables are made for compensation cases for one week or less; for more than one week a separate classifi cation is made because the law clearly makes such a division GENERAL REPORT OF ACCIDENTS FROM JANUARY 1ST TO DECEMBER 31ST, 1917 Compensation for Injuries Lasting More Than One Week — Total number cases reported 7,647 Total number of cases completed 7,562 Total paid in compensation $101,204.51 Average paid in compensation $1,323 Total paid for medical and hospital $34,109.07 Average paid for medical and hospital $8.34 Total number of weeks lost 37,724 Average number of weeks lost 4.93 Compensation for Injuries Lasting One Week or Less — Total number of cases reported 5,631 Total paid for medical and hospital $17,627.25 Average paid for medical and hospital $3.14 Total number of days lost 10,094 Average number of days lost _ 1,79 Fatal Accidents- Total number of fatal accidents 15 Total money paid in fatal cases — to date $8,642.28 Average money paid in fatal cases $576.15 Total paid for medcial and hospital $90.90 Average paid for medical and hospital $6.06 Total paid for funeral benefits $1,500.00 General — Total number of cases of negligence 758 Total number of cases of negligence of employer 1,343 Total number of cases of negligence of fellow workmen 198 Total number of cases incident to employment 2,693 Total number of cases fault not placed 8,271 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 43 COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING ONE WEEK OR LESS FOR THE YEAR 1917. FROM JANUARY 1ST TO DECEMBER 1ST. COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING MORE THAN ONE WEEK FOR THE YEAR 1917, BEGINNING JANUARY 1ST AND ENDING DECEMBER 31ST "e M S n * jp No. Medical- Compen- Total Com- Av. Cora - ls &lt;-&gt; Cases Hospital sation pensation pensation 5? No. of Days Lost Time of Days 3t Time No. Cases Medical- Hospital Average Benefit to Employee 0 V; 1 2 3 4 5 ( 7 3,734 68 380 377 285 210 193 159 225 $ 10,484.32 250.50 718.35 1,065.55 1,023.15 891.20 822.98 865.40 1,505.80 $ 2.81 3.68 1.89 2.82 3.59 4.24 4.26 5.44 6.69 Total 5,631 i 17,627.25 $35.42 2 3 4 5 •; 7 S 9 in 11 12 IS 14 15 16 17 18 19 M 21 22 23 24 More Than 24 1,949 1,468 964 879 820 348 240 224 202 135 120 59 40 35 91 4 5 6 4 3 4 5 7 ! 1 35 $ 3,372.91 5,356.15 3,841.63 3,177.40 2,330.78 1,495.40 1,856.35 1,225.50 1,338.41 940.69 1,214.75 717.50 554.85 314.00 1,266.25 131.00 163.00 303.00 198.00 229.00 191.00 212.00 342.00 3,407.50 % 4,423.53 6.004.23 3,803.78 3,795.21 4,423.45 2,853.20 3,906.09 1,879.17 2,719.28 1,885.63 3,275.28 1,174.19 1,415.93 1,477.10 2,046.21 674.50 721.50 2,217.45 628.00 483.00 728.00 841.00 928.00 14,724.50 $ 7,796.44 11,360.38 7,645.41 6,972.61 6,754.23 4,348.60 5,761.44 3,101.67 4,057.69 2,826.32 4,490.03 1,891.69 1,980.78 1,791.10 3,312.46 805.50 884.00 2,521.21 826.00 712.00 619.45 1,053.00 1,260.50 18,132.00 I i 4.00 7.73 7.93 7.93 8.23 12.40 2.40 13.84 20.08 20.93 37.41 32.06 49.51 51.17 36.40 201.37 176.80 420.20 206.50 237.33 229.86 263.20 190.07 518.00 'otal 7,647 $34,109.07 $67,028.73 $101,204.51 $2,930.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 44 GENERAL REPORT OF ACCIDENTS FROM JANUARY 1ST TO OCTOBER 31ST, 1918 Compensation for Injuries Lasting More Than One Week — Total number of cases reported 2,126 Total number cases completed 1,523 Total paid in compensation $90,967.48 Average paid in compensation $42.31 Total paid for medical and hospital $24,882.91 Average paid for medical and hospital $11.70 Total number of days lost 9,956 Average number of days lost 4.68 Compensation for Injuries Lasting One Week or Less — Total number of cases reported 4,927 Total paid for medical and hospital $14,311.58 $2.90 Average paid for medical and hospital Total number of days lost 8,998 Average number of days lost 1.82 Fatal Accidents — Total number of fatal accidents reported 13 Total money paid in fatal accidents — to date $11,573.00 $890.23 Average money paid in fatal cases Total paid for medical and hospital $42.50 Average paid for medical and hospital $1,300.00 General — Total number of cases of negligence of employer 880 Total number of cases of negligence of employee 721 Total number of cases of negligence of fellow workmen 155 Total number of cases incident to employment 3,354 Total number of cases fault not placed 1,930 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 45 COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING MORE THAN ONE WEEK FOR THE YEAR 1918 FROM JANUARY 1ST TO OCTOBER 31ST. No. of Days Lost Time No. Cases Medical- Average Benefit Hospital to Employee to Employee 0 2.851 $ 8,192.95 $ 2.87 4 312 688.00 2.20 1 403 1,010.45 2.57 M0.30 •&gt; 329 3.01 3 301 898.38 2.98 4 215 818.10 3.85 5 156 650.30 4.19 6 133 582.60 4.38 fi 133 4.38 7 227 1,371.50 , 6.04 8.04 I Total 4,927 $ 14,311.58 $32.09 Total 4,927 $ 14,311.58 $32.09 COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING ONE WEEK OR MORE DMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING ONE WEEK OR MORE FOR THE YEAR 1918, BEGINNING JANUARY 1ST AND ENDING OCTOBER 31ST FOR THE YEAR 1918. BEGINNING JANUARY 1ST AND ENDING OCTOBER 31ST is « r No. Medical- Compen- Total Com- Av. Com- &gt; Cases Hospital O r&gt; &gt; w Cases Hospital aation pensation pensation sation pensation pensation i! . I i 2 687 $ 3,779.80 $ 7,126.94 $10,906.74 S 15.87 •&gt;-&gt;7 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 44 GENERAL REPORT OF ACCIDENTS FROM JANUARY 1ST TO OCTOBER 31ST, 1918 Compensation for Injuries Lasting More Than One Week — Total number of cases reported 2,126 Total number cases completed 1,523 Total paid in compensation $90,967.48 Average paid in compensation $42.31 Total paid for medical and hospital $24,882.91 Average paid for medical and hospital $11.70 Total number of days lost 9,956 Average number of days lost 4.68 Compensation for Injuries Lasting One Week or Less — Total number of cases reported 4,927 Total paid for medical and hospital $14,311.58 Average paid for medical and hospital $2.90 Total number of days lost 8,998 Average number of days lost 1.82 Fatal Accidents — Total number of fatal accidents reported 13 Total money paid in fatal accidents — to date $11,573.00 Average money paid in fatal cases $890.23 Total paid for medical and hospital $42.50 Average paid for medical and hospital $1,300.00 General — Total number of cases of negligence of employer 880 Total number of cases of negligence of employee 721 Total number of cases of negligence of fellow workmen 155 Total number of cases incident to employment 3,354 ERRATA THE FOLLOWING CORRECTIONS SHOULD BE NOTED ON PAGES 44 AND 45. On page 44. Compensation for injuries lasting more than one week. — lines seven and eight should re;id "weeks" instead of "days. On page 44. Fatal Accidents. — line three should read Aver- age money paid in fatal cases "to date." Line five should read Total paid for funeral benefits, instead of Average paid for medical and hospital. On page 45, The heading should read "Compensation for Injuries lasting less than one week," instead of Compensation for injuries lasting more than one week. GENERAL REMARKS The Compensation Department, by bringing the employer and injured party together, settled at least six hundred eases __ w ._ £ .^ ■&gt; VB ~««*^*j -ivinvv* ai ivciai r&gt;i-v uuilUKU taoCQ without a formal hearing before the Compensation Commis- sioner. This Department also approved of three hundred lump sum settlements, which were also approved by the District Court. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT ■»r, COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING MORE THAN ONE WEEK FOR THE YEAR 1918 FROM JANUARY 1ST TO OCTOBER 31ST. COMPENSATION FOR INJURIES LASTING ONE WEEK OR MORE FOR THE YEAR 1918. BEGINNING JANUARY 1ST AND ENDING OCTOBER 31ST 12 a» B » r No. Medical- Compen- Total Com- Av. Com - &gt; w Cases Hospital sation pensation pensation No. of Days Lost Time No. Cases Medical- Hospital Average Benefit to Employee 0 M&gt; 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 2,851 312 403 329 301 215 156 133 227 % 8,192.95 688.00 1,010.45 990.30 898.38 818.10 650.30 582.60 1,371.50 ? 2.87 2.20 2.57 3.01 2.98 3.85 4.19 4.38 6.04 - J_ Total 4,927 $ 14,311.58 $32.09 2iJ 2 4 5 I 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 II 17 IS 19 2&lt;&gt; 21 22 23 24 More Than 24 687 491 272 212 95 60 77 37 19 24 24 23 20 13 15 5 ! 7 s 3 None 22 I $ 3,779.80 2,714.41 3,409.93 2,600.17 2,002.35 1,163.95 1,423.83 956.60 714.93 482.00 505.30 557.50 6.00 660.80 358.85 172.25 606.40 521.63 605.20 90.50 34.00 25.00 1,486.51 I $ 7,126.94 5,532.05 6,572.34 6,511.56 4,623.08 3,459.17 3,148.79 2,340.51 2,113.19 1,313.68 1,597.85 1,755.93 1,468.00 2,066.42 1,430.00 601.10 1,183.00 1,259.00 1,177.26 714.29" 264.00 236.00 8,873.58 $10,906.74 8,246.46 9,982.27 9.111.73 6,625.43 4,623.12 4,572.62 3,297.11 3,543.05 1,795.68 2,103.15 2,313.43 1,474.00 2,727.22 1,788.85 773.35 1,789.40 1,780.63 1,782.46 804.79 298.00 261.00 10,360.09 $ 15.87 16.79 41.99 42.97 69.74 77.05 59.38 89.11 186.00 74.82 87.63 100.58 73.70 209.98 119.25 154.67 298.23 296.77 254.64 160.95 99.33 87.00 470.91 otal 2,126 $24,882.91 $65,362.74 $90,967.48 $3,087.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 46 RAILWAY ACCIDENTS Common carriers engaged in interstate commerce do not come under the control of the state compensation laws. The government controls all matters pertaining to compensation. However, as an item of interest the number of accidents and fatalities of the various railroads in Ne - braska for the year 1917 are given. In the table the other items giving the number of employees and wages are for the entire systems. A nn l 1 Acci- dents Fatal- ities Name of Road Employees Wages Wages Acci- 1 dents Fata itie C. B. &amp; Q. Ry C. S. P. M. &amp; 0 Ry. Co. . St. Joe &amp; Grand Island .... Mo. Pacific Ry. Co Chicago N. W. Ry. Co Chi. &amp; R. I. &amp; Pac. Ry. Union Pacific Ry Omaha Br'ge &amp; Ter. Ry. Union Stock Yds Omaha K. C. N. W. Ry Co 50,197 9,356 1,301 1,749 54,009 41,243 28,753 69 159 $49,179,625.13 9,019,615.28 1,093,197.85 884,839.10 50,326,948.69 38,318,590.22 27,742,710.84 92,467.32 155,163.25 954 Not i compiled ■ 13 119 340 17 491 9 58 26 3 3 M 3 ?A 1 1 Totals .... 186,836 $176,813,157.68 2,001 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 47 PART V Synopsis of Compensation Cases Heard Be fore the Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner There was a man who'd worked with gas For years and years and years, And by and by it came to pass He hadn't any fears. One day he found a leaking joint He used a match to find it. He also found that leaking gas Has lots of force behind it It blew him through the cellar door He traveled like an arrow And crashed against the garden fence, Which jarred him to the marrow. They picked him up; all sick and sore, And speechless with amazement He couldn't figure out at all Just how he left the basement. But when they'd stowed him safe in bed And bound by all his scratches, It dawned on him the thing at fault Was his foolish use of matches. So now with tied-up, busted face, Burned, cut and parched with thirst, He sobs, "B'gosh, when I get well, I'll sure Be Careful First." — R. N. Predmore. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">48 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT DECISIONS OF COMMISSIONER Appended hereto are the decisions of the Compensation Commis - sioner from July 24, 1917, to December 1, 1918. These decisions are not decisions of points of law, but they are simply to determine whether or not claimants under the statutes of Nebraska for compensa - tion are entitled to it. A brief summary of each case is given together with the award and notation of appeal and decision of court to which appeal was made. Where no decision is given the case has not yet been settled or decision not known. Each city where hearings are held constitutes a separate Docket. Following is a list of the dockets: Docket No. 1 — Omaha Docket No. 2 — Lincoln Docket No. 3 — Beatrice Docket No. 4 — Fremont Docket No. 5— Red Cloud Docket No. 6 — Grand Island Docket No. 7 — Curtice Docket No. 8— Neligh Docket No. 9 — Wahoo Docket No. 10— North Platte Docket No. 11— Scottsbluff Docket No. 12— York Docket No. 1, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Altnira Dawson. Plaintiff, vs. The F. P. Gould and Sons Construction Company, Defendants, and the Aetna Life Insurance Company, Respondents. J. C. Dawson, husband of Almira Dawson, plaintiff, was engaged as night watchman for the F. P. Gould and Sons Construction Company in the buildings of Armour and Company, South Omaha. Said company was repairing said buildings. Mr. Dawson, while on duty, was injured by falling into a defective and unlighted cellarway. Death took place a few months later as a result of the injury sustained by the fall. Com - pensation was awarded the widow, Almira Dawson, as follows: $7.00 per week not to exceed 350 weeks and $100.00 for funeral expenses. De - fendant appealed the case to the District Court, which sustained the decision of the Commissioner. Said defendant settled the claim by pay - ing $100.00 for funeral expenses and $1,800.00 in a lump sum. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 2. In the Matter of Arthur Bleich, Plaintiff, vs, Guy L. Smith, Defendant, and London Guarantee A Accident Com pany, Respondent. Arthur Bleich, employed by Guy L. Smith as assistant garage man, was injured while on regular duty. Bleich took a car on the elevator to the basement. As he was about to run the auto off from the elevator, it suddenly started upward. Bleich received a badly lacerated shoulder and head, numerous bruises and a severe shock. The Commissioner gave award as follows : The defendant to pay the sum of $5.00 per week for </seg>
            <seg id="p051">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 49 partial disability for a period not to exceed 300 weeks, and a further sum of $20.00 for Doctor bills. Smith appealed the case to the District Court, which gave award as follows: Defendant to pay the sum of $2.00 per week for a period not to exceed 300 weeks. On agreement the amount was paid in a lump sum. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 3. In the Matter of Hazel Adams, Plaintiff, vs. The City of Omaha, Defendant, and The City of Omaha, Respon- dent. John Q. Adams, husband of Hazel Adams, was employed as a fire - man by the City of Omaha. He was killed while in the fegular per - formance of his duties in trying to put out a fire at the Morris Packing Company plant. The City of Omaha asks that the petition for compen - sation be set aside, or if awarded that said compensation shall be credited to the City of Omaha in lieu of the fact that the said Hazel Adams was drawing a pension from the said City of Omaha. Later case was dismissed by request of the plaintiff. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 4. In the Matter of Alfred Pettie, Plaintiff, vs. The Union Pacific Railroad Company, Defendant, and The Union Pacific, Respondent. Claimant was a hosefitter helper in the Union Pacific shops at Omaha. At the time of injury claimant was bolting clamps onto air hose, and lost the sight of an eye the grounds that as the defendant not come within his jurisdiction. Commissioner dismissed the case on as engaged in interstate traffic it does Docket No. 1, Claim No. 5. In the Matter of Gabriol Zozula, Plaintiff vs. A. B. Alpirn, Defendant, and Martin Brothers Insurance Company, Respondents. Gabriol Zozula, an employee of A. B. Alpirn, engaged in the business of buying and selling junk, was injured while working for the said A. B. Alpirn. Defendant had paid Zozula a compensation of $7.78 per week. Plaintiff claims $8.50 per week under the compensation law of the state. Award was given by the Commissioner as follows: Defend - ant shall pay plaintiff the sum of $8.50 per week during the period of total disability, not to exceed 300 weeks. Settlement was made in lump sum of $687.56 paid, and medical bill of $147.45 allowed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 6. In the Matter of Gust Carlson, Plaintiff, vs. American Smelting A Refining Company, Defendant, and the American Smelting &amp; Refining Company, Respondents. Gust Carlson, regularly employed by the above company, lost a part of his foot while oiling machinery in the plant of said company. Commissioner made award as follows: Said company to pay the sum of $10.00 per week for a period of 150 weeks. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">50 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT On approval of District Court a lump sum settlement was made for $931.55. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 7. In the Matter of William Renner, Plaintiff, v*. Burrell Engineering and Construction Company, Defendant, and the London Guarantee &amp; Accident Company, Respondent. Claimant was injured by a jack handle striking him in the eye. In a short time said claimant returned to work, and the company paid compensation for the time he was laid up. Claim was made for further compensation because of alleged permanent disability of said eye. The defendant refused payment, alleging that said eye could be restored by an operation. The Commissioner made a conditional award as follows: That if claimant would submit to an operation, defendant should pay for same and $12.00 per week for six months. At the end of this time if said eye is not restored the defendant shall pay claimant $12.00 per week until $1,380.00, exclusive of surgeons fees and hospital fees, shall have been paid. Appealed to District Court which approved a lump sum settlement of $300.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 8. In the Matter of Matt Forturn, Plaintiff, vs. Wertheimer A. Degan, Defendants, and Wertheimer A Degan, Re- spondents. Matt Forturn, regularly employed by Wertheimer &amp; Degan, live stock merchants of Omaha, was ruptured while feeding cattle in the barns of this firm. The defendants paid $35.00 of a $60.00 doctor bill and $72.00 compensation, but refused to pay more on the grounds that plaintiff was cured. Case was settled before coming to trial by de - fendants paying to plaintiff the sum of $250 in addition to amounts already paid. This settlement was approved by the Commissioner. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 9. In the Matter of J .W. Mathiesen, Plaintiff vs. The Sanitary Wet Wash Laundry Company, Defendant, and Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp, Ltd., Respondents. Claimant was employed by the Wet Wash Laundry Company as an engineer, and machine repairer. While repairing some machinery Mathiesen fell off a laundry tub, breaking one of his ribs. The Commis - sioner awarded compensation amounting to $100.00 and shall thereafter pay him the sum of $10.00 per week until his disability is removed not to exceed 290 weeks. The case was appealed to the District Court by the defendant, but settled before coming to trial, by claimant agreeing to accept $100.00. Docket No. 1 .Claim No. 10. In the Matter of John Delay, Claimant, vs. J. C. Mardis A Company, Employer, and the Love-Haskell Com - pany, Insurer, Respondents. The employee was engaged by J. C. Mardis &amp; Company as a day laborer. At the time of his injury he was engaged in helping unload </seg>
            <seg id="p053">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 51 tiles. The bricks are thrown from man to man and while thus engaged Mr. Delay was struck over the left ey? by a tile brick, causing the total loss of the eye. Compensation was awarded by the Commissioner as follows: Twelve dollars per week not to exceed 100 weeks. Further that defendant shall pay medical expenses to a reasonable amount. The defendant appealed the case to the District Court, but same was settled before coming to trial by the defendant paying Mr. Delay the lump sum of $1,000.00. $15.00 court costs, approved by District Court. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 11. In thte Matter of Joe Lotta. Plaintiff, vs SeldervBreck Construction Company, Defendant, and the Maryland Casualty Company, Respondent. Claimant was injured by a fellow workman starting an elevator on which claimant was engaged in removing a wheelbarrow. Claimant was forced to hold on to the edge of the elevator, and as the elevator passed one of the floors, the claimant lost his grip and was thrown to the floor below. Compensation was awarded by the Commissioner as follows: $7.50 per week until disability is removed not to exceed 300 weeks. Case appealed to the District Court. Settlement effected before coming to trial on approval of. the court by the said defendant paying to claim - ant the sum of $375.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 12. In the Matter of Sonke Hansen, Plaintiff, vs. H. Gross Lumber &amp; Wrecking Company, Defendant, and H. Gross Lumber &amp; Wrecking Company, Respondent. Claimant had femur bone broken while engaged with the above named company in helping to wreck a building. Defendant paid com - pensation of $7.50 per week for some time and then stopped payment. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: Defendant required to continue to pay to plaintiff $7.50 per week until disability is removed, not to exceed 300 weeks, and a reasonable amount for medical attention. The case was appealed to the District Court by the defendant, but settled before trial, with the approval of the District Court, by the de - fendant paying to the plaintiff the lump sum of $1,000 and in addition $40.00 for doctor bill. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 13. In the Matter of Michael F. dishing, Plain- tiff, vs. Morris &amp; Company, Defendant, and Morris A Company, Respondent. Claimant was working in the box department of defendant, run - ning a circular saw. The fingers on one hand were injured and blood poisoning set in and fingers were amputated. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $220.00 as compensation for 5 months and con - tinuance of payment at the rate of $10.00 per week for 78 weeks, and defendant to pay costs and physicians and surgeon's fees. Case was ap - pealed to the District Court and sustained. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">52 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 1, Claim No. 14. In the Matter of Frank Ramsey, Plaintiff, vs. Hayden Brothers, Defendants, and the Maryland Casualty Com- pany, Respondents. Ramsey was enployed as a clerk at Hayden Brothers, general retail and dry goods merchants. While engaged in storing goods Ramsey was obliged to use a step-ladder, which gave way, causing Ramsey to fall, and severely injuring one of his knees. The defendant refused to pay any compensation. The Commissioner awarded compensation as fol - lows: Defendant required to pay Ramsey 111.33 per week until dis - ability removed not to exceed 300 weeks. Defendant appealed the case to the District Court. An agreement was reached before coming to trial by Ramsey agreeing to accept the sum of $226.60. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 15. In the Matter of Frank N. Williams, Plain tiff, vs. Omaha Structural Steel Works, Defendant, and the United States Fidelity &amp; Guarantee Company, Respondent Claimant was engaged as a watchman by said company. While on duty he stumbled over a coil of rope and fell on a lump of coal. He suffered a stroke of paralysis a short time later. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $9.33 per week until the removal of disability, not to exceed 300 weeks, and medical fees. Case was appealed. Claim was disallowed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 16. In the Matter of Edward Montgomery, Plaintiff, vs. McCord Brady &amp; Company, Defendant, and London Guarantee &amp; Accident Company, Respondent. Claimant slipped nad fell while hauling a truck loaded with goods. He was going down an incline. As a result of said fall claimant sus - tained internal injuries. Case was settled without hearing. Defendant pays $9.00 per week until disability is removed; however, not to ex - ceed 300 weeks. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 17. In the Matter of Roscerio Nocita, Plaintiff, vs. J. J. Parks Construction Company, Defendant, and J. J. Parks Construction Company, Respondent. Roscerio Nocita, a day laborer employed by the J. J. Parks Con - struction Company, alleged he was ruptured in the left and lower abdomen, while working for the said Parks Construction Company. Compensation was denied on the ground that the said Nocita was not injured while working for the defendant. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 18. In the Matter of George Misarka, Plaintiff, vs. Morris A Company, Defendants, and Morris A Company, Respon- dents. Claimant was employed in the cattle killing department of Morris &amp; Company. While about his regular duties he slipped and alleged that the fall caused hernia. The Commissioner denied an award on the </seg>
            <seg id="p055">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 53 grounds that the claimant was not injured while in the employ of the defendant. Plaintiff appealed the case to the District Court. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 19. In the Matter of Nellie Schick. Plaintiff, vs. Globe Automatic Sprinkler Company, Defendant, and Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp., Ltd., Respondent. Ferdinand Schirk, husband of Nellie Schick, was employed as sales - man and manager of agents for ths defendant company. While re - turning in his auto from an inspection trip which was necessary to his particular line of work, his auto was upset and he was instantly killed. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $12.00 per week for 350 eeks and $100.00 for funeral expenses and $5.60 costs. Case ap - pealed, but not within time limit. Court sustained award of Commis - sioner. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 20. In the Matter of Earl D. Altman, Plaintiff, vs. The Phoenix Construction Company, Defendant, and The Phoenix Construction Company, Respondents. The claimant was a regular employe of the Phoenix Construction Company. Said company was remodeling the electric light plant In Omaha. Altman, who was working on this job, was injured by his hands coming in contact with a bus bar, which had in some manner be - come heavily charged with electricity. Altman not only claimed com - pensation under the state law, but at the same time brought suit at common law before the District Court to recover damages. The Phoenix Construction Company asked the claim to be dismissed on tha grounds that Altman was not eligible to compensation after having elected to resort to common law procedure. Defendant later admitted Altman's right to the claim. Commissioner gave award as follows: Defendant required to pay Altman the sum of $10.00 per week for the loss of the use of both hands, which is total disability, for the period of 300 weeks and $8.00 per week thereafter during the life of said Altman. The sum was lumped by agreement of the District Court and claim was settled for $11,500. This settlement includes amount paid by the third party involved in the case. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 21. In the Matter of Frensworth L. Hurd, Plaintiff, vs. E. A. Wickham, Defendant, and the United States Fidel- ity &amp; Guarantee Company, Respondents. In this case there were two causes for action. Frensworth Hurd was employed by E. A. Wickham as a skilled carpenter. While thus employed Hurd received two injuries; one by a plank falling on his foot, and the other by a hammer hitting him on the finger of the left hand. Wickham refused to pay compensation. It waa later settled in the District Court wtih the approval of the Commissioner, by Wickham pajring the lump sum of $350.00 to Hurd. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">54 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 1, Claim No. 22. In the Matter of Frederick A. Siess, Plain- tiff, vs. Omaha Box Company, Defendant, and the Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation, Respondents. Claimant, while working for the Omaha Box Company, was in - jured by a dodo saw. His left hand was cut and the little finger was permanently damaged. Compensation was awarded by the Commis - sioner as follows: Defendant to pay plaintiff. $10.00 per week for a period of fifteen weeks, and reasonable expenses for medical attention. Defendant appealed the case to the District Court, but later asked for dismissal of the case as said defendant agreed to settle in accordance with the award of the Commissioner. Plaintiff accepts this agreement. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 23. In the Matter of Wm. E. Russell, Plaintiff, vs. Fairmont Creamery Company, Defendant, and Fairmont Cream- ery Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed to drive a truck by the defendant company. He fell down an unprotected elevator shaft and broke his leg. Com - missioner aarded compensation as follows: $7.00 per week for 30 weeks, and reasonable expenses for hospital and medical fees. Case appealed by defendant. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 24. In the Matter of Marie Michka, Plaintiff, vs. Alamito Dairy Company, Defendant, and the Alamito Dairy Com- pany, Respondent. Alfred Michka, employed by the Alamito Dairy Company to deliver milk and cream, was injured while on duty. The team he was driving started to run away just as Michka got out of the wagon. In attempt - ing to stop the team he was struck by one of the wheels and injured; he died ten days later. The case did not come up for hearing, but an agreement was reached between the parties interested and approved by the District Court, whereby the defendant paid to Marie Michka, mother of the deceased, the sum of $700.00. Dockt No. 1, Claim No. 25. In the Matter of Nora Williams, Plaintiff, vs. Nelson-Morris Company, Defendants, and Nelson-Morris Company, Respondents. Oscar Williams, husband of Nora Williams, was engaged as a day laborer by the defendant. He was killed while working In the coal pits, caused by the supports giving away which hold the coal. The case was settled by approval of the District Court by compromise between the parties. The defendant paid the plaintiff $2,500.00 and costs. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 26. In the Matter of Matous Sporel, Plaintiff, vs. Swift &amp; Company, Defendant, and Swift A Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed in the beef skinning department of Swift * Company. While so employed the hook, supporting the beef, gave </seg>
            <seg id="p057">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 55 way, causing the beef to fall on him and the hook to strike him on tne head and causing permanent and total disability. Defendant paid com - pensation at the rate of $6.00 per &lt;veek for 5V4 months, then stopped payment. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: Defend - ant to continue to pay $6.00 per week for 300 weeks from date of acci - dent and $4.80 thereafter during the life of the claimant. Case ap - pealed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 27. In the Matter of Leo R. Brown, Plaintiff, vs. Bertschy Manufacturing Company, Defendant, and Bertschy Manufacturing Company, Respondent. Plaintiff claims he was injured while operating a machine in the shops of the defendants. Compensation was denied by the Commis - sioner on the grounds that the alleged permanent injury was not caused by the injury which the plaintiff sustained in the shops of the defendant. It was also held that the injury was only a minor accident. Docket No. 1 .Claim No. 28. In the Matter of Clarence Frederick Stone, Plaintiff, vs. Omaha Tent &amp; Awning Company, Defendant, and the Millers Mutual Casualty Company, Respondent. The claimant broke his left ankle while engaged in working for the defendant. After a few weeks the claimant returned to work. He was given an office position because the injury had incapacitated him for his regular duties. Defendant paid medical and hospital service cost - ing $389.10 and $465.21 as compensation and refused further compensa - tion. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: Plaintiff awarded the sum of $10.00 per week for a period of six months beginning March 14th, 1918. That if plaintiff's disability still continues, permanent or partial, the defendant shall continue to pay plaintiff weekly compensa - tion for such further time as shall then be ordered by the Compensation Commissioner. Case appealed to District Court. Settled by order of District Court approving a lump sum settlement of $500.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 29. In the Matter of Adolph Radii, Plaintiff, vs. Morris &amp; Company, Defendant, and Morris &amp; Company, Respon- dents. Claimant was employed in the beef loading department of the de - fendant. His hand was injured by tellow workman dropping a beef quarter on him. Amputation of the first joint of the middle finger be - came necessary. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $11.80 per week for fifteen weeks; $81.00 for medical attendance. Case ap - pealed. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">56 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 1, Claim No. 30. In the Matter of Fred Brix, Plaintiff, vs. Morns &amp; Company, Defendant, and Morris &amp; Company, Respondent. Claimant was handling sheet iron and while so employed cut the finger of his right hand. Infection set in, causing the amputation of said finger at the second joint, also the second and third fingers were awarded compensation as follows: lor medical attendance. Case was injured by infection. Commissioner $12.00 per week for 60 weeks; $92.00 appealed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 31. In the Armour &amp; Company, Defendant, dent. Matter of Jude Redd, Plaintiff, vs. and Armour &amp; Company, Respon- Claimant was employed by Armour &amp; Company as beef lugger. While thus employed a fellow employee pushed a truck in front of claim - ant, causing him to fall over same, bruising the bone of his right leg; the bone later became infected. The defendant paid the claimant com - pensation at the rate of $12.00 per week for some four months, then stopped payment on the grounds that the claimant refused proper medi - cal attention. The claim was denied by the Commissioner. Plaintiff ap - pealed the case to the District Court. Settled before coming to trial by defendant paying to plaintiff the sum of $150.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 32. In the Matter of Wesley Harmon, Plain - tiff, vs. M. C. Peters Mill Company, Defendant, and the Employers Liability Assurance Corporation, Respondent. Claimant was injured by sacks of meal falling on him. His leg was wrenched and head injured on the cement floor. Commissioner found against the plaintiff as same did not appear for hearing. Case dismissed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 33. In the Matter of Norval S. Alcox, Plaintiff, vs. The City of Omaha, Defendant, and The City o' Omaha, Respon- dent. Claimant was injured while working for the City of Omaha; his thumb was split by a chisel. Commissioner gave award as follows: Defendant to pay plaintiff the sum of $10.00 per week for a period of 15 weeks, which was paid. Docket No. 1. Claim No. 34. In the Matter of Clarence G. Martin, Plain tiff, vs. R. H. Folwell, Defendant, and the United States Fidelity Company, Respondent. Claimant was engaged in repairing a car repairer when injured. The turning tool with which he was working caught in the emery wheel and jerked the hand of claimant with great force against his chin, thereby knocking out some of said claimant's teeth. Claimant further alleges that he suffered permanent injury to his spine and therefore claims com - pensation for permanent disability. Commissioner awarded compensa- </seg>
            <seg id="p059">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 57 tion as follows: The defendant shall pay the plaintiff the sum of $5.00 per week for partial disability from date of injury not to exceed 300 weeks. Plaintiff and defendant aceep; the above award. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 35. In the Matter of John H. Smith, Plaintiff, vs. Morris 6. Company, Defendant, and Morris &amp; Company, Re- spondents. Claimant, an employee of Morris &amp; Company, was cleaning vats used to cook hair. While pulling out the vat plug, he slipped and fell, sustaining injuries. The case was settled before coming to a hearing. The defendant paid the plaintiff the sum of $64.80. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 36. In the Matter of Almira Greer, Plaintiff, vs. Omaha Cooperage Company, Defendant, and Omaha Cooperage Com- pany, Respondents. William F. Greer, an employee of the Omaha Cooperage Company, received an injury to the middle finger of his left hand while working for said firm. Later he died and his widow, Almira Greer, claimed com - pensation. Same was denied by the Commissioner on the grounds that the said William Greer died from apoplexy, and not as a result of the injury he received. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 37. In the Matter of Otto Gos Becher, Plain- tiff, vs. Frank Svoboda, Defendant, and Frank Svoboda, Respondent. The claimant, while drawing a truck loaded with a large slab of marble, slipped and was injured by the truck handle striking him on the shoulder and breaking the bone. The Commissioner awarded compensa - tion as follows: Otto Gos Becher to receive $11.20 per week for a period of eight weeks; defendant to pay a reasonable doctor bill. Case settled. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 38. In the Matter of Elmer Rocheford, Plaintiff, vs. Hoye &amp; Nicholas, Defendant, and the Employers Liability As- surance Corporation, Respondents. Claimant had his knee injured by falling from a scaffolding while laying brick. The defendant paid compensation for 40 weeks at the rate of $10.00 per week, then refused further payment. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: The defendant to continue to pay the plaintiff $10.00 per week until removal of disability not to exceed 300 weeks. The defendant then entered a petition in the District Court for a lump sum settlement. Same was approved and the defendant paid the sum of $325.00 to claimant for settlement in full. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">58 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 1, Claim No. 39. In the Matter of Joe T. Trebon. Plaintiff, va. Selden-Breck Company, Defendant, and the Maryland Casualty Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed by the Selden-Breck Company to load and unload wheelbarrows. While taking a wheelbarrow from off the eleva - tor, a fellow workman gave the signal to lower said elevator while the said claimant still had one foot on it. The claimant fell three stories, and injured and bruised his left side, and strained the muscles and tendons in his side and back, and fractured three ribs. The defendant paid compensation for a period of 17 weeks at the rate of $12.00 per week, then refused further payment, alleging that the claimant was able to perform his usual labors. The Commissioner gave award as fol - lows: The defendant required to continue payment at the rate of $6.00 per week for 9 weeks. Claim paid in full. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 40. In the Matter of Emma C. Barrett, Plain- tiff, vs. Selden-Breck Construction Company, Defendant, and the Maryland Casualty Company, Respondent. Alvin J. Barrett was working on the construction of a building which the defendant was erecting. He was injured while working and died from the effects of said accident. The defendant claimed not to be responsible for compensation because said defendant alleges the said Alvin J. Barrett was a sub-contractor. The Commissioner gave an award as follows: The defendant shall pay to the plaintiff $12.00 per week for a period of not to exceed 350 weeks, beginning with the date of injury, April 6th, 1918, and an addi - tional sum of $100.00 for funeral expenses. Defendant appealed case to the District Court. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 41. In the Matter of John Darland, Plaintiff, vs. Puritan Laundry Company, Defendant, and the Maryland Casualty Company, Respondent. Claimant was an engineer in the defendant's laundry. He was in - jured while adjusting a pump. Two fingers were bruised. Commis - sioner disallowed the claim because the injury was a minor accident, and claimant lost no time. Case appealed. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 42. In the Matter of Joe Blotkien, Plaintiff, vs. Swift &amp; Company, Defendant, and Swift A Company, Respondent. The claimant's thumb on the left hand was injured while operating an iron bolt cutting machine for the defendant. Total disability for the injured part was claimed. Defendant paid compensation for nine weeks at the rate of $12.00 per week. Further compensation was refused on grounds of recovery. Plaintiff claimed $12.00 per week for 30 weeks. The following settlement was effected and approved by the Compensa - tion Commissioner: Plaintiff shall receive the sum of $96.00 -(eight weeks' compensation) in addition to what defendant already paid. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 59 Docket No. 1, Claim No. 44. In the Matter of Peter Becker, Plaintiff, v«. Morris &amp; Company, Defendant, and Morris &amp; Company, Re - spondent. Claimant was injured at the plant of Morris &amp; Company. His band was injured between a truck handle and an iron table. Settled without hearing. The defendant paid Becker the sum of $36.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 45. In the Matter of James A. Comett, Plain- tiff, vs. George W. Platner, Defendant, and George W. Platner, Re- spondent. Claimant was injured while unloading bales of wire. The end of a wire struck the claimant in the right eye. Settlement was effected, with the approval of the Commissioner, before coming to a hearing. The claimant received the sum of $350.00 from the defendant as settle - ment in full. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 46. In the Matter of Emil Kofka, Plaintiff, vs. Omaha &amp; Council Bluffs Street Railway Company, Defendant, and Omaha A Council Bluffs Street Railway Company, Respondents. The claimant was engaged as a motorman for the defendant com - pany. He was injured by car jumping track, thereby sustaining a broken collar bone, two fractured ribs, and broken arm. The defendant paid compensation amounting to $376.69 at the rate of $10.00 per week. Defendant refused further compensation on the grounds that claimant had returned to work, and had completely recovered. This the claimant denies. The matter in dispute between petitioner and defendant is the question of further compensation for above injuries. The case was settled before coming up for a hearing by order of the District Court approving a lump sum settlement amounting to $150.00. Docket No. 1, Claim No. 49. In the Matter of Aveline L .Stevens, Plain- tiff, vs. Smith Brick Company, Defendant, and Travelers Insurance Company, Respondent. Claimant was engaged as a teamster by the defendant company. The team he was driving for defendant ran away and claimant died from injuries received. The Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: The Smith Brick Company shall pay to the plaintiff $3.00 per week for a period not to exceed 350 weeks beginning with date of injury, April 30th, 1918. Plaintiff and defendant appeal case to District Court. Doc. No. 1, Claim No. 50. In the Matter of Chris Mathieson, Plaintiff, vs. McMullen Transfer Company, Defendant, and McMullen Trans - fer Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed to load and unload freight. His left leg </seg>
            <seg id="p062">60 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT was injured while working at his accustomed duties. Compensation had been paid to the amount of $24.00 and defendant refused further pay - ment. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $12.00 per week until disability is removed, not to exceed 300 weeks, and defendant pay medical fees. Defendant has failed to file an answer to the petition. Docket No. 1 .Claim No. 56. In the Matter of John G. Gray, Plaintiff, vs. The Industrial Chemical Company, Defendant. The claimant was employed by the Industrial Chemical Company as a common laborer. While helping move some heavy articles he was injured by an iron bar falling on his foot. Defendant refused to pay compensation, alleging, first, that the plaintiff was not regularly em - ployed, and, second, that he was injured less than one week; third, that it employs less than five persons. Commissioner made award as follows: The defendant shall pay to the plaintiff the sum of $12.00 per week beginning with the date of the injury, August 21st, 1918, until disability is removed, not to exceed 300 weeks. And further pay the reasonable expense for medical attendance for the first twenty-one days. Case appealed by defendant to District Court. Docket No. 2 .Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Edna Jacobson. Plaintiff, vs. Cox A Underhill, Defendants, and Maryland Casualty Company, Respondent. Sherman Jacobson, husband of Edna Jacobson, had died from effects of injuries received while at his regular work. The defendant refused to pay more than $7.10 per week as compensation, and also re - fused to pay $100.00 for funeral expenses. Commissioner made award as follows: Defendant required to pay $9.00 per week for 350 weeks and $100.00 for funeral expenses. Case was appealed to the District Court, but was withdrawn and paid according to the decision of the Commissioner. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 2. In the Matter of Anna Coster, Adminis- tratrix of the Estate of Peter J. Coster, Deceased, Plaintiff, vs. Thompson Hotel Company, Defendant, and the Thompson Hotel Company, Respondent. Peter Coster, a regular employee of the Thompson Hotel Company, was killed while riding a motorcycle; said act being in the performance of his ordinary duties. Commissioner r warded compensation a=i follows: $10.00 per week for 350 weeks, and $100.00 for funeral expenses. Case was appealed to the District Court. Judgment was given by the court in keeping with the Commissioner's award. Same was appealed to Su - preme Court and sustained. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 61 Docket No. 2, Claim No. 3. In the Matter of Edward L. Simon. Plaintiff, vs. London Guarantee A Accident Company, Defendant, and London Guarantee 4. Accident Company, Respondent. Defendant had been paying compensation for some time for in - jury received. At times, however, said defendant was delinquent in making payments. Claimant asked the 50 per cent added compensation provided for by law for delinquency in making payment. Commissioner awarded $70.00 as amount due for delinquent payments. Ca:&lt;.- was ap - pealed to the District Court, which upheld the award of tho Commis - sioner. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 4. In the Matter of Frank Wagner, Plaintiff, vs. Fidelity Investment Company, Defendant, and Fidelity Invest- ment Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed as janitor in the Metropolitan Apartment House which is controlled by the defendant. While moving a heavy box claimant was ruptured in the left side. Commissioner awarded com - pensation as follows: $150.00 for doctor bill and loss of time. Case was appealed to the District Court. District Court awarded $100.00. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 5. In the Matter of Edward McCracken, Plain tiff, vs. Farmers Union Stock Exchange, Defendant, and Farmers Union Stock Exchange, Respondent Claimant when injured was assisting in moving some machinery. He was injured by having the third finger of his left hand bruised and cut. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $12.00 per week for 11 weeks and medical fees for th&gt;j first 21 days. Plaintiff and de - fendant accept the above award. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 6. In the Matter of Fred Lewis, Plaintiff, vs Forburger Stone Company, Defendant, and Millers Mutual Casualty Company, Respondent. Claimant was injured while helping to place a piece of stone on a planer. His foot hit an obstruction causing him to fall. A fellow work - man who was assisting him pushed his end around, thereby crushing the groin and rupturing claimant. Permanent disability was claimed. Case was filed, but settled without hearing. With the approval of the Dis - trict Court, the defendant paid a lump sum of $265.00 as compensation and hospital and doctor's fees. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 7. In the vs. James Hudson, Defendant, Company, Respondent. Albert Huffman was employed Matter of Albert Huffman, Plaintiff, and London Guarantee &amp; Accident as a laborer in the excavation for the Rudge &amp; Guenzel building. He was injured by a large chunk of dirt falling on his foot. Case was settled without hearing. Defendant paid claimant $110.00 compensation. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">62 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 2, Claim No. 8. In the Matter of John Bathel, Plaintiff, vs, F. Staats, Defendant. Claimant had a leg injured in a corn shredder which he was run - ning for defendant. Case was settled without a hearing, the defendant paying a lump sum of $800 to the claimant. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 9. In the Matter of Hattie L. Depue, Plaintiff, vs. Acme Delivery Service, Defendant, and Acme Delivery Service, Respondent Charles Depue was an employee of the Acme Delivery Service. While making a delivery he was struck by a street car and killed. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $5.00 per week for 350 weeks and $100.00 for funeral expenses. Case was appealed by the defendant. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 10. In the Matter of Frank Elder, Plaintiff, vs, Lincoln Gas Company, Defendant, and Lincoln Gas Company, Re- spondent. Claimant was employed as a common laborer. At the time of in - jury he was laying brick and fell from a ladder upon which he was working. His back and loins were wrenched. Case was settled without hearing. Defendant paid claimant $61.60. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 11. In the Matter of Emma Wickline, Plaintiff, vs. Northwestern Iron A Metal Company, Defendant, and the United States Fidelity &amp; Guarantee Company, Respondent. Claimant was struck by an iron frame and severely injured. The respondent had paid claimant $6.00 per week for eight weeks and a small sum for physician's fees, then refused further compensation. Com - missioner awarded compensation as follows: $6.00 per week for two months and 50 per cent additional fine for delinquency in making pay - ments. Claimant must submit to an examination and in case of refusal further compensation is denied. Case was appealed to the District Court by the defendant. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 12. In the Matter of Emma Swan, Plaintiff, vs. Lincoln Terminal Company, Defendant, and Ocean Accident A Guar- antee Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed as janitress at the Terminal building. While at work she fell and injured the carpal bones of her hand. C!aim was made for total disability. The defendant had paid compensation for 14 weeks amounting to $84.00, then stopped payment as the claimant had signed an acknowledgment of payment in full for said injury. Com - missioner refused further compensation. Case was appealed to the Dis - trict Court. This court reversed the decision of the Commissioner, thereby ordering further compensation to be paid to the claimant. Case appealed to the Supreme Court. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 63 Docket No. 2, Claim No. 14. In the Matter of Rote Coffindaffer, Plaintiff, vs. The Globe Laundry Company, Defendant. The claimant was employed as a general helper by the defendant While operating a pressing device, her right limb was injured. Com pensation during period of disability and $50.00 medical fees were asked Plaintiff's attorneys asked the case to be dismissed. Case dismissed. Docket No. 2, Claim No. 15. In the Matter of Elizabeth Graham, Plain- tiff, vs. The Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company, Defendant, and the Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company, Respondent. Roy Graham, husband of Elizabeth Graham, was employed as a lineman by the defendant compary. He was on top of a house which was being moved. His work was handling and controlling the wires and cables of the defendant. The wires in some manner became heavily charged with electricity and Graham received a heavy electric shock which caused him to fall from the building and killed him instantly. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $12.00 per week for 350 weeks, 50 per cent additional for delinquent payments, and $100.00 for funeral expenses. Case appealed. Docket No. 3, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Goldie Maiwald, Minor, by Her Father, William F. Maiwald, Plaintiff, vs. The Model Laundry &amp; Cleaning Company, Plaintiff, and Model Laundry Company, Re- spondent. Goldie Maiwald was helping a fellow employee recover the mangling machine. The foreman started the machinery going without the knowl - edge of said claimant. She was struck in the side and leg, sustaining injury thereby. Claimant returned to work the following day, yet other complications set in which caused her to lose much time and resulted in having to submit to several operations. The defendant company claimed that said complications were not the cause of said injury. With the approval of the Commissioner the case was settled by the defendant paying to claimant the sum of $120.00 as compensation, $50.00 for sur - geon's fees, $4.00 for medicine, $25.00 for attorney's fees. Docket No. 4, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Jasper N. Pettit, Plaintiff, vs. Barnett &amp; Record Company, Defendant, and Barnett &amp; Record Company, Respondent. Claimant was ruptured while carrying a large pannel, used in the construction of an elevator. The injury was caused by stumbling over a pile of debris. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: De - fendant to pay the surgical, medical and hospital fees for an operation and $10.00 per week until released by the doctors and able to work. Case appealed to District Court and a lump sum settlement was made for $192.45. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">64 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Docket No. 4, Claim No. 2. In the Metter of Robert J. Rubash. Plain- tiff, vs. Fremont Manufacturing Company, Defendant, and the Millers Mutual Casualty Company, Respondent. Claimant had his hand injured while operating a machine known as the squaring shears in the factory of the defendant; more than one phlange was destroyed on the second and third fingers of the right hand. The Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $10.80 per week for a period of 25 weeks. Case appealed to District Court and settled according to the award of the Commissioner. Note: — The insurance company offered to make immediate payment amounting to $10.80 per week as required by law; this the plaintiff refused to accept, claiming he was entitled to more. Docket No. 4, Claim No. 3. In the Matter of Peter Edquist, Plaintiff. vs. Fremont Stock Yards, Defendant, and the Ocean Accident &amp; Insurance Company, Respondent. Alex Holnberg, a citizen of Sweden, was killed while feeding stock for the Fremont Stock Yards Company. The team he was driving ran away. Holnberg was caught between the posts of a gate and a hay - rake. He was killed almost instantly. Holnberg's mothed resides in Sweden and the Swedish vice-consul, Peter Edquist, prosecuted the case for the mother. The Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $8.75 per week for 350 weeks and $100.00 for funeral expenses. Same to be paid to Edquist as representative of the estate. The case was appealed to the District Court. Docket No. 4, Claim No. 4. In the Matter of Clarence T. Douglas, Plain- tiff, vs. Hammond Printing Company, Defendant, and GFobe Indemnity Company, Respondent. Claimant caught his right hand in a printing press. Claim was made for total disability of said hand. The defendant paid compensation for 46 weeks at the rate of $10.00 per week, then stopped payment. Commis - sioner awarded compensation as follows: $10.00 per week for an addi - tional 129 weeks, and 50 per cent additional for all delinquent pay - ments, medical and hospital fees not to exceed $200.00. Plaintiff and defendant accept the above award. Docket No. 5, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Fountain F. hincher, Plain- tiff, vs. Glenn P. Beaty, Defendant, and Employers Liability Assur- ance Corporation, Respondent. Claimant was employed by Beaty in digging sewer ditches. He was injured by a ditch caving in where he was working. Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: $175.00 as compensation from April 25 to December 26, 1917, which is at the rate of $5.00 per week, and to continue to pay $5.00 per week until the removal of the disability not to exceed 300 weeks. Defendant appealed case, settled by agreement on </seg>
            <seg id="p067">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 65 approval of District Court. Plaintiff accepted a lump sum settlement of $500.00. Docket No. 6, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Claus H. Grotzky. Plaintiff, vs. Nelson Lumber &amp; Supply Company, Defendant, and thte Nelson Lumber &amp; Supply Company, Respondent. Clamant alleged that he was thrown from an auto truck and that said fall bruised his left hip joint, thereby causing an abscess to be formed on the injured parts. Claim was denied by the Commissioner c.u the grounds that disability was not caused by the fa'.l, but by a tubercular hip which claimant had had for some years. Docket No. 6, Claim No. 2. In the Matter of Delia Elizabeth Minor, Administratrix of the Estate of Alva B. Minor, Deceased, Plaintiff, vs. Trans-Mississippi Grain Company, a Corporation, and the Trav- elers Insurance Company, Respondents. Alva B. Minor, husband of Delia Elizabeth Minor, was employed by the defendant company to run an elevator at Alda, Nebraska. He ran a sliver in his hand while coopering a car which he was getting ready to ship grain in. Later blood poisoning set in which caused his death. The Commissioner awarded compensation as follows: The de - fendant to pay pi aim iff the sum of $12.00 per week for a period of not to exceed 350 weeks and a further sum of $100.00 to defray funeral ex - penses and that said defendant shall further pay the reasonable ex - penses of medical attendance for the last illness of the deceased. And that all delinquent payments be made within thirty days of date of award, together with the costs, $24.60, taxed against the defendant. Plaintiff and defendant accept the above award. Docket No. 6, Claim No. 3. In the Matter of Sarah Tyre, Plaintiff, vs. Fairmont Creamery Company, Defendant, and Fairmont Creamery Company, Respondent. Claimant fell from a platform while at work, and sustained a broken knee. Case settled without hearing. Defendant paid claimant $70.00. Same approved by the Commissioner. Docket No. 7, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of John W. Barclay, Plaintiff, vs. Olson &amp; Johnson, et ■!., Defendants, and the United States Fidel- ity &amp; Guaranty Company, Respondent. Claimant was employed as common laborer by defendant company. At the time of his injury, he was engaged in running a wheelbarrow off an elevator, and was compelled to run same along some planks which were some ten feet from the ground. He fell off the planks against the buildin. The bones of the instep of his foot were broken. Defendant paid compensation amounting to $131.30, then stopped payment. Com - missioner denied further compensation on the grounds that claimant was </seg>
            <seg id="p068">66 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT able to go back to work. Case appealed. District Court gave judgment tor $246.60, which includes all costs. Docket No. 8, Claim No. 1. In the Matter of Charles Sapp, Plaintiff, vt. Northern Antelope Telephone Company, Defendant, and Employers Liability Company, Respondent. Claimant was injured by falling from a telephone pole on which he was working. His back was wrenched and bruised, and his left wrist was broken and sprained. Defendant paid compensation of $6.19 per week for eight weeks, then stopped payment. Case was settled with - out hearing. Defendant paid claimant $349.00 as settlement in full. Ap - proved by District Court. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 67 New Commandments 1. Thou shalt not wait for something to turn up. but thou ; halt pull off thy coat and go to work, that thou mayest prosper in thy affairs and make the word "failure" spell "success". 2. Thou shalt not be content to go about thy business looking like a loafer, for thou shouldst know thy personal appearance is better than a letter of recommendation. 3. Thou shalt not try to make excuses, nor shalt thou say to those who chide thee, "I didn't think." 4. Thou shalt not wait to be told what thou shalt do, nor in what manner thou shalt do it, for thus may thy days be long on the job which fortune hath given thee. 5. Thou shalt not fail to maintain thine own integrity, nor shalt thou be guilty of anything that will lessen thy good respect for thyself. 6. Thou shalt not covet the other fellow's job, nor his salary, nor the position that he hath gained by his own hard labor. 7. Thou shalt not fail to live within thy income, nor shalt thou contract debts when thou canst not see thy way clear to pay them. 8. Thou shalt not be afraid to blow thine own horn, for he who faileth to blow his own horn at the proper occasion flndeth nobody standing ready to blow it for him. 9. Thou shalt not hesitate to say "No" when thou meanest "No," nor shalt thou fail to remember that there are times when it is unsafe to bind thyself by a hasty judgment. 10. Thou shalt give every man a square deal. This is the last and great commandment, and there is no other like unto it. Upon this commandment hang all the laws and profits of the business world. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">68 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Song We are coming, Woodrow Wilson, With assurance of our aid. In the crisis of the Nation, And you need not be afraid, We know we lack the training Of the soldiers custom made. You'll find old Nebraska marching on. CHORUS Hurrah, hurrah, for the country that we love. Hurrah, hurrah, for the flag that floats above, If we can't stay by her, it is time for us to move Or move the Kings, Czars and Kaiser. We are coming, Woodrow Wilson, By the millions if you say, The country needs our service, We'll be with you all O. K. But peace will suit us better far, For which we daily pray. You'll find old Nebraska marching on. CHORUS We are coming, Woodrow Wilson, With the noisy flife and drum. We're opposed to war, but with you If the damn-thing has to come, We'll go and slap the Kaiser, And we'll put him on the bum. You'll find old Nebraska marching on. CHORUS We are coming, Woodrow Wilson, Our faces to the foe. Some intent on gaining glory, Some hellbent on gleamy dough. But we are patriotic, that's What makes us holler so. Ycu'll find old Nebraska marching on. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">COMPENSATION DEPARTMENT 69 1 For statistical data on insurance apply to the Insurance Commis - ioner for the same, which report has been issued for the year 1917. For tatistical data on larm mortgages and agriculture for the year 1917 and 918 apply to the Agricultural Department. Respectfully submitted. GEORGE E. NORMAN. Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner POSTSCRIPT The manuscript for this volume was in the hands of the printer when the Armistice was signed, November 11, 1918. The department has sought to record an accurate account of labor conditions in Nebraska during the Great World War. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>