<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  NATIVE SEED CORN</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIf I Hi: University &lt;&gt;i Nebkabka. BULLETIN OK THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Voi l-MI XXIV, Aistm it: IV. NATIVE SEED CORN HV E. ('.. Mc&gt;\ Ii.cpMKKT. :ibi in. Ham ii 2n. 1911. LINCOLN. VKRRASKA. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION ol NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD BKAIII.K \\ i KAHI.I KABI THE STATION OFFICERS Kl. AVKRY. I'll. It.. I.I THE WORKING STAFF K. J. Ai WAY. I'n I.. \\ ' » •II. K Sn 1 1 ii ■ K. A i M. H. Sh ink. A. M OMW K. K. Link. S • llnri. II P. B. It u:kt i: A Ii I &lt;". H. I.IK. I ■ Jambs Cowan, M Knoi:i:. B • 1: », M. li ( l'la W. \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p003">MONTGOMERY. I hiring the past ten years there h;is Ix-en a general demand for m;i!i&lt;&gt;n regarding the relative values of different varieties r ii. of various types nf i'U', and of seed from different regions. The npninn of F&amp;naten has been tliai seed corn, brought from . ii in ■■other, will often not give good results the first 11 ilie new locality, tho sometimes it gives excellent results i few viars. or when it is "adapted." l.\|.&lt;iiiine varies, however, as considerable ()iiantities of seed triin the central west are used with sat isfactorv succi - 1a ami Texas, tho in the &lt; '■ 1 1 1 f states northern seed has H s;i'i&gt;fa. luiv. lu ihe North Atlantic slates silage - ijoite i- iiionlv urown from western seed, but in this iinl r\|Hiird lo mature the crop, but only to secure the m Me \ ield of gTtra cora. This western seed does not -mi isfaiioi \ results in |n-oducing inalure corn. It has km . urn lusi\cl\ |Hi;vcd. however, that, for the region west of mi river, securing' seed corn from more humid re. !. i-;ist dues nut fi\e satisfactory results. re c\ie|iiioiis to this, however, since in almost tfiTJ ili. re are iu Nebraska areas of high Io.jiI rainfall and oe -i-;isiiii when riinfall and humidiiv a|&gt;|iro.\iinate the lunatic conditions fouu&lt;l in states several hundred miles ■ ■ l.niska. [ON OF NATIVE VEGETATION TO CLIMATE AND SOIL. \ botanical survey of the Tinted States shows large well- deiined ivgions. each with a chacteristic native Mora. A comparison of tiguie 1 and figure 1 will show reason why a different i \ pe of corn is required for western Nebraska as com - 1 with a more humid region, such as eastern Nebraska. BUL. 128, AGR. KXP. STATION UK NEBK. Vol. XXIV. ART IV. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 liraska Tin- ■ ■ : ■ T i\ i &lt;i tin i cliinai i&lt; rondil ions. and a • ii in tin- ;il&gt;" siderint: tin- tM-eat li-nirt h ..: time rhat n has li:i'l ' indii different environmental condition* iould h. homogeneous niitivc on tlmiout IIS covered w j Til :l f&lt; on lull- t dilter in en ill or climate) from ■ | n-rt i i-i &lt; m- differ homogeneous native vegetation thruoul the eountrv. Th «-nt Uiiuls of foi-i- n and deeiduoon. while in i|i&lt;- |&gt;i"iii-ifs aktofi tlif Missouri river w« havi tal regetai prai«s inicl other pteati iu'li to man. in marked loatiM thf -sliolt i:lM--" e— tlj tlliee IllllKheil niilev M V.vi-u «it)iin ■ itate. distinct Ion I /ones ran often he identi lii&lt;| m in NeliiM--, iy.,,1. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 The "Short Grass" country, typical of western Nebraska. (By courtesy of the I'nited States Geological Survey.) KWIKONMKM UN THE &lt; YlRX Pl.ANT. It ha8 long ■ I that cadi regioo would have i distinct tvj&gt;e of example, in northern regions a leafy plant, with ■ &gt;l;m Ki horse very low. in « 1 r \ rep. ns ■ rtorkj plant, with a roportkn of car ami often scanty leaf im; while in the lates the plants arc tall ami arc low in proportion of ear k. However, the plant tends to ehaage or adapt itself when m ticiiii one ragtea to anutlier. u observed 1&gt;\ Ihiggar: "Corn Inoii^'lii south from higher latitudes heeoom later and latet Ml reral jttuem after introduction the pkmk prows taller and yineiall.x tin 1 piopoit ion of trashy, weevil eaten, or otherwise ■■Marketable yrain hefowen lew than tortag ilie first year of 1 t) so th " </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 lurrftCT OF ACi'l.l MATIZAT1ON ON YIKLD At the Nebraska Station six leading varieties of com ■ I for lw&lt;&gt; ami three \ears. tin- seed in amm &lt; ase '•■ native (iniwn an&lt;l in the other fn&gt;in Itfi nr Illinois E&lt;i nit hi n I com from mcrtimtmtcd *&gt;&lt;&lt;/ mnd ■ it tin \ &lt; hnixl.ii I' i /a /■/, 1 1906 Av. . ence 19tU *;/ a I 7n 0 R) 4 95 2 74 4 67 1 75 1 63 5 67 9 H I Derc in f\ci\ mm the native wid .,i the wiiik better viclil. the tTrngp being :i diffen ii.^ Imsli. A in.. i, n-snli was &gt;.-. uic&lt;l in l'.tici arhea Nptweatiag three it^rttn of aerlimatiuitioti «in- prowii in «.oii at the Kx|mm init-nt Si ;• i i.»n. Tin- lii^i group i&gt;: rarietu*u Mptwatai Mai tahea fraai Huuplvn reti arfaaa a| i !■** National Can Slmw for 1!»&lt;in. The* caue fran tht ver,\ lM-nt prawcn and ware aadaahtedh productive \;ui«-i corn in Illinois. Indiana, and Ohio, where the; originated, ll, aWar earn, it is probable they had beea (rrown ander favofaltlc conditions, thus making tln-in leai suited than the nverajie to withstand the ver.v dt-v and unfavorable season of IfM at this Station. The second group mas nmde up of a collection of rarietiea ■N\br»«km Experiment Station Bulletin 91. p. 11 Name and place of origin ! Hush ""■ Mine ! hfinoii . ' e braska * i Illinois &gt;raskk White 1 Illinois It Yellow i Nebraska . Roae j Iowa . i't Yellow i Nebraska Dent / Illinois Average </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 p met* in t It*- state. l«\it Im-stii-il mi mom ikrtaaee Mill 'in soiik'W 1 1 ; 1 1 ilili'i II III soil. Mil uiuiiii \\;i!- lll.ltlf ll|&gt; nf ;| mill c| iuu uf \ ;mcl iis grow - &gt;y fniiiuTs m;ir i In- Ktal inn. . i iinttii i-tll ion nil ilii III nf mi n. \ i hi -iixkil Station, t'.io'.i. E-WINMXIi BAMPLBi TWOU nil: NvrinVAI. COBS MOW. wer origin Yield per aci Origin Yiold per acre flHxhrh !Ui. shell 411 411 rj ' /ion, 111 41 .0 1 ii mingd-il •, 111 . irj Mi. Zion, III 41 (I i ngd ,111 l irmiiuidil ■. Ill . Bue ■ tin, Ind. . :U 2 m Busbi . 34 liicothe, Ohio 44 0 laoothe, (ihio 44 0 . :» 8 I H II II..- I i:. &gt; M i, . f itAI ■ Yield per acre Yield per acn Bushels I.") .") Rush 'I.I Wilimr. Nflir. 4(5 9 K Auburn. Nebr 47 6 4t 7 41 7 '- * 4li 2 45 6 1IH \l. VARIETIES KKilM \KAK I.I Mill \. Origin Yield per acre Bushel* I White F - J. Wetenoamp 47.3 ••I .O 48 4 2. Red Cob Wl .1. K. Young • Whitfl L.J.Evans to. » 53 2 I white l - ■&gt; Evans 53.2 i. Red Cob Whit- A Ri d 46.4 Inea &lt;^ou « nu'- ■ ■ ■■ • Mixed White. ' - 1 - Grahani Yellow Mlk( 43.6 fl. Yellow Mike Spahulc 56.6 1. Reid's Yellow Dent ?■ F Graham 47.1 Arerage | *8-8 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Character o Yield per acre Bushels ■ corn from Him from growers in state i b varieties 45 6 Local varieties near Experiment Station I- N TIk-w ivsulls weir unusually DUirkeri in limit. Hue li- tin - ili\. Imi mmm dnriag thi \\me. Inn a Mttmin ihu wi i*- 11 1111x11:1 1 f;iiilici- \\f«.i in the itat«*. The data plninl !■ tin ralue of n I. thai from ;i dhfttaBce jieUiag I lull from 1 1 mmm 1 ilisi.ui. 1 ImisIicIs: ami thai I'i ■ :n-;ir tin Ktation ■llslllls |MT ill cooperate Town Count y '"Jjj- Vai • \ATm. Bauerle Champ. A. H. Beckhoff Thedford l\ g A. L. Tarter Wai worth O*o. H Felt Brule Walter N. Giles Wilsonville Furnaa Goo D. Gunn Lexington Litchfield I iMMoa :« ."5 44 1 ** Albert Heapy 4.t I Sherman I K. A. Johnson Stanford Harlan E. G. Kendall Same* Knox. 6 41 J. J. Klein Kearney Buffalo Geo. E. Lyon Phelps . I Loomis J. H. J. Malm Gothenbuu 1; :«' B 49 5 Otis Mark Kavcn Browi, 7 6 30.0 Peter Nelson. . . L. C. Peisijjer . Sextorp Blue Hill Cheyenne 6 0 80 34 0 46 0 5 1-. v&gt; reiBiyer . . E. M. Pettycrew 8 194 24 0 m 4O n QA f\ Harmony Cherry a. Ml. renycr** C M. Planner Maywood Frontier 7 18.0 30 0 &lt;^ «. riannt-r W. W. Stanley Norden Keya Pah a 6 28 0 300 J. D. Stephentson JDundv 8 18 9 22 3 Benkelman J. is. ovouuei J. C. Weekly Joe Zook ... Grant Cozad Perkins D»w~iP 18 4 24 0 II I 17 B A 6 &gt; M 1 Bl ' </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 NATIVK BBBD FOR WB8TERN NEBRASKA. I rainfall of Nebraska is 28 ta 'M inches in the east and illy itCMHtl lo 14 inches on the western border. This gNftl ■ cksafB in cliinatic conditions in going west (Hi miles from the Missouri river as is found in perhaps i&gt; llif MMt. We sliould therefore expect a marked ncf in mi snitahle for the eastern and western parts of » ation of cooperative corn experiments. In both l!H&gt;^ and limit, experiments in variety testing were &lt; arried on in cooperation witli fanners in western Nebraska, It was known that varieties from east of the Missouri river could nc.i he e\pe&lt; ted to give good results, so the varieties used were \ from eastern or central Nebraska, and thought to be fairlv well acclimatized. The experimenters were in each case I to include a test of their own corn or some good native \ariet\ under the same conditions. Not all included the native . irn in the test, and also not more than one-half of the experi - menters were able to return satisfactory reports, owing to various causes. A heavy snow occurring early in the fall of 1908 nted many from husking until midwinter, and others lo«t Hm entire crop from drouth, hail, or other causes. However, 21 experimenters made a satisfactory report in 1908, and 27 in 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 4. The above pii niri' illustrates a type of corn »&lt;■!] adap' wsstern Nebraska. Tli. grain is rather broad and not very deep, and rob rather large. The ear is about six inches in i -in -u inference to nine inches in length, and would be railed somewhat slender. W'heiher the corn is yellow, while, or calico, this general type should be used, in preference to the deep gi ained and rather small -cob types suitable to the region alone iri Rirer and in &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 litTeri-ni v :i |-it d, e\ce|it T 111) t ill most cases the native com gave the yield. In 1M8 the avetage «f aJl nurd pared with tin- astir? ran, showed \ieldsof 34.1 haahehi ■a4 or ;in average dlfffwm of ti.4 bushels in favor of ilu- native .'&gt;rii. ;in advantage of altout L'."&gt; J«-r (Cat. ■ t'lifi right i&lt;i ten rarietiea wi-rc ;i^;iin sent to a list of n in rentral :i imI wisi.th Nebraaka and ia*fnial«i - in 1909 could 1m- divi&lt;h-il into three gffaopa, i line i-arlv vai'nlii-s from eastern Ni-lnaska. seven va ■ aiiliniated corn fi-om c&lt; ntral or wesiei-n Nelnaska. ami ■ « n or nai ', \ NK11KASKA VAIilKTlKS. r.arilttt Yellow Kent. IC.i.ls Yellow l»ent. 1'iiilc of tin- North. \l iKVTItAI. NKI'.KASKA. N \ I l\ I \ ARIKTIK8 Kl ; i:, . kh.iiis White Deal I \.,i\ White neat. Bhalouil's White I'ent. iiinn'i St. Joe White. (iune'i White Leamiag. Iresiilts slmw an Bverage yield of Jii.lt baahehi for tin* eastern ika varieties. 81.9 Imshels for the central and WW ka \.nieties. and '_'."). 4 liusliels for the •rrowers" own or seed. This illusiiates the value of seed adapted to loeal ons. -kiiI to include a i&lt;si of native corn. Jpfford'i &lt; ;i White &lt; "up. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 I |OOSOO0io«ao9i&gt;KOCioooascoae-s: •» ; ii' rooor-e&gt;5t~t~««Dt~'&gt;-&gt;«'*r-cMr--"Oe&gt;50«oooooo a |jj* ?J — -1 — — „_ — — __-.!_ — --ri-flNN- CM — — — — . i --i-n:ice»eficr-r-»e!Ci: -••iO I ■ ! ~ •"*■■* ' r x * •£ • r«» fj ■■■ ' *? «' &lt;M it /y* 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 lic concluded from this that it will be safer for western to us*- their native seed than to try importing seed even bi the eastern part of the state. Tti. i of local varieties Mattered thruout the western nd a can-fiil search should be made among i hem to find the \er\ Ust There is an excellent opportunity _:.i«iii^ of acclimated weai corn in western Nebraska. ti brought into a new region usually i proves in yield for • r more yean or presumably until acclimated. In here coin is moved from a dry climate or an un ■ilili- soil into more favorable conditions, good results are - iired from tin- first, but experimental data are noi able that would indicate how general this rule would be in sonic caaw where native corn has not been wisely ■ il. ■ food \arietv brought from a distance will often give rior ii'sults from the first, and improve in yield with time. There are also widely separated regions very similar in en mental conditions where an exchange of seed would prob ;iblv not affect \ it-Ids. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>