<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1916-06-01">1916-06-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 156. (Limited Edition.) North Plattb Substation Bulletin No. 17.) The University op Nebraska. BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXVIII, Article III. ROTATIONS AND TILLAGE METHODS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. Report of Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska By W. P. Snyder and W. M. Osborn. W. P. Snyder, Superintendent. E. A. Burnett, Director. Distributed June 1, 1916. OFFICE BUILDING AT NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U.S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (IMI »ECt«TS OF THE uaiVENITV.) HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, President, Falls City HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey. HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. E. MEAD WlLCOX, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy H. C. Filley, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. SNYDER, M. S., Supt. of Experimental Substation, North I'latte C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. Howard J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Associate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. H. A. McComb, B. Sc., Horticulturist of Experimental Substation, North Platte. L. L. Zook, B. Sc., Assistant in Dry Land Agriculture. V. S. Departmtnl Agriculture, North Platte. J. W. Calvin, B. Sc., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry Erwin Hopt, B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). J. A. Ratcliff, A. M., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. COOPER, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, A. M., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. 'FLORENCE A. McCormick, Ph. D., Assistant in Agricultural Botany H. E. VASEY, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Jambs Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. FRITZ Knorr, B. Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. 'Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. Page Summary 4 Rotations and tillage methods in western Nebraska: Introduction 6 Spring wheat 10 Corn r. 13 Oats 17 Barley 20 Sorghum 20 Spring and fall plowing 22 Disked corn stubble land 23 Summer tillage 26 Rotations 26 Crop sequence 28 Barnyard manure 29 Green manure 30 Alfalfa and brome grass 30 Cost of production 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY. The following statements are based on the average results of eight years as given in this bulletin. It should be remembered that this work is on the high table-land and also that winter wheat is not considered in this report. The weather conditions of the season during which the crop is grown are the greatest factor controlling yields. The seasonal precipitation has a much greater influence on crop production than methods of seed-bed preparation, crop sequence, or manure. During favorable seasons profitable crops have been produced by all methods, and during unfavorable seasons profitable crops have not been produced by any method. The system of alternate cropping and summer tillage has failed to overcome severe drouth conditions and has been less profitable in the production of corn and spring grain than ordi - nary methods of production. However, this system, during some unfavorable years, has given a large increase in yields over common practices and thus has served as a partial insurance against entire crop failure. From the standpoint of either yields or profits, it matters but little whether the land is fall plowed or spring plowed for spring grain or corn. Tho spring grain planted on cornstalk land has not yielded more than when planted on spring-grain stubble, it has given more profit when grow 1 on the corn land on account of there being les; labor required in preparation for seeding on corn land. fcarnyard manure has not increased the yields sufficiently to pay for the application of the manure, probably because water rather than plant food is the factor controlling production under these conditions. However, we believe the use of manure is advisable as a security against a deficiency in fertility and humus. Green-manure crops are too expensive for practical use under present conditions. If a value of $4 per ton is given to sorghum hay, this crop becomes one of the most profitable crops here considered. During favorable seasons and also under drouth conditions it has given a larger tonnage than any other crop. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">As a single crop, corn ranks above any of the spring small - grain crops in profit returned where the stover and grain are both used. Corn following corn has yielded 5 bushels more per acre than corn following small grain. Spring wheat ranks next to corn in profit returned in these rotations. It gives the greatest profit where it follows corn. Oats have proved the least profitable of the crops grown, and have usually been grown at a loss. Neither alfalfa nor brome grass has been grown successfully in these rotations. The failure of these crops should be expected when grown on high table-land of this character, unless seeded in rows and cultivated. Among the many rotations there was none in which the crops were grown according to common farm tillage practice conducted thoroly that did not give an average annual net profit of more than $1 per acre. The less expensive methods of tillage have given the most profit per acre. The results of this work to date commend the common tillage practices of the fanners thruout this region in so far as these practices are conducted in a thoro and intelligent manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">ROTATIONS AND TILLAGE METHODS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. BY W. P. SNYDER AND W. M. OSBORN. INTRODUCTION. The data reported in this bulletin are the results of experi - ments in rotations and tillage methods conducted on a series of one-tenth acre plats on the table-land during the past eight years. This bulletin is a means of reporting progress, or results thus far secured, rather than a report of conclusions drawn from a finished line of investigation. The results given should be considered as a means of comparing one method of tillage or one rotation or one crop with another, rather than as a basis for determining the average crop production in this region. While it is probable that the yields given in these tables are not far below or far above those secured on similar soil in this vicinity during thess years, yet areas of one-tenth acre may be more severely injured by a hot wind or an invasion of grasshoppers than a large field. However, ten-acre fields of grain grown on this farm during these years gave about the same results as the small plats. It should be remembered that this bulletin does not neces - sarily deal with the best and the poorest method of producing crops. Many methods are dealt with, and we trust that some of the poorer methods as well as some of the better methods 'Assistant in Soils and Crops, Experimental Substation, North Platte, and Assistant Agriculturist, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. Mr. Osborn resigned March 1, 1915, and was succeeded by Mr. L. L. Zook. The data presented in this bulletin relating to climatic conditions and soil moisture have been obtained by the North Platte Substation in cooperation with the Biophysical Laboratory and Office of Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. The data from which this report is compiled were gathered in the years 1906 to 1912 inclusive by Mr. W. W. Burr, then Associate in Soils and Crops, North Platte Experimental Substation, and Assistant Agriculturist in Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agriculture, who was trans - ferred in March, 1913, to become Assistant in the Office of Dry Land Agricul - ture, United States Department of Agriculture. The data for 1913 and 1914 were gathered by Mr. W. M. Osborn, as above indicated. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 7 have been tried. Some practices, such as spring plowing for corn or even fall plowing for corn, are not very practical under soil and climatic conditions which prevail in this part of the state but are being tried here in order to keep this work com - parable with similar experiments being conducted in other States having quite similar conditions. It should also be noted that winter wheat, one of our most profitable crops, is not con - sidered in this bulletin. Yield per acre usually is taken as the measure of profitable production. A low yield means a small profit or a loss and a high yield means a large profit. But this is not necessarily true. Europe produces high yields per acre but small profits per man. The measure of good farming in America is profit per man rather than yield per acre. As the yield per acre is increased beyond a certain normal the cost per bushel, on the average, will be increased, tho in individual cases or during short periods of time the reverse may be true. In considering the results of these eight years' tests, it has seemed that some attention should be given to the cost of pro - duction as represented in the profit per acre as well as the yield per acre. Not many farmers will agree on the prices that should be charged for each operation, but the prices used here are fair, at least, for comparing the results of the various methods and rotations. The final results show that some methods and rota - tions have given a profit, while others usually have given a loss. These facts should indicate that, so far as practical, certain methods of tillage, certain rotations, and certain crops should be used as little as possible. That large profits are not apparent should not cause surprise. The farmer has received interest on his investment and wages for himself and teams. The returns here given are net profit. A farm survey of representative districts in Indiana, Illinois, and Iowa, made by the United States Department of Agriculture and reported in Bulletin 41 of the United States Department of Agriculture, states that the average labor income of the farmers who own and operate their farms in these districts was, in 1911, $480 after the interest on the investment had been deducted from the profits and the fanner had been allowed the part of the jiving of the family usually secured on the farm. This figure is not quoted to indicate that the farmer does not make fair wages, but rather to indicate that when accurate methods of accounting are applied to farm operations the resulting figures may indicate that there is not as much net profit in any given operation as had been presumed. While the results in crop production herein reported repre- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. sent losses during severe years, like figures for almost any business enterprise would show similar results during periods of depression. Also, if we could include with this report the results the farmer se - cured by keeping live stock and feeding the roughage grown during these years, the final item of profit would look much more favor - able. This report deals only with certain phases of the farmer's operations, and these phases are those most noticeably affected by unfavorable seasons. That the farmer did not get fair wages for growing a certain crop, by a certain method, during a certain year, is not sufficient basis for asserting that the farmer did or did not make money during that year. It is probable that the farmer who judiciously combined live stock with farming secured a profit during the most unfavorable season. In order that a general and more comprehensive idea of the plan of the work may be had, Chart I has been inserted. The plats are 2 rods wide by 8 rods long, the area of each plat being one-tenth acre. The plats are arranged in groups or rotations ranging from two to six years in length. The rotations are also arranged so that each differs from the others in at least one par - ticular. There are only two six-year rotations. In each of these a hay crop is used in order to conserve soil fertility and also to furnish a good quality of feed or pasture for live stock. The larger part of the work has been done with three- and four-year rotations. All of the standard crops grown in western Nebraska except winter wheat are used in these rotations and systems of cropping. Some of the rotations, systems of cropping, or methods of tillage are designed principally to conserve moisture or organic matter in the soil. The study of the work as here presented is made in such a way that the effect of cropping and tillage for only the one year preceding the crop is shown. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 9 hi kj «»k Q W hill si 1 , JJj k_l IslJ LJ kJ K fc • k k I $ 5 rs § S I S 1 i i inr &lt;0 t e | J | p; &lt; S..J h_J tt_J k_ V n M CD B I - 1 lJLI ~ir I I, 2 5 c 8 k ! 5 5 I I I I innn^n » 2 «i i § v) 2 &gt; t g V si h .2 "^ k •» «&lt;. 5: &lt; 2 | I 5 | S 5 5 2 8 § 3 I s t I la_J k I b_J b_J LU I. % I Q ! 0. k e 5 1 k I 10 n * 1 I k « k i « i I g 6 I i I J I I I I * I W I Kj I k I W I ki 5 § k c i i i O 5 a 5 ! 4. (I k J 1 5 I 111 t » . 1 1 »i r I &lt;n * 4; «. n. "5 k "&gt; *&gt; &lt; &lt; k | I 8 8 | I I 3 5 5 I I i I to I k. I fe I w I L 10 k I i I I S I » I kt J R H Q ; k k k s $ • i i I g i I 5 Q 0 5 C i s I b | ki I fe 1 a I u_ s I I LJkl 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. SPRING WHEAT. Table 1 shows the annual and average yields of spring wheat from 1907 to 1914 inclusive, under different methods of tillage and crop sequence. Where wheat has been grown on more than one plat in the same manner, the average yield of all such plats has been used. Plowing has been done at an average depth of about eight inches, except on one plat where wheat has been continuously grown on spring-plowed land. In this case the depth of plowing has been four inches. Under the column headed "Green Manure," wheat follows winter rye and Canada field peas, which were plowed under when a maximum growth had been reached, usually about blooming time. Small-grain stubble that is to be plowed in the spring in preparation for wheat is usually disked once in the fall to pre - vent the growth of weeds. In the one exception to this, where continuous cropping is practiced, the stubble is left untouched until the time of plowing. Where fall plowing is practiced under the same system of cropping, one or two diskings follow the harvest operations as soon as possible. In the practice of summer tillage the land is plowed once, usually in the fall. Such cultivation as is necessary to keep the land free from weeds and the surface in a condition receptive to rainfall then follows until seeding time the second spring. This method of clean summer tillage may be regarded as intensive. It will be noted from the table that three profitable crops have been produced during the eight years. One year resulted in a total failure due to drouth and some injury from grasshoppers. The remaining four years are far below the point of profitable production. Between the general averages for the production of wheat on fall-plowed land and spring-plowed land the difference is less than 1 bushel per acre. Where continuous cropping is practiced the difference between the average yields on spring- or fall-plowed land is only one-half bushel per acre. Wheat on fall - plowed corn land has averaged 1.8 bushels more than wheat on spring-plowed corn land. Fall-plowed oats stubble has yielded 1.5 bushels more wheat than spring-plowed oats stubble. Wheat on spring-plowed oats stubble has given the lowest yield of any method used in producing wheat during the eight years. The average yield from this method, 9.6 bushels per acre, is 2.6 and 1.5 bushels per acre less than wheat following wheat on fall- and spring-plowed land, respectively. Further study of this method shows that in only one year, 1910, has wheat following oats on spring-plowed land given a higher yield than wheat on spring-plowed wheat land. The difference in this case was only 1.9 bushels per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 11 Altho wheat on spring-plowed sorghum stubble has given the next lowest average yield, it is only 0.1 of a bushel per acre less than wheat on spring-plowed corn land. Further study of the table by years shows that wheat under this method has yielded often as much and during some years more than wheat following corn, wheat, or oats, on spring- or fall-plowed land. Wheat on disked corn stubble has averaged 0.2 of a bushel more per acre than wheat on spring-plowed corn land and 1.6 bushels less than wheat on fall-plowed corn land. When the cost of producing wheat on disked corn stubble is considered, it is evident that this method is more conducive to profitable results than producing wheat on either spring- or on fall-plowed corn stubble or on plowed small-grain stubble. The yields of wheat have been increased by the practice of summer tillage more than by any other method, but the in - crease in yield has not been large enough to offset the increased cost of production and to return a fair margin of profit to the farmer. This method did not prove to be an absolute safeguard against drouth in 1911, when wheat failed entirely under all methods of crop production. During the year of 1909, it will be seen that spring wheat on land previously fallowed did not yield as much as wheat on spring-plowed wheat land. This was due to the poor stand ob - tained on the fallowed plat. Conditions for germination were not as favorable in the spring-plowed plat as in either the fall - plowed or the fallowed plat. Consequently, the grain on the spring plowing came up slowly and escaped a freeze that severely injured the grain on the other plats. The results secured in 1912 vary from the average more than those of any other year. The highest yield, 14.2 bushels per acre, was secured from land on which rye had been turned under for green manure. The yield from the corresponding plat on which peas had been turned under for green manure was only 4.8 bushels. Spring- and fall-plowed wheat land produced yields of 12.8 and 11.2 bushels per acre, exceeding the yields of summer-tilled land by 5.6 and 4.0 bushels per acre, respectively. In this year the difference in moisture in the first 4 feet between plats receiving various treatments was very small at seeding time. The inconsistent single year results call attention to the necessity of having results which extend over a number of years from which to draw conclusions. These eight years' results do not show any very wide dif - ferences as far as average yields are concerned. But, as will be shown later, there is considerable variation in profits per acre, due to the difference in cost of production by various methods of tillage. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155 o .. - ¥-1 i— I i « te — ' 5i g hwooio toxoeoN b •^i^^HIM HHNCCM s.^ t^ «o eo -i to ad O) t-BlDt- I lOQOCOXIt- I- i P4 . i s 5 R « S 1 ■~ £ c««n 1 : :::!■»« •S"-"-^ « few oi^-n&gt;-I daiwdc o a 2 "?'T N .^ c ? e i = ?^ t^ 1^ hr ~1 T i 5J &lt; i I OS CO^i^HCD W3 X C-i r? C- -T" Vs CO — S «J g t- to « 35 © &gt;o t- « « n 5r eo £ I *«a en e^&lt;o«D'*icoOTj«coco -*r 06 Sft. j g.3 OS &gt;i^ * MM«a hhh«» ix eo ?| . . , ; S g :::::::::: : : ii ft it m %l &amp; un urn % &gt; 1 ' I : M •a : °- a o o o I i 1 : I ! -Ill $ I =3 i a ! i £ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 13 CORN. Corn has occupied a rather important position in this study of crop production in western Nebraska. Altho the grain itself has been uncertain in production, experience shows that a fairly good quality of stover may be produced each year. If the max - imum feed value of the stover is obtained, the value of the crop is greatly increased. In addition to its feed value, the crop lends itself well to the preparation of the land for the succeeding crop. Such a combination of two valuable factors in one crop adds greatly to the importance of its growth. It is very evident also that corn becomes most valuable in a system of farming where live stock is produced. Potatoes have an effect on crops that follow similar to that of corn, but are not so well adapted as corn to growth on a large acreage. The effect of the growth and the clean cultivation of corn upon following crops approaches more nearly the effect of summer tillage than in the case of any other crop. This may be readily seen in the study of the tables showing the production of spring wheat and oats under different methods of tillage and crop sequence. Frequently the yields of small grain following corn have been higher than any others obtained except those on land previously summer tilled. Even where the yields have not been the highest, they have approached the highest so closely that they have produced the most net profit when the cost of seed-bed preparation is considered. Altho corn has had an im - portant place in the preparation of the land for other crops a study of different methods of growing the crop itself is highly important. A study of the production of corn as presented in Table 2 shows the effects of the cropping or the tillage of the land in the one year only preceding the corn. This table presents the annual and average yields for eight years, 1907 to 1914 inclusive. Where corn follows corn on spring-plowed land and on fall-plowed land, a system of continuous cropping is practiced. When continuous cropping is practiced on land that is fall plowed, the land is given sufficient tillage in the fall and early spring to insure the storage of a maximum amount of the precipitation that falls in the meantime. In the practice of continuous cropping on spring - plowed land, the soil is plowed to a depth of only about 4 inches and followed by a limited amount of cultivation. Where corn is produced on land that has been summer tilled, a system of alternate cropping and summer tillage is practiced ; that is, the land is cropped to corn one year and summer tilled the next. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. Where corn follows oats on spring plowing, it is the second crop after sod in two six-year rotations where alfalfa and brome grass are grown. Altho the yields are presented in such a manner as to show the residual effect of a sod crop, the real object of the method has been defeated. Yields of brome grass and alfalfa have been obtained in two years only, 1907 and 1908. The land has been reseeded since that time, according to the plan of a six-year rotation of corn, spring wheat, oats, and brome grass or alfalfa, but permanent stands of grass have not been secured. Because of the failure to secure permanent stands of grass, the yields of corn under this method will not be discussed. In view of the fact that we know that alfalfa and brome grass use the moisture in the soil to a lower depth than any of our grain crops, it is reasonably safe to assume that grain crops cannot follow these hay crops successfully until water has been stored in the soil. The length of time required to do this will depend upon the amount and character of the annual or seasonal precipitation. Corn has always been planted about May 10 with the lister at the rate of one to two grains every 18 or 20 inches. Former experiments reported from this Station show the advisability of using the lister in preference to the surface planter. The variety of corn used is commonly known as white dent, originally Silver Mine, which has been reduced to a medium size. This variety is well adapted to the country surrounding Xorth Platte and is early enough to insure maturity. The corn is harvested with the binder when mature, and shocked in the field. The shocks stand until cured, which is usually about one month or six weeks. The entire weight is then taken, and the grain is shucked and weighed separately. The unit basis for the weight of the grain is 70 or 75 pounds per bushel, depending upon the dryness at the time of husking. During the eight years that corn has been grown under different methods of tillage and crop sequence, four fairly profit - able crops of grain have been produced. Two years resulted in failures and the remaining two years were more conducive to lass than to profit. The final average for eight years indicates that there is very little profit in growing corn for the grain alone by the most favorable of the methods under study and no profit when grown by the less favorable methods, but these results also indicate that fair profits may be secured from almost any of these methods if the stover as well as the grain is utilized. The annual and average yields of stover for eight successive years show that the stover has produced a profitable and dependable crop of forage. This factor alone will seriously affect the profit </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 15 or loss from the corn crop. The necessity of producing forage for the maintenance of live stock in this country makes the highest utilization of the entire crop a very important factor. A close study of soil-moisture 1 determinations during the eight years that these methods have been in progress indicates fairly conclusively that corn does not use the soil moisture to such a close margin or altogether as deep as does small grain. On fall-plowed ground, corn following oats has averaged 1.1 bushels per acre more than corn following spring wheat. But on spring plowing the same sequence of crops has had no effect on the average yields. Corn following barley on fall-plowed land has given a slightly better average yield than corn following spring wheat or oats. The difference, however, is slight. The practice of growing corn on land previously summer tilled has increased the yields of grain but little. The yields of stover have been increased slightly. However, neither the in - creased yields in grain nor in stover have been large enough to offset the increased cost of production or to pay a profit from any point of view. Corn grown on land previously summer tilled has averaged only 2.3 bushels per acre more than corn grown under a system of continuous cropping on spring-plowed land and 2.6 bushels more than corn grown under the same system of cropping on fall-plowed land. Continuous cropping of corn on fall-plowed land has given an average yield of 0.3 of a bushel per acre less than continuous cropping of corn on spring - plowed land. Spring plowing has given the best average returns of corn of any method under study. A careful survey of Table 2 would indicate that corn should be grown for a feed crop rather than as a cash crop alone. As a feed crop, it is probably safer than any of the small grains. If a small-grain crop is destroyed before maturity by severe weather conditions, the plant growth already developed is practically lost so far as feed is concerned. But corn has the advantage in that it may usually be cut and handled in such a way that con - siderable feed is saved if weather conditions threaten to destroy the crop. In case the crop is destroyed by hail, corn land may be prepared for the use of emergency crops to better advantage than small-grain land. 'See Bulletins 109 and 114 and Research Bulletin 5 of this Station frr more complete data on soil moisture. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station , Bulletin 15 ft cd 8.32 s.8 5;SSS8 j: S NNNNM MMMMMN &lt;f I 3 1 I &lt; „ «»■» — — l"O«!0CUJ»» IS W g u 22222 (222'* 0 '™ ° •» ««** — *- itAXXOW I go xnoto'm 00 5 N »!S.28S5'g§ggi§ 2 1 3 s ' . _ .1 -— ±- 1 * l - • »••-■« xeioi ~ ?j ?" « 2 !2 "■*" ** 3Sei3&lt;af o eo «*• - --,_,..-■ I _„ — -_,-_- _- ?■ 1 -T O OS {57 a ■ WP. 3.3SSSS S 5 «25 [«» tit 2 a s&amp;s&amp;s i 5 ■ 2 5 5 ■ Itsse iiHsi? I H 2^ " !f ! I 11 §»» L SSSSS =sg=Sz § ' S C5 ■*»* ., SCJJ^S 1 . - iT X - - '1C s» sk ; " — — "—" - - t |» | 33333 j 333325 2 5 \ ?j *SJ wn^oi oiusxej-^ •tj \O j •mti-ti ii ¥ ! 1 I I" ?g . -ISS3 5il«i 1 1 * o&gt;S. a \SmJM SSSSJSs 1 i | ■ SSS£5 C •NNHtM mnb'm'n' -i rj I 1- o&gt;». | U |SS§SS iiSSSJSS;S S M ■ || . mm Sppju ! ■* -g g mwwww | ooneoneon I m" re" *"! -ills'- ysiis i I *1 -III- 5 yjias ? - ? 1 SOrsox so JfejS I i _:""«•' - — --- - J J I a &lt; -3, : """ : : | SS222 ■S25JS328 S S t t 3 5, f \MM\ 111 i aiumn i ; n » i if i w Sti o 3 or. g I M h i « is </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 17 OATS. In Table 3 eight years' results in the production of oats are presented. The data shown in this table are presented in the same manner as those for spring wheat and corn in Tables 1 and 2. Where oats follow oats on spring- and fall-plowed land the explanations are the same as those for spring wheat and corn. Kherson oats have been used continuously in this work. The seeding has been done with the press drill at the rate of 6 pecks per acre and at the same time as the seeding of the other spring small-grain crops. Altho large and profitable yields of oats have been produced, it was only during years that were very favorable to crop production. Later years tend to show that oats do not have much ability to withstand severe seasonal conditions. As yet, none of the many methods of tillage that have been tried have been able to overcome this unfavorable characteristic of the oat. Referring to the yields of oats under different methods of tillage and systems of cropping, in Table 3 it will be seen that the three years 1907, 1908, and 1909 were productive of good yields of oats. Since that time, the crops have been very light, with two absolute failures. Altho yields were obtained in 1910, 1912, and 1914, the grain was very light and chaffy. During these three years, especially 1910 and 1914, it would have been more practical to cut the crop for hay, rather than to let the grain mature and be threshed as a grain crop. Closer study of this table shows that seasonal variations have produced much larger differences in yields than methods of tillage and systems of cropping. During the years favorable to the production of small grains all cultural methods produced good crops. During the years when weather conditions were severe or extremely unfavorable none of the cultural methods were able to return a profit in the form of either a feed crop or a cash grain crop. Continuous cropping of oats on fall-plowed land has given the largest average yield, and oats following barley on fall-plowed land has given the lowest average yield of any system of cropping in use. Only once (1912) during the eight years has continuous cropping of oats yielded less than oats following barley. During the remaining seven years the difference has been distinctly in favor of the system of continuous cropping. Where oats follow spring wheat, the yields have been constantly less, and, on the average, 3.6 bushels per acre less than the yields resulting from the practice of continuous cropping. Spring wheat stubble that had been manured before the land was plowed in the fall has averaged 2.1 bushels more of oats per </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. 18 acre than spring plowed land that was not manured. During the eight years that these methods have been under study, manuring the land has failed to equal or increase the yield in the two seasons of 1904 and 1914. The practice of continuous cropping of oats on spring-plowed land has averaged 4.4 bushels per acre less than the same method on fall-plowed land. Oats on spring-plowed spring wheat stubble have yielded better than oats on fall-plowed spring wheat stub - ble in five years out of six that have produced crops, but the great difference in favor of fall-plowed wheat stubble in 1908 has reduced the average increase from spring plowing over fall plow - ing to 0.7 of a bushel per acre for 8 years. Oats on spring-plowed spring wheat land have given practically the same average yield as oats on spring-plowed corn land. These two systems of crop - ping have given the highest average yield of oats of any of the spring-plowed land. It would seem that on the average the time of plowing does not affect the yields of oats. An average difference of only 0.7 of a bushel per acre is found in favor of spring plowing over fall plowing. This would indicate that the land should be plowed for oats when the work can be done most economically, provided such tillage will not result in damage from soil blowing or from other causes. The average yield of oats on disked corn ground, 17.9 bushels per acre, is practically the same as the average yield of oats under all methods of production on both spring- and fall-plowed land. This is by far the cheapest method of production and should find favor in a system of farm management where oats are given much consideration. Summer tillage has increased the yields of oats more than any other method of tillage, but the increase in yields has not been sufficient to pay for the increased cost of production when com - pared with other methods. Altho the practice of summer tillage has given the greatest increase in the yields of oats, it failed entirely to produce yields in 1911 and 1913. Where winter rye or Canada field peas has been used for a green-manure crop as a seed-bed preparation for oats, the yields have been increased more than by any other method except summer tillage. Oats following alfalfa and brome grass as sod crops have given the poorest returns of any system of cropping that has been under study. The average production of oats for eight years under all methods of tillage and crop sequence is 19.8 bushels per acre. With the exception of the first three years the grain has been very light and chaffy. A comparison of oats with other small - grain crops during the eight years of production indicates rather definitely that oats have produced less feed or profit per acre than any other crop. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 19 cjjj &gt;-«(N c- ■» °o T ™ &lt;°. "? "? '" 1 ! c ": c i G ! e i c 2*"? °S S; 8 t-'os d«ot-|os«oo5«oo6|c-° I --nn I nnn os C* NMM ■:&gt; &lt;» d-*d xao^ne ! to o» I o« • I ni 5- c | Bq 3 ? , _ -i _ ■* (MM z a 1 1 Silfil icl 1 : Jl ; M i ift -"S « E _* 5 1 I ii 7. H 1 i — V .- C = o « E : ft 1 ill -b I bi &lt; .2 S s o &gt; U, x ' (MM C-©^ HOt; 00 ■* 00 0&gt; ©t-;O&gt; ffjtfj'* 00 i. '. -r »»[&gt;' N^Modn — ■ co «c Tf its :i-rr r-t I *H »-( »-( N t&gt;. 2 Saw nnm ecccmiMco in w eoeooo « — — in — * I ' § »-l 00 ,*io "5 — CJ U rt 00 «00 «O&lt;| 00 - § oooo odoio i&gt; •-; Tf us c^ I » I fc: JS 10 ? S2SS S S Q0 U5&lt;C CO^*C£ t lO|00 t— t— t^* CC^CO CD 08 It t-tCO O^XS lOOeOS «D« IOU310 ONH ■* $ HI : &gt;»||| : :J| Sf 5sS : S . i • I • I • I • I ■ 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. BARLEY. Barley continuously cropped on fall-plowed land has averaged 1.4 bushels per acre more than barley continuously cropped on spring-plowed land. On spring-plowed land it does not seem to make any difference whether the land was previously cropped to oats or barley. Barley grown on disked corn land has averaged less for eight years than when grown by any other method. Of the seven crops that were produced, only two on disked corn ground were as good as those produced on small-grain stubble that had been plowed either in the spring or in the fall. Barley has not given as profitable returns on disked corn land as spring wheat. Land that was previously summer tilled increased the average yield of barley but did not increase the profit per acre. In 1907, the practice of summer tillage did not increase the yields of barley as compared with other methods except disked corn land. In 1911, the practice of summer tillage failed as completely to produce a crop as any other method under trial. In 1912, the returns of barley from continuous cropping on spring-plowed land and from barley following oats under the same tillage were as large as from barley grown on land previously summer tilled. SORGHUM. Sorghum has been grown as a forage crop in certain rotations. It has been seeded with a press drill at the rate of 5 pecks per acre. The average annual yield for seven years has been 3.1 tons per acre. Spring wheat land that was manured and plowed in the spring has given an average yield of 459 pounds less of sorghum hay per acre than spring-plowed oats land with no manure applied. Corn land that was manured and plowed in the spring has yielded only 148 pounds more of sorghum hay per acre than the manured oats land. Such yields would indicate that manure has not had any beneficial effect on the sorghum crop nor has it left any apparent residual effect on succeeding crops. During favorable seasons and also under drouth conditions sorghum has given a larger tonnage per acre than any other crop. The feeding value of sorghum, as reported in Bulletins 105 and 117 of this Station, is about the same as that of native hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska 21 NNN H N M 0) i a c-. 1 S c "8 a « S ■s a &gt;- *r « i III O! Q (« •&lt; r £ a H i. §■•* i s &gt;.« o to ooooj en © « a. OS N eO&lt;D^" t-^ &lt;O 1O £ S«, $ d nsici h « oi ~ $ 00 ,-c »h M-&lt;N M (M -h — 08 O 1 _. $ n «nh « t^ ib S 1.2&gt; ■ .S •^tj s * «i * » ®. °°. s 3&gt; © oioo» © o» t-' 3 g S ■&gt;* «•*« « eo eo &gt;. „ .9 js &gt;» 6Ji -h - 10 -g £.§ : „ : : : : : O 00 3 .go, • ii : e I 0. i i i j I ; ; I ! I i II I </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. SPRING AND FALL PLOWING. From the standpoint of average yield but little difference has been observed in the production of spring wheat, oats, barley, and corn on fall-plowed land or on spring-plowed land. When the net profit per acre is considered in the production of wheat, spring plowing has been the more profitable. Altho oats have returned a very small margin of profit in various rotations on spring- and on fall-plowed land, they have more frequently re - sulted in a loss under both methods of tillage. Neither spring - nor fall-plowed land has returned more than a few cents per acre net profit in the production of barley. Both methods of tillage have given practically the same results in the production of corn. That spring plowing has been more profitable, so far as profit per acre is concerned, is largely due to the fact that the cost of production on spring-plowed land is less than on fall-plowed land, owing to fewer field operations being required to put the spring - plowed land into condition for seeding. However, this advantage may be overcome by employing labor for fall plowing that would otherwise be idle. Chart II is presented to compare the efficiency of fall-plowed land with that of spring-plowed land in the storage of moisture in the soil. The principal fact brought out by this chart is that during four years out of seven under study, there has been more moisture at seeding time in the first three feet of spring-plowed land than in the same depth of fall-plowed land. During the three years that spring-plowed land contained less moisture than fall-plowed land, the difference was practically negligible. The amount of water that can be stored in the soil from the harvest period of one crop to the seeding time of the next crop is com - paratively small except in very favorable years when the amount of rain or snow during this period is above normal and of such character that there is but little run-off. Under conditions that have prevailed during the last five years, this stored moisture is rapidly used by weeds and the growing crop in the spring. DISKED CORN STUBBLE LAND. Disking corn stubble land as a method of seed-bed preparation has given practically as good results from the standpoint of yields in the production of small grain, except barley, as either spring or fall plowing. The cultivation of the soil while the corn was growing kept the land free from weeds and left the soil in such condition that it could be made into an excellent seed bed easily and quickly by the disk in the spring. The low cost </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 23 c 0 o 03 Zl 7 BU PER ACRL 27 3 _■ V^5 INS AVAILABLE *VAT£R &lt;q B&gt;$^yXii$3 Z.50 ■■ O 3f3 //V3 PRECPTH - flPR I TO June 30 ~~| am BU PER ACRE -^ n J5 MZ50 IHS AVAILABLE WflTCH JqB itv - CM toy PHecfrn /tm/junelio] \SKKtf/K/k IB BU PER ftCRE 5 55^ 2 tf §p 5 r^ 0 ? i, s * I n i . *r m V/fl PRECP Tn f\PR I junc*\ I (^ O 0 a A rm y,£ld i&lt; 5 0 f* 1 B NO y/fLO t- 3? j, S E9HHHHMHHi v &lt;- ; //v5 au/hlablc watch J -j. i | ° 5M1 PRECPTN APR l JUNC 30 | JS"/,^ 1 ■ ilB 8U P£R AC/r£ fc f*» " 5 II 2. ■■ - • 5^ || \ Ml 7/ INS AVAILABLE WATCX d£ • § 5 1 77/ PRECPTn APR I- JUNE X | " O , H i £0 BU PER ACRE 18 XliBMS AVAILABLE WATEH *§I3O - «§5 S !"8 LO BV PER ACRE 52 .. to </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. * Kl &amp;? S5 tc K n I s ? *&gt; 5 !i I'S » S&gt; ! 9? 1^ ! life \ i I &lt;*&lt;! plowed and in fall-plowed land { I ha m ? t&gt; « I ft &lt; * k I Jl !•# &lt;•« ns; s5 i ! (1 L*i? 5 5 &gt; k\ j? I £ S5 S i .5 8 i. R b V 1° ™ .0 &lt;0 8 i?5 5 if ? •&gt; 1 a I I « ! Is | 1! I I* o \ I U I i I '8 irt III. 0 ?«J I itoragi of noist ire in spring-pl lowed s nd in </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 25 of such field operations has resulted in more net profit per acre in the production of spring wheat and oats than any other method. Even tho barley on disked corn land gave the lowest average yield of any method under trial, the cost of production was low enough to permit this method to return the most net profit of any method for an average of eight years. SUMMER TILLAGE'. Land summer tilled has produced higher yields of spring wheat, oats, barley, and corn than any land cropped every year, but has not returned as much net profit per year as land farmed by other methods. Summer tillage has not overcome the effect of a severe drouth, nor always produced larger yields than land that was cropped each year. Spring wheat on land summer tilled did not yield as much as spring wheat on spring-plowed jand in 1909. Land summer tilled failed to produce a grain crop in 1911, the same as land that was cropped each year. In 1912, spring wheat on land summer tilled averaged 5.6 bushels per acre less than wheat on spring-plowed land cropped each year, and 4 bushels less per acre than wheat on fall-plowed land cropped each year. In 1913, barley and corn failed to produce grain crops on land summer tilled as well as on similar land cropped each year. The average yield of spring wheat on all the plats cropped every year has been 10.9 bushels per acre. The average yield of spring wheat following corn has been 12 bushels per acre. The average yield of spring wheat following spring wheat on spring-plowed land has been 12.2 bushels per acre. The average yield of spring wheat on land summer tilled has been 16.8 bushels per acre, or 4.2 bushels per acre more than that grown by the most productive method of continuous cropping. This increase in yield due to summer tilling the land has not been large enough to overcome the additional cost of raising a crop on land summer tilled. A study of the results given in Table 7 indicates that this is true also of corn, oats, and barley. Next to the use of winter rye and Canada field peas as green manure for seed-bed prepara - tion, the practice of summer tilling land is the most expensive method under trial. Clean summer tillage is the most practical method known of accumulating moisture in the soil. But Chart IV indicates that only a small part of the precipitation may be stored in the soil. The condition of the soil, the amount of water falling within a ■A more complete discussion of summer tillage and the use of soil moisture is given in Bulletins 109 and 114 and Research Bulletin 5 of this Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. given time, and the weather conditions all play important parts in determining the percentage of the season's precipitation that may be stored. The seasonal distribution of rainfall and the weather conditions during the growing period have a greater influence on the yields of the crops than has the amount of water stored in the soil. Small-grain crops have been able to use all of the moisture stored by summer tillage, in addition to the pre - cipitation coming during the growing season. ROTATIONS. In studying the profit or loss of various rotations, all factors entering into each rotation should be given due consideration. The cause of a loss in a certain rotation may be due to some factor that might be eliminated in actual farm practice. For example, corn is grown on spring-plowed land in many of the rotations. Common practice indicates that in this locality as good yields might be secured at less cost by disking instead of plowing. This would give corn a higher place in common farm practice than is indicated in Table 7. In some rotations manure has been added at a high cost, tho there is no indication that the manure increased the yield. As two of the rotations having sorghum as one of the crops also have manure added, they are lower in net returns than necessary. A careful survey of Table 7 shows that nearly all rotations giving a loss were designed to maintain the soil fertility by barn - yard manure, a green-manure crop, or a grass crop. The other final items of loss occur where corn was grown on land summer tilled, where oats were grown continuously on spring-plowed oats land or on land summer tilled, or where barley was grown on land summer tilled. The rotations giving an annual net profit of less than $1 per acre all contained summer tillage as a regular practice once in three or four years, except two rotations in each of which the ground was prepared for corn by plowing instead of by disking, which increased the cost about $1 per acre, probably, without increasing the yields. There was no rotation in which the crops were grown accord - ing to common farm practice conducted thoroly that did not give an average annual profit of more than $1 per acre. If we should assume that the barnyard manure did not ma - terially increase the succeeding crop of sorghum, and we believe it did not, then the most profitable rotation of the entire series ■See Table 7, page 35. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 27 $ \ '■; I? V "1 i 9 "3 ! K 1 I! I As ST. K &gt; * ! «J | % wv. m ra« f I » L- s 9 V .5 &gt; 2 &gt; H 31 &lt;» &gt; I i k« w I &gt; i 5 3 I I K s 8 5 I h u «5 n ii. U I I I I j »N \ I i o w k I I I fc k ii I ! i 1 5 n % j S Chart I f. — Storai water b; •lean sui •r tillai ;p- 907 to 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. is sorghum, corn, and spring wheat. In this, corn stover is given a value of $3 per ton and sorghum a value of $4 per ton. Rotations of oats, corn, and spring wheat rank high in the profit per acre. The oats are usually the unprofitable crop in these rotations. As a single crop, corn ranks above any of the small-grain crops in the profit returned where the stover and grain are both used. The effect of corn in leaving the field in a suitable condition for the succeeding crop should add to the value of the corn crop in a rotation. Spring wheat ranks next to corn in the rotations. It gives the greatest profit where it follows corn. The results of this work to date commend the common tillage practices of the farmers thruout this region in so far as these practices are conducted in an intelligent and thoro manner. CROP SEQUENCE. Continuous cropping of spring wheat has given an average yield practically as large as that obtained from corn land. Where spring wheat follows sorghum grown for forage, the average yield has not been noticeably diminished when compared with spring wheat following either corn or spring wheat. Where spring plowing is practiced, spring wheat following oats has given the lowest average yield of any crop sequence for wheat. This difference, however, has not resulted where the oats land was plowed in the fall. On fall-plowed land, continuous cropping of corn has averaged 4.9 bushels per acre more than corn following small grain, and on spring-plowed land a difference of 5.3 bushels per acre has favored the system of continuous cropping. Corn following sorghum has given the lowest average yield for eight years of any crop sequence for corn. Oats following brome grass or alfalfa has been the lowest yielding sequence for oats for an average of eight years. On fall-plowed land, the highest average yielding sequence for oats has been continuous cropping of oats and the lowest average yielding sequence has been oats following barley. On spring - plowed land, continuous cropping of oats and oats following spring wheat and corn have given the highest average yields. The differences in yield between any of the various crop sequences for oats, except oats following barley, are so small that they may be reversed by one favorable crop year. Barley grown on disked corn land has given the lowest average yield of any crop sequence for barley. Barley following oats has given practically as good results as continuous cropping of barley. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 29 BARNYARD MANURE. Barnyard manure has been applied to certain plats once in three years at the rate of about 10 tons per acre. In Rotation 43 of oats, corn, and spring wheat, all seeded on fall-plowed land, the manure was applied before plowing for oats. In Rota - tion 3 the same crops were grown in the same manner except that no manure was used. The value per acre annually of the crops from the rotation not having manure is $1.78 more than the value of the crop from the rotation having manure. The other rotations in which manure is used are 44 and 47 in both of which grain stubble is manured during the winter and spring plowed for sorghum. There is no rotation differing from either of these rotations in manure alone, but Rotation 48 is somewhat similar and may assist in ascertaining the value of manure. The eight-year average yield of sorghum hay from the plat in Rotation 44, where sorghum was grown on manured wheat stubble, was 5,856 pounds per acre yearly. In 47 the cor - responding yield was 6,464 pounds, or the average of the two plats manured was 6,160 pounds. In Rotation 48, where sorghum followed oats and preceded wheat without any manure in the rotation, the average annual yield for the eight years was 6,316 pounds. There is no indication that the barnyard manure in - creased the yield of sorghum forage. Altho the manure has undoubtedly maintained or increased the fertility of the soil, it has given no appreciable beneficial effect on the yield of the succeeding crops. However, it should not be inferred that the application of barnyard manure is to be condemned. Generally the manure can be applied when there is little demand for the labor of men and teams. Also the cost of spreading manure on the land is not very different from the cost of dumping it into a ravine. It is pretty definitely understood that water is the limiting factor in crop production in the Great Plains area. Organic matter, if properly applied to the soil, increases the efficiency of the water in the soil and tends to keep the soil in a good physical condition. Since the history of land farmed longer shows that the soil will eventually reach a point of diminishing returns unless plant food is returned to the soil thru application of barnyard manure or some other form of fertilizer, it would seem advisable not to waste the barnyard manure even tho the succeeding yields as recorded in this bulletin do not show any beneficial effect from its use. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. 30 GREEN MANURE. During the three years in which spring wheat has been grown on land where winter rye and where Canada field peas have been plowed under to serve as green manure, the yields have not been greatly increased over those of ordinary methods of production. Oats have given a response in yield to green manure next to that obtained by the practice of summer tillage. No practical difference has been noted between the results from the use of rye and peas as green-manure crops. The use of green-manure crops has proved to be even more expensive and less profitable than alternate cropping and summer tillage. Tho the yields have been increased by the green-manure crop, the additional cost of producing the crop, as represented by the rental of the land an extra year, the cost of the seed for the green - manure crop, and the extra tillage that must accompany this method, are so great that the final profit from this method of pro - duction is not as great as from ordinary methods. ALFALFA AND BROME GRASS. Alfalfa and brome grass are each used three years in six-year rotations. The purpose of these rotations is the production of forage crops and the maintenance of soil fertility. During five years out of eight neither the alfalfa nor the brome grass has produced any forage. Since 1911 a permanent stand has not been secured of either. It is evident that neither of these forage crops has been used successfully in these rotations. COST OF PRODUCTION. Since the cost of production is an important factor in deter - mining the profits to be derived from any system of farming, it seems advisable to present data to furnish information on this point. In order to arrive at the cost of various methods, it is necessary to assign values to all operations and products. Some of these values are necessarily somewhat arbitrary, but all factors have been given careful consideration and the values are thought to be fairly representative for this region and sufficiently accurate to make comparisons reliable. By the use of the data presented here the farmer may adjust values according to his local conditions and get a fair conception of the net returns that may be expected under his management. In computing the cost of various operations, a fixed wage of $2 per day for a man and $1 per day per horse has been used. Factors included in the cost of production are calculated on an acre basis for each of the separate operations performed, begin - ning with the preparation of the land and ending with the harvest- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 31 ing and the shocking of the grain. To these are added the price of the seed and interest, and the taxes on land investment calculated at 8 per cent on a valuation of $20 per acre. Fifteen cents per acre is also allowed for deterioration and repairs on the binder. But no allowance has been made for deterioration on other machinery, as it is believed that the wages allowed for men and teams is sufficient to cover this item for the remainder of the equipment. The average farm prices of the various grains during the past 10 years, according to the Bureau of Crop Estimates of the United States Department of Agriculture, were: Oats 35 cents per bushel, spring wheat 80 cents per bushel, barley 47 cents per bushel, and corn 51 cents per bushel. It will cost to take the grain from the shock, thresh or shell, and put it into the bin about 5 cents per bushel for oats, 10 cents per bushel for spring wheat, 6 cents per bushel for barley, and 11 cents per bushel for corn. Subtracting these costs from the farm prices as shown above, it is evident that the grain would be worth in the shock the follow - ing prices: Oats 30 cents, wheat 70 cents, barley 41 cents, and corn 40 cents per bushel. The presumption in this bulletin is that corn is grown for the forage as well as for the grain and that, therefore, it is cut and the ears shucked from the shock fodder. In computing the value of the crops when produced, the average price of the crops in the shock has been used, as the cost of pro - duction is not carried further than that point. The following table shows what may be considered an average day's work and gives a fixed cost per acre for the various field operations when a wage of $2 per day for a man and $1 per day for a horse is paid. Table 5. — Average day's work of man and team in tillage opera- tions with cost per acre. 'In Table 7 the cost price used for listing is 60 cents per acre, which is probably too low. No. of Kind of work men No. of A' horses i iverag acres verage acres s &gt;l Cost pe acre ost per acre 'lowing 1 Double disking 1 iarrowing 1 Drilling 1 rultivating 1 listing 1 ' 1 man to shock harvesting Twine per acre ( Wearandrepaironbinder 4 4 4 4 4 4 3.5 8 ;i5 15 16 I 15 $1.75 .75 .17 .40 .38 .75' .13 .25 .15 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. When winter rye and field peas have been used as a green - manure crop, the cost of seed has been estimated as $1 per acre for rye and $4 per acre for peas. In the production of brome grass and alfalfa, the cost of seed per acre was $1.40 and $1.20, respectively. The cost of harvest - ing the crops was $2 per acre. By keeping an accurate record of the number of tillage operations performed in the production of the various crops, the values previously presented have enabled us to establish a fixed cost of production for each crop under any method of tillage. The data are shown in Table 6. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 33 Si 22222 SSSSSSSSS! §S fc £ :::::::: i h c L? «i«5«&gt; a « "S ooioouseo 2 9&gt;iOnTf91 5.£ iflioiniouj «i &gt;• _* ■ t- as to .a I :2-*» a x E I ■^ S B j: ?« t M Hsoone S J t-coiotor- c •t #' v; a t I — t-ee«t- &lt;fe j- &lt; £ 1:J h N &amp;m g °1 s- I r u r^ 41 &lt;OQ«Q©rt ■f » &gt;5 n •* 05 i. a r— -# — i £ E (B -09 ©JOB t : :8 :S :g tf </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. The following table indicates the average annual profit or loss resulting from each plat and each rotation for the eight - year period as calculated when using the values indicated in the preceding tables. The results given in this table have been referred to so frequently thruout the preceding discussion that we deem it unnecessary to discuss them further. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 35 -2 h- '£ a &amp; - i s I 2J =&gt; *, ■? T r, &lt;9 a 1 X — X s II 1 - — r-ooec i -wt-qj t-oow , m&lt;Nfr- M t--ao | o^. p S « «f «o i a^N © :a &gt;~ os Jfcj»-c **&gt;C -hojio 3|«oi S3S SSS S S «^ft- I OOi— O l S 8|fe IS— ' ot - tc s 2» t. m . coeooa osooeo rtip« ■*«(- a&gt; 2 i ot b Aidto t-teuS N«j 3«oi — -fi ■g.1 Mto-* lingi ■o «-^O5 — to ; t-oeo O^tC NiNt- 00 ! IN— (M« — Nrt I — -M c^a: Tl E B"«-, &lt; B ■? V ■UT3T3 s B 3 I *ii aa| a •*• o o o X "—.3 MWM I W^K HH fa I HBm 1 H O 1 9* s 1 s «.*? t ■ ■ S : : S il* si* OOm I OOcn &amp;i si:: 15 IP &amp;* OOcq BJOO Oaitti t- 5 h5 71 T •fl I * s J"S. = 2l&lt;u ©t-oo ©ooao •♦t-N gtiHt- o « •? • * &lt;°.&lt; o .'°. "••&lt;&gt;• "&gt;«.» 9°?'". » °° i^ tij — §" « io oo od io»t-' us oi oi t^oo'io •« c-i .5 . OCOCO t-;t-;N "-JCOOO CO » OJ 00 !« ™2 t~co— tbeoo aotdei a&gt;oit~ \ie -t~ =.i^ = </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 6 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. I ! ' .* !*g *. 2 *■ b ■ — h» I HI 2 I 3 7 « s s s ~T~ c I c 5 oo oc t- o&gt; V | | ° s| "1 ■ So* ■ • fc ' « -&lt; o i5 "*! I "! *? P ~ *- I "3 • I 2J * n H i» -— . — f|v °|^ SS§ gg^ S :8 §§S Sg :l T~ ~~~ *S O"i3h «a&gt;o as — to - is Oi-H^r —■.-;■.- * «§il ".'*'* o *" 1 * :•( ®' - *. — t-. * -1 W |&amp; ■ :- a. "Sfe lit a c o^co ■«»■** »■* -!«« ** C : H Sttl 'Jga iioooui ] aiosso oi :x t-'oiio act~; '.ii © I i ! ; I tS *S&gt; 'i. 6.»wt- »oo&gt; O)se 'as — as o&gt;oo fej — — J 1 — "3? • "Id ' &lt; ! l^' fl ! °? "? "^ *". 9 !t *? 0( ! 0 . "i™. — SR I 5 £2 io«m «•»- n ■» as es « no si §&gt;» p I 53 -^ — — « — im —;oj — 35 ;- of — ryr . . . . . . —-. ry fe &amp; * a, i, i, if 5 I 1 'X'P.. I " 3|| ||5 11= l|, JfcJ OO00 OQOO oaaiO mOoJomKO ■&lt; to t- oo os •«■ fc- 1 "■ [ I </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Rot ations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 37 3 I- i ? o *J 8-* E~ ?«&gt; e* p 8 « 009) ?l I" £ - •^.s llhls s a 6 i &amp; asod i I- II II-*- ,1 s t; toco N. s o •51? i SS-3 °- ■■%.*&gt; 6.2 r .c ■« ill ? ? i Etas O 0) 08 OaiPL,O ST. •-C -T * « » 5 T " T f OJ 11 »* r 1 R «i &lt;*&gt;. 2 t- « co co IN IN 00 JJ &lt;N 1 « •. 8 S 8 | 88 !g ?8 iS SS : §38 SS S§ IN« 00 CO CO N ' -&lt;»1N drt INCM ; i ; 1 : IT" T i nt^ '00 rtP !^ .-tf-lOtOtDCO -&lt;t-;C0tOtCCC t^ W &gt;d t-^ '*h t-^odco'cow t- ■» od co co to '■ I • aiaa t~ c^od !oo »••• '. —&lt;« t^«D . .0)^ C0t» ••&lt; Q^ 'TO »■« ' O4CO O»&gt;-&lt; ' Tf» O5&gt;o t- 3eo oi oooo ■ ooo uso ■ cjo IO ■ O4 CT1 Uv ■ N OJ CM ' let- COCO ■ * 00 1~ cS** '. i-^ »&lt;■ i !^ 04^h . . oj t-" - U3 (O ' 01 »O »• M C I O lOtO.O) o-^ co oi^ •* oo oj o» ■ ■ ;e» rt^i ;oi ni-i ;oi i-ii-i ; ; ;n n . . . n : : : : H~T~1 :::::: :::::: I ill 6 H \i Hill! iilili m m "2 Si. Z =•£ 'fvL i &amp; I .ua)- ~ M&amp;bi :*g : : : : - a&gt; « o&gt; o&gt; - « &lt;t d a ' UaiaiO CJoacapaoap U«&lt;!&lt;!&lt;;o </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. I ii 1 ? 9 7 7 I G r- — i I o" o o n I! 1 ' 1 I J ■ 1 a | 2 la 1 55 II* I &lt; jf I — II "s-Jl ■ •■ S 3 ! 8|h 2 »-• § ° I I- I §1 M .SB — ]1 T U a a-' s _ . . — go.- a $ ■ : - H O U«i 1 CO I I loeet- eeei I 1 ' &lt;caio Oft-; -r:i I- — io lOt-t- aoo-* : — oj Ijil §0.0.3 iii | T ■ o SS : tt; sit-' . i aB ~ r Si NO ! 1 ouai T 00 to pi sS : •at- : I |__ : 1 I So - - i ■ N ! et- '■ i «« ■ I OHh SES a o £ OOIX 1 o r~jj CM I o? So S5 § U5C-' « OCA Ol doc ei !t-o •* ! — -. I "* : j : o-^ia lariat : : E 51 1 I I I CO 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 39 =i i_ 5 h . x. a. 00 O •« to ci U3«n oxiH vno: t- 33 CO © © frl "-^ «O^JN o nns neiei o'ocji &amp;£ £1" 3 g IO IO«« tOOC-H S0O3O3 ■ •&lt; ane © oi -h iq cni oj coco© nww odd III c 5 8. * 00 -M i " 3 co eo •-H tDiOJj U) -^) *-« NO(C to qoow i-joqw io oq as o i-ho&amp;J as ad co udcDoo* t ] — ■ ■ i-H £ I t-^l SOIOOS lO^f — OCOSO ■»ro oooco H»» moos o'o rtd« osaoco io'sooo 1 -5 : Htb c * — o * - ■»o. ■Jo . JL-J o. r -c ccfaO ccfaO in * n « n o " o to rtoite aito© t»t-iu5 eo &lt;-&lt;^;« ousts oomw od t~t^oi &lt;dco&lt;H ustc^I §s 1 I &gt; I "1 I "I """I "I * Q} i ■s. ~~ - &gt;- ~t-oo »-i«h ooe&gt;3 isien «eao&lt;-i tcaia&gt; ij* *i. 5.9) "&gt;.-*. c ~.°i 05 .^ 9^-1 "?"* e i ° gj &lt;cl"b Nui'H ei^&lt; ©in »»d cocici S* 00 ]* &lt;»- fc. I «S« a0 . c i i:^ 'ii rN .^: e ? °.'9'°. a0 . n . 01 . ■B «5 fLai eject- woo SS» 4&gt;£ &lt;O«CP1 COO *rl .?£ * rt •£«^ I Z ■ : VOit. be o«u9 w«-i o» i^- Of t-oi- a ~ III : " : 8 s . -2 ''""!*": °° 9 &gt; t * 00 . «o e&gt;a oo C4 c-; e&gt; u» c-; »o £5 o • oi si os N -w ooooo e&gt;iwx tdoV S"« ««! r^- 0 i-H ; Wrt rt^HN r-.rt.-i hnn m a I- 1 I I _o_o_o aaa dad woaoa id ■ 1 ! a© ••■3. c d Pro Ml IB OO03 s O * &lt;-! t/afeO iii </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155 i O fc USC-00 |1- OO 7 | C L. O O «ot-ao ot-6 ©O&lt;N aeS. I » K 2&gt;»© tf i t 53? 3-.^^ 3 - I 8 ««2 5 .2 s = a 1 I 1 i I 399 !*«W »«« c Wt~c3S 5» e« £-■« =*. g^g t- iat-a » t-o ft ? OOCM ;* ii- 5-s £2 = &lt;5 5 &lt;= ■2 » o^fc »&lt;c© -i il? ~.^^- "^ ia»« f§ c ? *• ■ V* I "" I »MM •j; ?i m SOt-« c ti &gt; § r c-. 3" b &amp; 11 d g J ''■'—' is S* fa 6.4 5E SI ** M.\ -I s.f ; *; 2 3 «^«i OOrtt- &gt; c lOt-ffl |1 \\&lt; o* ==« 1 S5 ■ 5. I &amp; i.MS ?-s 5 I c i i i,- = ■s I &amp;*o v I- c I ? -^ ■~ 3 &lt;0QQ J •7. a &lt; e 5 H </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 41 Table 8. — Eight years' average yield of spring wheat, oats, barley, corn, and sorghum from different methods of seed-bed prepara - tion and crop sequence. Bushels of grain and pounds of forage Cofn Sorghum Preparation Previous Spring of seed bed crop wheat Oats Barley forage Grain Stover 1 Manure applied to stubble of previous crop before plowing. 5 In sod rotations. per acre, 1907-1914. Fall plowed Sp. wheat OaU Barley Corn Sp. wheat 1 Manure. . / Alfalfa Brome grass ; 11.7 11.1 12.0 I Spring plowed Sp. wheat Oats Barley Corn Sorghum . Sp. wheat 1 Manure. . / Corn 1 Manure Oats / 12.2 9.6 10.2 10.1 Green manure Rye Peas Disked . ;Corn 10.4 17.1 . 20.7 . 15.4 ll.» 2,019 13.4 2,184 17.1 18.2 2,383 19.2 . 12.2 . 12.0 . 19.4 . 16.3 19.6 . 16.5 I I 13.8 2,411 15.9 ! 13.8 2,262 6,316 15.8 14.5 2,400 18.5 2,438 I 5,857 6,464 10.6 2,323 21.7 . 22.2 "''" I 17.9 27.4 13.4 26.7 20.8 2,711 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. 42 Table 9 1 . — Yield of spring wheat in bushels per acre as influenced by different methods of seed-bed preparation and the preri&lt;}i&lt;s crop, with profit or loss per acre. Effect of tillage Effect of previous crop Fall Spring n - . . Summer After Mte {, After piowed pfoweS Dlsked tilled corn s ™» 1911 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 1912 6.7 7.7 4.6 7.1 5.0 8.4 5.8 1913 2.5 2.2 3.0 6.8 3.0 1.7 :i.:i 1911 2.5 2.2 3.0 6.8 3.0 1.7 :i.:i 5.7 4.6 5.1 12.5 5.2 5.1 5.2 1914 Average per acre; 11.6 10.6 10.4 16.8 I 10.7 11.1 10.1 CROP VALUE, COST, AND PROFIT, OR LOSS IN DOLLARS PER ACRE Average ! Value of crop I $8.12 $7.42 $7.28 $11.76 Cost of produc- tion 6.56 6.09 4.75 11.50 Profit or loss... 1.66 I 1.33 2.53 .26 1 Straw is not given any value in this table. • See Table 6 for values used in making these computatior Numb berpl hits 5 4 8 3 11 5 1 907. 908 909 910 Bu. at. Bu. at. Bu. at. 24.7 23.1 24.5 27.8 21.1 24.2 18.0 18.3 14.5 7.1 7.4 7.3 Bu. at. 28.9 41.4 22.6 15.3 -| ; . Bu. at. Bu. at. 24.1 24.8 25.0 24.4 16.0 17.4 7.1 7.2 Bu. ur 23.5 20.3 16.3 i 8.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Rotations and [ TiWofle Methods in Western Nebraska. 4: k is vi U ■?! e I! ■= i P sis 1 1 I i It- 2 , I i !"3. 1 I fc oo OOOOOOOO" t- R— I o&gt; us co^co o&gt; cc n "-it^, CO W O I * ei no -5 .S 3 o!NO»OHOa« m** - 2 J t-odu5'-o«5ot-C) od .9 y C -MNM «S NN ♦» ig fc oo oi co co n so co to t- 2 1*3 &gt;JO OlD-"»^ COOXSO T » o— " «C'*50tc_t-t-^'0_'^eo_ eo /§ — y qo t-"« .£ _ . (j 00 •• « .S3 oiqoqoousooNC) a S os-*»oioo&lt;oo«eo "• !9 _ 3 I oS od oooooooooc o o &gt;j x 10 1- ■* « •» Tf 5cc a _; _ • o- ; «.cHf*»«.^»'* Z So -, ?g ] N-H'-iol - 1 -•Oi.SJ 1 k t-'* 2*3 o« =3 •i 2 t r to .«°» c &gt;i 1 = 1 o"= - ? *" a £■" 00 00 OS 00 © ■*■ © 00 00 B •» CC y C i CMCON CO « w go i I if- ""I fcoaoeo-spioiooaoco BJ N &gt;js ; cm -&gt;»"o © &gt;o to rp &gt;o Tji a. eo I c« T7 s « si .S3 =-t — toa&gt;—&gt;©o&gt;eo q &lt;o B £•" 3J t&gt; to e&gt;j © to © eo co o •» Me O.S I "^^ N " d — ■# 5 I g'S i b 11 i&lt; aQ O O O O O O O O CO &gt; * |J SiilS8SSSS g I So 5S || — - — r : j : || 22222222^ I &gt;&amp;* I. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155. •9 ? E Si 2 I ooooo-HOusoooiO T ■s 1 "S? 5 e -S «: ■t. otooeo-HOooo-.o 5 ?; ■^1 3 i 2i£« &gt;r NNO ■»£ I II S5. 0)NOBO(J1» 9P^« fw« I .......... »_ z 3"§ ■ ■ | i5?s =: r •5 a. ?t E II - o ■X — i- Sk ! a, * S I ja^TfiooN'oaiN &amp; «1 i- t-ot- 7 •3^ § ~i^ z 11 •g||« | Scopes w-a HJ 8 § 5 1 — t- • s.s - _$ 31 • 3g &lt; jooccooooost- II a 05 «fe 81 g 2 &amp;o ~ * z i K v fi = s 5 ! o3 m •2-g -:Sn: : : : • n o — Z 3 i &amp; 3e« 311 F- &lt; SOO0C--OU5O00 1O 2 « fe a L_J . w s •9*** "O N 8«^&gt;o»ooiq&lt;|0 ■Q^ 3 -eoooiocoo&lt;»otcoi 5&gt;~ g ' &lt;NO " H 1 iioxcoqocxq — a^i £ | 1 1 B i r "o j § te -*f us o; q «o o oo o&gt; 1^- I o - 4»««s^»-s ,_- I &gt;o x -^ i t* 6 \ "5 •»' I gu)Neaiat-o«oo </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 45 Table 12'. — Yield of barley in bushels per acre as influenced by different methods of seed-bed preparation and the previous crop, wUh profit or loss per acre. ! Effect of previous Straw is not given any value in this table. 2 See Table 6 for values used in making these computations. Effect of tillage """^ lage crop &gt;-«"F After Fall Spring Disked Summer small After plowed plowed | tilled grain corn No. plats 12 1 1 3 1 Year Bu. at. Bu. av. Bu. at. • Bit. a*. Bu. at. Bu. at. 1907 40.0 39.6 30.6 39.0 39.7 30.6 1908 43.3 21.0 24.9 67.7 28.4 24.9 1909 10.4 20.1 21.5 23.8 16.8 21.5 1910 12.5 14.9 7.9 26.0 14.1 7.9 1911 0.0 0.0 0.0* 0.0 0.0 0.0 1912 14.6 20.4 12.3 10.0 18.5 12.3 1913 5.0 6.4 5.0 16.5 5.9 5.0 1914 11.0 4.5 5.2 20.8 6.6 5.2 Average per acre 17.1 15.9 13.4 26.7 16.3 13.4 CROP VALUE, COST, AND PROFIT OR LOSS IN DOLLARS PER ACRE. "Average III II 'Value of crop. . $7.01 i $6.52 $5.49 $10.95 I Cost of production 6.46 5.99 4.65 11,40 Profit or loss 55 i .53 .84 —.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 155 t— lO^t-Ntcxniext'MOxiete-wt-fC-xMSfjiaivi'Xi--*-*-:?;^!?. I X m _; — ' _;^^i « "WNii^wterjifi i p^ *"* &amp;l &gt;O 0940 10 t* CO CO N O) t^ SO N C*J SC C3 CO t* 01 •© *O TiiXN'rifiNJBKmXJ.t-XiaKl'KK 5, ionr-MAA i «««S«3eieo'vt-Mia'a3 t- ?j*ftir;M— M^ 5 II ' ■ O 1^ l' &amp; at-N^tox^xt-O — t- — « — ooso»ocft«i- — NxcxxfRVNSu:NXRnQ&lt;f ~ &lt;■ »»NNNNxaO'f«XX3)h31«^n*)»'r--i/;ftX3'.t-X"flXt3' ; *ifil-3'.i!:- X a. i I a, I i "&amp; "? 5 •? 1 I 9 s i (OICt-»«0-NMfiO'*t-xaS'-N! l Jf'0 10t-X3lO«N«j«5¥l-Xy.5-Nr:f h(-t-C&gt;t-»a0«KXXXXXXA9)«3)n«««««5ooSO9 53S3---" - 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 QO 00 00 0D 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 A Ql &amp;} 0^ Cft Cft Cft Oft Cb CA Cft 9) Oft Oft Oft Ie TT+++ 1 + 1 +T+T+ ! + 1 ++ ! iT i i 1 1 + 1 ++++++ 1 i +++ I R , I 82!|SS£3P3SgSg«§3SS£::S3§S!g2SS2^$i85?!g2|S 8 J&gt; S5S528SS3S?32gg!|§g=SS2SSS8S^a§S5SSa=S5^ 5 » - _2 - — i =Sa25ga85S2S£2MSS5§S§3=S88r«5«§o=»«9^r=» = * O 'mm ' 'oiei-lw — ' -* «W ' ■■ -« — « « ««-• ' — JU ot-ft-OBBxrxieNoit-j.t-sN-rrfSneiiOfi'ieoBio-^t-t-i-tCi- oe ■* • j 8S§g2SgSS2£S5S§S!SSgJ:2S§SSI£i?SS£g=ESg=SSS S QQtn "* * ' "*"* ' "WN'-NMNN^N^ — — «« — MM —MM NNN- M g*g| « ••■_;••-;■■_:■• -n --• • --^ • «n • • «- ' H| 3 ' S je S eot ~ aocia 2* 0l9X S tot " o * ol E:2 a) S:SiS22 to *£2 i *£SS2S'r x 't£!£^2S 9 * 3 a a8^t|§2SS2282gSgg?gg2a5f:=SSSaSlSg2S5S?22 5 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Rotations and Tillage Methods in Western Nebraska. 47 Chart V /8"7S- '9*/. 7&gt;*C /f/rr *St/st£ &gt;Stu.v sjrfy- Oct. /O ** JO IO dfi JO 9 /9 M9 9 '3 £9 B '8 18 7 IJ JtJ 7 If 7* H 1% \% as «* K It B' ax »■¥ OS 90 BOO O' a* OS OS or / / /SO J7/TY9' ff/TYZ. &amp;i 'T.3O </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Bulletin 155. Chart VI. (12-23-M5— 8M.) lifiiiiiitmlli i. ft; N ft* IH 5 V M 3 sa^i!!S?i^g??"?&gt;&gt; i *a 5 $ $ 5 5 3 5 3 $ « ? $ ? s * ? s 5 5 • • N • "» * •» H N " A </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>