<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pump Irrigation in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1917-09-10">1917-09-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, MARCH 10, 1917 CIRCULAR NO. 2 PUMP IRRIGATION IN NEBRASKA By E. E. Brackett, Associate Professor of Agricultural Engineering, and O. W. Sjogren, Assistant Professor of Agricultural Engineering INTRODUCTION Yields of the field crops of Nebraska are in a measure due to the farming methods used and to the thoroness with which these methods are carried out, but every Nebraska farmer knows that he has no control over the greatest factor influencing yields — the weather. Crops may be injured by too much rain, by hail, by wind, by frost; but lack of moisture usually causes more loss than all of these. Injurious shortage of moisture may not be evident when the total rainfall for the season is considered since this tells nothing of its distribution thru the growing season. Nebraska's crops have been curtailed in many seasons by this shortage of moisture during the critical periods of growth, and in few cases will it be found that crop failure was due to shortage of the total rainfall for the season. The use of water from the rivers of the state for irrigation has grown to a point where the down stream farmer is in jeopardy of crop loss thru shortage of the flow, and this condition has stimulated the installation of pumping plants to supplement an unreliable ditch supply or to serve as a source of supply for an individual irrigation system. Before one decides to install a pumping plant for irrigating purposes there are a good many factors that should be con- </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 sidered regarding the feasibility of the project and the con - struction of the plant. The material contained in this bulletin has been obtained from studying pumping plants in actual operation in this and other states and from experience gained while installing plants in this state. EXPLANATION OF TERMS USED Head — This refers to the pressure of water. This may be measured as the height of a column of water in feet or as the pounds pressure per square inch. A column of water one foot high has a pressure of .434 pound per square inch; or a pressure of one pound per square inch is equivalent to that of a column of water 2.304 feet high. For example, a column of water ten feet high has a head of ten feet, or a pressure of 10 X .434 = 4.34 pounds per square inch. To convert pounds pressure to head in feet multiply by 2.304, as 4.34 X 2.304 = 10 feet. Friction head — When water flows thru a pipe there is friction between the water and the pipe, and the head or pressure neces - sary to overcome this friction is called the friction head. Duty of water — In irrigation this expresses the relation between a given quantity of water and the area which it serves. In other words, it is the amount of water used per acre for the season, given in depth in feet or inches. It is also expressed as the number of acres that will be irrigated by a flow of one second - foot thruout the irrigating season. Acre-foot — An amount of water which will cover an acre to a depth of one foot is referred to as an acre-foot. Acre-inch — An amount of water which will cover an acre to a depth of one inch is called an acre-inch. Second-foot — A flow of one cubic foot of water per second is said to be one second-foot. Draw-down — The distance that the water is lowered below its natural level by pumping is the draw-down. Lift — The height thru which the water is pumped is the lift. AMOUNT OF WATER REQUIRED Determining factors — Several factors must be considered in making an estimate of the amount of water to be pumped. These are: the area to be irrigated, the duty of water or depth of water to be applied on the land, length of the irrigating season, nature of the soil, kind of crop, climate or weather conditions, and the distance the water must be carried to get it on the land. Of these the first three are probably most important even tho they are more or less dependent on the other factors. If one knows the </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 3 area to be irrigated, the depth of water to be applied, and the duration of the application, it becomes an easy matter to deter - mine the amount required. Sufficient allowance must be made for the influence that these other factors may have upon the quantity required. For example, if the water is to be carried over or used on an open soil, more water will be lost in the distribution system, and hence more must be pumped than would be necessary for a close soil. From data gathered in this state by the Office of Public Roads and Rural Engineering of the United States Department of Agriculture, it was found that the depth of water applied in the Platte Valley during the season of 1914 averaged 4.54 inches over the area irrigated. The maximum depth was 7.02 inches and the minimum depth was 2.3 inches. The season was quite dry, so it seems that when a pumping plant supplements the rainfall, more than one foot of water will rarely if ever be required. If this is considered as the depth of water to be supplied and if the acreage to be irrigated is known, the required capacity of the plant can very easily be computed. The capacity of pumps is given by the manufacturers in gallons per minute. A pump delivering 450 gallons per minute delivers one cubic foot of water per second. This is an amount sufficient to cover an acre to a depth of one inch in one hour or to a depth of two feet in twenty-four hours. If then a pump of this capacity is operated </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 for ten days of twenty-four hours each, enough water will be pumped to cover 40 acres to a depth of six inches or 20 acres to a depth of one foot. (See table 1.) Table I 1 Number Capacity,! Number of acres irrigated six inches deep, of pump Capacity, in second- Pump is operated the following number of 24 - or diam- in U. S. J feet, or | hour days each month. eterof gallons I acre- discharge per inches (Number of days operation) in inches minute per hour 30 I 20 I 15 I 10 I 5 I 2} 1 5 700 1.60 190 I 127 95 j 63 32 16 6} ■From University of California Agricultural Experiment Station Circular No. 117. Length of season and capacity required — Assuming that a 40 - acre field of some crop is to be irrigated in five days to a depth of three inches, this will be equivalent to irrigating ten acres to a depth of one foot, or ten acre-feet of water are to be pumped in 120 hours. This will require a pump having a capacity of 450 gallons per minute. If the plant is to be operated for a shorter period than 24 hours each day and it is desired to get the same amount of water on the land in the same time, a relatively larger plant must be installed. DISTRIBUTION OF THE WATER If the crop is of such a nature as to permit continuous opera - tion thruout the season a smaller plant can be used. The plant should not be so small that the distribution of the water will be difficult, due to the small amount pumped. A small quantity of water flowing thru a ditch makes its distribution difficult and also causes a relatively larger loss from seepage and evaporation than where a larger quantity flows. The cost of each unit of water delivered on the land is therefore greater for the small plant than for the larger one. On the other hand, the capital invested in a small plant is small, and consequently the fixed charges (interest on investment and depreciation) are low. A 2 V V 100 150 225 300 400 0.22 0.33 0.50 0.66 0.90 27 40 60 80 110 18 27 40 53 71 13 20 30 40 55 9 4} 13 6$ 20 10 27 13 35 18 2} 09 10 3} 13/10 5 2 61 2| 9 3§ 6 7 8 900 1,200 1.B00 2.00 2.70 3.50 240 , 320 i 430 I 160 120 ! 213 160 ; I 287 215 1 80 40 107 54 143 72 20 27 37 8 101 14J </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Pump'Irrigation in Nebraska 5 short period of operation demands a large plant on which the first cost (and consequently the fixed charges) will be high. The operating expenses, however, are lower per unit pumped than with the small plant. This difference in the cost of pumping may be more than offset by the increased fixed charges. Planning the system — In planning the distributing system several factors must be borne in mind, such as: method of applying the water, whether by flooding, border, furrow, or check; and location of plant with regard to topography, head available, and distance. In this state, the most general methods of applying the water to the land are the flooding and furrow methods. In locating a plant it is always well to place it on the highest part of the field if other conditions permit. This will make the distribution a simple matter in that the water can be applied to any part of the field. If the plant is located in a low place and it is desired to get the water onto the higher land, it cannot be done without installing pipe lines and forcing the water up to this land which would be very expensive if the pipe lines are of any appreciable length. Amount of water flowing — The amount of water flowing will determine very largely what type of distribution system to use as a small amount demands a treatment different from that given a large amount. The slope of the land will determine the smallest amount that should be used. The amount should be large enough so that the water reaches the farthest portion of the land without a large ditch loss. When water flows rather deep in a ditch, the velocity is greater and it will distribute better than if the water runs shallow. Distance — The distance that the water must be carried also influences the design of the system in that the seepage losses, sometimes called ditch losses, become larger the greater the distance from the supply. It should always be the aim, when conditions will permit, to place the pumping plant as close as possible to the fields that are to be irrigated. DESIGN OF PLANT If a plant is to operate efficiently it must be properly designed for the conditions under which it is to operate. The pump should be of the proper capacity and the engine should be of the proper size so that the power will be used most efficiently. The pump selected will depend upon the quantity of water desired and upon the depth of the well or head against which it must operate. The size of the engine depends upon the capacity and efficiency of the pump and upon the depth of the well. A large pump will ordinarily have a greater efficiency than a smaller one </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 of the same type. The type of pump also affects the efficiency. The accompanying table indicates the efficiency of single stage single suction centrifugal pumps and the horsepower required for each foot of lift. Theoretical H P = GaI - P^ min - X wt. of 1 gal, in lbs, x lift in ft. oo,(XX) A gallon of water weighs approximately 8$ pounds. The total lift in feet should include the head due to the friction of the water in the pipe. By head is meant the lift. If the efficiency of the pump is known, the actual horsepower can readily be obtained as follows: A , , . Theoretical horsepower w ,„ Actual horsepower= = r - X 100 Efficiency in per cent Size of pump Capacit; TABLE 2 Average I H. P. per ft. oflift efficiency, ■ Cost of Cu. ft. per cent 1 Theoret- .. . pump per sec. ical «""»" 0.22 30 .025 .083 $37.50 0.33 .037 .090 Gal. per minute 2 Normal 100 Max. 150 1\ i Normal 150 l-Max. 225 I 0.33 35 .037 .105 45.00 0.50 .057 .163 3 Normal 225 Max. 300 0.50 40 .057 .142 55.00 0.67 .076 .190 0.89 45 .101 .220 65.00 1.00 .113 .252 1.22 .138 .310 4 Normal 400 450 Max. 550 5 Normal 700 Max. 900 1.53 50 .176 .350 82.50 2.00 .227 .450 2.00 1 50 .227 .450 110.00 2.67 .303 .600 ► • &lt; I 3.56 i 55 .404 .730 150.00 4.67 .530 .960 6 Normal 900 Max. 1,200 X Normal 1,600 Max. 2.100 'University of Californi; a Agricultural Experiment Station Circular No. 117. Horsepower require in gallons per minute puted by the followinj id — If the discharge of the pump is given ;, the theoretical horsepower can be com- g formula: </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 7 Characteristics — The accompanying curves (plates 1 and 2) show how the efficiency, actual horsepower, and the speed of the pump vary with different discharges for a certain head or lift. For example, from the curves of the 4-inch pump (plate 1), the greatest efficiency is shown to be obtained when the discharge is about 450 gallons per minute. The horsepower curve indicates that 13J horsepower are necessary for this discharge. If, instead of the necessary power, a 10-horsepower engine is used the maximum discharge would be only 300 gallons per minute, thus causing the pump to be operated far below its maximum efficiency and capacity. It is thus seen that the pump and engine must be properly proportioned if the best of service is to be obtained at the lowest cost. : si I DISCHAROI II OiLLOIS MR MIlUTf . Plate I — Characteristic curves for a 4" centrifugal pump at a 60' head (Data from New Mexico Bulletin No. 77) Size of pipes — It is also important to use proper size of suction and discharge pipes. The suction pipes are generally large enough if they are of the same diameter as the suction opening. This is generally two inches larger in diameter than the discharge opening. An increaser should be used at the discharge so as to make it possible to use as large a pipe for the discharge as is used for the suction line. In this way, a considerable saving in power will result. For example, if a No. 4 pump is installed in a well I If - -iii II t ■ ! 1 xh : ffl ffiltf Wit \m LLl t Ml * S8 i , 1 ' I ■ ! &gt;+4. i I 1 i f i if t ri i-i IM/ft " ; ;.Jili II J jie ii*fn Tl 1 HI M a &lt;;j toi I t ' L|J| M ( 1 TT I . 1 "H -H'-'l r {HJi • i Hi ** »« o i» p * TfHHJ | : ! T Ill mm a* 11 11 .: 100 300 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 8 pit 20 feet deep and the suction pipe extends 20 feet below the pump and a discharge of 450 gallons per minute is desired, the following amount of pipe is necessary: 20 feet of vertical and about 4 feet of horizontal discharge pipe, and one connecting elbow ; 20 feet of 6-inch suction pipe, and one elbow. If the water is Plate II — Characteristic curves for a 6" centrifugal pump at a 60' head Data from New Mexico Bulletin No. 77) lowered almost to the bottom of the suction pipe when pumping, there would be a total lift of 40 feet not including friction. The friction head would be as follows when delivering 450 gallons per minute: If the discharge pipe is of 6-inch diameter, the following will be the result: } I ii mm i- Hi IM t I! tt « &amp;* 1 1 1 iiiti w ii iH W\ i »8« Ml I ffi m I ( T 1 4 1 L ;l rH 4 rt* *• I ii! Ml 1 Wwtirtf: i m ~. m n :■ S | S I 1 1 i-i ; 1 IPS h It* it t I T 4 1 iiij: !' Hli! i li lt4)H T-m i lit ft !'! f ! ! I • tlllli li, S ! * S -I 1 -li T l Hi Li 250 500 .750 looo 1250 1500 1 DISCHARGE 11 GALLONS PER KIKCTI. lead lost thru friction in 20 ft. 6 in. pipe del. 450 g. p. m lead lost thru friction in 1 6 in. elbow del. 450 g. p. m . . lead lost thru friction in 24 ft. 4 in. pipe del. 450 g. p. m lead lost thru friction in 1 4 in. elbow del. 450 g. p. m ... 0.092ft. . .. 0.392 ft . . 3.331 ft. ... 2.015ft Total friction head Vertical lift . .. 6.830 ft 40.000 ft </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 9 Head lost thru friction in 44 ft. 6 in. pipe del. 450 g. p. m Head lost thru friction in 2 6 in. elbows del. 450 g. p. m 0.8228 ft. 0.7840 ft. Total friction head 1.6068 ft. Vertical lift 40.0003 ft. Total head 41.6 ft. The water horsepower for the case where a 4-inch discharge pipe is used will be 5.18, while in the case of the 6-inch discharge the water horsepower is only 4.7. From table 2, a 4-inch pump delivering 450 gallons per minute has an efficiency of 45 per cent. If a 4-inch discharge pipe is used, 12 horsepower will be required; while if a 6-inch discharge pipe is used, 11 horsepower will do the work. Four per cent allowance has been made here for belt slippage. Thus, there will be a saving in the fuel that would be required for one additional horsepower. For small engines the fuel required is 1.1 pints per brake horsepower hour. For one horsepower this would amount to 1.65 gallons of fuel oil in 12 hours. At the present price of gasoline which is 17 cents per gallon, this would mean a saving of 28 cents for each 12 hours operation, or a saving of $11.20 for a season's operation of 40 days of 12 hours each. The discharge pipe should not be carried any higher above the surface of the ground than is absolutely necessary; for, as seen above, every foot added to the lift increases the operating cost. COST OF A PLANT The cost of a pumping plant depends upon several factors, — size, type and grade of machinery, method of installation, and kind and depth of well. The depth of the well determines the type of pump, and the operating head; capacity and efficiency of the pump determine the size of engine. Therefore, it may be said that the well is the determining factor in the cost of a plant. Due to the variation under different conditions, no estimate of cost can be made that will apply in all cases. The tables given below give the approximate cost of pumps, engines, and pipe and will enable an estimate to be made for almost any condition. These figures of cost were obtained from dealers very recently. The figures given do not include the cost of trans - portation but are net at the jobbers'. Other cost items that must be considered are transportation, accessories, and housing. Accessories include such items as pipe and fittings, primer, and belt or other connection between pump and engine. The cost of accessories will vary with the type of plant and method of installation. No certain figure can be given, and the cost must </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 be estimated after the operating conditions have been determined. The cost of transportation will depend on the length of haul by rail and wagon. The cost of installation will vary with the cost of labor and material and also with the size of the plant. A small plant should be installed for not more than ten per cent of the total cost of the machinery. This may be reduced for the larger plants. The cost of housing will be nearly constant for plants of all sizes, so that for a small plant the cost will be high when taken as per cent of the machinery cost, while in large plants this will be low. Approximate cost of engines at the factory: Horsepower Gasoline engines Kerosene oil engines COST OF OPERATION AND NET RETURNS The items to be considered in the cost of operation are: fuel cost, fixed charges, repairs, and attendance. In many instances, the fuel cost only is considered but this does not give the real cost. The money expended for the plant would bring an income if invested in other commercial channels, and it is therefore just to consider the interest on the capital invested as a part of the operating cost. The plant will decrease in monetary value from year to year so that the depreciation of the plant must be considered. Other items of cost are repairs, attendance, etc. All these can be v &lt;p«su 4 80 6 110 $290 8 160 360 10 225 420 12 266 470 15 325 520 20 690 Approximate cost of black iron pipe per foot: Diameter in inches Price per foot 2 $0.14i 2| 22 3 29 4 46; 5 62 6 81; 7 1.07 8 1.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 11 listed as fixed charges. As a basis from which to reckon the fixed charges the following figures collected by the Department of Agricultural Engineering relative to farm equipment are used : Depreciation 10% Repairs and maintenance 2J% 10% Repairs and maintenance. Interest 6% Total 18|% Attendance is figured at 25 cents an hour, but inasmuch as the attendant devotes only part of his time to the plant and part to the distribution of the water it is assumed that half of the time the plant will run without attendance. Gasoline and kerosene engines are used almost exclusively in this state for the motive power, and the following figures are based on this fact: Assume that a 40-acre field of corn is to be irrigated to a depth of six inches of water during a period of ten 24-hour days. The well has a total lift of 30 feet. A total of twenty acre-feet of water will be required in 10 days or two acre-feet per day. A 4-inch pump of high efficiency will deliver this amount or 450 gallons per minute. From the table it is seen that this amount of water per minute will require 0.252 brake horse- power per foot lift or a total of 7.5 horsepower to operate the pump. An 8-horsepower engine will therefore be installed. FIRST COST OF PLANT No. 4 centrifugal pump $65.00 8 H. P. engine 160.00 Primer and belt 20.00 Pipe and fittings 20.00 Transportation 35.00 $300.00 Installation, 10% of above 30.00 Building to house the plant 50.00 Total cost of plant $380.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 COST OF WELL Excavating pit 8'xl2' deep $8.00 Curbing (concrete) 24.00 Labor 10.00 Boring and casing well, 20 feet @ $5.00. . . . 100.00 Total cost of well $142.00 Total cost of plant and well $522.00 FUEL CHARGE Pump operated 10 days to supply 6 inches of water to 40 acres. Engine uses 1.0 pint of fuel per brake horsepower hour when using gasoline, or 1.0 gallon per hour for an 8 H. P. engine. The plant being operated for 240 hours requires a total of 240 gallons of fuel for the season. With gasoline selling at the present price of 17 cents a gallon, the fuel cost $40.80 Lubricating oil 5.00 Attendance 120 hours @ 25 cents 30.00 Fixed charges, 18J% of cost 96.57 Total cost $172.37 Cost per acre $4.31 Cost per acre-foot of water per foot of lift, 28.7 cents. Fuel and lubrication cost per acre-foot per foot lift, 7.63 cents. If kerosene is used for fuel instead of gasoline, the fuel cost will be reduced considerably as the present price of kerosene is 6} cents per gallon. For kerosene 1.1 pints of fuel per horsepower hour is used. The fuel and lubrication cost in this case would be $22.16 or 3.69 cents per acre-foot of water per foot lift. The total cost would be $3,718 per acre. These figures can not be taken as absolute nor will they remain constant for all depths. They serve, however, as an indication of what the cost will be. Figures collected by the Office of Public Roads and Rural Engineering of the United States Department of Agriculture relative to pump irrigation in the Platte and Republican River Valleys of this state during the season of 1914 show that the fuel and lubrication cost for pump- ing varies widely, from a minimum cost of 4.35 cents per acre- foot of water per foot of lift to a maximum of 13.0 cents. These figures are from 12 different plants. For the season of 1916 four plants have reported completely to date and show costs </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 13 varying from a minimum of 3.89 cents to a maximum of 10.4 cents per acre-foot per foot of lift. Not irrigated Irrigated Fig. 1 — Showing effects of irrigation on corn crop. Note size and number of ears as indicated by arrows. Pictures taken within a short distance of each other in the same field NET RETURNS The question most frequently asked where an irrigation pumping plant is being contemplated is, will it pay? There are so many factors entering into the reply to such a question that it is impossible to make a definite statement that can be applied to all conditions. The personal factor is a very determining one. One man will make a success of pumping with conditions under which another man would make a failure. Aside from this factor, here are others, such as locality and depth of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 Where the water is close to the surface so that it will not have to be lifted to any great height it can be placed on the land at a very low cost and a good return will be obtained from the ordinary crops. In the course of the last season a drouth came at the critical time for the corn crop. Where the pumping plants were used at that time for irrigating the corn, the yield was about double the unirrigated yield. At the prevailing prices for corn this netted a big profit. The unirrigated corn yielded from 15 to 25 bushels, while the irrigated corn yielded from 30 to 40 bushels. If an increase of 15 bushels per acre is obtained due to irrigation, this, at 70 cents per bushel, will give a gross increase of $10.50 per acre. If the cost of irrigation as shown in table 2 is $3,718 per acre, a net return of $6,782 per acre would be realized. With ordinary prices this net return would be reduced. The net return would also be reduced as the depth of the well increased, so that there is an economical lift beyond which it would not be profitable to pump for irrigation. The deeper a well, the greater the cost of the water; so that if the cost is too great to realize a fair net return from ordinary crops, higher - priced crops must be grown or the idea of irrigating by pumping must be abandoned. It was found in collecting data last season in cooperation with the Office of Public Roads and Rural Engineer - ing of the United States Department of Agriculture that un - irrigated sugar beets yielded 10 to 11 tons per acre, while irrigated beets yielded 15 tons per acre. With beets selling at $6.50 a ton this nets a large profit. ECONOMICAL LIFT Just where to place the limit of economical lift is rather difficult, due to the variation in market prices from year to year, in the season, and for different crops. About the only way to arrive at any conclusion regarding this would be to make an estimate of the cost of the plant, of the operating cost, and of the increased crop return due to irrigation and so get an estimate of the net return. TEST WELLS The first requisite of a pumping plant is that a supply of water large enough to supply the needs be available. Because this supply is found below ground a survey must be made of conditions below the surface. The method of obtaining some idea of the available supply is by means of test wells. These test wells are merely holes sunk or bored into the ground thru the water-bearing strata. Accurate observations are taken of the </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 15 different conditions met as the sinking progresses. Generally the first test well is made on the highest part of the land which is to be irrigated. If this first well gives indications of a supply large enough for the requirements, further test wells are unnecessary and the well proper can be constructed in this location. Some - times, however, several test wells must be sunk in different localities before a suitable location is found or before a definite conclusion can be drawn. Sinking — Where the water is relatively close to the surface an ordinary post hole auger can be used for boring the hole down to water. The handle is lengthened by means of iron pipe. Care must be taken in making the hole to make it plumb. After water is reached the soil generally gets too sloppy to allow the use of the auger, and a sand pump must then be used to take the material out of the hole. If the soil stands up well one may be able to go to water before the use of casing is necessary. It is advisable to use casing in the hole after the water level is reached so as to prevent the caving in of the sides as the material is taken out by the sand pump. Ordinary iron Fig. 2— Logs of three test wells sunk in the same field Does not give promise of a large flow a due to absence of a large amount of coarse material b) Gives promise of a medium flow due to a fair amount of coarse material Presence of a large amount of coarse c material gives promise of a large flow pipe or sheet iron well casing can be used for casing the well. The casing should be weighted to cause it to sink as the dirt is taken from the inside of it by the sand pump. Casing of four inches diameter is sufficiently large to use for test wells. This will allow gravel of sizes up to three inches to be removed. Samples of the material should be taken from the well when - ever any change in the nature of the material is noticed, and a careful record should be kept of the thickness of each layer and of its depth from the surface. This will be of great help in estimating the supply of water available after the test well is </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 Where the water is close to the surface so that it will not have to be lifted to any great height it can be placed on the land at a very low cost and a good return will be obtained from the ordinary crops. In the course of the last season a drouth came at the critical time for the corn crop. Where the pumping plants were used at that time for irrigating the corn, the yield was about double the unirrigated yield. At the prevailing prices for corn this netted a big profit. The unirrigated corn yielded from 15 to 25 bushels, while the irrigated corn yielded from 30 to 40 bushels. If an increase of 15 bushels per acre is obtained due to irrigation, this, at 70 cents per bushel, will give a gross increase of $10.50 per acre. If the cost of irrigation as shown in table 2 is $3,718 per acre, a net return of $6,782 per acre would be realized. With ordinary prices this net return would be reduced. The net return would also be reduced as the depth of the well increased, so that there is an economical lift beyond which it would not be profitable to pump for irrigation. The deeper a well, the greater the cost of the water; so that if the cost is too great to realize a fair net return from ordinary crops, higher - priced crops must be grown or the idea of irrigating by pumping must be abandoned. It was found in collecting data last season in cooperation with the Office of Public Roads and Rural Engineer - ing of the United States Department of Agriculture that un - irrigated sugar beets yielded 10 to 11 tons per acre, while irrigated beets yielded 15 tons per acre. With beets selling at $6.50 a ton this nets a large profit. ECONOMICAL LIFT Just where to place the limit of economical lift is rather difficult, due to the variation in market prices from year to year, in the season, and for different crops. About the only way to arrive at any conclusion regarding this would be to make an estimate of the cost of the plant, of the operating cost, and of the increased crop return due to irrigation and so get an estimate of the net return. TEST WELLS The first requisite of a pumping plant is that a supply of water large enough to supply the needs be available. Because this supply is found below ground a survey must be made of conditions below the surface. The method of obtaining some idea of the available supply is by means of test wells. These test wells are merely holes sunk or bored into the ground thru the water-bearing strata. Accurate observations are taken of the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 17 the upper end. The casing sinks as the material is excavated from the inside. If it is coarse, an "orange peel" bucket can be used for removing it; while if finer material such as sand or fine gravel is found, more rapid progress is made by using a large sand pump known as a "suction bucket" shown in figure 3. If clay strata are encountered a large auger should be used to bore thru these, as the orange peel or suction bucket will make but very little progress thru clay. Gravel treating wells — If a great deal of fine sand is encoun - tered in the water strata, the practice of "gravel treating" the well is at times resorted to. This consists of sinking a tight or "blind" casing of a diameter four inches or more larger than the diameter of the well. After the desired depth is reached, the perforated casing is lowered inside this blind casing and centered to place. The space between the two casings is then filled with gravel that will be retained on a f-inch mesh screen. As the gravel is added, the outer casing is withdrawn so that the gravel is kept about a foot above the bottom of the blind casing in order that the fine sand shall be held away from the perforated casing. Casings — Several types of casings are used. Figures 5 show three popular types. By means of a special tool, perfora- means oi a special tool penora- 4 _ Section ghowing pelted tions can be cut in the casing casing with a part of the gravel in after it is in place in the well; place and outer "blind 3 casing but if this method is used, the )*mg removed galvanizing is broken at each opening, leaving the metal exposed. Corrosion will tend to en - large the slots. This holds true also when the heavy sheet metal is galvanized before being punched. The per cent of perforation is to be considered carefully; if too much material is cut away, the casing will not be rigid enough to withstand the inward pressure of the earth and water, and collapse may occur. The </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 lower end of the casing should be covered to prevent the inrush - ing of material from the bottom of the well. This is accomplished by placing a sheet of heavy perforated material across the bottom end of the casing be - fore lowering it into place. If the well is not gravel treated the perforated casing is sunk as the well is being dug. Then a quantity of Portland cement tied loosely in a gunny sack is dropped into the well to seal the bottom. Developing — After the well is finished, it is advisable to make a preliminary test if a pump is available. This test is to determine the output of the well and also to determine the distance that the water lowers in the well while pump - ing, commonly called the Fig. 5 (a) — Perforated sheet metal well casing "draw-down." In the preliminary test, water should be pumped slowly for several hours. It is particularly important that this precaution be observed if considerable fine sand has been encountered in the construction of the well. If a centrifugal pump is used, the control of the flow is best accomplished by a valve in the discharge pipe. The rate of pumping from the well should be increased very slowly in order that sand which comes into the well may be handled readily thru the pump. A safe rule to follow would be not to increase the rate of pumping so long as the water carries considerable sand. Rapid pumping at first has ruined some wells. Not only is the pump likely to become clogged with sand, but the Fig. 5 (fc) — Shutter screen casing </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 19 sudden removal of so much sand near the casing allows the finer material to cave down from above in such large quan - tities that in some cases it acts as a permanent barricade or dam, shutting off a large portion of the flow into the well. Slow pumping seems to permit these changes to take place gradually, resulting in an increased flow. Capacity — The limit of the capacity of the well is reached when the water is pumped out as fast as it reaches the suction pipe. If an attempt is made to operate at this capacity, the water will be lowered so that air will enter the suction pipe and this may cause the pump to cease operating until it is re-primed. From the standpoint of satis - factory operation it is therefore necessary that a quantity of water somewhat less than this be drawn from the well. PUMPS Determining factors in the selection of pumps — The rate of pumping and the total head against which the water is pumped are two factors of vital importance in selecting the pump. Should the well supply more water than necessary for irrigating the proposed area, the pump of the size required to supply water at the desired rate should be selected (see Fig. 5 (c) — Wire screen casing table 1); but if it is necessary to use all the water the well can supply, then the flow of the well determines the capacity of the pump, and one should be selected that will operate at its highest efficiency when delivering this quantity of water. In both cases the total head against which the pump will work must be specified and this can not be accurately stated unless the draw - down is known. This measurement is easily made in connection with the preliminary test, referred to on page 18, if a weir is used to measure the rate of flow. Before pumping begins the vertical distance between the surface of the water and the center of the outlet is measured; the pump is then started and the distance again observed, the difference between the two measurements being the draw-down for the rate of flow indicated by the weir. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 Types and selection — There are available upon the market several types of pumps, such as the plunger, rotary, and centrifugal pumps and water elevators. The centrifugal pump is used in most irrigation pumping plants. If this type of pump is chosen, it should be borne in mind that there are several types of centrifugal pumps, and care must be taken that the one selected is best adapted to the needs of the case. The choice must be between the vertical and horizontal types of centrifugals. Some manufacturers will not guarantee satis - factory operation where the suction head exceeds 20 feet, and 25 feet may be con - sidered the limit for any pump. If the test has shown the draw-down to exceed this distance, the choice falls to the turbine type of centrifugal (figure 6), which is small enough to lower into the casing to any desired depth. This is one of the most expensive, as well as most efficient, types of pump. To avoid using it, additional wells may be constructed near-by. The suction pipes from all wells can be con - nected together, reducing the draw-down and allowing the use of a cheaper pump. This also makes a lower head or pressure against which the pump must be operated. If the pump is to be driven by a belt from an engine placed above ground, it is not advisable to place a horizontal type more than 20 feet below the engine because of difficulties encountered in mak - ing the inclined runway for the belt and because an extremely long belt would be necessary. The vertical type (figure 8) of centrifugal pump can be used to a depth of fifty feet. Shafting in greater lengths than this will be difficult to keep lined up, and will give more or less trouble because of the vibration which will be unavoidable on account of lack of rigidity of the bearings and their support - ing frame work. Fig. 6 — Deep well turbine pump Figure 8 represents a typical installation for a vertical pump, the pump being submerged when not running, so that no primer </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 21 is required. While this simplifies operation, the work of repair - ing this pump requires more time and is not so convenient as on a horizontal pump. Figure 9 shows a common method of installing a horizontal pump. The pump is placed as near the surface of the water as possible to make priming easier and to reduce the suction head to a minimum. More excavating is required for this installation, and the belt is longer, running at an angle likely to cause excessive Fig. 7 — Several wells connected to one pump slipping. The convenience for inspection and repairs should not be overlooked. Figures 10, 11, and 12 represent several different types of horizontal pumps. Figure 10 shows the cheapest type of pump, — one of very light construction and inadequate bearings. It is not recommended for irrigation plants where a large amount of pumping will be done. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Pump Irrigation in*Nebra8ka 23 Figure 11 shows a better design with two bearings and better con - struction thru out; fig - ure 12 illustrates a double suction pump of high efficiency; and figure 13 illustrates a rotary pump which has recently been adapted for irrigation plants. Installation — The installation of any pump requires a good foundation. Pipe sizes should never be smaller than recommended by pump makers. It re - quires a much smaller amount of power to force a large quantity of water thru a large pipe than to force the same quantity thru a small one. Pipes should be sup ported independently of the pump so that it may be relieved of any undue strain. All joints and connections in the suction line should be air tight, — a very small leak may cause unsatis - factory operation and will lower the efficiency. Fig. 11 — Side suction horizontal centrifugal with double bearings and hand primer Priming — Unless in stalled submerged, the vertical pump (as well as the horizontal) must be provided with some means of priming, or filling the pump shell with water, since the centrifugal pump can- Fig. 12 — Double suction centrifugal pump </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 not raise water to fill itself as does a plunger pump. With a valve at the lower end of the discharge pipe, the upper part of this pipe can be shut off and a small pitcher pump, such as is commonly used on cis - terns, can be used for prim - ing (see figure 9). If a foot valve is in - stalled on the suction pipe, the pump can be primed by allow - ing water to flow in from a small tank above (see figure 14). Some pumps are supplied with a prim - ing attach - ment as in figure 11. Fig. 13 — Rotary type pump. Note large pulley Manufacturers usually furnish instructions for the operation of their pumps, and such instructions should be followed care - fully for best results. POWER The most common kinds of power used in this state for operating pumps are gasoline and oil engines. In some instances steam engines are used and probably electric power is utilized to some extent. Very often it is not necessary to consider the purchase of an engine for operating the pump inasmuch as a tractor or portable engine is already owned by the farmer. This engine is not used constantly and it can very well be utilized in irrigation. In such an event, the pump selected must be such that it is not too large for the engine and at the same time will make as efficient use of the power as possible. Another factor in </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Pump Irrigation in Nebraska 25 favor of the gasoline or oil engine is that constant attendance is not required as in the case of the steam engine. In choosing the type of engine, the fuel cost must be carefully considered. An oil engine would, at first thought, seem to have a much smaller fuel cost than either a kerosene or a gasoline engine. However, with the present system of distribution, kerosene and gasoline are available in most places from tank wagons; and if another fuel is to be used the purchaser must provide a tank or reservoir of a capacity sufficiently large to hold a carload of oil in order to benefit greatly by the lower price. It seems advisable therefore under present conditions to buy an engine that will use gasoline or kerosene successfully. Selection — In the selection of an engine it is advisable to con - sider and compare the following points on several engines: </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 Lubrication — It should be simple and dependable. Size and kind of bearings — They should be large enough to give ample bearing surface and be of such material as to be easily replaced in case of necessary repairs. Cooling system — Simple and positive action is desired cooling ryyy/rs Fig. 15 — Plan of pumping plant as installed at North Platte Substation Fig. 16 — Sectional elevation of pumping plant as installed at North Platte Substation </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Pump- Irrigation in Nebraska 27 Ignition system — It should be simple and effective. Size and weight of flywheels — They should give uniform speed. Size of crankshaft — It should be large enough to withstand the shocks to which it will be subjected. " Piston rings — See that they are numerous enough to eliminate any great tendency to leak past the rings. Valve arrangement — Are valves arranged and located so that their action is always dependable? Are they easily accessible for making adjustments? Governor — The governor should be of such type and design that it will be sensitive enough to regulate the speed of the engine within five per cent of normal. Electric power — If electricity can be purchased cheaply, the use of an electric motor is ideal for driving pumps since the first cost of the motor is less than that of an engine and it requires practically no attendance or repairs. SELECTION AND OPERATION OF THE MACHINERY Selection — In making the selection of the machinery, it is well to have in mind the reliability of the manufacturers as well as the reputation of their machinery. The manufacturers usually furnish complete working drawings and instructions for the in - stallation of machines and these should be followed to the letter. Where it is possible, it is usually a profitable investment to have a mechanic, who is employed by the manufacturers, superintend the installation if he is available at a reasonable price. Tests — If the machinery is purchased under guarantee of capacity, fuel consumption, regulation, etc., it is necessary to conduct tests to determine whether the machinery fulfills the guarantee. A third and disinterested party is often called in to supervise these tests. During the test the future operator should be present and have an opportunity to learn as much as possible about the various parts of the equipment, adjustments, care, etc. If a gasoline or oil engine is used, he should make particular note of the exact adjustments of fuel and air valves and of the timing of ignition for minimum fuel consumption when the engine is running the pump under its regular operating conditions. The speed of the pump should be watched during the test and sub - sequently, since for a given condition of lift there is one speed at which a centrifugal pump is most efficient. Efforts should be made to operate it at that speed. The manufacturer will furnish information as to the best speed for his pump. Operation — In the regular operation of the plant, lubrication is of prime importance. Cleanliness is essential for careful in - spection, and results in discovery of needed adjustments before breakage occurs with its ofttimes expensive delays for repairs. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 2 REFERENCES The Selection and Installation of Machinery for Small Pump Plants. By W. B. Gregory. Circular 101, Office of Experiment Stations, U. S. Department of Agriculture. Mechanical Tests of Pumping Plants in California. By J. N. Le Conte and C. E. Tait. Bulletin 181, Office of Experiment Stations, U. S. Department of Agriculture. Cost of Pumping from Wells for the Irrigation of Rice in Louisiana and Arkansas. By W. B. Gregory. Bulletin 201, Office of Experiment Stations, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The Use of Underground Water for Irrigation at Pomona, California. By C. E. Tait. Bulletin 236, Office of Experiment Stations, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The Selection and Cost of a Small Pumping Plant. By B. A. Etcheyerry. Circular 117, University of California Agricultural Experiment Station, Berkeley, California. Measurement of Water. By R. D. Kneale. Circular 24, Montana Agricultural College Experiment Station, Bozeman, Montana. Cost of Pumping for Irrigation. By Sherman M. Woodward. Bulletin 49, University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station, Tucson, Arizona. Ground Water Supply and Irrigation in the Rillito Valley. By G. E. P. Smith. Bulletin 64, University of Arizona Agricul - tural Experiment Station, Tucson, Arizona. Oil Engines for Pump Irrigation, and The Cost of Pumping. By G. E. P. Smith. Bulletin 74, University of Arizona Agri - cultural Experiment Station, Tucson, Arizona. The Small Irrigation Pumping Plant. By B. P. Fleming. Bulletin 71, New Mexico Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural College, New Mexico. Tests of Pumping Plants in New Mexico 1908-1909. By B. P. Fleming and J. B. Stoneking. Bulletin 73, New Mexico Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural College, New Mexico. Tests of Centrifugal Pumps. By B. P. Fleming and J. B. Stoneking. Bulletin 77, New Mexico Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural College, New Mexico. Cost of Pumping for Irrigation. By 0. L. Waller. Washing - ton Agricultural Experiment Station, Pullman, Washington. Practical Irrigation and Pumping. By B. P. Fleming. Pub - lished by John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, 1915. (2-10- 1 17— 12M) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>